you will form
an orderly queue on this side going up
to those steps the first person will
come on
i will they can have a talk and they
will depart by going behind the lectern
and down the steps that way okay so if
you want to queue for the lightning
talks you will cue on that side of the
room
along the wall
up to the steps and those who have come
in late tough
[Music]
well good morning and welcome to this
session on useful primitives our first
speaker this morning is gabriel capchuk
who's going to be talking about
steganography the floor is yours
gabrielle
[Music]
great
i see people are still
oh i take my wraps right i can do that
yeah
um
hi i'm gabe capchuk i'm really excited
to be uh put into the useful primitives
session today my whole goal of my talk
for today was to convince you that
steganography is a useful primitive um
and to some extent the the pc chairs did
a wonderful job and they've already done
my job for me by putting me in the
session
um it's uh uh my this is my main goal is
to convince you that uh steganography is
very uh gonna be very useful what was
kind of nice is during the q a yesterday
we also had the reveal that next year's
real world cryptography is really going
to be real world steganography um so i'm
committing and i'm starting the
tradition now this is now a real world
steganography
i'm in order to try and convince you
that segonography is going to be
something that you should care about and
do research on um i want to take a
moment to just think about some of the
big threats that are facing the crypto
community today um the obvious one uh is
these quantum computer things about
which i know nothing but are very scary
um and the nice thing is that we as a
community have heard about these things
and have started doing research and
started preparing ourselves um as
evident from we have a session at real
world crypto dealing with post quantum
crypto so so we're well on our way to
addressing this particular threat um a
second and possibly more insidious and
more scary threat is some of these
pieces of legislation that are popping
up around the world that are taking aim
at encrypted systems by making them
illegal we had a wonderful talk
yesterday um going over all the various
different types of legislation and
things that are happening to our to our
crypto systems or could potentially
happen to our crypto systems in the
future um and so i likely can piggyback
off of that wonderful talk and and just
say you know we were shown this map
yesterday of all the different places in
the world that are currently passing
legislation aimed at reducing the
accessibility of uh strong encryption
encrypted systems
and just to zoom in on two of these
there's currently laws on the books both
in australia and in india that would
essentially go after end time messaging
antenna encrypted messaging systems and
make them de facto unusable or illegal
within the country um and so there is a
potential future not so far away from us
when all of our lovely crypto that we
spent so uh so much work building just
might not be available to us anymore it
might be criminalized or it might be
suspicious to use this kind of
technology um and there's a question
about what should we do then right once
we no longer have access to all of our
beautiful systems what kind of things
can we do to provide privacy preserving
communications to people around the
world
and steganography should be the solution
to this this question right so for those
who haven't thought about seconography
ever which is you know probably not that
surprising and probably most of the
people in this room um the way that
stego is supposed to work is you have
two users who are communicating with
each other in the presence of some very
powerful sensor and the sensor's able to
read all of the plain text
communications that are going back and
forth between these uh within these two
parties
and they get to decide whether or not a
particular message can go through or not
and potentially block it right and so if
we have a message that's being sent
between two users something like let's
engage in civil disobedience to protest
putin's invasion of ukraine this might
not be a great plain text message to
send in russia right now right um this
this would potentially get you in some
trouble and so the idea is because we
can't send this uh sensitive message
instead the center and receiver are
going to send some kind of mundane
message something that actually the
sensor might be really happy to see
there are people sending right so hey so
i've been texting a hot tech how's your
grandmother doing right this is the kind
of message that we really might want
people to send to each other in order to
our society's function and so the sensor
might look at this and say ah totally
great you should send this message back
and forth um and the idea is that we're
gonna somehow encode this this sensitive
one into the mundane message such that
only the center receiver are able to
kind of extract out the sensitive
message and the sensors uh none the
wiser
um we've studied steganography as a
community for a long long time it
formalized in the 80s lots of amazing
theoretical works on segonography but
this particular kind of seconography
where you get kind of like natural
language communication both has kind of
your input message and as the output
distribution um it doesn't really seem
to be used in practice at all um and the
kind of uh uh secondary that we do have
access to is stuff like format
transforming encryption or all the
wonderful work that's happening um in
the tour projects you get uh folks
around censorship walls but these aren't
natural communications natural
communications right they fall a little
bit short if you're kind of
sending something that looks like
another protocol that's not how people
communicate and so it's not a really the
kind of steganographic system that we
might want in a potential future where
we don't have access to these encrypted
messaging systems
and so the question that i kind of want
to bring to everybody is um do you feel
ready should we feel ready as a
community uh for the potential future
where pseudorandomness itself is
considered to be suspicious right and
this is not such a far-fetched idea um
we're kind of seeing various different
versions of this popping up around the
world and it's something that we have to
prepare for now before it's too late
right before suddenly our everything
that we're using is is criminalized or
suspicious or something like that
um and so uh to kind of show you how
we're doing in terms of studying
steganography here's a graph of the just
pulling uh you know keyword searching
out of crypto bib the publications for
steganography and then post quantum
crypto um you can see that once we
figured out that post quantum things
were necessary we as a community really
mobilized and has done a fantastic
amount of work um we have a conference
right we have a nist uh standardization
process steganography on the other hand
has kind of just sat around and it's
kind of decayed down to basically
nothing um over time and this is this is
a real real problem we're not addressing
one of the major threats that's going to
be facing our communities in the
potential future
i mean you might think well we're not
doing this research maybe somebody else
is picking up the slack for us um and
the good news is yes people are indeed
picking up the slack for us and this is
uh pulled off of dblp for all the
publications using the the word
steganography most of these publications
are coming out of machine learning or
computer vision communities
and and this is great they're they're
doing lots of work that we as a
community are not doing um the
unfortunate bad news is they're not
particularly good at provable security
and so at the same time there's tons and
tons of papers about stake analysis
breaking the exact same constructions
that they're making um and so this is
concerning right we kind of outsource
this work on steganography to
communities that are not used to working
with the same kinds of primitives not
used to proving security and as a result
we kind of had a giant mess on our hands
and secondography is for the most part a
little bit of a joke
um
good so so in order to kind of convince
you that there's actually something
interesting to work on here not just you
know maybe ethically or morally
important um i'll give you a quick
refresher or maybe the first time you've
ever seen a construction of universal
psychography and here's how these
generally work this is a kind of a riff
on uh nick hopper's work from 2004.
so the first step if you want to use
universal seconography is that you pick
the cover text channel the communication
channel that you would like to to kind
of blend in with um for example you
might choose bible verses if this is
considered innocuous by a sensor or
maybe you want something that's a little
bit more politically uh in vogue right
now and you want to send pro putin
posters back and forth a sensor surely
would not block some kind of these kind
of messages
these are a little bit hard to work with
in slides and so instead i'm just going
to use emoji and just pretend the
communication channel that we're looking
for is a uniform distribution over all
the emoji
right so now that we've picked our
communication channel what do we do we
start to encode our message
um so we're going to take our our plain
text we're going to represent it as bits
um and then we're going to encrypt it
using a pseudorandom cipher
the result here's right we get each bit
is you know probability one half one or
zero and now we use a rejection sampling
technique to basically pick out an
appropriate emoji that encodes each bit
of the cipher text right so i'm going to
sample this dragon i hash my dragon i
mean this hash function is going to have
a very special property it's going to be
what's called a perfectly unbiased hash
function which means that it maps
exactly half of the emoji to zero and
half of the emoji to one right so i've
hash my dragon i find that the output is
one great um and now i compare it to the
first bit of my ciphertext and i say yes
one does in fact equal one so this
dragon effectively encodes the first bit
of my ciphertext and i can add it to the
cover text
right now i'm ready to move on to the
second bit of my cipher text i'm going
to just do is more sampling right so i
sample something new here i've got my
avocado i hash my avocado and i got a
zero right but i look at my message i
say well zero does not equal one so i'm
going to do the rejection part of
rejection sampling throughout this
avocado and just try again right until i
get an exploding hand emoji that encodes
this correctly and i just keep on doing
this until i've encoded the entire uh
message right and it should be
relatively clear why there's a kind of a
exact same distributional match between
the cover text and the emojis right each
uh each bit was random zero one and then
all i did was i sampled something from
that random subset of the space right so
the distribution here is exactly the
same
how do you decode well in order to
decode we kind of leverage the fact that
this hash function is public information
right so the receiver can just hash each
emoji get out the ciphertext and decrypt
whereas the sensor could hash all these
down but they'll just get you know
random ones and zeros that they don't
know what to do with
good
so it seems like you know we have this
beautiful construction um it works for
any distribution you should be able to
use it for whatever you want but then
when you try to use it for natural
language like uh encrypt steganography
things start to be a little bit strange
right so the first thing that we should
do is replace this distribution with
something like natural human language
right and then once we kind of do this
we should immediately get cover texts
that are this kind of natural language
thing um turns out when you try to do
this things break um and i'll give you
kind of some some ideas that we recently
kind of unpacked and worked through on a
ccs paper this past year
in particular we looked at two major
barriers to deploying a steganography in
practice the first is the existence of
appropriate samples for natural language
type distributions and the second is
that a lot of these theoretical
constructions from the literature have
minimum entropy requirements that just
simply don't match how humans
communicate we just don't have that much
entropy in the way we speak or the way
we write
and so we set out trying to overcome and
actually design a steganographic system
that kind of addresses each of these at
the same time um and the first step was
looking at this appropriate sampler
problem so how do you sample from
natural human communication well it's a
little bit weird because natural human
communication is not like a well-defined
distribution that it continually updates
over time you couldn't even write it
down if you wanted to and so in some
sense the best thing that you can
possibly do is approximate that
distribution and so we just found the
best approximation tool that we have
right now the best approximation tool
that we have are these generative models
right these are machine learning
techniques that what you do is you feed
them in some kind of context and they'll
spit out an explicit probability
distribution over the next token or word
or whatever it is that follows that
context right this is a reasonably
efficient way uh to sample from natural
human language given that there's some
approximation error here that's just
introduced by the model itself right so
when we start to use these things as
steganographic samplers what we get is
provable security of our cover text with
respect to the output of a model but
then we get some kind of error between
the model output and real natural human
communication but the nice thing is that
you know this is the best we really can
do as our approximations get better and
better and better we can naturally get
better and better steganography
good so we've replaced our sampler right
we're now in much better shape
it turns out if you try to implement
this system as we did you get a 100
failure rate um so we clearly haven't
solved everything yet and the source of
this problem is actually this perfectly
unbiased hash function this goes to the
entropy in the system right natural
human communication has moments where
it's not possible to build unbiased hash
functions so i'll give you an example
right uh for context here we have the
largest carnivore of the cretaceous
period was the tyrannosaurus so at least
native english speakers will
automatically auto finish this in their
mind to say rex right and a generative
model is approximating in this case
english language communication and so it
should output some distribution which is
heavily heavily weighted towards rex
along with maybe some other dinosaurs
that it learned along the way
right um there just is no perfectly
unbiased hash function over this
distribution right it's going to map 98
percent of the probability distribution
to a zero or to one you can't get
something that's 50 50. right um there
are kind of uh techniques that are
explored in the theoretical literature
to overcome this problem you kind of can
replace these unbiased hash functions
with
cryptographic hash functions um or you
can kind of bootstrap the entire system
to get more and more entropy uh we tried
implementing those as well um turns out
they do work you don't get 100 failure
but it takes about 10 minutes to encode
16 bytes of information um not exactly
the high throughput channel that we're
looking for that would allow people to
actually communicate in these in these
censored regimes
and so what we did is we set out to try
and uh to try and uh design a new
steganographic system that would both be
efficient um and actually you know be
good enough to work
so we moved our construction meteor um
and here's the basic idea behind meteor
and i'll give you a quick idea of how
the construction works as well um so
like the first thing you do is the
encoder feeds in this context into the
model and i'll put some probability
distribution and then instead of doing
this rejection sampling thing what i'm
going to do is we're going to take the
encrypted bits of the message remember
this is a pseudo-random value and just
use it as an actual number to sample
into the distribution directly right so
in this case i've sampled the word the
out of the distribution
right on the receiver side how are they
going to decode well what they can do is
they feed the exact same context into
the model to output you know the same
distribution and now what they're going
to do is kind of use the information
that they received on the wire this word
the to kind of infer something about the
initial the bits that were used to
sample this value right this is the high
level intuition i'll give you an example
of this working in practice
okay so so here's my plain text message
now i'm just represented as bits because
a little bit easier to work with here um
what we're going to do first is encrypt
this message using kind of a one-time
pad we're going to pull it out of a prg
and this construction is going to be
stateful with uh symmetric key so
they're each going to have the same key
and pull data out of their prg so we're
going to xor these things together now
we've got a random value and we're going
to use this random value to sample into
the distribution
right so here's my my context my model i
feed these things into outputs here's
some distribution that you can sample
from
and i've got just a number now as a
random value and this just points
somewhere in the distribution i say ah
yes the thing i'm going to use is this
the i'm going to add that to my cover
text
right now on the receiver side how do
they actually go about decoding anything
right they need to learn something about
the randomness that was used to sample
so what they're going to do is they're
going to kind of look at the
distribution and say okay what's the
lowest bit values that we could have
been used to sample they're on the
highest bit values that could be used as
samples
oh and look they share a prefix right so
we know immediately that the first two
bits of the random value must have been
zero one in order for you actually to
sample the right and then the receiver
can then use the the mask sorry unmask
the randomness to retrieve the message
uh two bits of the message
right this is a very natural approach a
very simple approach and it has actually
relatively uh high uh high performance
um so let's just do this one more time
to make sure you understand so we add
the to our context we generate uh some
new random value at a new distribution
right this points to some other place in
the distribution in this case the word
yucatan we add that to our cover text
and we do the same process right where
we find the lower and upper bit values
that would correspond to this word
yucatan and now we see that they share
only one bit of prefix and receiver will
learn exactly one bit of the random
value and unmask that to
recover the plain text but you might
notice one thing that's really nice
about this if there's very low uh low
entropy in the channel for a moment well
we just don't send any bits right we try
and nothing gets recovered but if those
moments when there's actually very high
entropy we can actually asymptotically
show that we get optimal in an
asymptotic sense performance right so we
can transmit bits proportional to the
entropy in the channel
um so here's my my demo that's working
to get an idea in your brain of how this
could potentially go we instantiated
meteor the exact same protocol i just
showed you before using gpt2 as our
model um and what we did is we fed in
our plain text message right crypto
means cryptography um and now we need to
find some cover text sorry some some
context to feed into the model to make
the message kind of be relevant to
wherever we're trying to hide our
message right so we took something uh
you know just from twitter uh which is a
spicy take but not necessarily one that
anybody's gonna be too worried about or
get flagged for censorship right and so
all we did is we pulled out uh some text
here we fed it into the model and what
happens is that the model immediately
spit out some kind of uh message for us
to then post as a response to this
twitter message right so here's the
output of gpt2 seated on some stuff
about tabasco sauce um i know this
spring that the process has gone fairly
smoothly but i think that hot sauce
space needs to be more transparent less
afraid to be underestimated by
restaurants i'd really i'd rather have
really anything else so you know gpt2
has some hot takes of its own i guess um
and what's nice is that this is not you
look at it and you notice well this
doesn't quite look like natural human
communication but it's actually not that
bad i'm just using gpt2 which is now
kind of three models ago i mean our
modern performance is getting better and
better right so our steganographic kind
of approximation of real communication
is getting better and better
um some things that are nice about
meteor uh you can actually run it and it
runs in in real amounts of time um so
you get uh it takes about 0.1 seconds to
encode an ascii character if you have
access to a gpu you get slowdowns on cpu
um and on mobile because you don't have
access to the gpu to update your model
efficiently um we get provable and
distinguishability from the model output
um and additionally we also have a demo
that's put online so you can go and play
with this and you don't have to worry
about having your own gpu you can just
use google's gpus to play around with
the model
um and just to kind of leave us with
some future work directions i think
there's a lot of interesting things left
to be done in this
stage in a graphic world right meteor is
one particular instantiation one
approach that we took it's not the only
thing that you can do um some some ideas
for things that people could look at in
the future i think would be very
valuable um is just increasing
efficiency um starting to look more
systemsy at these things how do we make
them really performance enough to run on
people's phones on messaging systems um
also we've done all these good things in
end-to-end security like uh forward
secrecy and post-compromise security um
it'd be nice to kind of port those
lessons over to the steganographic space
as well and then finally it'd be nice to
consider actually what real world
deployment would look like there's a lot
to do in this space and i think it's
really exciting
and so with that thank you very much for
your attention there's a link to our
blog and demo if you're interested in
playing with the model
nigel
uh yeah cool talk um
so you the whole thing you have to have
this key key prf thing so both sides
gotta have a key yeah
so how can you stag the key agreement
i'm sorry
how can you do how can you do the key
agreement estate the key agreement yeah
yeah um it's it's a great question we've
looked at doing uh public key versions
as well but that doesn't really solve
the problem because how do you get the
public key um uh you know great future
work we didn't solve that problem
[Music]
yeah i 100 believe this belongs in the
field of cryptography thank you very
much for your really great talk and
really important work
um quick question though um
so one thing that stood out to me during
the talk is this um so you're you're
really working very hard to make these
uh cover text look like natural language
i mean do we have to work that hard so i
mean
it's so i mean one advantage that now
normal citizens have is that there's a
lot of us
so
there's a big haystack and if you're
forcing them to the sensor to look for a
a needle
um
yeah what am i trying to say i think you
understand yeah i do yeah no it's a
great question right um we're clearly
shooting for a higher level of security
than might be strictly necessary i will
say though that um generally when you
want to deploy secondography it's
because of the high-risk environment and
being detected even if it's unlikely
could have very serious ramifications on
the person communicating right so we do
want to shoot for something pretty good
um although there's probably space to
explore again with relaxations as well a
good target might just be like http how
do you make http look plain text eight
how do you make https look like plain
text http enough to force them to do
machine learning and fail with high
probability yeah great question um uh
you should look at the paper we actually
tried this uh turns out there's not much
entropy in http either um so you don't
get great performance but you can
absolutely kind of the model can do
whatever you want we kind of actually
treat it as a generic machine learning
model just easier to visualize with
natural human communication thank you
very much yeah
hi thank you for the talk uh two
questions uh of course i suspect that
this is in a model as you said where
like uh so the randomness is banned and
so you have a sort of like willing to be
active adversary that could stop your
communication
how resilient is this to an adversary
that looks at plain text communication
does their own classification and
changes uh one word out of uh 20 or 30
so that it still kind of makes sense but
it's not quite correct yeah absolutely
so our construction is cpa-like um and
therefore very very vulnerable to
malleability attacks um
again great space for future work uh
there's lots to do here and on the other
hand uh did you look at the possibility
of introducing typos to like generate
more randomness having more options uh
like imagine you're generating
uh human language that is like correctly
written but people don't so i wonder if
that's also a source of
potential running yeah there has been
some work um in the machine learning
literature um or natural language or nlp
type literature looking at these kind of
like injecting errors into communication
as a way to get bits through um
again they don't do a great job proving
anything and so it's a little hard to
analyze whether or not it's good enough
or not um one thing you could have a
model that kind of makes normal errors
and a way that's actually kind of very
similar to us um and that's kind of
generic in whatever model that you use
thank you yeah i'm afraid we have to
move on to the next talk but uh please
ask these questions on zulu because
there's lots of interesting discussion
to be had
thanks everybody
thank you
our next speaker is ayel ronan who will
be talking about password authenticated
key exchange
okay thank you and this is a joint work
together with the cascamas money no and
shakho pass and i'm really honored to
give this talk it's been a while since
anyone considered me useful
and
before we start and again you can see
password-based key exchange we need to
get one thing out of the way and this is
why in 2022 i'm still
talking to you about passwords and i
just want to clarify that we are not
some kind of password fanatics we are
not poor passwords we dislike password
as much as as you guys
but
unfortunately for us
passwords are here and
although it's been declared multiple
times in the past passwords are not dead
they are still probably the most
ubiquitous form of authentication and
they are used in the internet and
websites iot devices wi-fi is based upon
it tls 1.3 just completed a process of
choosing and a protocol to incorporate
passwords inside tls so it seems that we
are going to get stuck with them for a
while and now we need to understand what
is the best way to get stuck with them
okay and so there are a lot of different
use cases for how to use password we use
them to authenticate and website
assuming that we have already have a
secure channel like tls and we can use
them to actually create a secure
challenge the
secure channel and this is what password
authenticated key exchanges are for and
we have the symmetric one-to-one setting
and we also have the asymmetric clients
to server setting
however we need to ask ourselves what
happens in the many-to-many settings
and is it just possible to use multiple
one-to-one protocols or do we need
something else
so i want to start with
a typical use case which might be the
smart home network so let's assume that
we have a house
we have a computer the computer is fully
patched linux machine and the cpu has
the latest microcode updates to mitigate
all of the speculative type execu
execution attacks and all of the crypto
here is constant time so all of these
such an attackers have nowhere and
no chance in actually taking this this
is a completely fetched and completely
secure machine
if one exists
also um we have
this smart lock and this is
this smart talk is able to open the
front door which we might might want to
do sometimes and sometimes we might not
want to open it and this opens and
closes on a command from the network
we also had this thermostat
this thermostat was bricked by the
vendor because they don't provide any
more firmware updates and we need to
discard it with all of the credentials
still
in persistent memory we don't have
anywhere to address it
we also have this old tablet
this is android 8. it doesn't have any
security patch for the last two years
and it's support member of at least
eight major different botnets
um
we also have
the router and this route is going to be
replaced next month because i'm
very unhappy with my internet provider
and i'm going to try another one to be
unhappy with so they're going to get my
credentials
and
i also have multiple
visiting smartphones maybe you have more
friends than i so you love them i don't
have much smartphones in my house but um
as you see there are a lot of different
devices that have those um credentials
and we only need
one device to hold them all because at
least at wi-fi
the standard actually mandates the
devices to store the password and store
it in clear text on the device so if any
one of them gets compromised this entire
network gets compromised
and
let's assume that we don't want it to
get compromised so what can we do
and there are many challenges when we
try to make this type of many-to-many um
setting actually work
and we have one password and we have
many user devices
so we want to be able to have source
authentication want to be able to
understand if the specific message was
sent by the router or by the smartphone
or by
the thermostat which shouldn't be able
to open the door
we also want to be able to revoke
specific devices
for example if we discard this
thermostat we don't want him to be able
to connect to the network anymore
and
the main challenge is that we have a
very dynamic network topology
and people that are into smart houses
might go out to the supermarket and buy
a smart light bulb i'm not sure why they
do it but they actually do it sometimes
and now we need to wait to bootstrap and
make this light bulb join this network
and then communicate with other devices
moreover we need to support the
replacement of existing hardware so for
example we could envision a
world where we have this
magical protocol that allows us to
determine long-term
high entropy keys with the
access point or the router but then what
happens if we replace this router do we
need to go and re-authenticate all of
the devices in our home and people that
have smart homes apparently don't like
to re-authenticate their devices so you
want to be some a solution that is very
usable
and uh we want to be able to support
this asynchronous and offline password
input that is not dependent on anything
else so um we don't want to actually
have any communication rounds when we
enter the password we don't want to
assume that the router is currently
online or offline we can't really assume
any shared randomness because we don't
have any good way to communicate or
agree upon it and we can't really assume
a trusted third party or pki
and the let's decrypt just receive the
leveling price to try to scale up the
pki infrastructure to support a lot of
websites i feel that they will return
this prize if someone asked them to also
provide this for every home network so
we want to let them continue do their
important work without disturbing them
okay
so what are the current tools that we
that we have that we can use to solve
this type of problems
and um the main tools that we talk about
when creating uh secure channels with
passwords are password and dedicated key
exchange now they've been uh
about for a really long time we're
talking about 30 years
and um in this way
we have two parties that if they share
the same password they can
automatically create a secure channel
now the model of peak
assumes
that passwords are never stored each
protocol run you're going to reinput the
passwords to those devices
now i can ask
how many of you like to show reserve
hands re-enter their wi-fi passwords
each time they go back to the house
nobody has their answers okay
so it may be in reality
devices do store those devices so we
don't have long term storage of
passwords and they are usually in clear
text we don't have any real way to
protect this
storage
um we do have some more advanced
solution for the asymmetric setting if
we assume that we have
different roles we have one client and
one server then we can try to protect
the long-term password storage inside
the server
and we
and this is much better than regular
packs however clients still don't have
this protection so we need to assume
that the client doesn't store his
password but re-enter it each time which
might be
logical for some settings i i personally
haven't found them yet but um probably
not for many use cases
that we have and this is not portable to
the many to many settings
and recently uh there's been an invest
this is nice 1993 then we had to wait a
little bit and then 2018 we have a new
notion of strong augmented packs which
improves the protection against
pre-computation attack when i compromise
the server i can still try to brute
force guess the password out of the
dictionary and
in essay pack i can't do any computation
until i actually compromise this server
which is a very nice property
we can this allows us to actually use
salt efficiently when
calculating a one-way function of their
hash and this is what we
view as common
good comment practice
okay
there are some problems with it as i
mentioned
and
still one of the sides needs to store
the passwords in the clear and we we
don't want it in many too many settings
and um this is no real easy way to um
to extend it to
the
manufacturing setting
okay
so now we propose to
have some snacks
and what we want to propose here is that
we have all of this
um old really cool notions about how to
use passwords but we want to provide
some new ones and this is
basically identity based
peaks and here we can extend the
protection of the password storage to
all parties involved and we can actually
and we can also bind the password
storage to
some some tag to some party and then if
for example party one here gets
compromised this does not allow the
attacker to impersonate any other party
in the network only the the compromised
party
and we have a protocol named chip that
actually instantiates this notion
and
we have the stronger notion which is the
strong
identity based peak which corresponds to
the strong augmented pack which also
provides a stronger precomputation
resilience
okay so how can we realize this
we do this by using techniques from
identity based kick change and
agreements protocols
but we only use those underlying ideas
we don't actually need a trusted um key
generation center or any any other
trusted third party what we do is we use
the password as the secret seed and we
emulate the
all of the
process done by the
the key center on the device
then we derive a password storage and we
delete the password
um we don't actually need to have
unique or especially encoded identities
and we can
use some abstract tags
for the password storage to bind into
and we can choose them as some
identities would be al's laptop we can
also use roles so for example we can um
recreate augmented pack by using um the
one wall of a server and another as a
client while still giving the client the
same protection that we can't do today
with regular augmented pegs
and we can also use unique identifiers
like mac addresses but this is um
completely abstract and we can use
whatever we want
and we can also have multiple devices
that share the same tag if we have some
low permission devices in our network
for example the guest smartphones we can
have all of them share the same tag it
doesn't affect the security of the other
parties
and to give you a little bit of
intuition of how we can do it
i will try to explain and probably fail
the basic ideas behind the crisp
and
the way to do it we have two different
parts we have what you call the password
file generation where each party can can
generate its own
unique
random seed and it's going to store some
commitment for the for the seed and
we're going to use a hash to curve
on the password
again using the same seed to blend it
and we're going to store some commitment
um for the actual identity
and in the key
negotiation part in the protocol we're
going to um use the specific eclipse is
based on the linear pairing and we're
going to um use the commitment that we
have in order to have such an extended
development protocol and
basically
both sides are going to negotiate
a secret input that they both shall they
are it incorporates both the password
and the two sorts and then we're going
to feed these two to a regular protocol
in order to create a key that we can
actually use for the secure channel
and
on the second part we're going to use
the commitment that we made to the
identity to prove to the other side that
we uh that we are who we claim we are
and we are not impersonating anyone else
again this is the stronger variant that
is based on but in a pairing we have
also the the um less than variant that
is only based on
regular
development
and we did not just um go to the process
of invading the notions and the protocol
and writing all of this very cool and
fun to
handle and uc proofs we try to actually
implement this protocol and we try to
benchmark it compare it to current
solutions
and um on the
left side we have a sea pace which is a
very efficient regular uh bake and this
is the base we also base our protocol
on on this epic and afterwards we have
sae simultaneous authentication of
equals this is the current uh tech
protocol using the latest wi-fi standard
of wp-3
and you see it's much less efficient and
it currently has no real security motion
because it was never proven to be secure
and on that end we have a cheap protocol
that allowed that gives much better
security guarantees and it's a little
bit um
slower than cpas but um comparable to
opec that was currently standardized for
tls 1.3 and again
can protect all parties and we have the
crisp protocol which is currently a
little bit slower but not much and we
feel that still the overall overhead is
very low and it's is suitable for iot
device and wi-fi networks is it
comparable with the current wi-fi
protocol and we also have several
suggestions to how to optimize the his
protocol to make it run a little bit
faster and and we have the code
available in github if anyone wants to
try to play around with it
so to conclude
we
present cheap eclipse and we provide
stronger security guarantees for the
store password storage for all parties
and
involved and it works in a symmetric
fully mesh setting
and we are looking to
make ourselves useful so we would like
to have it standardized on the personal
if you're interested
please come and talk to us and you can
see all of the gory details and the uc
proofs in the
online
version of the paper and the code is
also available
thank you very much and i will be happy
to answer any questions
thank you very much are there any
questions
thank you for the very nice talk can you
explain a little bit what's going on
generically in that first part of your
protocol so i see there's a pick in the
second part but what's what's that first
part really you presented it as like
some id based thing
what's really going on there so
basically we want to compute some
one-way function of the password and
incorporate the
um
the identity with it but the problem is
that we want to we need to have it to
add some kind of salt because otherwise
it's trivial to
create a dictionary but we can't
share the salt we can't agree upon it
with other parties so all of this
process that we do around it is a way to
calculate this one-way function in which
it has some structure so when i will
send you
my salt or some commitment to it you can
also calculate the same
output
so is it not an attractive key exchange
um yeah basically it's uh it's partly
non-literate yeah
okay basically it's based on this
hello thank you for the talk maybe a
follow-up question to canis so if i
understand correctly you use
the password to create a commitment to a
certain identity and then you use this
commitment to
run a password authenticated key
exchange
right
but
one of the things you you promised is
that if i upgrade my router
then
i don't have to set up all my devices
again against this new router and how
would this work in in
your setting
okay so the main thing here is that
after you input your password the device
forgets about it the password is them is
the master key so if you replace your
your um your router
the router only stores the um the
one-way function of the of the password
with the um for example it's all all the
mac address you can revoke it now you
just re-input the password to the new
router and you can derive the same the
same secrets using using a new identity
and then everything can
work the same way as if you just replace
the router when it has a new mac address
but
would this mean that any device that
i authenticate could impersonate the
router
if um it depends if you assume that the
device is
honest and the second that you input the
password or if it was compromised if it
was compromised before you input the
password when the password is leaked
then everything is lost if it was
compromised after you input the password
then um then it it can't
change its identity anymore because it
binds it to him
it cannot change its identity but how uh
okay
right thank you thank you very much
so it looks like in your slide that this
is sort of a generic transformation you
do a head of a pig
i'm wondering you know what the secret
that you're feeding in seems to be much
more random than the usual password and
it also seems like for some page there
might be ways to com to do some of the
paperwork
up ahead of that box to save on rounds
i'm curious if you've investigated that
or if there are barriers
yeah so we we looked at it and
there are some subtle attacks if you
want to provide perfect for the secrecy
which usually requires something along
the tech we can run the peak um
in parallel which it changed the proofs
but
basically we wanted to have
something that is
easy
as possible to understand and easy as
possible to actually prove and when you
do uc proofs it's much easier to have
something that was already proven to to
some of this
to fulfill some of these requirements
but i feel that this is a really good
future work
thank you there's one question in the
zulu so please take a look at that as
well after uh after the session so
please thank our speaker and both
speakers in this session
okay and stay where you are we'll be
moving right into our next session with
an invited talk
[Music]
good morning and welcome to the next
session
cryptography in the ads ecosystem and we
have an invited talk
entitled building the next generation of
digital advertising with npc by james
rice
hello
i'm james reyes
i'm the tech lead of private computation
at meta
today i'm going to talk about uh private
computation
which is our effort to build the next
generation of digital advertising with
mpc
today's talk is going to focus on real
world product and engineering challenges
that we faced when trying to bring this
to market and to scale
as a caveat this will be a very product
and engineering focused talk
i'm not a cryptographer
i hope this is helpful to understand how
to productionize cryptographic protocols
as well as in advancing state-of-the-art
and bringing mpc to scale
so i'm going to start with a little bit
of background on what private
computation is
and then i'll move into the product
challenges we've faced when we have
tried to bring it to the advertising
market
i'll move into the engineering
challenges that we faced when dealing
with the scale that meta operates at
and then i'll close with some resources
on how to learn more as well as
cryptography at meta
all right so what is private computation
in december 2019
six months after the announcement of uh
that browsers were deprecating cookies
which are the foundation of the digital
ads industry
much of the ads industry still hadn't
internalized
and noticed that this represented a
larger shift
in users expectations
and the industry
those that did noticed that uh
we're concerned that this would
completely upend their business models
there were a lot of proposals at the
time
many were from the perspective of uh how
do we roll things back
and then there were others were
much more privacy focused
but they didn't practically work well
for ads use cases
our approach was to try to deeply listen
to the concerns of the industry and
regulators and understand the trend
we asked what would an ad stack look
like in five to ten years and let's
start building towards that now
so private computation started as a
partnership between our research and
engineering teams
we started a small team and set out to
see whether or not a semi-honest
two-party mpc
could scale to meet our ads use cases we
felt that
this technology had the shortest time to
market of the privacy tech that we
evaluated
other technologies that we evaluated
were trusted execution environments and
hope norfolk encryption
a key decision we made was to focus on
ads measurement
measurement is about helping advertisers
understand how their ads are performing
at meta we know that measurement is
foundational to any ads business
everything that comes afterwards
requires accurate measurement to work
so that was two years ago
in august meta announced that uh the
future of ads at meta were private
privacy enhancing technologies
and secure mpc and private computation
were a key part of that
we've grown to across the system team of
over 70 engineers and cryptographers and
we're still rapidly growing
we have two mpc products that
advertisers are actively using
private lift
which helps advertisers run randomized
controlled trials to get an incremental
impact uh to understand the incremental
impact of the facebook ads that they're
running
and private attribution which delivers
faster results but utilizes heuristics
everything that we've done is open
source you can see it on facebook's
research github and i'll share some
links specifically to it later in the
presentation
okay so let's talk a little bit about
what we've learned as we've tried to
bring this privacy focused product to
the advertising market
so we went to beta with private lift
in july 2021 and as a reminder lyft is
about running randomized controlled
trials
we targeted a 175 sophisticated lift
advertisers sophisticated lift
advertisers
because lift advertisers tend to be some
of our most sophisticated clients
they understand the importance of
privacy and can also take on the
additional constraints that it
introduces
lips is also a great stepping stone to
other measurement tools
advertisers tend to use
lift to calibrate the rest of their
measurement tools
so we interviewed our early adopters to
understand more about their journey
towards more private computation
our first learning was that
there is in fact interest
i see this as the inevitable feature of
all of our ad platforms
advertisers understand the value of
privacy and they see private computation
as fulfilling that
they expect the entire digital
advertising to move in this direction
over the next one to five years
so advertisers get it
that said
adoption took a lot longer than what we
expected
advertiser's primary objective is on
driving sales and measuring performance
they compare private computation to
existing systems that don't require npc
and thus don't have its additional
constraints
a few things that they noticed that
would increase the urgency were
regulations forcing them to adopt new
practices
other advertisers doing it they tend to
move as an industry
and more features and more accuracy that
would be provided by private computation
this hasn't deterred us the interest is
clearly there
it just means it'll be a longer journey
than what we were hoping
so our third learning is that more
education around npc is needed just all
around
this is the first time that the
advertising industry is seeing npc
they don't know how to reason about it
from a product or privacy perspective
we interacted with business folks legal
marketing sales engineers and even
security professionals who had never
heard of npc
this was true both on the advertiser
side and on the meta side
as an example on the security side we
have a very tailored setup for
networking between npc nodes
but this is different than typical open
internet tls communication and so it
required a lot of scrutiny from the
advertisers that we interacted with
after our first two advertisers we
invested significantly in education
simplification automation validation and
ease of use
okay so
those that's what we've learned on the
product side let's talk about some of
the engineering challenges uh that we
face when trying to operate npc at scale
before we dive into that i want to spend
another uh 30 seconds on lyft uh
so lyft is a really important
advertising product
uh
so
lyft is about running a randomized
control trial to help advertisers
understand the causal impact of their of
their advertising on facebook
what you're producing is an aggregate
statistic at the end so
if you take a look at the diagram uh you
start by meta starts by splitting the
population
of the uh the relevant population into a
test and a control group
uh the advertiser is providing the
relevant sales
and then and then you're producing a
mapping of a test and control group to
the amount of sales within each group
and when you have that you can
you can do statistical analysis on it
like performing a t-test and that gives
you a causal impact of the ad that
you're trying to run
so how we do this in private computation
uh the first step
is private record linkage
so you perform private record linkage on
advertiser and meta records this gives
you a list of private attributed records
called the spine which we use downstream
to simplify the calculation this is a
variant of private set intersection
neither party learns anything about the
other's information or records during
this step
second you apply a function in npc
called an attribution rule
you do this on the private records you
just generated to produce private
attributed records
the main attribution rule uh as an
example is called is a time comparison
so you just want to ensure that
you're only measuring the sales that
occurred after an ad was showing was
shown
finally you aggregate those private
attributed records
and anonymize the results
so for instance you might use some kind
of k9 amenity threshold or differential
privacy and again we use mpc mpc in this
step
uh this is all open source um if you're
interested um
i'll have the links at the end of the uh
presentation but you can see it in the
bottom left of the screen just a little
tiny um
and
fb.me pcs
so private record linkage is uh highly
complex
the most complex problem to solve is
that you often have multiple records
that map to the same unit
so as an example you might have like
multiple records that map to the same
person
on the right hand side is the protocol
that we've built to solve for this it's
open source we have a paper out about it
you can visit the link in the bottom
left of the screen to
see more about it
so
uh you have a mini to mini mapping in
this scenario uh because you have
multiple records that map to the same
unit or you know the same record mapping
to multiple units and you have to find a
way to pick a mapping
you have a number of different ways to
do this
you could use waterfall logic to
prioritize certain records certain types
of records over others or you could use
an algorithm that offers partial or
split credit amongst the different
records
any algorithm that you develop has to
support sharding
meta's scale requires that at no point
in your algorithm can you have
everything on one machine it just it
won't fit
for a single record uh private record
linkage this is simple you just use the
same sharding or hashing algorithm on
either side and then you just make sure
that uh
that's everything maps to the same shard
but for multiple records you have a
different definition of what a match
means and so
you can't assume that they're all on the
same shard and you have to set up
cross-chart communication and this can
be complex and slow
uh the different use cases that we have
to support in ads means that you end up
with a proliferation of custom protocols
to fit each different use case
this this doesn't scale
the development of each of these can
take up to a year that cryptography is
complex the debugging is hard and you're
dealing with really sensitive data so
you have to be really careful
uh as a result we're developing a new
generic record linkage framework that
can be extended and reuse components
across the different use cases
last but definitely not least the
quality of the records can vary wildly
depending on the advertiser
the
information on either side is changing
rapidly you can't just compute it once a
month you have to do it every
computation
all right so at scale you also have to
deal with supporting large computations
so
we decided to start with our largest
possible advertiser to prove that we
could scale and run npc uh to meet its
needs this advertiser
ran at 1000x of scale of our next set of
advertisers so we felt we could meet its
needs then we could meet any other
advertisers needs
we needed to prove that npc could be
fast uh fast enough cheap enough and
operate on large enough amounts of data
our initial target was one billion rows
in two hours or one one thousandth the
cost relative to the cost of the
campaign they're trying to measure
so as an example if an advertiser is
spending a thousand dollars on an
advertising campaign the communication
or the computation should cost no more
than one dollar
it's worth mentioning that this type of
computation is happening uh many times
per week uh you know often times up to
like once or more per day
so this was our target uh 1.5 years ago
and we're pretty proud of this
accomplishment
so how do we support that many rows that
quickly
the first decision we made was to
support uh was to use emp toolkit for
our mpc engine
we felt it had a emp toolkit is an open
source gobbled circuits npc engine and
we we found that it had good trade-offs
in terms of memory usage performance and
cost
many of the other npc engines we tried
were actually implicitly limited to
hundreds of thousands of rows by
internal engine limitations
we released a paper with our findings on
this last year
so measurement is easily chartable
it's conceptually similar to a mapreduce
so uh but you need to do so in a
privacy-safe way
so the diagram on the the diagram on the
left shows how we do that
we built a technique called private
scaling which outputs secret shares that
are rejoined in npc by a shard
aggregator
you can see it on github by following
the link on the bottom left of the
screen
okay so how do you make it cheap enough
although there is often much talk of the
cost of mpc especially general purpose
mpc
uh private computation today costs
significantly less than the budget
advertisers typically allocate towards
doing their measurement
typically the cost per run for
attribution is about the cost of
attending a movie
we measure by normalizing the cost
the cost and performance in terms of a
million input rows and then the cost
literally scales from that
for attribution advertisers tend to look
at results daily and then for lift is
typically at least once a month
some advertisers have many more input
rows and the costs can uh can go up
significantly by 10 to 20x but these
advertisers are also correspondingly
much bigger and so they have much bigger
budgets in all cases we're well within
the budget
there is a clear trade-off though in
terms of adding features and cost
our lift gain is much more full feature
than attribution and as a result it's
five times more expensive
this is despite the fact that our
algorithm is simpler lyft is actually
just a special simpler case of
attribution
but it supports a lot more product
features
this highlights the underlying problem
that every feature you add results in a
large increase in cost and wall time
you might ask why is this a problem why
do we have so many features but in a
mature measurement product there are
many valid different use cases you need
to support
as an example you might want to
support histogram outputs for each of
your test control groups not just total
amounts um
so
you might want to also run attribution
for each of these test and control
groups so you can compare that to your
to your heuristics that you're using
you might want to run like multiple
different uh study types within the uh
the test in the control group break down
by different objects that are within
each um
within each ad you might
want to break a breakdown by country you
might want to add custom breakdowns
depending on what the advertiser
situation is um then you might decide
you want to do ml training to predict
the whole thing so you have to add
features for that
this can get out of hand um it's it's
pretty common that you end up with
thousands of columns per row
these also change rapidly
uh you're you're dealing with companies
on either side that are the size of
cities
you uh so you you uh you have developers
that are they're not cryptographers
that's uh uh
that that have features that they want
to that they want to support
attribution has also has many variants
and features
we expect as we add them the cost and
the performance of that will also go up
so how do we address that
our plan is private computation
framework
private computation framework is our
general purpose npc engine
version two switches over from an emp
toolkit based backend to a meta built
backend
this new npc engine is fast
some key features it uh it's we're
switching from global circuits to secret
sharing protocol and has a standard
library of features that we can use that
the developer can use to improve
performance such as oram
as it results in a 100x reduction in
network usage a forex increase in
performance
now there's a 30x reduction in cost as
compared to emp
it's fully open source today
if you go to the bottom left of this
link at the bottom left of the screen
you can see it
we're working on a white paper and it'll
be production ready uh by the end of the
staff
a few key design principles we took when
we built this
the first was a protocol independent
front end
this allows non-cryptographers to
iterate rapidly and add and remove
product features as they wish without
redesigning the underlying protocol
it allows us also to make back-end
optimizations without affecting the
front end
and allows us to add in new protocols
later for different for different use
cases
we focus a lot on developer ease of use
as well so developing npc applications
is hard
a lot of times when you're debugging
you
by design you can't see any of the
intermediate data
and so in pcf 2.0
you can develop in clear text and then
with a simple configuration change
change to a secure back end
so at scale you also have to support
a ton of advertisers
has over 10 million advertisers and
there's a wide variety inside of that
we support huge corporations that have
teams of marketers data scientists and
engineers
but there's also a long tail of small
single person businesses that are
non-technical
you can't expect those businesses to
deploy npc
the way we think about this is delegated
versus direct integrations and this is
just about who's deploying npc so a
great example of delegated is priya
which we've talked a bunch about at the
conference
our focus right now is direct
with a plan to simplify over time
the number of direct advertisers is
small but if you look at the overall ad
market by spend
it represents the bulk of it
even for direct advertisers deploying
npc is too difficult
on average it takes three months from
beginning to end
our target by the end of the end of the
year is 24 hours
this is the biggest risk for mpc in our
mind can we actually make it easy enough
to use they're comparing to existing
systems that are
dead simple to set up
we've made lots of improvements uh we've
improved from six months to three a lot
of this has been education and process
and some of the things i mentioned
before
we shipped a one-click ui last week
which we hope will
lead to significant improvements in
onboarding speed as well
let's spend a minute talking about the
what the advertisers are actually
deploying so we can understand why it's
difficult to deploy
the diagram on the right shows a high
level architecture for private
computation
you'll notice that it's symmetric meta
and the advertiser are running the same
code base top to bottom
this is helpful for trust which is
critical both for measurement and for
privacy
this is all open sourced and it's called
the private computation platform
the link is in the bottom left of the
screen and i'll share it again at the
end
private communication is serverless
measurement computation is fundamentally
bursting you need to do some calculation
at some interval and then when you're
done you don't need to do anything else
support this
our computations are serverless so
example as an example on aws we deploy
docker containers on fargate
we tend to spend up a few hundred of
these per computation
uh
a big component of our architecture is
the simplified deployment so advertisers
as i've mentioned struggle to get
everything set up but also to maintain
it
we use terraform
docker and we have an infrastructure
management service that now provides
that one click deployment as well as
other simplified deployment tools
uh we also have a big data management
component so advertisers really struggle
to get their data in in the right format
encrypted with the right rotating key
hashed just the right way
advertisers also struggle to collect the
relevant data some are much better at
this than others we've had so many
advertisers who go through the whole
process of setting everything up only to
run their first computation and to
realize that they input the wrong data
into the computation
this is really hard to debug because by
design we can't see anything on the
advertiser side
so we've tried really hard to make this
simple and automated with lots of
validation and tooling along the way
although our focus right now is on
direct integrations here are some ideas
we've we're exploring for delegated
integrations
so we're excited about the idea of an
mpc consortium
centralized services are great for
accessibility
you just throw your data to it and you
get your results but of course with a
classical central service you don't
preserve the privacy of the data when
you do that
we think a consortium of uh
consortium running mpc could thread the
needle uh on and provide sufficient
guarantees on privacy while
also improving accessibility
we'll also be excited about the idea of
what we call partner integrations
advertisers are already delegating their
commerce and measurement needs to
third-party services
they tend to trust these services so as
an example if you're running a
storefront you might use shopify
or exploring systems that allow
advertisers to continue to leverage
those existing integrations and just add
npc on top
we're excited about the idea of managed
npc as well
so the idea here is to uh to separate
the the infrastructure deployment from
uh the data security
uh there's difficult privacy and
security trade-offs in each of these but
we're excited for the promise
all right so
these are the links um i hope you can
see them now um
all right
so it's all open source
the first the first link um private
computation solutions um you can see how
lift and attribution work by following
that link uh the second link private
computation platform uh
fee that means pcp
our new mpc engine you can find that
private computation framework at fe dot
me pcf i mean you can learn more about
how record linkage works
that open source tool called private
identity and is at fb that me slash pid
um i'm not going to go over each of the
areas that we work
on privacy tech at meta as you can see
there's a wide diversity of them
and we're hiring for a variety of open
positions on any of these teams so if
you're interested feel free to reach out
and a quick plug
we have a rfp out right now so
we're eager to continue our
collaboration with faculty and academia
we recently published details about this
rfp we're awarding 10 research grants
for proposals in the privacy enhancing
tech space
for more info go to
research.fb.com the deadline for
submissions is april 20th
uh if you want to learn more about
private computation um you know i'm here
so you can ask me questions or uh you
can contact me at jlreyes fb.com
uh sanjay couldn't be here today
but if you want to learn more about
cryptography at meta in general
then
sanjay fb.com
okay
any questions
thank you for a great talk nigel you're
first
it's really amazing really really cool
great to see this deployed um so just to
understand the security npc's about um
separation yeah so you're separating
between the advertiser and you yeah
that's correct and so the first thing is
you had as you had double circuits
because that's a two-party thing how are
you doing the secret sharing with just
two parties
how are we in the secret sharing sorry i
didn't hear that so you said you've
moved to a secret sharing based engine
yeah but with two parties how are you
kind of doing that how are you
yeah so so we actually have a white
paper that's going to be um out with
this um in like the next uh month or two
um i am not a cryptographer so i can't
get into the details um also i don't
want to
misrepresent anything that's going to be
in the white paper so um
let's chat and i can i can send you a an
email with the um with the white paper
when it's ready cool but well done
really cool thanks
hey thanks for the talk so i have more
of a like a systems question for you i
guess so you explained how one of the
challenges with all this stuff uh nbc
privacy etc is education which is a
consistent with our experience
in particular you mentioned how
like the the engineers that you've been
working with
um
educating them has been a problem so i'm
curious
like what
so i feel like to cryptographers npcs
new exciting et cetera but to like cloud
and distributed systems people they kind
of go like oh it's an external
dependency all right yeah um so what in
particular is like conceptually hard
here for people whose bread and butter
is distributed systems
i think it's it's uh
i mean there's like a product and an
engineering uh perspective on that i
think like uh you know you
you know from from a product perspective
i think uh because you're operating in a
space that has a lot more constraints
because of the computation and like
performance and cost
you um
you have to figure out how to um
introduce those constraints
to the user but from like from a systems
perspective um
uh
i'd say it's um
i'd say it's uh the cost and the
performance um again are are much higher
than like operating in the clear
and so uh
you have to figure out how to um
not run into the the limits um on like
uh the amount of containers that you
allocate on you know
aws and gcp and
so cost and performance is definitely is
definitely a challenge um
uh it's also uh
it's a different paradigm so it's like
uh you can't just take your existing
system and then just like uh expect that
you can
uh use it as is an npc we're actually
rebuilding everything from scratch and
so um uh
they're we're incorporating a lot of
learnings from uh from what we from our
production systems uh into the into this
system um and so there's just a lot of
work to do um i hope that answers your
question yeah it does thanks we have
some fargate war stories too i'll find
you later thank you
hi
so uh the ad ecosystem has issues with
opacity where users don't know why ads
are shown to them or why or where they
cannot see or correct their data
and in this case you mentioned that our
advertisers are already having
difficulty with
correctly implementing what they want to
do with debugging is very difficult so
with mpc how will this affect opacity
and how we prevent discriminatory
targeting
so can you repeat the first part of the
question i i didn't hear that how does
this affect the opacity of the
ecosystem for users
i think i think that's uh
yeah like you know ads and user
perception is as a whole as a whole um
a whole bag of worms but um
mpc
i'd say is uh
is
i'm not really sure that um
uh
like like you're providing better
guarantees to the users but like i i i i
think that you know what we have seen is
that um
uh
it's it's hard enough to explain to
developers um i don't think that you're
going to be able to explain
this very easily right now to
to users and so
um
i don't know if we have an answer uh to
that i think it's it's really it's like
uh we got to start somewhere um and i
think it's you know developers uh the
industry regulators um
and it's also not like
it's not it's not like there are so many
uh you're predicting what the world's
gonna look like in five to ten years so
um i think it's uh uh there are
different competing visions for that and
so um uh it's not a very clear answer um
but uh short period is we don't know is
it something meta is paying attention to
definitely paying attention to not
private computation uh specifically
with the combination with npc like is
there any part of your research group
that looks at that at all uh
at meta there's there's definitely uh uh
teams that do that um uh we're focused
more on like the distributed systems and
like you know a protocol side of things
um but i can definitely um uh connect
you with uh uh with folks who are
working on that i just like don't
personally have their names um
yeah thank you yeah
one whole short question i hope
yeah it's short
um so i'm very happy to see that peta is
working on privacy enhancing tech so i
just wanted to ask if you are
considering any uh
methods to transform transfer ads to the
client in an oblivious way such that
meta would not be able to know
what
if a client got an ad or not like
oblivious transfer or something of that
sort
uh
like transferring to like the to the
like the client like the device yes yeah
um so
uh one of the things that we that was on
the slide of uh uh uh areas that meta
was um uh federated uh learning in like
federated analytics and so that's so so
it's not uh i don't know if it's exactly
what you just described but i think it's
um
uh we did with the same blog post that
talks about um uh mpc being you know the
feature of
of ads at um meta it also talks about on
uh work as well so so yes there is there
is on device work as well and that's
kind of the competing visions for the
future that i alluded to in the last
question all right thanks yeah okay
thank you very much running out of time
so there is also a question in zulu but
i guess we can take that offline in
sulip so thanks again jim for a great
talk please join me in talking again
and i hand over to nigel for the
lightning rounds at lightning speed
nigel arrives
so queue up
this on this side if you turned up late
because you were too busy having coffee
you didn't hear the announcement you
start this side okay
indeed it's here's someone who didn't
turn up in time for the coffee right so
what we have to do is you will come one
of the time come up the stairs
do your talk do your speech at some
point i'll tell you stop
when i'm bored sorry um something like
that and then go down the back of the
lectern and down there that's safer okay
i don't want anyone tripping off the
stage right that's
health and safety first right so
go
[Music]
thank you
um so if you got inspired by the first
talk on monday first day of the
conference
and you would like to know more about
embedded systems that we have a
conference for you and this conference
is cardis it has reached already its
21st edition
and
you can visit the website it's going to
take place in the uk so we get some
extra points for that
university of vermont
belgium now
and the deadline for submission is going
to be the 24th of june um why else
should people visit the university of
birmingham oh
uh yeah so if you're into lord of the
rings you might recognize some of the
landmarks
like sireman's tower is actually the
clock tour of the local university
um birmingham has a lot of canals so
some call it even the venus of the north
or
maybe the other venice of the north
uh and lastly as yeah like all uk cities
a lot of pubs and beer
but birmingham also has a chocolate
factory that you might visit as a social
event
npk blinders
okay
so yeah come by
thank you
brilliant that was only a minute
[Applause]
hi
you might have heard of this new uh
end-to-end encryption protocol called
messaging lab security or mls for short
it's the spec is in its final phase now
and we are working on an implementation
um so that is uh open source of course
it's mit licensed and it's written in
rust
it's not entirely finished yet because
the spec is still moving a little bit
but it's fairly advanced and it's good
enough
to be used in a proof of concept
and the api is sort of stable there's a
lot of documentation
and
so yeah if you're interested in that at
all if you want to play with mls or if
you want to contribute or anything else
um yeah just come and say hi i'm rafael
there's conrad as well who's in the room
um or otherwise you can just google
openmls that's the name of the
implementation or go to
openmls.tech
thank you
thank you very much
[Music]
and go along
hello everybody it's nice to be back in
person i'm filippo and i do open source
i maintain the go cryptography libraries
i make tools like again make search ubc
agent so open source is special there
are no gatekeepers um and uh there are
no financial there's no financial
inertia to picking up a new project but
it's also unsustainable
this is something that
most people in the room know this is not
news a lot of people who maintain
projects are volunteers or employees of
big companies where the incentives don't
always align
so
this is not old stuff but what's new is
that companies are not getting what they
want either
companies
are talking about supply chain security
and uh and this is
kind of a buzzword is this now my thesis
is that companies would actually pay for
um
pay maintainers and projects if they
were approached like
if they could pay them like they can pay
all other professionals the businesses
are in the business of getting what they
want by paying invoices
uh so
if you are on either side of these uh
transactions if your company wants to
get a better relationship with the open
source maintainers that maintain the
projects you need or if you're a
maintainer who's been struggling to get
companies to care and pay for
them either search professional
maintainers on google or come talk to me
here i also have ag stickers obviously
thank you
thank you very much
and
while the next person is coming up just
like to say if you're out in zoom land
and you feel uh just you know like
disenfranchised and we will be doing
another version of this tomorrow for
those in zoom land so please tune in
tomorrow
um hi everyone i just wanted to take a
minute to make a personal thank you
because i didn't think i'd be able to
attend in person this year because i had
a baby in november
um but real world crypto have been
absolutely phenomenal they've provided
an on-site nanny that they've also paid
for um so i just wanted to give a real
thank you for that
um
yeah my my
my grandmother actually worked in
computing research but she quit that job
because she really wanted children so
i'm just really grateful to everyone
who's made it possible for me to have
more options than that so thanks again
[Applause]
[Music]
all of which that's really cool all of
which has been made
possible by our amazing sponsors
if you are a company in the audience and
felt a very warm glow at that point what
you need to do is email kenny
give us your money
and we'll see uh hope we can do a
similar thing in zurich next year thank
you
tokyo
sorry
okay we're all uh enjoying uh real world
crypto so much you want to know where
your next uh crypto fix will be uh and
uh i'm pleased to announce that uh
eurocrypt 2022 is the next iacr event
will take place in uh trondheim in mid
norway
um yeah
uh
starting on monday the
30th of may i repeat starting on monday
that is to say we have our reception on
monday evening and then we go through to
friday so it's a a day
uh later than the normal europe program
uh it will take place uh in a
purpose-built uh conference hotel uh
overlooking the trondheim fjord
we cannot promise you
sunshine but we can promise you at least
mild weather and lots of light it will
be 19 and a half hours of daylight on
the first day of eurocrypt uh this year
um the
program is up now the uh registration is
up now and uh you should register by
uh 29th of this month in case you want
to avoid extra charges so please get on
to ioci.org navigate to eurocrypt and
register now
and if you've already booked your
flights and you didn't realize it
started on monday evening there are
workshops on the sunday and monday to
turn turn up to very interesting ones
you should go to
hey hello i'm jalan from protocol labs
so maybe you remember in 2019 we
launched d-run so they distributed
random beacons
it's an open source software which is
run by the league of entropy to provide
a network of nodes providing public
verifiable randomness and it's seen
great adoption with at least one user
who's still using it nowadays and it's
pretty cool because it's using
pairing-based crypto and that allows us
to bring in the coming months
time lock encryption to the network so
if you want to encrypt something as a
gift for christmas
you'll be able to do that um around
august hopefully and we are still
looking for new members to join the
league of entropy so if you want to you
know provide a public service with
public verifiable randomness
just you know
say hi and i also got different stickers
thanks very much
i'm good
good morning amsterdam and good middle
of the night for some of the folks
joining remotely uh get excited this is
a hiring pitch um i'm david schnazzy
right thank you and i work at google i'm
building a team to work on mask which is
a technology of proxying on top of quick
the idea being that we want to change
how web browsers kind of access websites
in such a way that websites can no
longer see the ip address
to of the client to use it as a tracking
vector so if you want to learn more
about this
feel free to come and grab me i'll be
around all week and or if you just want
to tell me that i should feel bad for
writing protocols in c plus that's also
fine
[Applause]
[Music]
uh and i'm nicolas courtois i work for
qualcomm for france we are hiring
another pitch
um so we do a lot of crypto it should be
very very efficient we have like 50
crypto engines running parallel a half
of people here have in inside their
mobile phone
and we are champions of rnd we spend
twice the amount of microsoft spending
uh per um if you compare to our business
basically in research and development so
we do a lot of engineering post quantum
and a lot of traditional cryptography
thank you very much
south of frog sounds very interesting
hi i'm chelsea comlow i wanted to plug a
paper that is coming out soon uh it's
not out yet but promise it's coming out
soon um the reason why i'm talking about
it here um my co-author is dambone by
the way um the reason why i'm talking
about it here is because it's a response
to a problem that we've heard from
practitioners of threshold signatures
mainly that both properties of privacy
as well as the ability to prove or
disprove that you
signed a message after the fact
is desirable so that kind of thing might
be useful if you're signing a message
or you have a threshold signature and
some of your co-signers went and spent
millions of dollars and after the fact
you want to prove that you actually
didn't participate in that so it's a
very useful feature
and uh if anyone here is interested in
that or wants to talk more or learn more
please come and talk to me thank you
cool
[Music]
and
one of our new recruits the real
railroad crypto steering committee is
about to give a talk
thank you nigel uh so i just wanted to
draw your attention about some uh
discussion that is happening in the w3c
uh so you just heard the previous talk
that mentioned that a lot of companies
are thinking about how to restructure
the web advertising ecosystem because
third-party cookies are going away and
you will hear more about this in the
other invited talk by chrome in the
afternoon
but there is a private advertising
technology community group in w3c and
there is quite a lot of discussion
related to what kind of technologies and
what kind of designs
should be the new kind of establishment
for the web advertising community and i
think
this group will benefit from more
involvement
from people like you so please
google it or come to me and i will point
it
for you to this website and i hope some
of you will join
thank you
thank you very much
[Music]
[Applause]
you've just screwed over my counting you
know that don't you
oh god you're right you could have a
long time now
this was not a planned attack
um so my name is paul and i'm here with
my colleagues marisa jack and gerald
we're part of ncc group's cryptography
services team and we're hiring
we're hiring for remote workers we're
hiring for
students for internships as well
what we do is that we're essentially
lucky to be entrusted by many of the
bright people in this room to perform
security reviews of their solutions so
that is implementation and protocol
reviews in in cryptography
in the past we have done public work for
companies like zcash like google like
whatsapp
so it's always pretty interesting um
we also get a pretty good amount of time
to the research so i would i would
really encourage you to come to us and
come talk to us and uh
yeah any any other four here
thank you
i i'm gonna help nigel by staying on
stage for
30 seconds or something um
so there's a lot of people in this room
uh
yeah so i'm jack i work with ncc but i
also run a website called crypto hack
which
i know like 10 people in this room have
heard of maybe there's more
uh
yeah so
i built the website because i didn't
know much about cryptography and in the
process i learned a little bit about
cryptography and the goal of the website
is to encourage people
to
be less intimidated by the subject i
think within the security world there's
a lot of people who kind of look at
cryptography and kind of go that's what
mathematicians do and i'm not going to
get into that too much and i'm trying to
encourage these people that you can
learn a little bit hey not everyone
should roll their own crypto but they
should understand it
um and i had a lot of fun i made a bunch
of challenges
and i think the site's good but it could
be better
and
the next goal is to have a set of
challenges that discuss what we
currently hope are quantum hard problems
so if you're a student if you're a phd
student or if you're a lecturer with too
much time on your hands uh i
i i'd love for you to get in contact
with me talk to me about what you love
about post quantum crypto whether you
think you can write a challenge or a
lesson talk about a quirk maybe
something you think is a fun puzzle for
students to think about um the site's
free it's all open everyone can play
with it and the more people that know
about these post quantum problems
i think the more interesting work that
we can do thank you
thank you very much
go
[Music]
so most people you probably know about
zero knowledge proofs mainly from
blockchain but they also have
applications outside of blockchain
but they're pretty hard to
to make
creating r1cs is
very obnoxious
so we designed a tool um
we also made a paper called circuitry
which transforms datalog programs um
datelock is a subset of prolog into r1cs
so you can prove things like
access control we made implementation of
the belgian
eu digital code certificates
in a very efficient manner
we'd love some feedback on this work
so feel free to come give us
come say hi and
give some feedback
yeah
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
okie dokie
hi i'm deirdre you might have seen my
tweets
um
i would like to announce that zebra uh
all rust implementation of zcash the
fully private cryptocurrency is ready to
go for the next network activation in a
couple of weeks
um
it's been two and a half years in the
making and it's pretty ready to go all
the old bitcoin parts are rewritten in
async modern rust in many modules if you
have anything that is bitcoin like you
might want to look at some of our code
uh second uh i would like to talk about
frost which is a work with chelsea como
we have a bunch of rust implementations
both existing and iterating as we tweak
the frost spec the ietf spec that we're
trying to
get ready to go
um so we have code if you want to look
at that too and work with us to make
frost on your
favorite curve parameters to make sure
that we are fixing all the edge cases
that we found to make sure everyone is
doing the kind of same thing where
appropriate and three i have a podcast
uh with my co-host david adrian who's
now at chrome um and thomas patchat
called security cryptography whatever
and it talks about all the things that
we've been talking about today and if
we've been talking about at hax about
secure software secure cryptography and
sometimes football
thanks very much
if you aren't following the twitter
commentary you really should be
following the twitter commentary it's
one of the highlights of real world
crypto every year okay
folks i'm jason uh for the last couple
months i've been uh fixing a lot of
problems in the linux kernel random
number generator
which is essentially amounting to a
rewrite
and
i've
now handled a lot of the easier low
hanging fruits the obvious problems to
fix
and the remaining things to fix are
numerous
but not so obvious on how to do so there
are things like what to do during early
boot time when there's not a lot of
entropy and we collected enough entropy
there questions to answer how often do
we reseed then
is jitter on embedded systems a real
thing
there are other issues like entropy
extraction in the interrupt handler when
we don't have enough cpu budget
to do real crypto what do we do there
interesting questions
um there are these questions of entropy
estimation which is kind of a flawed
notion versus a fortuna like scheduler
and the complexities associated with
that
we got to answer whether state
compromise is even an interesting
real problem to solve
sponge constructions anyway there are a
lot of things to work on
without super obvious solutions too so
if you have any interest in these or
even if you have a strange opinion on it
please find me and
hassle me with opinions arguments
anything i'm just trying to collect some
ideas thanks
cool thank you very much
hello
uh the dutch national cyber security
center is working on updates to our
recommendations for um
quantum safe cryptography from 2017.
our focus is on
um
early adopters and also on
preventing store and decrypt attacks so
in short the the update
is expected to focus on
a hybrid key exchange and
cryptographic agility as mitigating
measures
if you'd like to know more and or if
you'd like to
give input on a draft then please see me
during lunch thanks
thanks very much
so this is another sort of excruciating
uh come to my workshop uh security
standardization research 2022 will be
happening on the 6th of june in genoa i
suspect it will be warmer than tron time
and
uh maybe not maybe not
uh and uh it'd be really good to see you
all there uh and it's just before your
smp
thank you very much
[Music]
we should have a few spaces if you want
to go to the end
yup so hello everyone it's another
workshop so i just want to promote the
verified workshop this is going to be an
eurocrypt affiliated event it's going to
happen on the
on the saturday before so it's a great
place to get started if you want to know
how to do like formal analysis of crypto
protocols and don't know where to start
it's a great workshop
verified itself is a great accessible
tool for students but we're also going
to cover tools like pro variff and
tamarind thanks
cool thank you
thank you
hi i'm steph and i'm doing free software
myself and five years ago hugo
craftchick presented here the swings
protocol
and i implemented that
and it's a very nice password manager
that has some unique security properties
that normal password managers don't have
but it um suffers from free software
development um limitations no marketing
so google crafty actually asked me to do
more marketing that's why i'm here
uh so i'm looking for some more support
and developers who can help me for
example we have no
apple client
so if you want to help me with that
you're very welcome
and we have some cool things on the
um
on a roadmap like threshold oprs and
moving to opac based password storage
there's a very exciting things ahead so
i encourage everyone to have a look at
my password swings
there's android clients
it is going to get packaged in debian
we have packages for nixos
if that is not your os
maybe look how to get it in there
thanks
thank you very much
and the next one
hello my name is tim and i work at the
internet security research group so
we're the non-profit that does let's
encrypt and we're also hiring so we have
open roles for sre on the certificate
authority as well as uh engineering on a
privacy observing metrics and mpc
um besides that you know we do a ton of
stuff from the ca the npc work uh we
have a lot of memory safety initiatives
for um
say more safer memory safe stuff on the
internet uh so yeah in general if you're
interested in doing uh public benefit
work for internet security um you should
come and check us out you don't have to
be a cryptographer like the major
qualification is to not be a jerk
so you can just uh you know look up uh
let's encrypt jobs or come find me
thanks
[Applause]
[Music]
i'm not sure if that last requirement
has ruled out half of cryptography but
anyway there we go
hi uh i just wanted to plug very quickly
uh if you are interested in rust and
interested in cryptography there is uh
the awesome rust cryptography list it is
a um it is a curated list of uh rust
crates uh we uh try to keep it updated
we try to keep it uh reflecting just
high quality crates uh you can find this
at
cryptography.rs we also have the rust
cryptography interest group which is
linked at cryptography.rs we're very
friendly if you have any questions if
you're interested in rust and
cryptography please come by
thank you very much
we have our penultimate well sort of
penultimate speaker
hi i'm daniel and i've been working on
using cryptographic primitives and
differential privacy to
use the trust mediating capabilities
that you get to separate incentive
structures in mechanism design and
mechanism learning so if you're
interested in
discussing applications of different
cryptographic new developments and like
how you get from trust separation to
incentive separation
come talk to me because it's like a bit
more complex you have like
larger layers of games
but you can get some interesting stuff
done and fulfill some assumptions in
economic games
thank you very much
[Music]
and over to you
[Applause]
hi everyone my name is julie i work on
the go programming language team at
google and we're hiring for cryptography
and security engineers that know go so
if you're interested please come talk to
me thanks
wow
i feel slightly old because not only do
i now have to learn go but it seems like
rust is quite popular and also prologue
oh my god it's going to be
anyway um there is another tradition we
have
kha'zik
is recruiting
the old timers go this yeah okay yeah um
kha'zix recruiting we have we're the
biggest crypto group in the world
academically we have like 100 people
working on all sorts from hardware to
privacy stuff to we do we did a block
cipher at some point that you might have
heard of so i would um yeah so if you're
interested there's loads of people from
kha'zik here it's a really cool place to
work it's in belgium the home of
cryptography so um yeah and
that's it
no now time for lunch thank you
everybody thank you for the all the
speakers and we'll do a bit more
tomorrow
[Music]
[Applause]
if people have jobs to announce they can
announce them on iacr.org same with
events
you