so I was interesting yeah I'll have to
be as interesting so you like this this
is given to me by the slide by a fellow
from a big telco so you can sort of see
what they're thinking so what I want to
talk about is I want to talk about the
universal people sensors and what are
the pluses and minuses and where we're
going so these are people moving around
in San Francisco the most likely stores
and by watching what people do you can
tell what their preferences are now I
should mention that I'm on the board of
Motorola telefonica Nissan Bruno so I
know something about this and the last
speaker made it very clear that there's
a lot of information that you can get
out of this data and the normal reaction
that people have is think that I've got
to stop this um and I'm gonna tell you
that that's wrong I think that you
should rename this conference not
privacy but something having to do with
data as an asset and it's an asset that
you should control not the company's and
that's really the question is who
controls the data and can you be secure
and sharing it for particular purposes
um so let me give you some quick
examples so for the car company it turns
out that if I can watch all those GPS
things that are in your cars nowadays
there are many circumstances where I can
predict whether or not you will have an
accident with about a fifty percent
chance in the next two or three seconds
because if i watch somebody else and
they have a breaking event and you're
going down the same place at a slightly
higher speed it turns out you are at
great risk so don't you want to share
that data so you can have your kids grow
up so that you can continue to have a
whole body maybe or here's another one
we build a system is for returning
soldiers but I think it'll be available
it watches you
on your phone it looks at your
socialization your physical activity how
the pattern of your life and it turns
out that those are diagnostic criteria
formal medical diagnostic criteria for
mental diseases like depression like
PTSD like schizophrenia so you can on
your phone visualize your mental social
health in terms that are understandable
focus activity social and what this does
is this uses a system i'll talk about in
just a second to share data in a
completely secure manner so that you can
see how you compare to people like you
because when people see these things
they say oh it's just a bad day or I'm a
bad person but when they begin to
compare with other people they realize
that maybe they should take action about
this I should mention that the mental
diseases in terms of disability are the
number one health problem in the world
or the cancer more than more you name it
that's the thing is the burden of
humanity and we can actually watch it
and through sharing we can begin to do
things about it here's another one
you're all familiar with pandemics and
flu and and you know about google flu
okay but it turns out that if I can
launch your phones on a minute-by-minute
basis how you move who you call where
you go I can do a really good job of
telling if you've been infected with the
flu and if I can watch the people around
you I can do a tremendously good job of
actually watching the flu move from
person to person to person now that's
George Orwell to cube power okay it's
the most invasive thing you can imagine
but now here's the trade-off there are
no protections today I guess pandemics
the vaccines don't really work they have
huge side effects not everybody takes
them anyhow so you have to ask are there
conditions under which we're going to
allow this level of spying on people
or are we gonna just let the 200 million
people die because that's what's
predicted for the X pandemic those are
the trade-offs so what I'm telling you
is really important is the big data this
sort of invasive data has rewards public
goods public goods that cannot really be
ignored because the lives of your kids
depend on them they also have enormous
risks which I think the people in this
room are very sensitive to what are we
going to do well I was concerned enough
about this that about five years ago I
convinced the World Economic Forum to
start a discussion about this with the
vice president of the EU a
representative from the US National
Security Agency the chairman of the
Federal Trade Commission the chairman of
Vodafone the chairman of Microsoft and
on and on as well as advocacy groups and
our conversation centered around what I
call the New Deal on data because in my
view the politics of this are that we
should not be talking about privacy we
should talking about how i can get
public goods to save our kids to make
our life better to cure global warming
we can actually do amazing things on
problems like that while at the same
time making sure the companies don't go
bankrupt wouldn't be any good to let
them go bankrupt but also it has to be
something that's in the direct in
immediate interest of the citizens of
the consumers it has to be a win-win-win
solution and the results of this
conversation were put out in a thing
that's called personal data emergence of
a new asset class and what it argues is
that the value and data is when it flows
and is shared that's how you save kids
that's how you make the buses run on
time that's how you by the consumer
goods that make your life may be more
interesting and if it's a good if it's a
public if it's if it's a good then it's
something that is an asset and the first
question you have to ask about acid
who owns this asset it's like land right
the first question is title to the asset
and the only politically viable thing
and industry agrees with this obviously
government does is that individuals have
to own in some sense data about them now
that's difficult in various ways but
i'll show you how you can do a lot of it
okay so we've gotten people the
industries were just talked about bought
off on the idea that individuals have to
control data about them they have to
have ownership in the sense of Old
English law common law the rights of
disposal the rights to take back data
the right to know where the data went
and these have helped shape the EU
initiative on human rights and data and
the consumer privacy Bill of Rights here
in the United States and in the last
Davos they have these wonderful artists
who draw the conversation as you do it
we had an industry spouse to these
regulatory proposals and it was clearly
we have to have true informed consent no
more euless no more terms and conditions
as they are today people were
enthusiastic industry behind you right
industry was enthusiastic by the idea
that all personal data would be legally
required to have metadata that gives the
provenance who gave permissions what
exactly were the permissions and that
that has to be attached to the data and
what that lets you do is that lets you
automatically audit where the data goes
who has it what they did with it and
where they compliant with the original
permissions and the local law it also
lets you revoke permissions say don't
like what you're doing with my data give
it back and because it's auditable you
can enforce that let me tell you a
little bit about it it's not just a
computer science problem but we've built
a sort of reference standard so together
with NGO we have Institute for
data-driven design John clip and juror
was head of the
harvard law lab and myself set this up
we've built a reference standard
software that implements these ideas
it's open source it's available for
everyone it includes things like open ID
connect so we some of my guys helped
chair the national strategy for trusted
identities in cyberspace and stick and
said daza Greenwood and as part of that
we've taken over from the military some
technology for highly secure identity
assurance in order to get rid of
passwords and get rid of many other
things that go along with that but
importantly it's not just a technical
solution there has to be a legal
solution not new laws as the last
speaker pointed out because that's like
really unlikely to happen but it turns
out that in contract law you can do a
very good job of enforcing data sharing
data privacy data ownership rights just
by contracts and that's wonderful
because it's interoperable among
different jurisdictions okay and an
example is the Swift network for
interbank transfer there's no laws about
it it's just a peer-to-peer contract
where the contract and the actual
technical computer science e messaging
are one-to-one the messages implement
contracts the contracts can be reduced
directly into computer code and that
combination of the two is what gives you
security because you can know precisely
what's happening and it's enforceable
under a contract law a framework and in
fact in the contract already is written
in harms and remedies and mediation so
you don't have to hire lawyers you don't
have to sorry for those are you or
alerts you don't have to go to court
another thing that's in the system that
is best practice is people talk about
sharing data most times that's stupid
you don't need to share data you need
share answers so the system here has a
secure way of answering questions
an oil you want and that way you can
answer the minimum amount of information
possible like yes I'm interested or yes
I'm in San Francisco not your exact
location so we've spun this up in
various places for instance in trento
we've got the government there the local
telcos the bus company in the power
company to adopt this framework and
experiment it to look at how secure is
it how does sharing data help I
mentioned some of the public goods at
the beginning and how do people feel
about it so we're starting with young
families and with elders and giving them
the ability to share data and see data
in a way that hasn't been possible
before and that's the point of spinning
these things up is to get facts on the
ground too many of these conversations
are done in policy it's all just talk
talk talk no facts we're going to get
facts let me give you one more example
and then conclude so one of the things
that comes out of this type of reasoning
this is that there ought to be a data
Commons we have taxes we have public
informations the government supplies why
doesn't this data that we're all talking
about have a Commons and so I helped
talk orage into creating what is
probably the first large big data
Commons it's in the country the ivory
coast which had a civil war that ended
about two years ago at this point and
what they did is they released all the
telephone records for the entire country
along with financial data etc etc but
aggregated in a very interesting way and
with a legal agreement under contract
law as I just talked about and we
recruited almost 90 universities from
all around the world to look at this
data asked wasn't safe could you break
it could you read n tify people and what
could you do that was a public good some
of the public goods as we figured out
how to reduce commute time by ten
percent in the big city that's enormous
we figured out how to radically improve
their malaria mitigation strategy and
their reaction to Penn
amex we also were able for the first
time to produce something that's like
census data in a place that's just done
with a civil war millions dead you don't
have census you don't know where poverty
is you don't know where the kids are
dying it turns out you can use this data
to determine where the kids are dying
with very high accuracy because people
have reliable behavioral changes when
they're in different conditions and you
could even look at ethnic divisions in a
way that had never been possible before
and of course those ethnic divisions are
the source of the Civil War so those are
some of the public goods and I will
notice ninety teams University teams
people who are experts at this no one
was able to reify anything no one was
able to do anything particularly bad and
if they had we would have thrown the
suckers in jail because they had sent a
contract that said they were going to do
this and only this and they would not
let the data go further so we had on
okay so what's next well there's a lot
of things that are next so this is me 15
years ago this is when we invented the
things that are now Google glass my
student there in front pad is actually
the technical lead for google glass so
we literally started it all and at it I
can tell you the privacy debates around
that were rather intense and that is why
google glass flashes and makes noises
when it takes pictures now we have some
other security elements to it which they
haven't yet put in but one can imagine
that they'll go in that direction and I
can also tell you that you know this
type of thing is just the beginning
you're going to see far more data about
far more things publicly available
personally available then you can even
imagine and it's up to us to figure out
how to turn that into a public good
rather than just simply to lock it down
so safety for individuals but public
good please don't forget the public good
I want my kids to grow up safe