good morning everybody your new
community to be unusually a tech
business kind of guy I've written and
spoken a lot about social media and I
have been writing a book with my
frequent colleague Robert Scoble it's
called the age of context and the
subtitle may change but right now it's
how it will impact your working in life
which is pretty comprehensive and we
didn't start this book with any plan to
have anything to do with privacy
whatsoever we went around as we've done
before we've talked to a lot of people
entrepreneurs and technologists about
this cool stuff that they're making it's
in five categories you know the
categories independently mobile social
media data of course location based
technologies and sensors we look at how
these five are converging into what we
consider a super storm and the result of
the super storm is the people in their
technology are going to have a new level
of closeness a relationship that is
different than we used to having with
machines of any kind and among the
reasons that it will be so close is your
devices are going to know everything
about you they're going to know you
healthier business your schedule your
calendar your friends what kind of email
you like first they're going to know
everything and based on that they're
going to be able to anticipate what you
want next which can get Airy as I'll
tell you about well we went around
talking to people who are making these
technologies we realized that there was
a freaky lying it's funny I was just
when I said freaky line I was reminded
to stay in
this line so you can see me so I
definitely and every time we looked at
something like what's going on in
retailer and health or an automotive we
found this freaky line and it involves
two powers that don't seem opposing
they're like Cohen centric circles I'll
get back to them later what a security
and one is privacy sometimes these two
as you know from recent events in the
news can be in conflict but before I get
to what I think about that let me tell
you a little bit about what we found and
I know you know a few of these and I'll
rattle them off rather quickly in retail
heineken and Walmart are working with an
Argentinian company called a smart
perception they created a sensor panel
they use American sensors called Prime
from primeSense and they go on above a
section and retail store so if you go
into the store and you're looking for
cereal they will know not who you are
they cancel your face but they'll know
what you're looking at if you reach out
and touch a box of curios an iPad
installed as a display on the Shelf will
offer you 40 percent off on the Cheerios
or perhaps will be a competing offer
from another serial saying instead of
cheerios tried Kellogg's k and we'll
give you thirty percent off this is one
thing going on in retail a whole other
way of looking at it is the National
Football League using you'll love it the
New England Patriots as the test case
working on contextual technologies in
the stadium why are they doing this
because they're real competition has
become HBO met HBO HD TV people are
staying home and watching football games
and they are they're going to taverns
but every year the stadium's losing
about two percent of their attendance
take
have always been the flagship for new
technologies in the working and using
data mobile apps and other technologies
so that their best customers can get
their beers in the dance their food and
advance or anything of the bling that
you buy at football games so these fans
and the best needs of course a season
pass holders and they get a little note
saying the halftime will be in five
minutes do you want another beer and
cheese tank and if they claim yes
there's an express line they go up there
they don't have to pay for it because
the credit card is on file as it is
everywhere else and so now you have a
contextual beer this of course will
spread from the Patriots to the rest of
the NFL other sports rock concerts and
everything else so everything I talked
about has bigger implications than the
little thing and mentioning we all have
loyalty cards and put them on our key
chains and in our wallets and they do
things but these are starting to be
linked up we're getting more and more
data so that smart loyalty cards and now
coming in there in trial stages but big
companies will be using them I would
guess in the next two or three years so
now when you walk into a payless they
know how often you were in here they
know you usually by when you're in here
they're starting to understand by a
sensor on the card the path you take
while you walk through there and as you
walk through you can start getting
special offers on things based on what
you're buying habits have been in the
past we think this will be in every
retail operation right now people call
it contextual marketing when you're in a
mall and suddenly you get 40 offers to
get discounts everywhere and it's just
another form of noise filtering is going
to come in so that the customization is
there and you're going to start seeing
things that maybe you want filtering is
important because the same technology is
going to be used by first responders
who run into a burning building and
don't need to know they can get ten
percent off on a cup of starbucks coffee
they do need to know other facts and
they will get to know them fast health
is one place that is just amazing of
what is going on there are a few
products that you may know I notice that
Trevor was wearing a Nike FuelBand Nike
FuelBand gives you some basic
information that helps people lose
weight stay fit but as where it's going
and what other technologies are also
doing in wearable devices deciding to
know every function of your body a
glucose level your heartbeat your your
galvanic the skin which basically means
the perspiration which shows you
nervousness whether you have
neurological health or not and other
such things and this is all for you for
your personal health except it's being
gathered and put in the cloud as a data
source where this data will be used
today is not in danger where will be
used 10 or 20 years of five years in the
future I don't know Jim medicine is
something else that we discover we never
heard of before it there's a clear
relationship between your health and
where do you live if you live in a coal
mine you're more prone for emphysema if
you live in the mountains cancer if you
live near a polluted river then the
drinking water you have to lead to
intestinal problems it's only now being
used not by the health industry but this
bottom-up movement of people who are
using technology for better health one
of the applications we came across in
this the area is from a company called
as a Midwestern company called as ma
palace I think I said it right yes the
as ma palace um application has a sensor
device that goes on top of an asthma
patient's breathing to inhaler and at
the same time
as a mobile app and a collects data on
where people use their inhalers in New
Yorker school was part of the pilot
program high school level and they
discovered that asthmatic children
excuse me I get all choked up when I
talk about asthma I don't know why um
asthmatic children walking to school
would always breathe the inhaler in the
same place and they discovered that
they're rather close to a refinery so by
getting the kids to reroute themselves
by one block they stop the kids from
having asthma attacks every day as they
walk to and from school there are many
other applications that are being worked
on we looked at cities we have a chapter
called the contextual cities and there's
a lot of stuff that's fascinating how 3d
modeling is creating as it has in
Seattle major urban projects that come
in on time on budget or even under this
is by dramatic contrast for those of you
from New England on something called the
Big Dig that was 44 years late and 55
billion dollars over the original budget
and they got away with it that leads to
another issue which is that there is a
trend that in the contextual cities we
talked about the new urbanist some of
you that I met last night of new
urbanist demographically we all left
home very often in the suburbs went to
college moved into the city for a few
years got a job there then get married
and moved back out to the suburbs but
this is reversing and people is staying
in the city they're using zipcar's
rather than owning cars they are
starting to raise families there and
they want better schools they want
better government and they want urban
projects that don't ruin their
neighborhoods and they're demanding
better access to government and
municipal level a lot of cities
Vancouver San Francisco New York Chicago
Washington of course is a forward
thinker in this area Chattanooga are all
putting more and more of city data in
the cloud where voters have access to it
and this is changing the relationship
between urban planners and constituents
because the urban planners are finding
it's a lot safer and better to get the
input in the planning phase rather than
after the damn thing gets built ha cars
cars in my favorite cars we can get to
the contextual car the self-driving car
that's technologically sooner than
regulators will probably allow it to be
but what's more interesting is this
thing called a data log earlier this
year John Broder a New York Times
reporter who often already I just got
here okay
okay thank you very much John brudder a
New York Times reporter who usually
covers the White House likes to review
cars and he reviewed the model asked
Tesla a while ago and gave it a really
awful review it culminated not in Boston
where I was supposed to but in
Connecticut where it had to be towed
away and for those of you who know who
Yvonne musk is he doesn't take this
stuff easily it turns out he had a data
box in the car that reviewed everything
that Broder did and he did a fact by
fact breakdown showing in his conclusion
that rotor had to work very very hard to
make the car fail so badly the New York
Times own buds woman wrote an op-ed page
basically saying this is true five years
earlier big business the enterprise got
into blogging when the vice chairman of
General Motors started arguing with
reviewers on the GM new blog called the
fast lane and he had to use the force of
his personality which use very well but
we've come forward in technology we're
now data is on the side of the defense
case and you can take on the New York
Times reviewer and prove your case
factually did will be used lots of ways
with this little data box because it now
knows who's driving by the seat position
and that sort of stuff what radio
stations you listen to it knows
everywhere you go and there is a record
of this you also have other devices in
this part of the country you have EZ
Pass where I live as fast pass but every
time you cross a toll but a gate there's
a picture taken showing where you were
at a certain time this data is collected
can this be used
by law enforcement and an investigation
not definitely but probably but can it
be used in a civil case when one party
is divorcing the other and wants to see
where a car was parked on a certain
night I'm going to wrap up so I'll go
right to Google glass which is something
that it's gotten a lot of news
everybody's concerned about what happens
when you go into a bathroom wearing them
well for one thing if I took a video of
you or a picture of you with google
glass it would light up it would ding
you would know I was taking a picture
for another thing i could only record
what's directly in front of me which an
arrest room would be very unwise
simultaneously this very little talk
about the fact that Google knows
everywhere your eye looks all the time
when you're wearing them so I have to go
to wrap up very fast and I'll rattle
through these quickly hopefully we'll
get to them in the Q&A again we have a
few conclusions one is this is a very
nuanced issue this trade-off between
security and privacy and I can't tell
you what you should do other than be
aware and pay attention to try to stop
it at this point as some people would
like to do is very idealistic I think
it's a little bit like standing on a
beach and trying to punch a tsunami
first of all you wants to see in the
second of all you're going to find
yourself in deep water we use this stuff
because there is this free ice cream
thing if you want to search on Google
for free that's really good stuff that's
free ice cream in return for that you
have to let Google know more about you
so they can give you better answers so
legitimate trade off but as you can
imagine there are many issues I think
Google is a very very ethical company
compared to other companies but the
people who run it now may not run it
five years in today at ten years from
today they all have nice retirement
packages
the other thing is I know many of you
talked last night my wife Paula and I
heard a lot about policy policy is
really nice and I believe it we're in
New Hampshire which 54 years after the
first seat belt laws were passed in
Wisconsin still doesn't require you to
wear seatbelts in a car they have on the
license plate instead live free or die
which i think is a real choice in this
stage but the point of it is technology
is moving at a breathtaking pace public
policy regulation or lawmakers don't and
if you try to get policy to control this
you need to leap forward beyond the
issue of should this data be collected
because it is being collected and it
isn't going to be stopped and I bet
right now something's going to tell me
to shut up and get off the stage so
thank you very much