and possible
and we're going okay this is better
manual web application testing through
automation so first things first I want
to thank you guys for coming out this is
my first b-side so I'm pretty excited
about that
so let's get started I did make some
notes but I've got a puppy at home that
kind of ate my homework true story right
I checked my bag this morning at the
hotel
yeah there's two marks on it's great so
thanks Duke okay
these are my resources twenty-one tips
for making a boring presentation so if
you guys are looking for something
boring you are there so a little bit
about me I started out as a sysadmin
primarily working on windows machines
and got interested in security and it
kind of went from there even as a kid I
had a strong quest to understand how
things work one of the stories that my
parents tell is that I took apart my
bike when I was a kid and my mom comes
home from work and she says now you
don't have a point to ride well like an
hour later I had the thing back together
and I was riding it so that's kind of
gun interesting how things work
my security career started out as a sake
analyst on the blue team which right now
I do Red Team activities so I do kind of
miss the blue stuff because it's fun so
after being on the sock for a while it
took an interest in offensive security
and I figured I should probably get a
certification so I could be a little bit
more marketable so I started with OS CP
I figured that'd be a great starting
point it was one of the most difficult
things that I've probably ever done in
my life especially the exam at the end I
was about two pots of coffee in so it
was fantastic experience so if you ever
get a chance to do that or you've done
that that's awesome
so right now I'm a web application pen
tester and that's what I do and the the
goal of this talk is to give you guys
some idea like what I do and what I can
do to help other people that do web
application testing because some of the
stuff is monotonous and the goal of this
talk is to kind of automate some of that
to make things easier
so again disclaimer this is my opinion
not that of my employer so that's that
so what do we want to automate things
well that's probably why you guys are
here and that's a great question so it
saves time because no one ever said I
have to too much time on my hands to do
this test consistency so the thing is
when you're doing tests back to back a
lot of times you run into a problem
where you're like okay what did I do
on that last test what application was
this again accuracy so you can so you
can go back to the client you can say
hey this is what I did because I did
this I do this in every single time and
it's also easier to teach new testers so
if someone's just getting into testing
web applications it's a great teaching
tool and again it scales very well so if
you can do something small and you can
do something large if you if you've got
a good plan in place testers are lazy
right I know I am
so another idea for giving this talk and
motivation to do it is when I was
working on the the sock that you could
see attacks going on where the bad guys
were automating things that they do
so the the ones won't ability that I
really like is shell shock because you
know you can see the different payloads
that they use again shell shock is the
bash vulnerability where you can see
attacks come in and they were actually
injecting commands into the web server
so that's pretty fun to analyze some of
that the malware automates as well it
spreads without user interaction I think
we can all think of examples of that
that just came up recently in fact one
of them was talked about in the keynote
so a great example of that botnets again
examples in the news recently of how bad
guys are automating the botnets and the
Britax malware this is one of my
favorite powers because it scans memory
to look for credit card numbers and I
think scanning memory is is a pretty
powerful thing so this is the first
example because you have to walk before
you can run so with this example I
created a simple script that will
essentially enumerate the IP addresses
on the network so this is written in
bash this is pretty much automation 101
so I will have the slides available at
the end or you can email me and I can
give you a copy of those if you guys
aren't able to see it so essentially we
create a range from 1 to 254 right
because that's how many IP addresses are
subnet
once we do that we can pipe that
information into ping and it'll
basically enumerate through all those IP
addresses and at the end we can actually
grep for bits from so then it did a
script output we get a nice little bit
of information that tells us just the IP
address of the better that are up on the
network if you guys do have any
questions feel free to just interrupt
this is pretty informal here so once so
once we find once we find out what's hot
on the network the next thing to do is
we need to scan because now that we
found a host that's up we need to see
what that host offers so you know
there's several tools to do that we can
use nmap nikto I like nikto I'm a big
fan of that especially coming from the
OS cpworld directory buster Bert works
scanner I love work scanner primarily do
my testing in that application and some
of you guys are probably doing
automation right now so the list goes on
so one of the things we can do with nmap
is we can scan an IP address range with
nmap and in the example here I'm
primarily looking for ports 80 and 443
right because that's our web interface
so we need we need to identify the web
servers that exist on the network and
what we can do is we can we can take the
end map information and we can type it
out using the - oh gee that's for
original gangster actually its graphical
format but I like ogee right and then we
can pipe that into nikto and if you're
using Kali if you do a an update to the
latest version of nikto which is
included with Kali it will have this
functionality built in so we can pipe
that information from nmap to nikto and
on the next slide I kind of break it
down for what we can how that command
looks oh so there's a lot of nmap
switches and so you can look at port 80
or 43 just as I talked about earlier and
that's going to give us a web traffic
so again I talked about if you're using
Kali this is this presentation is
primarily designed for users of Kali
because it's a standard platform
throughout so you don't have to worry
about you know what version you're
running if you just update it and you
should be fine so again with nmap we can
ban or grab for running services that
exist on the network
nmap also has the ability to use NSE
scripting which is the nmap scripting
engine so a lot of that has built-in
vulnerability scanning as well and in
this next example I'm going to talk a
little bit about that as well
so what we can do with nmap is we can
take the information that we get from
and map and we can export it as an XML
so the great thing about an XML is it's
pretty much like the universal format
that you know Metasploit can read from
we can import that information into
search poit
which if you guys use Cali search point
is built-in and it will it's basically
an offline version of exploit dB so if
you're on an engagement and you're
trying to find out what vulnerabilities
exist for you know you know WordPress or
you know a Java plug-in or something
like that like Search Lloyd is very very
easy to use and if you use search point
that's installed with Kelly then you
don't have to worry about the CAPTCHA
when you search on exploit dB so in this
example here you can call out search
poit and if you do the - - and map and
then supply that XML document then it
will take that XML and it will run
through search poit
and find the different versions the the
banners that exist on those servers and
it will actually look for
vulnerabilities for it so in this case I
use Metasploit able for these slides
because it's it's a great learning tool
and as you can see here there's the vs
FTP D with the backdoor command
injection that was identified this is
just a small excerpt of pages and pages
of stuff that it found for bet
exploitable
so so actually we've kind of worked at
the at the OS layer now we can get into
automating the web browser so when I
first thought about this but why would I
want to automate the web browser why
wouldn't I just use a web browser right
because that's what it's designed to do
but then then I realized that if you
script if you script those actions it's
faster it's easily repeatable and you
can use regex so I know I know there's
some guys out there that they like to
use regex
so this is like right up your alley so
there was recently a botnet that was
using automating web browsers to
basically create fraud for click ads so
they had a whole farm of servers that
were basically fake browsing the
Internet and this is where I kind of got
the idea from so for this example I
chose to go with mechanize and this is
available and severed several different
formats in this example we're going to
use Python so in just four lines of code
you can easily request a page and print
the information so that's that's why I
chose mechanizing though this works with
Ruby and pearl as well
so if you guys develop in either those
languages there's there's that
availability as well
[Music]
so this these four lines this will take
the information from the page and
display it out so what we can do is we
can look to see what headers are in
place and we can also see the cookies
that are that are being sent back and
forth so you know one of the things that
I do during a test is I look to see you
know if the secured flag is set on the
cookie as well as the HTTP only so this
is a great way to do that
there's also mechanize also has the
ability to manage cookies and it uses
basically the same cookie jar that Burke
uses if you're familiar with that
so again you got to walk before you can
run so in this next example we're
actually logging in to the web
application because I mean after all
most of the applications that I test
have logins because they need to be
secure right so this adds just a couple
more lines of code and as you can see
it's very human readable so even if
you're not that familiar with Python
there's still a lot you can just look at
this and figure out what's going on so
we are dot for obviously that's the
username and then the password for the
form field so in order to get this if
you all you have to do is look at the
source code of the webpage and that will
give you that information so in this
example we're using the dvwa which is
damn vulnerable web application this is
one of my favorites because it's it's
simple again I like simple and then the
the last option down there actually
emulates the submit button
so it you know for all intents and
purposes looks like that the user is
clicking the submit button so again I
talked about this earlier this is the
display of the information that we got
back that print our dot info and you
know we can see some of the you know
powered by PHP today we can also see the
cache settings on there as well so again
this is very easy to do and it will be
quick to get back information
so again we've got the banner
information we can check for the
different flags that are that are
present also the cross-site scripting
flag to see where scripts can be loaded
from also testing for cross-site request
forgery a lot of applications will
implement the cross-site request forgery
token that will show up in these
displays as well so now that we've kind
of talked about Python now we're going
to move into burp again this is one of
my favorite testing tools so we're
actually in a walk through showing you
how to create a burp macro and what it
will do is if the import detects that
your session is terminated it will
automatically log you back in and I came
up with this idea when I was working on
a test and I and I found a place that I
knew was vulnerable to cross-site
scripting but every time that I would
use a malicious payload so every time it
would see a carrot or a quote or a
racket or something like that it would
log me out of the application so that's
no good this is really going to slow me
down so that's how I came up with this
idea of using macros you know I think
you know all great inventions are driven
by a need so anytime you have a need and
you write a tool to fix it I think
that's pretty awesome
so I've got a I wanted to do a demo but
I was kind of nervous to do demos
because I know sometimes the demo gods
don't cooperate so I did a video and I
hope everybody can see this so again
we're using the damn vulnerable web
application so what we're going to do is
we're essentially going to log in and
we're going to look at that traffic
inside a burp and then we're going to
create that macro to replay that traffic
so the first thing we need to do like
step one is to log in and kind of behind
the theme but I've already got burp
setup and I'm already capturing that
traffic so so right now I'm logging into
the application
so this is a little I think the
resolution is a little bit off so
hopefully you guys can still see so in
the in the blurry text again I apologize
we can see the traffic that has been
sent back and forth so it looks like the
the login process is for requests so
basically you request the page you log
in and then it displays the page so so
what we're doing here is just checking
the HTTP history to make sure that we
have that traffic once we have the
traffic we can begin creating the macro
so once we're once we're inside a verb
if we go to project options and I know
it's kind of hard to see because of the
resolution but you can kind of see up
there it's the the tab closest to the
right so so once we click on that so
we'll click on project options and then
down here towards the bottom there's a
option to add a macro and you can kind
of see the add button but it's still a
little it's still a little blurry down
there
[Music]
and again I can email these slides out
if you guys aren't able to read it
yes Emax Jesus appropriators you have to
have a life I did this demo with the
free version yourself absolutely that's
that's one of the cool things that this
works even with the free version so with
the macros located down towards the
bottom end of the screen if you click
the Add button that will bring up that
list of traffic that we saw earlier in
the HTTP history so what what we're
doing here is we're essentially going to
select the traffic that we want to
replay so again a macro is just you know
recorded actions that we did we're
automating that process so we're going
to I think it's controlled to select
multiple events on there and then once
we have those selected then we can click
OK and there's the button here that's
still kind of blurry that says test
macro and that will actually reap a
replay the traffic
[Music]
Oh
so the next thing we need to do is we've
got our traffic recorded and we've
created a macro so the next thing we
need to do is identify the conditions
that exist to replay that traffic and
again this is a simple example of if the
if burp the text that your user session
has been terminated or you've been
logged out this can work for any number
of things if you're trying to test you
know cross-site request forgery tokens
login tokens anything that that you can
you need to replay over and over again
this will work and this is a great tool
so if you've never used this before you
know I encourage you to play around with
it because it's it's pretty powerful
stuff
so what we're doing here is this is the
sessions or the conditions that exist
but what we need to do to replay that
traffic so what we're doing in this if
we you the tab there's a if you can't
see it but there's an option in there
that that says if session is terminated
then run this macro
so what we're going to do is select our
macro and then click OK
and one caveat to making this work
successfully night I struggled with this
when I was setting it up there's an
option here that says only when this
macro if so only run this macro if
you're in repeater if you're if you're
in intruder so essentially what you're
doing is setting the scope so the option
that we need to select in here is the
option for proxy because without
selecting proxy it won't run as you're
browsing the site or you're scanning the
site in fact that's another good thing
to mention if you're if you've got the
professional version of work and you're
scanning the site and for some reason
your session terminates if you have this
macro set up it will automatically log
you back in
[Music]
see I think I start that
so once we've once we've got our macro
set what we can do is log out of the
application to test to make sure this is
going to work properly so as you can see
I'm clicking the logout button down
there and now we're logged out so the
next step is to require to request the
page that requires authentication and
what what Burkman will do is it will say
oh it looks like my sessions invalid I'm
going to run this macro so we'll be able
to watch this in the video here and it
takes a little bit longer because it's
got to identify that the session is
terminated and then replay the macro so
in this example I'm going to like the
upload page the cross-site request
forgery page
and it's working properly
if there's a there's time at the end I
think I've got a copy of burp on my
laptop so we can learn through that so
another another great benefit to using
these macros is if you're doing
something a little bit more complicated
you can actually record like let's say
you find cross-site scripting and you
know once you write up your report a lot
of times the developers asked well how
did you get to this page what payload
did you use what if the traffic look
like so what you can do is you can
actually record this macro and save it
and give it to the developer and then
they can watch the traffic to see you
know what's going on how you navigate it
to the page you know the different
payloads that you use to just fall in
that cross-site scripting or you know
whatever the vulnerability is again it's
a great teaching tool so you can take
you know you can have the senior tester
create this macro and then for a retest
when the application team patch is the
vulnerability then you can give that
macro to a junior tester and it makes it
a lot easier for them to replay that
traffic and retest it
so a couple caveats troubleshooting
macros the session management is really
big so if you can see it there's uh when
you configure the macro you have to tell
it to instead of reusing the cookie that
already exists you have to tell it to
get that new cookie from the web server
and replay it because if you don't it
it'll never work so now that we've
talked about you know scripting and you
know nmap simple bash scripting now
we're going to talk about Metasploit and
the different scripts that exist and
custom scripts you can create in
Metasploit so you know once once you do
find out vulnerability and you get a
foothold in the network one of the
things that you do first is look around
right you got to see what loot is
available and you have to find a way to
persist so if you script those actions
it's the same action every single time
so if the client asks what what did you
do to gain access and how did you pivot
once you got into the network well you
can say well we run these scripts and
and this is what we do every single time
so the other part of that just the
reverse of that is when you when the
engagement is over it makes it really
easy to remove your backdoor remove any
files that exist on those machines that
you've compromised because you can
basically unrunnable remove that so just
some quick information about Metasploit
scripting on the written in Ruby so if
you guys know Ruby that's awesome
because I don't but there's plenty of
examples that exist out on the internet
so I kind of learned the code from
necessity there's something that I find
that I need to learn how to do that's
basically my interest in coding
and there's a bunch of pre-existing
scripts that exist in the Metasploit
framework and I've got the URL saved up
there so you can either look at those or
you can run them to see you know how
they work what they do
unfortunately the Metasploit scripts are
no longer supported by Metasploit
they're no longer updated but they still
exist in this and the scripting engine
is still there so there's scripts and
there's also RC files like basically
resource files so these are recorded
commands that can be played back and
Metasploit kind of like a bash RC file
so it can it can contain Ruby code a
great example is you can use this for
enumeration or post exploitation and you
can also clean up after exploitation and
after the engagements over so these are
this is a screenshot of the existing
scripts so I'm sure some of you guys use
these right now it may not know where
you know where they came from like some
of the examples are like kill a V
migrate I know I use migrate a lot if
you if your spawn in a process that's
not stable and you need to migrate that
to a different process that's a great
script for that resource
also webcam if you're interacting with
the you're on a laptop and you're
interacting with the webcam that's the
resource script that exists and all of
these are saved in in plain text so you
can go in and see how they work and
maybe even combine them
so again this is a simple example to get
it started
so what this is is a dot RC or a
resource file so one of the common
things that I that I do on on engagement
is set up a listener right because
everything is spawned through a reverse
shell because like who has just a
firewall open that that will accept you
know new connections and not have them
be you know a reverse shell so I find
myself doing this a lot so I've got to
send a set up my handler I've got to
select my payload I've got to set my
port in my IP address so this is a
script that I created that does that for
me
so again it's just a couple lines of
code so we're defining what export we
want to use so in this case it's the
multi handler and our payload is going
to be met interpreter reverse TCP and
we're setting our local port which is
going to be the port that the machine
calls back on and then the El host down
there is going to be the IP address of
the machine we're working on so to
execute the RC script is is very simple
if you save it in the in the resource
directory you can just call it out by
resource and then the name of your
script if you don't do it that way then
you have to call out the full path so in
this case you know you type in resource
for slash route for it / listener RC and
you can see the V output there it you
know it selects the exploit we're using
selects the payload we're using the port
and the return IP address
another cool thing is there's an autorun
feature and metro reporter so just like
in the you know way back when when you
put the CD in your cd-rom at what it
would pop up with with autorun that
feature exists in Metasploit so a great
use for this is once you get a reverse
shell you can execute a series of
commands that will you know we talked
earlier about migrating the processes
enumerate the hosts to see what exists
enumerate the network interfaces to see
what networks this computer is connected
to in case it's a multi home machine so
I've created a simple example for basic
Linux privilege escalation a lot of this
works is taken from got milk which is
from offensive security to great
resource if you're trying to escalate
from let's say like the Apache user
account to route on a Linux box it's
great for that so what I've done is is
take the most common things that I use
from that script and incorporate it kind
of put my own spin on it
so in this example we are taking that
script and importing it into Metasploit
and basically any any bash command can
be run in Metasploit if you wrap it in
Ruby so it takes bash commands and it
also has its own proprietary commands as
well so so in this example what we're
going to do is we're going to get the
system information such as the target OS
we're going to see if we can enumerate
the Etsy issue so we can see what
version of Lennox this is running
because sometimes if you find a web host
and let's say it's running let's say
it's running tomcat i'm kat apache right
well that means it can either be lennox
or you know it could be solaris so we
have to identify that information
because if we're going to post exploit
this machine we need to figure out what
our OS is and if we're starting out as
that apache user account we figure out
what's installed and what
vulnerabilities exist so we can so we
can escalate to that admin account
so so this is our list of commands what
we're going to do here we're going to
we're going to execute the command and
then we're going to return it back to
the console and we're going to save this
is privy underscore ESC dot RB so this
is the the output of the script so
essentially this is once you've got your
mandatory reporter shell back you can
run this script and it will take it will
take those commands run it on the remote
host and give you the information back
so as you can see the first thing it
does is get the system information so
it'll nx-os Metasploit Abul it's running
version
colonel two point six point twenty four
now if you're familiar with this version
of the kernel you know there's that
there's all kinds of privilege
escalations that are available because
this is an older kernel so we can see
you know what the top what time it is on
the system if you're working on
something remotely in a different time
zone that can be helpful as well you can
also get the computer name so a lot of
times people name their computer names
something that's close to the function
so this could help you to identify what
the possible function is of this machine
so it does it do you know reporting does
it connect to a mainframe like what does
it do
so the end goal of automation is that it
simplifies things you run the same task
over and over again it makes doing
mundane things a little more enjoyable
right
it streamline streamlines the testing
process and the idea is that it saves
more time for doing manual testing
so at this time if you guys have
questions I know we're kind of done a
little bit early I'd like to answer
those now and actually let me see if
I've got burp installed here
[Music]
maybe not I might have deleted it we go
back to the presentation here so you
guys can get my email address if you're
if you're interested in getting a better
copy of the video
so I questioned yes yes yes a library
right how much control you have over
requests over here as a person so the
question was using Python and the
mechanized library how much how much can
you manipulate the initial request so
there's there's a lot of things you can
change so when I do a test sometimes all
you can set it to ignore robots.txt
because right out of the box
mechanized will not scan those
directories you can also change the user
agent string yes I mean you can yeah so
you can you know be anything from an
iPhone to a blackberry to a Windows
machine there's a lot of functionality
in there also if you're testing for if
you're doing like the shell shock you
can actually customize that so you can
put your shell shock payload inside of
that user agent string you can also set
cookies you can manually set cookies so
like for the the dvwa you can actually
set the security cookie to low or medium
when you log in so yeah so you there's a
lot you can do with that it's a great
question was there another question I
saw
okay well thanks for coming turtle