all right everybody hey first let's give
a round of applause for everybody it
puts on B sides come on hi Rocky now
these are interesting amazing event and
having come since the b-sides when I
think I've only missed one be sad he
goes in shy actually I think I made that
one I had a go to China right afterwards
but I did make that I didn't make made
the flight but it's great to see it in
Cleveland here especially in our
hometown so awesome turnout I think
we're are we are we at capacity at the
great yep confetti more in it's great so
it's awesome to see so I appreciate a
break coming to my talk today is really
talking about defeating a lot of the
next gen technology is he out there and
what I like doing is kind of showing
both sides both the offensive side of
what we're seeing today in getting
around certain types of techniques as
well as where the industry needs to move
on the detection side as well and where
how we can get better so hopefully you
can apply both concepts here for this
talk just a brief introduction myself on
Dave Kennedy I started trusted suck as
well as binary defense local companies
here in Cleveland one in Hudson and one
in Strongsville so different locations
we have folks all over the country and
it's been great
after the social engineer toolkit and
some other stuff been helping on and mr.
robot TV show which has been really neat
wait till season 3 is gonna be really
cool something a big surprise in there
but yes told about me so good news is I
don't really have to give a talk anymore
I'm just going to leave it there we can
all go home now so that's fun so in all
seriousness you know this is what we're
seeing today as far as the marketing
campaigns go you know goodbye data
breaches
you know artificial intelligence that's
designed to stop all the hackers you
know stuff that's that's considered
next-generation
and a lot of that's how it is you know
hey next generation is there so that you
can remove a lot of the controls the
traditional stuff you've had in place
before so that you can replace a lot of
the things that the bulkiness of things
like anybody see the latest I think it's
up 14 you know how large the installer
is step 14 is one gig one gig you're
putting one gig of shit on part of their
kids here sorry
any kids all right one okay you're
putting one gig of shit on your computer
and it's insane right whereas you have a
lot of these next-generation ones that
count a lot less right you know less CPU
less RAM you know left you know data
usage everything else and it's not a one
gig installer right with interesting
enough about a lot of these houses we'll
see whether or not they kind of hold up
we'll talk about that and so if you look
at what we do has attackers the big
focus now is either on the prevention
side so hopefully we have good
prevention controls in place right to
stop the hackers you know good good
ingress firewall rules on good egress
and hopefully you know in the event that
a user clicks on something we have good
preventative controls to stop that but
we also recognize as an industry that
you know when it comes to detection as
well that also has to be just as much on
par if not better on than a prevention
cycle so you know in the event that we
get a compromised
can we actually detect that and respond
and mitigate the risk that happens out
there and as attackers our goal is to
circumvent that those that detection
criteria right so to do things like
lateral movement and get undetected to
escalate permissions and move to
different systems to get access to the
data that we want access to and so I'd
say as a whole the industry itself has
gotten a little bit better you know I
would say you know if you looked at one
my talks probably three or four years
ago I would have said that the same
techniques that I used today are the
same techniques that I use 10 years ago
and I would say that I have had to shift
a lot of my tactics as an attacker we as
a as an industry head has had to shift a
lot of our techniques as attackers so we
can skirt a lot of it the traditional
detection methods out there
granted still a lot of horrible
companies out there no offense you know
a lot of companies where it's very still
easy to break in not a lot of detection
criteria but as an industry we're
progressing for pretty heavily and so if
you look at a lot of the next-generation
products out there taunting enhanced
detection and protection capabilities
and so what's interesting about a lot of
these is you know they're a lot of these
are built on a lot of core concepts of
what we talked about like known good or
application whitelisting maybe make it a
little bit easier or the artificial
intelligence stuff which you know if you
look at a scalability perspective makes
it a lot more difficult I will talk a
little about that here in just a second
but what's interesting about the next
generation product lines is they may do
something or one thing very well but
when it comes to the overall product
itself it usually Falls pretty
far and flat we'll talk about how that
works and so if you look at most
products and let's just use carbon black
as a good example
I actually like carbon black as a
product I think bit nine from an
application whitelisting perspective and
then the visibility you can get from an
e DRS a from a carbon black is great but
what's interesting about carbon black is
that you need to develop your watch list
right anybody familiar to listen cover
black on and stuff right so if you don't
have a team that's just sitting there
researching all day long different
attack patterns and building your watch
lists around the new attack patterns you
know you're not having a good detecting
a good detection around carbon black in
addition most of the watch lists that
are created are very simplistic in
nature you might look for things like
encoded command right well there's 12
different variations of encoded
commanders - easy there's sec there's
sen dozen en co you know you keep going
on and on and on there's a number of
different variations around encode a
command or just invoke expression
there's a lot of things you can do to
not even trigger PowerShell commands
that are our traditional ones and I'll
talk on some stuff on unicorn' that one
but what's interesting as most products
are very much still signature based if
this happens then trigger an alarm and
so we're still in a mindset today of hey
our patterns have to match what the
attackers are doing and I see a lot of
companies that focus on lateral movement
a good example on lateral movement is
you know they'll blow detection criteria
around W my lateral movement right
they'll look at PowerShell remoting look
at RPC and S&B as lateral movement they
don't look at that what the pattern of
that is right instead of looking at WMI
or RPC or has to be why not look for
successful logins across your network
from the same source IP address and look
more in the behavior itself and so as an
industry we have to focus more on the
behavior patterns and in addition but as
attackers we have to emulate that
behavior as well and so you look at a
lot of Technology tartar tolerance
artificial intelligence and machine
learning the great part about this and
the reason why is that this doesn't
scare me yet as far as the technology as
an attacker is because humans are crazy
right
humans do different things all the time
that is beyond reasonable expectations
of what human beings can do and it's
fantastic you know we have folks that
are an HR folks that are in sales folks
that are IT folks that are you know in
R&D and they all have different ways and
patterns of behavior that they leverage
on a different day to day basis and
that's why artificial intelligence from
a understanding around how humans behave
and abnormal patterns of behavior that's
so difficult to actually go and do I
think maybe five or ten you
is down the road AI will be a valuable
resource in the security industry it is
not a damn product out in the market
today it has stopped me once not one not
even close not even a little bit not
even a little tiny bit right and so you
look at this technology as touted as
stopping attackers and most of it is
still so rudimentary when it comes to
how it actually goes in dust detection
that getting around it's super Trivium
we'll talk a little about that so when
it comes to protection it's my favorite
slice I'm getting it that age now or my
kids are getting at the age now Eggman
is it time yet you know they're like I
might have a son that's 9 I'm liking
that too soon or Zin you know what's the
route was to really didn't you got a
good age 12 all rights well 13 17 18 no
okay
21 that's what my my my my daughter's
locked in the basement until 21 so yeah
so when it comes to it when it comes to
protection and talking about protection
you know there's there's different
variations of protection we have what we
call known good or application
whitelisting we have you know detection
when it comes to traditional antivirus
detection we have machine learning
artificial intelligence and see other
ones to name a few and so when it comes
to protection a lot of cases like
looking at something like sine Lance
most companies don't just actually stop
you from stopping the service we can
stop the service you no longer are
detected or just inject into its own
process and you can do whatever you want
to without being detected or just
renamed PowerShell dot exe and then you
can do anything you want to on that
system without an intersection which is
fantastic or just use a custom Packer
there's a number of different ways to
get around a number of these different
technologies but what's interesting is
that you know some of the detectives may
be cool in nature like hey you know
maybe it detects like red Jessica r32
going over but it doesn't like find
basic stupid stuff like you know macro
injection with you know viruses that
literally are from like the sub seven
days in AOL you know and so you know
there's a big variation of what we see
in a lot of these next-generation
products from what they actually detect
or what they actually prevent against to
what's actually real in the industry and
so when we go against a lot of these you
know a lot of the basic stuff on doesn't
get picked up and they're looking for a
lot of the more advanced apt type things
that are out there
in a lot of cases but
you know what's interesting about this
one is this one is actually super easy
to identify powerset ADHD when you're
calling PowerShell anyway it loads to
dll's well three technically reflection
that DLL system that management
automation of DLL and then system that
management ni dot DLL difficile is being
called by a non power side exe or non
power cell to underscore is e dot exe
application and it's probably a good
indication that you know someone's using
something like Ben or zennet but in here
not in here then there is using some
like no PowerShell that Ben wrote you
know or using something that leverages
PowerShell that reflects into the dll's
itself to actually call numbers power so
that goes in around detection so a lot
of these tools again very don't do a lot
of very basic stuff when it comes to to
actual detection and so if you look at
us per attackers I'm just little too
real no prevention for target attacks
some of the basic stuff the mess can
monetize things you know like ransomware
and stuff like that I'm a lot of these
next-generation products focus very
heavily on those pieces but don't look
on a lot of the other cases around you
know direct attackers or anything like
that
Amin so I'll show a quick demo on
unicorn and I just did an update the
unicorn recently I think as of Thursday
I did a new release and I know if I
pushed it up yet I think I pushed it up
I don't remember I don't know I was
writing on the airplane so I forgot but
I have a new version of unicorn but it
incorporates a lot of new techniques off
for getting around a lot of the
different PowerShell attack vectors now
what's interesting is most of these
tools when it talks about power saw
detection will look for certain patterns
right on the look for encoded come in
and VOC expression they'll look for you
know Colonel furniture DLL being called
a look for memory injection techniques
that are being leveraged in there on so
there's still very much signature based
now let me ask you a question if I
completely obviously I'm not calling any
of those will you detect me probably not
right but if you were on the blue team
side and you're looking more for hey
what's the length of the PowerShell
command or wise powershot ID XE peeking
out the internet would you detect me in
that case probably right and so those
are things that we need to look at much
different so let me show you an example
of unicorn here
so this is the latest version I'm
holding here we can see that I'll blow
it up in just a second if I can type so
with unicorn just you know any type of
tool you can't have a hacker tool
without ASCII art that's number first
and foremost right but what we're going
to do is just show you a couple of the
things you can use any payload you want
to now but by default you can use
Metasploit that's what I'm IP address
now when it comes to this specific
technique we're actually at a customer
doing a purple team exercise and it's
some really good detection criteria
around encoded command and so what we
decided to do is you know leveraging
coded command without ever calling in
coded command itself to get around their
watch lists and so in this case you look
at the code am I ever calling a code of
command pull looks legit by the way I'm
sure it's legit so what other ones will
do is the automatically try to
reassemble on the base 64 encoded string
so you can see the decoder version and
so what we do is we actually chunk those
up since they're not actually doing a
Python our powershell interpreter so you
look here we actually chunk them up so
that they're not really base64 just
stupid stuff like that gets around most
of them all only so far as I'm concerned
and so you can see here it's actually
going to be executing and you can
actually see it but it will execute
sharklet rapping member and this is just
say you copy and paste this into
anywhere you have remote command
execution whether it's you know PS exec
or other methods you're leveraging to
compromise the machine this will give
you a shell that directly on inject
shell code directly into memory and then
allows you to not touch disk in a lot of
cases so on easy way of doing that and
it gets around mana brush now we're just
using string variables on and then two
strings to convert it back to an actual
string for us so this is basically
assembling - ENC without ever calling -
you can see ever so you're not going to
see it let go echo sound better you mess
enemy Jason do you alright
so that's a good one there we go so
that's a good one
now what's what's great about that one
specifically um is it works well but if
you ever decide to look at my code I
always put other ones in there that I
don't necessarily publish and so there's
another good one here using chars to
convert encoder command as well so
there's a number of different ways to go
and do it now I happen to be don't look
at all this stuff here like I was having
a bad night I wrote a crappy signature I
think I was drinking to you and programs
and émigré there's nothing gives
security but if someone becomes popular
let's write a signature annoy the author
yeah yeah anyways so anyway it's a long
time okay I call that Kaspersky to you
here yeah I'm gonna play one right here
I gotta remember this one huh still
going okay little dying breed okay yeah
sorry for the ranch risk super stuff
because your work shitty cig okay
alright alright yeah oopsie anyways yeah
so you know real stupid stuff to get
around most of these technologies lot of
cases now one of the big ones is
obviously macro injection right 20
because macros still being leveraged to
this day are absolutely crazy right
because we still need to leverage as
business processes now let's say a lot
of the technology is starting to get
better at detecting what malicious
macros look like what's interesting
about that for like malicious macros is
a good example on is they look for
certain things inside the macros
themselves like are they calling
PowerShell so let me just generate use
unicorn again will generate a macro and
so to get around them looking for
PowerShell inside of it
we just type out power shondor ends as
little what we have to do and the
attacker is like hey this don't call
power cell directly and just do ends
it's cool right and then they were
flagging out some of my my variable name
so I to randomize my variable names okay
that was hard it's actually I tell you
it gets confusing when you're writing
your own like like variable generator
because you're like what the hell does
that and that add up to you to equal
that and then this and you're like I
don't know what I just did up here and I
forgot everything so I gotta go do it
all over again so writing your own
encoder really sucks on that hard is
just a pain in the ass but here we don't
actually call encoder command either and
then this is all of our stuff let's nice
about this one is when they go to open
it what will happen is it'll say this
this document is corrupt um you know it
says you know the document appeared to
be made of an older version of Microsoft
I should say when Microsoft Office will
change that please have the Creator on
save to a new in supported format and
then it closes the office document out
like nothing happened and then it still
compromised the machine which is
fantastic right so it looks legitimate
in every way it's something that you
would want to want to go and actually
open so that's another good one another
hotness as well nice this is a really
old-school
HTA's nhts are still um used and if
you're a defender just by blocking HDA
it doesn't make a difference you can
actually um change the extension type on
an HD a and do a mime type of HD a and
still download an execute that way so
what you might actually do is on your
web content filtering block mime type of
HCA's to actually stop those but you're
not familiar HTS or like what's being
used right now by all the drive-by
chrome update you know malware and stuff
like that
what's great about it is it doesn't need
to touch disk either you can call
PowerShell commands directly from it
I think it's under wrote the code on
remember here it is so here's an HD a
example looks totally good I'm sure if
you were to seat now again as a as a
defender you know I might chunk this up
you know might you might not get this
from your detection standpoint but this
should look malicious right if you're
actually getting the length of an actual
file right this is probably not legit
and again we do stupid stuff like hey
there flagging on command at Exe okay
let's chunk up commanded exe you know
hey they're looking for W scripts okay
let's
check them Dougie scrape that show fine
no problem and it gets around no problem
you know it's ridiculous
definitely ridiculous easy stuff new
stuff and I'll show you a demo using it
all together in just a second and so on
the whole AI a machine learning thing as
long as you have users on that and
that's the biggest thing that I've seen
on you know you see a lot of these these
tools and they may be very good for a
very small organization but as it starts
to expand on the false positive ratios
are substantial on these tools and
that's that's a business killer right
and so you have different variations of
protection you have something has a very
high false positive ratio and so
basically it just goes into tech Bo and
that's all you get out of it and that's
fine if you that's good for you then you
have the other polar opposites and a
good example of this is office 365
office 365 is the exact opposite now
think about their organ Microsoft as an
organization they're one of the largest
companies in the world right from a
technology perspective and they have to
cater to every you know a geographic
location you know millions and millions
and millions of users they have to be up
all the time and the protection features
can't block normal operations of
business right so think about that that
scenario right there are they going to
have a good protection product no right
and a good example of that is a long
story so a few weeks ago I was about a
month and a half ago you know I was on
Twitter which is unusual for me right
now I think I was just getting a huge
debate on cysts yesterday so anyway
burned the internet down that day but
what was interesting about this one was
there was a guy named Jose that's a part
of CNN and Hosea was talking about how
he gets all these deets and knowing spam
emails and he always hits the
unsubscribe and that if you hit the
unsubscribe you know that'd be a great
place to deploy malware and I didn't
even see that tweet but someone
responded back and is like oh hey Dave
Kennedy uses at all time you know in his
fishes I'm you should talk to him or
whatever cuz it works really well that's
what I do like I'll know the shit
awesome but I also don't like seven or
eight emails and it ended the link that
they go through just a bullshit survey
that does no malicious code but as soon
as he unsubscribe it compromises our
computer and even they felt the server I
keep hitting them with it right until
they hit unsubscribe
slowly pisses them off and I randomized
the email to so
comes from different email addresses
even if they like move into the rules it
fucks them up each time so it's so good
love it love it human being sluggish and
so what that one specifically um you
know you know he's talking about it in
and someone responded back and someone
from Microsoft responded back and this
is you know it's not a knock of
Microsoft anyway a lot of brilliant
folks over there and I respect the heck
out of them I mean a lot of my people
that I consider like top top folks in
industry out there but one of the one
respondent from like the the sales side
of the house and said well you know
Microsoft advanced threat protection
would have prevented this from happening
and it was funny it's like like there's
certain moments in life are like God
shines a light on you and I just gotten
off a little Microsoft advanced threat
protection review like I went in and out
of the whole thing right I knew
everything about those products right
and I responded back and I'm like well
you know my experience is I was trying
to be nice you know like my experiences
I would not have have protected against
this one specific great features with it
though right you know just trying to be
nice right and the person responds back
and there's on a Friday by the way and I
let me just paint a picture okay
I have friends coming over for dinner
have the whole weekend planned out you
know everything's going to be great have
a weekend off of not having to work or
anything like that this guy responds
back and he's like oh I see we're trying
to do you're trying to rep your shit
product then I put my Batman cape on
right someone wronged me on the internet
and and so so I'm in front of my
computer like you know and and one of
our guys Dave's coming over with his
wife and in and as I skipped dinner
they're watching me too taking pictures
of me inside me I might hoodie on you
might want a keyboards on fire and so my
whole purpose of this was it was to
obviously prove that and discredit that
in every way shape or form and so what I
did at the end of releasing a lot of
analysis around Microsoft advanced
threat protection and what was
interesting with it as advanced threat
protection is broken into two different
components okay you have what's called
safe links and safe attachments safe
links is you know for web contents if
you get an email what it does and I'm
going to ask a question here in a second
if you think this is a good idea or not
what happens we need to get an email
from safe links is it rewrites the URL
to a safe link Microsoft comm with a
random
at the end of it right so let me ask a
question so a user when they hover over
it it just says Microsoft safe links and
they can't even tell what the original
URL was okay so is that a good idea
first and foremost what does that do I
mean the gratis did the whole hover
thing probably doesn't work anyway for
use as we say it does so so the whole
hover over them we lose now we teach all
of our users the hover of the links now
they can no longer do that right so
that's one thing right but but hey if
they're there their protection is
superior out there right then it should
be fine right now do we trust input so
it's so basically we're implicitly
trusting Microsoft right now do we
implicitly trust Microsoft no right okay
we're on the same page that's fantastic
okay so i desided take a look and so you
know in order for me to to move to a
cloud service right there have to be a
couple criteria on things that we have
to be met first and foremost I would
have to have the same or greater
protections or the same detection or
greater detection okay that'd be my
criteria for moving to something like
that right so safe links you know you
hover over the link it says safe links
you click on it
what would be good protection equal or
greater protection to me would be
something that actually does dynamic
content inspection on the website itself
right like like memory corruption flaws
exploit code viruses like shitty virus
is that everybody catches or like
anything right like anything all right
it would be a criteria for that right so
what I found with safe links is it
doesn't do any dynamic inspection at all
of the website or anything that you're
downloading from the website at all so
so you can download like an old-school
AOL virus that gets picked up by every
single and you know antivirus out there
or just use like a Metasploit you know
unpacked you know uh not be skated Exe
that everybody picks up because I think
it's cool to detect Metasploit and put
that up as well on your fine no problem
zero what it does is they actually have
a blacklist and whitelist for things
that they've actually seen before in the
past and they blacklist those IP
addresses so that's one piece okay so in
by the way if you get blacklisted you
can just submit the Microsoft and they
they remove you from that blacklist and
give you a higher reputation about three
hours so alright works well fantastic on
the second piece was safe attachments
which is supposed to be a competitor to
like wildfire on you know or
fireEye a lot of those other ones ready
to do a sandbox and virtualization what
was interesting about that one is first
and foremost when you get an email with
an attachment it will it's a document or
zipper whatever it takes 15 minutes to
get that document or that attachment I
repeat when you get an email and it's an
attachment to it you have to wait 15
minutes your whole business have to wait
15 minutes to get that attachment right
so is that work no right
hey CEO security right we're going to be
the over draconian folks that you know
it's going to get to give a blood sample
urine sample and 15 minutes to get your
attachment as well too so so that was an
issue I think they're fixing that which
is a good thing but what was interesting
about the safe attachments piece of it
is that it does some basic macro
identification but very basic and it
does basically Windows Defender and so
from a virtualization and sandboxing
technology wasn't very good so again I
wouldn't recommend that as a big deal
but to polar-opposite environments right
one you have you know millions of users
and over here you have something that
doesn't scale to large organizations and
so there's no middle ground when it
comes to what we're dealing with on
next-generation product lines all the
way over to you know what is the
commoditized stuff I mean we either have
Symantec McAfee or other ones that part
in the language but is shipped from it
from a detection standpoint but at least
it does like stuff on basic stuff right
or the stuff over here that doesn't
scale and if we don't have a team to
manage like seven thousand you know a
million alarms then we're asked right or
to build all the content out to reduce
the false positive so it's one opposite
or the other is what we have today in
the industry okay and so the signal
noise ratio becomes important when it
comes to detection because if we can't
take this data and look at it which is a
term called hunt teaming right every
from the term hunt teaming right going
on the hunt looking everything's if you
can't you know take a lot of that noise
away we don't have the ability to
actually go down and look at that and so
how do we uh attack without getting
detected is the biggest part about it
right I love this one right so cool I
wish I would have a picture that I might
have accident on first and foremost I'm
going after your targets is important
okay and understanding what your targets
I'm going to assume that they have good
technology we're going to build our
attack profiles very much off of off of
the the targets that we're going after
and then from there we'll prepare for
what they might have and let's just say
we you know I'm sure no one believes any
information over LinkedIn about the
technology that you have in your
environment you know whether you're a
Microsoft shop or you're an arcsight
shop or you're semantic shop that's not
in our our BIOS when it comes to who we
are what we work with then from there
we'll do an register things like a
couple good examples is kept my fish and
domain hunter if you're not familiar
with them what will happen a lot of and
a lot of times is domains will expire
and they're already categorized by web
content filtering and so what you can do
is you can just use these two tools and
you just look for which ones are
categorized or I didn't go on biome for
you know 15 bucks or ten bucks and now
you already have a high reputation site
you not to worry about from when you're
fishing from and there's great ones like
survey sites and what's great a lot of
times it will do let's just say we're
targeting a company that's mostly
business a business will actually buy a
domain name on all the business that
they would want to sell to from a
business to business perspective
register that domain clone it and now we
have a direct Avenue to the sales folks
right hey I have a million dollars in
you spend by Friday can you open up this
virus dot exe so like me to you my P oh
sure no problem Cole um singularity
whatever you want to you especially your
guarantee money in the back end of it
right and so from the social engineering
side on
I love obviously set from a social
engineering perspective but tying all
these in I have a very unique voice
sorry i fluctuate and I get excited I
apologize so from the social engineer
toolkit side leveraging things like the
HD a tech book this is a number of ones
right you can use Java applets if you
start with strand doing earlier who did
a wonderful job on that you can use you
know attached documents direct data
types you know macro injection whatever
you want to to try to get them to click
on things on HD a still work very well
I'm in a lot of cases for most companies
and so let's go and do one for social
engineering will do to the website and
will do eight the HD a track vector and
I'll do a cyclone and also call and
Trust a sec as an example and then a my
IP address which I forgot to get before
I started
and I'll she's an interpreter and so
once it doesn't cynical own the site I
use the partial injection technique and
this is the new obvious gated one by the
way so it doesn't actually call encoded
command or anything like that anymore
it's going to use the unique stream
every time it generates and all
randomized variable names and everything
else not actually called PowerShell a
lot of other ones as well
and I also implement this in everyone
that uses the PowerShell attacks like
the MS sequel brooder a lot of the other
ones in the fast-track side for
exploitation the power saw injection
techniques it all uses the new encoded
PowerShell method so let's go to open up
internet for 0 1 1 and so we go to our
site and again we register a domain name
that looks in them they get this prompt
I'm sure no one would ever click open
ever
that's the prompt that you basically get
right that's what it looks like when you
go into Internet Explorer side now when
it's done it'll redirect back to the
legitimate site here in just a second
I'm a little bit of a slow internet
connection so take a second go to
redirect back and then we have access
this is a Windows 10 with Windows
Defender fully updated everything else
right you know down here we get our show
good and instantly enough I don't know
of anything that actually picks up the
new version of unicorn especially if
you're using the charm coding the charm
coding is fantastic so you know if
you're a defender looking on the length
size is super important and so on the
PowerShell is just one method now
PowerShell is becoming a very much
saturated market right because a lot of
folks are leveraging power shots or
attack boxes you have PowerShell Empire
you have power sploit yeah you know a
lot of research is happening from the
Russian hackers that use the elite you
know persistence methods and stuff like
that so a lot of other techniques you
could leverage for getting remote code
execution on machines there's a number
of them and you're not familiar with the
guy named sub T how highly recommend
following him on Twitter
su BTE
he's like the one that's coming up with
all these different app bypasses and
what's happening is let's just say a
company does application whitelisting
very well there's still ways and
techniques of getting around application
whitelisting on but even if they're not
using application where they say this is
universally things that you can leverage
in your environment to get remote code
execution things like reg svr 32
registry or 32 is one of the most
notorious ones because it has a built in
browser that's proxy where inside of the
executable and you can download order
called SCT files to get real code
execution directly into memory and it
doesn't need to be a dot SCT extension
so if you're just blocking on des cts
that's not a good indication subkey also
came out something recently where the
format of the file if you're looking for
an indicator has changed you can use
different types to get a remote code
execution as well so you're looking at
the content of files those also shift to
so you know the best way to identify
this one would be hey why is reg STR 32
beginning out the internet that's
probably a good indication there's some
other good things you can do with like
device guard a device guard actually has
some awesome policies of locking the
system's down to not leveraging a lot of
these executable that you can do out
there so that's what the FCC file looks
like but that can change as much as you
want to this is an idea of spawning
shell but our calc here the NSA
minesweepers the one that they leverage
out you're cool or too cool for calc
currently or no pen on this one's always
one of my favorites I'm using file as
persistence that's what I've started
switching to is leveraging less on
methods for actually dropping files to
disk for persistence we're using other
methods to get persistence that don't
actually reside on disk itself I mean
you can run into a number of different
locations you know standard run areas
most people aren't looking for all of
the persistence so it's environments but
autoruns has a number of those but this
one is my favorite so this is a so
remember when we did the HT a file write
well HT a file is actually call an
executable called MS MSHDA
and in the about parameters that's
vulnerable to being able to call script
tags directly from the command line I
mean you can execute commands directly
from the command line including
underlying powershell command commands
and so what we can do here is we can
actually spray our powershell command
through multiple registry entries like
five or six and then eval then back
- in actual statements and then execute
our PowerShell command upon each boot
without getting detected so so I wrote a
tool that does that probably publish it
soon we use it internally but basically
when you go to you ever jizz it's just a
PowerShell command that leverages that
rips into multiple registry keys all you
know obvious keys time randomized keys
in different locations and then and then
whenever they reboot it just does an
eval on to that statement itself and
then actually execute that PowerShell
command to get you persistence and
having it back there on the system
itself so and what's great about that
this is not limited to length size as
well so very difficult to actually go
into text against when it comes out and
there's a number of these too by the way
so like register you're 32 to get
example persistence hooks but most
people aren't looking for MSHDA being
called on the underlying operating
system with the about command there's a
number of these by the way that are
vulnerable and I just leave alchemy
about properties as well so there's some
good ones out there that I haven't
published so it's great about that is
you have the ability to use em SDC to
execute code powershell whatever you
want to and you can control a high
content formats then execute whatever
you want to under the context that user
account that you've compromised which is
fantastic if you're not familiar image
file executions on this is also not a
great place for persistence a long time
ago what you used to have to do for
persistence methods are for like out of
the sticky keys and remember the sticky
keys piece well used to have to reboot
the machine right and then you'd have to
like mount the drive and then from there
you have to go to seek want access
windows backup system 32 backslash site
HTTP or util mended exe or a few other
ones and then what you do is you rename
that to your backdoor right and then
when your computer pops up you can hit
the shift key like five times and you
pop of a command prompt write a funny
story we find these on pen sets all the
time like like I would heavily recommend
sweeping your network looking for sticky
keys because there's a good chance that
that some admin got locked out at one
point in time and used sticky keys and
never put it back find it all the time
like there's a customer's it actually
wrote a script to go out because they
kept finding them so often in their
environment they had to actually write a
script to actually go and test for these
talk about bad process control there but
regardless whatever on this one is nice
because you don't actually have to
reboot the machine I mean you can you
can replace any executable file
protected executable file on the Windows
operating system with whatever command
with whatever executable you want to and
so you can use image prosecution to take
set HT wxe and put it in debug mode into
whatever
application you want to you without
having to worry about rebooting it sort
of places that application and you have
a persistence backdoor on the file
system itself which is nice some other
awesome fi passes for remote code
execution tracker dot exe run DLL 32
we're do 30 has been around forever you
know if you're seeing a DLL being
imported in memory and then calling up
the internet that's probably a good
indicator that something's wrong
although HP Lexmark apparently leverage
there for some reason like for some
reason printer drivers need to be
Connaught to the internet and getting
imported through run DLL 32 no idea but
probably take a look at that let me see
msbuild idat picking up the Internet
another good indication that you're
probably compromised their own reg str
32 CBD there's so many more matthew
graver actually has a so subti the guy
you want to file for that by matthew
graver at manifestation on twitter on
he's got a he look at his github repo
he's got a great device guard policy
that you can leverage that actually has
all of these executables you actually
want to monitor for in your environment
that list them all out so those are some
attack techniques right how do we
actually go about detecting some of this
stuff because that's that that's the
problem that we're added to this
industry you know you you know maybe as
an attacker i'm really good at
understanding attack but i'm usually not
in the company that's also building
defense as well and so that's the that's
the big gap we have we have we have red
and we have blue and then there's this
big gap of knowledge in between the
blues blue people are awesome they
defend like no one no one else's
business but they don't understand the
attacker side the attacker side can
attack like no one else's business but
easy to understand and defensive side
and so what ends up happening is you
have a team that focuses on something
like carbon black or watchlist or things
like that and they only know what they
know they don't understand the patterns
of behavior the admiral pounds are
behavior that goes through and what it
takes to actually build allowed this
detection criterion and so we'll talk
about that so we talk about actual
layers for security program there's
three that are my favorite on that that
when we go into a company you know stop
us or at least trick us up to where we
get it detected and there's a there's a
good debate happening is probably about
a year ago or so between jeremiah
Grossman and egypt i think i've
mentioned this before
a jeremiah was saying hey it only takes
one vulnerability to get access to a
company right it's true right you find
one vulnerability exploit you get access
ransom then you move laterally across
the network but what egypt said was it
only takes
one indicator of compromise to detect
that actual attack existed and that's
the whole goal right can you you know
let's just say we're using some awesome
shit on the desktop and then from there
you know we start doing some crazy stuff
and you left us in your protection or
your detection but you hit us in some
certain stages along the way around post
exploitation that's a good way of
detecting us and it'll talk about the
session too and so you know method the
detection become very difficult when it
comes to specific types of patterns of
attack and new research coming on
everyday not to mention things like the
the unknowns and so let's take a look at
the NSA stuff what was nice about that
one is you know you know this doesn't
happen every day but we're going to use
this for the next five years you know
we're gonna be talking about the NSA and
wanna cry even though wanna cry barely
impacted us the United States but yet we
got budget and people are talking about
our CEO scheme now like what we're okay
you know you know so we have all the
stuff here that will leverage from a PR
perspective remote remote for a very
long time but if you look at at the
techniques that eternal blue and double
pollster leverage you know those are
things that we probably would not have
detected as it happened right you're all
in memory you know basically a skeleton
skeleton key things like like Emmett and
Microsoft's protection mechanisms didn't
help us is designed to get around that
right and so you know when you look at
that specific exploit model it's been
poured its intent to Windows 10 Windows
8 server 2012 r2 so affected impacted
every version of Windows so in that
specific case if we didn't detect on on
eternal blue or double pole star which
is you know highly sophisticated you
know a 15 0 day the equation group you
know going in and attacking we didn't
detect that could we have detected them
in other phases of the attack if you
look at the techniques that the NSA
leveraged what did they do once they
compromised the system I mean oh look at
the dumps what they do they move to
other systems in thing until they got
access to the Swift network that they
were going after or other systems that
they needed access to that one entry
point was the way into their environment
and you see that by the way commonly
between Russia between China between
everybody else that's the the actors out
there right
they'll compromise somebody in some way
shape or form through phishing or other
techniques and then from there they move
out to the systems they need access to
so if we couldn't have detected eternal
blue or double pole star could we have
detected other ways of getting access
into their environment and so
you look at that on things like like
lateral movements you know eventlog
46:24 login type 3 from same source IP
address to multiple destination that's
probably good indication that there's
something amiss on your network that's
abnormal in some way shape or form and
so what we can do is focus on unknown
good first so application whitelisting
and then from there start to build out
some of our detection criteria I'll talk
about some of that the fact that
ransomware is a problem is still a
problem like how does ransomware
infected machine how does it affect the
machine well email phishing but what
actually happens when they open up a PDF
or Excel document what's what's the code
execution piece encrypts files and how
does it in crypt piles like what's the
code that actually runs that ok so so if
I open up an excel document and it has
macros in there right and I hit an able
on the macros because I'm an awesome
user and I'm not that's lower Todd I'm
come on it's a design feature here I'm
an awesome user hit enable what what
what happens at that point in time
usually a macro will go out and probably
go and download additional code right I
can executable right or PowerShell right
what does that power show you to do goes
in albums in executable you look at most
malware samples that are out there for
ransomware is still downloading an
executable now what's the problem with
an executable it's the same battle we've
been fighting since the 90s right the
fact that we're still allowing unsigned
code non-code sign non co-signed
executables in our environments
especially in our downloads directories
our temp directories from our users is
the reason why I'm in this situation
today you take that away you take about
90% of the infections that we see today
out of the window right PowerShell is
morphing into that yes I'd rather us be
focusing on detecting PowerShell but we
still don't even have basic exe s taken
care of so using something like software
restriction policies app Locker or
device guard or something like that to
say hey I'm only going I'm going to
block all non code signing service maybe
put a couple exceptions we have some
shitty developers you know other than
that it should be pretty straightforward
right that's an easy one that's you need
you want to reduce a lot of the noise so
if that fails let's talk about detection
it's my favorite I use that in everyone
matter what presentation I do I have it
baked in somewhere and so we look at
that you know we have a number of
different detection areas now hopefully
you're familiar with system on this mine
is a free tool for Microsoft and it
installs as in agents now the first
thing I love going into a customer with
in being an MSSP company if first we
asked them is like okay hey you have a
sim that's great you know like yeah we
spent you know two million dollars on
it's fantastic it's awesome it does
everything like cool cool like what kind
of logs you getting for me oh we got our
fire well logs you know we got this we
got that we got our domain controllers
and like okay what about your server
logs like oh no no we're not forwarding
those we got a domain controllers we're
good down Mike okay what about your end
points no no no that's an f1 to mint too
much there's too expensive to get all
the end points going in there Mike okay
okay so when it comes to detection you
need your servers and you need your
endpoints all right can we all agree to
that yes you need your servers you need
your endpoints right so you take those
two and that gives you a whole bunch of
clarity that you never had before this
montt helps with that um there's a
number of things that you can detect
with this mod you know image load is a
good example image load event event ID 7
and and so that has dll's that are being
loaded it has network communications it
has you know service hooks persistence
hooks you name it it's all in one tool
that you can leverage for your detection
what's nice about this is free now we
learned this the hard way but if you're
using system on 60.1 it conflicts with
with antivirus and it blue screens
apparently so you don't want to do it
with 6:01 but they came out so what
happened was is that a-- confliction
antivirus at a confliction with image
load and so in crash surveillance a
while but they fix that in 602 by
breaking image flow completely but
what's great is they fixed it with 6:03
now and it doesn't blue screen and image
load now works so we're going now with
six out of three fantastic it's stable
it works fine
I hope and then you do a lot of cool
stuff of that a couple good examples me
me cast detection me me cat is actually
really difficult to actually detect on
because it's all memory on though you
can detect on the process injection
piece but the way that actually does it
is very very tricky um it will import
bulk lie that DLL so if you see Valk lie
that DLL being imported by a from an
image load from anything like commanded
exe power shot idea key or anything
outside of your system 32 or program
files directory is probably good
indication that Mimi has in your
environments but you can do things like
detect process injection a number of
other things out there which is really
easy to go and do that's your system on
what's fantastic is there's a great
resource out there from Swift on
security certain security started a
public config for for system on that you
can go and download and already has the
community support so we're adding things
to at all time on new detection criteria
that you can leverage within system on
to get the log that you need to
everything from like app bypasses and
whitelist and stuff like that so it's
really nice and they could also do
things like with with this mod you can
do things like detecting non PowerShell
so if you see system to automation 8i
DLL assistance automation IDL being
called from non partial processes and by
the way we talked about detection on
PowerShell there's two directories you
have to monitor for everybody knows that
right you have C colon backslash Windows
backslash six while 64 backslash
Microsoft power saw or Windows
PowerShell
backslash version window and C colon
backslash Windows back that systems into
backslash Power Cell when our Windows
PowerShell backslash version of one that
one at oh those are through directory at
the monitor since while 64 city to 32
bit compatibility which most attackers
use like things like PowerShell Empire
unicorn will call sis wall 64 for native
32-bit shell code injection and then you
have your normal system 32 directory
that has the the partial stuff fence you
want to look at both of those but if you
see partial being called by those two
specific areas it's aa really good
indication and something to miss some of
the good ones pass the hash detection if
you see if NID 4624 login type 3 key
length of 0 which means no encryption
low-level protocol like SMB RPC you're
going to see you know that kind of
happens so that's a good one but this is
also the same type of detection criteria
can leverage your lateral movement why
you know and you may have valid reasons
for lateral movement in your environment
you want to baseline those and you know
whitelist those eventually but you see a
vet ID from a local machine from 46 24
to login type 3 you know key length 0
etc etc those are all things that you
actually want to take take into account
the truth of the matter is though that
that detection becomes hard work now
what happens if your protection fails
and your detection fails what do you
have at that point
the breach right but it doesn't need to
be that way those other things there's
another line of defense you can place
and put into place that I really love
and this is one of my favorites because
it actually screwed me up and I'm one of
the ones that helps will help right this
one so when when all else fails you
always have deception okay and deception
is there is your last line of defense of
something that you can build in your
environment to make things look super
baller for an attacker to go after
that's your last line of tripping a good
example of that is we have something
built into our vision product a binder
defense we have a deception a whole
bunch of deception stuff and when we're
coming up with the whole deception
modules we have this thing called honey
tokens and we spray them into memory and
so what happens is like you know like it
looks like a domain admin account was
the great password and when a user goes
to leverage that or an attacker goes to
leverage that it creates a no-shit alarm
right you know someone's in your
environment right no no why I was on a
pen test recently and I had my windows
10 machine up which happen to have
vision installed on it and I happened to
see an LLM in our broadcast local link
multicast name resolution net bells name
services all happen and it was named
like you know like blah blah blah blah -
da I'm like oh that looks like a badass
account so I started cracking it I go in
I crack and I go and I using it doesn't
work am i quick - that's vision I didn't
even realize I'm going to put the count
up there like I said at the Charles I'm
like Charles this is a count that I that
I think would look awesome in there and
it got me like I'm like like a complete
idiot when we did it but there's cool
things you can leverage then I'll talk
about some of those today but it's one
of my favorite techniques by far because
if you make it look believable enough
and you make enough of them it's a good
chance that someone's going to jack up
and you're going to get them on the
latter stages of an attack and hopefully
stop you and so building multiple
detection techniques upon each phase of
the attacks on you know really creates a
whole different level of the texture
fear that you've never seen before on
and hopefully you don't have to until it
gets to that point what was cool is that
the during the election cycle during the
Paris elections they actually created a
whole deception wing for the
administration because it got heads up
that the Russians were going in trying
to hack in information to expose it and
so they actually put a whole bunch of
misinformation out there fake email
accounts fake infrastructure fake
everything and it works the Russians
went after it and then publish all this
bogus data that made no sense whatsoever
because they went through the fake fake
infrastructure so it works in there's so
many phases you can apply um you know
deception so you can do everything from
intelligence gathering you know putting
misinformation out there as far as what
technology leverage and LinkedIn
profiles fake email addresses to go
after you know fake infrastructures have
sequel injection a bunch of other stuff
out there I mean who know you need the
sky's the limit as far as your deception
how crazy you want to get to it but I
believe that you know as a industry we
should have dedicated people just to
deception in our environment like it
should be an actual full fledge like hey
that sounds cool like James Bond is like
hey what are you I'm director of
deception you know sounds pretty awesome
it sounds like mi6 mi5 you know type
type stuff and so some of these you can
do fake email boxes to expose email a
CEOs email address throw segmented
devices in the perimeter with c.coli on
it you know a lot of cool things you can
do but you can start with the basics
first you know doing minor things like
like creating you know with Windows
Firewall you can actually create allows
in that even though of course not open
and look for those connection types so
create low mid high subset port ranges
and look for those logs and you can see
if someone's ports sweeping your
environment your network another thing
you could do just that the Jack me up as
an attacker I wrote a tool called a
tiller II which creates honey fights a
hot big honeypot right what you can do
is use unused IP addresses in your
environment like I'm sure no one's using
all their ipv4 IP addresses or if you
are not using every single port so you
can do is net you know your unused IP
address to the unused ports to one box
on the internet that has all these ports
open and when someone goes the ports can
you across your ranges what does that do
create a shitstorm right I know you
what's going on like what it was what
the hell's going on equals open over
here sequel so going over here at net
files open over here I don't know what
to do right um so you create a shitstorm
for for folks on that side
honey Doc's are great a couple good
things is there's there's an awesome
tool by a group that wrote this is one
of my favorites it just got recently
open source which is fantastic on the
CIA had a leak called vault seven and so
now it's open source which is great but
it was there's a program there called
scribbles and what scribbles would do is
it would allow you to use watermarks to
beacon out and what you can do is create
things like password XLS or domain name
and passwords and network passes put
them everywhere right and as soon as
somebody opens it a beak that was a
watermark in there that actually beacons
out and sends you a notification
that someone was opening this document
out there so you can create these
documents inside of your environment
hopefully to get some detection now
here's my favorite one okay by far the
one where you get the most visibility
into right here so if you take anything
out of this from a defensive perspective
and I'm the deception inside use this
one as well as the next time I show
bends so this is from fuzzy security and
this is called in Boca run as and so
what I would do as a defender is I would
I would make this domain admin account I
create a domain name account it looks
just so badass it's unbelievable right
like he's part of every single group you
know enterprise admin domain admin you
know you know put it server
administrators whatever you want to put
everybody in there like it looks like
it's a kludge of permissions maybe put
in description like this is an old
mainframe account we need to
decommission this the password is really
weak as five characters right make it
look like the sexiest account ever that
you can possibly imagine right and make
that pass for like seven hundred
characters lock it in a safe and leave
with Erics you don't need to use it
again another way you can do with invoke
run ads is on a login script it's a
PowerShell command on a login script
what it does is it uses an API it's a
login Charles what's the API you're
paying attention you son of them so on
this there's a log log in process W I
think as the API that's leveraged for
this one and what it does is it caches
the credentials locally in memory and
why that's important is every promote
the tool called me me cats right now
additionally me me cats is in Windows 8
1 and server or Windows 10 the the clear
text password stuff in memory has been
fixed right oh it's great with the new
version and me me cats actually extract
the ntlm hash out of memory regardless
if it's fixed or not right oh it's just
the registry key if you do for a 0 to 1
on a registry key it'll actually start
logging the clear text passed as a
memory again which is fantastic but
regardless
put this as a as a login script for all
of our users every single one of your
users and what happens when they log in
you put that domain admin account in
there with the domain right and you give
it like a 5 or 6 character password
right and so if someone uses me me
casting your environment and you're not
detecting any of this you see that clear
text password a memory they go to use it
what happens fail logging it down right
today there ever be a failed login
attempt on that account hell no right so
you need to take that computer burn it
you know take the ashes and bury it and
then burn it again just in case right
because that machine's been calm for
our summits with the nasty on it right
so that's a great one that gets gets
attackers up and by to make that pass or
look look crap you like mainframe 2006
you know whatever you want to make it so
that the attacker believes that this is
real right things that would actually go
after and one thing that I will do as an
attacker is that will drop into a shell
and confirm that that accounts actually
real right now actually make sure that
that accounts active and leverage so you
could do things to make it more
believable again deceptions its own
industry there's another good one out of
Luminara NBN s broadcasts been who's
gonna be speaking next hopefully is
sending to his talk on Ben wrote honey
cranville Connie creds which will send a
lemon are an NBN s queries across your
network he's not familiar with that
welcome link multi yeah local link
multicast name resolution and net bells
name services I get the acronyms right
they you know a little happen is when
you log in your computer it'll say hey
where's file share one and it could be
for mapping drives or getting group
policy or whatnot and as an attacker you
can use a tool called responder and Bey
and say okay yeah I'm files to everyone
come on connect to me and it connecting
passes that net NCM v1 or v2 hashes
depending on group policy to that attack
on they can crack it offline so this
will send fake credentials across the
network and you can look for failed
login attempts but you can also do to
which been figured out on is if you put
a fake computer name fake username and
fake password should that fake user name
fake domain think everything else ever
be used to log in to a remote computer
know right it's fake right it's not real
so if you see an event ID there's an
event of a gets enter in the camera
which one is hopefully been talked about
it
46:48 happens over there 46:48 which is
explicit credentials are used to log
into the remote system should that ever
you should you ever see that have been
ID with that specific user account know
so a good indication that LLM in are are
or inve responders on your network
something good stuff using local admin
accounts create a local admin account is
specifically not used by any business
process whatsoever across your
environment and employ laughs with it so
if your automated laughs its Microsoft's
free tool is also one that we wrote at
open source called ships it randomizes
all the local admin pastors across the
board should you ever see any failed
login steps or even any successful login
attempts from those two user accounts
absolutely not right so good indications
right there as well to be able to
identify and yes you are creating a
local administrator
there's already going to be a local
minister on there not using in the past
as random so risk problem building a
very low exposure overall but roots the
matter is with these three areas the
protection right we have a decent
protection we feel we have a decent
level detection but if all else fails
you have that whole deception piece of
it now as attackers you know we are
crafty we will continuously find new
ways around new piece of technology as
an attacker myself I don't see a lot of
detection occurring on the types of
attacks that we leverage but again I
feel like the industry itself is getting
better so it's gonna be a matter of time
we have to continuously step up our game
but with these creates have techniques I
really have to raise my level raise my
bar to make things work a lot better if
that for the do thank you thank you
anybody any questions I can take one or
two questions real fast heard yeah here
yeah here no yes no users no yeah good
okay thank you here coming
you