all right so I'm already starting a
little late on I apologize because I can
never follow anybody that's that good of
a speaker it's not going to be nearly as
entertaining I have to warn you up front
the first time I'm giving this talk and
called cyber cyber cyber using the kill
chain to actually accomplish something
by show of hands how many of you have
heard of the cyber the cyber or
intrusion kill chain by Lockheed Martin
hi Dave right how many of you know what
all seven steps are yeah right
how many of you actually use it in your
day to day job where you apply it at
some point this is not very many of you
so a lot of our customers so some of the
stuff I do is a lot of defense work with
spunk and our customers a lot of our
customers want to use that cyber kill
chain to create monitoring alerts around
those seven steps and I was tired of
just guessing there's like The MITRE the
genre talking earlier about The MITRE
framework which is great to kind of
break things up into and there's other
people that break threats down into
different categories but I haven't seen
any yet that break it down into all
seven kill chain steps so my idea was I
would break down not only what happens
for those threats at all seven steps but
also what defensive mitigations you can
provide at all seven steps and what
alerting and monitoring that you can do
as well at all seven and you know
depending on the threat there's going to
be multiple at different steps sometimes
there's none at all that you can
actually prevent and we'll go over some
of that right now see if I can figure
this out this is actually the part of
the slide deck that I'm the most happy
about because I'm really really bad with
anything design related
let's see why actually looks fairly
decent so in tears and kill chains
broken up in the seventh step first step
is recon so when they duo sent right
they're going out there grabbing email
addresses from dumps they're trying to
find relationships based on you know
who's the CEO or who works in marketing
who actually has access to wire
transfers the attackers going out and
trying to find what what technologies
you use so if you're on your LinkedIn
profile and you say you know you've
implemented f5 and Barracuda filtering
or you know you have this DDoS
protection or this antivirus you're
listing all of those specific
technologies in your LinkedIn profile
they're also using those to build a full
file based on you know your company are
you specifically so they can be more
targeted text number two is
weaponization see I made that where it
goes on one image now it's broken up
into seven so it's the automation of
some type of type of tool they do you
know remote access Trojans anything like
that that's the tool that they're
building in their basement or or
wherever that you don't have any view
into yet you know they're doing that all
on their own just like with the ocean
you can't really see them doing the
ocean for the most part so step two also
is something that's completely out of
out of your hands number three is
delivery so that's the transit ah the
transmission of the weapon sending it
over email phishing that kind of stuff
drive-by downloads USB there's
exploitation which is step four that's
when the payload is delivered and
they're actually exploiting the Box the
code triggers and you know they're
actively running something on the inside
of your network or outside on something
that you can hold
installation allows them to maintain
persistence in your environment for all
that stuff they're going to do later on
command control it's when they that
thing that they installed is going to
talk back to them it's going to be Canal
it's going to be so they don't have to
individually attack one device it's
going to be you know centralized
management for the bad guys and then
last up is action and objectives and
that's the end that's that's our end
goal
they're either stealing your information
selling your information so data
exfiltration they're trying to get rid
of it they're going to wipe your boxes
they're going to do whatever they can as
whatever their end goal was maybe
they've set up like a jump box or a
botnet or to you know access other boxes
in your network whatever number seven
angle so that being said those are the
seven steps what I wanted to do was
break them in up into common threats
right so what are you guys can shell I
like inactive out of active
participation what are some of the most
common threats that you worry about if
your defender day-to-day ransomware how
does the kill chain effect ransomware
yes that's what this whole talks about
we're going to do ransomware so
ransomware data exfiltration DDoS web
app attacks all that kind of stuff but
defenders are worried about day to day I
wanted to break up into the seven steps
to the kill chain make it a little bit
easier to to give you actionable steps
to take right you're not just saying
okay I know I need a firewall I know I
need endpoint protection and I need this
and this and this you can actually break
it down to okay we know we're worried
about ransomware ransomware
over the last four years has gone from I
think was like the 80th 88 or 89 most
popular threat to number four over the
last three four years so it's everywhere
you know there's there's several books
out now about how to comment ransomware
and about ransomware itself and people
are seeing it all over the place and not
just what that kind of stuff if you
I know people kind of razz on the
Verizon Dvir but they do have a lot of
good overall information they're
basically telling us everything we
already know but they broke it down into
nine different things that we should be
worried about or that people are
continuing to be worried about one of
those was ransomware or other crime
where right haha Siberia cyber espionage
is on there denial of service which is
mostly large enterprises they said
ninety percent is towards large
enterprises things like payment card
skimmers pay point-of-sale intrusions
and everything else errors and like the
one that took down Amazon so we're going
to break it down the de militia faction
defensive mitigation and monitoring
alerting and not only should we worry
about defending against each action
we'll also cover a little bit of IR and
testing improve the concept as well hey
ransomware
what everybody is usually worried about
it gets brought up all the time at work
you know it's really hard if you don't
already have a handle on your defensive
infrastructure to prevent ransomware
it's very prevalent in in companies that
don't really have a security program and
are kind of just winging it I've talked
to people that have you know a dozen two
dozen incidents a year which to me is
insane and I know it depends on the
amount of endpoints you have but really
that's a lot of ransomware to deal with
especially if you don't have backups if
you don't have
me any idea what was on that box at any
point in time you know maybe it actually
contained sense of information and a lot
of the times they don't have a plan
so right on of them so before a lot of
people think that the first two steps
reconnaissance and weaponization does
not really think anything you can do as
a defender I think there is usually in
those first two steps for a lot of
attacks it's the same kind of stuff most
of the time it's fishing right you know
fishing always works they're always
going to use it as an attack vector but
there's a lot of things that you can do
to not only prevent it but kind of alert
on it as well kind of give you you know
a step up you want to use each step it's
kind of like a funnel right so other
than you know the rare case where you
have a zero trust network like beyond
Corps most everybody is still in the
network model where you have a VPN you
have a firewall you're segmenting you're
supposed to have all of the stuff a
segmentation and all that you're going
to want to work from the outside in
right because that's that's where you're
going to be attacked at the most and you
want to funnel that down so you worry
about less as you get closer to the
inside of your sort
so the militia faction in this case is
the attacker obtains your email
addresses technologies use like we
talked about before all of Osen and they
can build custom phishing campaigns you
know they know Allison accounting works
with this technology and you know maybe
she's put on social media that she works
in the same office with this other
person who may may be out of vacation or
something all that information can be
used in that specific targeted phishing
attack helps it help them get a little
bit further each time and
there's stuff you can do to prevent that
kind of stuff so it's not I don't really
I guess consider this defensive
mitigation it's more like a proactive
measure to do some of this stuff but
policies and procedures such so bad
teaching users that it's not okay to
list specific technologies have your
email address out there is going to
happen obviously but creating policies
and procedures around that kind of gives
you a little bit of more say you know
when when somebody's out blasting you
know on Twitter about what they're doing
day to day or taking screenshots so
their desktop or whatever it gives you
something to fall back on something like
this would happen and then for
monitoring alerting I like this idea
look at the database dumps that are out
there I have I know somebody that has
our own up stack with all of the past
like four or five years of database
dumps that you can look up like
star-delta calm and it'll say oh $500
calm employees either had their box
account leaked or Dropbox Ashley Madison
LinkedIn you name it all those the
database on so if they're using their
corporate email addresses for this stuff
you know they're probably using their
corporate password for it as well if you
can find that information out there
that's that's very useful for you you
can make sure those users have a little
bit more training their passwords might
change a little bit more often make sure
they're not using the ones that they
were using to cheat on their selves but
that that's kind of a proactive measure
that you can take in that case for step
one another thing you can do
is say you run your corporate website
put out there like a honey account so in
in the same background font as whatever
your website is you know say it's all
all black background file all black
background with white fun in black put a
account that you're going to monitor to
that email address form that's the only
place that you put it and if an attacker
is scraping the website and Linkedin
which you can do in like five seconds
with like the harvester or set or
whatever it will go out and scrape all
these websites looking for these email
addresses when you get email addresses
email to that address you know they will
have had to scrape that site to get that
email on business send you stuff right
so that's that's information that you
can use as well so now we're on to
delivery melissa faction like i said for
the most parts always fishing it's going
to be targeted based on the o since i
used we could just see a a mass email as
well those are pretty common there's a
lot a lot of defensive steps that you
can take for step to the first one is
block attachment types that are
definitely malicious that you probably
don't need not only block them at
whatever email gateway is but you can
also in group policy and we'll talk
about that a little bit later kind of
disable that kind of stuff so like jsj
fews fht a vb scripts all that in itself
is a list of like a dozen or so file
types that you can just completely block
at the perimeter okay every now and then
maybe somebody's trying to send you a
legitimate javascript file probably
going to be rare right for the most part
those are going to be exploits trying to
get in the phishing attempt in in those
rare cases have them zip it and password
protected that way they know what
exactly they're gay
they know who is coming from mechanism
number two you can scan on office
documents for macros use black lists or
gray lists like spam house DNS SPL a lot
of people don't take advantage of the
free blacklist and grey lists that are
out there too if they handle their own
mail filtering or just move to Google
Mail because they seem to handle all
that stuff really well proper user
education so if they get that JavaScript
file are they going to report it a lot
of people you know also think the user
education is worthless but honestly if
it's done right after you've already put
out all of your fires and patched your
boxes and you can't RDP in from the
internet user education is going to be
where they go to next because if an
attacker can go straight into your
network why even bother with a user who
might report you they're just going to
go straight in but eventually you do
want to have you know customized user
education for your environment and
that's the kind of stuff that you want
to you know instill in them is trust but
verify if it's an attachment they should
know that they're expecting an
attachment I'm sure you all heard before
you know teaching them just to report on
stuff is what I always try and talk
about right there you know hundred
different pairs of eyes hundred thousand
to prepare size depending on the
organization size that can work just as
well as any IDs for stuff with the IDS
isn't going to find if that email gets
through and doesn't get flagged on any
rule and it seems weird to them they
should have an easy as an avenue to
report that to if they don't feel
comfortable talking to you or your
helpdesk there
they might delete it sure or they might
click on it just if they're curious but
if they're aware of that something
that's happening you want them to feel
comfortable reporting it to you
implement ad blocking all browsers
install extensions across the Lord
that's always helpful for drive-by
downloads and stuff and for monitoring
and alerting on that flag screen server
files and JavaScript files over 22 and
15 Meg should never have those anyways
if your blocking them then you don't
really have to worry about it but you
can still flag them in Outlook or group
policy or whatever to to kind of end
point solution whatever you're using to
alert you if they end up on a box
somehow because they should never be
about that you know what's your
developer accreting screensavers for a
living and then we move on to
exploitation which is step 3 haha
everybody's favorite software this
malicious action is when they download a
JavaScript file or word with a macro
enabled that's an exploit code in it
[Music]
that's usually what happens in
ransomware cases right and for defensive
mitigation that all of this is showing
and it's probably hard to read anyways
but this is true policy for all of you
that are window admins you can disable
all of those file types that I mentioned
in your policy have them open with word
or notepad or whatever they're not going
to actually execute a JavaScript file if
it's a none user Power Cell files
whatever have it so the default program
is notepad it's more than likely only
going to hurt a couple people and great
thing about your policy is you can
restrict it so hey admins over here or
programs over here can still run that
shit on wherever they want and everybody
else is going to be you know kept from
doing it
endpoint protection a lot of people also
scoff at antivirus not only do some
regulations
and standards require you to have
antivirus it still going to stop a
baseline of just crap that's out there
on the Internet right
they have signatures for a reason
they're still doing active stuff with I
mean somebody wants to get in they're
going to get in and I've have antivirus
but for the most part automated stuff is
some stuff and other endpoint things
like carbon black what-have-you and then
for monitoring or dings you can monitor
proxy logs for unexpected file retrieval
this is kind of after the fact I don't
know that they have anything in line but
this is I think this is part of slaw
which will be obfuscated common strings
from melt from ransomware and you can
also block an alert on those depends on
if you do your own now we're reversal
that kind of stuff you can you know have
a have a list of ones that are already
known for common ransom like that's out
there and on to step forwards
installations the malicious action is
the payload executed on the end-users
device keep in mind things like was it
lucky server crypto wall and a couple
others all use the built-in Windows
crypto API so that's something that you
can keep an eye on that we'll talk about
in a second that's what's actually
encrypting the file of course I mean if
you're worried about ransomware you have
to backup right I mean that's that's the
one major defense of litigation that you
could possibly do for ransomware so make
sure you have not not only that you're
sure that you're backing up when you're
sure that that you can you're able to
restore from those backups I've been in
several places where yeah sure we backup
everything and then they covering
somewhere and it's either corrupt or not
accessible or whatever but testing your
backups is definitely very important you
can be file for some firewalls a little
softer
is one that I recommend that's pretty
good
Windows Firewall you can block things on
per process ASIS there's some
experimental endpoint stuff that can
actually block ransomware I've never
actually played it with played with
itself I have a note down here that the
kryptonite's an example of it and the
number four have a portion of your ir
procedure set aside to what you actually
do if ransom what happens I guess it's
not I don't know that it's really
considered a mitigation or not but if
you have a piece of ransomware come in
and you don't have a backup but you know
that there's somebody actively maybe
somebody's actually on your network
along with that ransomware you want to
know how far you should go in that case
every time you know maybe you categorize
your machines you could say across the
board all in endpoints sorry you should
have saved your shit up of the cloud you
should have saved it on a file server if
you had something on your desktop sorry
around a lot that stuff should be not
only built into your IR program it
should be also in other policies and
procedures that are written let's see
here oh and if if you don't have a fly
hour theft some people only have one or
two people handling their entire
security program you have other stuff to
do right you can't be sitting there
reversing malware trying to figure out
where it came from you can stop it next
time maybe you have enough money that
you can call on a professional and they
can do your on our maybe you ship out
your IR to a third party you don't want
to wait until five o'clock on a Friday
when you get ransomware and you're like
I'm going home for the day you can call
selling so and you don't have any kind
of relationship with them you're now
paying you know thousand dollars an hour
or whatever their rate is because
they've never heard of you you don't
have a contract in place that's the kind
of relationship that you kind of want to
get
forehand before any of this happens then
you don't have to worry about you know
spending way more money than you need to
for an emergency case situation and
here's monitoring and learning for this
step
like I said it uses a lot of them use
the windows crypto API you can monitor
for spikes in encryption like it should
be you know encrypting a million files a
minute on a normal user system you can
alert on that kind of stuff and another
thing that kind of doesn't really have
to do with the defenses that I talked
about before you can also monitor on our
outgoing domain so you're in the run up
you know collect DNS advance the u.s.
logging that have inordinate amount of
numbers most domains don't have you know
a random number string in them that
usually assure shots first sign of
malware some kind of ransomware
beginning out to plug in an X domains or
something and step number six its
command and control and right here in
the malicious action is contacting a CNC
server to do the key exchange after the
decryption key to be sent to them and
defense the mitigation for this as DNS
tinkles and autoblock outbound crap
right there's a lot of different sites
that will allow you to and most of them
let her know I think half of them are
probably paid but there's no sand has a
list of stuff that you can use for D in
a sinkhole and just outright blocking
this is where you can use you know
actually you threat Intel right block
clock all that shit at the firewall you
don't want to alert on him
yeah this is I think I took this from
sake whole list of known CNC servers
that they have to have this might not be
Samm malware domain.com maybe I don't
know I made these like tuning oh yeah
you can use all of those lists to pull
in and just be in a sinkhole they go
directly to a different DNS server and
they're not going outbound you can also
block not everybody has to get to the
internet you know you shouldn't be
browsing the Internet's and servers that
kind of stuff shouldn't be allowed
through your proxy there's only a
certain amount of people an amount of
devices in the in the infrastructure
that should be allowed outbound and
number seven is actions and objectives
so the last one and here's the Mauritius
action for this one they're pretty much
done they started to delete your volume
shot volume shadow copies if you have
those turned on in a Windows environment
try to delete any other backups that
might be connected and they start
encrypting all the stuff on your harder
this is one of my favorite things to
recommend is implement honey directories
so by this point it sucks it's already
started to encrypt stuff your point here
you know your your goal at this point is
to stop it from going any further
anybody else clicking on it you no need
to focus on whatever the first device
was you take your IR from there whatever
your IR procedures are but a hunting
directory is say for example you create
a C colon slash dollar sign dollar sign
there's a because I think it's
PowerShell script that will do recursive
dollar sign dollar sign directories
until the windows maximum file names
like and that ransomware is going to
continually just try and
go through each one of those over and
over and over and over again and you can
alert on that it's not it's already
started to you know effectively
ransomware the system and encrypt stuff
but you might be able to get on top of
it depending on how much data is on the
computer a lot of times ransomware will
go either by file file size or by name
alphabetically but most of the time it
will hit the dollar signs first the
reason why things like your recycle bin
gets encrypted before anything else so
the LS and recycle bin and for
monitoring alerting can you tell where
all of the files start as you get
encrypted so this is a font graph that's
actually looking for looking over the
advanced file auditing files
long sorry and you're not going to the
normal user others I mean every now and
then they'll like install a program and
there'll be a little blip right but
you're not going to see masked file
changes over the systems continuously
unless something like this is happening
or even if it is the random anomaly
probably something you want to check out
anyways also testing improve a concept
it's something that I struggle with
sometimes just because it's hard to sit
people down and run through a lot of
this nobody wants to program somewhere
on their network right there's other
ways that you can mimic it unless you
have a full test environment which I'd
love to find people or customers that
actually have a full test environments
that you could do this kind of stuff in
but not everybody is just going to want
to stick around somewhere in their
network so they can test out all these
defenses but if you have them all broken
up into the different levels and you
know
what it's supposed to look like you can
write a Python script to you know modify
a million files at a time you will
create write read whatever modified and
you're going to see the same kind of
stuff you just want to make sure you're
alerting is working and the defense of
mitigations that you put in the place
are actually you know make sure that IDs
will actually work so you think it does
don't just blindly put it in place and
hope that it's going to work when you
actually do it man somewhere and I don't
expect you to read this I just kind of
wanted to give you an overview of what I
plan on all of you to look at at the end
ransomware is the one I have done the
most of on so far next up I'm going to
do data exfiltration privilege misuse
insider threats a whole bunch of other
ones just to kind of put them out there
to give people ideas or at least a
framework to to go on this one I'll put
out there now but the rest of them won't
be until October because that's what I
actually have a training on it and
that's probably when I'll finish it and
that's me and all myself so a little bit
shorter than I wanted it to be quite gay
it's been ready have any questions or
comments or pointing out that in long
anywhere go home yeah yep I'll go ahead
and put these up on my blog um and then
as I add more to them I'll go and pick
them out there they're just in a Google
Doc right now so yep and if you have any
ideas of stuff that I can work on as
well no matter what level it goes that I
can just stick it in the spreadsheet or
you know I'm trying to be almost too
agnostic we're not you know specifying
any specific tools samosas
anything but out there that does it but
that's the whole idea dude Thanks
[Applause]