when we get started so this talk is
decentralisation for security and
freedom discussion of asymmetric and
decentralized technologies right and
what we're going to do is we're going to
go through for some introductions for us
we're going to kind of problematize like
identify the problem that were trying to
deal with here talk about how some of
the approaches that we use in
information security in a professional
context right so like in the industry
context probably aren't specifically
suited for this specific problem set and
propose a philosophical or conceptual
approach a kind of framework for
thinking through how we can actually
start to contribute to solutions to this
kind of a problem right and then of
course we're going to do the obligatory
tool drop right we like wrote a script
that's prepped for baby and approach to
this and Link it up target but yeah so
my name is Tom I'm from a group called
the digital freedom initiative we're a
local organization in Cleveland
affiliated with the Electronic Frontier
Foundation where we've been handing out
flyers for crypto parties and stuff all
day but yeah we're sort of a new
organization this kind of our first big
public thing a little bit about myself I
am a rogue former philosophy professor
than I did threat intelligence for a
little bit now I worked as an
application pen tester it's been kind of
a long circuitous route for the last you
know six or seven years of my life to
where I am now
I've always been relatively passionate
about digital rights like going back to
the late 90s as one of those like
internet generation kids like being able
to see the promises of the Internet even
back in the days when everything was
like static HTML pages and like static
links pre you know Wikipedia and all
this other kind of stuff you could even
see it that right I've been very
passionate about that and over maybe the
last four or five years have become a
total nerd for security stuff largely
because it's just cool right like
security stuff is cool and Chris
Nickerson said it but maybe was a 2d
sides ago where all of us a lot of us in
the serve are lucky because we get to do
our hobby for job right and that's
that's one of things I love about this
industry yeah so I'm James I'm also with
the digital freedom initiative and by
trade I'm a software developer and by
night I do DevOps stuff more
that a little bit later and I'm also
interested in security and digital
privacy and have been for the last six
years okay the problem right and I think
it's a problem that gets alluded to a
lot kind of in conversations but we
haven't really attempted to deal with it
sort of in a frontal way right you have
an attempted to really like dive into
this problem but the problem result
revolves around a very basic issue of
the internet right that the modern
Internet is a paradox that on the one
hand we've been handed a tool which is
probably the most important tool that
humans have been able to to construct
since the printing press right if we
think back in time the printing press
was the tool that create the Protestant
Reformation right it was the tool that
created the American Revolution it was a
tool that create the French Revolution
it's a tool that has facilitated social
and political change ever since its
inception and popularization since the
advent of the internet we have seen a
very similar thing happen right we've
seen repressive regimes fall the Middle
East right not always with the best of
outcomes but we've seen it happen we've
seen people do things that they were
never able to do before and that's been
a capability that has been developing
slowly for the last fifteen years or so
right so we have this incredible tool
and this tool carries with it an
absolutely profound prompts all the time
every time we log on but at the same
time the Internet has been constructed
in such a way as the centralized control
over communications and to engage in
unprecedented levels of surveillance
right we are just having a conversation
about this on the fact table before this
presentation about how within the United
States we don't deal with at least until
net neutrality goes away we don't deal
with the same kinds of problems of
having connections throttled and cut
that you see in a place like Turkey or
India or China or something like that
what we deal with there's a very
different sort of problem set right we
deal with the problem set that revolves
around the personal limitations that we
place on ourselves because we're
concerned about who's watching what
we're saying right and that has
has created a situation which is tool
all of a sudden becomes something that
we use with hesitancy right we don't use
in the way that we possibly could
that the dream of the internet was a
dream that was of a network that was
horizontal and dynamic right and this
wasn't necessarily the dream of the
architects but this was the dream that
came into being in the 1970s right and
formed the basis of organizations like
the Electronic Frontier Foundation this
idea that we were going to have this
thing that could make us into different
kinds of people they had access to more
information that had access to
communication tools we never had before
however due to the origins of the
Internet and the reliance on already
existing telecommunications companies to
form the backbone of that network the
dream has become disrupted complicated
right that instead this vision sort of
exists alongside a vision of the
Internet as a centralized mechanism for
commerce and surveillance not
necessarily one purely for expression
that the internet is controlled by very
small number of entities and none of
them can be trusted and we see this as a
problem here but when you talk to people
in places like Turkey or in places like
Senegal or in places like Nigeria or
China or Vietnam that problem is so much
more apparent to them and the thing that
I always hear when I talk to people from
those places is we have to be mindful we
have to be vigilant we have to be
cautious right that it's not that we
that the mechanisms don't exist in the
United States to have the same kind of
controls it's that they just haven't
been weaponized yet that's one of those
things that's at stake in the discussion
around a portrayal of you right is this
idea that all of a sudden the ISP which
controls the actual lines our
communications go over have the ability
to limit our access to certain assets
not necessarily by banning them but by
throttling their connections down to a
point where it's impractical to get to
them right and that's the first time
that we've really been dealing with that
specific sort of problem so this can be
easily demonstrated in a myriad of cases
right this kind of problems that we're
large service providers have handed
information over to repressive regimes
and ISPs have colluded with repressive
governments right and stories like this
can circulate around the internet all
the time we can also see the impacts of
this in places like Turkey India China
Syria and so on right we're having a
conversation on the back table earlier
about
kote right and the use of Bluecoat
appliances in Syria to do deep packet
inspection and we've also seen this in
situations where service providers have
been complicit in surveillance and
throttling or cutting off connectivity
to whole regions websites things like
this but this is not only a problem with
foreign regimes and providers right that
there's a long history of AT&T working
with the NSA as well as companies like
Blue Coat right which I already
mentioned selling DPAC inspection gear
to Syria and Turkey which is then used
for repression and in some cases has
been the deciding factor in rating
someone's house throwing them in prison
and torturing them right in the midst of
these challenges encryption and anima T
and the control over services that we
interact with has become a project of
many developers and people within the
information security community right
that this has led to an explosion of
tools that attempt to preserve or expand
the ability of people to communicate
privately that increasingly these tools
are becoming easier to use for the
average user right so how many people
here use tor say before 2007 right I did
say would remember having to configure
your circuits manually right then you
have to like set your proxy settings is
really easy to screw up right another
store browser and like anyone can just
like go download the executable like or
whatever and just run it signal is the
same way right signal is incredible
because all you do is download the app
configure it and all of a sudden your
crypting your text messages it's easy
right there's been a lot of work kind of
pushing this direction you know again
primary examples of this a signal and
tour and but for as great as a lot of
these tools are oh okay they sort of
present a central problem right and a
problem that's relatively common amongst
these tools at this point so in BO
signal in tor but also VPNs and many of
the many other of the technologies have
been utilized in order to preserve
communications privacy we run into a
similar problem right that to the degree
that these systems remain technically
complex to run rather than use so even
running a tor exit node can be
complicated especially legally right
running a signal server I mean like the
software's out there but there's no
documentation let alone a lot of the
other more comply
protocols to the degree that they've
become technically complicated to run
rather than use we end up with a large
amount of users trusting a small amount
of anonymous ish operators and some dude
named my name marks and Moxie
Marlinspike right who's got dreadlocks
and like you know talks in metaphor a
lot of times here's like a chill dude
but not a lot of people actually know
him as a person right and that creates a
problem that the problem with tor is
that it's based on a technology based
trust model rather than an interpersonal
one right so what we're doing is we're
constructing a synthetic network that
people are relying on for their safety
and freedom right even though no single
entity can bill the totality of
information about a connection those
that run exit nodes do still hold a
significant amount of control over the
safety of the content one is accessing
the ability to monitor usage right that
this is mitigated somewhat by the use of
hidden services which remain within the
network and do not utilize exit notes
for communication but other risks also
still exist within a context right but
with the with the risks of running exit
notes being widely known the number of
willing operators is very small like I
don't know how familiar are people with
the kind of legal risks of running exit
notes right you get letters see some
justice letters constantly people try
and sue you because it's your IP address
that people are like pirating content
off of or like hacking things things
like this so the number of operators of
exit votes are incredibly small very
very small and people that operate exit
notes as has been demonstrated by some
studies where people have been actually
sort of querying exit nodes to see if
they're tracking traffic and things like
this the privacy of users is not almost
the primary concern right most exit
nodes are fine but malicious active
nodes have very much been found within
the Tor network signal just like Tor
sort of relies on the trust that we have
in anonymous service providers within a
centralized messaging network now even
if we can audit the code base for the
client and the server right which you
very much can for signal the server code
is partial right so not everything is
there and there's a statement up on the
open whisper system site as to why
that's the case and the implementation
of
parallel signal signal networks is
difficult if not radically impossible
right like you can't communicate with
people on other signal networks if you
set up a parallel network though the
concept of ratcheting diffie-hellman key
exchanges holds a significant amount of
promise and it really really does it's a
really interesting protocol there is the
option of verify and there is the option
verify and key changes in person like
does anyone ever try to verify a signal
key change in person like I've done it
involves like scanning QR codes on each
other's phones right
they even though you can do that
impracticality long-distance
communication makes this difficult if
not impossible to sort of implement
right so therefore we have to trust the
cryptography as well as the chain as the
claim to not store data by the provider
right and the integrity of the key held
by a likely remote other user right
someone that we may or may not actually
be in direct communication with that
within all of this we are still able to
be identified by the simple fact that
signal requires a phone number to
register and it is more and more
difficult to obtain clean anonymous
burner phones or sign up for things like
Google Voice without giving any sort of
identifiable information that since the
discussion of ISP data collection that
happened earlier this year right the use
of VPNs is even risen dramatically like
all over the internet on the low click
Beatty site so you see it on BuzzFeed
everything else everyone's talking about
like how do you identify good VPNs and
these kinds of things but all of these
providers regardless of whether you
trust them or not like air VPN is pretty
good and you know like Nord VPNs pretty
cool they all suffer from the same flaw
which just like signal and tor we have
to rely on the integrity of an anonymous
third party VPN providers are also
increasingly difficult to evaluate right
like incredibly difficult to evaluate
then unless you run your own which I
don't know many people have tried to run
their own VPN but now with Streisand and
algo and things like this it's a lot
easier to do that than it used to be in
the past but unless you run your own it
becomes impossible to have assurances of
actual privacy that for dissidents
journalists and radicals this could be
an issue of life and death and VPN
providers have turned information over
to regimes which has resulted in arrests
and on at least one occasion the torture
and death of a dissident and this
happened in Syria
so we also have an additional problem
right and that additional problem is a
problem that with in information
security discourse we don't often deal
with right which is a non-technical
problem it's not one that has to do with
coding computers and processing power
and things like this and that problem is
that the those that are the most at risk
are often not very well resourced or
technically savvy right has anyone read
glenn greenwald's book about the edward
snowden leaks you know there was right
it was pretty good it was good but right
really good yeah there was a half a
chapter to an entire chapter I forget
how many pages just about the process of
Edward Snowden convincing Glenn
Greenwald to use PGP and the process of
training about how to do that and to use
like you know pigeon and OTR right and
things like this because even though
this is a guy who writes about national
security issues he had no idea how to do
this stuff right and so the people that
are often the most at risk are the
people that don't have the resources
where the time or the technical
knowledge to be able to utilize a lot of
the technologies that we put out in the
most effective way possible right the
solutions that many of us helped to
architect and test at our day jobs are
not applicable in this kind of a context
right we'll get into this a little bit
more but a lot of us work at relatively
large corporations right with a lot of
resources and firewalls and security
monitoring teams like all these other
things right and that's not technically
feasible for even Amnesty International
let alone your small grassroots
organization the activists dissidents
radicals and journal and journalists and
so on do not have the capacity to build
and run persistent well protected
systems on enterprise great hardware
mind enterprise great firewalls and
and assim to monitor at all right it'd
be awesome if they did but that takes
entire staffs to do the outside of the
excellent work that many of us do each
day and every day the discourse around
information security must address the
problem of high risk and non enterprise
users more effectively right we put
these things out all the time we release
white papers we do all these things and
they're great right and they lead to
approaches that we can use in this kind
of a context but we tend to hang out
with each other right we tend to
circulate around other technical people
and talk in a specific lingo and haven't
actually been effective for as much as
many of us have tried and communicating
outside of those circles as well as we
probably should that this takes
rethinking the way that services are run
thought of and architected right
specifically it takes rethinking the
idea of persistent services organized
through technical trust models that the
task before us is to build Internet
accessible services that can operate to
manifest the promises of the Internet
while minimizing the harms that can be
caused by usage that examples of a new
type of autonomous decentralized and
asymmetric Internet infrastructure can
be seen being deployed in conflict zones
the examples that that we have appear
some of which are well documented some
of which are not but in Egypt during the
Tahrir Square demonstrations the
internet was cut off right I'm sure
almost everyone heard about that right
like they cut the internet off
completely tried to shut down access to
the network and what some people did is
they contacted a satellite internet
provider in Malta they got a connection
they bounced that connection to Libya
they messed netted the connection all
the way down the Libyan coast into Egypt
and bounced the border and then started
handing out little dongles to receive
connectivity and clients so people could
connect to the mesh net and that
actually connected tens of thousands of
people to the internet on this
autonomously constructed mesh net that
was built in like 48 hours right so
these things are possible right
activists in the umbrella revolution in
Hong Kong right when people are camped
out in Hong Kong use firechat which you
know firechat for better or worse I mean
it's not open-source necessarily it's
not the most secure thing ever but what
it did do was it allowed people to
communicate
peer-to-peer without using the actual
lines owned by the Chinese government
right and that allowed people to
maintain communication that in Turkey
activists have built infrastructure to
monitor internet shutdowns and
throttling right they use like a simple
JavaScript embed on websites to do this
as well as networks of redundant VPNs
which during the gezi Square protests in
assemble they would spray-paint the URL
for the VPNs up on the walls so people
could go and actually pull down the
certificates to connect to them and the
Google DNS right so people get
circumvented DNS blocks right so these
are like relatively simple approaches
built on relatively simple technologies
that are you know well known already and
people have been using them in these
kind of crisis situations at a time of
which surveillance is increasing right
not just in the United States but all
over the world and that's largely
through technical capability the legal
limitations are becoming either
ineffective or weakened and in which net
neutrality is under assault it is ever
more important that as a community we
turn our eyes and skills towards this
problem but from the lessons of past
attempts and the technical flaws of
these attempts we can learn the lessons
that will facilitate us as a community
contributing to making the promises of
the internet a reality so but before
getting into some of the things that can
provide some of the baselines for this
right and before getting into a sort of
technical framework for thinking through
these problems we have to clarify what
we're not talking about so we're not
talking about large-scale enterprise
deployments which exists between thick
walls like behind thick walls of
protection right that the requirements
of such systems are completely out of
the reach of most high risk users and
most high risk users find themselves in
situations in which the construction and
maintenance of such a system is
completely outside of financial and
technical capabilities as well as
existing in such a way as to be easily
located easily seized very easily taken
down that we're not talking about
something that lives behind expensive
firewalls right we're not talking about
something that lives you know in
relation to expensive monitoring systems
right
the enterprise grade security mechanisms
that many of us spend our days either
building or certain
Banting are incredibly complex and
difficult to deploy right anyone that's
ever tried to roll ArcSight
knows this painfully right that the
average user may have access to
something like PF sense right how many
people have played around PF sense yeah
PF sense is pretty awesome they might
have access something like PF sense they
know someone who's a little bit more
technical and might know someone who can
help configure it correctly right you
snort in a way that's not going to block
all your connection to the internet and
all that some may even go as far as to
deploy their own DNS servers right and
network defect defense mechanisms at
really small scale but even in this case
all this provides all this provides us
for the highly technical user the
ability to protect their own connection
right and their own ability to connect
to the internet rather than the
connections of other users or the
security of their systems that as has
been seen in repressive operations in
the past and as we constantly state when
talking about OPSEC and work sack and
entity is only as secure as its weakest
link right a lot of the cases in which
organizations have been taken down which
people have gone to prison it's been
because one person got you know their
phone backdoored or one person opened up
the wrong email or you know some site
wasn't secured the right way or someone
left an SSH key and github or something
like that right it's always one little
tiny flaw on anyone here that works as a
pen tester knows what one little tiny
flaw can lead to right it's your
beginning toehold into something much
bigger then the absence of these
mechanisms static services exist over
time right these things that we try and
build forever and are centralized in
their operation become really easy
targets for malicious actors whether
state-level actors surveillance
companies or like random scriptcase
right so what are we talking about right
we've gone through problematizing we've
gone through over not talking about so
what are we talking about here but there
have been a number of projects have
attempted to decentralize services right
I think how many people heard about
mastodons right like there's Mastodon
right what was the one before that um
what can do social Diaspora right like
there are these there are these systems
that come up all the time and like lots
of devs like to talk about how they have
solution to the centralizing the
internet and stuff like that like these
these populate github to an extreme
degree but many of these projects have
been left for dead right you go to these
pages and no one's updated the codebase
it's three years right there hasn't been
an issue filed in two years right even
more are largely undocumented or involve
really complex setup right so is anyone
trying to go to something a bit like man
this is really cool I really want to run
this and then you go to their like read
the docs page and it's like three lines
long and there's like absolutely no
description of what to do right
many of these protocols require really
well provision machines right that you
need a system with 16 gigs of RAM and a
quad core processor and stuff like that
right 4 terabytes of storage and things
like this and a large number of these
protocols are completely untested right
completely unaudited an attempt to build
something that's completely new rather
than relying on trusted proven
technologies that we can use as a
baseline for something like this
many of these protocols are often really
difficult for clients to adopt right
there's a lot of these protocols exist
out there that you can only interact
with over a command line right which you
know I always I always call it the mom
and dad test right that my mom and dad
can't use it or if they look at it and
go what is this it's probably not the
most effective solution I could come up
with so the question that we have to ask
ourselves is how do we build tools that
are autonomous right so it can be run by
an individual person don't require an
entire collective or group or your
techie friends or whatever to run our
secure at least secure ish right so
things that will deal with some level of
attempt and attacking them right they're
not going to stand up to the NSA right
they're not going to stand up to like
persistent attack over six months but
they're secure ish and they will have at
least a limited time to live before they
become completely compromised right and
our relatively surveillance resistant so
that's this is a question of how do we
allow clients to attach themselves
through a service right are we talking
about plain text internet are they using
VPNs to get into something do they have
to connect to a message net first are
they using tor right providing some
level of anonymity to circumvent some
level
surveillance is an achievable goal right
we're talking about services are
deployable and usable by normal users
that aren't security engineers right so
we'll talk a little bit later about
Tahoe le FS which is an absolutely
awesome protocol but the joke when I
talk to the developer is he I was like
the fourth person he'd met that actually
set one up because it's something only
security engineers do right because it's
a really complicated thing to set up
we're talking about things that can
exist easily as temporary or ephemeral
services and we'll get into this in a
little bit too but in the absence of
being able to build the castle with big
tall thick walls being able to move and
bounce the location of your
infrastructure though not a perfect
offense and those something that people
in the info section hate when we talk
about obscurity does potentially provide
at least a minimal level of security
we're talking about things that can be
deployed on cheap and free Hardware
right cheap laptops you buy the thrift
store desktops raspberry pies phones
things like this like stuff that you can
get for $50 or less maybe $100 maybe 150
at the top limit the things that you can
get for you know not a you know super
significant bank account breaking amount
of of dollars right and we're looking at
systems that can leverage sis ops and
DevOps tools right another thing that
InfoSec people tend to not like is like
DevOps e stuff and James will talk about
DevOps stuff in a little bit but DevOps
makes spending up things easy right sis
ops tools like ansible makes pinning
things up easy right not necessarily the
most secure way but they make the
spinning up and running of the service
easy we're also looking for things that
are very well documented right so don't
start this process of writing a tool
that you want people to use to secure
their like freedom and safety and then
not write documentation for it because
that's what people do like all the time
so people need to be able to use the
thing right we're looking for projects
that have to be open-source right if
anyone has you know looked at like wire
or anything like this or any of these
kind of propriety what's the one that
was being used in the white house they
would remember the one that like
revealed some what was it
now it like revealed only some of the
message and then like deleted it as you
saw there's I forgot what it was called
but it's a completely closed source
technology right what Twitter but these
are completely closed source
technologies right like we have no idea
whether
actually doing and we have no idea of no
way to monitor the codebase right we're
looking for tools that are built and
this is probably the most important
point built through a development
process that involves engagement and
listening to the users that we are
trying to protect right
we are not super great at that as a
community right this idea that we're
going to listen to people that we might
perceive as not knowing what they're
talking about it's one of those like
it's a process of getting out of our
offices and like actually talking to
like regular people that might not know
what's going on and this is the thing
that a lot of users that I know they try
and use these things complain about
constantly but we have to be willing to
listen to the people that we're
developing tools for we have to develop
tools that are adaptable to different
sorts of threat models and deployment
circumstances right that we tend to
build these tools that are really good
in our situation right but that aren't
super flexible and we want to build a
tool that facilitates operation among
existing physical real networks of trust
right not synthetic networks of trust
not networks of trust that build through
the use of a tool right like Facebook
like how many people here are Facebook
and how many people have Facebook
friends they don't actually know right
raise your hand high raise it proud
right I mean there's a lot of people
right that is the whole point of
Facebook is that you have friends you
don't actually know right so caution
there's dragons and pitfalls and stuff
right and we have to keep this in mind
like again we're not building NSA proof
systems here right we're building secure
ish systems that facilitate the promise
of the Internet that's a different thing
though building systems like this are a
lot of pitfalls like we're not going to
have a hundred percent off time right if
like the person down the streets try to
run the chat server they're not going to
have 100% uptime like the chat server is
going to go down and if they're not
paying attention to a desert work or
something it's just going to be down
right we just have to be comfortable
with that we're going to be using
consumer grade gear a lot of the time
from tools like this and what happens we
can super great gear breaks right we're
not using like fancy SAS drive so they
don't just like run forever like they
break and they die services are not
going to be able to be in most case
tested for security vulnerabilities
right on every deployments due to the
resources of those deploying
technologies right that the anti Dimity
of users and the trust between the users
in the service becomes super paramount
here but the ability to pen test every
single instance of something is just
completely impractical and we have to be
comfortable with that so to spend a lot
of time focusing on the protocols
themselves that there will be likely in
most circumstances absolutely no
mitigating controls right there's not
going to be something that's going to be
able to compensate for the fact that
someone's trying to run a SQL injection
on your service right there's not going
to be a laughs there's not going to be a
real firewalls
like in most of these circumstances even
being connected to the internet in a
reliable way
is like somewhat of a victory that
without an eye towards how to explain
the system to non-technical users the
project will likely gain very little
uptake right so if anyone's ever tried
to read the documentation for a lot of
these things like I have a hard time
understanding it a lot of the time I've
got to spend some time with it I've got
to read through it if I'm trying to like
train the women's rights group in the
neighborhood how to do that and how to
deploy something and they don't even
know the lingo they don't understand the
terms they might have one or two people
they're a little bit more technically
inclined right or like the tenants
rights organization or something like
this
they're going to give up right and
people give up on things like this all
the time because the barrier to entry is
so high we have to work on lowering the
barrier century then again we have to
develop these systems through process of
listening which sometimes again we're
not very good at as a community by and
large so some recent developments to
help in this project right first cheap
hardware so cheap hardware's abound like
how many people have tried to go buy a
laptop on ebay in the last like six
months right it's relatively easy to
find a laptop with like an i5 and eight
gigs of ram for like $300 or less I
think that's totally a thing like you
can buy servers on eBay for 150 bucks
right and so the idea that you can have
relatively well provisioned
hardware is not insurmountable but
you're not going to have indefinite
capacity
then with the increasing speed at which
enterprise-grade gear is being released
into the secondary market with a
dramatic increase in processing speed
and power of consumer grade gear
adequately provisioned equipment can be
purchased at minimal cost but we must
still be conscious of the limitations of
the hardware the high risk users have
access to even though that calculus has
changed right so it's no longer
ten-year-old desktops and stuff like
that it's newer gear it's more powerful
gear but it's still somewhat limited in
its capacity so it's but it's not
impossible to imagine though because of
cheap gear and the proliferation of
cheap gear decentralized networks built
off cheap
headless desktop computer stashed in
closets raspberry PI's some $200 laptops
and a couple hundred and fifty dollar
servers right that's totally something
that is able to be constructed at this
point in time and decentralized design
makes the scaling kind of easy we're
much easier than it used to be of course
depending on the protocol you can jump
up and talk about that ops real quick
yeah so another thing that has happened
over the last five years in particular
although the trend has been going on for
the better part of a decade now is tools
like that enable us to deploy
applications and infrastructure quickly
so how many people are familiar with
like DevOps tools and some level ok so
there's a few this is all the ones that
I've used personally and on that list
we've got things like docker which lets
you do jails and you can do
deterministic deployments so how
difficult was it five years ago to do a
build of your application in such a way
that every time you ran it if if the
code didn't change you would get the
exact same hash that was that was
incredibly difficult with with tools
like docker now coats the same I can run
it on here and I'll get one hash and
then you can run it over there and you
will get the exact same hash so there's
tools out there that are enabling
you have more and more complicated
infrastructure to be built an example of
this on the enterprise side that a lot
of people do is well let's spin up your
load balancer and five web servers that
can take like 30 seconds and when you're
doing this on cheap hardware it's here's
the pre-made playbook for how to build
this service run this command and it all
fires up and the accessibility of these
is only you know it's only getting
better because most of them started off
with the idea of ephemeral environments
right servers are cattle they're not
pets you know when it gets owned we get
rid of it we create a new one and that's
exactly what like going back a vagrant
rebuild development environments that's
what it was created for right you messed
it up
oh we just restart okay so what is this
all equate to right so you've been
talking about a lot of problems and some
things people have done some conditions
what does this all equate to right it
equates to a conceptual model right a
way that we can start to think through
this problem set that's slightly
different than the way that we've been
thinking about it so far right that the
combination of cheap Hardware slash
disposable hardware so stuff that we
could use and if it comes under threat
literally destroy advances in encryption
increases in processing power and the
use of deployment technologies allow for
the basis of a conceptual approach to be
crafted that begins to work through this
problem by using cheap hardware the high
risk user is able to destroy nodes and
clients pretty much whenever they need
to write that this was one of those
things that was really important in
Syria when Syrian dissidents talk about
their use of computers right that if
they were using Facebook and the
government was storming into their
apartment building there was an approach
that people started picking up of like
trying to think through that problem
beforehand so they could pick up their
computer and throw it out the window
right we're literally thinking about
something that exists in the same way
but not necessarily
destroying the hardware but destroying
the service destroying any trace of the
service right just eliminating it from
actual physical storage the use of
deployment technologies allows for an
ease of deployment and redeployment
right and that creates a process in
which we can change where services are
deployed we can spin them up and we can
tear them down it we can move those very
quickly that this equates to the
building blocks of a femoral asymmetric
technical infrastructure or
infrastructure that can be deployed torn
down and redeployed very easily right if
we think about this within theories of
modern warfare for example right and use
that same sort of framework when forces
that exist at a disadvantage can't
defend themselves what do they do they
move right they move around they change
location they change their operational
modes right and that's a problem set
that we're just beginning to start to
approach here that though this does not
eliminate the problem of compromise at
all right these aren't again bulletproof
services by limiting knowledge of
service to trust circles embedding the
service and hidden networks and limiting
the lifecycle of the service as much as
possible the service becomes a much more
difficult target to discover and
compromise right I don't know if
anyone's tried to do a network pen test
on a network for things change all the
time you'll see this in like
capture-the-flag
vm sometimes like the services will
change or they'll change ports or
something like that it makes it
significantly harder to even pinpoint
what you're even looking at some
technologies that exist currently
utilize similar concepts right but have
certain kinds of weaknesses but contain
lessons that we can learn in the
development of these things the first is
CJ DMS like does anyone here familiar
with CJ DNS cool CJ DNS is awesome it's
a mesh netting protocol right it allows
the construction of either localized or
remote and distributed mesh networks
right so construction network where
systems within that network can connect
to each other and serve services to each
other which are not discoverable from
outside of that network right
what's interesting about CGI DNS and
what holds promise in CGI DNS is the way
that nodes get added to the network so
it's not that anyone could just go oh
hey this is cool I'm going to get added
to the network but if anyone's ever done
research on like hyper boria's probably
the largest CJ DNS network that exists
right now you need to be trusted by a
node that already exists to be let into
the network and what that does is a
builds a model which depending on
implementation becomes one based on
interpersonal already existing trust
that's been facilitated through a
technical model it also becomes
incredibly easy to get rid of nodes if
you need to right and so this constructs
a sort of parallel network that we can
start to serve services through Tom Ola
FS Tahu le FS is like probably my
favorite project that exists right now
what it is is it's a distributed file
storage system which doesn't sound super
exciting until you like get into what it
does so if you have access to the system
which means that you need to know where
the system is you need credentials to
get access to it and so on and you
upload a file when you upload that file
that file will copy itself a set number
of times right which is set in
configuration you can set at 3 so that
600 whatever copies itself a set number
of times then encrypts itself cuts
itself up and distributes pieces and
parts of itself all over a distributed
storage network that you've set up and
that storage network can include any
note that has literally any storage
capacity so that could be a phone that
could be a Raspberry Pi it could be you
know the desktop that you bought for
college that's been sitting in your
parents garage for the last 10 years
like whatever it could be anything that
actually has any storage capacity what's
interesting about is that files aren't
to parents so you can't just like go to
a Tahoe node hack the node and then find
all the files right that you have to
know what's called the furl so you get
an address for the file that needs to be
sent to you to be able to actually
retrieve the file but the coolest part
of Tahoe and why it's useful in this
situation is that if any one storage
node is seized or taken you can't
recover the entirety of a single file
right even if you knew how to decrypt
the file which in itself is relatively
difficult just encrypted with AES
even if you could do that you still
wouldn't have the entirety of one file
you'd have to decrypt every single
little tiny portion of every file and
then kind of guess at how they go back
together right and you can figure it in
such a way so that a percentage of your
storage notes can be taken down but you
can still retrieve the file back right
so you can set that at 80%
you could lose 80 percent of your nodes
simultaneously at once and still be able
to get your files back right so this is
starting to be deployed in like
corporate contacts because it provides
redundancy and resiliency but it's
specifically useful in this kind of a
circumstance the problem is is that it
is like insanely difficult for one like
insanely difficult to run and set up and
managed at this current time although
there's a lot of work being done to kind
of remedy that ipfs so has anyone ever
tried to use IP FS cool yeah I was
messing around with it like last couple
months it's pretty interesting so
outside of the kind of like funny name
right ipfs stands for the interplanetary
file system and there's like a mythology
around it built by the devs about how
this is going to be the way they get
files to Mars and like stuff like that
there's like this a very strange
discourse around this protocol but
what's really interesting about the
protocol is you sort of get on the
network right and you form connections
with other nodes within the network you
start backing up their files and once
you backup the files you can have access
to those things right but within this
what's interesting is it does version
control right so you kind of pull a file
in but if it's different than the hash
of the file that you pulled down like 30
seconds ago you know the difference
right and so you end up with this
ability to build forward and rollback in
a decentralized network which didn't
exist really before ipfs in any way that
was like widely available magic wormhole
like magic wormholes something like
almost has anyone ever played with it
like we were playing around with it
magic wormhole is a much smaller project
done by the people who wrote Tahoe le FS
and what it is is you like download it
like you downloaded through pip write
Python packages X you download it
through pip and you run it
literally by typing in wormhole send
file name and it seems totally
unremarkable right but what it does is
really cool um it encrypts your file
client-side and gives you a three word
passcode sends it up through a server
right and then someone else goes
wormhole receive and then the the
passcode and then it pulls a file town
and encrypts it for you what's great
about magic wormhole is it will run on
literally anything that can run Python
it is so small and so limited in the
amount of power it takes to run and it's
so incredibly simple but it provides I
mean like a very easy way to transfer
files peer-to-peer that has at least a
minimal level of security and is
inherently ephemeral right doesn't exist
for any period of time so okay we're
going to move on to the obligatory tool
release right pretty much when like I've
given a talk and I know a lot of people
I know given talks we usually drop some
sort of like tool in this case Python
script so we wrote this tool we're
calling go serve it was written in
Python 3
and what it does there's the the get
address man who wants to take a look at
it it's a proof of concept script right
so this is not something you should be
running in a life-or-death situation
merely what we're trying to do is sort
of prove out an idea okay so the script
leverages ephemeral tor hidden services
to run services which are spun up and
torn down through a simple command-line
interface so like literally after you
run the install script which downloads
everything pulls everything down
configures your tor configuration file
all of this stuff you're literally
running Python 3 go serve dot py TAC I
to spin up a tor hidden service IRC and
then hitting enter to kill it what's
interesting about ephemeral hidden
services an ephemeral hidden services
are sort of a newer thing within the tor
protocol what's interesting about
ephemeral hidden services is unlike
traditional hidden services which are
essentially just websites or web
services that you have accessible
through support and get stored on disk
like anything else
ephemeral hidden services run entirely
memory which is really cool so they're a
little bit more difficult to configure
which is hence why we wrote the script
to do it
but you spin them up the script kicks
you out a nice little dotty in a dress
you tell people what that is then when
you hit enter tears it down and as it
tears it down it's gone there's nothing
left like if you store something
persistently like there a file share
that's still there but the service in
the history of the service logs anything
are gone completely there's one of these
protocols that the Tor project has
really been playing around with more and
more and more and more and more but it
hasn't really picked up a lot of
adoption simply because it is relatively
difficult to do right so again proof of
concept right don't don't go to you know
Turkey and try and run this to
circumvent government surveillance I
mean it might be successful but I'm not
going to like guarantee anything so our
task the information security community
often discusses our social
responsibility right this is like a
large part of our discourse internally
and why a lot of us got involved I know
it's part of the reason I got involved
in learning these things was a sense of
social responsibility and many of us
contribute to technical projects right
then manifests the idea of what this
means to us right we all have different
ideas of what social responsibility is
but most of the time these interventions
are confined to the technical realm
right to research that results in
technical solutions that those super
important and that formed the basis for
the things that we're talking about in
this talk very rarely ever leave
technical space right that tools are
often developed which are technically
sound but difficult for users to
implement but to be able to manifest our
social responsibility it's necessary to
kind of leave the screens right leave
the offices leave the basements and
enter into a world which is unplugged
and in a lot of ways a lot more
complicated than the nice technical
worlds that we surround ourselves with
all the time right like you go look at a
web app and it's a machine it's an
abstract machine but it operates in a
certain way and you can pretty much
figure out what that is even without
looking at the code and all of that's
simple and the importance of that is
clearer in the abstract right but the
material world and the problems people
deal with are much more complicated than
the technical problems that we look at
every day and the solutions are much
less direct right and that's a difficult
space for us to to start to interact
with
but it is a necessary thing by grappling
with the question of security for users
in an increasingly treacherous
centralized online space we can serve
that profound social purpose and we can
help to manifest the vision of the
Internet which has formed the foundation
for first a hacker scene and then the
information security industry for the
last 25 years right that assisting and
decentralisation is one of many ways we
can contribute right I know people
around here are circulating that you
give camp right helping nonprofits do
security there's you know you could
teach your parents how to use encryption
there's a lot of ways to contribute this
is one way that we can actually start to
manifest that vision so if anyone has
questions or tomatoes to throw or
whatever you can't really read that
contact at digital freedom initiative
org I've got cards and stuff people want
them because anybody have any questions
yeah not that's a question that might
even be too big to even deal with right
here it's it's hard because part of the
promise of the Internet is anonymity
right but sure yes right so we can
demand more stringent requirements when
people start making random claims right
that doesn't mean that's actually going
to take hold right I think one of the
things to keep in mind and this has been
talked about since you know the American
and French Revolutions is freedom as a
complicated space and it means that
things are going to happen that we don't
necessarily like and that it's our
responsibility to try and fight back and
do something about that but that there's
really no singular answer I don't think
it's a hard question it's a very hard
question and I think it takes a lot more
conversations we have probably right now
Paul do you have a question
yeah part of me wants to say don't know
if we have to convince everybody right
no I'm serious about that like there are
going to be a lot of people that for
whatever reason don't think this is
important and we're not going to nor do
I think we have to convince everyone of
this what we have to do is we have to
develop enough momentum to overcome the
apathy of the indifference and the
attempts to move against this sort of
attempt right that it is a question just
like any other sort of social and
political questions always a question of
inertia's right it's a question of not
necessarily even support because support
does really mean much but it is a
question of being able to intervene
right directly in the situation I think
for a long time we were asking
politicians and you know the public to
sort of engage in this discourse and
we're watching right now with net
neutrality even though we've won the
argument right it doesn't actually
matter right so that requires a
different approach now it doesn't mean
we shouldn't engage in that kind of that
form of engagement right but it does
require now that we have to actually do
things are a little bit more to rats and
I think that that's an important thing
right we have to start thinking about
this on the level of action not
expression right and I'm starting to see
that happen
learn more and more all the time a lot
of people here are thinking along those
lines I think that's really helpful yeah
that's what I would say I don't I don't
know if it's a necessary thing yeah if I
can add to that
um it's not just you know people who are
in third world countries or oppressive
regimes it's happening here in the US as
well you know there's the women's
shelter that that needs that that type
of help it doesn't have to be building
that the types of tools that we're
talking about you know a federal hidden
etc it can be something as simple as
just helping with basic digital digital
literacy and whatnot you know there's
involvement is a target right and you
can be on the outer edge and you can
also go go ever in closer to to the
bull's eye and not everybody has to be
there frankly there's not a whole lot of
room there but you know everybody can be
involved in it and can help in some way
yeah and so security training has I
think it's fallen into kind of two
different models right there's two very
different models we have the like
security self defense guy kind of model
that the ffs puts out right we have a
like post guard here that our
organization is handing out about like
five things you can do to make your
privacy and security better right like
patcher system like use VPN like there's
very general advice that we give however
in a lot of situations that general
advice is
right when you're dealing with the
tenants rights organization or a trade
union or something like that that has a
very specific sort of threat that
they're dealing with we have to engage
in a much more persistent way I mean
that involves conversations and
listening and figuring out what they're
dealing with and actually putting
together material for them right
following up doing the kinds of things
that like I mean how many of us do that
kind of work at work every day right
like I do how many of the rest of you do
like we know how to do these things
we're very good at it
in fact we're incredibly good at it we
have to take the same approaches that we
use we're a pentest are talking to a dev
team right or we're trying to do fishing
training for our employees right you
work at a bank or something you're like
cool why are people gonna want to break
in they're going to want to break in to
get to the system that routes the money
right that's a little bit different than
they're going to break into ransomware
you right and what we think through
these questions all the time I think
that's the important thing we're dealing
with user education it is an issue of
capacities right like we don't have the
time or bandwidth to train everybody and
I think that that's a legitimate thing
to recognize but when we do engage with
somebody when we do engage with an
organization we can actually take the
time to sit there and figure out what do
they need what are they facing what are
the capabilities of the people in the
organization and how can we help them
right think about it like we would as a
consultancy think about it like we would
like we do at work right I think we have
models for these things right and that's
what I think that that this community of
people above others can actually do
really important things in the world
when it comes to things like protecting
for asteroids organizations and things
like this because we know how to do this
already we're actually very good at it