all right ready to go cool
all right thank you to b-sides and thank
you for coming to see my talk my name is
Adam Hogan I'm a security engineer for
for CrowdStrike though I'm not talking
about that today what I'm actually
talking about is pirates and the
proposal to legalize hacking back a bit
of a controversial topic to be sure but
what I want to talk about is uh first of
all pirates because that's what led me
here and when saw my talking here ago
they's actually talking about how I
started learning about pirates is a way
to learn about criminal organization I
had started doing some research on the
economics of exploit kits in some black
market and ultimately hit a lot of dead
ends it's pretty hard to learn about
black markets and what I was doing was
starting to learn instead about some
more history historical criminal
organization always learning a pirate
and what if they're looking at was they
had a lot of similar challenges when
pirates first became a problem I was
because there was the the international
waters were beyond national law there
was this whole new medium which people
were operating that went beyond normal
definitions of crime and if I have new
ways to legislated new ways to go and
catch a new way to stop the bad guy and
I thought that sounded awfully familiar
so it's really looking at pirates and
actually if you're did talk about that
last year here we're sort of turned
around from there and so just learning
about the bad guys themselves look at
okay well how did we stop pirate right
if they are so similar what do we learn
about what actually we're successful in
catching pirate and stopping them and
bringing this criminal organization to
heel and what actually found out was one
of most successful ways was called
privateering
which actually allow people to go after
the Pirates themselves which leads me to
the hacking back debate so I want to go
through that I want to go through the
controversy because it's considerable
and for very good reason and actually go
under this can actually suggest a
regulatory framework of which we could
sort of solve a lot of the problems that
we see around the hacking back to base
my goal here is not to give as you
hacking back is a wonderful thing we
should all be doing it or anything like
that
it's not in fact the most frustrating
part of this debate as everyone seems to
be talking about whether everyone should
be hacking back or no one should be
hacking back and it's obviously that
those two poles are both incorrect but
we seem to have stopped in the debate
right regardless of addressing like yeah
there are really significant concerns
with hacking back okay why aren't we
working on addressing them directly and
that's ultimately what I want to do
today is convince you that there's a way
to move forward and address those
concerns directly also I want to suggest
that we should be doing that ourselves
I think we should be regulating
ourselves instead of waiting for
legislators to do it for us and it's
actually something we're starting to see
is new laws coming out of talk about
legalizing hacking back and again what
we're looking to do as professionals is
what reduce time to the detection
increased time to recovery and the bad
tides can reinvent themselves and all
their attacks in the time it takes a
legislature to pick out the calligraphy
for the invitation to the dinner where
you'll talk about proposals to the law
that you'd like to change right we can't
wait for that so again I also want to
talk about laying out a framework we
might be able to agree on the hopes that
we can regulate ourselves the community
instead of waiting for someone else to
try and do it so ultimately I came the
Pirates and again sort of talked about
all I saw that we actually learned a lot
about the adversaries I learned an awful
lot of respect for ultimately the
Pirates were so successful because they
could adapt and change so much quicker
than the Navy could then merchants could
and why were they so successful but Wow
which is really pretty interesting also
we go the farther back in time you go
you realize how romanticize Pirates are
it's honestly they were criminals
against humanity at the time they
redefined it these weren't just like
thieves at sea they were tribes it URI
categories is crime against humanity it
is literally like thinking into the
future and thinking that Disney might do
a kids movie about terrorists 300 years
from now that's about where we are with
pirate movies all right so these are
horrible people but we still
back and romanticize I got these dashing
robes at sea and all these past things
right but one of the more compelling
ways were actually found to stop pirates
was by commissioning privateers which
was if you were a merchant or you wanted
to go into pirate hunting business you
can actually get a what was called a
letter of marque and reprisal that
actually gave you a license to go out
and hunt pirates I mean it's okay we're
going to specify these pirates or I
don't know criminals in this area or
maybe if we're at war we'll just say hey
anybody from this country right and so
you've got this commission the specific
sexual license to go after these types
of pirate this was successful hunting
pirate and by the way was also
instrumental in America continuing to be
a country it numerous historian to point
out that without privateering America
probably would not have won the
Revolutionary War the war of 1812 and
certainly the first war with terrorists
the Barbary pirate who were harassing
American trade on the other side of the
ocean and that kind of leads me back in
the hacking back see if we want to
emulate this way that was successful
topping pirates we're talking about
going a bit actively pursuing our
attackers which leads in that hacking
back controversy and we also want to try
and draw the line here because bar too
often we lump in cyber self-defense with
retribution and we need to draw that
line there is a huge difference between
somebody broke in my house and I shot
them and somebody broke into my house so
I chase them down the street and then
shot them right totally different things
but we want to be able to make those
distinctions we want to be able to make
distinction of where we have a right to
go after an attacker to today that is
all very very murky from a legal
framework why we want to do this is well
ultimately traditional law enforcement
artists aren't going to scale for the
internet that's all clear right because
we're all here um doing this job right
the reason these kind of jobs invented
because there's a whole new class of
crime that was invented and now it's
kind of up to us because that
traditional model he isn't scaling right
that's just fact above all so we want to
make it difficult to be a criminal
right we want to make it more costly to
be a criminal we don't want to say well
it should have had a better firewall no
we want to be able to you know go after
if we can if it's possible we want to
make sure that we're doing it in a way
we can agree it's going to be safe and
effective because there are considerable
hack objection to being allowed to to
hack back and I actually want to go
through them because they're um some of
them are really good and actually
deserve some attention the one that's
most often talked about whether or not
it's actually illegal to hack back I
want to kind of skip over that if that
interesting you may we come back to the
end if you have questions about it but
ultimately what I'm proposing is that we
sort of work on ways to make it legal
that we need a better framework because
regardless of the law or gray area it's
a huge gray area and that's where a lot
of the confusion comes from if you ask
the federal government is hacking back
illegal they say probably and and beyond
that someone has to decide to prosecute
you and if you're literally going after
bad guys only that's going to happen if
it did there are many different ways you
could appeal but again I want to skip
over that ultimately what I'm proposing
is like let's look at a framework to
make this legal and more acceptable and
it's entitled levels to which I think
the failings of the Computer Fraud and
Abuse Act addresses because it is so
nebulous the suit is so gray
international law may actually play a
part because say under article 22 of the
United Nations responsibility of states
for international wrongful acts the
wrongfulness of an act is precluded if
and to the extent that act constitutes a
countermeasure so beyond a mile beyond
US law there is also recognition that
okay its own harm you there is a
different set of circumstances in area
for that but also we may have a duty to
clarify this gray area because of
standards international law actually say
states have an obligation to do due
diligence to prevent significant trans
boundary harm to another state property
so if we are actually being attacked
from some in another country and our
laws do not address how to respond to
that we could actually have a situation
where the government is sort of
negligent their duties to address that
where it could actually be incumbent on
a third citizen in order to fill that
gap and and go after the bad guy that
actually comes from a president set in
1941 from a cases called the trail
smelter there is a smelter in trail
British Columbia that was putting on all
kinds of smoke it was actually damaging
forests and farm in well Canada and the
US so people in Washington actually sued
because it was across national
boundaries it couldn't go to either one
of their national courts right so it
goes to international tribunal for
arbitration and what they found and what
was set as a precedent in international
law is that a state may not use or allow
its national to use its own territory in
such a manner to cause injury to a
neighboring country so if a country
actually know is that some of the
attacking is going on they're not doing
anything about it they're actually
negligent if they know that that's going
on then we actually have a situation
where the citizens may be incumbent on
them to respond so we have a very very
gray area here where we should be
working to clear that up right another
objection to hacking back to the idea of
escalation and this comes in a few
different flavors could hacking back
create an international incident one is
well there's people always being a
drones and talking about cyber war which
I don't know if someone's talking about
cyber war probably trying to tell you
something I get your vote I really don't
know how likely it is war has a very
clear definition and if no one's being
physically harmed I really don't think
we're talking about that scenario in
fact there's a great book by Thomas Rib
called other the cyber war will not take
place something along those lines
very well thought out very well written
book Juli described that yeah this is a
whole other world and frankly all the
incentives are all there to not escalate
this and they induce some kind of you
know actual like physical kinetic war
but also there's international precedent
to say like we don't have to ratchet up
into an escalation for this kind of
situation the International Court of
Justice actually had a case of Nicaragua
versus the United States in 1984 where
they actually had two people in two
different country
where budding had and actually finally
look they were in the middle of the
frontier they were out in the wilderness
where there wasn't a whole lot of law
and order and we're calling that a
friend to your incident we don't have to
Leslie it was not an act of war because
it was on a frontier because the law nor
the situation are so poorly defined and
I don't see any reason that couldn't
obviously be applied to our to
cyberspace so we don't I think have to
worry about any potential problem going
right to war right there are any number
of reasons to believe that saw that not
likely an international law itself is
really set up to give everyone many
opportunities to back down from war if
that's not what you want there are
plenty of loopholes to step out of that
there's also some risk that comes with
hacking back if you go and attack the
hacker maybe you become a bigger target
yourself maybe you're actually going to
bring some heat on yourself and that is
a legitimate concern what I don't think
it's a legitimate concern is whether or
not hacking back should be legal and I
think we are because we're sort of
lumping these things together we're
confusing what should be two separate
debates one should hacking back illegal
and and under what under what
circumstances and two should you be
hacking back to wildly different debate
and they are being lumped together and I
think that's where a lot of the
confusion in this debate has actually
come from it's also arguing we should be
hacking back because it could destroy
evidence
the prosecution would need later to
prosecute this crime which I find absurd
I don't know how much worse that is I
think if prosecutors were prosecuting
these people that we wouldn't be having
this discussion so I don't know how much
this is an actual serious objection it
has one I've read numerous times up
also in judgment that's not effective to
the means of that it's not a good idea
for for your return on investment that
the average company shouldn't be hacking
back that it's not going to be worth the
risk
the reward is bringing to be pretty
small and again I agree with that
but again that's the difference that's
that other discussion it's not what
announced that should be legal whether
it should be possible it's whether you
should be doing it you should be doing
it you should be doing and frankly I
find the idea that everyone should be
hacking back we'll just set up a
firewall to do a hack back that is
absurd it is ridiculous but that's a
character to which I don't know why
everyone is still arguing more right and
of course the big one is attribution
attribution is incredibly difficult how
do we know who responding to and who
were attacking and I really thought I
was going to have to double down here
and talk about how attribution is hard
and when it's not and in the
mid-afternoon keynote John got up here
and ran a live demo that showed
attribution wonderful what a way off my
shoulders that was fantastic
right there are very clear situations
where we can do we can do attribution
and easily showed a great example where
on the I don't see where anyone can have
a legal objection I didn't hack into
your network you hacked into mine and
then you took software of mine and
that's allowing me to catch you that's
what we observed earlier in that demo
and that's a you know a considerable
legal difference so attribution yet it
is difficult in some situations but not
in others frankly and even when we look
at comparing to say traditional law well
even if a conflict rises to the level of
war attribution does not seem to be a
firm requirement at least for an
individual soldier and times of imminent
danger it is enough to know that a
sniper is shooting you from a certain
position without first identifying who
the sniper is and what side he is on his
intentions or anything else so there are
situation where we can say yeah there's
risk but this situation warrants that
risk and that the destruction were not
having because we're so hung up on the
possibility of it of that risk being a
situation and of course the the biggest
objection I think being idea there could
be a decoy or a false flag they don't
know where the term false flag comes
from it comes from from the era of
pirate it was totally legal to fly a
false flag and in fact it was normal if
you wanted to pretend to be from another
Kanjar you can do that you hope what up
a false flag it was legal to have a
false flag unless you're in combat if
you open fire on someone you had to have
the legitimate flag going otherwise it
was totally legal to have a false flag
up and frankly pretty normal for ships
to have multiple sets of documentation
which actually going to come back to
so the preeminent example why is hacking
back dangerous well the bad guys could
route their attack through a hospital
and there is a supreme concern but it
also raises the example of well okay
well what if I'm running that hospital
and I'm under attack right so again I
think we're going to agree there are
situations where it weren't attacking
back but we have to address them
recognize those different level of risk
and say well if we are going to put
people at risk if we are gonna be
shutting down these systems that might
be in a hospital who's going to be
responsible for that that's the problem
we're really running into and then
another example of why hacking back at
the problem scene come up so often is
that if we do that the internet will be
the wild wild west and I hope so
to be honest of all whoever's making
this claim is doing it from a place of
all they know about the Wild West what
they learned in movies Cleveland wishes
they had the Wild West crime rate okay
it was really a pretty safe place to be
the idea that it wasn't is entirely a
cooked up in MIT right but again that I
don't think anybody's arguing to a
situation where everybody should have
their firewall set to to hack back right
there is a character in a straw man that
we have to get past in order to identify
when the risk is going to be acceptable
and the cases where the risk isn't
really that significant like the
beginning back example we saw in the
keynote John ran again John he had to
run but thank you for teeing that up for
me totally owe you a beer at a dirty
heart prank but if I can summarize the
objections where it really comes down to
is you're saying well not everybody
should be hacking back but I agree with
that
I I think everyone would and we're also
saying that there are problems that
could come with hacking back but the
real problem with that is if they're
happening quietly if they're happening
silently if they're happening in a way
where no one could be held responsible
for them so what if we can change that
what if we can make uh uh if we're going
to have a situation where we can
actually incentivize people to take some
responsibility for their actions and and
that's where my head automatically goes
but that I might my graduate study was
in economics I was all about trying to
lay a regular framework for having the
right incentive to get the outcome we
want right that's why there's picture of
Adam Smith here so can we add
transparency and responsibility to
process well if we look at a
privateering model I am actually not the
first to suggest that having privateers
in the Internet is a way we could go it
hasn't suggested many times before but I
don't think anyone's actually looked at
the legal framework that went around it
because we go deeper in the process
there is an entire legal framework to
address there and make those people take
responsibility for their actions as
privateers we had a prize court the
price Court is actually set up outside
of national court as a part of the
Admiralty Court so it actually exists as
a part of maritime law and not national
US law or common law so the prize court
was actually set up as a regulatory
framework to oversee these privateers so
if you wanted to be a pirate hunter what
you did is you had one you had to have
that letter of marque and reprisal so
you had to have that you guys
essentially that Latian which wasn't
handed out to just anybody it can be
handed out to responsible people and as
in that letter of marque you can
actually specify the target so it's not
a license to go after anybody and
everybody but these particular pirates
so the people that are attacking you or
whoever it is right they also had to
post a bond you had to put money up
front to get that letter of marker pile
to get that license and go after pirates
because again if you were wrong if you
made mistakes well you're not getting
that back right and then the prize
transfer right getting to keep that
pirate ship in any of the booty on board
well that was only 100 percent legal
once it was awarded by the prize court
the prize court had to sign
on that so in that adjudication required
public record so they could review the
evidence and the price Court had to sign
off on so the way that happened was
actually said that a decree or sentence
of condemnation my apprise court of
competent jurisdiction is now
universally held to be requisite effect
to complete a transfer of maritime
prizes from the original owner to the
captor it not being thought fit to use
the words of Lords oh well who is the
judge who really laid the front of
foundation for all of the legal cases
and precedent that came for these price
Court to say that the property nature
should not be converted without the
sentence of a competent court so you had
to bring it to the regulatory body you
had to bring it to the price Court for
everything to be official once you did
that they put out a petition saying hey
if this is your ship if you were
captured if you know the owners whenever
let them know we're going to have a
court case and if you want to make the
case that you weren't a pirate or that
you were allowed to be there or that
this was taken wrongly you can show up
and defend yourself the court then
undertook questions for one or more
representative from the captured crew so
they actually interviewed them who are
you are you a pirate are you sure you're
not a pirate and they go through all
these questions really feel like okay
what were you doing and then of course
the if their answers matched up with
their colleagues and trying to figure
out okay what were you doing where
you're going well you know why are you
guys out there to make sure it matched
up with the being a legitimate capture
and they have to take responsibility for
that after a maritime capture is
complete the possession of the captors
is in law regarded as bona fide
possession and they are not responsible
for any loss or injuries resulting from
your accident or casualties but are
bound for fair and safe custody and are
liable for any loss occasioned by their
neglect or want of proper care this
responsibility attaches to loss
resulting from misconduct of any of the
agents employing the captors as of the
prize crew and prize master neglect is
not employing a pilot or responsibility
in cases of gross misconduct on the part
of the
captors the court will decree a
revocation of the commission and I'm
going to come back to an example that
what says look if you're going to take a
capture someone you are now responsible
for it because it's not really yours yet
it exists in this quality state whereas
kind of yours but it's not 100% yours so
the court signs off under picky
particular circumstances and in cases of
overruling necessity captors may without
their and being deprived effects of
Massa possession land or even sell the
prize good but in all cases the burden
is upon them to satisfy the court of
their perfect good faith and
circumstances giving rise necessity what
does it say like if you can take a ship
you can't go it welcome through their
possessions you can't eat their food you
can't take all that stuff because it
doesn't 100% belong to you yet except in
case of extraordinary circumstances
which is fairly normal when you're at
sea if you're out of food someone has
food you can kind of take their food and
at this legal gray area you probably
have to pay them back later but this is
difficulty of surviving at sea had some
some difficult but you were
responsibility for you're responsible to
take care of their possession until it
was 100% yours after and that was again
another precedent set by Lord Stilwell
of the Admiralty courts of London now if
you want to get all the spirit of 1776
and you don't care what some snooty
British Lord had to say about all this
well here the exact same sentiment
quoted from from Benjamin Franklin so
you can take a look at those as well it
was really a matter of common law at
that point it was adapted by the US as
well I'm not gonna go through them but
essentially the same thing but let's
take a look at some of the cases because
we can actually see this working um in
action so I keep the breaking bulb which
means that you went in you took a pride
and then you actually went through their
stuff and he went through their cargo
there was a Swedish special called the
saloon palan something like that it's a
Swedish word I don't on means bookcase
now but whatever was in a lot of Swedish
it was captured by the Liverpool packet
and the retaliation was your English
baffled
and they accused the retaliations pride
master Henri fader of allowing his crew
to break into the cargo drive good and
fill their jacket so full quote that
they appeared almost as big as a
hogshead with their coats buttons around
them so they took this ship hostage and
they're like I'm going to go below deck
for a while they come back out
everybody's all fat enough with all of
their but their goods with the crews
personal effects and all that and what
we just captured these guys ours right
no not on a percent you got to take it
to the prize court and then and only
that is a Harmer sent yours so when they
brought it to the prize court they
protested well actually before that he
protested and I went and say hey you're
not allowed to do that and the mate was
told that if he did not hold his tongue
he would put him in irons calling him a
damn rascal and many other appropriate
terms which is how they actually wrote
it down and this is all public record
you can actually go through this this is
all written down you can go through
these cases and actually see how these
be transpired but when I brought into
the court and said okay we took these
they said okay that ship you captured
legitimate pirate that you wouldn't
captured it totally legitimate well you
can't go into their stuff and take their
stuff until the prize court ruled they
gave the entire ship back the captors
had to turn everything over and pay an
additional two thousand pounds on top of
that because they broke the rules
because they did not yield to the
supremacy of the prize court to say Rhys
I knopf on when this is legal not you
and you went in before that so you're
responsible so they got to keep their
ship even though it would have been a
legitimate take and they had to pay
another two thousand pounds
we're talking about integrity where
again you are responsible for that ship
and everything on it so take the cake of
the Scottish Whaler the rate it was
captured by a french privateer they
removed all the crew except the captain
and the first mate
they put a prize crew of 16 Frenchmen in
charge so at night nine men forming the
watch on deck found the Scot uh the
Scottish people's with you
and it really got into it they got
incredibly drunk and tumbled into a
whaling boat hanging over the side to
sleep it all right so the two guys who
ship originally this was our standing
there like okay so the guards all passed
out because they can't hold the roof the
other people that took us hostage are
now below day so they nailed that door
shut they drop the whaling boat into the
water and took off they brought it to
their prize court not the French prize
court but a Scottish one today these
captured us and they unveil them took
all those guys booted them out and said
okay this would have been a legitimate
capture but you screwed up you're
responsible for taking this in safely
and you didn't you get nothing all right
and kind of badass for two guys to sail
a whole ship undercount like taking this
guy's prisoner and sail the entire ship
back by themself right and also again
one of the biggest problems we have
again with the hacking vacuum a is okay
well attribution is hard what if you're
wrong about who you're attacking that
problem came up along with privateering
so a case where we had missed
attribution the USS Constitution so
England American ship now on her maiden
voyage no less goes out and I was going
to cruise French shipping that's doing
the quasi-war with France so any
friendship is essentially up for grab
first capture was a privateer the ship
was called the Niger Stefan that
carefully their documents all indicated
that it was a British ship so British
passport British registration the law is
all British but the captain of the ship
was one George du petit hussar who was a
French aristocrat who actually been
displaced by the revolution so the
Americans take the ship they're looking
at the documentation they talk to this
French captain like it's a friendship so
they take it they take it back to the
prize court and the prize court has to
go then through all the evidence and
they're looking at it and I'm like all
the documentation says it's British
and did you talk to this frog that guy's
pretty like yeah that doesn't matter
that's just the captain it is a British
ship it is owned by British crew who
write about a British port you did not
have the right to take that they had to
return the ship to its own owners and
pay eleven thousand dollars in damages
alright so they were held responsible
for making that misattribution and doing
attack based on or fundamentally quality
intelligence so they were held to task
by the course because they were required
to engage in this act of transparency
they were able to hold them accountable
okay one of more interesting things I
think about is again what we want to
look for in any kind of situation we're
going to be regulating cyber security is
it has to be fast it has to be efficient
because we can't rely on traditional
legislation to do it this industry
changes far too quickly to rely on that
it is remarkable how much people in the
prize court valued efficiency they said
that was it customer reports ten in the
limit deliberation to one or two tide
and the early Admiralty law animals
Court continuous tradition they
conducted their business close to the
water's edge often below the high tide
water markets so they actually built the
court on the high watermark the idea
being wrap this shit up quickly guys
right we have to keep this in mind and a
high tide rolled in roll up your pants
let's let's get this over with
right in fact efficiency was critical
all along this entire process in fact
during a period of war between Britain
and Spain in English privateer sees a
vessel near the mouth of the Mississippi
River and they brought that ship to the
emoji court in London which actually
means they've passed off a lot of
English prize courts they could have
stopped at a number of bytes amateur
Vice Admiralty courts in the West Indies
in the American colonies
I don't want year this was possibly even
Halifax whatever was right
they had options a lot closer than to go
to London it was a valid take they had
the right to capture that ship they
could have kept all the stuff but when I
got to London
lord stola again a guy who laid the
foundation for all his legal precedent
said hey this is crazy that you brought
that ship all the way from the mouth of
the Mississippi River to London and he
made them give the shit back and awarded
damages for that said this is crazy you
have to respect the efficiency because
when you take this pirate ship you it's
not harm percent yours it's in this
quality legal state where the where the
price Court had to sign off on it first
so you have to respect that you have to
bring it to the court and bring its
record as fast as possible so what if we
can model this what if we can have a
cyber Admiralty court what if we can
issue letters of marque and reprisal so
trustworthy look white hat not everybody
don't don't open up the board for
everybody to hack back but what if we
can say look we actually think you'd be
pretty good at this you're going to put
up the bond you know so that we can hold
financial responsibility if something
goes wrong and we can now staff an
admiralty court to adjudicate a takedown
hey you want to take down that botnet
okay well I'll bring the evidence over
here we want to review it and make sure
that this is a legitimate capture so
yeah it's not a capture right so it's
not a capture the same way we thought
with privateers right well you've got
you going to keep the ship right so the
incentive is absolutely not going to the
same we have to address that and I think
like if you are going to get privateers
interested there have to be some
incentive for that right what we could
dangle on the line well one immunity
from prosecution because the computer
Computer Fraud and Abuse Act is crazy
there so maybe we make a a contingent
legality on you're going to participate
in the prize court but we can also again
offer press right there are a number of
organizations who if they were to take
down a massive botnet or exploit kit
would love to take responsibility for
that and if you can have a prize court
certified yeah we looked at their
evidence it's great um that would be
fantastic for them I know I work for
CrowdStrike
we've been the attribution game we take
a bunch of shit for it right
people are always accusing us of not
know what we're talking about and going
on a limb I was called out not me but my
colleagues were called out by an Coulter
on Breitbart and what we were working on
it gets surreal when you're getting the
attribution game people absolutely play
out so we had a neutral third party to
certify these kind of things there can
be a lot of benefit in that so instead
of getting to keep the prize of taking
possession we're now offering a
different sort of incentive right what
we didn't say we couldn't also offer
money cash is always nice and if we are
looking at a really nasty exploit kid
out there that's a you know a burden on
all of us then when we can pass the Hat
and actually put up some some money as
for whoever is able to take them down
but instead of it just being a bounty
hunting program we're now actually
encouraging people to operate within a
framework of transparency right so oh if
we do it we might be able to incentivize
people towards transparency and
accountability
now what problems can we have with this
I want to try and anticipate some of the
objections here well first aren't I just
kicking the can down the road with the
prize court right what I haven't said is
who deserves to get a letter of marque
and reprisal
I haven't said what a good prize should
be I haven't said who is allowed to be a
target
who is it okay to go after I haven't
really specified these things and to be
honest I I don't really know the answer
those questions my concern is nobody
really knows the answer to those
questions
this is an insanely complex process and
it's not one we're ever going to design
from the top down we're never going to
come up with a perfect solution and then
implement it what I like about what I'm
proposing here is that if I'm wrong we
can tweak it if we issue a letter of
marque to someone and they turn out to
be irresponsible dicks we can revoke
that letter of marque if we're if we
have too many people going out there we
can lower the prize they're getting we
can reduce the bounty or the prize or
whatever it is we can tweak the
variables to try and get the level of
hacking back to balance that sort of
responsibility with the ability to go
after and mobilize
to help attribute to help get you know
the Intel we need to help address some
of the bad guys out there right so
ultimately what I'm saying is not that I
have all the answers but we should try
and look for a process that would allow
for some discovery what is the right
level what is the right number of people
it involves our hack back because I
don't have the answers to that I'm just
saying no one else does either so if we
have this kind of framework we can now
tweak around the edges and change these
kind of variable to get the outcome
we're looking for now could this be
abused because the White House makes
mistakes yeah absolutely right but again
if we are holding responsibility if you
have to put up a bond then hopefully we
can address that if we are adding a
financial penalty to to to hacking back
and being wrong well then we're not
going to have this crazy like well it's
going to be the wild wild west out there
we are addressing that and again taking
from one of the books on private hearing
art I believe the book was is called
prize and Prejudice which is a pun so
good I hate I didn't come up with it
which is a really self-absorbed emotion
to feel about this book but wonderful
take that actually wrote and looking at
the history of saying that the unvisited
behavior of many early privateers
resulted in abuses that painted the
reputation of both privateers and price
making but one strives courts were
universally recognized as the only way
to determine whether Paes was good and
lawful or not the practice of
privateering regained its legitimacy so
by building that framework around it to
actually build legitimacy into that that
process against we're going back to when
the original objections hacking back
doesn't make sense for shareholder value
we should like you shouldn't be hacking
back you should be hacking back I should
be hacking back that may well be true
but if we have this framework then I'm
not going to I'm going to look at the
ROI and say yeah I shouldn't be doing
that I might be wrong and I can't afford
the penalty if I'm right I'm not able to
prove that I deserve a letter of marque
revisal so I'm not going to do that so
this works itself out and that's another
difference between law enforcement
unlike the Royal to quote from the same
book
unlike the Royal Navy privateers could
not be obliged to attack enemy vessel in
fact most of them took good care to
avoid combat situation this was not lack
of courage on the airport but rather a
realization that exposing himself or the
prizes damage could result in
time-consuming repairs ashore and reduce
their profits as criminal state Hard
Knocks blood & Glory has small
commercial value for an investor while
battle honours may have held an appeal
for naval commanders privateers men kept
an eye on the ledger so if we have a
framework responsibility that has a cost
to going along with this they can we can
balance the supply and demand to where
we actually want a legitimate level of
hacking back ok so let's say you still
absolutely hate the idea of hacking back
it shouldn't be done it causes nothing
but problems I still think you should
support my proposal and here's why if
you hate my proposal while adding you
still if you hate hacking back you still
want to add transparency to this process
and then you can help determine the
acceptable parameters for when this
process is actually legal because one
it's happening hacking back is actually
occurring out there to quote Tom Keller
and chief cyber security officer for
Trend Micro and former a member of
President Obama's Commission on cyber
security state active defense is
happening confirming this belief I
surveyed a recent blackhat it was a 2012
revealed that impressive 36 percent of
respondents admitted to engaging in
retaliatory hacking Blackett may not be
a representative sample but still it
goes to show that this act actually
happening so if you hate the idea of
hacking back then you also want to be
able to add transparency and
accountability of this process and this
is one way to do it right so again I'm
not come out and saying is we need
illegally attacking back for everybody
and I don't necessarily know where the
levels are but we can now add this would
actually also be then a framework for
stopping hacking back because you could
increase then the letter of the
requirements to obtain a letter of
marque and reprisal you could increase
the bond required the money how to put
up front in order
get it you could increase the oversight
so if you hate hacking back I think you
should still be on board of this kind of
proposal because now you can argue for a
higher standard for this levels of
accountability all right so to kind of
summarize this what I'm really arguing
is that the optimal level of hacking
back is greater than here oh I don't
know what it is I don't know what it
should be but I want the debate to move
forward I actually find an incredibly
frustrating this debate has been
pigeonhole between everybody hacks back
or nobody hacks back I don't know why
they got caught up there I find it
puzzling that a community we have but
mostly engineers are saying there are
some problems associated with it so
let's not talk about it I think the
problems we can solve I think the
problems we can address I don't know if
this is exactly the right way to do it
but if we roll this kind of framework
we're now in a situation where we can
adjust we can tweak at the edges we can
adjust this as we go instead of waiting
for someone else to write the law
because again that's going to happen as
well in 2016 the republican national
platform was amended to include
legalizing hacking back as one of the
party's agenda items as someone who
believes hacking back should be legal
for some people at least Hardman wants
to think okay that could be good but how
are they going to do it I have no idea
but if we get a bad law it's going to
take I don't know how long to change and
if they pigeonholes into a corner where
it can't actually do any good then well
the bad guys are going to come up with a
whole new way of attacking us in the
next six months and if we want to go to
legislation hey we want to amend this
law well ok you got a thousand dollars
to come to missed my fundraising dinner
we can sit down and talk about it we'll
address that and if I like your concerns
and I think people will vote for it then
we'll talk about it and the next
legislative session that's not going to
keep up with cybersecurity so I think if
we can be in a situation where we're
actually going to regulate ourselves
instead of waiting for that then we can
get ahead of the problem we can
demonstrate that we can lay out when
hacking
acceptable and maybe we'll disagree on
where that is but we can start to have
that conversation and so there's
throwing off our high on the saying hey
there's some problem clacking back so
let's not talk about it
that's all I interesting some of the
references where I was getting into
learning about how the price courts
actually worked um and with that if
there's any question I've been happy to
take those I think of a little bit of
actual time left problems of any
questions that's them now or of course
I'll be around today as well right and
we do losing idea and then founding in
here we're comparing it to the idea of a
responsible disclosure rights again I
know the contentious debate in the
community okay how long should we give
people and then and so forth and that
doesn't have a court I would manage to
find that um and I think that's great
and if that's a model that we can
emulate as well then that may well work
and I actually wouldn't want to say hey
no they need to have a court because
they seem to be getting by I think the
one difference in this standpoint is
we're stopping the debate I'm hacking
back because these kind of potential
problems disclosure is still happening
now we're obviously still arguing over
what whether it should and what actually
makes it responsible that debate hasn't
gone anywhere but it's still occurring
but knowing what is right I don't think
people in the law I know right yeah and
it's not set by legislation right and
when I say core I saw some in I don't
know if that should be a legal entity if
that should be a 501 3 C staffed with
with with part-time hackers I don't know
what that looks like I don't know if it
has to be an organized body or a set of
ideas that we've loosely agreed on which
is probably what it kind of happened
with with the closure on you oh yeah if
there is actual no right right yeah and
the way I framed it there's this kind of
organizing body to do that I don't know
if it's a harm percent required and
again I won't claim to know exactly what
this will end up looking like or should
look like I don't know but I'm hoping at
least kickstart what it should look like
yeah um okay so what do you gain from
from going after the bad guys well
stopping a bad guy may be worth that in
and of itself right if you're the one
that's under direct attack so that could
be one the other thing could be two is
that um if you look at a lot of like
research firms and everything there's
some great publicity in doing that right
and if you look at a lot of different
security companies their blogs are will
happily take credit for when you know
they help stop this now or take down
this botnet what my colleagues included
right
and the ship itself yeah right right
right and I don't and there's yeah so
you're not one get that back if you have
an attack right
so yeah hacking back isn't going to make
it pull it's not going to make you whole
right that's not going to be the
incentive and and frankly I it's not
like going after pirates as a private
here was was possible for everybody out
there frankly I'm actually the look of
it probably sixty to seventy percent of
the people who went out there and became
pirate hunters were not profitable
alright but some were wildly probable
right so the word I would sort of
incentivize that now there other ways we
can in some way so it's not to make you
whole necessarily but maybe you do want
to stop those guys or maybe they are
such a pain in the ass that people are
willing to put up a bounty for whoever
does take them down so there are
different ways we could structure in the
pepper if that's what it takes to do go
out there but again I don't know what
that should be that's one of things we
can tweak along along the way all right
okay yeah crowd funded an audit of
TrueCrypt right right now it's a really
good example and if we were all being
just kicked around by the same adversary
I absolutely see that happening as well
and so hey if you got spam and your spam
filter from these addresses want to kick
five bucks in this thing that will put
off the bounty and then if someone takes
them down then they can they can take
this right so we could actually
structure that you can kind of do that
today but I think what we want is also
the responsibility to go with it right
but if we are putting together a
Kickstarter if you're doing that you
have the opportunity saying here are the
parameters for when and it will pay out
it's not just hey I took them down they
will prove it right and I think that
would fall into the same kind of
parameter so I don't have to be a legal
court it could be a bunch of people
putting together a Kickstarter it'd be
the same kind of framework
I don't know how legal that is but it's
one way that we could address it right
they do and I think they'd be pretty
interested if they could actually you
know start to hunt some of these people
down and shut them down right so I do
think there'd be an incentive
I don't know if every piece of spam you
get is going to result in people being
mobilized against them that's obviously
not the case right but there I think
there are certainly cases where people
be interested in passing the Hat so to
speak to get people interested in going
after these people and maybe that means
finding them in a tributing and going at
but maybe it means shutting down their
server maybe it means gathering enough
Intel that we can share from a threat
Intel perspective to be able to stop
these attack like look great because
listen maybe it's not shut down that
server maybe it's reverse engineer the
DGA and make that algorithm public so
we'll get into everybody's feeds right
it's not just going kick down their door
right
that's ultimate legally problematic to
be certain and then ultimately probably
not a great use everyone time when we
talk about hacking back there's a lot of
ways to do that it might just be
blocking IP address maybe we can open
source a DGA
so that everyone can now you know
respond to that maybe it means a co
daughter that's another really good
example
any other question well thank you guys
for coming out thank you to b-sides and
all the volunteers who are doing this a
lot of fun appointment together super
nervous about talking about something so
controversial thank you guys for the
great question because I've had a lot of
fun talking about this over the past
couple days and look forward to any
other questions you have I'll be around
the rest today thank you
[Applause]