all right
[Music]
it's better if I'm not that particularly
sharp focus all right
that's that no whatever I just rather be
closer to the this is a better group
dynamic are we good we live all right
good morning everyone thanks for coming
we did a little you know schedule change
at the last minute because Chris Robert
had Roberts had some flight delay this
morning he is on his way and he's
promising to stop at a liquor store
because he owes me but I I took his slot
name of the talk is more Tales from the
Crypt analyst my name is Jeff man
there's my contact information if you're
interested I repeated at the end if
you're still interested I got a lot to
get through this morning
so I'm going to apologetically talk very
quickly just very quickly I work for a
company called online business systems
they pay my way to come out here and
speak at conferences so I like to give
them a nod because they're very
appreciative of me doing this and I'm
very appreciative of them letting me so
please give online a quick round of
applause if you would please thank you
we do consulting we do security
consulting in the compliance field we
have security testers we have managed
security services we're always hiring if
anybody's interested I'm happy to pass
your name along it's all I'll say about
them I've been in the information
security field for about 37 years this
is my background a good chunk of that my
formative years were at NSA the National
Security Agency which is kind of what
this talks about today I do want to
apologize because as I was putting this
talk together and trying to make it
interesting and trying to find cool
screenshots for you know the slides I
realize you know back in the day
we're going back into the mid early to
mid 90s this is how we took screenshot
so please bear with me if the graphics
aren't up to the usual caliber of AK on
top I'm gonna try to involve you guys
today and interject some important dates
in history this is a little bit of
audience feedback audience participation
we're gonna try it out real quickly add
eight flashes on the screen you get to
shout out why this data is important in
history anyone know anyone have any idea
I'm not gonna give you a whole lot of
time to think because I got a lot of
slides go through give up wait for the
laugh track alright another thing I'm
throwing in this talk today because I
had this idea a couple weeks ago and I
knew Circle City comm was going to be
doing the the mental health hackers here
something that's really important I'm
sure we've all known people that have
had struggles in this industry some very
severely and some very permanently so I
wanted to as I was going through this
talk I'm going to interject and I don't
know when because I threw in the slides
yesterday and I'm not I don't have my my
crux of seeing what the next slide is
but there's gonna be some occasional
slides when they pop up I'll tell you
why so just be on the lookout the the
nature of this talk originally there was
a Tales from the Crypt analyst talk and
is this is all about the ten years that
I spent at NSA from 1986 to 1996 while I
was there primarily or the good chunk of
the time I was a Crypt analyst a
cryptographer I actually worked on both
sides offense and defense as it were and
also got into which is the crux of this
talk doing security testing penetration
testing vulnerability assessments the
original talk Tales from the Crypt I
went through the first several years of
my career and I sort of had three
different careers at NSA three different
duty stations if you will very quickly
the first couple years at NSA just a
recap in case you haven't seen the
original
I was a cryptographer on the InfoSec
side of the house working in the manual
cryptosystems branch we produced paper
products primarily one-time pads one of
my customers very early on asked me hey
it takes us hours to write out these
messages encrypting them and decrypting
them with a one-time pad but we've got
this computer sitting on the desk
couldn't we use that to do the
encryption decryption and I thought sure
why not that seems reasonable it's not a
complicated algorithm you just need to
have the key so I ended up producing
what to my knowledge is the first
software base crypto system that NSA
produced which was no small feat and I
share that because at NSA at the time in
the InfoSec InfoSec was responsible at
NSA for producing all the cryptic Africa
quipment that that was used by the US
the military the you know the government
and it was all boxes it was all hardware
in fact I had a chief scientist say to
me one time there's no such thing as
software it's really all hardware so in
you know thinking about this talk which
ultimately is about the beginning of
hacking and pen testing at NSA I thought
back to this incident and I thought you
know I didn't think about it at the time
but I was really hack in the system
because I had to take requirement specs
that were written for hardware and sort
of jerry-rigged them and rewrite them to
make them make sense for software so I
was sort of one of my formative
experiences early on I also had a
customer that used a one-time pad with
the the algorithm that they used for
encryption and decryption was 26 offsets
of the alphabet reversed that's called a
visionnaire table or a Visionnaire
square they memorized the algorithm
which the the table actually produces
unique three letter combinations I did
not have them memorized so I just made
this little simple aid to help me do the
encryption and decryption process and
they liked it so much we ended up making
like 15,000 of them I gave this talk a
little while ago with cypher con and a
friend of mine came up to me who happens
to be in the room I don't I don't know
William if I should say your name or not
but he asked me have you ever heard
about this Diana cryptosystem that the
Special Forces used and I'm like well
that name doesn't sound familiar to me
but I googled it and I found this site
and I thought to myself gee that looks
really familiar and and you know I told
William I said you know I'm the guy that
invented it so long story short I got in
touch with this guy that was making
these wooden versions of my visionnaire
wheel and he was so happy to hear about
you know hear from the inventor and hear
the real story about how it came about
he sent me a bunch of these wooden
crypto puzzles you can go on Etsy and
find this guy they're really cool
puzzles I forgot to put them in my bag
otherwise I would have shared them with
you but we had a really good
conversation via email my ultimate goal
is I want to make sure that this gets
into the National Cryptologic Museum
because there's not a lot of InfoSec
history at the National Cryptologic
Museum and as far as I know the Special
Forces use these wheels for about 10
years at least 10 years so they
remembered it and somebody thought it
should be memorialized in wood so why
not put it in the museum that's actually
a picture of one of the production
models I have a prototype I have it in
my bag if anybody wants to see it I
carry it with me wherever I go because
you never know when you need to encrypt
with a one-time pad one of my early
bosses he called me a loose cannon
looking back on it's like yeah I had the
hacker mentality even before I knew it
my second career I became a crypt
analysis intern and
one over work on the operation side of
the house and I happened to be there
during the first Gulf encounter which
was called Desert Shield Desert Storm
so not a whole lot on that but that's
just a quick recap of what I did in my
early days of the my formative years at
NSA ultimately I was certified as a
Crypt analyst at NSA that's really the
only certification I carry to this day
which leads me into the crux of this
talk which is the last chapter of my
time at NSA which started as my last
tour as an intern I went back to InfoSec
and I ended up working for an office
called fielded systems evaluation field
those field and systems evaluations was
interesting because somebody had the
brilliant idea that you know NSA had a
reputation for producing all the crypto
and we produced the best crypto the best
little black boxes in the world they
were unbreakable they were perfect
everything worked fine but somebody
realized well the way that we were very
often successful on the operations side
of the house was we were able to read
communications from adversaries and from
foreign countries because the people
that used them did silly things like
they didn't change default settings or
they found bypasses around the crypto or
even something like a one-time pad which
if as the name implies you use the key
one time but for you know conservation
efforts or whatever reason every once in
a while somebody might use a page of key
you know maybe for a day maybe for a
week maybe for a month I guess they
thought they were saving paper when you
do that you introduce vulnerabilities
which makes the underlying message
ultimately solvable that's a lot of what
cryptanalysis is so somebody had the
idea of well gee if we're doing it to
them how do we know they're not doing it
to us so there was this whole office
that was looking at how our systems were
being used in the field so it was a lot
of observation you know looking at the
the way that 18 19 20 year-old
communications come kamo soldiers were
using the things in the field this is
one of the devices that I was actually
working on
from an evaluation perspective not that
that's a big deal but that's really what
I was working on Oh another date this is
a date that changed history anybody have
an idea what it is when once going twice
flipper chip no this is the day that
gave us all our occupation the day that
the internet became popular in public
the day that mosaic came out and that's
actual I know this is that screenshot
thing that's actually what the first
mosaic browser looked like anybody
remember this thing few people you're
all you're old like me so and then you
know as soon as the internet became
popular what came along hackers people
who were trying to figure out how to
break it people that were figuring out
how to use the hidden features and not
so hidden features back in those days I
think it was interesting and it's
interesting to me at least in the early
days we called it Internet security
nowadays we call it that ugly c-word
that a lot of us don't like but in the
beginning the idea was organizations
primarily governments and research for
universities and military contractors
that's who was using the internet back
then you know they were talking amongst
themselves but it wasn't terribly public
but when the public when the general
masses came on board the belief was well
everybody's got networks and computers
already all we have to do is protect it
from the evil internet so it was all
about creating a barrier creating a
perimeter and you know much like
military tactics if we just build a wall
like a firewall we'll be safe oh here's
one of these insertions I want to just
interject while I'm going through this
talk I asked my wife to she does
scrapbooking and does a lot of photo
albums which I'm very grateful for but I
want to just interject while I was doing
all this stuff at NSA I also had a life
one of the benefits of working for the
government was both mostly had a
nine-to-five job so you know while I was
getting into fielded systems evaluations
and all
getting into hacking at NSA I was also
married buying a house raising children
so these are just some shots you know
I'm in here first and foremost I'm a dad
I'm a husband I have a family
that's me with hair and me without a
beard and and back in the early days I
grew my hair long what was left of it
and that's almost like a mullet and
probably shouldn't have put that picture
up there I'm sorry there anyway there
was a small group of us in this office
doing fielded systems evaluations that
started focusing on what we called it
the time networked systems and one of
our great inspirations was a book that
was out at the time called the Cuckoo's
egg anybody ever read the book heard the
book heard of the book if you haven't
read it I encourage you to find it and
get a copy it's a story of this guy and
this actually happened you know cliff
stalls his name in 1986 he actually
discovered I'll make a long story short
no spoilers but he he was working for a
university and figured out that bad guys
had broken into the university systems
to steal government secrets and he was
able to track them down and figure out
and find them and they were ultimately
exposed I figured whether they were
prosecuted or not because they were
spies after all
I bring this up because this really was
a motivation and also because just a
little while ago I actually got to meet
cliff Stoll I was at a conference in
Halifax Nova Scotia and he's as zany as
he comes across if you've ever seen
videos of them or seen him live but it
was a fanboy moment for me you know one
of my early inspirations I actually got
to meet and we got to hang out anyway
back back at NSA management got ahold of
things and started learning well you
know there's this thing going on called
hacking and computer security and
internet security and what the
government likes to do very often is
reorganized so they reorganized and they
formed an organization that was called
the systems and network attack center
and I became a part of that
we were designed to be Chris made it
Chris made it if I say hi Chris
there's cups in the back and I am
thirsty proper please so this this
organization was organized as the center
of excellence and and it was designed to
be you know because the government has
to management has to put their fingers
on it we were going to go real deep
where that we're the best in the world
of crypto were in the best of the world
at everything else so we might as well
be the best of the world at doing all
this computer security internet type of
security stuff there was a group of us
that we got together and we said we're
gonna we're gonna learn how to hack
we're gonna learn how to break into
systems we're gonna learn how to break
into networks and it's all sorts of fun
management had a different vision they
just figured all we need is a bunch of
these you know smart guys who'd be
better than the whole world well you
know I don't care how good you are if
you get 10 20 50 people together you're
not going to compete against the world
where there's hundreds and thousands of
people's out there doing all this stuff
and that's proven true I think but this
was sort of the mentality that we were
up against from the very beginning here
thank you that's great thank you this is
why you should always pay it forward and
and and occupy time slots in a pinch I
don't even really care if I finished my
talk now but you did so there's a small
group of us who've got together at the
time the organization that sort of owned
the internet or owned the network for
the for the DoD was the Air Force they
they were responsible for making it run
and they were the first group that put
together what was you know a Security
Operations Center a sock they were the
first ones that started getting into
like you know how do you detect bad
things that are happening on the network
so we decided you know learn from them
we wanted to see what they were doing
get set up so we took a road trip we
went to meet some of these guys these
are some of our early
Mentors I'll just have to tell you their
names the person on the left
captain's ice he unfortunately passed
away about two years ago and on the
right Captain Waddell I actually had a
chance to talk to him as I was putting
this talk together we reminisced over
all the times they were putting together
what was essentially the first sock and
like many government employees did back
in the day they went out and formed a
company anybody ever hear the will group
they lasted all of about what 18 months
and they they were quickly acquired by a
company that is known neo world over as
being a security company anybody know
what company acquired them Cisco
trivia that's all on full o so we took a
trip they were down in San Antonio we
took a trip to San Antonio they were at
an Air Force Base so we got to see cool
sights because we were vacationing a
little bit it was a boondoggle those are
actually some of the guys that I worked
with there the sr-71 spy plane that had
only been recently Declassified so I was
the first time we got to see one for
real that plane was primarily
responsible for winning Desert Storm so
quickly the I think it's the a-10
warthog of course we saw the sights we
saw the Alamo San Antonio is a really
cool Riverwalk and if you go to the
Riverwalk and this is very important in
hacker lore we discovered the 46 ounce
margarita and I recommend if you are
going to do any kind of security testing
penetration testing hacking whatever we
call this stuff obviously alcohol is
involved another excursion I took I took
vacations with my family it wasn't all
work I put this particular slide here
because I remember being in San Antonio
calling my wife to see how she was doing
because I had just finished like a 25
ounce steak dinner and then was drinking
this forty six ounce margarita and she
was telling me about how she had like
split a can of tuna with her and the
four kids and I'm like wow it's I'll
make sure I'll take you on a vacation so
work-life balance I
always do it well but I always tried to
make up for it
so remember work-life balance our
biggest takeaway what we took you know
other than you know smart guys the you
know we kind of knew what they did in
terms of the technical methodologies and
things like that what we had learned at
the time but they had an office
structure that wasn't just cubicle after
cubicle they had pushed their cubicles
to the corners and literally had a
roundtable so we've recreated that in
our new office in the snack and the idea
was if anybody was working on a project
and had a question or had a problem and
they needed help they would simply any a
lot of us could simply call round table
we all drop what we were doing literally
just spin our chairs come to the middle
and we'd collaborate and try to figure
out the problem it was a great way to
work collaboratively back in the days
when people worked in offices we very
quickly realized that we didn't fit in
with everybody else we tried to create
our own space and our own personalities
we were trying to live the hacker
methodology excuse me men they occurred
to me I should actually drink this
and this is sort of the story of what
came to be known as the pit we as part
of the reorganization we moved locations
these are office buildings that are just
outside just west of BWI Airport
Maryland and when we moved into our
office part of the part of like the
living the hacker culture was we decided
to give our office a nickname and we
called it the pit and the pit was simply
what we called our office it was located
in this particular building in that
particular corner and I forget I think
was on the second or third floor it's
been a few years you can drive by these
buildings today they still exist why I
bring this up is a couple years ago a
book came out called dark territories
anybody read this book heard of this
book recommended reading in this book
there was a chapter called eligible
receiver which I'll get to later what
what the title means and in that chapter
one
members of the pit got the book and read
it and then emailed all of us and said
hey we're in a book so I like to do it
as a dramatic reading for you but in the
middle it's it says during its most
sensitive drills the red team worked out
of a chamber called the pit which was so
secret that few people at NSA knew it
existed and even they couldn't enter
without first passing through to
combination locked doors well that was
very impressive and kind of accurate we
did work in an office we called it the
pit and it didn't have to lock the doors
though I don't know where that came from
but apparently somehow my humble
beginnings as a hacker pen tester at NSA
somehow grew into folklore that made it
into a book so that should be
everybody's aspiration is to make it
into a book someday and the pit although
that's what we called our office it was
really six guys and we were all just
trying to figure out the stuff that
we're still trying to figure out today
it was just a group of guys that were
trying to be hackers and trying to make
the world better by breaking into things
and telling our customers how to prevent
the bad guys from breaking in one thing
that we discovered though was nobody
ever really done this before in an
organized fashion so there wasn't sans
courses to take there weren't sans
instructors in the room listening to you
give this talk so we had to kind of
figure things out for our own selves and
so we had to come up with methodologies
but while we were doing that of course
we still had management oversight and
management sometimes had different ideas
which that's what management has to do
and they had some concerns and there was
sort of two primary concerns well one
that came more of an issue later on but
it's simply you know the whole issue
that NSA does what NSA does to foreign
countries and and
and persons and not US citizens the
other one was more political in nature
of NSA had never done something like
this before
you know it was new and different and
maybe some of the managers you know well
you know hacking was just kind of
mysterious and they didn't understand it
so that they they wanted us to follow
rules and in a bureaucracy rules are
time-consuming and and and and so one of
the biggest problems was if we wanted to
do some sort of a test against a target
against a customer we had to go through
all sorts of bureaucratic permission
gathering which back in those days was
done on paper and so paper had to pass
from desk to desk to desk secretary to
manager secretary to manager and it
would often literally take a month for
us to get permission to do what it was
that we were itching to do and to be
quite honest honest might have already
done that nobody knew it because there
was no such thing as intrusion detection
back then anyway we came up with
methodologies you know we started out by
doing reconnaissance we wanted to know
our target we wanted to figure out what
we had to work with what was out there
we caught a recon these days you might
be more familiar with the term Osen or
open source intelligence it's
essentially the same thing we would do
our initial discovery doing some sort of
network probing and find out the targets
find out what they were you know what
ports and services they were talking on
things like that what kind of you know
if it was on a network you know we'd
find out trust relationships find out
basically whatever we could find in
terms of what our target was so we could
develop an attack strategy and then
execute the TAC and have lots of fun and
you know get giddy when we got root or
to use the vernacular of the day Poppa
shell and then we report our findings
and move on hasn't really changed a
whole lot today somebody I mean you
teach the methodology is it changed a
whole lot
not a whole lot I mean we didn't invent
it we just you know there's a right way
to do it and there's a methodical way to
do it and
it hadn't been written down at that time
so we just kinda had to come up with it
on our own what I want to impress upon
you too though and this is a little bit
of a history lesson is we didn't have
all the tools that you guys have
available today all these things didn't
exist or we didn't have access to even
something is fundamental as nmap and I
had to stop and check myself when I was
putting together this talk to find out
when did nmap come out and it came out
after I had left NSA another
interjection you know while we're having
fun working I still went home and got
involved in family activities and
carving pumpkins and all that kind of
stuff those are my kids they're all
grown up now I want to share with you a
little bit about what you know I've told
you what we didn't have now I want to
share a little bit about what we did
have in terms of our tradecraft and I do
have to give a disclaimer here an
additional burden that we had or
challenge that we had is the way NSA
rules work rules worked was if we were
targeting a system anything that we did
to that system no matter how benign had
to be classified at the level of the
system that we were targeting so in
trying to tell you what stuff we were
using back then what I will say is I'm
not going to tell you what we were using
necessarily I'm gonna tell you what was
commonly available at the time
nudge-nudge wink-wink with me all right
so we had these things called Network
sniffers they were appliances they were
hardware they weighed 2030 pounds we
would roll them around on a cart and
plug them into a network prior to
Ethernet there was other types of
network cables and we had that had the
right attachments they were quite
cumbersome but they were quite useful we
had available to us at some point early
vulnerability scanning tools Satan being
one of the first ones anybody remembers
Satan Satan is actually still out there
somewhere I should put the Euro URL up
on this sometime you can download it I
don't know if you can get it to run on
anything because it's yeah actually
compile the code does anybody do that
anymore I don't know but it's out there
one of the things I do as an aside is
I'm a host on security weekly in case
you didn't know that we had a chance to
interview the authors of Satan last I
think was last November or December does
it say there
you can look it up on YouTube it's
episode 584 another I've had a lot of
fanboy moments in the last year this was
another one of them because I got to
meet the guys that wrote Satan you know
they're like that's the original tool
that we got to use great guys great
conversation I think that's one of our
best interviews that we've done oh
another date anyone I've been I've been
stumping everyone so far something
called bug track came out in 1993 it's
that old it was later taken over by
Aleph one in 1996 but it's been around
since 1993 how many years of that 26
years Netscape bugs so some of you might
be asking what is bug track and we'll
get to that right after we take a dip in
the pool
remember work-life balance don't always
have take time out to have a life
another this is an example of bug track
what bug track was was a way to report
vulnerabilities and issues with software
and code and hardware and whatever you
were dealing with and it was done pretty
much by a mailing list email there used
to be this thing called email that
people would communicate with and so you
know you would write a question send it
to the group and hopefully somebody
would be familiar with the problem and
could answer you know give you guidance
or they might be interested and do some
research and you could work
collaboratively and in the very
beginning I don't remember that it was
very particularly searchable but people
would gather all the bugs
data and eventually put it into
searchable databases where you could you
know if you wanted to investigate a
particular topic or a particular system
or application you can do that there was
also organizations that would public
advisories if they saw hacker activity
bad guy activity they'd report about
computer emergency response teams I
don't know if you can read that if you
get down there there should be a chuckle
at some point this is a bonafide sir
divisor that was released in July 4th
1996 1999 1996 it's kicking in and it's
all about malware that could affect
alien spaceships which is the plot of
you know how we won the day in
Independence Day so back then certs had
a sense of humor they had time for a
sense of humor
I mentioned reconnaissance we did
open-source collection back in those
days I said we didn't have you know all
the stuff we have available to us now we
had some rudimentary search databases
that were available there were mostly
searching databases because that's where
information was kept large mainframes
had large databases at large
universities and they would set up very
rudimentary search engines that you
could use things like Archie you also
back then every IP address for every
system was internet routable we didn't
do Net masking then and you if you
wanted to be on the Internet you had to
purchase or lease I piece address space
Class A's B's C's subnets and everything
had an address so you could look up you
know if you had a target that was X Y Z
dot gov since this is in the military at
the time or dot mil you could look up
and see what XY Z dot mil owned in terms
of address space and that would help you
figure out what your targets were going
to be gopher is another search engine we
didn't have Google but what a kick-ass
search engine back in the day was
something called Alta Vista it
it was light years ahead of its time and
it was built on systems that were
quicker than any other systems and then
of course you know we had the good old
Netscape Navigator Nick netscape browser
where you could start to do you know
things over the web rather than things
over these you know most of these other
search engines I go for Archie they were
they were command driven from a shell
where you were doing something like hell
netting to a database and then of course
the original Yahoo it might remember the
original Yahoo one of the features was
they had a click a button I forget what
it looked like and I don't have a
picture of it but there was somewhere on
it was like because nobody was on the
internet back then and web browsing was
kind of new they had kind of a roulette
button where you could click and just go
to a random website because they just
wanted people who experience the
Internet go and search what's out there
discover it was wonderful we would
acquire targets using things again we
didn't have end maps so we had something
called strobe strobe was a tool that was
written that would do TCP port scanning
so you could figure out what services
are live what systems were out there
you'd figured out the address space so
now you could figure out how you were
going to get to it
trivia quiz and buddy know who wrote
strobe I didn't remember it either until
I saw the name strobe was actually
written by Julian Assange I don't know
why that's interesting I just when I was
looking up and doing the research and I
saw that and like that's why the guy's
name sounds familiar because every time
you would launch strobe a little you
know welcome to strobe version whatever
written by Julianna sighs like I knew
that guy's name sounded familiar other
search engines you know looking up
domain registrations and you know people
would name systems and things like that
and of course nslookup which again
nothing was private everything was at
you know everything was addressable and
reachable and so and then a name service
lookup here's the IP address what's the
name of the system that's using that IP
address we had rudimentary
network mapping tools and and it was
kind of fun didn't really give you a
whole lot but it gave you an idea of
sort of the topology sometimes another
date anyone at least somebody's guessing
first time the pants came down and the
crack came out crack is an early
password cracking tool one of the one of
the things we bit did back then
was crack passwords and that was a way
to get into systems of course that
problems been solved and passwords are
no longer an issue back in those days
passwords were kept with user IDs and
something called the Etsy password file
there was no shadowing there was no
hiding home I blacked out real people's
names but you know those are the user
IDs and then a colon and then a hash
which is the password so you can copy
these files and run crack and figure out
how you know guess what all the
passwords were it was originally
designed to be used by system
administrators to make sure users were
using good passwords not easily
guessable or breakable passwords but
again passwords have been solved now so
this is just ancient history one of the
common techniques back in the day of how
we would break into primarily UNIX
systems was to find applications and and
services that were running on the UNIX
system running was something that was
called set UID set UID meant that the
program even if you a mere user executed
the program it would run as the owner of
the program which very often was the
root account and what you could do with
that if you found a program like this if
you could get it - hiccup if you could
get it to halt execution very often it
would execute it would exit in the state
of the ownership that it had so a very
common way of getting a root shell was
just to find one of these scripts and
figure out how to get a way that alter
hold on
it will make it's making a better or a
figure a way to halt the execution it
would drop you on a root shell you
were done you had root so that's kind of
a very very very quick rudimentary
snapshot of what we had to work with
what we were dealing with in terms of
the tools in the tradecraft so I wanted
to share a little bit of our growing
pains
I mentioned this very early on go into a
little bit more detail we had this sort
of overarching challenge that NSA
doesn't do what NSA does to u.s.
citizens and of course the idea of
testing systems you're testing us
systems so there were some people that
had concern about that but there are
ways around you know getting get not
getting around the law but there were a
waste to meet the laws but do it in a
way where everybody was aware and that's
why we took a month to get permissions
to do things another date
PGP PGP was revolutionary and it was
very scary for NSA because it was free
encryption Phil Zimmermann and in fact
got into a lot of trouble because back
in those days crypto was classified as
munitions and therefore not exportable
to foreign powers and then PGP comes
along free to everybody they they the US
government tried to prosecute him for
years for violating basically committing
espionage by allowing munitions to be
exported outside of the US but I have a
different story to tell about PGP PGP
was impactful to NSA because we you know
because we built the crypto for our
customers which was the Armed Forces
there was a day when one of the one of
the branches of the military came to us
came to our management and said why are
we spending millions of dollars for NSA
to develop something to secure our email
communications why can't we just use
this PGP thing it's free so there was
this literal on hands on deck call from
our higher level highest levels of
management everybody was supposed to
drop what they were doing and
everybody's supposed to work on coming
up with an attack against PGP some a
group of guys that actually worked in
the office next to ours or across the
hallway from us came up with a very
clever attack against PGP and they were
hailed as heroes they're given all sorts
of cash awards they were taken down to
DC and the Pentagon and had to do
briefings about this wonderful attack
that they came up with let me tell you
about what the attack real quickly I
learned about it some months afterwards
where they did like a brown-bag lunch
and learn just for us minions that
worked with them they described how they
took a I want to say at the time it was
word star which was our word processing
document application at the time they
found some unused byte space in the
document and they were able to insert
some code in that document that would
extract the public and private key rings
that PGP relies upon and attach it to a
document and email it out the next time
so all they had to do was send this
email as an attachment to somebody get
them to click on it and open it it would
launch the attack and they would steal
the key rings PGP is broken does this
sound familiar to anyone what is what
did I just describe a phishing attack
right this was like 1995 so if you think
phishing attacks are new I beg beg to
disagree with you
I had the when I heard this lunch
briefing and they described this to him
and they got to the Q&A time I raised my
hand I said wouldn't this attack work
against our stuff too and they kind of
stopped and thought I said yeah it
probably would and I said then why are
we making such a big deal out of this
there they got very indignant said well
we were passed with breaking PGP not our
own stuff okay whatever I actually again
another fanboy moment I got to meet Phil
Zimmerman last fall I was down in
Atlanta at the Issa International
Conference now I got to tell him that
story he got a kick out of it
so we're buds now too I've met all my
heroes now I think so let me share our
share I said I wasn't going to share one
any of this top-secret stuff we did but
I do want to share one with you so you
know let's not let this leave this room
suffer it's being recorded
I'm going to share some of our
top-secret tradecraft are you ready for
this was our primary attack tool you
know it's it's that whole Paul's for
effect
imagine a world where you have to wait a
month to get permission to issue a ping
command and imagine how that didn't sit
well with us so what we had to do was
start working with our lawyers our
general counsel because they were the
ones that were not making the rules but
they were enforcing the rules or helping
us to find ways to work within the
boundaries that we had been provided and
their original idea was well just tell
us ahead of time all the different
tricks and techniques and tools you use
and we'll kind of pre approve them so
that when you have a job come up you
know you'll just sort of click through
an ala carte menu and tell us you know
we're gonna do a couple pings and we're
gonna do a couple of this and a couple
of that and we know what those are and
so we'll prove it much more quickly and
for some reason I was the one that
either volunteered or got stuck with
working with the lawyers I think it's
because I have a brother that's a lawyer
and I felt like I could speak their
language so I ended up working with the
lawyers and trying to explain to them
that you know it's not that simple
because it's a very imprecise science
this is an art form you don't know what
you're gonna do until you encounter what
you encounter and you're not going to
know what you're encountering until you
start probing and looking at it and of
course you know ping was considered the
reason why I was considered top-secret
was it was ruled by the lawyers to be an
act of attack because it elicited a
response from the target that was the
mentality that we were walking into you
know they had their ideas we had our
ideas what I ended up doing was we ended
up meeting on a weekly basis this was a
popular TV show at the time home
improvement and the show within the show
was called tool time so I started a
weekly meeting with the Gen
council just teaching them all about our
trade craft and all about the things
that we did and just sort of debunking
and and demystifying this thing called
network security or Internet security
which was really just teaching them how
to use unix and teaching them about you
know things like file permissions and
and things like trust relationships
which was basically just how unix worked
but it was magical to him it was
eye-opening and in fact you know he
would you know we were on networks
within a network and we were on sub
networks that were supposedly isolated
but very often I would demonstrate the
violation of trust by modifying his file
right in front of him his login file so
that I could gain access later and then
would do things to him for a week and
then come back and show him but one of
the most eye-opening things for him was
we looked at his simple directory
structure and things that he had in
terms of work product as a lawyer that
he thought was super secret that nobody
could see very often were in world
readable directory files than anybody in
the whole you know organization could
look at that was eye-opening for and
while I was doing all that I still did
stuff with family word got out you know
we were doing this fun stuff you know at
first it was in s NSA only and it was
within the DoD community you know the
Armed Forces we're doing it and I don't
really remember the details but somehow
other agencies found out so we were
approached by the Department of Justice
this isn't actually a clip of an article
that came out a couple years after I
left it talks about what I'm about to
describe to you but basically we were
approached by the Department of Justice
they wanted us to look at their internet
presence and do what we were calling a
vulnerability assessment or a
vulnerability a threat assessment
against their internet presence of
course we had to go to the lawyer's
because you know we're not supposed to
do that to US citizens and especially
not unclassified systems NSA was allowed
to do what NSA did traditionally to
classified systems the organization that
was responsible
unclassified systems at the time was
NIST but it was well understood at the
time that NIST didn't have the the
capability that they didn't have that
anyone that had the chops nobody was
doing this at NIST so it was very common
we learned through the lawyers that NIST
would sort of you know do a little
handoff to NSA asking for a special
favor anyway I went to the lawyer and
learned what the rules were and
basically it said well it needs to be a
cabinet-level sort of personal favor
from the Department of Justice through
the Department of Defense so a letter
came from the address to the person
responsible for this stuff which was an
assistant secretary of defense at the
time and it actually it was signed by
the Attorney General at the time Janet
Reno and it said hey could you do that
cool stuff that those kids are doing at
NSA to us please and I was working with
you know it was like a three months
process to get all these you know memos
written you know I don't know if you
know it but you know the the people that
write these letters they don't write
them they're written by the lawyers and
people that work for them and it all
gets negotiated down to every jot and
tittle and word and ultimately was
signed by our director going back to say
yeah we'd be happy to do this you can
see my name is listed as the point of
contact I I kept all this information
because you should always keep things in
writing that are that are kind of edgy
right before we got a chance to do it
this thing happened this was the first
hack of a government website it was a
big deal back in the day although in the
grand scheme of things all they did was
website two-faced but they didn't steal
personal data
they didn't find out any deep secrets
about what the Department of Justice was
doing and we could go off on a tangent
there but we won't what it was at the
time was you know the Department of
Justice which had their own network
which had their own internet facing
systems and they'd set up their own web
server it was defaced by hackers and
they discovered this over a weekend
and of course what do you do when your
system has been compromised you pulled
the plug you wipe it yeah and and you
start over but I got a call from the guy
that I've been working with on a Monday
morning and he said help and so I set
out to find out how to help them so I
you know a group of us from the pit went
down to DC we spent a couple days with
them I'm making a long story short but
we were there for about three days we
weren't finding a whole lot there were
no forensics courses there were no
forensics methodologies at the time so
we were kind of learnt you know the
first thing we learned was you know you
destroyed all the evidence so we really
don't have anything to look at but there
were some other you know devices on the
network you know other systems that week
we were looking at but we were there for
about three days when I got a call from
somebody who had stayed behind it the
pit that said shit's hit the fan you
guys got to drop everything and just
come back now and so we dropped
everything we went back we were escorted
into the Deputy Director of NSA's
conference room and the lawyer that I'd
been working with for the previous year
proceeded to read us the riot act and
tell us about how we had done all sorts
of illegal things because we were doing
things too unclassified systems and
we're not supposed to in NSA isn't
supposed to do what NSA does to u.s.
citizens and we were doing it and we
hadn't gone through the right procedures
and rules
trust me I've gone through the
procedures and rules I had asked the
general counsel what do I need to do to
get there but somebody in the executive
management chain somewhere got their
nose out of joint and blew the whistle
on it it became a big deal I do a whole
talk on this but the bottom line was
they tried to get us in trouble and they
and because I was the ringleader they
tried to fire me
and and they couldn't because every time
I interviewed somebody from security
they said really that's it that's what
you were doing you were just trying to
help I was like yeah and then everybody
dismissed it it was traumatic for me at
the time but the upshot was one of the
things we learned was and I became a
contributor to one of the
first sins institute documents on
incident handling i think i think they
listed me as like an editor or reviewer
but it was you know putting out the
basic steps like don't destroy the
evidence you know pull the plug if you
must off the internet but preserve
everything take it offline so you can
look at it the upshot though was we were
ultimately sort of vindicated and we
were we were we were escorted back into
that conference room and talked to by
senior management and they said look we
love what you guys are doing and and
we'd love for you to do that here but if
you're gonna do it here you have to do
it by our rules so a lot of us just up
and left myself included the six people
that were originally members of the pit
two of them are still at NSA four of us
are out in private practice the only
other person that I'm allowed to say who
was a member of the pit is Ron gula if
you don't know Ron gula he was the
founder of tenable network security the
authors of necess the third one of the
other people out in public he he has on
his LinkedIn profile that he did NSA
pentesting and I have yet to talk to him
to include his picture on this slide but
I'm working on it
the fourth guy very private guy he'll
never never agree to be associated with
any of us but that's us so you know as
an epilogue you know we've all you know
many of us have been out in the private
sector for many years I won't even ask
nobody knows what this is but going back
to that book where they wrote about the
pit the chapter four which was eligible
receiver eligible receiver happens from
June 9th to the 13th you know about
three and a half days back in 1997 I
left in October of 96
what eligibles receiver was was a joint
NSA wide hack of the DoD it was designed
and set up to be very clandestine not
not anybody you know very few people
knew about it for any of the targets any
of the military services and there was a
lot of coordination with the Pentagon
and so on and so forth and it was
designed to last I think for 14 days and
they had to cut it after three because
they'd already
and everything they talked about it I
guess it was on the 20th anniversary
because it was in the fall of 2017 they
did a symposium called cyber at the
crossroads at the University of Maryland
University College and they got all the
big you know senior management types
that were smarter than all of us
actually doing the work to get together
and talk about it and of course I wasn't
included but what I did learn and I
think that website is still up there
although they've they've pulled down
like the video recordings I think the
guy will email it to you on request but
they basically said nobody from the know
but none of the original members of the
Pitt participated in the eligible
receiver one of the idea was they didn't
want to have the uber elite hackers
doing it they wanted to have just sort
of run-of-the-mill hackers so they
trained the B team to go out and do
eligible receiver so I don't know if I'm
feeling honored by that or feeling
snubbed I haven't decided yet but I was
gone anyway September 1st 1997
that's when nmap came out for all of
those you that love and map those of us
that are were the original members of
the pit we still try to get together
once or twice a year it's usually over
breakfast one of our recent visits one
of the guys is still worked there he
brought some tchotchke for us there's
this place called the National
Cryptologic Museum that's outside of
Fort Meade outside of NSA I encourage
you if you ever come to Maryland to
visit it they have a gift shop where you
can get cool stuff like NSA secret sauce
who doesn't want that and you know you
can get an NSA pen that projects a light
signal which is the NSA seal so that's
not a seal on a cup that's a projection
that's coming from that pen
they got t-shirts they've got they've
got flash whiskey bottles wine glasses
shot glass with all sorts of fun stuff
so you know and it all supports the
civilian welfare fun which gives
employees discount tickets the Orioles
game so that's it in a nutshell problem
I apologize for having to go through
quickly I mean it was three years and
lots of stories to tell I'm going to be
around all week
and happy to tell more stories happy to
go into more details it only cost you a
drink possibly a cigar if you're
interested in learning more about me and
the stories I tell because I've been in
this business forever I mentioned I am
one of the hosts and Paul's security
weekly hack for kids and by familiar
with that for kids yay they put out a
game called Freaker life a year ago and
they let me be one of the what they call
the endocrine isms the face cards that
was most of us last year Vegas getting
together for a group photo so I'm in a
plane I'm in a card game
tribe of hackers came out the beginning
of this year I'm in that book and if
anybody happens to have a copy of that
book with you I'm happy to sign it for
you I have my sharpies with me I
encourage you to get it I am sometimes
escorted by storm troopers when I give
talks so I consider myself a Jedi Master
and two years ago I was invited and this
is a serious semi serious thing people
at at RSA in San Francisco get together
with gene Spafford again one of the you
know there's books that I showed you at
the beginning the Bible was in an
Internet and UNIX security written by
Spafford staff as you go as he's known
to his friends there's a small group of
people mostly old-timers that go to
dinner with them and they call
themselves a cabal of the curmudgeons I
was invited into that group two years
ago and the person that sort of
sponsored me into the group is the guy
on the end there in the red sweater that
I had my arm around he was the one that
represented me into the group and I was
voted in and once you're in you're in
for life the guy that I had my arm
around happens to be the lawyer the
truck that I worked with at NSA that I
tried to teach pentesting and who
ultimately tried to get me fired turns
out because we've we've talks and we
didn't talk for probably 20 years but
I've gotten you know reacquainted with
them and it turns out he was taking a
whole lot more than I was he was he
was providing a lot of cover because you
know he originally when we got back
together
that I forgive you and I'm like wait I'm
supposed to be forgiving you yeah
we're buds now any questions comments
Chris I don't know if I'm taking up your
space but you owe me anyway I got time
for one or two questions comments and
then I'll turn the floor over to Chris
who is finally here otherwise I'm here
all weekend anyone yes when did it all
happen it was like August 96 yeah
any other questions I mean there's like
there's I forget the name of the website
but there's like you know hacker
archives out there you can find it and
they have preserved the original website
as well as the hacked website it gets
you know not suitable for working
conferences if you scroll down on it any
other questions comments they didn't
have a name they didn't have an identity
they were just government weap wants
they were computer scientists and
engineers yes ma'am Laphroaig is good I
also like Lagavulin 16 and whatever
Chris is packing because he usually
brings like 200 things to take but not
today because he was so rough all right
I will yield the floor to the gentleman
from Colorado
you