hello everyone my name is Matteo Utrecht
and today I will be talking about my
latest project called the box pol
reloaded which is using x86 emulation
and stained tracking to disclose to
discover this closure of initialized
memory in operating system kernels so
the agenda for today is first off to
briefly start discussing the
communication between user and kernel
mode in operating systems and what are
the common pitfalls that are related to
them and then introduce the box pawn
reloaded project the principles behind
it how it works in general and how it
uses the full system emulation to
discover any kind of bugs then I will
talk about the system specific
approaches which are specific to both
Windows and Linux which are the two
operating systems that I analyzed I will
talk about the results in in those
operating systems and then wrap up with
some ideas for future work on how this
project can be extended and improved and
how we can deal with this type of issues
in the future a few words about myself I
am a low-level security researcher
interest obviously in all sorts of
vulnerability research and software
exploitation I work at freedom 0 at
Google in my spare time I place in CDF's
as part of the dragon sector team and I
have a blog and Twitter where I post
some of my research as well so yeah
let's start with with some basics very
quickly about user and kernel
communication so as you all know user
applications run independently of other
programs and independently of the kernel
and whenever they actually want to do
something in the operating system they
call into the kernel to request the
operation that they want to do and when
they do it the ring free memory which is
a shared memory between the user and
kernel mode is used as the exchange data
exchange channel so this is how it looks
on a simple graph so we have the user
mode program which wants to perform some
operations so it writes input data to
the shirt user mode memory then in it
invokes the system called which
transfers execution to the system kernel
which then reads the input data performs
some logic writes output beta back and
returns to user space then the use
program reads the output data back and
operates on it so in this presentation
we're mostly interested in these two
stages of the system kernel first
reading input data and then writing
output data and especially in the in the
second part so let's imagine in a
perfect world where the kernel doesn't
have any bugs so we would like in this
perfect word for the kernel to only read
every memory unit once within the scope
of a system call and then write to it
also at most once after it is done with
all of the system call logic do it in a
secure manner and only write the data
that is intended for user mode so that
is the state of the perfect world that
we could imagine but of course we have
free LT instead so these assumptions
that I mentioned can be broken in in a
number of ways so for example we can
break the assumption that every memory
unit is read from at most once it may
happen that memory is actually read most
and more than once this was the subject
of the original box boom research that
we performed four years ago we've been
very cold wind and the possible
violation is that we have two or more
fetches from user mode memory which may
allow some race conditions to break code
assumptions which can lead to buffer
overflows right what with work
conditions arbitrary it's all kind of
badness so these this original research
resulted in discovering more than 40
vulnerabilities in Windows and yeah so
we wrote quite a few papers on this
subject on both trying to find these
kind of double fetters and also exploit
them this research was also presented
here at blackhat we can also break the
other assumptions in a number of ways so
for example we can have like unprotected
accesses to user mode pointers in the
kernel we can have multiple writes to a
single memory area which can also
indicate that something fishy's going on
in the kernel we can have reading from
the user mode address after already
having written to it which is also kind
of fishy because why would a kernel do
it and there are some other behaviors
which can raise an eyebrow for example
accessing ring
memory within very deeply nested skull
stacks or with the first enabled
exception hands are very high optical
stack these are also some some weird
behaviors that could happen but the
subject of this talk is actually this
part about only writing data that is
intended to be used by user mode so
that's what we will focus on so writing
data to use during 3 happens in general
in 4 different cases so we have system
calls which exist in all operating
systems that were interested in we have
IO CDLs which are also a special case of
sis calls but they have often dedicated
output mechanisms so we can consider
them differently a little bit we have
user mode callbacks which are a
mechanism which is specific to Windows
and win 32k graphical subsystem and we
finally have exception handling where
the kernel has to build an exception
frame on the user mode stack so then it
also writes to the user mode memory so
let's let's go back a little bit and
think about where when writing
initialized memory or some kind of
unintended memory to user mode can
happen so we have this easy problem on
the example of a fake Windows system
call implementation here of writing an
initialized value of a primitive type
variable so here we have a system call
which calculates the multiplication of 2
of a value and of course as we can see
the local output value is not
initialized if input value is equal to 0
so then we are leaking for or yeah
basically for 4 bytes of initialized
kernel stack memory back to user mode so
this of course can happen and will
happen but this is not not as bad as it
seems because first of all it's it's not
a very trivial bug to make for
developers compilers will often warn
about instances of such issues it
doesn't leak too much information
because it's just a single variable and
it very well may be detected during
development as well because it may be a
functional part so this is not not so
bad but we have many many other
definitely harder problems so first of
all we have structures and unions which
are used in C and C++ so here in this
example we have a structure who has
which has three fields which are being
used to output some
user mode so the two of them - two of
the fields in this structure and are
initialized because they are used by the
system call but the third one is
reserved so it's not honest it's not
initialized by default kind of by design
but still it's allocated in the kernel
stack and it still output back to user
mode so it's leaking some some data
within that fuel furthermore we have
unions which can have fields and you
know types of fields that have different
sizes so here you can see that we have
one D word and one Q word and only the D
word is initialized here which leaves
the other four bytes unutilized and they
are also leaked back to user mode in the
in the annualized state and furthermore
we have structures which have padding
holes inside so we have a D word
followed by a Q word
but since the key word has to be 8 byte
aligned the compiler inserts a pairing
whole of 4 bytes which in this code are
also not initialized properly and output
to user mode so we have as I said
different problems related to the
structures and unions first of all they
are usually copied in memory entirely
using functions such as mem copy and
size is calculated by the sizeof
operator they have often many fields so
it's either easy to forget about about
setting some of them or they may be and
not set by design we have padding halls
we have as I said different sizes and
unions and worst of all compilers don't
really have too much inside into
structures especially when they are
dynamically allocated from the heap or
pools and also because of the fact that
they are often copied using functions
such as mem copy then we have another
problem related to fixed size erase so
here we have an example of a system call
which returns the path to the system on
file system and as you can see we have
this huge array which is allocated from
the stack but it's only partially
initialized with with the relevant
string that we want to return but the
kernel still returns the whole array
with more than 200 initialized bytes
inside
and we have a lot of instances of such
long fixed size buffers in a window in
the Windows kernel which are used in the
exchange of data between user and kernel
mode they used for paths in the file
system for names identifiers etc and
most most often even though these
buffers are fixed in size the length of
the content inside is variable and
usually most of the storage used by the
array is actually not not used at all so
and the other problem is that these
these arrays are often part of
structures which are which makes it even
harder to only copy the relevant part of
the string to user mode so and also the
bad thing about this is that since the
yes array can be very huge
they can also leak a lot of data from
the kernel to the user space at once and
then we have yet another problem which
is kind of specific to Windows but not
not not only so even though we have this
system call which only returns 12 bytes
in total in three magic D words it
allows the user mode color to specify
the length of the output buffer and it
allocates a number of bytes that is
requested by the user a mode color and
even though it only writes a limited
number of bytes into the buffer it
copies this use this kernel mode buffer
in a hole back to user mode so we also
end up with a lot of uninitialized data
here this is also very common in Windows
as I said and the interesting thing
about this is that it this this kind of
bug may actually enable disclosure from
both the stack and the heap in the same
affected code because of the fact that
Windows uses an optimization so for
small request sizes it uses stack
buffers and for a larger one it uses
heap allocations in many cases and it
often leads to large leaks of control
number of bytes and the worst thing is
that in this particular case it could be
possible for the user to actually be
able to specify that the size of the
allocation that is being leaked so it
may enable the attacker to try to
collide with interesting objects in
kernel mode memory in order to leak
something interesting
so apart from all of this we have some
more factors which contribute to this
whole problem so first of all neither
windows nor Linux actually pre
initialized allocations on the stack or
heap by default of course there are a
lot of exceptions mostly in Linux such
as the case a lock function the GFP zero
flag etc but in general allocations are
not initialized by default a recent
change in Windows from a few months ago
is that some some allocations used for
ioctl IO buffers are initialized now but
that is that is something that was not
true two months ago but the general rule
still stands and as you can see here in
the screenshot even the official
documentation of the X allocate pool
with tagged windows function warns about
the fact that allocations returned by
this function contain initialized memory
and if the code wants to return it to
user mode it has to memset it first
another factor is that there are no
visible visible consequences of this
kind of behavior so even though C and
C++ don't really make it easy for the
code to copy data securely between
security domains there isn't any
punishment if you fail to do it
correctly so you know even if the kernel
discloses if you initialize bytes in one
syscall or another nothing will really
crash in most cases and so no one will
discover this bug and so as a result if
a kernel developer is not aware of this
bug class and they are not trying to
actively prevent it they will probably
never kind of find out because the code
crashes or something doesn't work so
it's a very silent type of bug yet
another factor is the fact that it might
be not very easy to discover that any
leaks from kernel mode are actually
taking place because some of them could
be hidden behind the user mode system
api so even though data is actually
leaked from the system kernel back to
user mode in general that the original
color of the system api might not see
this data at all so yeah
when it comes to the severity and
considerations of this of these bugs you
can say that they are not very severe
because it's just local info leaks there
is no memory corruption taking place now
remote exploitation involved by nature
and and and etc but the actual severity
depends on what we managed to leak out
of the kernel
this can be addresses that we can use
for further exploitation of other
vulnerabilities or it can be some
sensitive data that we can use more
directly to elevate our privileges in
the system but on the positive side from
the attacker perspective these bugs are
mostly silent and transparent so we can
try to exploit them basically
indefinitely and very silently without
ever worrying about the system going
down or someone actually discovering
that something something fishy is going
on hmm so as I said these bugs are
mostly useful in practice as a single
link in a full exploit chains for local
privilege escalation especially given
how much effort is actually being put
into protecting kernel address space
information in Windows and one real-life
example of this would be an exploit
found in the hacking team dump two years
ago so in order to exploit another
vulnerability they used a pool memory
disclosure which leaked the base address
of the winter dedicated sis driver and
so yeah it was used in practice and at
the same time a few weeks before all of
this came to light a project zero
researcher mod state also discovered
this independently and reported it so
yeah when it comes to the benefits of of
this kind of disclosures you have to
consider them separately when it comes
to whether they are stack or heap
disclosures so when it comes to stack
these are consistent and immediately
useful values because you know these are
the desert this is the type of data that
is being stored on the stack so we have
things like addresses of the kernel
stack because of the stack pointers we
have heap addresses we have addresses of
executable images because of return
addresses we can leak
values of stock cookies which can be
then used to exploit a stack buffer
overflow we have some Cisco specific
data that is used by services called
directly before the leaking Cisco and
also interesting thing is that we can
sometimes leak data of interrupt
handlers if they happen to trigger in
the same context as the exploiting
threat but that's only on Windows 7 on
the other hand when it comes to heap
disclosure we have kind of less obvious
memory because it's it's not always just
pointers to the stack into executable
images but we have more potential to
collide with something that is more
sensitive so of course we have addresses
again of the heap and potentially of
executable images but we can collide
with virtually allocations of any active
kernel modules related to the disk
networking video etc yeah interestingly
there hasn't been too much work with
within that space on Windows so
according to my best knowledge people
have started to take interest in this
kind of issues something like two years
ago so we have this this one issue in
project zero tracker discovered by Mott
state then we have a presentation of
given by wandering glitch last year
about several unutilized memory
disclosure bugs fixed in 2015 and we
have two more we have a presentation
from this year from can sequester
which doesn't really concern this
subject but mentions that there are some
leaks in win32 k user remote callbacks
and also we have this work from just
last month from two researchers which
also collided with my research and and
tried to find some sum of info League
parks in the Windows kernel
automatically on the other hand the
problem seems to be much better well
known on Linux
so already seven years ago Dan Rosenberg
apparently went on a rampage and killed
several dozen I think more than 20 info
leaks in various subsystems he presented
some of this work in
patien given by him and yon aburrida in
2011 and then there are also a lot of
other comets provided by different
security researchers which who
discovered this kind of bugs throughout
the history
so this problem seems to be much better
well known and well well understood in
Linux than it is on Windows probably
because of the fact that Linux is open
source so you can more easily find this
kind of stuff there so let's look into
the design of the of the tool now we'll
start with a quick description of box
because box spawn reloaded is is based
on the Box emulator it's a full emulator
developed by Intel it has a full
implementation of the CPU it has support
for all of the latest features of the
CPU all of the extensions such as SSE a
Fe X and stuff like that it also has all
basic peripherals so you can just run a
full operating system on this single
emulator without any problems and a good
thing is that it also provides an
extension instrumentation API so we can
we can in addition to just running the
system we can look into how it works and
we can change its behavior in any way we
want in terms of performance of this
emulator since it's a full system is
full software emulator the performance
is not very good so here we have you can
see that I at this at the point of
taking the screenshot it was executing
for to me about 40 million instructions
per second so that's not too much
the longer story is that if we have a
non instrumented guest it can run up to
100 IPS which is sufficient to boot a
system in kind of reasonable time which
is under five minutes and when we do it
the environment is fairly responsive we
can you know like use the system
move the mouse open some applications
and stuff like that when we add some
instrumentation on top of that we have
some overhead depending on what
instrumentation we write in my case in
in case of box phone reloaded that
performance drop was to around 30 to 40
million IPS which was still kind of
acceptable for research purposes so I
can still interact with the system and
get some visible results but when
interacting with box we actually had to
put a lot of effort into making sure
that the logic that we're implementing
in the instrumentation is is as simple
and as fast as possible so about the
instrumentation support in box
technically it works through macros
defined in C++ starting with the BX
instru prefix and then we have a lot of
callbacks to actually choose from so we
can we can execute our own code on
initialization of the virtual machine
shuts down before and after executing an
instruction on linear and physical
memory access on exceptions interrupts
and stuff like that so we can control
and everything that is going on in the
system and this enables us to develop
virtually any logic that we want to do
so we can count statistics on what
instructions are executing and how often
we can trace instructions or trace
memory accesses add metadata and stuff
like that
so here you can see a full list of the
instrumentation callbacks that box
provides and the ones that are
underlined are the ones that that I used
in box one reloaded so it's not not too
many of them basically the most
important ones are just the ones
triggering before and after execution of
an instruction and the one triggering on
accessing linear memory and the
CoreLogic of box bone is that we want to
change track the entire kernel address
space and in order to do it we need to
first be able to send change on new
allocations that are being performed in
kernel mode both from the stack and the
heap then we want to be able to remove
taint when memory is freed of course we
want to propagate taint in memory and
then most importantly we want to detect
when some initialized memory is copied
from the kernel space to the user space
apart from that core functionality it's
also good that
we are able to reproduce the bugs and
analyse them somehow so in order to do
that we want to also keep track of all
the loaded cast kernel modules so we
know which driver is triggering the bug
we will also want to read full stack
traces to be able to duplicate the bugs
not to run into the same vulnerability
all over and over again of course it's
good to also symbolize the call stacks
to have pretty reports that we can
analyze and finally we want to break
into kernel debugger attached to the
guests when an error actually happens so
that we can interactively try to see
what's going on in the system here you
can see a representation of the shadow
memory so we have the guest the West
memory divided into user a lot and
kernel and for every kernel and byte or
rather we have a mapping of the a full
mapping of the shadow memory
corresponding to the kernel land and
then every memory unit is described by a
few variables of course we have detained
bit but also we have information about
what is the base address of the
allocation that despite belongs to we
have the information about where despite
was allocated in the kernel and stuff
like that so this this shadow memory
size is linear in relation to the size
of the guest kernel address space
currently we only support 32-bit guests
but that shouldn't be really too hard to
to modify and some of the information is
stored at one by two on orality and some
at eight byte granularity so right now
with my implementation the size of the
shadow memory is three times the size of
the kernel address space so we have six
gigabytes of memory for for a windows
guest and three gigabytes of memory for
linux guest so it can easily run on any
any host machine that has a reasonable
amount of RAM memory and apart from just
painting the memory that we that is
being allocated in our shadow memory
what I wanted to do is also part the
guest memory with some special marker
bytes so we have a
with the a a bite for hip allocations
and BB bite for stack areas this is used
mostly first of all in order to
eliminate all false positives because
now we have the guarantee that if shadow
memory indicates that there is a bug we
can also refer to the actual guest
memory and see if these original marker
bites are still these values of a a or
BB and it can also trigger some use of
an energized memory bugs that are not
just info leaks but also other bugs so
about setting paint on stack this is
this is actually very easy because all
allocations performed on stack are
performed using the same assembly
pattern so it's close cross-platform
what I do in my instrumentation is I
just detect these three instruction of
adding subtracting and ending against
the ESP register and then after the
execution of this instruction if ESP
decrease that I just sent the taint on
the whole new memory region that also
allocated this way of course you can
imagine cases where this would crash the
operating system if it didn't perform
properly but unfortunately both windows
and linux do so this behavior doesn't
crash anything and it all works out on
the other hand setting taint on heap and
full allocations is completely different
we cannot do it universally in any way
we actually have to know how the system
allocates memory where the allocators
are located in the kernel address space
and how do how they work so right now we
can just say that after we detect an
allocation and we know the address and
the size of the allocation we've just
tainted and I will talk about how we do
it specifically in later in the
presentation then we want to remove
taint on hip free which is also very
reliant on how the heap implementation
works on the specific system but
basically when we break on a free
function Prolog we look up the
allocation size of the memory that
corresponds to the address and we just
clear all of the taint and metadata that
corresponds to the whole memory region
another idea would be to escape this
this clearing of the taint and is
that retains this this memory in order
to detect use after free and leaks of
freed memory but that's an implement
implementational detail and the hardest
part of all of this is the taint
propagation because we can easily detect
allocations but detecting data transfers
and handling them correctly is
definitely the hardest part so in case
of my project I only propagate time for
the red mob as Dee and her red mob as be
instructions which correspond to the mem
copy kind of construct it's used both in
the mem copy implementation of various C
clients and it's also used as an inline
version of the mem copy function and the
good thing about handling this specific
instruction is that we know the source
and destination addresses at the same
time so we know how many bytes are
copied from which address location to to
which one so we can analyze this very
easily and you know of course this is
only a best-effort approach it's not
perfect we don't handle all of the data
transfers but you know it still gives us
a lot of information and we still mostly
care about copying large memory blobs
and not single variables so this this
lets us to spend as little time on this
with as much benefit as we can get and
it also has a quite a small CPU overhead
so if a memory access is not a result of
this instruction that we specifically
analyzed then we perform the following
steps if this instruction that we
encounter is writing to some memory
we'll just clear the taint on that
memory area and if the instruction is
reading from the from the memory we
check the taint information and if the
shadow memory indicates that this is
actually an annualized read we verify
whether this is the case or not with the
marker bytes that I mentioned before in
case there is a mismatch for whatever
reason we just cleared the taint again
but if the marker bytes are still there
in the guest memory we we report the bug
and also the real detection of the user
mode or kernel mode information leak
triggers on the read mode as be
instruction where the ESI is in kernel
mode and idea is in user mode which
which is a very clear indicator that
initialized memory is actually copied
from kernel to user mode so once we have
all of this information and this picture
of how this product should look like we
can try to run it on some real systems
starting with Windows what we have to do
first is we have to implement the
painting of pool allocations in Windows
we have a lot of functions which
allocate memory from the pool all of
them start with X allocate pool but
there are different variants but
fortunately for us all of these
functions eventually call into one
called
X allocate pool with tag and it's very
convenient because it uses the STD call
calling convention which means that we
have the arguments on the stack and the
return value in EAX and this means that
when the read instruction is executed in
this function we have all of the
information about both the allocation
request and allocation result at the
same time so this is this is very
convenient for us this is how it looks
on a graph so we have we have different
colors of all of the allocation
functions eventually they all call into
X allocate pool with tag and then we
break on this single read instruction
and read all of the relevant information
from ax
and from memory under ESP so we read
where the allocation is being made from
from the return address and the
requested size and the allocation tag
for some debugging information and then
we also break on the X free pool with
tag function this time in the prologue
of the function and we just read the
address of the regem that is being freed
in order to clear the taint
unfortunately there are some corner
cases which we also have to take into
account in order to find all of the bugs
so for example in Windows we have some
optimized specialized alligators such
though such as the one used by winter
okay so there is this alligator which
first of all tries to return a cached
memory region that is pre allocated and
after only it is busy the actual Windows
kernel
a locator is used so and it's called
from from quite a few locations so we
have to take care of that but what we
can do is we can just simply patch this
function to always use the system a
locator instead and we are good to go
when it comes to propagating taint and
detecting bugs in Windows
we are quite lucky because the the mem
copy function that is used by the
Windows kernel actually uses the red
morph as B and wrap morph as d function
instructions sometimes they have some
optimizations that we have to care about
so for example in Windows
if the copy size is less than 32 bytes
then morph instructions are used instead
of red morph as beep or red Mofaz d but
we also can just modify that in assembly
so in general as a result tracking most
transfers of data blobs in Windows works
out of the box with the approach that I
mentioned before I'm not sure oh you can
actually see that quite well so I
created a small visualization of the
whole address space in Windows 7 so here
you can see the whole 2 gigabyte kernel
address space over time this is an image
which is of dimensions 1024 by 512 each
pixel is a single memory page and so
these pages that are that have some
stack memory taint are marked in green
and the pool ones are marked in red so
now we can see that what the patterns
are in Windows when it boots up and when
you start some of the some of the
applications in Windows so that's 40
minutes of runtime a new snapshot was
being taken every 20 seconds here so I I
found I find that quite interesting
myself and here you can see the similar
image on Windows 10 over 120 minutes
with a snapshot taking every 60 seconds
because
the boots time was much longer on the
box emulator so you can see that much
more memories consumed by the operating
system and the patterns in which memory
is allocated also is also quite
different when it comes to other
technical details such as keeping track
of processes and threads it's very
simple it's the same as in the original
box born from four years ago it's just
about traversing a simple traversing a
single a linked list of of modules in
the kernel address space and the same
goes for keeping track of keeping track
of loaded kernel modules you also just
have to go through a list of descriptors
and note the values there so here we
have an example of Bach's bone that that
was generated in an actual runtime so
you can see all of the information that
we have about the bag that happened we
have the address of the memory that is
being read we have information about the
process in this case it's Explorer dot X
ax we have the faulting instruction
which as I mentioned before can only be
read more of SD in this case and we have
information about where the memory
region was allocated in this case it was
just a generic function inside of win32
K and the stack trace of where this
happened so this is all very good and it
looks very nice but it was a very simple
example and there are much more complex
examples where we have a bug but it's
it's not just to stack frames it's
actually like 30 stack frames because
the back happens inside of a ioctl
handler someone very deep inside of the
kernel so it's not very convenient in
that case to try to analyze the bug
based just on the single box spawn
report so as I mentioned before what I
wanted to do is to be able to attach
windbg or wind back to the emulated
guest kernel and this is not a very big
problem because box actually supports
redirecting comm ports to Windows pipes
so we can just enable kernel debugging
in the guest system and then attach a
wind wind back to it from outside of
course this is very very slow if you try
to attach wind back
takes maybe five minutes for it to fully
on initially and provide with the
interactive shell but it's still
workable for our purposes and of course
this is not sufficient because even
though we have this kernel debugger
attached we don't know when when the
bugs are happening so what we also want
to do is that we want to break on the
specific moment when a bug happens and
this is achieved by injecting an entry
instruction in the emulator exactly at
the moment when the bug is detected so
this this lets us break into the
debugger and see exactly what is going
on and what memory is being copied to
user mode and why so for me at least it
seems it feels quite magical that it
will all works but it does so here I
have a screenshot of wind wind bag
attached to the box guest here yeah when
it comes to the testing that I performed
in order to get some reasonable cold
coverage first of all I run the
instrumentation against Windows 7 and
Windows 10 in order to get above the old
code that could have been removed in
Windows 10 and also the new code that
was added in that system and within that
guests what I did is that I of course
booted up the system started a few
default applications such as Internet
Explorer WordPad stuff like that
I generally did some network traffic and
I also run so-called react OS unit tests
which is a bunch of applications which
are used by react OS to test whether the
behavior of the system is the same as
Windows so it actually helps us provide
or get a lot of code coverage in the
kernel that we wouldn't be able to do
otherwise we already used this these
tests four years ago but they were
largely improved since then so they were
very helpful for us but of course even
though we did all of those things it's
still not the perfect amount of code
coverage that we can get so it's still a
major roadblock in every effective usage
of full system instrumentation because
we can find only as many bugs are
actually triggered on the system so
let's look into the results
this is this is the results on a single
slide so it's a it's a couple of
screenshots from Microsoft Billiton from
the last four months the summary is that
we found so far 30 vulnerabilities 13 of
them were in from the pools and 17 from
the stack so it's quite evenly divided
and we can see here the pool ones were
triggered in a number of kernel drivers
so we have both the core NTS OS kernel
we have win32 k we have a bunch of you
know like partition manager drivers
volume manager driver stuff like that
and root causes of those bugs are also
very diverse so we have bugs caused by
structure alignment unicode string
alignment padding halls and you know a
lot of different things and also the the
amount of bytes that were leaked is also
quite diverse so it ranges from just a
single byte to over 6 kilobytes of
information at a single request and then
we have the stock disclosures as well
from a number of functions they are also
diverse for some of them I wasn't really
able to figure out what the reason for
for the leak was but yeah it's still
quite a lot of them so it's it's an
important problem once we detected these
bugs we want to reproduce them of course
and this is another important problem
that we have to look into so in order to
reproduce the pool info leaks what I did
is that I used regular vm in order to
make sure that this bug is not specific
to box but also a normal environment
what I did is that I just found out
which drivers making the allocation that
is being leaked to user mode and I
already had this information from the
metadata I enabled special pools for
that model reboot the system and then
started the POC twice and then I could
observe a repeated marker bite at the
offsets where the data was leaked so
this is how it looked like for the
volume disks extents vulnerability when
I run it the first time you can see 39
marker byte but then when I run it again
it's another byte so you can easily see
where the leak is actually taking place
here when it comes to stacking fully
reproduction that is much more difficult
because there is no official or
documented way of padding stack
allocations with marker bytes but on the
other hand we still want to reproduce
these packs reliably and be able to show
where the bytes are being leaked because
otherwise you know first of all it's
easier for Microsoft to find add to to
to fix those bugs and also it's easier
for us to make sure that the back is
real and also reproduce outside of the
test environment what we can do in this
case is that we can use stack spraying
this is a technique that allows us to
spray the kernel stack with some
controlled memory and it works thanks to
the fact that Windows uses optimization
of using local buffers for small
requests and some of the system calls
actually have very large buffers for
storing optimized local data so we have
this system call called anti map user
physical pages which allows us to put 4
or 8 kilobytes of controlled data on the
stack so it's very convenient so this is
illustrated here first of all what we do
is that we just spray the current start
with some easily recognizable patterns
such as the for 1 byte and then we
trigger the vulnerability and we see
where this marker byte happens to to be
in our output buffer so this is another
example of running the anti GDI get
realization info POC here which leaks 8
bytes from the kernel stack and a quick
digression is that if memory marking can
be used for bug demonstration it can
also be used for discovery that's what I
at least thought and the basic idea
would be to first of all enable special
pools for all of the kernel modules and
then invoke invite invoke test tested
system called twice pre spraying the
kernel stack with a different bite each
time and then we can compare the output
of the system call and see if if it
differs in a reliable way
and the perfect candidate to to test in
this way is that function is the family
of anti query information system calls
which have a very calm
structures so we have a handle to the
object that we want to query we have
some information class which is just a
simple integer and we have a pointer and
size of the output buffer so we can
create the object that we want to query
and then we can just brute force pretty
much both the information class and the
expected buffer size and our about ten
such functions which we can test this
way so this looked quite promising and
indeed it turned out that this was a
fruitful idea and I was able to find
about five bucks this way as well so it
was it was quite easy so in summary the
problem seems to have remained mostly
unrecognized until now probably because
of the factor that factors that I
mentioned before that it's quite
invisible and not obvious to find these
bugs but on the other hand it's a
fundamental issue which is trivial to
overlook but very difficult to get right
in the code so I think it's also a tip
of the iceberg so even though I found
thirty bucks so far there are hundreds
of men copy calls to user remote in the
Windows kernel and every one of them is
a potential disclosure so so there are
still probably a lot of such bugs
lurking in the codebase of Windows and
this is especially true in the cases
where the size is user controlled but
the amount of lab relevant data is fixed
or otherwise limited there are some
mitigations ideas that Microsoft could
probably implement in some way in order
to to try to mitigate those bugs first
of all of course they could just memset
all stack and pool allocations we
learned there made or requested which
would make the bug go away without doing
any bug fixing at all but of course that
is probably incurring too much of an
overhead so it's not realistic and
especially given the fact that most
kernel allocations probably don't at end
up copied to user mode anyway but it
turns out that Microsoft implemented a
part of this idea by mem setting the
buffered i/o output buffer in the ioctl
implementation just just a few weeks ago
so they are definitely looking into into
this there are some other
creation ideas that are more realistic
such as for example Creek clearing the
kernel stack between system calls they
could also add a new a locator function
which just clears the returned memory
regions before returning them and they
could also just detect which allocations
end up being copied to user mode and
then only clear those either
automatically or just by adding Maps it
calls manually and in general since when
the Microsoft has the wins of source
code they could bring this idea to a
whole new level by writing better
instrumentation which has more
information about data transfers and
stuff like that they also have probably
mode code coverage that I am able to
achieve by just running a few simple
tests and starting a few applications
which also means more bugs found and
static analysis is also easier to use to
guide this dynamic approaches so when it
comes to closing remarks for Windows of
course this box phone approach could be
also used to detect regular use of an
initialized memory but the results in
case of Windows are much harder to try
out because we don't have access to the
source code so we cannot easily analyze
if this use of an initialized memory is
an actual buck or not and another point
that I wanted to make is that the the
subject of leaking specific sensitive
data from pool disclosures is still an
interesting subject that hasn't been
explored too much now I also wanted to
talk about running Bach's bone against
Linux but I guess I don't have too much
time anymore
so I will just quickly say that the
tainting of heap allocations is much
more difficult on Linux because the
allocators themselves are plenty it's
not just a single function but we have a
couple of families that are schema log V
ma log K memcache a log and stuff like
that all of them work in different ways
so we have a lot of these functions for
came along a lot of these functions in
vemma log we have to hook into most of
them in order to be able to catch all of
the allocations in my case it was seven
of them we also have problems such as
the fact
we have a different calling conventions
with arguments passed through registers
and not the stack so instead of just
hooking into a single read instruction
we actually have to hook into the both
the prologue of the app function in
order to save information about the
allocation request and then we have to
hook into the return instruction in
order to be able to read the address
that it was being allocated and then we
can set the taint then we have this
troublesome family of K memcache
functions which create a cache of
allocations which are initialized and
tainted at the time where the object is
initialized but not at the time when it
is requested so we have to implement
some additional logic to account for
that other than that we have a few flags
that we have to set in the config in
order to make the mem copy function be
compiled into a set of rep move move SB
instructions we have this visualization
of Ubuntu memory layout which I'm gonna
skip right now we have a few other
config options that we also have to set
in order to enable debugging symbols use
the right kernel user address mode split
and disable some of the mechanisms that
we don't want to use in the emulation
then we also have to set another config
option to make sure that copy to user
which is used to copy memory back from
kernel mode to user mode is also
compiled into read mob SP and read more
SD instructions unfortunately there is
one problematic function that we have to
also care about which is put user which
is a macro used to copy simple types
back to user mode but we can take care
of that by just using a hack of using
these prefetch instructions in order to
enable and disable strict mode in box
which means that we just sanitize all of
the reads from memory that happened
between those two instructions you are
welcome to ask me about the details of
that after
presentation but that's how it looks in
assembly so we have the preface one and
preffered two instructions and be in
between these instructions we just
sanitize all of the memory reads so yeah
we have we have a very similar log from
box pawn report right now so it's all
the same information about the
instruction the stack trace where the
back happened and stuff like that we
also have a kernel debugger attached as
well so we can we can debug these bugs
that happen at runtime we perform some
very simple testing as well by running a
few system professors such as Trinity
pools I know this also a few unit tests
such as the Linux test project and a
couple of other things unfortunately we
are but we weren't able to use this
color because it's currently only
supporting 64-bit architectures and we
were working with 32-bit when it comes
to the results they are much less
impressive than on Windows so it was
just a single bug which was very minor
because it was in the ioctl of a device
that was only accessible to route I'd
still discovered it around April 20th
and I was I was still able to I was
still going to report it a few days
later but when I started looking around
seeing if anybody has reported it
already
I discovered that seven days after yeah
after I discovered it someone from
Google already have have fixed it so too
bad but since that didn't work out so
well for me to detect does direct kernel
to user info leaks I decided that I
could enable that global strict mode and
detect all uses of unutilized memory and
analyze all of them because I had access
to the source code in this case so I
could just look into the in-depth root
cause of every such instance so I did
that and this was more lucky for me so I
was able to find a few bugs one of them
actually led to the discovery of an
actual kernel info leak in the LLC piece
or connect in NFC sockets the other ones
are much lesser
they were still uses of uninitialized
memory but not directly leading to
information disclosure thankfully all of
them have been fixed now and as you can
see some of them have also been found by
external researchers as well so it turns
out that when it comes to analyze reads
from kernel mode my project was not the
only one in Linux so there is a project
called kernel memory sanitizer which is
being worked on right now
it's called km Sun it's developed by
Alexander Potter Penco and it has
collided on a few on a few of my
findings and the important thing is that
it's actually working in a different way
it's adding instrumentation at compile
time it's very similar to projects such
as address ionizer memory sanitizer for
user mode and this is the the correct
way to do it in Linux but I still wanted
to also test my approach on that
operating system so the conclusions in
terms of Linux is that here we have we
have a community which has been on top
of the problem for the last few years we
don't have so many info leaks here and
even if we find something it turns out
that these bugs seem to be quite
short-lived from my experience at least
yeah there is a little bit of future
work to be done here we can run further
iteration on Windows we can try to look
into improving code coverage which is
always something that needs to be done I
can also think about improving taste
propagation beyond just rap of SB and
implementing support for 64-bit guests
which also should be able to identify a
few more new bugs there are some other
more crazy approaches such as taint less
approaches of not having any taint but
only looking into writes into user
remote memory and seeing if there are
any marker bytes that are being leaked
there this addresses the problem of
non-ideal tyne propagation but it has
other problems as well yeah we can also
we can also think about detecting leaks
not just into user remote memory but
into other sinks that
outgoing network traffic file system
metadata and stuff like that so there is
a lot of work to do still but I think
the results so far are still quite
impressive and are motivating to look
into info leaks more in the future so
thank you for listening and I'm happy to
answer questions
[Applause]
[Music]