it's a good morning everyone I'm Kim and
I'm going to just first of all introduce
panelists so I've switched I have got
start with Jay Jay on my far left is a
senior research scholar at Columbia
University's School of International and
public affairs specializing in cyber
conflict competition and cooperation
prior to this he was founding director
of the cyber statecraft initiative at
the Atlantic Council and from 2003 to
2005 was director for cyber policy and
cyber infrastructure protection at the
White House he's also a former US Air
Force intelligence officer who had jobs
at the Pentagon and the NSA next to Jay
I said Jay Jason is Lilia blond as an
information scientist at the RAND
Corporation where she does technical and
policy research on cybersecurity
emerging technologies and other issues
prior to Ram she worked for the Defense
Department helping to create various
cryptographic and network exploitation
technologies and she's also the proud
owner of a black uber badge from DEFCON
to my to my right we've got Trey her is
a postdoctoral fellow with the Belfer
centers a cybersecurity project at the
Harvard Kennedy School he focuses on
trends in nation-state malware and the
underground criminal markets for malware
previously he worked with the Defense
Department as well to develop a risk
assessment methodology for InfoSec
threats and to Trey's right as Katie
masseurs
founder and CEO of ludus security which
advises companies lawmakers governments
on the benefits of hacking and security
research
she's also as you all know an authority
on vulnerability disclosure bug bounty
programs having been the driving force
behind Microsoft's bug bounty programs
and an instrumental partner in helping
the Defense Department launched its
first bug bounty program the hacking the
Pentagon she's also a visiting scholar
with MIT Sloan School doing research on
vulnerability economy and the exploit
market so the format we're going to do
is I'm just going to we're going to take
care of a little definition stuff so
that we're all clear on what we're
talking about why we're talking about
this then we're going to have Trey and
Lily do a brief presentations on their
papers and then we'll get into the meat
of that and then we'll take your
questions afterwards so first of all
before we get star
briefly Jay tell us what the vep program
is for anyone in the room who doesn't
know and what it does
great thanks hey good morning thanks for
coming so like we're at blackhat most of
us some are comfortable to technology we
understand bugs and but we might not
understand the vep so back in the
prehistory like 15 years ago two decades
ago NSA or other government information
warfare cyber security folks when they
would discover new vulnerability they
had to say all right are we going to
keep this or are we gonna tell the
vendors richard Balak has a great story
when he was at Air Force cert in the
late 90s and he found a Cisco
vulnerability router vulnerability and
he told Cisco and the offense folks in
the airforce came by and said don't do
that right that's not your decision you
give it to us the offensive side and
we'll decide if we're gonna tell Cisco
or not all right I mean I'm not sure
that's that's really one of the offense
folks to decide if if that's the right
decision so in the government they said
we need this process so the director of
NSA had an internal process where they
would say we'll go through we'll figure
out how bad is this bug is this
extensively used in the u.s.
infrastructure how hard is it to try and
figure out is it likely that a lot of
people are gonna figure it out or is it
this is gonna be nobis nobody but us
nobody but the u.s. that can figure this
out so now they had this pretty good
process but at the end of the day it was
still the director of the NSA that that
was making the decision and so a couple
of years ago the US government
especially after Snowden said now we
need to do a little bit better on that
so now it's a White House process so now
the president runs that and so NSA and
the other more offensively minded folks
DoD intelligence community they're just
one of the seats around that table that
says all right here's the new bug here's
the criteria that we're going to assess
and now if the other defensive-minded
agencies like DHS say no we think this
is serious and we need to get this
patched right away if they don't like
what they get out of
process they could escalate all the way
up through the NSA see chain
theoretically up to the President
himself so the main purpose of this
process is to try and buy ourselves more
security to try and figure out this
decision our week is the United States
as the internet better off if we plug
this or should we use it for some time
to try and figure out what the Russians
are doing trying to figure out if
Islamic state or al Qaeda is trying to
attack us use it for espionage or
potentially offense purposes and to try
and do it smart trade off on that that's
not the only purpose it's also there
just for that interagency process right
so that the defensive-minded agencies
feel like they've got some voice on
what's going to happen to these bugs
right I'll bet there's a chance that
eternal blue came out before this
process and so imagine you're at DHS
you're trying to make America more
secure you're trying to tell people to
patch and then use find out in the news
one day oh my god like what did we just
do when these come out and so you want
to process inside government where you
can bring that to everyone together the
third purpose of it is not just for the
government but for the government to go
to the public and to go to Silicon
Valley and the vendors and say look
we've got a process from these we're
being adults about this we're not
keeping everything and that we do have
this process to come and talk to you
about that so when we were doing our
report Columbia University did a report
on this last year we briefed it at
DEFCON we didn't have a lot of good
information about how many Boehner
abilities were being kept by the
government how many being released and
whether it made any difference and so
now I think with the report cyber coming
out we're learning a lot about so we
don't have a lot of data on that just
excuse me or interchange it's the
government has this is the only thing
only see what they've made about it they
they claim that they disclosed ninety
one percent of the vulnerabilities that
that they use in the US and then the
other nine percent they say our
vulnerabilities that were actually
disclosed before they got a chance to
close them or they were ones that I
think got fixed right or yeah there were
already fixed they also include things
like that that were trivial or they
don't include if it was outdated right I
mean so right now if they had an awesome
XP boom they're not gonna try and talk
about that because Microsoft probably
you know probably isn't gonna patch that
so from the from the government's
perspective what we're talking about
when we're talking about collisions and
rediscovery they're telling us that it's
a really small portion of things that
they're withholding and but the
rediscovery and collision rates are
still important for right it's
absolutely critical as a fear saying I
would bet many of the people in
Washington DC said are going through
this process we're saying well if we've
got it probably other you know everyone
else does too are a lot of other people
I would have guessed if you talk to them
they might have thought no there isn't
maybe 50/50 of of if we have guided then
probably someone else does and so I
think as this comes out you know we're
learning more about what those rates are
going to be we're learning how much
security we're buying and if I can do
one shameless shout-out yeah one of my
colleagues and the academic side during
I would has happened to see said this is
a weird kind of conflict because if we
develop a nuclear weapon or we get rid
of a nuclear weapon
it doesn't change everybody else's
nuclear weapons right we're not
disarming others and this in in this
field I think we reveal a vulnerability
and we tell the vendor we're taking that
out of everybody else's Arsenal's but
that's mostly true if you've got high
rates if everyone is having the same
same vulnerabilities if it's having a
very low set of vulnerabilities then we
might be buying less security and less
disarmament than we actually think and I
just want to add one other thing I think
you're just when our thing about that
90% thing when the government says that
they disclose 90% they don't tell us how
long they withheld those before they
disclose them so 90% may be that they
may they held on to something for 10
years but oh they disclosed it so now
they can put it in that figure we don't
know just because they're not answering
questions follow-up questions about that
so that's giving us the overall did you
want to say something before I jump into
there just just a note to be clear when
there's disclosure it
not necessarily that it's out of
someone's arsenal disclosure doesn't
necessarily mean that the vulnerability
gets patched or that that patch exists
and then it gets applied it's just in
public knowledge so whether or not that
makes grant money more vulnerable or
less vulnerable more secure or less
secure okay so that just sets the stage
for why these reports were done in the
first place to provide some information
for possible reuse and policymaking why
if if there is a local issue right then
it contributes to the argument that it's
okay to stockpile zero-day
vulnerabilities if the collision rate is
high and the chances are good that
someone else might discover them and use
them then of course you want to
re-evaluate whether or not you're
withholding so so - the two papers main
papers that we're talking about today
are the first one that we're going to
discuss is lillies paper zero-days
thousands of nights the life and times
of zero day vulnerabilities and their
exploits it was done by Lilly and her
colleague Andy Bogart at the RAND
Corporation and this is the first
publicly available research to examine a
database of zero day vulnerabilities
that are still currently unknown and
I'll let her tell you where they come
from but they're still in the wild many
of them are still in the wild and being
actively exploited so really great
thanks I have a few slides here this so
I'll just grab the clicker so the
motivation for the study is as Jay has
pointed out and Kim has mentioned and
many about others have talked about
publicly available information about
zero vulnerabilities a sparse there
should often shrouded in secrecy and
when questions come up about them
certainly collision rate or the
percentage of vulnerabilities that get
independently rediscovered and be
disclosed in a given time period is is
something that people care about they
also care about the longevity or the
lifetime of a vulnerability as well as
the life status whether or not something
is a vulnerability or not these can help
inform discussions like the vet but also
discussions that vendors are having
discussions that pen testers and
security researchers are thinking about
when they're thinking about what bugs to
look at
so our researchers can mentioned looked
at a data set of more than 200
vulnerabilities and their exploits we
are data covered more than 14 years or
four to 14 year timespan from 2002 to
2006 teen and came from a vulnerability
research group which we dubbed Busbee to
protect its anonymity many of Busby's
products are used by nation states many
of Busby's researchers have worked for
nation states so we considered this data
set to be comparable to the capabilities
and skill level of a nation state or a
government and the data set that we had
had information about things like the
vulnerability class source code type
exploit class type vendor who the
exploit developer was and then when they
found the particular vulnerability when
we think about the various who searches
for vulnerabilities we've broken it up
into two different groups those who
search for vulnerabilities to make them
public knowledge those who search for
vulnerabilities to make them or for
private use and you can break up those
for private use into blue and red a lot
of the bugs that get found for public
disclosure might be kind of bug those
that are in those bug hunters look for
those that are in bug bounties that's
kind of that the green circle there
those who look for vulnerabilities for
for private use can we broke them up
into blue and red where blue would be
think would be the in the sense of
governments or the nation-state so it'd
be us and our allies where red are the
opponents or the adversaries of blue so
this is not red team blue team
penetration testing this is from a
government nation-state point of view
military point of view red and blue what
Jay was alluding to and what Kim has
mentioned as well is what this purple
overlap is this is really where the vep
thinks about how much overlap or what
are the characteristics of the
vulnerabilities in this purple overlap
how much overlap there is if there's a
lot of overlap then then the opponents
the adversaries of blue and red are
finding the same bugs if there's little
then they're finding different bugs so
this is really what we want to know
now I had data the data that we had the
Busby data was a proxy for blue I didn't
have access to data for red if you have
access to data for red I'd love to talk
to you then i can help refine our
research so what we did in our in our
study was to look at the public-private
overlap or the the prep of overlap
between blue and then green and
specifically we looked at life status
longevity and collision rate what we
found is that there's granularity to
calling a vulnerability it's misleading
to call of vulnerability either known or
unknown zero day or non zero day we
found several different category as we
called them alive living immortal dead
zombie and several more I have the link
to the report down at the bottom the
next thing we looked at was the life
status or that are the longevity the
lifetime of a vulnerability how long
will it remain privately known before it
becomes publicly disclosed and what we
found in our data set is that our data
lived for the average the average
lifetime of a zero day vulnerability and
it's exploit lived for six point nine
years before it had been disclosed this
gets us to the title of a report because
six point nine years is also two
thousand five hundred twenty-one days or
nights so zero days and thousands of
nights then the third thing we looked at
was given the knowledge of a group of
vulnerabilities what percentage of those
get independently rediscovered and
publicly disclosed given a time in a
given time period if that time interval
evaluated is a year time period then
that collision rate the percentage that
gets into vindicates independently
rediscovered as disclosed is five point
seven percent as ever as this as our
findings relate to so our findings to
help inform those and offense those and
defense it can also help inform those
that are in this that are thinking about
the government retention verses
disclosure discussions and we're not
trying to tell what they tell you what
the answer is but we simply see that our
data can help inform these discussions
can help inform both those who are pro
retention those who are POTUS Pro
disclosure what we see in our findings
is that in our data set this data set
that is a proxy for what a nation-state
or sophisticated private you scroop
might have the long average lifetimes
and
relatively low collision rates might
indicate that vulnerabilities are dense
which means another vulnerability can
often be found or vulnerabilities are
hard to find and these two things are
not necessarily mutually exclusive that
said those could be the argument for pro
disclosure that since the vulnerable
collision rate is nonzero that there's a
probability no matter how small that
someone else especially in an adversary
might find the same vulnerability would
help support the argument to disclose
that bug of course hoping that the
disclosure would also be combined with a
patch release and that patch applied
that's a very very brief overview of our
study I well I welcome you to check it
out at that link and just underscore
that I thank you for correcting me I had
said that these are vulnerabilities that
are currently being exploited in the
wild these were defensive not offensive
no okay did I misunderstand the blue and
the red yes so our dataset is is it's
not blue defense red offense this is
blue us and its allies one could make
the paralyze analogy listen its allies
red could be an adversarial country okay
so this is one what could be used
offensively by a nation-state okay okay
so now we're going to switch over to
Trey's study which came out was it two
weeks ago or a week last week taking
stock estimating vulnerability
rediscovery of a son by Trey and Bruce
Schneier and Christopher Morris this
uses a much larger data set but it
involves currently disclosed
vulnerabilities primarily submitted to
bug bounty programs and it also involves
data from for example as Google's
chromium's fuzzing project so great so
thanks again everybody for coming in for
those of you for whom this is the first
post hangover panel welcome what we were
trying to address is a sort of recurring
question we've had this debate about how
often to different people find the same
vulnerability for an extended period of
time
and most the time when you get into this
debate it involves napkins and sort of
scribble calculations and very anecdotal
discussion and evidence and data the
problem with that obviously is that this
has
a significant impact on the policy
debate around government disclosure but
also in the way companies run bounty
programs and the way that they
prioritize patching so what we were
trying to do in this paper is to bring a
more empirical approach to this issue of
how often two different parties find the
same vulnerability this is a quick
summary of our data set we looked at
four different versions of software
Chrome Firefox Android and the library
open SSL the aggregate rediscovery rate
for this entire data set came out at
about 10.1 percent now there's two
issues with that number the first is it
obscures variation between software type
and the second is it obscures variation
over time so as we're stepping through
this I just want to very quickly go
through this is an our aggregate change
rate over time so we're not splitting
out by software yet but it shows us a
little bit of the difference as we're
moving through and this data said
although it's constituted primarily in
the early days by Chrome sees a lot of
Android and Firefox are unrelated as we
go through so this notion of rediscovery
is really important our definition is
two independent parties finding the same
vulnerability we don't make any
assumptions about who those parties are
their skill set their resources their
motivations why they might be doing this
discovery or how well or how long they
might be doing it which is really
important is that something that's come
up and part of this discussion is about
what are we actually talking about
for our purposes rediscovery is two
independent parties and stops there so
previous estimates using data had come
to between one and six percent the
Keystone study for this is a piece of
work that was done by a researcher at
Cambridge Andy Ozment who formerly of
DHS now at Goldman Sachs had reviewed
some data from Microsoft between 2003
and 2005 looking to see how often they
credited more than one person on their
disclosures found that that rate hovered
about four to six percent using this
data what we found is that the
rediscovery rate is a little bit higher
actually between 10 to 15% breaking it
out by software type you can actually
start to see how much variation there is
between these different code bases in
this plan orange is chrome blue is
Firefox green is Android and gray is
OpenSSL a quick note about openness
itself this is important open SSL is an
open source project and for a long time
for a long time they've been supported
on a shoestring budget by a couple of
volunteers very few paid full-time
professionals what that means is that
most of their energy and effort has gone
towards mitigation and not necessarily
towards accurate record-keeping so one
of the problems that we have in trying
to parse what data we were able to get
from OpenSSL is how accurate they were
about recording when disclosures came in
from multiple people right at the core
once a bug has been disclosed you can
begin to mitigate it the second
disclosure the third disclosure of the
fourth disclosure don't really change
the underlying response process on the
part of those securing the software
itself this is often not an incentive to
accurately categorize those second third
and fourth disclosures as an example the
OpenSSL data that's available on the web
has a record for the disclosure of
heartbleed which most of you probably
have heard of what's missing though is
that there was two disclosures so Harper
Lee was discovered within a few days by
both Neal meadow Google and the company
code nomicon only Neal metas accredited
on the database so we wanted to include
open SSL to try and show some diversity
in this but we're a little bit suspect
with that record-keeping so we have some
limitations there so a couple of quick
takeaways first the rate of rediscovery
has an impact on the policy process bugs
that I hold secret presuming their
secrecy are ones that I could use for
some period of time in an operational
way the challenge is if those bugs are
rediscovered by another party I in this
case the US government haven't given the
vendor an opportunity to create a patch
for that software now lily and others
are going to make a very good point
which is disclosure does not equal patch
and patch being available certainly is
not equal patch apply these are very
separate parts of the process the vep is
a very small part of the overall
software security discussion and focus
just as on this critical oversight
function related to how governments
disclose vulnerabilities so this
rediscovery rate tells us what's the
likelihood that this stock that I have
around that I have actually available to
me are likely to be discovered by
another party while I'm still using them
and keeping them secret there are two
other implications here as well as we're
not just looking at that the second is
looking at how product excuse me patch
product turn in the malware markets so
what this is the notion that of
vulnerability once it's expired has
declining use for different types of
criminal actors so you can actually use
a rediscovery rate to try and generate a
stock renewal rate and looking at these
different products how often is an
exploit kit for example going to have to
renew the exploits that are embedded in
it
the third is patch buyer is
in forming bug bounty programs
essentially how am I paying for bugs
that I think are likely to be discovered
by multiple parties as opposed by one
that's unlikely to be found by all but
that one very talented researcher in
terms of patch prioritization if a bug
has a high rediscovery rate I should be
pushing that up the ladder and
prioritization because the chance that
I've been given it through a pass with
the vendor means that it's also likely
to be found like many other parties
whereas if that's lower I could
personally push that down the rate so
these are a couple quick implications to
the research but I think we want to get
into the discussion so I'll let it there
thanks and Katie you guys you you
presented a paper two years ago at RSA
looking at some of the same kind used a
different methodology for your study so
what was the methodology that you used
and why did you choose that so what we
did two years ago at RSA in conjunction
with MIT Sloan School was we did a
system diamond dynamics model of the
vulnerability market and as part of that
we did look at bug collision rates but
we quickly realized that the rate of bug
collisions vary with target right you
know if you have a fixed codebase you
know as you guys were looking at at
different different code bases different
pieces of software you're looking at it
in terms of a model this is what we did
so we we were looking at if
vulnerabilities are scarce in that fixed
code base versus vulnerabilities are
dense in that fixed codebase the
statistic likelihood of a bug collision
is higher when there are more of our
vulnerabilities in the code meaning more
vulnerabilities because the code base
itself in that fixed code base is less
mature and has more bugs the reason why
we had to model it is because it's
actually really difficult to extrapolate
anything about even the next version of
that same piece of code in terms of what
the rate of bug collusion is so we
looked at it as as sort of a density
modeling problem this actually takes us
back to my old days of fighting all of
those bug counts equal you know CBE
counts equal less secure right does
anybody remember when vendors would try
and compare the security of their
similar products like you know one
database vendor would have a chart of
how many CVEs it has
versus the other database vendors CVEs
and how they were trying to say that
because they have more published
vulnerabilities found that they're less
secure than the ones who had fewer and
that was a completely erroneous way to
try and compare the relative security of
two different code bases so in those
days what I was trying to do is make
sure that there was no false correlation
between completely unrelated things and
so to me when I look at the question of
the vulnerability equities process and
whether or not bug collisions should
factor in I look at that as actually
completely unrelated things and the
reason is that you can't actually
extrapolate anything from one fixed you
know one fixed piece of software's bug
collision rate to even its next versions
bug collision rate you add new features
things change
different researchers enter the scene
and then there's also the problem of you
know omnipotence in this space there's
no real way to use any of the published
data or even private data but some folks
you know that some folks are correlating
to know what is in the mind of hacker
number one hacker number two hacker
number three so again I think that for
purposes of informing policy decisions
around the vulnerability equities
process we certainly need to look at the
balance between our you know our duty to
preserve national security and protect
our critical infrastructure and you know
our offensive capabilities which we need
to maintain you know our ability to to
combat and to protential II gather
information you know during regular
intelligence activities so why do these
studies then I mean what is it what do
they contribute for us okay if it's not
so helpful for the P is that helpful for
the other purposes that you were talking
about in terms of patch and things like
that
patch policy I mean all I put up to
everyone I mean what do these studies
are they worthwhile what do they tell us
what do they offer well one of the
things that you know again getting back
to that old bug counting you know
fallacy of this piece of software is
more secure than this one because of the
number of CVEs what I would encourage
people
to do instead of comparing completely
different code base to completely
different code base even if it was the
same type of product the only real good
measure is comparing yourself to
yourself
so saying you know this version of you
know sequel is has fewer bugs than the
last version and so I think that is a
meaningful in a way to kind of measure
progress over time of trying to reduce
the number of vulnerabilities and a
given piece of software but that doesn't
necessarily again like I said I think I
think these topics are not only you know
they're not just orthogonal there they
are unrelated and and I what I'm really
concerned about is that interesting
studies like this are being Mis applied
to draw conclusions for policy decisions
and so I think we we just need to be
really really careful about how we start
to approach a generalized you know
assumption looking at specific data
datasets for specific target software
know so I think this is interesting
right and there's so three points first
there's obviously a role for simulation
of modeling data you know one of the
challenges about this space is that
there are some real difficulties in
obtaining access to the information that
we'd want to truly make the decision and
Lily Zahra made a reference to this
right to get accurate collision data
we'd like to look within the Chinese
stock and within the US stock and see
how that overlaps over time probably
unrealistic is a research goal if that's
someone's aspiration I've fully support
you
so that's issue one issue two though is
that we still have the opportunity to
gain some fidelity of understanding from
looking at what's actually going on in
the space so the notion of modeling and
simulation can contribute a lot to our
understanding about process and
structure but it doesn't necessarily
replace tracking behavior and actually
capturing the performance of a system
and the activities of these different
actors so they're certainly
complementary which i think is an
important part of this discussion
the third though is with respect what's
being looked at it's more than just
counting security and I would argue I
don't think either study really is
trying to characterize the security of
software by Counting bugs rather I
wasn't implying that
yeah just reminding people of this this
was a fallacious way to compare security
of different products and at what my
assertion is is similarly here I think
we have a well intended attempt to kind
of get your head around some useful data
and then use that to to make some policy
recommendations so such as the vep
process or maybe even other policy
recommendations and that's what I'm
saying is that much like that erroneous
CVE counting and comparing across
completely different product lines I'm
asserting that this is also an erroneous
specific data set to a specific data set
that actually doesn't help us make any
decisions in the vep process that's what
I'm asserting right so I think it's good
we move past this bug counting for
security issue but the point I was going
to make is that both these data sets are
describing not only the characteristics
of software but the behavior of the
community of researchers doing discovery
which is a really important point
because parsing those two things out
isn't necessarily what we've both been
focused on I think in terms of
rediscovery and collision there are
studies that look at vulnerability
discovery characteristics of discovery
patterns skills and how those vary with
different types of code but this
rediscovering collision issue I think
both is related are looking at both that
population as well as the underlying
software I do but go ahead and so um
it's interesting gonna have to be
working through Katie's point here on as
I think through this but you've got this
big debate you know there's a lot of us
that say the government needs to be
doing matter--it and it needs to
prioritize defense and it's really tough
because we in government leaders not law
for those in government there's not a
lot of knobs on where you get to decide
whether you're gonna prioritize defense
or offense there's very very few places
we can do that especially because we
don't have a strategy that says which is
more important right even in the last
administration President Obama would say
it's a balance well when you're actually
in government or at NSA or Cyber Command
and you've gotta decide but what the
hell does balance mean right I mean when
I've now got this decision about whether
how to make America more secure by
keeping or disclosing this bug what am I
supposed to do
and so the about the only knob that
we've got right now is the vep so I
think there's a lot of us that are
saying why are we doing this to
defensive to offensively or about right
and one of the major conversations for
those of us that like really push
defense myself Robert Kentucky and
others we like to the EP and we say
let's do it more and let's do it better
there's a really strong counter-argument
by Matt Tate Dave I tell and others that
say that's stupid because out of this
vep you get so little value from each
new bug that the amount of time you're
spending on this is just a waste and
it's a dumb idea to begin with so we're
really desperate for these things like
the collision right like what Lily had
said earlier about our bugs dents or are
they sparse because that helps us figure
out are we actually buying down our risk
with all of this that we can do and I
just hope that we start getting other
dials other knobs that we can turn
because we're making way too much over
the EP it's more important than it
written it really is because it's the
only knob we've got so can I can I dress
like that at that point you want more
knobs more dials you can turn that was
the point of our doing the the system
dynamics modeling a couple of years ago
because this is systems level thinking
here these are things that that you know
trying to play whack a bug on a very
dense code base is not going to be the
best lever so the the whole
vulnerabilities sparse and dense
conversation how many of you remember
where that actually originated from dan
gear giving a keynote in 2013 and the
insert so this was the inspiration for
the research that I did with MIT Sloan
School because his assertion was if
vulnerabilities are dense just kind of
writ large
if vulnerabilities in especially in
critical infrastructure are dense then
you know it's not gonna make a
difference to try and play whack a bug
you know and maybe try and buy all of
those bugs and whatnot and then he
asserted if vulnerabilities are scarce
if software code or if code quality from
a security perspective in general is
getting better then the then his
recommendation was the US government
should defensively by up as
many critical vulnerabilities as
possible so that was his assertion
saying that it would be possible to
corner the market and basically drain
the swamp of vulnerabilities so that was
that was where that originally came from
and so we sought to address the question
what is the mode you know what is the
most effective lever in the overall
system and that's why you know a lot of
this work we're looking at it as as very
dynamic and that that's essentially why
we chose this modeling approach are you
taking one bug out of 100 or one out of
a million and you should very right is
it statistically significant will it
make a difference but yeah I mean that
that's that's the whole thing different
than sparse and dense is also easy to
find hard to find if bugs are dense but
they're really hard to find then it
doesn't matter that they're dense there
they can be hard to find those things
can be all the same in terms of the the
various studies we all have different
approaches if you're interested in
looking at it from a heuristic point of
view of theoretical modeling and
simulation point of view there's great
information on that great information on
vulnerabilities if you're interested in
the world of what bug bounties are are
finding what bug hunters are finding and
being disclosed to vendors then
certainly that's where a trace trees
research can help inform if you're
interested in the kinds of bugs that are
being kept for use by by nation states
that are difficult to find and that are
used for offensive operations for
purposes of that matter then that's
where our research comes into play and
the bugs all blogs are applicable to be
considered for the vet but but the ones
that I would think would be majorly
debated within the Beppe are the ones
that are hard to find or are ones that
are used by the nation-state I will say
again though that before disclosures or
vet will ever be the solution we need to
fix patching and because patching is the
major problem and applying them so this
is an interesting part of the debate
that doesn't get dealt with specifically
enough I would argue and I think this is
a fun point to parse that vep is
distinct from patching processes and
companies for two reasons the first is
that vep is intended to be an oversight
function
on the government disclosure and use of
vulnerabilities a necessary element of
operating in a modern computing
connected environment without question
all right from the telogen standpoint
from military standpoint but also an
issue where these are pieces of
information which absolutely could
provide benefits individuals security to
those individuals
if disclosed to a vendor and patched so
we have this balancing test between
achieving how comes in security by using
vulnerabilities and achieving outcomes
in security by disclosing
vulnerabilities DEP is intending to try
and calculate the cost and balance
between these two spaces that is
distinct from the vendor behavior which
is my second point one of the things
that gets really challenging when we
talk about that as it gets very
all-encompassing and becomes the thing
and it soaks in energy and attention and
all through the room but it's a tiny
piece of the software security puzzle
there's no question that patching
processes are a huge issue patch
application especially is something that
we just have not dealt effectively with
as an industry and as a community but
that is distinct from those related but
distinct and so I think that's really
important that we're not going to solve
what companies are doing not gonna
change vendor behavior just by how
government discloses vulnerabilities
however many of them they disclose I
agree that's a different topic certainly
and to me the VP's almost as much about
managing outrage as it is about actual
risk but I mean when you've got you know
new shadow brokers released to the rest
the vep is one of those processes by
which the government can say look we're
trying to do our best you don't get
don't get outraged we're trying to do
the right thing here and it's almost it
I'd say a lot of the benefit that the
government get out of it is about
perception and trying to just handle the
outrage and and calm people down we
already have people lining up so I even
though I have other questions I want to
jump with you guys unless you guys yep
mic myself I I worry that the whole way
this conversation is being framed as
offensive and defensive is is really
missing a huge point which is that this
is not a zero-sum game it's not about
and I'm a Brit but I get you know I'm
part of five eyes so we get to see some
of this stuff too it's not about just
defending United States government or
even about defending United States
businesses in a global economy this is
not a zero-sum game giving out these
vulnerabilities has the opportunity to
improve the world economy and improve
the Commonwealth and I use that in the
old sense of the term not the British
Commonwealth right well that's nice too
and it's not just about you can't just
say that people in the red circle are
against the people in the blue circle
that also gets people in the green
circle because they are against the
Commonwealth and the global economy and
I think if we phrase it just in terms of
defense and offense and in terms of
nation-state offense and defense we're
missing a huge thing here so certainly
what we had there it was a simplistic
point of view that was for for pictorial
illustration purposes there are more
groups in each of those than each of
those I would ask though is it the
government's responsibility to make the
world secure is it the government's
responsibility to make a mama pop shop
secure or so yes it is and maybe I don't
know if the DHS is the right people to
do that I don't know if you have a
Department of Trade and Industry if so
they're the people who should be able to
on the vet panel not the DHS and you
know well the others should be as well
but you need those sorts of people in as
well or you're missing a point and this
is part of what one of the
recommendations from the VP a my
colleague Richard Kanaka who's to be
part of this process was saying right
now NSA is still the executive agent
that runs the vep and we need to do way
that it needs to go to DHS and needs to
be the defensive organization one I'm
happy to say the UK is one of the few
other governments that's actually come
out and talked about disclosing
vulnerabilities to the vendor and the
last bit is this goes back and forth in
Washington DC quite a bit of our week is
Americans I'm gonna stay with American
as American national security better
served by having a safe secure internet
that's going to be here to drive
innovation in the United States and
around the world or are we better served
by having all of the high ground and the
internet to make sure that we can spy
and take out against against our
adversaries and I'm sorry to keep
putting this in u.s. terms but in this
goes back and forth a lot and and so
it's gonna be very interesting to see
how that plays out over the next couple
of years so one thing one thing it's
important to note here
there is a bill that's been put forward
in both the Senate in the house while
the patch act that's intending to codify
this equities process and the criteria
associated with review for vulnerability
and one specific criteria that they
mentioned is the type of software
involved so which you would expect not
unreasonably is that you would weigh if
something is for example a widely used
cryptographic library it is not unique
to the United States there's not unique
to a particular country versus a
proprietary piece of software like say
me doc it only shows up in one
particular state so I think that is
something that's being come part of the
debate panel thank you I guess I I'm
really happy that there are these
studies coming out and I think that it's
early days and hopefully they'll be
better data and possibly more more
relevant stuff but my main question is
for Lilly
can you give me a little bit and you
know J or K do you want to jump it now
would be awesome but can you give me a
sense of what you think the best pro and
con arguments are for why or why not the
green circle is a proxy for red because
it's not obvious to me that it is a it's
it's not a proxy for red what so I gave
a very abridged version of of our of our
study and what we looked at it's it's a
proxy for what the public is I ideal
would be to have access to to multiple
private data sets to try to examine the
characteristics of the overlap since we
didn't have access to multiple private
data sets we looked at the private
public overlap the green and the blue to
find some baseline numbers that could be
used to help inform discussions that go
between the the blue and the red
it's the there are certainly caveats to
our research I think sorry I think I've
remembered what point I was trying to
make earlier so just you know just to be
clear the the modeling that we did a
couple of years ago the conclusion on
the vep process that we had was that it
was much more beneficial for to err on
the side of disclosure and the reason
for that is if you think about it if
we're playing a game of cat
the flag and we've all got the same
flags what do you think you what do you
think is smart thing to do to protect
your critical infrastructure and in
terms of preserving your offensive
capabilities do you actually need 0 days
to achieve most of your goals and and
you know the answer is a resounding no
and we definitely see that that mirrored
in general you know exploitation of
software that we see in the world zero
day exploitation is at that tippity top
of the pyramid if any of you saw Alex's
he note opening keynote the major you
know source of actual harm in the in the
internet ecosystem is this broad base of
feature abuse you know so so that's to
us that was the conclusion was that the
vep should err dramatically on the side
of bowland disclosure because that
actually does preserve the main goal
which is we've got the same flags as
everybody else so I know we were never
we're kind of dancing around that topic
but I just wanted to say that that the
prior worked two years ago that was the
conclusion Joe I'll continue with that
actually just to continue with what I
had been saying while it's not
necessarily a proxy for red and blue
what we had was a data set of blue up
until now there's not been any publicly
available information about what might
be a proxy for what a nation-state has
so we're not just looking at the the
collision rate but certainly what are
the characteristics of the types of
vulnerabilities that live for a long
time or that might be used for news
maybe I want to see this level of
analysis going in on the shadow brokers
in figuring out what was in these how
many yet we still don't know I mean
they're no researchers have gone in and
said how many of these did we act were
actually not known that's why we would
really like to know because we do have a
blue data set yeah unfortunately the
first thing I want to say before my main
question is I think the government is an
is a potential enabler of in of
improving critical infrastructure and
and remediating vulnerabilities all
right I don't want to certainly get into
and I know Lilia blonde is perhaps
involved as I know some people in R and
R with the with the whole question of
the laws of cyber warfare and there been
a number of papers on that particularly
from your colleagues at Rand
let me however get to the main question
and that is to challenge the notion that
you really can't you can only really use
one sort of universal code base as far
as you know doing these kinds of
vulnerability studies because so many
products now are open-source or come or
use a you a you know a large part of
their product is open-source now there's
a lot of open source B by almost by
definition that is goes throughout the
creative world all right and as it's
these are the kinds of vulnerable for
psa's of data where you know where this
kind of research is it is particularly
appropriate and I don't see that being
done here and I don't see any any you
know future attempts to do it so you
know if you if you use let's say you
know for example you know a lot of
people use content use containers for
example whether it's docker or or you
know kubernetes or something else all
right but the kind of research you know
based upon that because that goes across
a whole large number of products I don't
even wear out of time so we let them
answer the question the question is a
challenge to the statements of you can
only do these kinds of the kind of
research you're doing with just a single
code base as opposed to comparing one
code base with another mean it was
tweeting earlier this makes software we
used as vulnerability reuse right I mean
the more that were you you know that
we're using the same the software and in
the common libraries you know the places
we're seeing these end up in a lot of
places and I think we end up with a lot
of concentration risk and I think we
learned this with heartbleed and open
SSL of you know this critical
vulnerability on a lot on some code that
just didn't wasn't having as many eyes
on it as required for such a critical
function we have time for a quick
question quick one okay so I found
quickly we've discussed a lot about the
density bugs in
and vulnerability disclosure but there's
a problem with the fact that a number of
bugs out there can simply not be patched
and how do we address the disclosure of
those things and how do we factor in the
impact of those and also in addition
even when we disclose vulnerabilities we
have such a long cycle for those bugs to
be patched and sin cases they're people
who don't even know that they have those
bugs on their systems they don't patch
them so how does that factor it so so
this is a killer point absolutely I
think the the pushback has to be twofold
the first is again in disentangling
passion theft we have to look at patch
and patch adoption patch application is
incredibly important the the time delay
associated with how often individuals
and organizations have to wait for a
second vendor to validate for example a
an operating system patch before it can
be applied is a tremendous burden on
that on that security process there is
some work it's been done with this I
would encourage you to to poke around
the Belfer website I think there's a
couple of pieces that address this but I
would say - the other thing is when
we're looking at patching when we're
talking about vulnerabilities that
process is dealing with only a portion
of the security landscape so I think all
this discussion is not to remove
capabilities necessarily from the
government but as Katie's pointed out
there are a variety of ways to get to
the same end you don't necessarily have
to sit and rely on the same
vulnerability so there are a number of
paths there anyone want anything before
the close yeah I mean I think we I think
I think we it's people who really really
care about this process we we need to
make sure that where we're trying to
speak the same language and we're
counting the same things and applying
them to the same problems because I what
I see over and over again is really well
intended efforts to to inform policy
decisions that are just somewhat
orthogonal or unrelated and so I just
want us to get on the same page about it
and really really concentrate on what
will actually have the best effect I
think that's what we all want is we all
want the best effect and we have
disagreements on methodology on how to
get there and the government is having
these conversations right I mean they
are trying to figure out all right how
how do we do this what's the right kind
of process that we can have and I bet
they're there
there are brawls as they try and talk to
what the best thing to do her but you do
have this offense defense conversation
if they're trying to figure out the
right thing great everyone thank you
join me in thanking the panelists or
[Applause]