all right thank you thank you for being
here this is a subset of the members of
the global Commission for the stability
of cyberspace and you're gonna hear us
make some opening comments from our
perspectives of what we think the
challenges are and then we're gonna get
into sort of a conversation amongst us
and my hope is that you'll be left with
a feeling of listening to a conversation
of some subject matter experts having a
debate and you can really see like the
edges the contours of where we agree and
where we don't agree where the
challenges are and what we sort of
consider is settle the issues and then
we'll hopefully be able to go to
questions in the audience and so I
really don't like panels where everybody
just reads a set piece I like it when
you feel like you're kind of in a
conversation he's dropping in a
conversation and then you get to join
the conversation later so that's what
I'm gonna aim for so with that in mind
we're gonna start all the way on my left
with with Joe Nye and he's going to talk
a little bit about his experience and
his perspectives and then I'll just work
down the line we when we get to the end
we're gonna start our conversation so
pretty simple straightforward and let's
kick it off thanks Jeff
let me start by picking up where you
left off this morning at that very
impressive
keynote session in which you said that
defense is a combination of Technology
and social and the interesting thing is
that the social is by far the harder
part of it and when you think of that at
the international level its squared so
the question is can we develop norms for
the internet and would that help to
reduce conflict basically there's a
general view that the cyber world is a
Wild West in which there aren't no norms
but in fact that's not quite true there
are islands of norms in many parts of
international relations in the cyber
mein all right if you take the domain
name system there is a pretty coherent
regime focused around I can now if you
look at Trey there are norms that are
imported from other aspects of trade law
if you look at issues of crime there is
a Budapest treaty on cybercrime but
there is also a network of cooperation
through Interpol and elsewhere so there
are islands of norms but they're loosely
coupled and the argument that somehow we
should have some big un treaty which
would solve all this we probably set
things back rather than their advanced
them when you have a domain that is
technologically diverse and dynamic is
this but what about interstate conflict
is there any prospect of norms in that
area there has in fact been some
progress a proposal that the Russians
made in 1999 was to have a large UN
treaty outlawing conflict and this area
information that communications
technology was the term the Russians
wanted to use not cyber that got nowhere
but States did agree to set up a United
Nations group of government experts
which tried to develop some rules of the
road or norms informal things not
treaties and it met after 2004 that a
series of meetings and actually came up
in 2015 with an interesting set of
propositions rather than trying to
outlaw certain weapons because it wasn't
possible to say what was a program that
was a weapon or not a weapon and be able
to verify it they said let's out outlaw
certain types of targets such as
targeting civilian infrastructure and
that got a fairly broad approval
it was the proved by the group of 20
most important
economies in the world but in 2017 this
ung GE is is called ran into a roadblock
the roadblock we should ask marina since
she was a member of the group but the
roadblock in my view was largely a
function of the sour relations between
the United States and Russia and that
set things back so there's something of
a stalemate there though we don't know
how that's gonna turn out but before we
become too discouraged let me point out
that when you have a new disruptive
technology it takes States quite some
time to develop norms or rules of the
roads
Hiroshi Mao is 1945 the limited test ban
treaty was 1968 sixty three and the
non-proliferation treaty was 1968 so a
couple of decades before you have the
first real progress in terms of getting
rules or agreements and even without
that you should note that you don't have
to have global or universal agreements
you can have some that are global some
that are if you want plurilateral or
groups of like-minded states and some
that are purely bilateral for example
people would normally say you cannot get
an agreement in espionage and yet in
2015 the United States and China agreed
to not use cyber means for commercial
espionage mothers don't steal secrets by
cyber means to advantage your own
companies that is something which have
been thought of as unthinkable but it
was endorsed by the group of 20 and it
has had some effect on Chinese activity
so is there progress yes slow and
halting yes but the argument that we're
in a Wild West and that it doesn't make
any sense to try to develop the social
part of this defense mechanism at the
international level I think we have
enough evidence that it's worth doing
and this commission which we all
are participating in is to try to nudge
that along as best we can all right
thank you bill
next up is Wolfgang maybe just also say
just a little bit about your perspective
or your experiences so we know kind of
where you're coming from okay thank you
very much
you know I'm an academic person i
readers professor from the University of
always in Denmark but I was involved in
the Internet Governance debate since the
early days in the 90s I was member of
the board of ICANN and all the member of
the United Nations working group on
Internet Governance and you know when
Jeff gave her welcome speech the day
before yesterday he remembered the good
old times from the 1990s when he said
okay at this time we only technology
people in the room and we had the ID and
now we can rule the world and I remember
when when Peter Barlow published his
declaration of cyber independence so he
even said you know governments of the
old go home
so we overtake a lot of dysfunctions and
all I can was based on the idea of
governance without government and the
question of power was not well certainly
in the room but you know the system how
the DNS is organized is that all the
power is on the edges and the knowledge
and the root server system in the middle
is has just to function to deliver
packets you know from one place to
another one and this powerless that
means no central authority no power in
the center all the power went to the
edges but as Jeff said yesterday you
know after technology you know became we
can for this as a business case this
business came money this money came to
criminals as with criminals came the
government's so welcome back to the bed
all times so now we are sitting here
with a with a new complexity and you
know which is even more complex than it
was 20 years ago and again you know this
is about power
Toffler brought in the in the early 90s
and I spoke about power shift and Joe it
published a lot of paper said you know
we see the fusion of power you know from
central authority to non-governmental
actors and and and and to us a players
and this is really the challenge we are
facing now that that power is in place
power is shifting so we see a
redistribution of power and this is part
of a power struggle
before you reach a new distribution of
power you have a power struggle and we
are in the midst of this power struggle
and it's a very complex power struggle
because we have power struggle among
states we have power struggle among
non-state actors and the power struggle
among states and non-state actors and we
see the emergence of all kind of rainbow
collisions around various issues so it
means it's not just unit that you can
settle the problem with one silver
bullet so it's a very distributed system
where you probably need solutions in a
different way for different issues so
that this is what we call the Internet
Governance ecosystem which has no one
single answer to a very complex issue
and you know can we learn something from
the past probably you know how to go to
another former Harvard professor mr.
Kissinger when he wrote his PhD he
studied the Vienna conquests from 1813
to 1815 and if this conclusion was okay
if you want to have stability you have
to have a balance of power so that means
you do not put for an imbalance of power
so the balance of power has saved more
less stability in Europe of the
nineteenth century you know a number of
decades and but this is very complex can
we learn something from this how to
organize a balance of power among states
balance of power among non-state actors
and the balance of power among state
actors and and States so this is really
a big issue and this commission is about
the stability in cyberspace and probably
or hopefully we can in two years from
now you know develop some ideas which
are useful for the 2020s
because this is a long way to go and you
will not have a solution within the next
two or three years thank you
I come from a background of law
enforcement I am a retired Commissioner
of Police from Singapore and I was also
the president of Interpol from 2008 to
2012 this is a non-executive chairman of
the board and the CEO is actually the
secretary-general now I'd like to speak
from the perspective on law enforcement
and use three courts which I've come
across the first was one from the
previous secretary-general of the
Interpol he says all if the national
crime is local crime somewhere that's
true for most physical crimes but
actually we now know that in cyber it is
not true because in many countries they
don't even have laws regarding
cybercrime so that you can straightaway
know that criminals will take advantage
of operating from these countries the
second one is a code which one of my
colleagues at tassels are used quite
often cybercrime a sorry cyber criminals
operate at the speed of light while law
enforcement moves at the speed of law
okay I think this points out to the fact
that we need three TS like the mutual
legal assistance treaty to get things
done and you know to get across requests
to government's to their foreign affairs
ministry will take ages right and then
the third one is it takes a network to
fight a network I think this originally
referred to the Islamic state but now we
think about it we are facing a network
of very well organized criminals so how
do we form our own networks a network of
trust when when this bilateral network
cooperation there's regional cooperation
there's multilateral and it's quite
difficult because
in Interpol we have 119 member states
and they include well Syria Iran Russia
China in fact the current president of
Interpol is Chinese and that vice
president's are Canadian Namibian
Russian and South Korean of course there
are members who are Americans
there's American member there's a
British in Belgium so it's quite
international we represent all the
continents so how does this then help
our efforts to fight cyber criminals
when you have such issues who do you
bring to your circle of friends do you
work on a bilateral basis do you work
only among friends or do you include
everyone now when I was president
Interpol I met point to my government
that we are very small country we can
solve our own crimes within ourselves in
fact our crime rates very low but
cybercrime has been increasing so how do
we effectively control crime within our
own population when the attacks come
from overseas so we solve them the idea
that we want to set up an Interpol
global complex for innovation where we
set up a cyber fusion center and when it
opened in April 2015 immediately there
was a great success because Microsoft
came to the centre and said we've got
this sim des botnet and it's growing by
leaps and bounds at a time I think in
fact at seven hundred seventy thousand
computers and they were used to steal
Bank passwords and also inject malware
into Microsoft systems so Interpol got
together the people and then using the
Intel intelligence identified that the
command and control centers were
surprised surprised based in the
Netherlands and in the u.s. rather than
in China or in Eastern Europe as
previous botnets so the operation took
place and immediately what happened was
the people behind me quickly moved to
Russia right because they knew that that
would be where you'll be safe so if it
were Europe or operation or an FBI
operation I think he would have failed
but then this was Interpol so they
called up the Russian exactly committee
member it was from the FSB and
immediately they took action to to shut
down the service also so this was a good
example where it's a speed of law it was
probably a speed of a phone call but I
think what's happened is in terms of
prosecution and actually arresting those
people it is not that easy right you can
shut down the botnet but they can
resurrect it but how do you go further
steps to get them in jail and that is
where a lot of what still needs to be
done and that's where I think the
law-enforcement agencies and the
government's will have to try to to get
their act together thank you yeah I am
the Woodcock I guess this is the
Commission's a bit like The Village
People I am the representative of the
private sector network operators on the
Commission yes so so my interest is
really in how the Internet
infrastructure which is essentially
almost entirely private sector owned
operated financed and so forth can
withstand the attacks that it's faced
with constantly a lot of what you're
hearing from us is about coordination
between sectors so if you look at the
coordination within the private sector
we've got NSP sack anti ass I not DBA a
whole lot of different coordination
mechanisms that work just fine that
allow private sector private sector
cooperation to deal with crime and
mitigation of attacks and so forth when
you look at private sector to law
enforcement it's not perfect but it's
pretty good and it's getting better all
the time so that's not a big it's a
difficult thing it's a problem area in
the sense that there's a lot of work to
be done but it's not a problem area in
the sense of something that's getting
worse or something that needs particular
remediation relative to other areas so
like one of one of the areas where
there's really good interesting work
being done there is bertrand alicia pals
internet and jurisdiction project where
we're trying to harmonize the way law
enforcement in the private sector
communicate with each other at a
protocol level such that law enforcement
doesn't have to learn a different way of
talking to facebook than they talk to
Apple then they talk to LinkedIn and
they talk to Dropbox because right now
you've got this sort of babble of a
thousand languages where every
law-enforcement agency has to figure out
how to coordinate with every different
private sector organization and since it
all winds up back in two circuit courts
in San Francisco in Seattle it's not as
complicated as it could be if it were
all in different jurisdictions really
but it's still way more complicated than
it needs to be so again it's an area
where ten years from now we'll look back
at at how things are done right now and
say gosh that was complicated I'm glad
we've got it
you know simplified to the point where
we can address the inherent complexity
rather than sort of the artificial
complexity of the process where things
really break down though is in the
coordination between the private sector
and military and you think what do they
have to do with each other and that's
the problem right now there's a feedback
loop that's not complete so in
militaries
offensive operations are rewarded and
defensive operations are not if you want
a promotion you go and you attack
somebody and even if you're not a
hundred percent successful it'll look
like you're out there doing something
and you get a promotion or a little
ribbon on your chest or corner office or
something right whereas defense it looks
like you're not doing anything you're
spending more and more money every
quarter and there's nothing coming back
and nothing's happening and eventually
somebody says well why don't we just
take that money and use it to beat
somebody up that would be a lot more fun
so that happens it happens all the time
we've got law enforcement you know
trying to deal with criminals at the
same time that militaries are doing
exactly the same things that criminals
are and now suddenly everybody's got
this additional layer of complexity of
well was that a criminal act or was that
a military act if it was military gosh
we just got to let them do it because
sovereignty right this this thing of
allowing governments to do things that
are clearly defined as crimes because
sovereignty makes life really really
difficult for the private sector right
because now the private sector has to
start understanding attribution in a way
that they don't have to if it's all just
a crime we have then this problem of
blowback right so not only our
governments attacking private sector
operated infrastructure then there's
blowback because now that infrastructure
is in some country that decides that
it's going to counter-attack you know in
order to penalize the country that
attacked in the first place under
military theory that's pretty good right
that's how you would do it except that
what they're counter-attacking is not
the government because the government
doesn't have significant cyber assets
it's the private sector because that's
where the Internet is so now you've got
a blowback against the attack that was
conducted from the first country
and so there there are huge huge losses
to the private sector in that first
country as a consequence of the attack
that their government is prosecuting but
there's no feedback loop to tell that
government you shouldn't be out there
kicking Hornets nests right because
there's no responsibility there there's
no feedback loop to get militaries to
stop kicking those Hornets nests just to
give an indication of just how about a
problem this is my my network operations
is is to do with the DNS and with
internet exchange points and in both
cases looking at a thousand times over
provisioning to deal with cyber attacks
so if we compare the amount of traffic
that's running through the
infrastructure for legitimate use to the
amount of infrastructure that's
necessary to withstand these attacks
there's a thousand times difference
we're having to buy a thousand times
more equipment a thousand times larger
equipment to deal with the malicious use
as opposed to the legitimate use that is
a huge huge infrastructural cost I was
about to say investment it's not an
investment that's just a cost there's
nothing we get back from that that is
not serving legitimate use so I think
the where we where we're trying to go
with this as a commission is towards
norms that would declare cyberattack
against critical infrastructure to be
outside the realm of the reasonable in
the same way that kinetic attacks
against hospitals and schools are
outside the realm of the reasonable and
if we can get to the point where that's
globally understood and acknowledged
even if there are a few countries that
are bad actors then there will be a lot
more leverage for getting it stopped
are you well thanks thanks Jeff first of
all I'm really honored to be in this
panel and and to cheer the Commission
I've come from Estonia for those who
have heard about it it's a country
it's not a country club with 1.3 million
of population and were working on that
we are trying to attract more IRA's
to come to Estonia and to provide them
digital services were providing to our
people what do I hope to bring to the
Commission first what have I experienced
nationally but also the international
dimension I'm former Estonian foreign
minister
I'm a former career diplomat I've been
posted as ambassador to Russia to a US
Canada Mexico Kazakhstan Israel and now
I'm sharing the Commission a couple of
facts about Estonia so that you won't
forget it
Skype was invented by stony and guys as
soon as the first country in the world
to introduce paperless government as
to introduce Internet voting and we're
still doing it also in November this
year and the stone is the first country
in the world to introduce digital
signatures nation widely with population
1.3 million we have given more than two
hundred and philia of two hundred and
fifty million digital signatures experts
say it save us five working days
annually two percent of GDP our defense
bandage is two percent which means
defense comes free black hat is
celebrating this year its 20th
anniversary back in Estonia we kind of
celebrated ten years or the first cyber
attack to an independent country being
politically motivated yes those were
cyber attacks on Estonia we learned our
lessons nationally and internationally
nationally the driving force when
talking about cyber security has to be
government but government can't be
efficient if it doesn't cooperate with
private sector and other stakeholders
academia IT experts and others we were
lucky 2007 IT geeks
the guys whom we can never afford as a
government came to assist the government
some local ones some were foreigners but
the games assist the student government
and since then we have the example of
public-private partnership the example
of cyber defense League internationally
2007 I was a student ambassador in
Moscow so during the cyber attacks I
tried to find ways of cooperating as you
can guess I felt I couldn't but we
understood that cyber does not have
borders and that's why international
cooperation is crucial international
cooperation in different organizations
some of the international corporations
have been successful ones I can say
European organisation of security and
cooperation with confidence-building
measures NATO was defense even EU with
digital marketer lose far far from being
perfect and some have failed Jill
mentioned one is the United Nations
yes UN failed a month ago to have an
agreement between different countries on
stability and security of cyberspace
more precisely on international law
cyberspace is not jungle international
law replies we agreed that already in
2013 the question today is how
international law applies and these are
the questions that we help to address in
the Commission cybersecurity has become
a new not only new challenge but part of
security if we talk about security we
are talking more and more about cyber
security the more ambiguous zones there
are the more there are possibilities for
misunderstanding each other for
provocations the more grey zones we have
in application of international law the
motor attempts to touch the boundaries
like we're seeing with interference
international elections or cutting off
power grids
events that are happening around us on a
daily basis I'm a lawyer
I believe in international law but also
I believe in norms
not legally binding norms but norms of
responsible state behavior today
globally we don't have any for us to
discuss it with multi-stakeholders the
four as I mentioned are for states and
governments but this commission is
unique professors from Denmark us former
Interpol boss IT experts and majority of
the Commission is sitting at the front
line with this powerful group I very
much hope that we'll be able to develop
and introduce and convince states to
adopt some norms of responsible state
behavior and we're very happy to have
Jeff with us holding down the fort here
ok so I've got just a couple kind of
opening questions to get the dialogue
moving and then we're gonna move into
some questions and answers and one is I
don't know if I'm trolling bill or some
of the other members here but on norms
there's sort of this mean in the
security community online floating
around that while we're all debating
norms Google and Twitter and Facebook
are building norms that there's another
set of norms out there that are being
formulated de-facto
by these you know the way that patch
management is managed the way that
Microsoft does things are creating sort
of these institutional norms that now
the government's are having to react to
so now governments are in the passenger
seat not the driver seat do you see that
flipping do you ever see a situation and
I'll go to whoever's got a comment so I
would look back to sort of the 1980s and
how device management worked back then
and for every kind of router every kind
of switch there was a separate
management console and communications
whose proprietary and there was no hope
of getting unified management across a
spectrum of devices right and then there
was SNMP
and everybody said gosh that'll never
work it's too complicated you know
vendors will never start all talking the
same language because it wouldn't be in
their interest they all each have their
silo and as long as they can defend
their silo they've got customers locked
in and so forth and that's where we are
right now with coordination you know
Facebook says you know everybody in the
world has to come and fill out our form
and justify themselves to us thus in
such way and then Google says not
invented here we do it this way and
here's our form and here's what the
information we want and here's what
we'll respond to and you know Apple says
something different and it's that's not
gonna work in the long term right the
the big huge market dominant company is
saying you know our way is the only way
and we have so many customers that we
can just dictate to the world is not
going to persist and I think we have
lots and lots of examples in history of
increased communications increased sort
of globalization leading towards a
harmonized uniform way that everyone
expects to do things globally over time
and so I don't think ten years from now
we're still gonna be having to deal with
individual private sector companies
saying no no my way is the only way
right though of adopted I'm nice Joe
well I I agree with Bill just said but I
think it's worth noticing that companies
are not going to be in quite as much
control as people think going back to
John Perry Barlow in the 90s with this
view that governments get out of the way
what the trends have been in us just the
opposite the trends have been to try to
increase the role of sovereign states
inside cyberspace and if you ask to what
extent is Google stronger than the
government of China the answer is pretty
clear Google's not China it once was but
they kicked them out and if you ask as
Mark Zuckerberg with all his billions of
subscribers been able to get Facebook
into China the actors know one of our
commissioners Jim Lewis who's not here
this right now has said that for the
last dozen years or so the Bajor trained
in cyberspace has been the increased
role of sovereign governments and I
think when we talk about those companies
getting stronger and stronger we're
missing that point I don't particularly
think that's a good thing even though I
once worked for the Defense Department
and the State Department in addition of
being a Harvard professor I've had some
government experience
I don't celebrate that I think it's
actually too bad but as an analyst
somebody's written a lot of books about
power internationally those are the
facts yeah I don't think the power
struggles between government and
individual private sector companies I
think ultimately the power struggle that
matters is between governments and
multistakeholderism
and then the other question I had we
talked about a little bit briefly at
lunch because it's gotten a bit of news
coverage was this the vulnerabilities
equity program in the US government of
sharing when do you share zero days when
is a government expected to share it
with a maybe an affected party and the
VP programs been up and running for a
little bit a lot of people since it's
classified are speculating as to its
effectiveness can any of you talk to
sort of do you see that as the future of
trying to diffuse some of the pressures
this inequality between the private
sector and these militaries that are
rewarded for purely offensive operations
is this part of that feedback loop the
bills maybe talking about I think it's a
really a complex issue and john lloyd so
from microsoft is here
Microsoft has proposed this Geneva
Convention Digital Geneva Convention
which includes special arrangement on a
new they called it attribution
organization and so this gets
on the one hand it's a very reasonable
proposal if you see all the attacks and
throw that you would be good to have a
neutral impartial organization like the
IAEA in Vienna which looks into the
scene and says you know where something
comes from and so that you have more
data the problem is that it goes really
to the heart of intelligence and and as
a secret information just two weeks ago
there was in conference to cybersecurity
week in Israel and there was a good
debate between Microsoft and Chris
painter who was has now its last days in
the State Department and while Microsoft
argued you know we have good information
which is probably useful a painter
replied yes you have good information
but not all information so and that's
the problem so that means if you have
only good information probably that's
not sufficient to have a final fix
answer for the attribution so that means
there is a gap how this can be settled
probably if you introduce let's say a a
confidential layer into such an
organization this could be you know one
step forward so here innovation in a
political thinking is also you know it
needed so I remember when I was in the
United Nations working equipment
Internet Governance 15 years ago Kofi
Annan who was the Secretary General of
the United Nations argued the Internet
is the result of a technical innovation
but in policy we do not have innovation
we deal with new issues this instruments
from the old time so we need more
political innovation and insofar you
know was all the doubts I have is the
Microsoft proposal I think this
challenges us to think about innovative
about future political frameworks
mechanisms which has to be based and I
think this is also very important on the
mighty stakeholder approach it means it
cannot be done by government alone it
cannot be done by the private sector
alone you need a third form of
collaboration among stakeholders
if you want to have a sustainable
solution I think as the private-sector
guy I'm gonna say something will make me
unpopular with my colleagues here but I
think there's a moral question here and
I think it's fairly simple one I think
that military and intelligence folks
will often use the rationale we have
secrets and if you knew what we knew you
would make the same hard decisions that
we have to make and you would come off
looking like a bad guy too
you would have to kill people you would
have to steal things so forth right you
would have to do things that are on
their face morally empower unpalatable
but they can't justify that using
publicly available information only
using secrets which you're not entitled
to therefore you cannot judge them and I
think that is just morally bankrupt I
don't think that's a valid argument I
think that we live in a world where
public information is the only
information that matters in the long run
and if you do something if you attack
someone
if you hoard zero-days whatever that is
not in the public interest coming back
and saying well if only I could tell you
my secrets that allow me to feel good
about the thing that I'm doing even
though it's obviously morally
unpalatable it's a worthless argument
from my point of view marina
I just just very briefly elaborate on
what wolken said personally I'm very
skeptical about any new conventions any
new institutions begin for having been
in foreign policy now for more than 20
years very often it's a possibility to
postpone fulfilling of what we have
today we have international law let's
look into that if we find something
missing then at some point we might come
to the new law new international
organization can you imagine any state
giving up state sovereignty or
attribution to an international
organization I don't think so at least
my government is not because at the
moment yes I agree that there has to be
close cooperation as I said private
sector academia expert it has to be
there but giving attribution such a
sensitive question not only technically
but also legally and politically to
somebody else I doubt very much about it
okay we want to go to some questions so
if anybody has them we have two
microphones set up over here three
microphones I'm sorry
first-come first-serve and this
gentleman is the winner great you're
from Estonia and so just say your name
where you're John Hawes from
embry-riddle university in Prescott
Arizona just a neighbor and the Estonia
has now talent version 2.0 which is a
group of rules essentially and based on
Tallinn one and I be curious to have
everyone's comment on that document
because it is something that's been
worked on for a while and it's we're
even in a second version why can't we
start with something like that and then
improve it yes please just for those who
don't know Bailey manual is a
compilation of international law
application of international law written
by nineteen experts of international law
so it has nothing to do with official
positions of NATO although it's a
was done under the umbrella of NATO
center of excellence and it does not
include national positions of government
19 lawyers have proposed how to apply
international law 600 pages I'm a lawyer
very difficult to read but I agree that
now we need the next step what's the
what the next step should be next step
should be 200 pages legal advisors legal
advisors advising governments MFA's
ministries of justice ministries of
Defense should look into that and start
applying we can't apply even if we want
only governments can apply international
law so now it's up to governments so if
there are legal advisors in the group I
encourage everybody to buy it to look
into that and to say what you like at
what you don't sir
I think you had a comment oh I'm sorry I
just a quick footnote Jeff which is
Talan Manuel is a huge important step
forward with the Russians and the
Chinese don't accept it and if we're
talking about international law that's
gonna be applicable he's gotta get
beyond just the light find it so if you
consider a zero weight just introduce
yourself sorry about bilko just I work
for Stratis solutions a small business
consulting company in Maryland so if you
look at a O'Dea is basically a cyber
weapon because that's sort of how it's
being treated right now right come or
countries or nation-states or companies
or organizations create them they hoard
them they use them right so I think what
we're trying to say when you want to
companies or country or nation states to
disclose them is to disarm themselves do
you think it's realistic that you know
the US for instance will want to disarm
itself in a time when you know China or
Russia or whoever you know is probably
not going to go that way all right we
can't we can we can do sanctions with
kinetic weapons right but you might say
doesn't really seem to make a difference
so do you think it's realistic in the
future to really expect nation-states to
do that zero days okay who wants to take
that
I'm looking at you Joe well let's think
for a second about would you really want
to live in a world in which you had no
ability to deter Russians and Chinese
who have used cyber weapons against
Estonia against Georgia against Ukraine
and who have a reputation for having
penetrated the American grid you want
NSA to have zero zero days probably not
and that's why I think Bill's comment
earlier that the people who defend that
are morally bankrupt they don't see it
that way if you go back to what Alex
Thomas talked about this morning of
trying to understand the mentality of
those who are seeing defense in a
slightly different way I don't think
they are morally bankrupt
I do think hiding behind secrecy about
how much they have to keep or hoard is a
different question and we ought to think
of better procedures for reducing that
but just to categorize them as morally
bankrupt I think is not an adequate way
of phrasing the proposition the question
is wouldn't we all be better off if we
hoard it a lot less we can disarm many
criminals we can disarm many Russian
tools by essentially being much tighter
in the number of zero days that we keep
but zero zero days in my minds a little
bit like zero nuclear weapons there are
people there's a treaty now in the UN
four zero nuclear weapons I personally
would not feel safer I think Joe and I
could argue for a long time about sort
of the specifics of this stuff I think
that were in agreement on that last that
if if there are say a hundred
governments that are all trying to
accumulate zero days and we can reduce
the number of zero days in existence by
finding and fixing vulnerabilities then
in relative terms we have made the world
a better place because we have reduced
the stockpile
of the other 99 countries collectively
far more than we've reduced our own
stockpile if you want to look at it from
a national perspective and I think
rather than looking at zero days as
weapons looking at them from an
open-source perspective as problems that
need to be fixed is perhaps more
productive it gets us to where we want
to be a little better in that more eyes
on the code more eyes on the problem
leads to a faster better solution and if
we can have more people looking at the
problems and helping to solve them we
move more people from the secret making
and hoarding problem side to the solving
problems and moving forward side so I
guess my argument would be that insofar
as for instance the NSA has people who
are dedicated to finding and solving
problems and people who are dedicated to
finding and hoarding problems moving
people more into that first category
makes the world a better place and makes
us stronger relative to the people who
would attack us I think we agree on that
good yeah beer okay one quick last
question I'm sorry we're not gonna have
time for our last person in line there
yeah my name is Sean Waltman I'm a
reporter I've been writing about
cybersecurity for more than a decade now
and I wanted to ask about the
vulnerability equities process because
you know one of the interesting things
about it is that no other country has
one as far as I know i mean there's
Estonia have one and I imagine that the
Estonian intelligence services are
finding and hoarding zero-days as the
other you know more than 100 countries
that are now developing cyber war
capabilities how important is it that
there's some sort of reciprocity or
generalization of these obviously the
United States in a unique position for a
number of different reasons but how
important is the is some sort of
reciprocity in these in that particular
arrangement you know as it is in all of
these other issues we
talks about like you know putting
malware on okay infrastructure
insightful thank you
does this Tony you have a vep that you
can talk about not a strategy like you
described that's describing it not not
not that one Singapore but you know of
it's no secret I don't think they even
tell me I don't yeah yeah probably you
know when Joe mentioned that Hiroshima
was in 1945 and it took eighteen years
to the test ban treaty and another five
years to the non-proliferation treaty
and another five years to the first
strategic arms limitation talks which
was a bilateral agreement and the NASS
of five years until in Vladivostok you
know both sides opened their photos and
said we know what you know and we know
what you know so that means this created
a certain balance which was the basis
for further reductions so and I think
this is what I mentioned BC you know if
we you know if we are in a zero-sum game
then it's difficult to reach an
agreement if we are in win-win situation
or when we try to identify mutual
interests then we can even if we have
different opinions or you know state say
to each other we can define a certain
layer where we have common interests
I think it's an interest of all sides to
protect hospitals against cyber attacks
so it it means we can single out this
layer the agreement between China and
and and the US which was mentioned you
know no cyber espionage that it means if
you define the whole system in two
layers and you try to find you know some
solutions for the different layers you
have still a big body they have no
agreement but you know you make you know
you have moped probably not 100 percent
but eighty percent is better than sixty
percent and even sixty percent is better
than 40 percent and zero percent is
really bad
all right well with that I'm gonna close
the session I want to warmly thank
everybody all the panelists here and
like we mentioned earlier in the front
row here we have a lot of the GCSE
commissioners will be around and we're
holding a session thanks to black hat
we'll be here all day tomorrow holding a
meeting and just come up talk to us love
to talked about what we're doing thank
you so much for paying attention and
coming on out