so before I start I wanted to shudder
for my coders
I'm originally from UC Santa Barbara but
I did this work last year during the
summer while I was in internet georgia
tech so is a big kudos to my quarters
chang-jung Simon and when Kelly without
whom this work with a nurse in the light
and the other thing is that I already
presented his work in the past and you
may have heard about this work but today
I'm gonna have a couple of new findings
for example you know the title says from
two permissions we can do best stuff but
maybe in some cases we actually don't
need them we don't need them both and
it's just a little teaser all right so
one lie about Who I am I'm a PhD student
at UC Santa Barbara I hope he's gonna be
like for my last week in my life I'm
graduating next week Rossi fingers and I
play with shellfish again team and if
everything goes fine in September I'm
going to join here echoing friends is an
assistant professor and for my PhD I
mostly focus on mobile security I did a
bunch of program analysis I was involved
with the runner on Android called
dreamer with some folks from you we even
got the pony world yesterday for that
was awesome all with some studying cross
the right tracking we do the sound and
now my recent works is mostly on UI
attacks and I do procrastinate a lot but
when I don't I'm on Twitter trying to
push human knowledge boundaries as I
know that you're very committed and
among - terrarium er so if you're in the
Sinister from a waterfall alright so
this work is about three things the main
one is bunch of tricks to play with with
your eyes to do UI attacks some of these
tricks on you some of these tricks are
actually old and what we do with the old
ones is to show that defenses they were
in place to defend from this old tricks
and no tricks are actually not that
useful in terms that they can be
bypassed and in words they can actually
be abused to mount even worse the target
there wouldn't be possible without these
defenses and what we show is that these
two tricks are enough to completely
compromise the UI people look whatever
the means I'm going to tell you ii and
the
means that you can say bye-bye to your
device security follow me with your IP
below
well it's actually pretty simple you
have the UI it shows something to the
user and in mobile phones the UI is also
the main way the user can interact with
the phone so there is an input channel
and so for example a kid tap something
and the UI needs to update itself to
show to the user yes I received your
input and so that's where the loop comes
in this work is about two things one is
to show that if an attacker can
implement for attack primitives which is
basically the active and passive version
of an attacker trying to compromise the
input and the output channel then you
can do a lot of bad stuff and the second
point is that these attacks are actually
possible we identified a number of
design vulnerabilities that allows us to
mount bunch of attacks we call cloak and
dagger and these are the tacks I'm going
to present today so first of all why
should we care about UI security and
mail sign I come from an academic
background so some of you would say ah
come on what what is this stuff
help me out here you know Android
features in number of low-level security
mechanisms same boxing and you know even
Nick travellish Lee the pleased to see
here give a fantastic talk on reducing
the attack surface and this is amazing
stuff and you know is actually making a
difference and I have seen around this
researcher they're having actually much
more difficult life trying to explore
this related vulnerabilities however
some of these UI bugs can actually
bypass this vulnerable this design
security mechanisms and you know if you
can click like a user then you can do
something you would call confuse deputy
which means you know instead of hacking
the Settings app what you can do is to
click calculate user and ask the
settings up can you please get all the
permissions okay so that's why I believe
this UI attacks are actually important
of course they are not as powerful as
you know root exploit see things like
this but you know as a researcher I
believe that this is also a direction an
area where we should focus our attention
now the title of the talk starts with
two permission
and when Estonia which to pursue
permissions are in Android permissions
work in this way in latest version of
Android what happens is that in app can
require for example the location
permission and at runtime they use the
the application can have the user or can
you please get any user need to say yes
you can
or no you cannot okay so the two
permissions we use the first one is what
we call system and app window informally
we call it the drawn top with this you
can draw arbitrary overlays on top of
your screen and it can be completely
custom in shape content transparency and
they can be either clickable or
pass-through and that's an exclusive or
and I'm going to I'm going to go back to
this in effect and this permission is
actually despite of them 10% of the top
5,000 apps we withdrawal and some of
these applications are quite popular
with billions of users like Facebook
Skype and so forth the second permission
is the CBD service in theory it's a
mechanism through which an application
can assist user with disabilities and it
is very very powerful ek is notified for
each UI event and you can also inject UI
events such as clicks and so forth there
are some security mechanisms to prevent
abuse but it's very very powerful and
it's also you by number of applications
not that common but is actually used and
for example LastPass is using this
permission to automatically fill your
password in in your forms okay what we
show is that these permissions are
enough to do a number of bad things now
the question you might have in your mind
is why would the same user ever grant
these super missions right you know if
you that needs to a manual enabling this
you know it's not that stealth attack is
not practical
well it turns out that's not the case
what we found is that the drones of our
mission is actually automatically
granted for applications coming from the
Play Store the reason is that before
Android remember which version but the
duronto permission was considered as a
normal permission but then Google
understood it is actually quite powerful
and so it classified that this dangerous
one unfortunately there are so many apps
and so many users rely on
permission that one understanding is
that we will didn't want to explicitly
have pop-ups bugging users and so as or
now if an app ask for this permission
and it is thought from the Play Store is
going to get it automatically and the
second point is that now we have develop
a number of rejecting tricks so that the
user can actually be lured to enable
speedy service what's even worse is that
the list of permissions in 'native is
shown to the user at any point in time
in latest version of Android as I said
there is no like list of permissions
required everything EpiPens the runtime
you know there on top is automatically
granted we get the other permission to
play jacking so the user doesn't
actually see this what's even worse is
that in some version of Android it's
quite tricky to understand if an
application requires these permissions
or not for example this is a view from
Android 6 setting from my proof of
concept which requires both permissions
we're using this work as you can see
here there is a no permissions if you
click you actually see no permissions
and even if you scroll down here that is
not like special access drawn table
there is absolute noting the way you can
see if an app get drawn to permission is
actually to go to settings apps click on
the gear symbol then there is adding
special something and then click on draw
on top and then you can see the list of
applications now I said that these two
permissions are powerful but there are
number of security mechanisms there to
prevent abuse and now I'm going to give
you an overview about these security
mechanisms the first one is that for
each click two things can happen and
overlay can either get the click and
knows and know where they use a click or
the click goes through and then the
attacker doesn't know where the user
actually click so you cannot implement
out-of-the-box
things like capturing and propagate
clicks what is the case well imagine
this if you could do this what you could
do is to draw overlays on top of the
keyboard and then what you will do is to
wait the user click somewhere so for
example if the user clicks on this W
overlay the user would reject the click
understand ok the user click on W
propagate a click and enter the user
Cavanaugh's the user clicked on the
double and so you could create the
number of relays and you can understand
exactly where the user key of course you
cannot do this another trick if you're
familiar with the windows manager there
is a flag called flag made watch outside
touch for which an overlay can receive
notification about clicks that reach
outside other applications okay it's a
security mechanism in this case the
coordinates of the click are set to zero
so an application can understand the
user click somewhere but it doesn't know
where the user clicked ok second
mechanism is about making sure that it's
quite difficult to enable a CBD service
and so it's a multi-step approach you
need to first browse to this window
where you need to select your
application and then you need to click
on this switch and then you need to
click on yes I actually want this so
this is make sure that the user is very
rare about put is doing third security
mechanism is a prevention about Glee
checking now clicking has been known
email mobile for quite a few years and
I'm going to give you a very quick
introduction about out this attack works
this is not normal stuff this has been
presented somewhere else let's say that
you want to lure the user to click on OK
button what you do is to create an
overlay on top of everything and then
you create an overlay that seems like a
button for which the clicks actually go
through and so where the user clicks
hear the click actually reach the bottom
ok so what Google did to prevent this
attack actually this was there are a
number of talks about this topic
the latest one and the most
comprehensive I found is from the
Katyusha from 2014 and mobile did as I
said is to implement the protection
mechanism which we call obscure flag the
way it works is the following basically
when you have a widget and is gonna
receive a click there is a flag that is
going to be said if and only if there
was the click actually went through
another overlay so the ok button can
understand ADA or standing on top of me
I'm not going to try this click another
way of implementing this is to call this
method set filter touches when obscure
which basically means the test the
framework please if there was something
on top while I go click don't even
deliver the click to me
I don't want to know about this okay so
the way it's implemented in the CBD
service is the following let's say we
have this view let's say we cover it
with another lay if the user clicks here
is going to get a pop-up like this what
it says because an app is obscuring me
I'm not going to trust you please
disable whatever overlay you have but
there is no way I'm going to try this
clip why again for preventing reject the
last security mechanism that is in place
is that the CBD service cannot reach
sensory information for example
passwords and if you check from the
augmentation what was written is that
basically since privacy can be
compromised by leaking sensitive
information the password is not exposed
to a CBD services and in fact if you
take a password widget into a get text
method you're going to get an interest
ring you're not gonna get anything okay
good now I'm ready to show you what we
found
I'm going to start with an attack we
call contacts directly jacking and PJ
can get me tricky when you need to have
multi stage settings the question is
where do the user click should I move to
the next stage or not and anything's
like this so what if the user click
somewhere else we need to reset myself
so there are number one certainly that
might arise and you know again there are
number security mechanisms to prevent to
an application to understand where the
user click if they click doesn't reach
the model all right and so the key point
here is what if there is only one way
for a click to not reach the malicious
application think about this we want the
user to click this button what you could
do is to cover everything but the bottle
with some overlays for which the clicks
do not go through ok
and the remaining part you have to
recover it with with another layer for
which clicks actually go through now if
you click here you're gonna get some
coordinates same if you click here but
if you click here your head 0 0 for the
security defense I mentioned before and
so the attacker knows exactly that the
user click exactly where he wanted and
we can go to the next step so you can
adapt and go to the next step the second
part of this attack nuclear jacking is
that we need to bypass this obscure flag
and the school flag is a food to
understand if there was something on top
and if there was some other overlay
covering the bottom however who says
that to do clickjacking we need to cover
the target bottom think about this again
we want the user to click on this OK
button
what if we cover everything but the OK
it's an OK button is extremely generic
and it's extremely simple nowadays to
reuse them to click on this quite simple
you know this is just an example but
it's just like a button anything is that
these buttons protected by this obscure
flag are usually very generic and so as
long as you can hide the context the
attacker wins so more in general we call
this context hiding attack and the big
issues that applications do not have
enough context information to take
informed decision and you know the
school flag to us seems concept very
broken is not enough to protect only the
button you need to protect the entire UI
unfortunately it's not that easy to fix
because if too much context is disposed
a malicious application can actually use
it to mount different kind of attacks
like fishing and things like this and
you know if you have the entire context
to know exactly what's on top you can
now do state inference attacks and
things like this so not easy now the
problem is there with these two tricks
it's actually becoming very very easy to
do click jacking to enable CBD service
and again we just need to eject three
clicks these clicks do not need to be
consecutive there is no guessing
involved not timing tricks we don't need
to guess did the user click here or not
know the loser can clicks whatever you
want and if you click there then we go
to next step otherwise we keep the same
UI now before we go into ok what we can
do with the disability service I want to
have a quad discussion about this
obscure flag because not only we found
is not useful but we find a couple of
things were quite interesting the first
one is that the implementation is
slightly misleading if you check the
docs there is written that this flag
indicates whether there was an overlay
the fully or partially cover another
layer
so it seems this is not true in the
sense that if you cover it partially and
then you click any place that was not
covered Ashley this leg doesn't seem to
set to be set and it seems the Google is
quite aware of this we check the source
code and we found a different flag which
is hidden from the documentation called
flag window is partially obscured the
interesting part is that the
documentation here this part is exactly
the same as the flag windows obscure the
difference is this or we say alike flag
window sphere this is actually true and
this is not exposed to documentation and
I tried and I never seen this this flag
actually set so I guess is going to come
in a newer version of Android the other
point is actually a little bit worse we
found out there are ways to abuse this
obscure flag in in a way to mount even
worse attacks and so the trick is that
when you attack we call it invisible GUI
attack where we can call all the
keystrokes by only requiring this drone
top permissions and we basically used
obscure abuse the obscure flag security
mechanism the attack works in this way
these represent the phone that is lay
down so now the attacker can create
overlays like this okay these overlays
are drawn invisible so the user doesn't
see them the clicks are pass through so
the user even interact with the phone it
doesn't see that there is something on
top because everything works respected
and we create them with this flag watch
outside touch which means that wherever
the user clicks each of these overlay is
going to receive a different motion
event of course the coordinates are not
set because of the security mechanism I
mentioned before but they're going to
see a motion event and the god of the
targets understand where the user click
what we found out that the way the
obscure flag is implemented actually
allows the trackers to understand
exactly what the user click the way it
works is the following basically for
each click let's say the the user clicks
on number one the highest target point
is computed and then each overlay is
comparing it as the level say with the
target point so in this case overlay one
is saying well that means that okay and
everybody else is gonna see the same the
target point is actually lower than me
everything is cool however if you click
on number two
the target point is higher than one so
one is going to set obscure while all
the other three are going to be not
eschewed and I guess now we are
understanding the trick right if I click
on three you're going to get this part
and if you click on for even eight this
button so from the patterns of the
obscure flag that each of these motion
events receive you can actually
understand where is a click by using the
screw flag edge side channel now the way
you weaponize this is that the state of
trading just run for overlays you
actually create a number of them one for
each key and now the second knows
exactly where the user is clicking
passwords and things like this this
again only requires the drawn toe
permission there is not CBD service
involved and the big problem here is
that in our opinion this window manager
is crazily complicated and US security
seems to be like as an afterthought I
don't mean a Google doesn't care what I
mean is that it seems that it's less
understood and more common bugs like
buffer flow at things like this and it
seems more for more systemic work needs
to be done to understand what's going on
and how can we protect from this side
challenge for example it may appear the
other thing we think is that it seems
that there is a violation of the
principle of least privilege were
basically overlays our application can
create overlays are completely invisible
pass-through and they are completely
customizable and these allow the packet
to actually play we are tricks with the
UI and you know it might not be
necessary that you could do this now
back to the stability service once we
get it what can we do
so another design issue we found is that
by default this UI objects are all
treated non security sensitive so in a
way we are treating security as the
exception and not as the rule and we
don't secure this quite bad when you do
this for example I mentioned before that
CBD service should not be able to get
your passwords but what we found is that
the key is building up the keyboard
itself as treated as normal buttons and
so whenever you click on a button
basically the model is going to receive
a speed event with exactly which but
when you click and so now you can get
all the passwords similar example
two-factor authentication codes all
these guys are not protected so
is a malware with the CBD service can
actually read em off the screen one of
the most powerful actually that we found
is the security pad these the over the
view through which you unlock your phone
what we found is that these buttons are
treated as normal buttons so whatever it
is that in the background an application
is going to receive notification when
you click on the pin which means you can
steal the pin and what you can also do
you can inject the pin and unlock the
phone in a crazy part for us is that
apparently you can do this while keeping
the screen completely off so we have
this attack scenario where once you're
compromised you know you leave your
phone there you can stare at it and you
have no idea what's going on now there
are more interesting attacks if you can
mix these two permissions together and
for example this our traditional fishing
works in mobile in the mobile world so
what happens is that the tackiness
understand the user went on Facebook and
it was something on top that looks like
Facebook and now the user types the
password in clicks again and the problem
is that at the end of the day the user
is actually they logged out and so it
may be suspicious did something bad
happen if you make this super mission
work it what you can do is the following
you understand traceability service the
user went on Facebook you create
something on top then the user and start
typing things it pressed again and then
with a speedy service we still the
passer we put the password in the real
Facebook app you click login and at the
end of the day the user is actually
completely LogMeIn exactly as you was
expecting and easily this is doing
complete UI in the middle and there is
no way to detect this even if you know
you're under attack another attack is
where basically we serve it is the user
and then the mean time we actually click
around and we can do bad stuff
one example is basically we can install
a second application from wherever and
then we can enable all the permissions
and then we can do cleanup steps so that
the user doesn't see any weird artifacts
after the attack was run other tags you
can do some run somewhere where it's Ted
of encrypting all the files what you can
do is to change the pin to Sunday this
attacker controlled and then
and then basically the user is locked
down locked out from his phone in other
ways that you can cover the chrome
application and then you can basically
take over a Google account by stealing
past students for doing steal State
passwords and in things like this and
the other problem is that even if Google
speaks its own applications there are a
number of apps there that we remain
vulnerable unless they start to try to
defend themself and a couple of videos
now let's see if it is going to fly this
is going to show these going to be clear
jacking to get to be serviced and then
we're going to stall the secondary app
let's see all right all right so we're
going to open the proof-of-concept so
what we do is to simulate the user needs
to use some kind of tutorial and so
we're going to say okay please stop
tutorial and then we're going to say you
know we're going to show you something
and it's going to Tory about being a
nice guy humans are going to be
represented withdraw it press next and
now we're going to tell the user we are
going to show you a video and please
press ok when you're ready and the user
press ok at this point we start showing
a video and what happened is that the
CBD service is actually already enabled
and while the video is playing we are
actually clicking around automatically
and installing a secondary application
enable all the permissions and things
like this
and it said if you do recent that is not
in there to see now I'm going to show
you what actually happened behind the
end the same we open the same
application and basically the first
click on the start to toriel actually
went when the first click you need to go
to the CBD service and then the next is
actually clicking on the switch and the
ok button you see now is actually the ok
button from the real a CB d service and
since the ok button is not covered of
screw flag is not triggered and then you
can pull the back off now what's
happening is that very stolen secondary
application we are writing now enabling
device and means now we are enabling all
the permissions and now we are going to
resend and wipe everything off so the
user is absolutely no clue about what
happened and the tip another thing is
ransomware and I don't know if Simon is
here but it is thanks a lot and it the
video is actually quite fast what's
happening is that we are we already took
the pin with the targeted show before
and then we are basically changing the
pin and this can happen very very fast
really ok star this will change the pin
or set the pin and putting a message
that the user knows is affected powering
off and the user is out of this one
alright so I hope I convinced these
attacks are quite powerful or one other
question is are these actually practical
now the question for this UI attacks you
need to ask this question because it's
not like you know root exploit and then
you need to run your script and then you
get a shell or something like this but
there is user interaction and you know
in the past other people actually on
that this is from plea jacking that you
can get a CBD service these rows I think
March 2016 so a while ago and we would
say we are not going to take this
because we believe the TAC is not
practical so we actually now our paper
made a big deal out of this with trying
to show we have to try to get the
smoking gun
these attacks should be considered
seriously because they actually work and
that's what we did from my background I
coming from academic background when we
need to have a smoking gun about
protocol ative attacks with the user
studies so I recruited 20 guys at
Georgia Tech and when when I did the
news experiments and we try to talk
these users with the three most
complicated attacks we had from the
technical step points and the results
are pretty bad nobody could get nuclear
jacking same for the sangoma
distillation nobody in this award
epidemic and it's only we just trying
attack we run the attack and then we
give the phone to the user so the user
was actually able to freely go around
the phone try to understand if there was
something weird or not and again nobody
was able to tell us say something
actually happened the third attack was a
stealthy phishing actually 1802 any fell
for it toward them managed to trigger a
bug in my prototype implementation
basically we had some facebook fishing
thing and I told them to click login and
these guys click on the ok button from
my from the keyboard
my prototype was broken and so they
noticed something fishy in the UI but if
they did not understand they were under
attack what we also did was to fix our
prototype and then we call them ok we're
going to run experiment twice one time
with vacuum at that time with dot with
not and even if they knew they knew we
were attacking them they could not tell
me when they were actually attacked so
we believe this stuff is actually quite
practical and you know we took this
occasion to actually ask them my way do
you know about these permissions and it
seems the none of them knew about both
and a point is if a user doesn't know
about this permission why the hell
should go around in special settings and
special views and so forth to see if an
application as these permissions there
is no incentive for the user to actually
try to figure this out now how can we
fix this the first thing we did was to
report at the simple bugs we have
through AOSP issues this was August 2016
and the first one we reported was the
invisible grid attack and it was
recognized as an actual bug
unfortunately it is not fixed yet we
recorded those two that see
the service that you know we can do it a
number of things for example stealing
passwords what documentation says we
cannot do this and it's actually it was
quite tricky to have a discussion with
them so we reported a bug and a
first-century got after a month was one
fix work as intended
so guys documentation says I cannot get
the password and have a proof of concept
a shared from your checking at the
pasture or sridham month later great
high severity champagne was opened and
were super happy however one month after
we actually got another message with
work six work is intended because if you
think this you know if we limit these
services the device will be unusable and
it's kind of a mix-up here where
basically it's like we don't know how to
fix it and maybe we should fix it so
it's kind of kind of confusing thing if
it's a bug it should be fixed or maybe
we don't know the system in such a
community we should figure something
else but we don't believe that the
trigger is 'm but we still felt at some
guys that is written in your
documentation that you should not be
able to get your password in the reply
was awesome was real updated
documentation the amazing part is that
they actually did so what a check is
that a June 6th security Nova still
there I got the link from the internet
time machine and the current version
this year the note actually appeared so
at least you know documentation is
consistent consistent with what we found
and I can brag for ever my friends like
all the indentation and still no cvd
unfortunately
they're not covered by this alright
kidding about what we did next is to you
know to think on how to convince Google
that
clickjacking is actually quite powerful
and that we should probably do something
and again it was tricky
I checked the poly pomona biddies and
there is a message like this some
classes of my videos generally do not
qualify and guess what tap jacking which
is another version of clickjacking and
you are addressing generally are not
covered by the bug bounties which make
me very very sad and after this I went
to this mode and this mode and is mode
for
month and you know the point being I
don't care about money but it's weird
that some bugs like this were sure they
are not like root exposed it should be
fixed immediately
but you know they're actually quite
powerful and maybe we should treat them
more seriously and so yeah said what we
actually did eventually is that we had
an opportunity to share the paper with
EDM ludic with thing that of Android
security and we did not have come to
directly with him but we know that you
write the paper the easting read the
paper and they are considering this very
seriously
unfortunately all the tax the present
today are still knoppix
latest version of Android even with
July's updates I have PC on my personal
phone it is a Nexus 5x and is fully
updated which is well disappointing and
you know in our mindset where we believe
these are actually bill how are they
reacting so either two is one is
something like this where it's like
whatever you I bugs which is my best bet
at least in in the past
the other one was something like this I
think is quite unlikely thing is always
true dislike somewhere in the middle and
I actually was born day on the option on
the left because you know I worked on
the right security for with one of my
PhD colleagues at UC Santa Barbara and
you know we try to report this UI bugs
and you know it seems that the response
is not that all this amazing we should
fix it absolutely no we reported I think
about three years ago where we could
cover the screen navigation status bar
things like this I think is still an fix
after three years and apparently I'm not
alone so I was browsing through internet
and checking some some some some talks
and he found a thought from Nick where
basically it was the end of security
symposium and we was present again this
attack surface reduction things like
this and the first question got in the
QA
was you know this is great stuff but
they're all so plain boring bugs like in
the UI and I'm stop reporting them
because you know it seems that you guys
don't care and you know I don't know if
I'm going to ever meet this guy and make
the case years
see this presentation I want you to know
that I hear you bro I understand what
really you've been through now kidding
about again this is another example why
at least on our side we have this
feeling well this UI bugs are not are
not considered seriously again I'm not
trying to say these are as bad as other
low-level bugs they are not they are
less practical and things like this but
I think we should do something and you
know on our site with an academic paper
we published this paper as typically
security and privacy with a proposal on
quite academic buzz around how we should
fix the ndred UI and we have a number of
things I'm not going to go through them
today but everything is in the paper and
you know what given the reaction we said
hi you know maybe we're not ready yet to
understand ok we need a defense now we
really need to push for ok maybe we
should fix this these things and this
was published in May what happened next
was quite interesting basically
representatives paper we even got an
award for distinguished practical paper
award and we should have a website which
is about it and then it went insane I
think thread post start to cover this
and after that it exploded it was all
over the news and the reaction was
fantastic some people said it's amazing
some other people this is absolute
override BS you know if you are into
popcorns there is a trial on Twitter
that you should really check it out it's
amazing and we even got nominated for
the most override bug yesterday we did
not win but I'd my speech rate try to
put some more eye for this talk other
was my joke Nick version of getting this
and so it seems there was a lot of
interest and of course mixed some people
got P is equal to much publicity for
this and you know of course I'm a big
fan of this work I like it on the
override part I actually hear you guys
it was crazy amount of press coverage
and for us what was interesting is that
some of these news articles actually
asked Google to provide an answer to
provide a comment and so the comment
from Google was
we have two ways of dealing with this
the first one is that we deploy some
protection mechanism in Plato text and
Playstore to the tech deserts and as of
now even before this rapist came out
this was may we have security mechanisms
to to make sure the Android or these are
not possible and so we took this part
and we try to investigate ok are we
really what can we do about this do we
agree that everything's going to be fine
or not so we start with a person and we
start to ask ourself if I would I fight
we Google how can I detect this these
attacks now from the behavior point of
view I think is quite tricky because you
can implement these tricks in many many
different ways so personally what I will
do is to scan applications on the store
with these two permissions they are not
the many applications I believe with
requiring both permissions so that's
already red flag and somebody should
check them out and so this led to the
question of do we actually need both
permissions to do these attacks well
well so what we found was interesting
the first part is that fun a way to
boost up these attacks only with this
system and a window and the point is
that ok once we have this application
the goal is to stole a second
application from the store where a CBD
service is required and so you get the
first one you stole the second one and
then the first one can enable the
activity sorry for the second one and
after these desserts can actually play
together and do the malicious activity
by collaborating so good luck with this
the question is how do we do this right
so rejecting again what we found is that
many have structure it will negatively
jegi including Play Store app so
basically what you can do is that
programmatically you can open the Play
Store to specific application before you
of course you have your yoga verb in MLA
you lure the user to click here and then
after while the application is already
installed you know it can be after 2
days whatever and then again you can
open this view programmatically with
main intent and then you load the user
to click here after this point the
secondary application is installed and
again you can do all the tasks actually
before enabling they want from the
second
application now let's go a step further
do we actually need the system air
window so while we're stinking with this
we had this challenge accepted we had
this realization that seasonal window is
used to create windows of this type type
system type alert system okay and the
point is that we don't need to create
windows with this type so each type in
Android defines in which range of the
level your overlay is going to be
created and this kind of a left system
is quite powerful because you can go on
top of the status bar and things like
this but for these attacks we are not
going to do run some other things ladies
we just need to go over all activities
and that's it and talking to our my
friend realized Wow first actually the
way to go so toasts are one of the
features where you can create them with
this make text API when you create them
they look like this they're just very
brief notification it turns out that
there is this API and you can create
them for a limited duration either 2
seconds or 3.5 seconds now toasts have
been abused in the past and the trick
usually is that you keep creating them
okay
and what we found is that it's actually
possible to create custom toasts by
using exactly the same API that you
would use to create this system overlays
so you have this window manager ad view
and things like this and it's actually
pretty simple to port the current probe
probe concept to use those and when I
say pretty simple I actually mean it you
literally substitute the string with
type toast in the tag works out of the
box now this works actually in Android 6
and so you can move stop these attacks
with their permissions and the protocol
issues that you need to object to more
clicks to get the CBD service but you
know for the invisible grid attack we
don't need a CBD service so out of the
box and application with 0 permission
can read exactly where you are clicking
this actually was speaks in and reach
seven so Google you know toast have been
abused in the past in different ways
move aware of this and so you cannot
pull this trick off because there are a
number of protection mechanisms against
toast abuse and so in this case the
latest version you can bootstrap these
attacks with one permission
now we also look later though
I was a couple of plot twists here so we
looked at preview three developer
version basically invincible-attack
is fixed and apparently google fix it
and the way we propose in the paper that
means no propagation of obscure flags
for motion and side events so fantastic
job for clickjacking were quite
surprised because we saw the is actually
more vulnerable than before the ok
button is actually not protected by the
obscure flag and the third point to use
their own words works as intended this
is an economic kick so I'm not surprised
they're still there but the very very
good news is that three days ago Google
is the preview for for Android or and it
was out decklid jackin to enable CBD
service is fixed and again we are super
happy because it seems they use what we
suggest in the paper it is at least for
the settings up which is super important
just don't draw overlays and is there
are no before compatibility issues what
you can do is that you make the
application believe that the overlays
are drawn but you just don't draw them
so if something is fishy the user is
gonna notice so in Android or preview
for what happens is that if you go to
CBD service overlays are disappearing
and so you cannot do clear checking
anymore and that's the same thing they
did for permission list is now in 97 if
you go to permission all overlays are
automatically disabled and you know this
makes all the tags more difficult so
that's super promising direction and I
hope these kicks are gonna also be
present in the final Android or a
version now I give this talk a couple of
times around and I start to talk with
norm some companies and it seems that
fixing clickjacking may be actually much
much much trickier than at least what I
was expecting when I started working on
this and you know for a Settings app
what you can use to disable everything
but if this obscure flag should be used
in other contexts place to wrap or you
know Facebook credentials but Twitter on
all these things then you can have
protocol issues why because it seems
there are applications like this one
whose main functionalities to get an
overlay on top of everything that is in
a transparent you still see it but it's
just fine
which clicks go through okay and if you
the obscure flag around these create
potential problems and for example when
you study the application they are going
to warn you the attention there are some
issues within the six and you know you
need to disable this application when
enable permission and they see something
like this it is endre six only bugs they
prevent granted permissions this bug is
actually the implementation of those
skills Lex is actually the security
mechanism and they say fix in under
seven because ninety seven when you go
to permissions they are actually develop
disable automatically but of course if
this obscure flag is used in other
applications then you know a third-party
app came and just decide let's cover all
the let's disable all the relays the
Settings app can do because this is
system at from Google and so I believe
this is been an open open problem
another thing that I've been told is
that there are some manufacturers they
basically have this keyboard that are
implemented with overlays where
basically see the keyboard and then you
see there is an invisible over later and
so apparently some of these companies
try to use the obscure flag in
production and then they need to disable
it because it was creating too much
problem people could not type anything
anymore because again there was this
invisible veil on top of the obscure
flag fix out and say no another address
anything alright so I think it's been
another problem now I have a couple of
the lies that are not really related to
UI adducts is more generic and it's
ready to you know Android security in
general and because I thought okay we
are going to have this eventually fixed
but when our phones are going to get
these sticks so I gave my old Nexus 5 to
my dad and that's okay maybe sooner or
later it's gonna get fixed but I found
this table from Google that says you
know for Nexus 5 later date for severe
that date is going to be October 2016
and so Nexus 5 is actually stuck with in
verse 6 there are no updates there and
so all these bugs are I don't know I
think if Google doesn't change anything
I want to remain there for a while
5x same thing basically ting in a year
my car in X 5x is numb when I see
updates and you know what should I or
should I change pawn and situation
doesn't get much better with newer
phones were basically you know the
I think that expensive but in a couple
of years they're going to be you know
out of range for getting security
updates and I don't I think the
direction of attack surface reduction is
fantastic it is a fantastic job from
Nick and his team and one other thing
would be to move for this modernization
of this application didn't talked about
it maybe so that you know all phones
don't get stuck to previous version of
Android and they can get the actual
updates all right let's release it let
me wrap up present a bunch of uie
attacks again new tricks some of these
tricks are old and we found out that the
five mechanisms to prevent these old
tricks are actually not very useful and
they actually open the doors to much
more powerful attacks and many low level
security mechanisms can be bypassed and
so this why we think UI
security bugs matter and honestly I
believe these are little low-hanging
fruits for the Tigers because it was
actually quite simple to implement these
attacks and you know if I could do this
in a couple of weeks and pretty sure the
guys experience with crazy low-level
buffer flows and second bypass and stuff
like this can pull this out in in an
afternoon or zone we set up a website
the more information there is a paper a
bunch of demos and things like this this
is my content information of course I'm
very very happy to you know talk about
the stuff you want to bring me and
that's more or less yet thank you much
[Applause]