my name is Avram you know time also
known as upon tester principle security
researcher with HP fortify team and here
with me my colleague Alexander meters
which is also security researcher with
the HP fortified team so we have a
packed agenda for today so let's jump
straight in 2016 last year was the year
of Java desalinization attacks right it
was a very well known vector since 2011
but probably because of the lack of
remote code execution gadgets in very
popular libraries this vulnerability
kind of got ignored by the community and
no one was actually looking for it until
last year so this is also true for the
dotnet visualization it's a very well
known vector at least for the binary
formatter and for the net data contract
serializer because it was presented like
40 years ago here in the same conference
by James for so but since there was no
remote code execution god yet again the
community is not actually looking for
this vulnerabilities or kind of ignoring
them so at that time the solution was
like okay I stopped using Java this
realization altogether it's dangerous
you should not be seer eyes and trusted
there and developers were like well yeah
I would like to do so by need to store
my objects into this database I need to
move our send these objects across the
wire so I need to use something and then
the security experts were like okay then
use something like a secure JSON or XML
library instead so our goal with this
talk is twofold
first of all we want to verify those
JSON libraries are any better than the
Java visualizer like the object input
stream and also raise awareness around
the dotnet dissertation vulnerabilities
who will be providing a list of
vulnerable libraries and gadgets so in
the first section we will cover JSON
libraries for both dotnet and and Java
we will provide gadgets live into
arbitrary code execution and then we
will have some demos so in how to get
arbitrary code execution on web
application frameworks and then the
second block is about dotnet serializers
we want to raise this awareness
we will provide courteous living to
remote code execution got yet and again
we will show you some some demos so with
any further ado let's jump into the JSON
section and just to set the expectations
clear we are not talking about JSON when
used to exchange simple data or simple
JavaScript object between the front end
like a JavaScript front-end and maybe I
don't know a spring controller in the
backend or something like that
we're talking about replacing Java
visualization and dotnet this
realization with JSON libraries which
means that you need to serialize Java
objects and dotnet objects and in order
to do so you need to deal with
object-oriented programming features
like how I'm going to serialize a java
applet or how I'm going to serialize a
system object Internet I'm going to deal
with generics I'm going to deal with
interface figures polymorphism and so on
so a very quick recap on how attackers
were able to get a rhetorical execution
with javadi's realization attacks
basically they were sending like a
stream of untrusted data to the
visualizer to the vulnerable endpoint
and this data contained some type
discriminators that is nothing else that
the class name for this for some types
of arbitrary types that the attacker
could control then the desi eliezer were
basically instance here in these types
and then invoking some visualization
callbacks on these types right so
basically attacker need need to find a
type or a class containing a read object
or read resolve method which could be
chained together with other types or
classes in order to assembly a cut the
chains leading to arbitrary code
execution
however JSON libraries don't normally
invoke any DC allocation callbacks so we
need to start this cut yet sense in a
different way so let's see how the
adjacent libraries to reconstruct the
objects when DC a licen and see if we
cannot take benefit of some of these
methods in order to start our gadget
chain so normally this libraries it
depends on the library
every library is different from the
others but normally they will invoke the
default constructor which is not very
useful for the attackers because it
takes no parameters and then they will
use either reflection or Colin setters
in order to set the values of the fields
or the properties of the class some of
the libraries will invoke some
visualization callbacks or a special
constructors some of them will call type
converters that is I don't need a
specific type which we don't have time
to cover in this talk but it's included
in our white paper that will be
published today I think so let's just
make sure that you check it out and then
most of the libraries will also invoke
some common methods like for example
when dealing with hash tables hash code
or equals maker invoke to a string may
get invoke when raising an exception if
you can force the library to raise an
exception finalizes always invoke by the
garbage collector where click when
claiming the memory so we can actually
start our gadget change using some of
these libraries by far the most common
one used by all these data libraries is
the setters most of the libraries if not
all of them will invoke setters so what
we did is research and look for God yet
starting with setters living through
arbitrary code execution both in Java
and.net let's have a look on a few
godred in dotnet all of them can lead to
arbitrary code execution
some of them has the own requirements
and/or limitation but we believe so that
it's not very difficult to pick up
proper one for specific library so our
first gadget is a set of path property
in assembly installer class it allows
code execution during library loading
from path controlled by an attacker
there is no additional requirements in
case if
assembly this payload is on local
machine but if we try to provide remote
resources dotnet framework may have some
additional security checks the next two
gadgets are uses
user sam'l parser we will show a bit
later how it can be used for arbitrary
method invocation so
property inspector font and color data
in workflow designer type a requires
single-threaded
apartment set it's quite strong
requirement but if your target has such
configuration you will get remote code
execution the next gadget is source a
setter in resource dictionary it has a
few requirements to Jason and Marshall s
they should call setters in four types
that implement a dictionary interface
often in such case our Marshalls are
just populating key value pairs also
they should be able to reconstruct
system override type and this type does
not have default constructor but very
often parser can do this
and finally our guarded in object data
provider type it's quite flexible and I
love allow allows us to use a lot of
vector attacks so as a result we were
able to use this gadget in almost all
our and Marshalls and formatters let's
have a look on it closer so it's called
diagram that will cover a fresh method a
refreshment that will invoke begin choir
begin query will call query worker and
finally in invoke method earnest
instance we can see line that you is
that you'll call our arbitrary matter
here we can see example of JSON payload
that will pop-up calculator in json dot
net parser
this gadget offer us the next way to for
attack we can call non default
constructor with own parameters we can a
[Music]
in invoke method on unmarshal at object
or we can call any public method
including instance including instant and
static ones these are our own parameters
Java has the own setter gadget as well
after our our last year research on JDI
injection attacks we have found a few
setters that called gene yellow cup
method by the way oracle recently
disabled ami and corba vectors in
default configuration of java but LDAP
vector still works so set session factor
jin-gi name in statistic service class
we already mentioned about this in our
talk at blackhat 2016 very similar to it
is to string gadget from remote client
use the transaction Clause and finally
set auto commit from already known gdb 0
set in pal class let's have a closer
look on it it is from GRE libraries so
we don't require we don't need any
additional and dependencies as we can
see on this slide cetera will call
connect function and here we will call
initial contacts contacts to lock up
method with our value from data source
name properties so we will get we will
get a remote code execution
apart from mention at the gadget that
allow code execution by themselves we
have a few other interesting gadget some
of them can be used as building blocks
for a gadget chains like string template
to think in Java or buildings source
said that a member in dotnet can be used
for arbitrary gutter call other can
trigger non remote code execution attack
like inner XML in XML data document type
or data view setting collections in in
that view manager type can be used for
external XML entities attack in some
version of the.net framework and now we
will switch back to our bar he will show
where we can use all these gadgets so we
analyze a set of different JSON
libraries but for Java and.net and we
were able to create arbitrary code
execution in most of them as long as
they meet these three simple
requirements so the first one is that
the attacker needs to be able to control
the type the class name that is going to
be reconstructed at the service agent
type so normally that means that the
JSON will contain something some
attribute like this underscore type
dollar type class class name or
something like that that contains a
value that looks like Java class name
with a namespace or something like a
dotnet assembly or something like that
and then the libraries will to
instantiate that type the second
requirement is that the library need to
invoke any method normally it will
invoke setters but we saw before that it
can invoke some other methods and the
third requirement is that the attacker
needs to be able to find large enough
gadget space for the him to craft or
assembly a cadet a chain leading to
arbitrary code execution so we
categorize all the libraries what we
analyzed according to this
categorization that is basically based
on two different factors the first one
is whether these libraries include the
format or they sorry the type
discriminator by default or not for
example in this case you can see here
that this is jason dotnet library and
contain this dollar type with something
that looks like a donut namespace and
then the second factor is how they
control which classes or which types are
going to be instantiated
during this realization some libraries
performed just a post this allocation
caste operation which is basically or
basically offers no protection at all
because by the time that you get the
cast exception they say recession has
completed and the pay load has been
executed so you are already in trouble
and the other type control that most of
the libraries do is perform what we call
the inspection of the expected type
object graph which looks like a little
bit complex but is actually very simple
the library will shape what is the
specter type so for example the library
may be expecting a user type and then it
will recursively analyze the object
graph and when they serialize in from
the JSON data it will check if the
expected type is a signal from what the
attacker or what the user is sending so
for example if the user or the library
expects a string if we provide something
like an object data provider that is our
gadget then the library will throw an
exception and will fail to digitize the
data some of the libraries in addition
to this a sigma bility check will also
build a whitelist during construction
time so at runtime when they see a licen
they will apply this whitelist and only
those types that appear in the object
graph at construction type will be
allowed to be the seer lies we found
that these libraries are still
vulnerable if the attacker can control
the expected type which is more common
that you may think and we will see an
example later or if the attacker can
find an entry point in this object graph
so for example in this simple object
graph all the elements in red are entry
points that the attacker can actually
use to place their load at their payload
so that may be for example a system dot
object type or a non-generic collection
like a hash table or array list so in
our paper we have like a more detailed
explanation of how to find these entry
points in the epigraph so this is the
list of the libraries that we analyzed
as you can see we have some of them that
are donate and some of them are Java we
included the most popular ones like the
JSON donate for donate and the deduction
probably the most common or most popular
one for Java the ones in red
are those that are vulnerable by default
out of the box no matter what you do you
cannot protect them and make them safe
for example fast Jason sweet Jason Jason
IO or Fleck station because they include
the type discriminators or type names in
the satellite data and because they
perform no type control at all except
for this post DC allocation cast
operation they will always be vulnerable
because they invoke a setters and then
we will be we will be able to use our
setter gadgets to get a bit recall
execution the one in yellow depends on
how the developers configure the library
in order to for the attacker to be able
to get arbitrary code execution or not
so by default normally they don't
include the type information in the data
and they perform an inspection of the
expected object graph and you may think
that these two requirements are hard to
meet at the same time or to find in a
real application but it's actually the
opposite because if developers are
sterilized in something that contains or
our object profit of containing for
example a system data object or a java
language yet they will need to enable
these configuration settings to include
the type information because otherwise
they won't be able to serialize that
data the one in green JSON is actually
the one that we consider secure because
there is one way of making it insecure
but I mean you need to be Jimmy you need
to be able to or you want to make it
vulnerable in purpose because it's very
difficult and in addition as you can see
here it invokes no setters at all it
uses reflection so you cannot use our
Center gadgets you need to find new
gadgets for example in finalize methods
or other methods that may carry invoke
in this and so we consider it as kind of
secure library so let's see some of
these libraries for example first Jason
was one in the in the red category they
always included type discriminators they
perform in no type control at all so if
you find an application using
frustration with untrusted data you will
be able to get arbitrary code execution
and that's what we found for example in
this calico a content management system
that was visualizing untrusted data
leading to arbitrary code execution then
we have JavaScript serialize ER that is
one of the dotnet native serializers by
default is secure because it
not include the type information so it's
good but when calling the constructor as
you can see here developers come pass a
type resolver if they do that these type
information will be included in the
sterilized JSON data and would be
processed when this arise in the data so
that will make the library vulnerable
because this library performs no type
control at all just this post DC
allocation cast operation so again these
libraries can be used securely with
untrusted data as long as you don't use
any type resolver then we have data
contract Jason serializable and a
different dotnet native rotation
sterilizer by well this is probably one
of the most secure Jason de salida that
we've seen it performs that type aspect
the type of the graph inspection but it
also builds this whitelist
at construction time that is applied at
runtime so finding an entry point is not
an option for this library and the other
way that you can attack it and get
arbitrary code execution is if you can
control the expected type you may think
that something like this that the spec
that time comes from a cookie and then
is used to initialize the satellizer is
nothing in common but we will show you a
demo on a very common or rapidly popular
content management system in don't net
that does exactly does then we have
Jason donate that is probably the most
popular dish on the net Jason satellizer
for the net by default is secure because
it does not include type information but
again developers can enable this type
name handling setting which will make
the library include the type is a
discriminator sort type information in
the json serialize data so this is
another example by the way all these
examples are from github so this is real
code in this case the title is going to
be set alight at his message contains
this body property with his system
object so because of that as I said
before developers will be forced to
enable this type name handling setting
that will force the library to include
the type information because otherwise
add this allocation type it won't know
to which type visualize that data
so this library will invoke set-aside
realisable constructor callbacks even
some custom call box type converters so
you can use a very broad set of Cadets
to get arbitrary code execution
portation today okay so let's see one
example of an application or in this
case a framework that is using JSON
dotnet in an insecure way so we can we
were able to get a baterry call
execution so this is bris this is a beta
management framework which basically
exposes a REST API for both JavaScript
and dotnet clients to connect and
perform like entity management operation
like adding new records deleting records
updating records and so on it's kind of
popular in the.net work and if we look
at the source code we will see that they
use JSON dotnet as the global stabilizer
this JSON dotnet is configured to use
this type name handling object which
means that when satirising system object
properties they will include the type
information now if we check the source
code we will see that at some point the
JSON donut satellizer is used to
deserialize untrusted data and the
expected type in this case is safe
option if we perform this inspection of
the expected type of the graph that
looks like very complex but it's nothing
I'll start looking at the expected type
object graph in this case very simple
and we can see that it contains attack
property that is system object so we
will be able to place our payload in
this property and get arbitrary code
execution so let's see that in action
this is one of the sample application
that comes with with breeze it's a
sample application that lets you update
or create new car models just something
simple to teach developers so if we send
like this change for the car model name
we will see that in our request we have
the change of the model name like
Mustang 2 and then an empty dictionary
with that is called safe options if we
send
this request in the response we will see
this dollar type attribute with
something that looks like a Jason donate
cell ice type so this is a good
indicator that this application is
vulnerable so now we're going to use our
object data provider setter gadget in
order to call the process dot a start
method and pop up a calculator so we
will copy and replace this empty safe
options dictionary with our payload and
if we send it well let's check that the
victim server is not running the
calculator of course if we send it we
will get our calculator thank you so we
wanted to give a shot shout out to
Morris Bachelor that is a recognized
data security researcher he published
similar research on May 22 aware after
our research was finished and published
and accepted for black hat and DEF CON
but he serves the same kind of premises
and conclusions he focuses exclusively
on java and he overlaps with our
research in both the jackson and this
one i or libraries although for today
Shanaya he founds a completely different
vector and here he also overlaps with us
in this JDBC rosette imple Gardea that
was kind of no views choice because it
was previously used in the Java
devastation world but he also found a
very interesting gadget in spring
libraries another library so if you are
more interested in the java version of
this talk less go and check his his
research and now Alice will switch gears
and move into the dotnet section let's
back to the dead dotnet world
potential security problems in binary
format and data contracts aerolizer
where knows were known for the years
for example great work of James for flow
about weaknesses and main attack vectors
in
net formatters was presented and black
hat 2012 so five years ago anyway we
could not find a good remote code
execution gadget chain there was one
published by by florian gold here but it
uses memory corruption so it's quite
difficult to build universal exploit for
different version of windows but we were
sure that there should be a lot of way
to get code execution during dotnet this
realization so we spent some our time
for searching cells guarded and have
found one that can be used in binary
format or some another other dotnet
formatters but after our talk our work
was ready and talk was accepted by black
hat is the same james forceful published
a couple remote code execution execution
gadget for binary for matter as he is
owned as part of his own research by the
vein not connected with with jason or
our talks anyway you could find details
about this guarded in on his post-op on
google project zero block here we will
focus on our own we will use PS object
type this type is from powershell
libraries so are available is available
on almost all windows machine and before
we go further there are a couple remarks
about this gadget in first version of
powershell this type is not serializable
so it's not suitable for attack but all
modern web version of windows starting
from a Windows 8 and Windows 2000 server
2012 are shipped with newer and
vulnerable version also if you updated
your PowerShell in on older
Windows version and this problem is
relevant for you as well
next remark we we reported this problem
to Microsoft and two weeks ago they
released a fix so if you are not
ignoring their updates you are safe
so Pierce object it uses custom
digitizer and in case of tea I am
instance it will call GIM instance
rehydrate see I am instance property
here we can see that attacker is able to
specify own type as element type of
array and the sterilizer will try to
deconstruct object of this type for
finding proper way to do this it will
use a figure conversion method it's
quite interesting for attacker us there
a lot of option to attack and we
highlighted only the most obvious one we
can call a concern on default
constructor with one argument and we can
control this argument we can invoke
setters on public properties so we can
use mention it earlier gadgets or we can
call static public parts method of
arbitrary type let's try to use this one
as we said earlier some reader parts can
be used for arbitrary method invocation
here we can see a payload that we'll
call process start with our argument we
can notice nine space assembly type
method name and finally calc as our
argument
apart from already mentioned binary
format and net data contract serializer
dotnet offers a lot of other formatters
unfortunately we don't have enough time
to cover to provide the talat view of
each of them so we will briefly cover
them in today today talk and if you are
interested in deeper analysis we can
offer our white paper as good source so
we can group them in two big groups for
matters that are vulnerable in default
configuration like binary format absorb
format net data contract serializer also
we can adhere for matters that
internally use them like object state
formatter loss formatter binary message
format they should not be used for the
serialization of an untrusted data or
you have to proper configure them to
limit available types for example use
restricted type resolver with
whitelisted types the second group is
for matters that are safe in the full
configuration like XML sterilizer data
contract sterilizer and data contract
JSON sterilizer but if you are using
weak data contractor resolver by the way
we have found such examples even in
official Microsoft documentation or
attacker is able to control expected
type you have a very serious security
problem and we will show a bit later how
that in this case code execution in
Israel even for the most
Limited for matters like for example XML
serializing now we will switch back to
Alvaro
and he will show our next demo so
because demo is probably worth of
thousands lights let's see how can we
use our PS object Katya - Casper mode
remote code execution on any application
build using this Nancy framework so for
those of you that are not familiar with
Nancy's our web application framework
for the.net world that is very similarly
inspired by the Ruby Sinatra framework
they offer some security features like
for example C soft protection which is
good but in order to protect against sis
our protection SSR they open the doors
to remote code execution which is not
that good in this case what they were
doing were basically setting this unique
body that we used to protect against
itself instead of putting that value
directly into the cookie they were
putting that as the property of a class
and then said arise in that class into
the cookie and then do not send in the
cookie over the the wire so what we were
able to get pre authenticated remote
code execution on any application built
using Nancy and let's see well this is
actually the payload that is basics
different coded if you find this
eh-eh-eh D magic number in any of your
pen test then you do get remote code
execution so this is a sample
application that we built using Nancy
very simple if we take the cookies for
this application that this application
is set in in our browser we will see
this NC star cookie which contain these
magic numbers so we were like oh this is
code execution nice now if we check the
source code we can see that this same
value is also included as a hidden field
for this form so this is making this
kind of data submission of the CSR
cookie now we will be used in our PS
object code yet now because it's a fixed
by Microsoft you can use any of the gems
for circuits instead so they will work
as well as
and if we replace the cookie with our PS
object Katya that is configured to pop
up a calculator and we just submit the
form we can see that there is no
calculator again and if we send and
submit the request we will get a 505
exception but no problem because we got
our calculators running thank you
so we wanted to highlight that this is
not a problem in Jason this is not a
problem in XML or for example in Java
visualization or binary formatted for
the net this is actually something that
is a problem in sterilizers themselves
so most or if not all of the serial isit
will need to reconstruct those objects
during this allocation and if you find
that these serial icers are worth
satisfying these three requirement that
we mentioned before so including
including type information in the
sterilized data i invoking methods on
those reconstructed objects and then
with some large enough cutted space for
the attackers to assembly gadget
changing into arbitrary code execution
then you will be able to attack any
format in any language that you will
find also because most of the library
libraries will invoke setters the katia
table we presented here today object
data provided and the JDBC row setting
imple can be used to attack most of the
CLI sirs out there that satisfy these
dis requirements so we found many we
review many formats and we found many of
them vulnerables we want to highlight
these three because well we don't have
time for more
for example FSP clear and subsidizes our
dotnet c realises that work not just
with a donut framework but also with
dotnet core silverlight windows mobile
phone so developers may choose these
serializers over the native ones when
working for example in silverlight or
whatever so both of them include type
information by default both of them
invoke setters and will FSP clear
performs an inspection of the object
graph inspection of object spectrograph
expect the type of the graph but so you
will need to find these entry points but
subsidy eliezer performs no type control
at all which means that it cannot be
used with untrusted data at all then we
have wire that is now known as Hyperion
and is the steriliser for a cadet akka
doughnuts basically the total net
version of the famous s Colin and Java
framework to deal with concurrency using
a dis actor based models which basically
these factors communicate exchanging
messages that are satellites with taste
on the net using the insecure
configuration that we saw you before
this type name handling equals all
however you can enable this new customs
they realize that they implemented that
is called Hyperion that also includes
type discriminators also invoke setters
and also performs no type control at all
so if you can send any message to an
Academy net or akka actors you will be
able to get remote code execution as
well
also beware of rolling your own format
this is like crypto right
for example Nancy the framework that we
saw before they decided to move away
from binary format because binary format
was not going to be included in the
first version of.net core so they
implemented their own JSON parser so
what can go wrong
well they included this type object
discriminator so attacker can control
the type and they invoke setters so we
were also able to get arbitrary code
execution in these pre-released to the
text version well it was released as a
beta but it was not like the official
version and then we also found one of
the most popular CMS for the.net world
that is called the DotNetNuke beginning
or if not the most popular library which
uses XML serialization
to serialize untrusted data and in this
case for example the value in a request
cooking what they wanted to use XML
serialization with arbitrary types so in
order to do that they created this
wrapper around XML sterilizer so they
send the type that is going to be like
the Spector type and then the payload
for the XML serialization
XML I'd say there I said is the most
limited by far
serial I said in the donut family so it
was like a challenge for us if we were
able to get a better recall execution in
this case we were sure like like we can
do that for any other libraries so we
wanted to use our object beta providers
data and gadget and well best so far so
good because it's XML satellizer
friendly I
see realized by XML is realizing no
problem at all however if we want to
invoke processes of the start then we
will get our first problem because
process contains interface member and
for example XML serialization is very
limited as I said it cannot settle eyes
types with interface members it cannot
serialize types we have system dot type
properties for example and many other
limitations so we couldn't use the
process daughter start as the final cut
yet
however this was easily solved because
we can use our summer reader load cut
yet or the object state formatter this I
realized in order to get remote code
execution or even better you can
actually search the target application
class path for interesting gadgets and
the guy is at DotNetNuke were kind
enough to provide us with this file
system use class that contains methods
that are very convenient to deploy web
web cells or to read flyers and put the
response the data into the HTTP response
so that problem was solved no problems
so far now when XML said I said builds
one of these white list that we talked
about before so a construction type it
will see that the object data provided
contains a system dot object property so
it will include system dot object as the
in the white list but a runtime we will
be providing something else we will be
providing the sun'll reader or maybe the
file system units or maybe these object
state format have something else right
so these types won't be in the white
list and so the XML serializable prevent
the visualisation of these types so we
needed to fool xml cell i satellizer
into including these types into the
white list and the way they we did it
was basically using this expected type
which is basically basically a
parameterized type and in the
parameterized type we're using we're
placing our runtime types so these are
going to be included in the white list
and when we send our payload it will
work like a term so let's see that in
action as we said we were able to get a
bit rowdy code execution pre
authentication on any instance of the
dotnetnuke see
and well this is the source code leading
to the vulnerability the source is in in
this piece of code that gets executed
for example in many cases but one of the
cases is when visiting the 404 page the
error page so at that time this DNN
personalization cookie is going to be
read and then pass to this DISA realized
hash table XML method then here will
basically extract the type from the XML
cookie and then use that type to build
our XML sterilizer so the attacker can
control the expected type remember I
told you that this is more common that
amazing here's an example and then it's
this year they serialize in the rest of
the cookie so this is how a regular
cookie looks like it contains the
expected type and then this blue box
here is the payload for the XML
sterilizer and this is how our our
payload looks like a little bit
different so here the expected type is
this parameter S type and here here we
are telling XML Iser to include these
types into the whitelist then we will
use this file system users class to
download our webster deploy it in the I
is root directory and we will be able to
deploy our Watson so let's see a video
of that so this is the out-of-the-box
installation of DNN if we visit a
non-existent page we will get our 404
error page that will force the
processing of the DNN personalization
cookie so we will send this page this
request to burp we will capture it and
because it's by default is not including
this cookie even if it's processing the
cookies not including it we will include
it we will write here our dnm
personalization cookie and then we will
paste the XML payload that I just showed
you
basically it's invoking the pool file
method of the file system Uriel's class
to download our website and deploy it in
the big team server so let's format this
a little bit now if we go to the victim
server we will check that the cell aspx
file that we are going to download is
not existing here if we send the if we
send the request it will be downloaded
and we will get the cell available for
the attacker to interact with the with a
system so at this point the attacker can
just use the web cell as I said to
interact with the system install metal /
tear or whatever they want to use thank
you and just to wrap up as I said before
this is not a problem in JSON or XML or
Java DC allocation this is a problem in
sterilizers themselves so try to avoid
visualizing entrusted data with any
formatter even if you think it's secure
but if you have to try to get that
library evaluated from a security point
of view by your security expert of
choice and try avoiding libraries that
performs no type control like the ones
that we saw that I've just do in a post
a civilization caste also try to avoid
those libraries that they are including
type information in the sterilized data
because that's not sufficient to get
arbitrary code execution but is a good
indicator that they it may lead to
arbitrary code execution also don't let
the users control the expected type of
any initializer because they will be
able to control the object graph
inspection and they will be able to
place anything there and that's what not
least try to not roll your own format if
you don't know what you're doing so with
that thank you very much
what's a pleasure and if you have any
questions I think we have like 5 times 5
minutes 5 minutes questions please go to
the to the mics I think in the aisles no
questions
also we will be publishing the white
paper it will be published today in the
black hat side so does make sure that
you check it out it contains a lot of
information on details okay so thank you
very much
[Applause]