hi everyone welcome I am Thomas Cohen
and I mean I'm walking at wix.com
currently leading the iron D security
team me and my team are responsible for
all physical security aspects of all
productions operations including the
application the infrastructure instant
response and everything um
and I'm here to talk about hi about how
to create a botnet by abusing Chrome
extensions um and I won't start with my
personal and my personal experience so
the first big challenge me and my team
had to add with the bots was on April 2
2016 it was a regular there in the
office and suddenly a dramatic increase
in the new user signup event rate
happened so that this basically means
that a lot of users are sign up a lot
more than in planned unusual and and we
started checking things and we saw that
all these requests are not originated in
the same ip or even country so we
started to understand that we are coping
with what we generally call a bot attack
now before we dive into their instant
interesting part of this attack few
words about BOTS
so um according to a Imperva the
majority of the traffic in the Internet
today is done by BOTS most boats are bad
BOTS and most of the bad boards
impersonators impersonators out bots
that that fake user human behavior in
websites and they cause big headaches to
internet companies because they they
blend into the websites a regular
traffic and make it very hard and do
malicious stuff and make it very very
hard for for for the for the website to
distinguish distinguish between the
legit request and the bottle quest
so back in our vector attack
we started investigated deeper what what
is the original origin of this request
and we found few patterns so and this is
what we knew during the investigation of
this attack the first thing that we
noticed is that most of the increase in
the sign up event is is originated in
Latin America countries and it was this
was where very will because it was in
high numbers and as well as most of the
even almost all of the clients were
coming with chrome with Google Chrome
second things we've noticed that for
some reason I mean we did not know the
reason at the time the signup form used
to say to send the signup request to to
to our servers was inside it was in a
frame inside a facebook tab there was a
facebook tab and we saw that the
requests are coming from a frame that
within is within the Facebook tab we
didn't understand like I said what it
means or it meant but we'll see in a
second why it was like this third thing
that we saw so little into about weeks
weeks is a website creation platform
anyone the Internet can come a sign and
sign up and create his own website for
free and so what we've noticed is that a
lot of users that sign up to a new
account and win weeks and only a 10
seconds after the signup event we see
that the user publishes a new week's
website now this is real because and ten
seconds is obviously not enough to edit
your website and then publish it so we
this is the this is the point when when
we got a good pattern and we started to
to distinguish distinguish between the
legit requests of users and this bot
requests and so we went
I went and and looked what were these
websites abou about and this is what we
found all the websites that were create
in this way in that tent the second
pattern led to an attack page when this
is in English and what we see in here is
there is a common scam attack page it
says that if you want to see who looked
at your profile at Facebook you can
install a Chrome extension and and see
who who view your profile as a bonus by
the way you can also always see what is
the meaning of your name if you want but
let's let's go anyway let's click on
start and see what we get
so we click on start and we do get to
the real Google Chrome Web Store okay
this is the original Google Chrome Web
Store
it has an extension called Viad 30
something we didn't recognize this
extension and but we needs to edit stone
that this attack has to do with this
extension so we started investigating
the extension and following the code the
code was highly appreciated and we we
had help from some guy from a lot of
guys including parameter X which is a
company and that fights bots that we use
and this is what we found
once the extension is installed the
first thing it does is inject code into
Facebook tab and now Chrome extensions
are with the with proper permissions
like this one has have the ability to
inject JavaScript code into tabs so the
first thing that this extension does is
inject code into Facebook why Facebook
I guess because everyone is on Facebook
all the time and other reasons we'll see
in a minute next thing it does the code
that is injected into the Facebook tab
opens a week's iframe this is what we
saw before
and this iframe is transparent the
victim user does not see anything is
that you cannot notice anything but the
frame is is reading two weeks signup
form
then from within the frame and attacks
request is is fired to our two weeks
sign up a serval now one quick question
why would the attacker even need to open
a weeks iframe I mean he has the ability
of an extension he can inject just
inject code into Facebook and then send
request the signup request two weeks
from Facebook tab to week server this is
the extension is able to do that to do
it because it does not have the
limitation of course origin request of
same origin sorry now the answer here is
that because of this we have basic or
even more than basic bot detection
system and if you if the attacker just
send a design up request just from any
tab on the Internet
it fails because this request does not
have the right the proper cookies and
headers and access tokens and and things
that we do in the signup form before the
user comes to the signup a endpoint so
this is this fails however and if okay
so once somewhat small thing the
attacker wants to send the request to
sign up to the - - - the sign observable
from the page that runs the signup form
but extension but he but you don't want
to open a new tab to the victim because
the this will be visible to the user and
there are no invisible tabs in chrome so
if you want to open new tab the user has
to see it so instead of that the
attacker just injected code into
Facebook that creates an iframe of which
signup form in the Facebook page and
when the request is sent for
with in this with this I framed the
succeeds
now I remind you that this iframe was it
was entirely transparent so the user did
not notice anything but his browser his
Facebook tab
sent a sign-up request two weeks and it
worked okay let's go back to the
extension course of action go on with
that so we saw that that it was inject
code into Facebook then open a week's
iframe then send the signup request from
within the frame and the next thing he
does is after signing up a new a new
week's user it publishes a new website
now all the websites lead to one page
that we saw before
this website has a newly created URL and
the extension then takes this URL and
distribute the link the you this URL the
attack page URL of the week's web site
among all Facebook friends of the victim
using Facebook messaging the last thing
that this extension does after this
distribution phase is submitting is
using the users the victims Google
Google authorization token it submits a
review of five stars in Google Web Store
of the malicious extension okay cool so
this is what extended did extension did
but my question here is why would the
attacker even need weeks in this in this
campaign I mean can't he just inject
code to Facebook and then distribute his
link to that did his attack page to to
the friends of the victims why would he
need weeks on the way so the answer here
is the tweaks was used to distribute a
malware and the whole part of the whole
role of weeks in his campaign was just
was to supply disposable URLs okay the
attacker did not want to send all the
victims the same URL that off his server
his attack serval because it's easier
this this way it's easier for Facebook
to detect adblock this attack every
victim opened a new accountant in weeks
and created a new website and sent the
new URL to his friends and then the
attack was fully distributed okay so
what will be described so far is
obviously only the infection phase of
this attack obviously after after the
infection these bots are used to gang
one thing and you guessed right
it's money and so both masters do with
this with with their botnets a lot of
things you're familiar with I guess and
they send spam for me they're on DDoS
attacks scrape website run click frauds
and they make money after we have to fit
as many as the more boss that they have
they make more money of course they can
also put this bot for rent and get money
for doing these operations for other
people or on top of that you can always
still steal personal information or
sense the information from the victims
and lateral move through their networks
so this is what they do after after the
the infection phase after the campaign
of the infection and I'm here to talk
about the infection phase and and I want
to show you another example that
happened just two months later at June
to think 2016 so in April we struggled
with this this which this attack attack
actors for a while and in the end we
blocked them but two months later and a
new attack came to our knowledge it was
in the news and it says it said that a
Facebook comment tagging malware is
spreading via Google Chrome and the
warning is if you receive a facebook
notification regarding a friend tagging
you in a comment be very careful because
it can be a malware now this attack what
named tag me if you can buy you don't
know is researcher in Kaspersky Labs and
he published a very detailed report
about this attack and the thing is that
when I saw there it was a report on this
attack and you this was the same
attackers that attacked us two months
before how did I know it you'll see in a
second let's see how this attacked
walked so the first thing that the
victim see is a notification on Facebook
that a friend of his has tagged him in a
comment upon clicking this comment after
short facebook warning that you are
getting out of Facebook jay-z file is
immediately downloaded to the victims
browser now a jay-z file is a is access
and executable on all Windows machines
and and if I'm going to the next step
and I'm clicking this Jessie file and if
you will in the malware is run runs on
my machine so what it does this malware
it's firstly it cause it causes Chrome
to crash then it creates a copy of
Chrome
Exe file just with a little addition a
malicious extension installed on the new
chrome process then when the egg when
chrome is reopened the extension runs
and does two simple things the first it
uploads a new jay-z file to the victims
Google Drive using the Google or Google
authorization token the next thing it
does it takes the URL one little more
thing
it makes this file public to everyone so
other victims could get this URL of the
jay-z file and access it so after that
it takes the URL of the jay-z file
upload it to a Google Drive and
distribute it and using Facebook
commenting plugin
and as we saw before what it does it
creates a comment with a tag of all
these friends that lead to the newly
created JC file in the victims Google
Drive is that clear so one of the
victims friends on Facebook opens a
clicks on this notification and the
whole thing runs over and over again and
we got an exponential growth infection
process you must be asking yourselves
how did these attackers and create a
notification that lead to a download of
a JC file so this is very interesting
but it's too long for this talk you can
find more more details in the white
paper of this dis presentation or in
Donna's report in more details about
this attack tag me if you can
very interesting so we saw two attacks I
promise to tell you how I knew that it
were the same attackers so the
extensions that were used in both the
text were very similar and they use
mutual code snippets called code parts
and also used in some in some cases the
same domains belonging to that these
attackers this is how we knew for sure
that it's the same attackers and now in
these two attacks that we saw there's a
pattern okay this is this is how it goes
this is also how are you recognize that
it was the same attackers it all starts
with a user clicking in the first attack
it was user clicking on a Facebook and
message on a second attack it was a
notification then somehow an extension a
malicious chrome extension is installed
on his browser and in the first attack
it was a the user had to install it from
the web store in a second attack and
executable the JC file created the sixth
install this extension next thing the
extension runs and
create a new malicious payload instance
in the weeks attack it was a new Wix
website that that that offers you to
install the extension in a second attack
it was a JC file upload to it uploaded
to the users Google Drive then it always
takes the URL of the newly of the newly
created payload instance and send it
somehow among to all Facebook friends of
the victim can be with messages or
notifications one as we saw before one
of the fu victims friends click and then
the whole thing runs over and over again
now the company's abused in these two
campaigns and we reviewed are not mine
of companies right we are talking about
Facebook Google and vidcom and the three
of them the this magical bot somehow
comes and defeats their body detection
systems of all these companies all day
all the company all the em the services
that we were discussing discussing
upload a file to Google Drive send fed
with Facebook messages it all have
bought protection mechanisms on them so
how why why do common bot common BOTS
fail to bypass this protection and these
BOTS succeeds so let's have a second to
analyze what makes a good bot so the
goal of good bot is to look as human as
he can right it has to the good but will
want website to think that he is a human
that is sitting on his computer and
surfing at the Internet using his
browser right so um and how do popular
bot protection techniques walk okay the
first thing that what protection
mechanism a challenge BOTS to what BOTS
with is JavaScript most boss today run
JavaScript but you can always create a
tailor-made JavaScript calculation to a
client
ending on his version of the version
that he claims he is for example if I if
I'm claiming that I'm running a chrome
in some version there are specific
JavaScript challenges that can be that
can be given to the twist client and and
if it's a if if it's if it's not a real
home chrome browser it the odds are that
he will not succeed now this problem is
solved he solved in our case right
because Dex our extension is running as
sorry our bot is running as a Chrome
extension which runs inside chrome so
you can give us you can give this bot
whatever JavaScript challenges that you
want
he will we will cope with it
successfully the second thing is what I
like to call human context so this
includes a lot of stuff for exam for
example a mouse movement and keystrokes
and all the human behavior that that
involves when you surf the Internet
in addition it also um the user context
here is very important as we saw in
weeks if you just there's a flow of of
events that should happen when a user
for instance signing up to two to two
apps to a way to story to a website
first it has to go through the signup
form and only then he can send a signup
request um so this bot need to somehow
get into context of a real user now the
best way to get into a context of a user
is to inject JavaScript code into the
users active tabs right if i if I'm able
to put my code into the users real
active tabs that you walk with for
example Facebook I can get his context
and with the site um and this is
actually what browser extensions are all
about
getting the context of the user
injecting JavaScript into active tabs
now if you ask yourselves how didn't how
did Facebook and Google and not block
this attack or block extensions from
doing this these operations the answer
is that it's not a bug it's a feature if
you think about it extensions should be
able to do all these kind of stuff to
send send Facebook messages and upload a
a and upload a file to Google Drive and
and actually anything else that people
wants to have a on the Internet in with
Chrome with extensions so this and this
makes BOTS that ran on on browser
extensions very power very powerful tool
let's have a second to see the to
understand the full capabilities of an
extension let's have a second to see
there to review the manifest file of the
extension that we saw before attacking
weeks so in the red and the word frame
you can see the name of the extension
viadon Locker and they that these
attackers used a name of an already
existing extension that was already in
the in the store I guess they as they
figured out that it's easier that way to
pass Google's screening process in the
webstore so what we see here and this is
the most important part of the manifest
it has a permission to to fire
cross-origin requests to any destination
he wants on the internet and this also
allows this extension to inject
JavaScript code into any tab of the URL
that the user is using what else we have
access to all user cookies in all tabs
that by the way includes also HTTP only
cookies next thing we see is that the
extension had has
a back on script back on script runs in
the background once the extension is
installed and let's have a look at this
get that script what we see here so this
background script is actually the
command and control system of the
attacker
I'll explain let's see what it does so
first every time it adds it adds a
listener that is triggered every time a
tab tab is is updated any energy on any
change on a tab and then it goes to a
server belonging to that Tucker this is
what what you see here and gets a file
called data dot GS which is the commands
file to this bot from the attacker
server then it takes this data j as a
script from the attacker service and
eggs and using the chrome API tabs a
copy I tabs dot execute script it runs
it on the active tab so this actually
make this bot not static I mean the
attacker is able to adjust his attack
all the time he can always change the a
commands file that is that is served to
his boss he can also create a commands
file specifically for every domain that
is updated for example I want to send a
send messages on facebook and I want to
upload if I'm on Google I want to upload
the file or whatever and this makes this
is a very powerful thing because it
allows the attacker to change his attack
according to to what happens for example
I told you before that we had we saw
that users that only ten seconds after
the sign up they publish the site so we
set out to ourselves okay that's easy
let's just unpublish a web sites that
are published only less than 20 seconds
after the sign up event and we started
I'll publish this we
this website and the attacked stopped
for about half an hour and then the
attacker just changed the commands file
to run to like have a randomized timeout
between the sign up link event and and
and the published website event all
these makes browser extension the
perfect but it can struggle it can cope
with any JavaScript challenge it can run
it can inject code in the context of the
user the thing is that it's just too
much work right I mean this campaigns a
required much effort from these
attackers to run and if they had to if
you want to distribute your own
malicious extension you have to somehow
pass the screening process of Google Web
Store and and smuggle your malicious
extension into the store after that you
have to somehow persuade and convince
victim users to install this extension
or in the other hand which is
complicated as well somehow one
executable on on these victims also once
if your malicious extension is in the
Google Web Store once you have your
extension is revealed as malicious
Google remotely and installs your
extension from all connected devices so
you lose all the bots that you collected
so how can we make it easier the thing
is that to get the abilities of an
extension we don't necessarily have to
create and distribute our own malicious
extension if we just had an ability to
run JavaScript in the context of Chrome
extensions that will be enough right
okay running
javascript in the context of web
application I know XSS so instead of
explaining the difference between
exercising webpages and extensions let's
just have a look at some recent examples
and the first example I want show here
is the Adobe Acrobat extension exercise
now this extension aims to allow users
to turn to convert any web page into a
PDF file and on January 16 while it had
30 million installations by the way the
Adobe installed it automatically without
users awareness on on all devices that
had Ted Adobe Acrobat Reader on it
that's why it got so many users 30
million users just fought for
proportions and the mere ibotta tech
that was the largest attack the bullet
about a tech that was not was noticed is
estimated to be tens of millions of
devices so it's the the same numbers
more or less and so on general 16 well
it had 30 million installations and a
researcher from Google project zero
Tabby's Oh Mandi and reported this
extension is vulnerable to dom-based xss
now this is a services report I can I
know that you don't see a lot of a lot
of it but it included a POC code we can
see that the directive or ability lies
in an extension page called frame dot
HTML and our payload is here inside a
parameter called message and if we put
HTML here at this the this runs on the X
extension page now it's one ability
almost allowed Universal XSS and but it
didn't before
at least from what I tried
why so let's see where the vulnerability
is it's pretty straightforward here's
how our our payload in a requested
message it gets into STR status and then
STR statuses get gets into the raw HTML
of the title of this page so that's
really a common easy truth trivial case
of XSS it's so trivial that actually
Google CSP content security policy
blocks a JavaScript execution in this
case now
Tabitha mandi in his Linds the report
mentioned that there's a way to to pivot
that to confucian but I didn't invest
too much effort on that I'll show you
other examples the thing is that there's
nothing new here okay what I'm showing
the exercise some extensions it's
something that mr. Kotter with an oz oz
born already shown here in black hat on
2012 so I wanted to say that that that
might the topic here is not XSS on
extensions it's how to create a botnet
abusing these extensions and one
addition is that the is there is
something that was changed since 2012
and this is the content security policy
of Chrome extensions since 2014 Google
enforced a default CSP context security
policy on all the extensions this
prevents a lot of trivial common and
Java code injections including this case
of Adobe it
for example prevents inline scripts and
it prevents eval functions and yeah so
it wouldn't comment Java JavaScript
injections that this was in my opinion a
very important move from Google side
because before that there were a lot of
cross-site scripting vulnerabilities in
a lot of extensions and this while it
made a
a lot of walk for extension developers
because they have to take all the their
their buggy inline scripts into into the
extension its I I think it saved saved
us from an XSS extent extension exercise
horror scenario um and I wanted to show
you that because the thing is that this
P is not enough it's a generic policy
the default CSP and thinking that a
generic policy will cover all the cases
is is wrong and let's see an example
let's move to the next example which is
the avg web tune-up extension this
extension aims to protect users browser
and but on December 2015
well it had 9 million installations the
same guys the same guy at mr. Treviso
Mandi found this extension to be
vulnerable to to have several critical
vulnerabilities including XSS and in
this case CSP did not walk and I will
show how short we shall show why and
this is Travis and a report the
hilarious thing here is that his his is
the signature disappointed Travis the
obvious if you're here you're my hero
I mean this is an extension that aims to
protect users and it actually made all
day all these browser all these users
hackable in several ways so I'm gonna
I'm going to run a little demo of this
XSS that allowed it's it's an it's a
universal exercise meaning that you can
inject code a on on victims that runs
this extension to any time to any domain
let's have a quick look
so what we see here is the exploitation
POC a code it's it's a little it's it's
basically the the POC code by it by mr.
Normandy with some adjustments that I
added
actually it's let's look on this farm
which is similar what we see here is
that there's a loop that sends a wind
that post window messages with the
message now if you if you pay close
closer attention you can see that the
payment the message is sent to the
window of of the attack page itself it
is that the attack page okay this is the
page that I'm going to send victims in
order to attack them now that the attack
page sent a post message to the same
window it runs on okay so this is weird
because we are sending a message short
to our own window the thing is that the
extension also inject content script
into our attack page because it inject
it eject the script to any just any page
and for some reason it also listens to
this messages okay we see it in a second
in the in the extension cord but what I
wanted to show here is that in this
inside this mesh missed message I
indicate an action that I call navigate
and I give also date data in the data I
give you our L the URL is a JavaScript
column URL that runs this script on the
on the on the active tab now just for
explain it the navigate the navigate
action causes the extension to to update
a tab an open tab with our URL to
navigate to our URL and our you already
the JavaScript code you can see that
there is a for loop that you can notice
that there is a table ID year here and
and I'm going to
and three thousand a messages like this
with all the cob IDs of all I all my
tabs and in these tabs I'm going to
check if it runs on black a.com if it
runs on black a.com if it's a black dot
com tab I'm going to inject the beef
framework a code in order to gain
control over this tab and just a quick
look at the epicord of the extension so
what we see here is this is the
background script on the of the X
extension you can see that there's a
function called navigate and it takes
our message here here is our message the
data of the message and run this
function navigate and this function in
turn you can see it here uses qualm api
and traps update in order to update the
table ID that we chose to the URL that
we chose here this is the URL so why
let's let's run it and then you explain
why CSP is not effective here
okay so I have a Blackett page and I am
going to refresh it to show you that
everything is normal and let's turn on
the avg web tune-up the vulnerable
version of this extension now is on and
I'm also going to delete this this is
Biff I'm going to delete this is aam be
M by the way this is our attack page
okay that you just saw this is the code
that you just saw and you can see that
after injecting the beef and the beef
page of the beef script it also alerts
that we have a hook so we've got the
blackheads the blackheads window here
you see there are no online browser and
beef and now I'm going to refresh this
page as you see we've got another
I injected code to blackhat without any
any vulnerability on blackett okay just
by abusing this extension you can also
see that now the beef the beef double
javascript is injected into the page and
the best beef requests are starting to
run and we can see that in beef we have
a new a new hook browser in a hoop tab
and now the thing is that attackers can
can use these vulnerable extensions in
order to run scenario 1 campaigns just
like the ones that we saw earlier if I
get control gain control over Gmail and
Facebook which I will I will show in a
second and I can send my payload my
attack page which is the data credit we
saw two other victims using Facebook and
distribute my payload effectively
through social networks in order to
create by my botnet my chrome extensions
botnet and not again just a quick
example from beef you can do something
like this a fake notification bar on the
page and just one second and what the
victim will see is something like that
additional plugins required to display
this this page and if you click it a JC
file is downloaded and then this in this
example it's a JC file that can act like
the J's file that we saw in the tag me
if you can attack
thank you and the last thing I want to
show here is how I inject code also to
Facebook and Google and in this case
Google Drive this is another file very
similar what it does it checks if I'm on
Facebook on Google and then just right
that we have a success on the domain
let's run it and you can see that we've
got XSS on Facebook and Google Drive
okay
getting back to the presentation great
so why is CSP not blocking this kind of
exercise the reason here is that there
is no generic JavaScript injection here
there's no inline script there is no
eval okay
all we all all we do is sending a post
message to our own window and the
extension listens in in the in the code
that it injects to our window to these
messages and then pass it to the
background script of the extension now
the background script has the ability to
update tabs and adjust update that you
are URL of the tab so I'm not I'm not
even injecting it's it's not the the
application that injects the code is not
the page itself is the background script
of the extension that he's able to
control the tabs because it has
permissions and one small example I want
show a also show is JSON view how many
in the room have this extension
installed or had it in the past okay
great
there are a lot of people with this
extension and it was for a year and a
half since that it was since February
till November 2016 it was vulnerable to
XSS and no one there were reports
bye-bye mr. Joe veneks on this XSS and
no one repaired it a quick quick demo
second demonstration is this so let's
let's open the enable the JSON view
extension you can see here that there's
a page on wix.com which has a category
that I I put input here and this is the
input you can see
this is the input and the thing here is
that a lot of websites including weeks
take input and make and generate a JSON
file out of it so this is this is the
JSON file that it contains my input and
if I run it I can see that I have an
exercise and this this example is very
different from the from the other from
the first one that I showed you and CSP
does not block it as well great
and one second okay I think I'm finished
it's time for questions
[Applause]