our nightmares of data breaches and the
apts keeping you and your CISOs up at
night you probably know by now you
should be hunting but what should you be
hunting for and when and how rob and I
have a definition of threat hunting
we've been using for a little while that
says threat hunting is the collective
name for the set of manual or
semi-automated processes that you do to
find the bad guys the security incidents
in your network probably the ones that
were missed by your automated detection
systems that you already have in place
and there are there's a lot of interest
in this topic right now but weirdly
there's maybe not so much good guidance
on how to figure out what you should be
hunting for everybody yeah you should go
hunting if you go into the vendor area
you'll see lots of threat hunting
messaging going on but how do they how
do you know what you should be hunting
for what are the priorities you should
be setting for the things you're hunting
for how do you create from how do you
create from that to going to coming up
with a finished hunt plan that you can
turn over to your hunters and let them
start hunting well we've thought this
was kind of a big problem and we wanted
to do something about it and have a
little bit of fun at the same time so
Rob and I are gonna tell you a bedtime
story about how you can solve these
problems in your enterprise and come out
with an actionable hunt plan so snuggle
in relax and enjoy go to hunt then sleep
if my mic works okay a lot of suspense
there we go there we go
the bad guys are inside your network
today from finance to HR they creep if
you expect to ever rest well go to hunt
then sleep so thanks for joining us my
name is David Bianco and I'm here on
stage with Rob Lee I'm I'm a malware
researcher I'm sorry I'm a security
researcher but a little bit different
than the kind that you will see here
mostly at blackhat because most of the
people who describe themselves I think
says security researcher here are like
malware researchers or offensive exploit
researchers or you know I I don't really
do that my whole career is focused more
on protecting networks by doing incident
detection and it's in a response and
kind of sharing what I've learned with
the rest of the community and so I'm a
my research mostly focuses on better
ways to do incident detection including
threat hunting I'm also the main
instigator behind the threat hunting
project that threat hunting net and I
will turn this over to Rob and he can
say a few words about himself
sure hey so I'm Rob Lee I run a company
called Drago's which is ICS focused and
basically my whole career focuses on
things that blow up and can hurt people
is we try to keep it from happening I
teach at Sands Institute as well I've
seen a bunch of you out here from my
previous classes either on the threat
intelligence side or the ICS Incident
Response course but most people actually
know me for writing the little Bobby
comic I like to pretend I'm technical
and know things but everybody always
comes out to being goes I read your
stuff I'm like oh my latest paper no no
no the comic book I'm like oh okay
that's cool so Jeff Hoffs obviously
can't be with us today but Jeff Haas is
the illustrator for a lot of the stuff
you saw on the screen today we'll see
I'm he's the the illustrator for little
Bobby and we are know samuel l.jackson
but we will try to narrate the story for
you the best that we can we also are not
doing a hunting 101
type talk so a lot of the stuff we want
to deliver to you is actionable and
things you can go back and use however
if you're interested in some of the 101
type material on what is threat hunting
how to get started before sort of the
planning discussion we did include some
links up on the slide these are
resources that David and I have worked
on it before obviously he runs the
threat hunting project but we also have
the hypothesis generation for successful
hunting paper and that really details
the three ways you can generate
hypotheses to get started because
realistically because it's a human
driven process a lot of your challenges
will be around generating good
hypotheses to go out and test in your
environment so then get you started with
that we're actually going to go through
though read you the story and get you
your first five hunts and that you can
leverage in your own environment we were
serious
chapter two a song of Intel and planning
know what you're doing before you start
hunting prepare for success my sweet
take the time to think things through so
you can go to hunt then sleep good
hunting requires successful planning a
lot of planning you can't just take some
ill-formed ideas and pass them on to
some thread hunters and be like okay go
do this
they might produce something but how do
you know it's going to be the most
useful use of their time right is it
gonna be something that is really
important to your company or not that's
part of the planning process so we're
gonna talk about in this section the
three phases of good hunt planning the
first is how to identify the adversary
tactics and techniques that your
organization more specific most
specifically should be concerned about
there are obviously commonalities across
different organizations that are you
know you can leverage but in my
experience many of the organizations
because of either their industry or the
way they do business
or even just the technologies they have
in use the specific tactics and
techniques vary a little bit so we're
gonna talk about what tactics and
techniques you should be to figure out
what you should be concerned with and
then we're gonna talk about how you
prioritize that big list so that you can
come with a picklist you know the most
the most important things on the top and
then how you take each one of those
individual things and turn them into a
fleshed out plan for the individual hunt
so we'll have a hunt plan at the macro
level that shows that what you want to
hunt for and and in what priority order
and then we'll have a hunt plan at the
kind of a micro level for an individual
hunt so the first thing is to identify
your hunt targets the first step is to
kind of look at the friendly Intel that
you have about your own environment
things like the core business processes
that you have the the assets that are
directly supporting those a lot of times
you refer this kind of analysis as like
a crown jewels analysis but you're maybe
not only specifically concerned with
things like oh let's identify the mail
servers and the Active Directory servers
you also want to look at the business
side and say well what are the most
important things that are going on in my
IT environment that are actually making
my business work and it could be
manufacturing it could be intellectual
property generation depending on what
your business is but figure out what the
most important things that are going on
that make your business run as the
unique kind of business it is the other
thing is take a look at the kind of flip
side of that and what are the things
that are going on in your environment
that if someone were to cause disruption
in them would most impact your business
so that's where you do get into some
kind of IT pieces like yeah if they take
down the Active Directory servers you're
probably not going to be able to log in
and have a bad day
but there may be some other things that
are specific to you so if you're in one
industry maybe you're very concerned
with data breaches of customer info if
you're in a different industry maybe
you're concerned more with I don't know
like if you're in the medical industry
you might be concerned more with the
security of the medical devices that
you're working with things like that the
next thing to do is I'm going to make
the whole slide here actually the next
thing to do is figure out what those
tactics and techniques are for your
environment and then go to something I
like to use the mitre attack framework
for this to find the tactics tactics and
techniques that you've already
identified in the mitre attack framework
and look at the other things that are
near to them on the matrix because those
are the related things it's not so much
that you're going to have to cover
everything in them in the miter attack
matrix but think of this as more of a
well I think of it as like the pirate
code it's kind of a guideline more than
a rule there are some things in here
that you cannot detect for example I
think one of the entries and the command
part is something like use of
multi-layer encryption like encrypted
and then encrypted and then encrypt it
on top of that that is a thing that
attackers might do but it's not
something that you're going to be
expected to have to develop detections
for so don't think of every one of these
things as something that you have to
detect but think of them as kind of like
security conversation starters like to
spark other ideas about other tactics
and techniques that might be related to
what you already know you want to look
for and it's a little bit of weights of
getting a little bit of breath right
so now you have a list of things that
you're interested in and it's probably
unordered and kind of looks random ish
the next idea is to map them to an
attacker lifecycle model and there are a
lot of choices
probably everyone here is familiar with
if I can get this to work the Lockheed
Martin cyber kill chain mandiant also
has its own and again since we're using
the mitre attack framework just for
purposes of this presentation we're
going to go with the mitre attack
attacker lifecycle but it doesn't really
matter which one you use and you may
even have your own and there's other
ones out there as long as you find one
that you're comfortable with so what you
do then is you take the individual
things that you identified the tactics
and techniques and you match them up to
where they fall on the attacker
lifecycle model that you've chosen so
you can see here I've kind of done this
a sample it's a very small sample yours
will probably be a lot more detailed and
on the x-axis I've got all of the attack
lifecycle phases and on the y-axis I
have my gut feel of relative priority I
can't say that there's an
industry-standard scoring for priority
of these things right but the idea here
is that in most the attacker lifecycle
models the things that are closer to the
end of the chain or the model are
usually higher priority because it means
the adversary has gone farther into
their attack and they're executing
things that are more impactful to your
organization and so if you align these
things you've matched these these
tactics and techniques up and you place
them on the grid in their proper life
cycle and sort them rank order them with
what your rough priorities are then
you end up with a graph here that
basically shows the it's kind of like
the Magic Quadrant for threat hunting
and it's in detection these are the
things up in the right-hand corner upper
right that you need to probably think of
as your priorities now what you're gonna
have to do next is you have a still kind
of a matrix of those and you will end up
then taking those and collapsing them
down into a single column fully ranked
and there again this is one of those
situations where there's not exactly a
correct one correct way to do it but if
you think of things like the whatever is
at the most corner part of it the upper
right corner that's probably the first
thing if you look at the bottom of that
column though the bottom of that column
may in fact be a little bit less of a
priority than the top of the previous
column so you'll have to collapse them
in a way that makes sense again there's
no one way to do it but just take these
as a guide and and merge them into a
single list and that is what you should
be hunting for and in what order now the
next part of that though is we want to
take each of those individual pieces and
flesh them out to be a hunting plan that
you could give to a threat hunter and
get them started right right now you're
not really ready to start hunting on
these things because you don't really
have a lot of details other than a title
for the hunt so you're gonna have to
start with doing a little research and
depending on the way your organization's
hunt program is structured you might do
this before you send it to the hunt team
or the hunt team could actually do these
before they actually start hunting
somebody has to do this but it doesn't
necessarily always have to be you and
you'll take each one of these and do
some research to see okay what does this
actually mean match it up to what you
know about your technologies that you
have it in place and say well if I did
see this
what would it look like in my
environment in my specific environment
not somebody else's environment with a
different kind of data set right and we
want to get basically three things there
are four things out of this the first
thing is we want to get some kind of
research summary of background
information that the hunters are going
to get in reality not everything that
you're gonna hunt for is gonna be like
your hunt teams built already built
expertise I mean you're going to give
them things that they don't really know
that much about occasionally and so this
summary of the technics tactics and
techniques and how they operate and what
the purposes of them are and things like
that it's gonna be very useful for
getting the hunt team up to speed based
on that and then based on what you know
about your own technology is in place in
your own IT infrastructure
you're gonna then create a hunting
hypothesis this is what Rob was
referring to in the intro when we talked
about they talked about that paper that
we wrote together about how to frame
your hunting questions like I have my
hypothesis is this kind of activity may
be going on in my environment if so this
is what it you know might look like once
you have the hunting hypothesis then you
can start looking for things like okay
that's the hypothesis now in my data set
specifically what type of side effects
or artifacts would I expect to find if
my hypothesis were true and these could
be things like and we're gonna see some
concrete examples of these as we go
through our hunt plan for the specific
organization that we chose a little bit
later but these could be things like I
should see a spike in this or I should
see a dip in this or I should see a
combination of these events in a short
amount of time
I should see something visual that would
look like this
depending on what you're hunting for it
could be a lot different so this is one
of the reasons that you have to do this
kind of planning so that you can know
what to what to expect when you're
actually hunting and know what a
successful find might look like and
finally once you know what you need to
find then you can decide on some
analytic
nooks that might help you find that
information so it could be stacked
counting or it could be a least
frequency of occurrence analysis it
could be visualizations or machine
learning or anytime it's all kinds of
things so you kind of make a rough plan
and that may change as they get into the
hunt and that's okay
but you're going in with a plan and the
last thing I just want to mention it's
not technically part of the hunt
planning but I think it's in a very
important part of the hunting process
overall
is we need to be able to take the
successes that we have in our hunt
program and automate those so that we
don't have to keep doing the same hunt
over and over again because we want to
have our time free to do new hunts so
even though you may have to revisit
occasionally just to make sure
technology and processes didn't drift
too far and and invalidate the
successful hunt we really should be
considering that the end goal is to try
to automate it as fully as possible so
that you can go off and do something
more productive than just doing the same
analysis over and over again so don't
forget when you have a successful hunt
even if you didn't find anything in that
hunt but if you know that your hunt is
working and it would have found it
automated all right chapter three the
jungle incorporated book your product
plans and manufacturing deeds are the
things that you'd like most to keep
rivals could still these not just the
Chinese so go to hunt then sleep in this
section I want to tell you about the
company that we're going to be hunting
in so the next course the slides we're
going to be giving you concrete examples
of hunts that would be like your five
first hunts and we are structuring it
based off of this manufacturing
organization one of the reasons that we
chose a manufacturing organization is I
think it's very important to understand
that all sorts of environments are
different and have different priorities
and the way that you hunt in them is
be driven just as much by those business
processes that David talked about as the
type of intelligence that you're
actually gathering so in a manufacturing
organization as an example you would
typically have a business network where
your normal IT systems your Active
Directory and domain control email
servers but you would also have your
industrial control system networks and
these would be actually where you're
making the manufacturing gear in this
case jungle Incorporated is a leading
provider of jungle themed fidgets
spinners so this is what the
intellectual property that they're
trying to protect is it's not exactly
differentiated but it's pretty special
and then they go for a high rate so we
really want to keep that and we're gonna
try to structure our hunts to not only
include the type of activity that would
be in a business network type intrusion
but also the ways that your adversaries
would pivot into your industrial
environment and then take advantage of
this again one of the reasons I really
like this is we will often find those
cultural divides inside of organizations
where you might have IT security and
operational technology security and they
just never talk or if you're a big
company take any of the major airlines
as an example they have just as much
financial data and credit card
processing as they have intellectual
property as they have maintenance and
manufacturing lines with industrial
Internet of Things and all sorts of
crazy stuff a lot of times we see siloed
teams that form and a lot of your
hunting should help to bring together
those teams and make sure that you're
looking for the gaps in the security
that they're doing in those little silos
I mean it's perfectly fine not to find a
threat when you're actually hunting I
think we talked to the CTI some of this
year and sérgio I gave a presentation
on this as well noting that if you're
only metric for success is finding
threats you will be a very unsuccessful
threat hunting team and that is
obviously what we want to look for but
the byproduct of it is really supposed
to be driving value to your overall
organization and identifying where your
collection and detection doesn't match
up correctly so let's go through our
first five hunts here so your plans have
real merit don't just cover your rear
your priorities are spelled out so neat
these are things that you'll be look
for deer now go to hunt then sleep in
these first five hunts what we really
want to identify are building off of the
plan that we started with so David you
want to cover the first couple and then
I'll hit the ICS absolutely related ones
just to give you a little bit of a
preview we took those that piece of
information off of the slide that we
just saw where Rob was talking about
what this company really needs to
protect they need to protect the plans
for their products but they also need to
protect the unique manufacturing details
the plans don't tell you how to make it
entirely right they just tell you the
specifications of what needs to go there
but maybe there's some unique materials
that it they're unusual to work with and
so in order to fully replicate this
product you would need some information
from the corporate side the plans and
some information from the ICS side the
manufacturing details so based on that
we've come up with the first five hunts
that this company probably should do
they some of these may be in your first
five as well some of them probably won't
be but consider this to be a like a
concrete instantiation of the planning
that we went through in the previous
sections so we're going to do a little
few things here first of all their main
concern is their adversaries they're
their potential rivals stealing their
things right so most likely that will
happen through one of their border
connections to either the internet or it
could be through a partner VPN or
something like that but wherever it is
we want to look for data exfiltration
going out of the network there are many
ways to do data exfiltration and so in
your real hunt you'll probably have your
hunt plan you'll probably have multiple
hypotheses around data exfiltration but
the first one here is kind of
straightforward even though it looks a
little bit mathy
at first we're using we're using
something called the producer-consumer
ratio and you can see more about this at
the URL on the threat hunting project on
the bottom of the slide but basically
it's a measure of what I call the the
shape of the individual systems
interaction with the network it's a
ratio of the bytes produced to the bytes
consumed so that is bytes sent out onto
the network and versus the bytes
downloaded from the network and in this
case quote the network is a little bit
different depending on what type of
activity you're looking for one thing
that I find interesting about that
producer-consumer ratio hunt is that you
can use it to look for two different
things with the same exact process first
of all we can use it to look for data
exfiltration that is information leaving
our networks the idea is if a computer's
individual PCR number is let's say it's
you know starts out at zero which is the
midline it exactly it doesn't really do
that much maybe it starts out at one I
don't know wherever it is it's there
because of what that computer is
typically used for so like a person a
desktop a person browsing the web on
their desktop probably downloads much
more information than they send they
send small HTTP requests they get giant
gif files and streaming videos and
things like that file servers might look
the exact opposite a file server might
say you know I get very small requests
but I send lots of data out to the
network and that's okay because the the
PC are number by itself doesn't really
tell you that much about whether it's
being misused what you do is you look
for the shift the change in the PC RS
over time so I did a simple analysis in
in our testbed environment where I had a
number of hosts that I then proceeded to
compromise and do a data exfiltration
and I collected the information from the
test bed and computed the PCR for like
the the previous month and you see that
on one axis and then the PCR for the
time period of the week that had the
malicious activity in it on the other
axis in many cases things didn't really
change like that system was not
compromised or touched in its role
didn't change so it basically stayed the
same and that's where this line comes in
that line is the reference point for
there was no change anything on that
line is by definition fine anything off
that line in in the direction starts to
be a little bit weird maybe not too far
off the line not too far weird so we've
color-coded it so that when the PCR
shifted positively that is they started
to send more data than normal we color
coded that more red and when they
shifted negatively they started to
consume more data we color-coded it blue
so obviously the red can be data
exfiltration and in fact in in our
sample it actually turned out really
well because even though we had kind of
a priori knowledge about which network
node was doing the exfiltration we we
just did the math and came up and we
found yeah actually that was the highest
PCR shift it was the most red dot on the
on the graft but the other thing is you
can look at the blue dots as well
depending on where you collect your data
the blue dots may indicate things like
data collection and data staging prior
to X filtration as the attacker sits on
a computer and copies things into the
computer that they're going to later
send out you have to basically have your
data from a different collection point
but it's the exact same data the exact
same analysis process if you're looking
for data exfiltration you'll do this at
the network perimeter and if you're
looking for data staging in collection
you're more likely to do it at your core
networks so you need Network session
data you need like net flows or
Kahn logs or anything similar to that
and our analysis was straight up
visualization was our technique and what
we were looking for as you can see the
the artifacts that we expect to find are
things that don't fall on the line and
they're probably pretty far off the line
so for the next hunt we chose to merge
two different hunts into one because
they kind of are looking for the same
things and they're looking through the
same kind of data so it made a lot of
sense we're looking for evidence of
lateral movement because going you know
before you can ex rel trait things
you're probably going to have to find
things that you want around the network
you're unlikely that your initial access
point is going to be the place where
they have the product plans and it's
almost certainly not going to plead the
place where they have the manufacturing
details because you're probably not
going to get in through the ICS network
at first so you will have to have an
attacker move laterally to accomplish
either of those two goals so let's let's
talk about how we we find this again
these are both documented more fully at
the URLs that you see there I'm a threat
hunting project but the idea here is
basically two things our our hypothesis
is that the commanding of sorry the
lateral movement that might be happening
in our network is probably going to
happen from the command line that's not
always the way it happens but it is a
very common way for attackers to get in
just drop a shell or a shell like
program and and start running often with
native commands so we have two things
that we want to look for we're going to
look for shells or shell like things
like WMI services or whatever that are
being started by parents that don't
usually start them so documents Word
documents Excel whatever web browsers
even system services I mean this kind of
basic things right and but this will all
be in your process creation logs well
you'll have the
information about what was started and
what its parent process was and for that
hunt mostly we want to do lease
frequency of analysis or stat counting
so we actually just count all the unique
pairs of parent and command shell and we
find how many times that pair occurred
in the dataset across our enterprise
without exception the very common things
are going to have high counts and
usually you can just like ignore those
so we'd usually start with like a
reverse sort and we look for the most
uncommon things first and this seems
like why are you talking about this a
black hat it's very simple but actually
it's very effective because they're I
guarantee you they're not that many
times that you're your individual users
browsing around accidentally start up a
PowerShell from within Microsoft Office
right the other thing that we want to
hunt for through this same data is the
kind of the next phase they get a shell
somewhere what's the first thing that
they have to think about they want to
know where they got their shell what
what kind of computer that is where it
is in the network maybe what domain it's
in who the users are maybe what what can
it see in its network neighborhood so
they can maybe decide if that's the
place that they need to be to gather
their information or if they want to
make another hop somewhere else
and again there's many ways that they
could attackers can get this information
but a lot of times they just get it from
straight up from the commands that are
already installed on the computer so
we're gonna look for unusual spikes of a
cluster of these commands usually like
anything in system 32 like IP config and
and all these all these ones in their
queue user and things like that and we
want to look for spikes of those
occurring on a single system in a short
amount of time relatively short amount
of time it could be a kind of large
amount of time like a one hour bucket
even because they just don't get called
that often and so whenever they have a
spike it's probably pretty obvious
and our analytic technique there is is
basically just straight-up counting and
a little bit of visualization with the
timeline and at this point I'm going to
turn it over to Rob here he's going to
talk about the next couple hunts perfect
so once our adversary moves from the IT
networks into the industrial control
system networks things get a little
weird and when you look at industrial
control system environments they're
obviously not typical IT like
environments even though you might have
a Window System in that network it's
doing entirely different things with
entirely different purposes and we have
to appreciate what those purposes are to
fully understand what adversaries might
need to get and how we're gonna find
them as an example a lot of the
different instant response cases and
hunting I've done before in ICS
environments it's actually pretty
typical to find adversaries positioning
themselves on places like human-machine
interfaces the human machine interface
which I gave a sample little graphic up
there yes
they all do kind of look like Windows 95
paint but the human machine err faces
are the way that the operators interact
with the physical equipments sending
commands to open up valves or spinning a
turbine faster or getting a different
rate of fidget spinners off the line so
adversaries tend to position they're one
of the one of the reasons I thought this
before is it feels like common territory
usually again Linux or Windows
environments hosting these systems but
also in that HMI you will get a
representation of what the physical
process is it's not going to give you
everything you need to know but it's
gonna give you an understanding that oh
there is a valve on the network there is
a conveyor belt and here's the type of
systems I can expect to pair up off of
what my logical discovery on the network
is to an actual representation of it a
lot of the difficulty for adversaries
and industrial control system
environments is not things like
vulnerabilities and exploits it's an
understanding the actual systems
themselves I often push back on a little
bit of the hype in the community where
we hear things like oh my gosh an energy
company had an adversary access the
system and it's like yes now make the
lights blink it's a little harder than
it sounds so for our adversaries they've
got to get to that HMI to understand a
lot about what's going on with our
manufacturing process
some of the things that we can look for
some of them seem pretty trivial but a
lot of times the biggest problem is
actually getting data collection off of
those environments but as an example we
might see new processes spin up on an
HMI these are not environments that we
should have a lot of new software
applications installed on or new process
is spinning up especially not outside of
maintenance periods so there's a
temporal nature to a lot of industrial
control system environments about what
it's supposed to be doing and then given
course of time we shouldn't see updates
to systems or new processes spawning or
systems rebooting outside of things like
maintenance periods that they're going
in to maintain the equipment so that
would be exactly what we're looking for
in this environment you could do some
sort of exfiltrate off of this as well
and apply some that previous hunt
knowledge as well but realistically what
we're looking for is new connections
maybe even VPN session lengths in one
environment we were looking at VPNs into
the environment from the maintenance
personnel and they would come in on a
fairly regular basis they were logging
into the network about once every two
weeks and they would be the VPN itself
up for about thirty minutes to an hour
as they did their small maintenance but
in the same network we saw a compromise
one time that the adversary was using
the VPN but now they were coming in
every day and they were doing it for
five to fifteen minutes at a time
grabbing data and leaving so the session
length and duration would be entirely
different and how they're accessing
things like HMIS and then of course is
things that we want to look for
but HMIS alone won't give you the
manufacturing details we will want a lot
more information sometimes that
information can be stored in places like
data historians a data historian at
times is really just sort of a sequel
database but it gives you an
understanding of exactly what's going on
in the industrial process itself how
fast the turbines spinning how how far
did you slow it down and in a given
point it's kind of the brain and memory
of what's going on in the physical
process so even if I had a specification
for what the fidgets spinner was if I
wanted to know exactly how to make it
there's a lot of timing and interesting
details around how much mixture in terms
of the recipes or or exactly when did it
leave one section of the conveyor belt
and go to the next and again all that
information would be in somewhere like a
data historian in this location
sometimes we can get a couple different
types of artifacts one might simply be
more alarms or additional inputs than
normal especially if somebody was
actually doing an attack in our
environment so that type of distribution
would look very different in a lot of
visualization analysis taking place
there but in the same way we might see
exfiltration again coming off of these
types of environments especially for
ready to espionage and intellectual
property theft so looking for these
systems and and I think again from a
hunter perspective you might be
misguided to look at and go oh it's a
Window System I'm gonna do the normal
things there's a lot of different data
on that system that we can start pulling
off to identify the type of activity
that an adversary would be doing one of
the things I want to note about that as
well is again if you're if you are in an
ICS organization and you're looking to
go do these hunts you'll find that over
the years we have prioritized a lot of
network data which is really good
because a lot of information flows over
the network for us but a lot of the host
based data has typically not been
collected out of these environments and
so our hunting can actually drive our
collection process as well because we
can come up with a hypothesis that I
need that type of host data and realize
that I have no ability to collect it so
even though my hunt wasn't successful in
actually doing the hunt I then drive
future processes and how to actually
position the organization better in the
future
and that some of that seemed sort of
bridging that we talked about earlier
what David how far off our final hunt
I'm gonna invoke a buzzword machine
learning so one of the things that we
had in our priority plan was we wanted
to look for okay we already did data
exfiltration and lateral movements we
did some stuff inside the ICS
environment and then the next thing in
our priority list is we want to look for
evidence of possible command and control
activities or malware activities in our
network there again this is a situation
where there are many different ways this
could be accomplished so you kind of
have to break them down and do the
individual hunts for each one of those
different ways that you've identified
would work in your area
the most common probably that
I would venture to say Oh probably
everyone in the room probably has is
HTTP communications out to the Internet
that's particularly hard to find things
that are unusual in there just because
of the volume and velocity of that data
that is and in many cases truly a big
data problem just just figuring out how
to store all that information about your
outgoing HTTP information coming off
your proxies or your network monitoring
sensors or anything like that but our
hypothesis is that if you can figure out
how to look for that some things in
malware command and control or attacker
command control are a little bit
different than regular HTTP transactions
and it could be a combination of many
factors that are different such as the
length of the session the the order of
the headers that they've provided in
their requests the URLs that they're
going to even the domains etc there's
many things to look for so this actually
makes it a really good candidate for
doing some machine learning to help you
this is a kind of a situation where I
said earlier at the beginning where some
of these processes are semi automated
well a friend of mine Chris McCubbin and
I released a tool I think early last
year it's available on github called
clear-cut clear-cut is our proof of
concept to show that you could actually
get some value just by applying a simple
machine learning model to your own HTTP
logs to find the things that are a
little bit different or odd and I'm not
going to go into exactly how machine
learning works in my last eight minutes
of the presentation because I am NOT a
trained auctioneer and I cannot talk
that quickly however I will say please
if you're interested in in mutt in more
details you can find more on the the
link here on the slide and there's even
some YouTube videos but I will tell you
our
our clear-cut tool has two different
modes of operation one of them is it
uses a kind of traditional random forest
model to learn these things have been
labeled as malware transactions we had
to provide a bunch of malware
transactions and these things have been
labeled as totally legitimate
transactions we do what's called feature
ization that is we break down the text
of the HTTP logs into basically a set of
numbers that we can do computations with
and all this code is available in there
and documented so that you can use it
and mess with it to feature eyes your
own logs the way you like them and and
then we train them through this
algorithm called random forests that
basically says it creates a bunch of
individual decision trees and says if
this random feature that I took out of
the data set for an individual line this
random feature splits the data this
other random feature splits the data it
makes a tree until you get to the end
and they and you have a yes or a No with
this malicious or was this benign and
it's a random forest because it creates
a bunch of these random decision trees
many of these decision trees and each
time basically it goes through and
computes all the trees and and basically
averages them out at the end and then
you get the average answer yes or no
it's very effective
it's very pretty quick I won't say it's
super quick but it's pretty quick and it
does a great job of cutting down the
logs that you have to look at I think in
our tests we found that we were only
reviewing something like point oh one
percent of our logs manually after
clearcut ran and the random forests so
it still is a role for a human but not
quite at the scale that it would be
impossible to do anymore the other
mechanism that clearcut has is it has
this unsupervised machine learning where
they do a little bit of clustering with
a kind of I don't know unusual out
called isolation forests in the
isolation forests take the same features
that the random forest does but we don't
have to tell it these are bad and these
are good and train that model that way
what with what they do is they plot kind
of a it sounds like this is gonna sound
like Doctor Who but they say plot like a
104 dimension matrix and it's all timing
why me
wibbly-wobbly stuff but they and then
they look in that hundred and four
dimension matrix to see which points are
closest to the other points and which
ones are farther away and they do this
by making a series of random cuts and
they say the number of cuts that you
have to do to isolate that individual
data point is a measure of how far from
normal that data point is so if you can
then do a relatively few cuts it's very
far from normal
if you have to do a lot of cuts it's
close into one of these dense compact
things again I don't really have time to
explain that in detail even if I did
understand it entirely but definitely if
you're interested go check out the tool
watch the YouTube video and you'll see
Rob you want to bring it home bring it
on home all right
our story is done you know what to do
when you're back in the office next week
make a good plan aligned with your needs
then go to hunt and oh you're asleep
thank you everybody for attending our
presentation I hope you found it
enjoyable and educational
[Applause]