module my name is Ellie Biscayne I work
at Google where I lead the antabuse
research team and today I'm going to
talk to you about the sha-1 collision
obviously it has been a long and
interesting journey over the last few
years while we created this first
collision this is a German work with a
bunch of you people including Mark
Stevens the mastermind behind it
Pik poor man owns Alberta new yard
Markov and that expertise bianco before
we get started to make sure everyone is
on the same page let me quickly recap
what the hash function is so what is the
hash function is it's basically a
function which will take a file of
arbitrary length and will reduce it to a
fixed size string which we call a digest
or hash this house has two specific
property which are very important for
security
the first one is hash uniqueness which
means if you were to hash two files even
if they have one bits of differences the
hash will be drastically different the
second one is one way function meaning
that from the hash you do not learn
anything from the file you've been
hashed that's very useful for if you're
sharing a sample of so forth so that's
why the main is basic cryptographic
property of a hash function so where do
you find hash function well you found
them pretty much everywhere they are
used in document and software signing
for example to verify the integrity of
the windows update they also use
obviously into HTTP certificate to make
sure your certificate is valid I've been
signed by a CA they are used in version
control for integrity purposes and the
hotels and obviously they are used in
backup for integrity purposes they also
using the law of slew a slew of software
is including databases sometimes file
system legacy system and whatnot and
this huge diversity of software who use
hash functions explain why it's so hard
to understand what is the consequences
of a collision because we can't know for
sure who is using it I'm going to talk
to that a bit later so
today I want to go through three points
with you guys so first one is we're
going to talk about the past and we're
going to talk about what our hash
function and how they been used and
attack in the past many drawing from the
MDF I example which was the biggest
break before hours then we're going to
talk about how we found the hash on
collision how we did it and what was a
complexity behind it and finally we're
going to look forward then we're going
to talk about a post collision world
what happened next what is going to
happen and in particular for everyone
learning software how to deal with
legacy software we still use sha-1 and
what is the future hold for show for
hash security as a whole so before
getting started a quick show of hands
how many of you know what the collision
attack is okay how many of you know what
to pre imagine attack is way less okay
how many of you know what is the
difference between the preimage and the
second preimage attack even less people
okay so let's go briefly around what
they are so everyone knows what we are
talking about and then we go into how we
do that before I want to do that I want
to give credit to everyone what I'm the
one standing in the room and talking to
you about sha-1 collision it's important
to remind that it's a collective effort
actually that's the last piece of a
puzzle the Kryptonite is of sha-1
started about 15 years ago and two
people stand out of the community who
this research the first one is wrong
she's the one who brought all the theory
behind how to break md5 and sha-1 in
cred collision so she's the one who
should be credited for breaking sha-1
and tirion as well md5 the other person
who stood as a giant is Maxim and my
collaborator and MIT is the mastermind
of the project he is the one who for the
last 10 years have been carrying the
fried for the entire community and never
drop and keep pushing forward until we
reach his final milestone as a matter of
fact many people dropped out this is my
second attempt at breaking sha-1 by the
way when I was at Stanford in 2008 and
2010 I briefly considered the idea with
Dan Boneh to actually go after sha-1 and
try to enter the race and we looked at
the complexity of the attack and need of
resources and were like that's too hot
come do it and then we been discouraged
and give up and we reconnected when I
joined Google after a few years on
Google with Markham 2014 and we're like
well I think we can help you
we can put at your disposal the
technical mean and which is to help you
finish this project and we've been
working on that and I'm really glad we
could help him but I'll show you that
many people actually were afraid of that
and I'll show how much mark was
instrumental in to this and so if one
person needs to be credited for that
that should not be us that should be him
so I didn't want to make that very clear
to people because what he can't be there
today he's the one who is behind me and
actually the one who did most of the
thinking behind that okay so how do you
attack hash function well as I said
there is three type of attack the first
one is called a collision attack that
the one we're going to talk in detail
today
the idea is yet I have one fine and then
his goal is to create a second file who
hash to the same hash right so two five
we have the same hash that's the
collision attack a pre-image attack is a
little bit different you have an unknown
file and you know the hash and the
attacker has to come up with if I will
hack which actually able to hash to the
same thing so you don't know the file a
second preimage attack which is the most
confusing at least in the documentation
is this idea of you know unknown file
let's say SSL certificate and then it
has been issued and you are creating a
file which will hash to the same thing
while of fully preserving pre structures
both pre image and second preimage
attack are not feasible in practice that
is why I'm not going to cover detailed
discuss them too much in this talk but
they do exist it's just for
understanding that there are other
attack which are more dangerous so of
the tree the collision attack is just
want to do and that the only one which
is today available in practice whether
it's for md5 or sha-1 and
that gets about it so how do you create
a collision well the first thing which
is very important to explain is you
cannot use brute force while the number
we publish are like very huge in reality
if you were to just say let's put as
much resources I want to break this
thing you can't the reason for that is
we estimate that if you watch the brute
force attack you will need 12 million
years of GPU to do one collision
obviously no one has this power is not
feasible on earth so you can't do brute
force brute force attacks are
impractical so you need something called
crypt analysis which
the offensive part of cryptography to
understand the flow of the algorithm and
exploit them to reduce the complexity so
crypt analysis use a number of set of
techniques and I'm going to show you a
high-level overview to be able to reduce
the attack complexity to a manageable
form in our case that would be two to
the 63 which is again trillions and
trillions of computation but it's in
more manageable as those 12 million
years of GPU certain one can do so no
crime scene analysis for function no
break so how do we attack a hash
function the first thing to understand
is how a hash function is constructed
there is two things there is a
construction of the hash function and
there is a compression function so the
construction of the hash function is the
mechanics by which it's able to reduce
an arbitrary length file into a fixed
size hash so in the case of sha-1 we use
a merkle-damgard construction which was
invented by Mercker during his PhD in
1979 it works as follows
you start with initialization vectors
which is known and you take the first
the first block of the file and you pass
both into what we call the comprise
function in our case that would be the
sha-1 compressed function then you take
this output and feed it again to the
compress function with a second block so
now you have reduced to block into a
fixed size and you keep going and going
until you reach the last block and when
you reach the last block you basically
have successfully reduced your entire
file where depending how many blocks you
have into a single string that we call
the hash right this is the construction
of them as a miracle dam graph
construction it also works this is the
same one which is used both for md5 as
well as shout 256 and every shell to
family members okay so the important
thing to understand there is by looking
at the picture and you can see it very
clearly there is no dependency between
the blocks so if you look at the sha-1
compression it only depend on the input
of the previous block compression and
the block itself so there is no
dependency from previous block or past
block which means that if you were to
attack it all you have to do is focus on
one block at a time which make it in a
way more easier because there
is no non linear dependency so how do
you attach the shaman compression
functions well let's take a look at that
here is a very non-traditional way to
represent sha-1 if you look at the
Wikipedia page will not see this one
this is the cryptanalysis version of
sha-1 what we do is we unroll the entire
function all the 80 steps and we lay
them out because we need to understand
very precisely how the bit are moving at
each step along the way to be able to
understand how we can control them and
reduce the unsharp is generated by user
function so this is exactly the same
compression function I showed you you
can see the block on the top and the
chain value at the bottom does the same
thing except it's unrolled the purple
box do represent this competeing part of
the function for example f is a
nonlinear function we told you to permit
blocks and the process the addition says
it should be so basically this is the
thing which is responsible for
scrambling is a bit and compressing it
to the short string okay
so how do you attack that I'm going to
skip over a lot of detail there is 15
years of cryptanalysis so I can't really
go into detail and personal aid on the
origin myself I just want to give you an
overview of how kryptonite is work so
you can follow along with the rest of
the talk so the crypto is work as
follows we look at what we call message
differential paths which is this idea of
can we study when you input a class of
messages how the betas change and how
the difference are propagated along with
a function this is represented into the
diagram with red blocks we have been
able to study them very carefully and
along the year we were able to actually
solve the first 16 step so for us the
complexity and the entropies aware of
the function has been pushed by by 16
step making it's a function less
complicated to attack and then after 62
step we have a few more steps
which is about eight steps where we
can't really predict what will happen
but we have a bunch of techniques to
help control how the binary is a bit
will diverge not fully but enough to
control it a little bit we use for
example boomerang neutral bits which
basically helps you to
what my feelings are they're being able
to control how much the complexity
explode and then well we don't know that
that's what is the right part is the
part where we have to do this very
expensive computation is we have been
able to push back the complexity to only
a fraction of the function to see the
big fraction that we have able to push
it back as you can see on the diagram
and that's where that's why it's not a
brute force attack right I hope it gives
you the intuition that by able to
understanding how the function work
we're able to reduce the steps where we
don't know what happened to a minimal
amount we can so we would use a
computation cost fair enough
all right that's there are people
nothing good all right so let's move it
okay so I lied I'm a liar story what
happened is in reality when you do a
collision you don't do one block you do
two block actually that's what's wrong
main idea so she's the one who come up
with a technique it turns out it's
easier to do a collision with two blocks
than one block so the way it works is we
have the file and we have a first block
and it doesn't matter this is just your
profits and you can do whatever you want
there then you have a first block which
we call a near-collision
so the near-collision is basically you
find two blocks on two different file
which are almost the same almost the
same for this for a notion of distance
and constraint which means those two are
we believe we can glue them together
back to cancel out the differences and
this is a collision itself so first we
find the block which is producing as
close to the result and then we have
this thing which finally with of all the
differences and then remember there is
no dependency between the block so when
you're done with the collision and all
the difference has been resolved you can
basically put whatever you want because
obviously when the collision is done the
two have the same output so collision is
complete so one other thing which is the
most misunderstood about collision
attack is suffix can be whatever you
want and even after you found a
collision you can swap it for anything
you want because it doesn't matter right
that's why people were confused when we
attack say we can predict create as many
documents as we want is because we can
swap the suffixes to whatever we want by
appending the collision blocks to it so
we'll be able to create many documented
I will show you a demo of that all right
so now that we kind of know how to do
collision I'm not going to give you more
details than that because I think it
helps I think here is the idea by now
let me tell you how you explore them and
how you make them useful so the first
type of attack we have with when you
have a collision is called the fixed
perfect attack which this is the one we
use in sha-1 in that case we have a
prefix that you have to choose before
you create a collision because it's
going to be remember the input of the
prefix will be used in the coalition so
we can't change it after the fact then
you have the blocks which is where you
do all your competition and those are
pretty like random blocks and then you
have the arbitrage traffic that you can
change I don't get the other thing
there's the thing but you can swap them
as much as you want
it doesn't seem very powerful at first
glance but actually there is a very neat
trick which is if you craft the prefix
ahead of time which is specific enough
you can use it to displacing which are
not the same so the idea would be use
the question block let's say for a
length of a g-pack comment as we did in
that case the first collision we point
to a part of the suffix whereas the
other block will point to another part
and as a result you will displace
English are different while having the
same sha-1 so it's not the fire are
different the only different of the
collision block but they are displaying
different things so you can trick people
let's say with a list contract to
different German to 4th that's the basic
idea of why spending a lot of time on to
finding the right prefixes was very
important the other option which only
work for md5 but it's worth mentioning
because it was quite a few interesting
attack about it was when you can
actually choose the price as a perfect
in that specific case you relax the
assumption and actually so preference in
both cases would give you way more
flexibility where you can actually do
whatever you want before the collision
the collision and whatever you want
after the collision and give you way
more flexibility and when you have this
kind of power a lot of things to open up
so let me walk you to concrete example
and illustrate that better so let me
show you too because a lot people say
well collision is more in the academic
world
didn't have real world consequences they
do so these are the two form md5 because
we have the history of time in front of
us and we can look at example from the
past sure one is too recent to see this
kind of attack yet so the first one is
the md5 ssl certificate forgery so in
2009 Mark Stephens and Alex Oliver and
the bunch of people were able to create
a signing certificate by using an md5
collision so how that works well here's
what a certificate look like so when you
buy a certificate or when you get one
from let's encrypt you get something
which have a sales number a valid DPL
which tell you when it's going to expire
and then a wheelset domain name which is
basically what is your certificate is
valid for let's say my domain calm and
then you have a bunch of other
information one of them is of course
your RSA public key for the cryptography
something which is called extension
there in green which basically said you
cannot sign other certificate obviously
you know to see a and find a little
signature which is using at that point
md5 which basically is a way the browser
verify that your certificate has been
signed by an invalid Authority and make
it valid right so that's the tracing
solution you have so how do you expose
that with a collision well the first
thing is you to the put you basically
add so sale number and to validate
period as back then you're going to
change the real domain name choose the
one you want and in that case you won't
store meaning you can sign for
everything that would be Weber I think
it will work for everything then you add
our new RSA public key which is the one
you want to use to sign the certificate
with your certificate key then you have
to change the extension and say actually
this is a signing certificate because
you also want to be able to delegate and
create new certificate and finally you
have to push back everything right
because remember we have to keep the
same data so you have to a move to the
collision and you also have to put back
so write a certificate so how you do
that well you use what we call the nice
cape comment extension so it turns out
there is one extensions for SSL
certificates which is called
the comment extension no browser cares
about it but it exists so the idea is
you push the old private key or the old
public key sorry as well as some other
information directly into the comment
extension so they are known unify and
this is why you put your collision and
then all you have left to do is to store
to put back the same signature
the signature would validate because
they do a checksum on you using md5 and
you have a signed certificate this is
how you create a colliding certificate
Wow okay this is very complicated no one
is going to do that in practice right
well not true in 2012 I believe the
weather report of a super malware cover
cool flame flame was used to infect
Iranian computer and what's makes flame
unique and you can see it on the screen
was a use of a call gate the correcting
certificate was actually a Microsoft
Terminal Server certificate which was
used lifted and we package to actually
be used to sign fake Windows Update so
they were collision to be able to
actually push fake windows update and
infect computers that way this is the
first and monie weaponization of
collision we know of but it's ok is that
actually collision can have real-world
impact for trivia okay Mac changing
[Music]
can you tell all right so sorry about
that Suzy so for the trivia what's very
interesting about this this case is Mark
and the few cryptographer other 1/4 all
right we are little bit unlucky today
all right great
so what's interesting is when Mark and a
few people look at the forensic analysis
of the certificate been used of course
abuse is about the collision except the
collision didn't use two blocks as I
told you but four and you're like why
would they use for well it turns out
that's a very sub optimal way to create
a collision the certificate date back
from 2009 and if you remember I told you
the collision was published in 2009 so
someone somewhere well from dead and
well-versed in cryptography have
developed their own way to create SSL
certificate collision it was not as
efficient as the one which was developed
by academia but it was nevertheless
working and they created their own
collision so we know from the forensic
analysis of the certificate that so
people wanted lifted to certificate in
2009 use their own cryptographic
knowledge and tools to create this copy
whose that might be I leave you guys up
to
gas but these are clearly people who
knew what they were doing yes it was a
little bit suboptimal but it did the job
quite well and so this is the only
example we have a weapon ization of a
collision but they do occur in practice
which is why collision needs to be taken
seriously by everyone at least that's a
good example of why it's important all
right so to recap where do we stand
today md5 is broken like literally three
operation that's horrible
md5 has been broken for a long time it
is to the point where you can do it on
your cell phone you can literally create
an md5 collision on your cell phone if
you would like for sure one which is our
new result you need to to the 63
computation which
she trilliant of computation so you
can't do that on your cell phones you
need the data center for that but you
can do that and I also added on the
right side the security for first for
premature attacks and as you can see
while there are some number which are
lower than the security claims that are
so high that they are completely
impractical so that's where we stand
today for the old generation of hash
function and talk about the new one at
the end of the talk okay
so how we went about finding a sha-1
collision so the first thing is you need
a plan and so after we talked with Marc
in 2014 as I said the most the first
thing you have to do is choose carefully
what prefix you want because you're
going to compute a collision based of it
and you can't change it after the fact
so you need to be pretty sure of what
you're going to do the person who
created the prefix first was unsure
Bertini from our team who came up with a
very clever idea of combining PDF and
JPEG to actually be able to create a
very nice way to swap images and show
different things and so he created the
preferences and then during the
2015-2016 we ran the first phase of the
competition which was finding if you
remembers a near-collision block at that
time the Google Earth GPU infrastructure
was not yet ready to send that kind of
computation so instead of trying to test
something which is not quite ready for
production I opted out to use CPU so we
use about 300,000 CPU for about eight
months to be able to compute a
near-collision then so the 16 was the
most exciting year we had to develop the
full attack so we got near-collision
back and it was I think in February 2015
16 and from there many mark and Pierre
worked on to finding developing the full
attack so those who I will see the most
eventful part because we encounter
unforeseen difficulties and then in 2016
we leverage the GPU infrastructure of
Google to do the second phase of the
computation we had to use way less
resources because at that time GPR one
more efficient for crypt analysis if you
program them correctly and so we use
only a few thousand there all right so
what ang come about prefixes was this
idea that we're going to have a PDF
header which we contain a g-pack header
because PDF is like a Russian door it
has a lot of frame and you can embed
whatever format you want in it and the
jpg header would have a comment and we
will put the collision block at the
border of the length of the comment so
what we will do is the length of the
first file will go to one place and then
hopefully the cur is a second block
which is different will point to another
place which reverses fixed ability to
point to different part of the fixes so
at that point we have this ability to
swap one another so it has been tested
extensively and then our confidence will
work we use that as a perfect then I
worked to help mark two parties code to
Google infrastructure and the few
interesting engineering tidbits are one
we had to find the right trade-off
between the size of the batch of
computation so you have to change to
switch between failure and efficiency so
more you distribute your code the more
it cost the more if the longer you run
to more efficient it is but you run into
the risk of having fail CPU fail machine
reboot preemption whatever and whatnot
so we settled on to have like batch of
one hours so we would do one hour of
computations as a result one hour of
computation and repeat and repeat one
thing we did earlier on and I think that
was really the saving grace was to be
able to have code which runs stateless
so the original code has a way to
distribute
which composition you will do we try to
use random generator and try to
distribute the code without being able
to retire without synchronization first
ever the headache of having fell over
and the database of synchronization and
pushing things and the cap theorem so
stateless was way easier to distribute
and turn out and finally it was my first
large-scale computation as is so
I thought MapReduce was awesome and you
know you have this huge hammer is that
always going to be you map everything
and then you reduce the potential
solution seems a great idea it turned
out it's a whole board idea I ended up
with what we call strangling you can see
it on the graph basically most of the
computation happen and then we have a
few shard which is a part of the
competition which are not done and being
rerun and because you don't use the full
capacity of your job you are losing a
lot of time so it was really not
efficient for the second part of the
attack we moved to a client a factories
see a factory design pattern where we
have a producer and then we run a bunch
of job and they all distributed and
independent and you returned it was way
more efficient so we learned a lot
during this first phase and it's
influenced a lot how we did the second
one okay so in 2016
send an email to mark we found it here's
the blog was really excited we have our
first near-collision
we know it's going somewhere Marcella
give me a few days I'm going to look at
it make sure everything is fine okay and
then Mack come back to me like I think
we have a problem okay
what happened was the block we found
using the traditional approach we had in
mine didn't work out because it was over
data mined with meaning that we couldn't
find the person potential solution so we
couldn't find a way to resolve it to the
food collision it was ok we actually
decided to use novel tricking with mark
and Pierre spent months trying to figure
out novel way to actually set use a
solving to actually make it solvable but
the first few ways were a little bit
we were sweating a lot because we really
might have to redo everything or it
might be impossible so try that one
controls is difficulty which we believe
will happen to anyone trying to the
collision and the one mentioned them
before led us to believe that actually
no one ever reached the compression of
phase one because they will have had to
face the same problem anyway
no sure is too short they fixed it found
a good way to do the speed up using the
boomerang attack and so forth that's
what you have here and to tight box are
basically the extra step we did first
step
which is like finding this additional
condition and fixing the sort of ability
issue and we wrote the attack code
mostly care and New York in GPU and then
we're good to go to run the final
computation so final computation took
place in two GPUs and one of the
interesting property of GPU is you can't
do what we did with CPU we see view what
we do we'll do it with you end-to-end
and then come back into another and 2011
24 GPU because of the memory transfer
you can't really do that so clear and
mark come up with great idea of we're
going to event step by step so you
remember there's 80 steps what we do it
will generate our potential next step
like at least enough to fill out the GPU
buffer then compute all the step forward
and then when we have exhausted our pool
if we couldn't find anyone backtrack and
to would feel backtrack field backtrack
backtrack so reason what you want to do
this is because it helps to maximize the
use of the GPU memory and the
paralyzation while having to limit the
number of wiping the memory and filling
it out again you really want to do it up
sequentially and minimize the memory
transfers so we had one instructions and
multiple thread which was exactly what
we wanted to give you an idea of how the
complexity increase in shower this is a
graph with no Derrick logarithmic scales
and you can see that when you are step
fourteen you have about 50,000 potential
solution and then you go up and you
remember it blew up right after that so
you have a hundred million and then you
have ten million and you have a hundred
million and then you have 300 billion
and you have tens of trillions and then
you reach a point which is roughly
around except when is trees 22 23
whereas this is the maximum computation
cost and then it fairly goes down and
then you reach the last point which is
where basically you found a collision
right so the first the initial phase
because I associate solution to compute
CPU so large me middle sink in CPU and
then the last stage would be in CPU
alright so all that said and done as a
new attack would call shattered
we took about 110 years of GPO that's
how much she took way less as we
mentioned at the early in the early part
of the talk of the 12 million years you
would need for brute force so it was way
more efficient silly large computation
one of the largest we believe today and
we got our collision almost what
happened is then we sent the we with an
anaemic hey we found it yay we're
excited with Derek and then he wrote but
if you're later attack that doesn't work
what yes it doesn't work and then you
realize that we had a by big-endian
little-endian problem we were computing
one and it was explained in another
format so it took us like a day of like
crisis mode to figure that out and then
we told resolve and it was working and
then it was the first to PDF which had
the same shell one and everything was
fine but again this was like the second
time we were sweating bullets and I'm
like I'm done with that so here you have
it this is the two first PDF for this to
the world you maybe have some time down
shattered the tiles you want them where
you have to PDF is which have the same
sha-1 and yet have two different display
two different things and have two
distinct share 256 and one we really the
website we say we're in I today we're
going to be to release the code to
actually create those PDF yourself
remember you can swipe those two fixes
as much as you want so you can remove
any image and put anything okay in 90
days we give people fair notice you know
disclosure policy or that turned out two
days after the internet come up with a
better tool than our so that the one we
use for demo and I'll do a short demo
for you to show you how it's easy when
you have a collision to do with two
images so if you have a cat and we have
a tiger and we want to rumble and so
there are two PDF and as you can see in
a second they will have the same they
have distinct showers right there the
two basic things so now we're going to
do it we're going to use the collision
to combat both of them into a single PDF
and use the collision so you use the
code as I said from the internet
the link below and then if you look at
what happened and you see it's very fast
no both of them have the same sha-1 and
it will display easier Tigers as a cat
by omitting both of them and if you were
to look as a shot 256 well not the same
so that's basically how you can create
your own collision at home download the
code you can with yourself tricky is out
of the bag so now everyone can now
create to sing this is of course a fun
example of how you would do it you can
implement imagine nefarious purposes
attacks where you have let's say a Rand
contract and you sign something which
says you're going to pay $1,000 and then
low and behold the other one that you
have to pay $10,000 so basically having
using sha-1 for for any kind of
integrity is now kind of at least for
PDF it can the point less because you
can't trust it and so it defeat so how
did it work behind the scenes were just
to give you like a clean outline
actually this is something which was
done by actor Martin he did that a few
days after we released the attack he was
kind enough to give us permission to
reuse his diagram that's the best one we
come up with what better than the one I
did so I'm going to use this one so in
the right on the left side you see this
is a fixed part this is our chosen
perfect and the collision block and the
green part is the part you can swap so
on the top as I mentioned we have the
PDF headers and then below it we have
the g-pack header and then you have a
g-pack comment right and g-pack come and
have a lens and the lens is at the
border of the collision block right so
obviously in one file it is 73 on the
other file it is 170 F and obviously
different blokland for comment mean we
have distinct relized
what is displaying both fine while they
have the same suffixes they are
synchronized and so in one case you
would have a comment and the next image
will show way lower into the content in
the other case it will show the first
images so that's how we embed two images
you wanna see that's how the trick works
so I hope this illustrates a little bit
better
what is happening behind the scene
anymore how you can use one collision
and use it to create many many colliding
PDFs yeah
JPEG commands Oh sighing I didn't
mention okay
both collision world so what happened
next well first thing the most important
thing for us was and there's a reason
why we search what's really important to
do a collision is Mozilla I decided to
give up on sha-1 thanks to them they
give up a few days right after the
announcement of the collision and the
deprecated ahead of schedule that was
really important it was ruined more that
we might extend the lifetime of sha-1
and i think that was the final nail on
the coffin so that's a great outcome we
wanted to have microsoft did fellow
follow in May and was again crediting us
into the advisory for pushing it further
so we glad that no every browser in the
world did not you share one certificate
and that seems that's a good thing for
the world so that was the main thing we
wanted to achieve so that's great with a
click I don't know what happened but
someone placed a very large bet about 24
hours before we released the attack
publicly saying yes sha-1 will be broke
in 2017 so the guy cashed out I think
something like getting like eight or
nine bitcoins so basically the guy
someone found it out mark in the early
morning of the announcement struggle
with eternam but was able to cash out a
bug bounty so mark was able to cash out
the bounty we had for the sha-1
collision
not a lot of Bitcoin but still nice for
him to get it this is the unforeseen
consequences I was mentioning to someone
who is working web she decided to test
if WebKit would be not bring about the
collision attack because WebKit you
shall one so he submitted a unit test to
the SVN of WebKit and then it was gone
elect literally destroy his entire
WebKit as we inject Ori for eight hours
no more WebKit you everyone was freaked
out it turned out it was a huge bug into
SVN which actually do not work well with
sha-1 collision its usual one for
integrity was never meant
to withstand collision so you completely
collapsed and then Apache reacted very
quickly and say hey please please past
patch and do not be careful because you
might destroy your your represent Ori if
you if you do that you can recover it
but it's way more to use and no more
common because everything is completely
messed up so that was this watershed
consequences I was talking I read it
earlier is this is the one window of
there may be a ton of legacy software
especially in corporations that we don't
know of where collision might figure
weird but that we are not aware of so I
bring up the question of what do you do
right I mean the collision are in the
wild and maybe you have a legacy
software so what did well happened to
get I turned out that despite people
wanting Linda Stovall that you should
not use a one in 2005 me like no I'm
going to use it and so now they are
slowly transitioning it out of kit but
it's really complicated because it's
really backed into the system and they
have a lot of assumption around it so
what do you do you use something which
we call contour crypt analysis so
remember I told you is the way we
compute a collision is very specific
with differential path so there are
places where is different and you can
see it on the screen cancel out and they
are very very noticeable there is also
other clue so it turns out that mark
developed a very nice technique where
you can actually with a single file test
is for the collision or not and it's a
little bit expensive about two three
times more expensive than normal shot
one but it will tell you if there is a
collision so you can use that to test
for collision and it has very very
little false beauty basics like zero
point zero zero zero zero zero zero zero
one so you can use it and basically
believe in it and it works both for
sha-1 and md5
so that's something that you can deploy
if you are still using sha-1 anywhere
that what we did and that's what also
get update so a Googler actually shown
patch said jig it to make sure that when
you submit something to get if there is
a collision it will reject to commit and
a few in much get up the design silence
it in the blog post they start to use
max events code to actually detect
collision and say if you are trying to
call to me something which are the
collision fighting it we're going to
reject it to github what's protected
it was patched and then in 2002 twelve
did also now include crypt analysis as
well
they made recently and as a patch to
improve it so now we do have
cryptanalyst contact with and is also
backed into gate which is how we deal
with legacy software last thing I wanted
to mention is we also took the decision
to scan an incoming document before
Gmail and drive early on because we
don't know what our clients use some
might use all client which might read
your blog we don't know of so better
safe than sorry so if you were to try to
send any collisions who grew so Gmail
you would see the warning is that you
see here and as I said the reason why
you might want to scan for collision as
well is it chronically gets the client
software it does like as the NV 30 was
brought to its knee
colliding Documenta might be used for
nefarious purposes like I told you the
rent example might be other one like
contract or instruction or password or
whatever you want and black swan which
is unforeseen consequences that we don't
know of so rather than to face them or
rather pay the price and cannot how much
will pay we have to set on 1 billion
document this is a sample we tested with
and without it it's about 4.4 percent
overhead for us we still believe it's
well worth it to scan every incoming PDF
document to protect our users so I wish
on clearly encourage you to do the same
if you have you do with document and you
showing someone so whether it live as
for the future well future looks great
we have three different type of the hash
function that we believe would be very
useful we have set 256 which is a
natural replacement of share one then we
have char tree which have been a
completely different form of function
which is really good it's use a Spanish
construction so very different from this
institute so we have no diversity and we
also have Blake which is another hash
function very fast and back to so we
have a lot of diversity and of good
option to choose from so basically we
have all the tool to mitigate the next
collision when it will happen and so we
are in a very good place
so it's a very transition period but the
future looks at me
and to take away for you sure when is
that please do not use shy one please if
you use cylinder six defender who see
you shall want a certificate please tell
him to stop do that
contact Krypton Aries is a very
interesting tool I don't know if you
heard about it before but that's very
something you should add your detection
if you are dealing with document and
integrity and stuff like this and
finally the future looks great we have a
lot of hash diversity a lot of good
construction and that's where having
good funding for academia who do
cryptographic research is important
because they are working ahead of the
curve and when we need new algorithm
they are here for us to use so that's
why cryptographic research is more
important now than ever we can't rely on
current standard we already need to
think about new standard what will
happen with post quantum world and so
forth so we are ahead of the curve and
because cryptographic is so cryptography
so important for security around the
world and the internet in particular so
I take a few questions you have time for
one or two question also if you are here
today we our team have two more talk I'm
crazy to come and see us today we have
tracking run somewhere and to end at
5:00 and tomorrow we have talked about
attacking encrypted USB so if your I I
would love to see you there as well and
with that I would take some question
thank you very much
[Music]