hi thanks for being here today I really
appreciate it
I'd like to start off thinking some my
colleagues that long term for supporting
me also some shoutouts to the rpi set
crew I see them soon over there thanks
for coming and thanks to Apple for
fixing the bugs reported so my name is
Alex or dojo I've been working security
quite a while now and I really got
started playing a lot of CTFs I'm a
recovering addict but the recovery isn't
going so well since we qualified again
this year and unfortunately I might play
a little bit so please distract me
you'll be good for me get some sunshine
and I I really enjoy CTF because you get
a lot of hands-on experience so it's you
know one thing to learn about it in
class but it's another thing to go and
actually try to write an exploit and
usually you learn a lot just failing and
making a lot of mistakes and another
thing that I love about blackhat is
we're here to celebrate a lot of
mistakes so defense is hard and if you
only work in office sometimes you don't
see that but I I do love a good bug and
that's what this talk is about so what
is iCloud keychain iCloud keychain is
secret syncing and recovery in the cloud
that's kind of hard to pull off if you
think about it because you're talking
about some very sensitive material going
on servers that are maybe not even in
control of your own company because when
you talk about the cloud nowadays many
of the large companies they want
redundancy so they go to different
providers so how do how do you exchange
secrets on other people's machines which
is what iCloud keychain is doing so I
call keychain was designed to be highly
secure very strong and 10 cryptography
and we'll go more into detail about what
that means what is m10 cryptography and
is it too strong nowadays according to
some law enforcement and it's designed
to be resilient even if our server is
backdoored or there's a rogue employee
or someone manages to break in and it's
also resilient when someone has their
iCloud password compromised back in 2016
we saw something like 300 million
credentials get
and all the hacks were in in 2016
they're happening in like 2012-2013 with
like linkedin myspace tumblr and 2016
they surfaced to the public so the
average teenager all of a sudden had
access to 300 million passwords some of
which would presumably work with iCloud
but keychain was designed to be strong
even if someone has your iCloud password
because you need an additional device or
an additional password besides that to
actually get in and we found some bugs
that were gonna celebrate here today
there are now fixed and we're gonna talk
about keychain sync in detail there is a
white paper there's a talk last year at
blackhat that covered some of it but the
details of the protocol even though the
code is open source are not really well
known so in this talk we talked a little
bit about them and tried to bring light
to how some of the works to the best of
our abilities and this is not the first
presentation about iCloud keychain there
have been some in the past in 2014 andre
blanco focused on the recovery mechanism
for a forensics company doing data
recovery there's also talk last year i'd
say it provides a great overview of how
keychain works and then earlier this
year
elcome soft also focusing on data
recovery did their presentation on
whether or not to factor auth accounts
or secure or not with iCloud keychain
and the security guide is a great
reference as well when looking at at
crypto bugs there's a quote that always
inspires me with a nice picture of
Robert Moore senior and his beard so
Robert Morris senior is the father of
Robert Morris jr. who wrote the Morris
warmth and he was a Crypt analyst at one
point or another and I don't know too
much about all he did but I hear is
pretty good at it and he says that you
know when you're when you're talking
about signals and information you should
really assume that your adversary will
not stop at any limits so you should
really go all out and defend defend
something against all feasible threats
on you're building a system and when
you're talking about end time crypto
you're kind of talking about that sort
of system where you're really trying to
defend against a lot of different
threats
and iCloud Katrien has two major
features associated with it part of it
is the recovery so if you lose all of
your phones your tablet's your computer
you can still get your iCloud keychain
data back so that's what the recovery is
about and then there's the syncing which
is keeping all the secrets synchronized
across all of your devices so they're
available so you can use them painlessly
and then you can have better passwords
that are more secure without having to
remember them so the recovery is based
on an HSN escrow system the HSM is there
to prevent brute-force attacks and kind
of people accessing the data too much
trying to pull off different schemes
there's also SMS verification it seems
there have been some problems in general
with SMS now that two-factor is becoming
very popular attackers I've been looking
at some mess but it's still a good
additional measure because it increases
the cost of an attack and then in
addition to that ID password forgetting
- keychain sync there there can be an
additional password that's needed for
recovery so when you setup there's
something called an iCloud security code
that's separate from your Apple ID and
separate from your device passcode
however if you have to factor off there
is a device passcode and this is what
the hell comes off talk back in the box
went into depth about and then you think
okay well I have these additional
passwords but I'm still sending them to
Apple right so how secure can that be
well it's actually not so bad because
you do something known as SRP which uses
some hashing and some exponentiation so
that you don't actually reveal your
password to those back-end services you
kind of do a proof of work that you know
the right password and then you'll get
access to something that you can be good
locally so it's pretty good recovery
those not will we'll be focusing on
we're mostly going to be focusing on the
syncing feature so syncing all of your
secrets to all your devices using the
cloud also known as someone else's
computer and doing it with end-to-end
encryption so it doesn't matter whether
it's China Telecom
or Amazon or Google cloud or whoever is
hosting because they're just serving as
a conduit
they shouldn't have they won't have
access to that data unless they have
access to your devices as well and it's
about building up a circle of trust and
your devices I'm going to talk about the
protocol that's there and what that
looks like and I think part of thinking
is also about how does someone join the
circle of trust and what does that
approval look like and we'll talk about
that and they're there to sort of
protocols involved so the circle thing
it's not like a real protocol that's
documented but if you read the
documentation and the code it's it's
building blocks for doing this kind of
stuff so secure objects Inc circle I'll
just call it circle SOS circle I'm gonna
call it a protocol maybe it's not a
protocol but for our purposes we'll be
and then there's a are anyone here heard
of OTR before off the record do you guys
know is an iCloud keychain sync so this
wasn't very well document in the white
paper
there's no occurrences of OTR and we
reached out to in Goldberg and and I
think he was quite happy to see who's
there but he also didn't know is there
so it's open source code but as far as
we know we're the first ones talking
about this so the protocols still a
little bit under explored I would say
for researchers and let's talk about the
circle part so somewhere in the cloud
there's a blob of data that holds
signatures from all the different
devices this is a science thinking
circle and devices also get a local copy
and that's that's a circle of trust that
we're talking about and the protocols
about how people can join the circle you
can have an approving device approve and
add you in or you can also join it if
you have that iCloud security code or if
you have to factor auth a device
passcode so it's also about how that
works and the math that's involved for
the signatures here is a 256-bit ECDSA
on sec t 256 r1 so I'm not particularly
could talk for I'm more of a Code
Breaker but to understand what this
curve is it's a nist curve
bitcoin uses sac P 256 K 1 and SEC P 256
R 1 is the one DJ Bernstein doesn't like
so much but
fundamental to the security the internet
it's using TLS and lots of other places
so it's a very very standard algorithm
and how does circle work how does
somebody join a circle so when someone
first sets up an iCloud account they
turn this on a circle is created and
what's in the circle so you have pure
information that has information like
the computer name the version of the
protocol that device uses and an
identity key the public key the private
key stays on the device and then there's
a signature for this pure info and then
they create the circle and the circle is
signed not only with the identity key
but also the users current iCloud
password now if a second device wants to
join they make a request to join the
circle and it includes the identity key
of the new device and it's also signed
with that Apple ID password the first
device will get a notification and the
user will manually approve it and then
they'll update the circle and say okay
the second device is now also part of
the circle and it will be signed and
when device is joined like this there's
some automatic counter signing that can
happen so the other devices if they see
that up here that they already trust has
signed something they will automatically
sign it as well without having to do
another user notification to each device
because that would be a nightmare all
right and because all the different
devices countersign when a new device
joins any of the devices that are in the
circle can approve the new device and
this all on the whitepaper
kind of scribes how it works it's pretty
straightforward
but there are some things to think about
for usability so what would happen if
you lost all of your devices while
you're traveling so if you go to the
recovery great you have your passwords
but now the new device wouldn't
necessarily have a way to join the
circle because you don't have an
approving device to go and update that
so it seems like kind of a tricky thing
from usability and the full details of
these aren't really document in the
white paper and we're gonna discuss this
a little bit about kind of how it looks
like and how it works excuse me
so there let's take a step back and talk
about some of the different passwords
that are involved because a little
confusing there's the Apple ID password
there's device passcode there's the SMS
code and there's this iCloud security
code so if you have a default account
that doesn't have two factor
authentication type a swerd entered on
both devices you can also join the
circle without an approving device if
you also have the SMS code and iCloud
security code so it is possible to join
on a new phone without device approval
and then if you have to factor off the
difference there is that the device
passcode will be used instead the iCloud
security code and then if somebody
didn't set an iCloud security code in
the first case they wouldn't have a way
to join this way and the interesting
thing is that the circle is not reset
when this happens meaning that the
existing devices aren't booted off when
you join in this way but from what we've
described there's this identity key so
do the new devices have it and if you
look at the details the identity keys
are only on those devices they're
setting in a keychain protection class
that never leaves and they won't be in
the escrow either because this class is
not synced up to iCloud backup so the
new devices wouldn't get it so we
actually have another peer that's in
there when the circle is first
established there is also an iCloud
identity key that is created and in the
code this is called a hidden and peer
and is created with some different
attributes that can be synchronized into
the iCloud keychain so these are
available from the escrow and it's this
cloud identity that can be used to go
ahead and join the circle and it's kind
of interesting to see this there because
it's not all document and this is what
the updated circle protocol looks like
when Alice first set up that circle
there's also this cloud identity that's
also in there and it can also sign the
search
and this is well that's new devices join
the circles without booting off to the
other ones and when you're looking at
protocols like this when you see things
that are not documented it's usually a
good thing to check out so so far this
seems pretty okay because even if this
was an iCloud backups those key bags are
still wrapped with the UID key for the
device so someone on an iCloud server
wouldn't be able to get to this and the
other thing is that escrow itself you
can't get that unless you bypass some
other mechanisms so it's pretty ok and
that was basically circle and the second
part of this is off the record which is
used for rent and encryption and it's
got forward secrecy so that if someone
has a key at one point in time they
won't necessarily be able to get the
plaintext of previous communications as
well as deniability which is something
that might be useful for a chat but not
necessarily critical for keychain
syncing and it works with diffie-hellman
key exchange
that's how OTR sets up a secure Channel
and then peers can verify each other as
part of the protocol and the encryption
over that secure channel is done with
AES and counter mode and OTR uses
rotating keys so in the context of where
does this communication actually happen
it happens over iCloud services so
there's a key value store as well as
directory services or IDs that's some of
the stuff used an iMessage in other
places and the first layer of security
here is you have TLS so it's already
encrypted from the get-go but if it was
only TLS then anybody on the receiving
end would get plaintext access to those
communications and it's really the
intent encryption that allows Apple to
make claims that it cannot be decrypted
by Apple or other devices that are not
part of the syncing circle so here's
kind of a pie in the sky view of how the
OTR key exchange works there's a hash
commitment that gets sent out by the
initiator and this prevents some
malleability attacks I actually did some
research on telegram where they don't do
something like this and it's
possible to weaken the protocol so Oki
tries to defend against those kinds of
attacks and then they set up a duty
Hellman key exchange and once they set
up that secure channel then the Pierce
sent some packets that they can verify
that they know each other and the peers
verify each other with those identity
keys that are in that circle and once
they've done this they have the secure
Channel now they can start exchanging
secrets and they can exchange pass code
they can exchange password material so
iCloud keychain has Wi-Fi passwords
credit card numbers that kind of stuff
and one thing about OTR a long-standing
features they really want group chats so
some of the new protocols out there like
signal they have group chat support for
encryption Oh char doesn't have that
it's peer to peer direct one period
talks to no there's no shared key across
all the devices
so when iCloud keychain gets set up all
of your devices actually have a pairwise
communication to one another so
performance wise that's not great but
when it comes to sharing passwords it's
more than okay
and Apple States some pretty strong
security goals that they have for iCloud
keychain they want to protect the
passwords even when an iCloud account is
compromised so if the password gets
leaked reused someone had a weak one
shouldn't matter their their credit card
info should still be secure they want to
keep it secure even if somebody manages
to break into the iCloud server which is
pretty much impossible to do without
something like antenna cryptography and
also when third parties access user
accounts and this is from the white
paper and it's kind of a visual of the
different layers you had so the very
first layer you have is TLS then you
have the security of the iCloud servers
themselves not anybody can go and walk
into a datacenter and access that and
then the last thing I've defense is
really this end-to-end encryption that
they built up with circle and OTR and if
someone wanted to gain access that
plaintext password material they'd have
a few different paths so these are some
of them first one is just write a really
good exploit that gets you right into
the device
you have some kind of remote exploit
gets you into the kernel then you have
complete access to the security daemon
and passwords that do come down to that
you'd have access to that's supposed to
run something like a million dollars
today or at least that's how much that's
the eye pays for them and the second
path is if you want to just attack this
protocol you have a few different
options you you kind of have to be two
layers so the first layer is how do you
get access to the data that's in in the
iCloud services so the first thing you
could do is get some of these iCloud
password the second thing you could do
is compromise
iCloud services so rogue employee rogue
data center you know there it's the
cloud and the third one is if you had
access to TLS then you you'd basically
get access to that first layer but now
you still have the antenna encryption
that you got it fee so then you need
some kind of flaw in the OTR protocol or
the circle setup if you can somehow get
a device approved without a user
notification or maybe fish someone if it
comes down to that fishing usually
always works eventually but we we went
the OTR floor out in this
so we found a cryptographic failure in
OTR so it's a it's not the open-source
OTR that you would have if you go to
likely boat er this is a custom
implementation from Apple but it is open
source so you can check it out and we
found a flaw there and we also found a
memory corruption flaw and these were
slightly exacerbated because there's no
TLS key pinning so any of the CAS that
are trusted by an iPhone could have
potentially been abused for this attack
and the OTR failure was in the signature
verification so here we have some lines
of code from the vulnerable routine and
this is a routine sec verify signature
in mac if it returns successfully that
means that the signature checked out and
it's also established the secured
Channel correctly so
the key exchange and when they're
parsing some bytes off of the wire they
set the error code so usually just
reading bytes if the packets long enough
it'll succeed and if there's a failure
it's supposed to reset that error code
and say something went wrong we failed
to fail this key exchange but here you
have some error handling where they
didn't the code did not properly reset
the error code so this is very similar
to go to fail and when the go-to fail
flaw came out at that time
Disko lived in the same project so it's
kind of interesting that people who try
to detect that bug with static analysis
failed and essentially what you can do
is provide an invalid size field that
will shortcut the signature check and
it's pretty trivial to to trigger this
flaw so here's a 32 byte OTR packet that
will do it
you just encode a size field that
doesn't make sense and then you have
some data later with the actual key
material that you're setting up but
that's about it and it's a pretty
trivial bug and it would have loud and a
man-in-the-middle attack err that had
some kind of access to someone's a
keychain circle to start negotiating OTR
and what's kind of interesting is that
this attack could be pulled off silently
so with OTR uses ephemeral keys and the
user wouldn't wouldn't say necessarily
notification and because it's a logic
flaw it's highly reliable so sometimes
it's the simple bugs that are most
devastating and this really undermines
some of those goals if someone's iCloud
account and password was compromised or
somebody gained access to an iCloud
server they would have been potentially
able to pull off this attack and start
receiving Wi-Fi passwords credit card
numbers all this really interesting data
but of course there's still TLS that
they'd have to get through now there's a
actually a second flaw that that we
found and we and we
found this one first which is well led
to the other one there's an unbounded
stack allocation so we reported these
back in January but since then there's
been a really great and thorough
presentation or article by Qualis called
stack clash so if you don't understand
these flaws you should check that out
now basically the the code is threaded
so if you work with embedded systems you
know that you don't have so much stack
room and threaded code is it's kind of
the same deal so if you send a really
long ago gr packet that packet data
would start to overlap with an adjacent
thread stack so you could get program
counter control through that and this
could have been a potential sandbox
escape to route so this is a daemon that
lots of that applications communicate
with in one form or another you would
need some entitlements though for this
one so the remote path might be more
interesting because then however this is
a tricky tax point because there's a
race condition between the executing
thread and the writing thread hitting
the guard page so kind of a crappy bug
if you're in tax plate development so
wrapping up I think it's it's
fascinating it's awesome to see endtime
cryptography in a form that's also
usable for tons and tons of people
because the usability and intent
cryptography are actually I direct odd
one another it's about keeping people
out of data and what happens when when
you lose all your stuff how do you get
back to your data and so we we talked
about how keychains sync works some of
the inner details I hope you guys found
those interesting and we reviewed a
crypto failure I think something that
our industry needs to do is step up its
game when it comes to static analysis
and there are leaps and bounds there but
when it comes to go to fail I actually
have an open challenge the static
analysis companies go detect both these
bugs they're in the same project so goto
fail was go to fail repeated twice on
the line you can find out with grep but
can you do some Mantic analysis to
detect both of these so some researchers
have reached out to me
and we'll take a look - this should be
detectable there's also some crypto
testing talks by JP Emma song that would
have definitely detected this fall
another thing for app for Apple I don't
think the documentation is sufficient
here for researchers I think for an
average person the the details of the
math at use that's great but it's nice
to see it would be nice to see in depth
how the protocol actually works so some
companies out there are starting to
document their m10 crypto in great
detail it'd be great to see that for
iCloud keychain - and in particular I
think some of the two factors stuff
could use some more research where the
exact security properties there so
welcome soft alluded to some things but
they didn't go into great detail either
so that about wraps it up so thank you
and I'd like to take any questions you
guys may have
[Applause]