I'm Stephan Crandall welcome to Pima
whole bunch of words what we're really
talking about is a normally detection
new ways of doing it so I'm a PhD
student from Curtin University
where's Curtin University all the way
over where that arrow is pointing in
Perth Australia so it's been a bit of a
flight to get out here I'll put it that
way I work on network security detection
with my research team we've got from
Curtin University's Department computing
associate professor me hi les a rescue
and dr. Dukes on fan dr. seedings so and
from Oklahoma State University we have
professor Suresh kak now that I've
mentioned them I can go up we can get
into this so denial of service attacks
they suck they're very easy to use
they're very simple they're very
effective basically anyone can start
them these days you'll get something
like this in an email from your clients
they'll say help I can't access the
internet even though it's just their
website but I've worked in help desk so
so basically you know they're very very
easy these days social media lets people
coordinate form a certain are
distributed knowledge service attacks we
have botnets around you know it costs
the attack is basically nothing to
launch and it costs you a lot to deal
with especially when they are very
effective this only gets worse we have
the Internet of Things the the Internet
of Things to exponentially increase the
amount of devices attached to the
Internet over the next decade and into
the future and hope God God knows where
so basically these things we've been
seeing on particularly well secured so
we're expecting to see enormous
quantities of effectively
denial-of-service vectors entering the
market over the next decade so flood
based attacks will become exponentially
more powerful over that time an example
of where we're going was the Krebs and
security distributed denial-of-service
attack or we saw over 600 620 gigabits
per second of traffic which is which is
ridiculous completely ridiculous so it's
basically inevitable that this is going
to get much much worse over time and
it's gonna get much much more prevalent
as become
easier and easier for people to keep
leverage this kind of thing so what can
we do
can we install the firewall well no
because you're actually hosting the
things that are being attacked there
they're legitimately trying to use them
just abusing their use of them so we can
install intrusion detection system yeah
you know a signature based IDs can
detect attacks from botnets it knows
that you know it's the bad ip's out
there you don't want traffic coming from
them but you can spoof IP on the
internet so maybe maybe not and you can
make your traffic look like normal
traffic so the signature based system
can't really tell because again we're
not sending you know actual smart sort
of viruses worms or whatnot we're just
sending a lot of what looks like
legitimate traffic so you can pretend to
be whatever you want so why don't we
teach an AI to do you know our stuff for
us you know an anomaly based detection
IDs system you know what if we taught an
AI what normal looked like on our
network and then tell us when things go
wrong when things aren't normal anymore
you know AI pretty good at fitting this
sort of thing out you know problem
solved right not so much I mean they are
very effective I'm not here to poopoo a
normally based intersection systems
they're great but they do have their
issues they are big you know clunky sort
of pieces of software they can often
require a dedicated hardware through
your network they have training time you
need to have two you know one two weeks
of time where you actually have to sit
there and tell it okay learn this as
normal you have to make sure there's
nothing unusual going on during that
time because otherwise it will learn the
unusual as the new normal and then you
have to tune it right as the network use
case changes is the business you will be
working with your clients their use case
changes you have to change what normal
changes so you have to change what the
actually sees as normal so you have to
constantly retune and of course during
this process you're going to get a lot
of false positives um the other thing
specifically with denial of service
attacks is that you can detect a sudden
burst of traffic a sudden you know large
amount of legitimate users using your
website as an attack like say for
example you're working with a web host
that for some reason is hosting I don't
know steam
and the seat the steam sales start and
suddenly everyone visits the website now
an anomaly based intrusion detection
system might go that's a lot of traffic
a lot of legitimate looking traffic
showing up at once
it looks like an attack and that can
generate false positives which can lead
to alert fatigue which isn't
particularly good for your security
department we have a different solution
though we call it primer the probability
engine to identify malicious activity
so what comply Madhu well it's an
anomaly based detection system right so
pretty good it detects attacks within
microseconds of them starting it's
accurate doesn't have that problem where
if you send a whole bunch of
illegitimate traffic it confuses that
with an actual denial service attack it
knows the difference between them I uses
only metadata alright so you can
actually do this without having to
decrypt or do any sort of deep packet
inspection with the traffic you're
working with which is great for privacy
sort of things and it doesn't require
learning before it starts working so
it's basically plug-and-play how is that
possible how can I possibly know what
normal is before we get there well we
use these things called these are
numeric patterns called power law
probability distributions which I'm
liable to show them to power loss during
this talk which isn't mathematically
accurate so if you're a mathematician
out there I'm very very sorry so
parallel probability distributions power
loss they're these artifacts of natural
number distribution system a bell curve
shaped sort of thing if a process
generating numbers is statistically
natural then numbers that generated or
descriptive of it tend to feel fulfilled
these sorts of power law distributions
so power laws like this are very
interesting they show up in all sorts of
weird places there's some really good
videos as a resource video you should
definitely check out if you're
interested in this sort of thing so what
we have we've got like this is this is
the big granddaddy of them the Pareto
distribution
it was developed originally to explain
the distribution of wealth in Italy
basically it's also really talked about
it's the pressure principle the 80/20
principle 80% of the wealth resides in
20% of the holders you know 80% of the
attacks go to 20% your endpoints a even
of your hard drive failures come from
20% of the hard drives this shows up in
all sorts of weird places
now it's great it's very very generally
applicable what it is a continuous
distribution which means lots of
floating-point calculations and no one
no one likes floating-point calculations
they take two on so conveniently need to
have discrete distributions for example
zips law
zips law relates the popularity of
categories to the number of elements in
them and it's basic example in any given
book if we rank words by the amount of
times they appear the second most
popular word will appear about a half as
much as the first one and the third most
popular appears about a third as much as
the first 1/4 1/4 of the first and so on
and so forth this has been determined to
work with any book in any language ah
which is pretty cool it also works with
other things like city populations the
most popular cities do the same sort of
thing species distribution over a
certain area so you can be given area
check the numbers each type of species
game or movie popularity in a group of
people Twitter followers and so on and
so forth it goes on forever anytime you
can count a thing that is generated by a
natural statistical process
zips law comes into application and
we're not entirely sure why all we know
is that it does now the interesting
thing is this zips law is not being
followed by say a book that means it's
generally gibberish and it's not
gibberish as in random letters because
that does tend to follows its law it
means that there are real words they're
just arranged in a way that is gibberish
so Benford's law
this one's really great benefits law
actually doesn't change for numbers
right so it's interested in numbers not
categories numbers generated by a
natural process that are large enough so
they have to be the ability to be
several as a package in size that means
they have to be several orders of
magnitude in size so the probability
that the first digit of that number that
comes out of that process is 1 is about
30% all right not one online as it
expects from a completely flatly random
sort of process if you did this with say
a random a pseudo-random number
generator you'd expect to see one online
for each of those digits you don't see
that in natural situations the
distribution is completely static
regardless of which situation you apply
it to you
is always going to be the same numbers
you can actually hard code the thing
which is really really cool
so really great for computation for our
purposes now it has been used for
detection of anomalies before it's
actually been used in fraud detection in
finances in the banking sector for years
because financial transactions are a
natural process and financial
transactions follow Benford's law so
when it's not you know that someone's
done something a bit shifty with their
finances so you can detect fraud that
way
so why is this interesting well it turns
out that network traffic is a natural
process for whatever reason somehow
numbers extracted from and descriptive
of network traffic follow these power
law distributions specifically you know
whole packet lengths follows Zips law
the time between packet arrivals into
arrival time follows Benford's law now
interestingly both of those things that
I just mentioned can be ripped out from
packet headers so you don't need
anything more than that you can you can
just turn on TCP dump and away you go
when a denial of service attack happens
as we found out the network stops being
natural and you end up with something
like this this is for a test network
where we had multiple users actively
using the network and one user who was
trying to stop them so that was pretty
fun um there are there are ten distinct
do s attacks here each one starting and
then stopping before the next one mostly
we did that because we didn't want to
break the network all the capturing data
off it you know denial of service
attacks that came pretty damaging now
these data points each data point on
these graphs actually shows up every few
microseconds so it's very very fast this
system can actually determine when an
attack has started and stopped almost as
it happens and the reason why is is this
the top graph here is normal traffic
what you'd expect to see normally it's
not perfect but it's fairly close and
the bottom is a flood denial of service
attack all right denial of service
attacks fundamentally change how your
network works and change the process
that's generating the traffic right this
is incredibly difficult to fool if you
want to do this properly if you want to
hide this you have to regenerate the
original distribution
and that makes it basically impossible
to do without breaking your attack now
explanation of why there's an example
back home in Australia the march of the
red crabs on Christmas Island each year
the red crabs on Christmas Island March
across the island to the ocean to breed
right there land dwelling crab species
there's thousands and thousands and
thousands of them power laws apply to
species over a certain area so when the
march of the crabs happens you end up
with zips law being broken in this case
there are far too many crabs in a small
area it Oh completely overwhelms the
distribution and breaks up in order for
you to return the power laws back to
them back to working again you'd have to
spread out the crabs so far apart that
they'd basically be where you'd expect
them to be and at that point are the
crabs really having their year-long mark
they that once a near March you know are
they really is there really an event
going on anymore cuz this sort of where
they would usually be at any other time
of the year so that's that's really
what's going on is that breaking power
laws is fundamental to both the march of
the red crabs and do s ddos attacks all
right it is a feature of those attacks
so you can't do the attack very easily
anyway it's it's extremely difficult
without breaking these laws even if you
time your attacks properly you're still
interacting with all with a just salt of
all other traffic on that network so
it's incredibly difficult to manage to
perform this attack without breaking
these laws so the fact that this is
something you can hard code and then
chuck a static threshold on makes this
process really really powerful for what
you have to do but wait there's more
we can do things we can use these things
as an interest detection system in
general power law is great at telling
when a process is altered all right so
the tax altar a network that means we
can detect them what we have seen in our
research is that nmap and brute force
style overflow attacks can be detected
our example is an ng INX buffer overflow
attack we could detect that but we're
doing it very crudely using thresholds
you could make this a lot smarter by
strapping traditional detection
techniques on top of it so you could
build say a signature based detection
system because again
you don't have to now tell it what
normal looks like you know what normal
for any given Network looks like you
just have to tell it what each attack
looks like different to the normal
distribution that you're looking at so
you could just build signatures for your
anomaly detection system so you now have
an anomaly detection system sort of
power level with signature based
detection system deployment which is
pretty cool
speaking of detecting altered processes
though users are a natural process
because they're human right language is
a natural process finance is a natural
process humans just do things naturally
where natural or from the natural world
so you can create unique profiles of
users based on error from power laws not
necessarily that they follow the power
laws but that their process is unique in
what the error from the power laws is so
when the user changes that profile
you've generated changes as well because
now you've got a different process
generating information we've seen this
done in other research with keypress
latency timing so the time between each
key press that follows its law so you
can actually check one when a human is
not using a computer and also when a
human you know when each guinea any
given human is actually using a computer
it also works with Benford's law even
though benfits law does not come
anywhere near with complying with that
distribution it doesn't follow Benford's
law at all but the error from that can
be used to determine when a user has
changed now this can be this this is
configurable to be extended to anything
user has access to so command usage
network usage I mean you know if a human
is interacting with that it's more
likely than not going to be affected by
natural processes and even if it's not
again because the human is the process
generating it you can detect when that
process changes so you can combine this
with other analysis to you know start
giving you an idea of how an attack is
living through your network so you can
sort of say are this users been changed
I know this machine's been breached so I
know which account they got onto where
you know this sort of thing going on and
again this is minimal setup minimal
resource usage and it's fast so how do
you use any of this well pilot consists
really of some power law based analysis
tools plug in to a decision system that
can then take actions
so like a normal idea so I PS right well
no the senses can be really really
lightweight so for example in our
prototype we've actually got TCP dump as
one of our sensors so you can basically
run it on the same machine as the
decision mechanism all we need at the
metadata from the packets all we need is
packet headers so we it's really really
lightweight and fast so the detection
mechanism can just consist of a law that
is hard-coded with a threshold that is
hard-coded so it's it doesn't it's all
integer math so it's really really fast
and lightweight um the whole thing can
be run on a household router if you need
to now obviously that's going to get
overwhelmed by any attack you throw at
it because it's a household route and
doesn't have very much you know
throughput but the point is you can run
this on really really small systems and
scale it up to be a very very low
footprint on a really really wide scaled
system so how can you actually use this
well the first thing you want to do is
you want to find some metadata when I
find some data you can use out now in
terms of research we don't know where
this all goes we don't know how much or
what things like a complete listing of
all things that apply to these laws so
experimentation is really handy here but
we do know that network traffic and
users are natural processes so if you
find something that's related to them
you're likely on the right route zips
laws really easy to find stuff for look
for groups and categories an example is
that we haven't talked about yet is a
TCP flags and on the amount of sin our
packets the amount of act packets the
amount of Finn packets that sort of
thing so benefits needs numbers right
and then you have a sufficient length so
look for things that can be many digits
long but I relate it to these these
numbers they're generated be aware that
sometimes zips and benefits can converge
and you can actually use the same data
on both laws so don't think that just
because you have one you can't use
another this is actually possible to you
know cross pollinate the next thing you
do is you need to create analysis
windows now statistical analysis needs
batches of data to work with so you had
a group packets or group events together
in order to do statistical analysis on
them you can't just look at one at a
time so you know you can make them
really big you can detect really slow
sort of long-term events happening in
that case but your sensitivity does
decrease in that case
if you make them small the insensitivity
does to go up but you start losing your
big events and if you go too small you
start having breakdown your statistical
analysis anyway so it's okay to go big
you've got to be careful with going too
small in research the best size we can
tell is about 1,000 events or a thousand
packets each but that's really based on
and some guesses a sensitivity analysis
so really again experimentation with
your specific usage is a good idea so
then you analyze you Windows respective
power laws you want to do something like
a goodness of fit test this is really it
sounds more complicated than it is
really what you can do is you can take
the differences between each between
what you expect to see and what you've
currently got square all of those
differences and add them all together
and that number tells you how far away
you are from what you're supposed to be
on it's really really simple very very
fast so then you pump those numbers into
a decision mechanism and that can be a
threshold a single number that if you go
above something Bad's happening that can
be a signature based system that can
even be a neural network you've thrown
together so sorry so then then you want
to you know then then you can also have
that do things like a learning star for
taking direct measures or changing
firewall settings or you know so what
have you so a small example you have PI
running on a gateway it looks at the
inter arrival times on Benford's law so
it grabs packets checks how far apart
they were checks that against Benford's
law it's got a hard-coded law in there
it's got a hard-coded threshold anything
goes above it configures IP tables to
silently drop those packets you've now
got silent denial of service mitigation
on that gateway it doesn't require
anything else just it's like eight-way
the whole system's entirely encompassed
in it the second example we can go with
very very big the eye of Souren approach
you ever seen you like your scene you've
set it up really nicely a cavity gets
data from everywhere gather started from
users of computers to user data it has
Network data it has everything you take
that data metadata or data from that
that the scenes collecting put that into
primer and then pass primers analysis
back to the scene um you now have an
alert you can now have an alert and
panic and say this is bad
and now you actually have things like it
he actually now have a
Atika law of nature telling you hey
something's wrong so if you've got an
attack going on and primers telling you
it's bad it's probably something
actually going on but if you've got an
alert for denial of service attack and
pinus everything's good then it's likely
you know it's just a false alarm now
this will improve your assistants
ability to determine alert severity and
reduce alert fatigue
so in conclusion early days here I mean
we're not entirely sure where everything
what the entire space of this is it's
not been completely plumbed but what we
have seen so far as reasonably
impressive now this is a wild west of
anomaly detection right now if you're an
engine you want to strike gold here now
is the time to experiment these
solutions are coming and they will
affect how you defend your networks so
thank you very much hopefully you
enjoyed hearing about this brand new
method of anomaly detection and you're
reasonably interested if your engineer
and playing are with us yourselves any
questions um yes
there's microphones there there and
there I mean if you just yell it out to
mekin operator
um so power loss can be can be um the
nice thing about them is they're
generally applicable to any subset of
data you've got so if you go there's an
attack going on you can split up by
endpoints and you can go the attack is
going here and it's coming from here
can you determine between you know
spoofed addresses and non spoof the
dresses that way not really but at the
very least you can have something that
turns around and says I know it's this
IP address I'm gonna blacklist it for a
little bit yes
yep
I'm so determining difference for the
standard deviation from our attacks
they're so very from our mother what we
expect if it's built up slowly won't we
be able to own twee not be able to
detect it well that's the difference
this uses a solid law that never changes
it never has to that's always the same
right we don't have to shift an average
we didn't have to create an average we
know everything should be following
Benford's law for example so if they
start building up and attack slowly and
you know the start attacks slowly and
build it up build it up build it up at
some point it will reach a point where
it is so far from Benford's law that
we'll be able to go well as an attack
there now so unlike you know having to
build a you know distribution you know
and then work with it all the way
through you can just work with these
solid ones that we've got and you can
just work with that and it doesn't have
to change hi I have a question can I go
back to example one oh it sample one
shop and do you mind describing a bit
more what exactly use to apply seapower
Paulo okay cool so what we're doing is
we grab the you grab your packet headers
all right you'd really you don't have to
grab very much out of them you grab your
packet headers you figure out how far
apart each one the mass so how many
microseconds of the elapsed it's the
last one hit you take those specific
people or across all know it's across
everything this can work with any subset
of data right you can use flows you can
also just use just start data directly
out of their network interface it does
not matter it applies to everything so
you're measuring time between yep when
two packets arrive yeah and obviously
that time will decrease that number of
requires goes up yeah and what's the
difference between your approach to just
counting number of requests because if
you count number of requests and you're
looking at a you know normal traffic
hitting you
that number will still be high so you
can turn around say that that's actually
an attack in this case the difference is
that we are because we're using the
power laws the number of requests aren't
important it can be an asset number
request but because this split nicely
and following these power Wars even in a
small way we can determine that there's
actually a difference between legitimate
traffic and scripted you know attack
traffic
but when you have the increasing
requests your average time between two
packets will decrease which means it
will break yes but it doesn't decrease
in the same way than an attack does one
is inherently artificial okay thank you
thank you all for your interest in this
topic if we have additional questions
we'll be going to the speaker wrap room
and you can actually follow us there and
continue your questions in that room so
I encourage you to please follow us to
the speaker room if you have additional
questions from this point thank you very
much for coming
[Music]
[Applause]