we go
[Music]
so shoot the self-driving car drive over
the father or should it drive over the
daughter that's the classic question
regarding self-driving cars
artificial intelligence and the
technology future the head of us my name
is Miko I work for f-secure and since
this is the twentieth black hat the
organizers asked me to take a look at
the next 20 years we've seen pretty wild
rides over the last 20 years since 1997
technology has changed remarkably and as
we might guess it's going to continue
changing remarkably in the future as
well so I'm going to try to forecast
what's gonna happen over the next 20
years
although the title of the talk is not
2037 it's 2038 which is 21 years in the
future but we'll get to that in just a
moment and the good side about speaking
something 20 years in the future is that
I will be 60 66 years old
in 2038 so with any luck I'll still be
alive and we can all gather around to
blackhat 2038 and look at how wrong I
was about the forecasts because time
travels fast especially on the internet
time travels fast
let me give you an example 10 years ago
every single one of you had either a
Motorola or a Blackberry or a Nokia in
your pocket and today none of you have
any of those in your pocket and that's
just 10 years right 10 years that's not
a long time but on the internet it is a
long time so what happened ten years ago
well exactly pretty much exactly 10
years ago
Apple released iPhone and the world
changed and now the world is different
because of that in fact 10 years ago at
blackhat a 2007 I was speaking here
about mobile devices my talk title was
state of the cell phone malware in 2007
this is my actual slide from 10 years
ago look at the mad PowerPoint skills I
had remarkable
I'm so proud let me just show you one
slide on there did his statistics of the
mobile malware we had found by year 2007
and the platforms I list are Palm Pocket
PC from Microsoft Cindy and from Nokia
and Java I'm not mentioning Android I'm
not mentioning iPhone Android isn't out
yet ten years ago and I thought had just
been released so what's going to be the
future we'll look at different
categories first let's talk a little bit
about the future of computers so what's
the thing about 2038 well I guess most
of you know what's going to happen in
2038 if you don't I suggest you take
your phone from your pocket and try to
change today's date I mean to date in
your settings to 2039 for example and it
turns out you can't do it you can't do
it with your current iPhone or with your
current Android and this is the UNIX
epoch buck also known as the apocalypse
which really is a simple buck it's been
there for decades the buck is just a
limitation because originally the indica
only did the variable reserved for time
was said to be assigned 32-bit integer
and that counts seconds from first of
January 1970 which means we will run out
of beaks and it's going to happen in
2038 on January 19th at 3 a.m. in the
morning that's when stuff starts to
happen and of course this reminds us of
an incident which happened 17 years ago
y2k and y2k was a big deal those of you
who were working 17 years ago in
computing remember it was a big deal I
remember spending the
a new year 9th through the night on the
phone speaking to our offices and
partners around the world starting from
New Zealand that's day switch is over 2
to 1st of January 2002 check if
everything's working all right
and just to illustrate how paranoid
people were doing the turn of the
century you would actually buy magazines
which would tell you how to survive the
crises of y2k doomsday mm and then when
mm arrived in 1st of January every
newspaper was writing articles about how
this was all a dud and how nothing
happened and how we wasted all this
money and nothing happened
and that misses 2 points the first point
it misses is that there was so much work
done before y2k during the years and
months before why'd you cave fixing real
bugs the fact that most bugs were fixed
is actually a success story not a
failure because real bugs were found and
fixed I know this firsthand and then the
other thing they they missed was that
not all problems show themselves right
at the midnight for example in UK there
was a major problem with health care
systems because of y2k problem in
computers because of computers which
couldn't handle the year being four
digits because they were only saving two
digits and the particular problem the
worst problem they had in UK healthcare
was a problem regarding risk assessments
for bregman mothers regarding whether
their unborn baby had the Down syndrome
or not so they give wrong answers to
pregnant women on this and as a result
babies were aborted healthy babies were
aborted because of y2k which is a pretty
big deal of course this was only found
out months later so the news articles
written the first of January have no
idea about the problems that were found
and mark my words even though 2038 is
still way way in the future I will
guarantee that you
we will have problems we will have 2038
problems exactly in the same way as we
had y2k problems and there will be a
massive effort to try to fix everything
you think we have a lot of time to do it
I'll guarantee to you we will run out of
time so what about the future of the net
we know that everything's going online
if you look at numbers from Gardner
we'll see massive growth in not actually
in computers going online but in mobile
devices going online and especially IOT
devices going online one remarkable
figure is how many iPhones has Apple
sold over the last decade there's seven
and a half billion people on the planet
Apple has sold 1.1 billion iPhones over
the last 10 years 1.1 billion iPhones
and the thing that really fuels device
is going online is because of this guy
this is Gordon Moore father of the
Moore's law and typically when we speak
about Moore's law we emphasize how it
talks about how the computing power
doubles every 18 months or the amount of
transistors we can put on a chip doubles
every every 18 months but you can also
look at the other way around you can
also look at it that how what's gonna
happen to the price of existing
computing power the price of existing
computing power hubs every 18 months and
what that means is that the price for
that one chip that you have to add to
any appliance to turn it from a dump
appliance to a smart appliance the price
of that chip is going to be eventually
two cents or one cent or Hospice's
because it's so cheap that all vendors
will add them to all appliances because
they want to collect data so very
quickly we will see an era of IOT where
consumers have no idea that the device
they've bought is an IOT device it
doesn't look like an IOT device there's
no app there's no screen but it's still
online and it might not be going online
using Wi-Fi it might be going online
using LTE n or 5g or low rung or any of
these future wireless technology
that are already becoming a reality and
we are seeing smarter devices I am the
father of the HIPAA and law which is
that if something is described to you as
smart what you should hear is that it's
vulnerable right so you know smartphone
vulnerable phone SmartWatch will never
watch smart city it smart quick well you
get my point and smartness is not really
a property reserved to humans alone
animals can be smart machines can be
smart
artificial smartness also known as
artificial intelligence if a great
example on how we keep moving the
goalposts in the 1970s when we were
building artificial intelligence one
goal both we set for ourselves is that
when computers are able to beat humans
in chess then we have artificial
intelligence then when it actually
happened a decade ago in May 1997 when
deep blue beat Kasparov in chess then we
finally decided that we'll actually no
that's not artificial intelligence
that's just you know a lot of computing
a lot of calculation power and we move
the goalposts and we will be moving the
goalposts in the future as well we might
never actually reach what everybody
would agree is real artificial
intelligence or artificial smartness the
deep-blue machine which beat Kasparov in
1997 the computing power of that machine
was 11 gigaflops the phone in your
pocket most likely has something like
700 gigawatts so 70 times the power of
deep low your phone is 70 times faster
than the computer which beat Kasparov
think about that and think about how
much more powerful our devices will be
in 20 years time because it is only
accelerating we've only seen the very
beginning and I believe that the
upcoming
machine learning and artificial
intelligence revolution will start from
self programming programs from programs
that are able to write programs and
that's not hard to do I've actually
written a program which wrote programs
already years ago the programs it wrote
really sucked but they did compile and
you could run them and you can you know
imagine that if you just keep on making
it better it gets closer and closer to
my level as a programmer and then one
day it's close enough that it can start
making better versions of itself and
then it will bypass me and then it will
skyrocket because it's going to make a
better version of itself which is going
to make a better version of itself
which is going to make a better version
of itself and we will end up with super
intelligent programmer which means that
every programmer on the planet is
immediately out of a job because we
don't need programmers anymore and this
could actually happen sounds crazy but
this plenty of research papers about
exactly these already out there and
there's like several startups already
selling self programming programs or
selling programs which will write other
programs they want another thing which
is changing right now is the future of
money now we all know about crypto
currencies things like Bitcoin or or at
the realm designed by Vitalik Putin
right here but I don't believe that
crypto currencies will kill banks I
think we will still have banks in 20
years we will not be needing banks to
move money we will be using blockchain
based technologies to move money now we
will still be needing banks for
investments or loans or things like that
the bags will lose a big part of their
business but right now as we have many
times seen cryptocurrencies are mostly
used to buy drugs on lime in tor hidden
services or to ask ransoms from ransom
trojan victims in fact they were
yesterday a great talk from Google
outlining the amount of revenue
Ransome trojan gangs make the combined
revenue of ransomware gangs right now is
over a million dollars a month
constantly a million dollars a month
every month is the profit made by
ransomware gangs and by the way that's
tax free so let's go back to this petia
fear
it's a Petya ransomware Trojan on an ATM
which I find interesting because
normally you go to ATM an ATM gives you
money in this case the ATM asks you
money right and we're seeing
cryptocurrency is being used in crimes
which have nothing to do with computers
we've already seen several cases of
real-world kidnapping where people are
kidnapped and the ransom is demanded in
Bitcoin and of course the reason why
bitcoin or Manero or z cash is being
used by criminals is that they believe
they can be found if they use online
currencies so why is it hard to find
criminals when they use online
currencies let's take a look at the
petia what Betty happened a month ago
exactly a month ago all the ransoms were
paid to this one single wallet and
around two weeks ago the orders of petia
started moving money away from that
world initially they moved it to six
months and then they started moving it
further from there let me just play this
to you you'll see how the money starts
going from one address to another
address from one wallet to another
wallet and very quickly you realize and
it's very hard to follow where the money
goes this is the basic problem in
monitoring blockchain based money
movements
and then we have many other problems to
worry about if we think about the future
of technology as a whole what we really
think about this future of security
right and one thing that's going to have
a major impact on our work over the next
20 years could be quantum computing now
quantum computing is a tough cookie to
crack we might not have a real useful
quantum computer in 2038 but we already
have prototypes IBM actually has a 17
qubit quantum computer available right
now this actually exists but to have
them work at the level where we would
actually start doing full-scale
simulations could actually be further
away than 20 years but one thing that
could happen is have enough functional
in quantum computers to start to factor
primes the quantum computers would be
well suited for factoring calculations
based on primes which means breaking
everything every encryption system based
on multiplying large primes with each
other most notably RSA and that's
important because almost all SSL
certificates are TSL certificates today
are on top of RSA so imagine one day
waking up and every single SSL
encryption system on the web is broken
no more sequence this could actually
happen and then we would have to recover
from that which we could do by going to
encryption systems which are not based
on multiplying large primes with each
other they do exist super single or
elliptic curve cryptography one or latus
based crypto so we could actually
recover from there another problem we
have to solve is the problem of securing
these IOT devices because clearly the
vendors are not going to fix this
problem by themselves and you cannot
secure your washing machine by
installing a none dividers so what can
we do and I actually believe we are
right now seeing the birth of a whole
new security product category security
home routers we actually have one
ourselves we call this F secure sense
the basic idea is that the devices you
can secure with software you secure from
the net
you create a separate new network in
your home for IOT devices then you
connect them all to this separate
Network and they are secured as well as
we can through the network and we've
already seen McAfee Symantec big
defender or some other vendors entering
or at least announcing that they will
enter this market this could be one of
the big shifts in security products in
the near future so what about the future
of conflict the worst examples of what
could happen we've seen in Ukraine but
obviously Petiot was one and two years
ago
the attack against the electricity grid
provider per capita table near ago is I
suppose the most famous one but if you
think about what could be done by
hacking systems when you in your
targeting the whole country turning off
power is really bad but it could be much
worse one thing that I worry about is
targeting consumer devices and making
them fail physically and when I mean
physically I mean actually for example
making them catch fire and this is
doable because our devices are
programmable at micro code level here's
a picture of a GPU Catching Fire just
purely based on software so you can
imagine a conflict when one party of the
conflict sets fire to every home in the
country that's at the other end of the
conflict
technically could be done and that's a
scary scenario if anything which brings
us to the future of war now wars today
are being fought with drones and drones
are still being controlled by human
beings most before I don't know
philosophical reasons they could
perfectly well apply themselves and we
already have our to fear artificial
intelligence being used in other kinds
of weapons as well can we turn on the
audio
baylin's and security system with ichi
[Music]
samsung's intelligence surveillance and
security system with the capability of
detecting and tracking as well as
suppression is designed to replace human
oriented gulfs overcoming their
limitations
they are designed to replace humans
overcoming their limitations and that's
made by Samson so Samson makes you know
they don't just make this place and
phones they actually make guns and tanks
as well which gets us to the project
which was underway already couple years
ago the energetically autonomous
tactical robot which is a battlefield
robot which is able to operate without
fuel it uses biomass as fuel and then it
takes you a while to figure out what
actually that means which takes us to
the perhaps the best press really is
done by a company ever company behind
these lot of press release where they
say we completely understand the
public's concerned about futuristic
robots feeding on the human population
but that is not our mission so machines
are getting smaller and if you want to
avoid one mistake is I'll give you an
advice whatever you do don't kick the
robots don't kick the robots because one
day the robots will be smart enough to
go to youtube to watch videos
and they will see this and they will be
angry
so shoot the car drive over the father
or the daughter well I don't know that
these are the problems these are the
questions that we have to find answers
for because we are the ones they'll have
to fix all this we who work in security
because our work is no longer to secure
computers because today everything runs
on computers your work is not to secure
computers your work is to secure the
society thank you for your work
[Music]