thank you everybody for attending this
talk it sort of quickly introduce myself
I'm a ruin vishwanadh I'm a faculty at
the University at Buffalo and most
recently I'm also faculty associate at
Harvard's berkland client where Bruce
Reiner is so looking forward to working
with him this year I want to give you a
little bit of a background of what I do
what I've been doing for the last decade
and a half of my life for for a while
now as an academic researcher my focus
was on how hackers terrorists cybertor
is called them what what you may affect
breaches and how they do this by
compromising people alright so and I've
been working in this area of technology
use technology adoption for close to
more than a decade put out a lot of
publications I don't want to bore you
with the list but there's a long list
which basically only the academic
community cared about so the longest
time my paradigm of working was to
actually create attacks and to study why
people fell for different kinds of
attacks be they social engineering
attacks be the different kinds of you
know spoofs and breaches and so on and
so forth my focus was on undoing these
attacks and studying why answering that
why rather than just showing that it can
be done like I said I spent a lot of my
time doing that and most of those work
was for the academic community and no
one really cared much about it outside
of that community then I like to say
came King John and what Kim did thanks
to Seth Warren's movie about him was you
know he decided to breach Sony Pictures
and suddenly thanks to that bridge there
was now a real visible outcome that
people started seeing there were jobs
people were losing their job
millions of dollars were being spent in
trying to you know remediate these
breaches and suddenly I was all over the
place started writing on CNN quite a bit
and at every point along this way I
started trying to tell people to stop
focusing on the breach and the salacious
gossip that was coming out and start
looking at what this really meant and
each breach
starting with Sony Pictures followed by
Ashley Madison followed by Target
followed by OPM followed by
infrastructure attacks they kept getting
bigger and bigger and bigger and I kept
writing about this and for a long time I
was the only one trying to build
attention to how these breaches were
happening let alone saying hey you know
we got a problem here and the problem is
we gotta start studying these users and
understand how these guys are getting
into these networks let's not look at
the outcome alone let's look at the how
right and we had the DNC hack we have
and this seems to be an ongoing process
that is never ending with all of these
one of the common threads that was
weaving through this was spear fishing
and spear fishing is something I'm going
to talk about today although my research
looks at other types of breaches as well
but spear fishing was starting to get
everywhere it was kind of so common that
almost three-quarters of all breaches
were using this particular vector so
this became the common the most favorite
vector out there when it came to
affecting breaches when it came to
getting a foothold into a network and
these guys were hitting every industry
you know thanks to thanks to people like
King John Putin you know every hacker
out there every hacktivist out there
breaches were everywhere in a we thought
education was not getting breached by
2016-2017 education was getting hit
every industry was starting to get hit
with spear phishing attacks and what you
constantly saw was that the attacks were
getting more and more consequential so
in Sony Pictures
you had the leak of emails in target
that was leaks of passwords and it kept
getting bigger and bigger and bigger and
every time when you looked at the cost
of remediation it was keeping on going
up just to give you an example last
month in Buffalo New York where I am we
had a hospital that was hit by a
ransomware attack they refused to pay
the ransom
they spent fifteen million dollars in
remediating that attack which lasted for
all of like a month so the hospital
networks were all done for a month
people are losing their jobs things are
getting more consequential and arguably
you know even the ransomware attacks now
we still don't know exactly how these
came in but spear-phishing had a hand or
a bar or a something to do with the
passage of these attacks and if we just
track the scope of these attacks the
speed with which they've been happening
we had 300,000 infections in 150
countries in less than 48 hours and I
wrote a piece about this on CNN saying
this is the first global technological
pandemic that we had and this was a huge
deal because now the paradigm has
changed its global and if this were a
disease every one of us would be really
really more concerned about this than we
are and so everybody is on this though
right
everybody's perpetrating this you have
activist groups out there you have the
PLA working there you have the Russians
doing it you have local guys doing it
and all along the target is the user
right the employee in the organization
the end user out there they have become
the weakest links and we like to say
this all the time you're the weakest
link you're the weakest link so what do
we do about these weakest links I mean
that's what I'm going to talk about
today so in general there are
essentially three approaches that almost
every organization out there or
everybody out there who cares about this
all over the world and I I've worked
with people in the EU I've worked with
people in Asia in Singapore and there's
basically three approaches that it comes
down to and I call it the three C's the
first C is that is a technical approach
right
containment so we've tried to contain
people within their networks this is how
we deal with users the second thing is
where we try to constrain them right
this is also a technical approach right
we air-gap and and all of these are
relatively successful there's not one
answer here although everybody is
looking for that one answer these have
all been relatively successful the third
approach the one I'm going to talk about
and I just want to talk a little quick
about how successful these approaches
are people find workarounds okay this is
the constant problem with with with
users today everybody is constantly
trying to be one step above security
folks and when I talk to the security
folks they're constantly lamenting how
users are not paying attention not
listening trying to find a workaround
and I know of people who work in
government in insecurity who don't do
patch upgrades or don't upgrade their OS
on their mobile devices because their
children are watching Netflix on it and
they don't want to do an always upgrade
because it's gonna stop their ability to
watch so you know I collect these
stories and I talk about what challenges
out there when it comes to dealing with
users so the third approach which is
what I'm going to talk about today is a
very much training all right and there
is a an industry out there now work
close to a billion dollars of various
awareness education training programs
that they're constantly hitting people
with okay this is right now one of the
most popular perhaps the most proactive
approach out there when it comes to
dealing with the user the weakest link
in our networks and this is called the
convincing approach right we try to
convince users and broadly this approach
takes one of two forms the first form is
what is what I like to call as didactic
training that active training is where
you get the user in you focus your
energies on teaching them how to do
things better how to be safe how to use
you know email see if there are programs
out there companies out there that do
this this is a focused approach you
spend a day maybe a couple of days
trying to train them to get smart to be
like us to be you know cyber secure
resilient and all that stuff
some of this you know he's done on an
onboarding basis but this is an approach
that's out there quite a bit the second
approach is what is the embedded
training approach and what is this this
is where you know you're you're teaching
people by making them make mistakes and
I'm going to talk about both of these
approaches and I want to talk about what
we have seen when it came to the success
of these approaches because there really
isn't much data out there about how
successful each of these approaches are
other than the data coming from the
software the companies the training
companies that are putting them out so
you know I am very skeptical about that
data sometimes so the first one that
active training this is this is that
focused training that we spend a lot of
money doing when you look at the the
overall success some of the academic
research on this comes from we are on
2004 2005 so it's a little dated and one
of the first studies this is a very
highly
you know commonly cited study was done
at the US Army Institute at West Point
where basically what they did is they
took about 500 you is similar to Cadets
they trained them for about a day and
then they fished them a week later and
what they found is by the end of 24
hours they'd forgotten the training they
all fell for it all right 80 percent of
them fell for it very high numbers very
problematic now again this is 2004 2005
so my research team and I we decided to
replicate this we said let's do this but
let's do this right let's do this with
you know a different control group and
so we did this study we took a large
financial company in the United States
it's it's a pretty large company we took
about four hundred of the Templars who
are all from the same who are all
playing the same role in the
organization they're distributed across
the United States we took half of them
and we trained them using off-the-shelf
software that I will not name very
highly rated and then we fish them 4
weeks later and one of the things that
we did is we check to see that we didn't
fish them every day we fish them on
three non-consecutive days and there's a
lot of reasons for it some of the
literature some of the the data that we
see is it
on which day that attack comes in like
some for some reason people are just
more likely to click on things on a
Friday as against on a Monday because
it's the first day of the week and so on
and so forth so we wanted to get that
data right and we fished them on three
non-consecutive days and what you
quickly start seeing is when you look at
day one and I'm just going to show you
the day one data by the way this is the
attack we used this is a very simple
attack we just copied a Google Drive
page and just we sent that attack out
okay when we sent this attack out we
were looking at some of the data that's
out there
Verizon's data breach investigative
reports they talked about 50% of all
clicks happening within the first 24
hours or within the first hour actually
and when we looked at our data it
matched that so within the first 24
hours the vast majority of the clicks
were happening very very quickly people
would just it didn't matter it was a
Monday and they were just hitting it
this was very interesting because we had
two groups in this we had a group that
was highly trained and a group that was
not trained and so when we looked at the
people who were highly trained it was
absolutely identical with a little bit
of a difference it was statistically the
same in other words the training was not
really having the effect that people
think that it is right so we were saying
wait a minute didactic training doesn't
seem to really do it although when we
looked at the final data you know about
32% of the people who were trained
clicked 35% of the click people who were
not trained clicked okay so there was a
big 70% that didn't do anything that's
you know good news but 35% is a lot ok
35% is real bad news if you look at it
that way but the training effect was
marginal actually it was non significant
it didn't matter so in other words you
know do something train don't train
you're gonna get the same results at
least when it comes to didactic training
from what we looked at okay
so we said okay let's look at and better
training so what is it better training
this is the more popular training this
is what's out there today many companies
many of you probably work in companies
that actually do this right this is the
kind of training where you test people
right and you constantly test them and
then every time so basically you know
you have a person in the company who
does a phishing test right some of you
sitting here do that you've faced this
test you get this test you repeat this
test often enough at varying intervals
and then every time you click on a link
something pops up and says hey wait a
minute you just clicked on a link you
got finished right you're the weakest
like and here's why and we train you and
this is a this is an interesting
approach and and if you fall for the
fish once they train you in some
companies you fall repeatedly they've
warned you in some companies they
embarrass the hell out of you there's a
lot of different approaches to this
that's you know it's open territory what
you want to do to make this stick but
this is the approach that's more common
out there this is more popular most
companies buy into this I call it and
are trying to learn to drive and by
making mistakes so you know it'll try to
learn to drive throw a stop sign you
then show different signs this is like
trying to learn driving and you keep on
doing this till the person becomes an
expert driver right hopefully at some
point these persons are gonna have
accidents anymore that's the approach
it's a great approach I think it works
to some extent so how effective is this
mirror did a study this is from 2015
this is a commonly cited study and we
wanted to replicate it so in the mirror
study they did three trials so they took
three different attacks on about 1,500
people they found that 35 to 60 percent
of the people fell for the attack
regardless of the training so once again
the training did not have an effect what
was interesting about their results as
they found three groups one group all
clickers they click on anything that's
out there all right 11 percent that's a
big 11 percent it's really problematic
if you're sitting if you're an info
circular like Jesus Christ that's a lot
you have the 22% non clickers who don't
click on anything now if you're a
security guy you're like wow that's good
but if you're in a company that's
looking at productivity what are these
guys doing that's probably not an
opening email I don't know what's going
on there my problem as an academic how
look at that random 67 percent and I say
we're screwed
we have no explanation for that we don't
know what these guys are doing
they're just randomly clicking on things
if I know you click on everything I can
take you aside if I know you don't click
on anything I can say all right this
person's not a security risk but if you
don't click on anything and you're just
randomly doing stuff I gotta figure out
what's going on so we looked at some of
this data ourselves we looked at a
company that provided us some of this
data their data so this was a company
that provided data of 20 spear phishing
attacks over a two year period so we up
the game quite a bit one from three we
went to 20 and this is a popular
spearfishing program out there right
anti spearfishing program each of them
were followed by embedded training
popular product which you've probably
heard of and these were the results we
got and here the results are a little
bit better but they're still very
problematic if you look at that second
column there 24% of the people were
clicking on at least one attack and this
was over a two year period of 20 trials
so if you do the math they're around 30%
of the people in this company after two
years of being hit repeatedly we're
still clicking on links in other words
still falling for a spear fish after
spending all that money all the time all
that energy we're still not getting
where we want to be getting and when you
look talk to sis ozon and then 4 sec
people who are running this show they're
always perplexed they're annoyed by this
you know they'll say things like and I
can't believe these guys I don't we
train the hell out of them they don't
get it
they'll say things like you know we
should fire these guys Admiral Rogers at
the NSA said we should court-martial
people who fall
spear-phishing test it's it's we should
embarrass them some people shame them
out if you're a little bit of a
pessimist you start saying things like
you know we need to learn to accept that
people always gonna be a problem if
you're optimist you start saying things
like I think we can just keep doing this
and it'll get better right we've gotten
to 65%
maybe we just keep on doing it keep on
doing it and then they get better over
time and get better over time and better
unfortunately if we really want to solve
the problem
we gotta stop just saying people fall
for an attack and that over time it's
gonna get better we got to figure out
why I mean why is this happening right
as Alex Tamils yesterday said you know
we're very good at showing that there is
a problem but we're not very good at
explaining or correcting it and to
correct it we gotta get to the how and
the why why are people falling for it
and the answers are important because
right now the cost of training is
expected to increase the most it's
exceeding any other form of technical
solutions if you looked at that three
seas containment and constraint is
actually far more inexpensive compared
to training training is gonna exceed all
of these costs and we don't even factor
in the time lost in training the
ineffectiveness of some of these
approaches and so when you look at the
answers though the answers are right in
front of us so one of the things we did
is we did our studies where we fished
people repeatedly and unlike other
studies we went to the bottom of why and
when we ask the questions the answers
were right there people would say things
like I clicked on it inadvertently
without thinking or they would say
things like you know I clicked because
it was the week before Halloween so I
got a Halloween fish I clicked because
it seemed very suspicious so I emailed
the person back very rational answers
actually if you really think about it or
they would say something like I didn't
think it was a big deal I'm just
clicking on I got damn bling do it all
the time um I was careful to open it on
my phone these answers actually tell us
a story
and the story it tells us that what we
think of as a people problem it's not
really a people problem it's an
understanding of people problem we don't
get it we haven't spent time answering
the why and so one of the things we did
and when I say we my research deivanai
is over a Peter of the last you know how
decade we've been constantly doing these
tests but we've been trying to do come
to the answer of why so that we can
build an understanding of why these
things happen and how do we make things
better and that's what I'm gonna talk
about right now
so why do people fall for spearfishing
what is our research tell us the first
thing that we are understand is all the
people out there in companies today who
are constantly phishing people using
these phishing software to try to make
people more resilient you kind of have a
mechanism to understand what's a good
attack because you find keep fishing you
every day or every month twenty times
over a period of two years and I keep
varying the attack and make attacks
looks very complex or very easy make it
so easy for you that you fall for it
make it so complex that you never fall
for it I need to be able to tell you
what's a good attack what's the standard
of a decent attack and for that we
realized that there were only basically
three things that we needed to
understand and what we call that is is
there's a model that we developed called
a suspicion cognition automaticity model
called scam it's it's a published peer
review piece and we started by looking
at what's a good attack and we came up
with the triad and the triad we use the
word called vishwas which is a Sanskrit
word for trust it's a trust fired the
trust crier the vishwas tried and it
consists of three parts right what you
need is you need a trusted source so a
good phishing attack has a trusted
source and there are tons of trust
sources out there right Google is a
great trusted source
Amazon's a trusted source PayPal's a
trusted source
you need a modifiable field you have to
have a field in that attack that is so
easily modified and it's constantly
something that gets modified to the
end-user so the end user is not paying
that much attention to it and you can
see it right here this is a good attack
we modified the URL we modified you know
the cell the provider name and a good
attack as a third part to it and that is
some kind of user routines some kind of
user expectation if we could get these
three things right we can match the user
to the attack I can get into any network
and and when we have done this we can
get a 50% success rate if you can get a
good enough trustable provider and do
this so here's an example of gizmo DOS
test if you guys have been watching
reading the stories on this gizmo did a
non scientific test well basically they
sent a phishing email to 15 people in
the Trump administration and what they
found is roughly half of them clicked on
the link in fact two people responded to
the fish okay now was it a good attack
yes look at what they did they took an
attack from a very credible source a
trustworthy source a modifiable field
and what do people do when they get a
Google documents link they click on it
user routines all these people expected
it so the 50% success rate on the other
hand if you did an attack like this in
those 20 attacks that we reviewed from
the company that I was talking about one
of them was this 0.2 percent success
rate of course there's nothing here you
gotta be crazy if you click on this
right but one person did so but we used
this right and the bad guys out there
are very smart about it they use it so
this was the letter I got because of the
anthem attack giving me credit
monitoring just to give you an idea this
attack happened I think in February I
got this letter in November
by mail because never being very careful
but the next day after the attack I got
this and what do you think everybody was
doing they were all clicking on that
because it was something people expected
nobody thought anthem would wait nine
months to send you a letter that's a
good attack and there are many such
attacks that we see and if we can
compare the good attacks we can
understand what's going on the second
part was understanding why people click
so we understood that there's something
about the attack that we need to match
to the user expectation then we were
looking to see what is it about people I
can we come up with a quantitative model
where I can say you know what here are a
few things that you need to measure and
if we have done this over a period of
you know 5 to 6 years doing repeated
attacks all over the world you know
within companies that have allowed us
from her giving us permission to do this
within university settings and we
realized that there's basically only
three things that we needed to measure
one was was there something that
triggered the end-users suspicion the
second was there was something about how
that person was thinking and the third
was there was something about how that
person was doing and if we could capture
these three things we can actually
predict who's gonna fall for an attack
before we send that fair shot so that
was the goal of this process that we
engaged in and so I'm going to quickly
explain to you what each of these things
really mean right so first things first
I'm going to talk about cognition right
what we found is how do users think
becomes pretty important and what do
users do use there's a cognitive misers
what's a cognitive misers they're not
spending time thinking they're making
the fastest decision with the least
amount of information and the least
amount of effort all right and so
they use cognitive shortcuts there is a
huge body of published literature on
this and the cognitive shortcuts people
use are triggered by something in that
email generally a logo or trust
indicator something that quickly tells
me what is this that I have to do and
I'm gonna do it and if it's part of my
routine I'm just going to do it here's
an example every time I go to Starbucks
I get to click on a link the Starbucks
logo gives me credibility so we tried
this attack and we found it was very
successful for some reason people
thought Starbucks and Google because
they're part of that same Google Fiber
thing people gave us their logins and
passwords it's very easy to do right
because they're using a shortcut and we
took advantage of that shortcut and our
success rate was around 60% and there
are many examples of this here's that
here's an example we would be created
for different Facebook pages and for
those of you out there you can see
there's a missing e there's a missing
there's a different color there's a
missing Yi and a different color and
then there's the original login page
which one do you think is the most
credible here anybody which one do you
think you were to open or to put in your
login and password anybody this one does
everybody think it's this one right this
one is the most credible isn't it would
you put your login and password in here
I wouldn't
all of them are spoofs right how
difficult is it to do this I just copied
and pasted the whole thing right so if
you're using a shortcut and you're
thinking trying to out think the process
i canäôt think you because without a
URL you don't know what's going on here
right so but what we realized which is
pretty interesting which this never
mattered neither did this because we did
this study in October and a lot of
people said oh we thought it was Breast
Cancer Awareness Month and they changed
their color I don't even have to work
hard at this you know it's it's easier
to be a bad guy because people just give
you their data
the other thing we were measuring what
do people believe and this is a real
interesting data and I can tell you this
we've done this we've asked these two
questions now in in Asia we've asked it
in the United States we've asked it in
Europe in different parts of Europe and
I can predict the answer the first
question we ask is how easy is it for
you to spot a spear phishing email and
these are employees 600 employees in a
company and everybody thinks oh somewhat
easy very easy I can do it I'm pretty
good at this and then we ask them a
follow-up question how easy is it for
any other employee in your company to do
this I look at this everybody is a ninja
in their mind right everybody thinks
they're better than everybody else and
this data is so predictable
we did this exact same thing in the
Netherlands same answers how easy is it
for you somewhat easy how easy is it for
somebody else
somewhat difficult and then when you
look at the training data and you say
how much time did this person really
spend looking at your training some of
them are spending less than 30 seconds
on it because they're geniuses they know
this stuff they don't take it seriously
that's a big problem right you need to
be able to convince this portion to
first pay attention to what we're giving
them the other thing and this is
something a lot of us suffer from is
what I call the dunning-kruger effect I
don't know if you guys know who Dunning
cook of what dunning-kruger effect is
but this is a this is a real story
this happens in Pittsburgh I know you're
from Pittsburgh and there was a guy by
the name of McArthur wheeler real name
who you know broke into a bank and
before he broke into the bank he applied
lemon juice on his face because he had
read somewhere that lemon juice makes
you invisible because it makes ink
invisible so he figured the digital
cameras he's got to be invisible to it I
can't make this stuff up okay that's
that's all real the story is so when
they caught him he kept saying how the
hell did you guys catch us and he said
well we were on the camera I said how'd
the camera catch me
lemon juice on my face so two of these
guys Dunning and Kruger wrote a paper
about this and they said what makes
people think that way right there has to
be a hubris about us or a lack of
knowledge and we did the same thing with
technology which cybersecurity and what
we found is people have ideas in their
mind all of you do I do
you got a snout you know as the end user
out there what's the safe word document
a PDF document or a Word document
invariably 80% of them will pick PDF and
ask them why
well I can't edit it which means it's
safe right we think we know and there
are lots of this right when you ask
people you know what's up safer email
client you know what's a better
operating system you know what's a
better Wi-Fi network and watch more
secure everybody in their mind is
carrying these ideas of security most of
which are not based on fact and the
problem with that is with these risk
beliefs people who have low risk beliefs
tend to be very confident so you think
you know when you really don't know and
no one's told you you don't know yet
so you go about doing what you're doing
and that's how you get the macarthur
reader of fact right you wear a helmet
and you stand on top of them in a
tightrope because you think the helmets
gonna protect your head because that's
all that matters right your head but the
problem is you don't know what's the
risk there and so this is a problem
right this is something that we've been
trying to measure the other is habits
automaticity people have habits and this
is checking email and you know checking
email when you're walking when you're
talking and a lot of these things make
you click on things when you're not
really thinking it to you're doing it
really fast and what we have found is
it's easier for me to get you to click
on a link if you're on a mobile device
it's a lot easier for me to do that ok
so we put these things together right we
put these
for ideas together and said let's try to
measure this and come up with the best
ways of measuring this and we realized
all we really needed to measure when it
came to this was a few different things
and this is an empirical model and it
basically consists of five five and six
different constructs and we have a
measure for it okay and this measure is
what we call as a cyber risk index so
what we found is if I can ask you
questions basically comes down to 40
questions we're able to come up with the
individualized score that ranges from 0
to 100 that tells me your risk your
likelihood of clicking on one of these
spearfishing links okay it's an
individualized score so each person gets
a score and you can use that score and
change it and get it updated over time
so it's not a static score and all you
need is a person to answer 40 questions
in a survey okay and it's very quick to
do and you can do this using whatever
software you're using so if you're using
a package right now to you know an
embedded training package you can fish
people do the survey and then fish them
again and see if the data works out so
we've been able to do this to match and
to refine our measurement to say you
know how good is this and then we've
been able to now aggregate it across
division so I can take the score just
like a credit score and make a risk
score for that division for that group
for all the employees in that area
because right now there is no metric out
there right just saying how many people
fell for a phishing attack or a
simulation doesn't do it we need to be
able to say why and we need to be able
to say what's the quantitative threshold
error and so what we have done is we've
then come up with mechanisms of taking
that index and the answers that gives us
so the index not only gives me a number
for each person it tells me why you're
gonna fall for that attack so in other
words
is your risk beliefs problematic the
index tells me okay here's where that
number is coming from primarily it's
coming from their risk index or it's
coming from their risk beliefs that way
when I'm training you or whatever I'm
trying to do that change can be focused
on the problem rather than basically
just keeping on hitting you with more
and more simulated attacks and we have
done this where we have developed a flow
and we said okay what is the index
telling us what is this person suffering
from so the analogy I use is if you go
to the doctor the first thing the doctor
does is he diagnoses you and what are 40
questions help us do is it helps us
diagnose what's ailing the patient
because right now the approaches you go
to the doctor he throws a pill at you
you take the pill you come back sick he
throws more pills at you and then you
keep on doing that and then you keep
blaming the patient for not getting
better it doesn't work on the other hand
we're able to pinpoint why and then say
okay here are the answers and for some
people they may be bad habits that they
have come up with for other people it
may be their risk believes for some
other people it may be a combination of
factors and now I can come up with a
solution based on what that person ails
from okay and that's what we're using
this index what is really interesting is
when we did this across companies and
you're still collecting data on this
we're still trying to refine it and make
it better and make it sharper what we
found is that there is a tipping point
to that 0 to 100 number okay there is a
tipping point to it and the tipping
point is around 68 to 75 so you have a
score from 0 to 100 when you get between
68 and 75 what we find is that people's
resilience actually goes up right so
we've actually studied this we are
actually implemented this and looked at
it and what we notice is for people
whose scores are about that threshold of
68 to 75 you start fishing them they
don't fall for it anymore
okay so the job the way we look at it is
we want to bring people in companies to
get beyond that 68 to 75 threshold does
that make sense so that's our index and
right now what we're doing is we're
trying to figure out ways in which we
can refine this even better right we're
trying to make it such that it becomes
easier to implement it because all it is
is 40 questions and it gives you a
diagnostic that is you know a agnostic
to the device so for instance a lot of
training today is with the no use case
that is very limited so you're training
people to work in a Microsoft
environment and on a desktop environment
many of these environments are changing
and don't even exist anymore
many people are bringing devices to work
many people are in different
environments and whatever training we
are doing is so siloed so limited and
yet so ineffective at times that what we
need is to move beyond just looking at
the technology to the person the actor
behind that machine and that's what
we're trying to do here all right I
think we're running out of time so I'm
going to stop here and hopefully take
some questions if anybody has any
questions
how much 10 minutes or so we have about
10 minutes so if anybody has any
questions yes yes I have a question
cyber risk index is it peer-reviewed and
is it being used in practice in the
industry and so what are you saying
right so this data is all coming from
companies right now the index is still
it's it's in review right now but the
model that's using to come up with this
is already peer-reviewed and it so it's
available to the public the 40 questions
is that available it's a public awesome
the 40 questions are in that's in that
instrument but we are refining it and as
it gets better we're gonna just put it
out there so people can use it okay all
right um I have it my question is about
empirical results with actual intrusions
so is there any data coming back from
these companies where instead of a
simulated phishing attack it was an
actual phishing attack and seeing how
the CRI of the employees are lining up
against where there's a a real intrusion
as yet there isn't any to be honest so
as yet the only way we're doing this is
we're using the existing pen testing
methodology and we're using our approach
to give them the index and trying to see
if the pen test data matches it but
unfortunately we don't even that data is
really hard to get I mean that seems to
be the bigger problem and and to answer
the peer review question I mean we're
going through you know the bad guys out
there are attacking us every minute and
my peer review cycle is six months to a
year so you know by the time I get this
thing through the process I mean we're a
year down the process the bad guys have
already hit us like ten other times or
100 other times successfully yes
um yeah sorry that just got kind of out
of curiosity like I mean it's confusing
why's 76 to 100 would not
better for CRS Cortlandt is an example
on this chart here what's with that
green bar on the far right what's that
is that little guy just like an outlier
it was just there are outliers so the
problem with working with people as you
know is it's not we don't get perfect
data I wish we could write I wish we
could get that hard data right two
molecules of hydrogen and one molecule
of oxygen always makes water but people
unfortunately it's not and so we're
gonna have outliers on both sides so
here you have a bunch of people with
lowers lower scores on this side also
not getting fished so it's not very
clean and that's why the more data we
get the better this gets but on average
what we're finding is once you get
beyond 75 these guys are very resilient
okay once we get to that threshold and
this is pretty compelling once you get
below it we're in a whole world of
trouble
okay and that helps in itself yes you
can add other types of security behavior
like employees making choices about hand
a handle customer data and stuff like
that right
and so one of the things we're doing is
we're trying to predict what what I like
to call cyber hygiene but within an
organizational setting it's about
handling PII more more you know hygienic
lis for lack of a better word so we're
working on it the issue is again we're
still collecting data to make this much
more robust than it is how much it
applies across the board we still don't
know because that's where the training
comes in so if you can clean people
better and train them based on some of
this at least you have a metric that you
can fall back against okay yes I just
want to point out something that it
looks like you discovered inadvertently
that's really cool you were collecting
information on why people click the link
after they did it and you found some
interesting information some people were
suspicious of it before they clicked it
but it seemed like they just didn't know
what to do with that link so I'm
thinking that's something that companies
could do to be more resilient
is they can tell the employees what to
do if they're suspicious because they
might not know like who to go to or who
to send it to and then instead of all
this negative reinforcement like you've
got to embarrass or punish them you can
start doing positive reinforcement like
rewarding or recognizing people that
discovered the vulnerability or the
attack before it got widespread right
and that's a great point right so we got
to come up with better mechanisms of
reinforcing people there's a whole part
that I didn't talk about for instance
you know we have tried different
approaches to improve behavior a lot of
behavioral training today misses habits
right what are people's routines and so
one of the things that we've been
working on is how do I make you develop
better routines and part of that routine
might be you know making you more
conscious of using to affair as often as
possible or multi-factor authentication
of looking at your logs of emailing you
know problematic emails that you see to
somebody in IT assuming that there is
that setup for doing that and what we
find is you know some people benefit
from that but not all right so you need
to be able to say okay who benefits the
most from an habbit intervention and so
again using our measure we were able to
pinpoint where that CRI is coming from
and then go to that person and train
just them and we're actually doing that
I have some data on that and we find
that you know within three to four weeks
you start changing the way these people
are thinking about their routines and
one of the actions that we did is we
took away their mobile access to email
so we cannot right off the bat said
these people shouldn't have mobile
access because their habits are really
problematic and I'll give you some data
that is really really interesting I
can't explain it yet but there were
people who click on links multiple times
I don't know if you guys have seen this
in your data set but we're starting to
see this where people are repeatedly
clicking on a phishing email link or
repeatedly opening an attachment and it
boggles our mind and one of the things
we realized was a lot of the mobile
clients that people are using are loves
you to have the email come back at a
later date so the person is clicking on
and saying I'm going to come back to
this and then they come back to it and
they come back to it so you're getting
multiple infections from that same
person in theory and some of these
people shouldn't have access to it by
email by on their mobile device so we
just took it away right so that's one
way to think about it all right
any other questions I'm interested that
ye this study kind of depends on
self-reported information how much data
or is it ever possible to infer some of
these behaviors particularly habitual
behavior where you you have information
on devices how are you cross-checking
yes yes so one of the good things about
using a lot of these training packages
is depending on which one you're using
to do your testing your pen testing for
instance your red team's or whatever
they're using you can say okay how are
these people accessing the link are they
accessing on a mobile device are they
accessing on you know on a PC
environment how many times you're
clicking so some of the behavioral data
we're correlating with the self-report
data that we already have so we've been
doing it in multiple ways we've been
doing a pre post we'll be doing that
post only so so what we're trying to
bring this to is forty questions that we
can use with regardless of whether
you're getting tested or not so we can
just use it across organizations I mean
that's the standard we're trying to get
to and and I think we're getting close
all right any other questions yes my
very subjective observation is that
sometimes people click on links simply
because they're curious right have you
explored the role of curiosity and
motivating people to open phishing
emails well you know curiosity is more
it's it's a very subjective notion but
where we get to that is with our trial
its expectation so more often than not I
mean there are going to be those people
out there we're going to click on a link
just because you know I remember the
Israeli Defense Forces were fished they
fell for a phishing attack which
basically said you know girls of the
Israeli Defense Force it was a youtube
link that was sent to all of them and
that I would call curiosity but now if
you fall for that in 2017 you've got a
problem right so we get that 1% we're
gonna click on pretty much anything
right but we got to move beyond that to
say okay what are the
expectations hopefully we can protect
against the vast majority of this but if
we can find what those expectations are
that people have and match it we have a
better deal at stopping it sure yes did
you I have attempt to make a correlation
to like age group or our functional
group within the company we did age
doesn't predict much except at the upper
ends of it it really doesn't between
groups in the company in terms of what
their functions are we find technical
people fall just as well as
non-technical people who are in info
sack they think that they were smarter
than they are okay we all do and one of
the reasons for it and it's a very
simple reason is there is just so much
that we can do to match an attack to you
that it's likely I can catch you if I
really want to right if I'm really
motivated I can do this and then what we
find is repetition helps so even with
highly technical people if I repeat that
attack the same attack the likelihood of
us getting twenty fifteen to twenty
percent is not not pretty long we can
easily get them so we're not seeing big
differences in them okay hold on to that
do you see more attacks to like the
company executives in higher level on
the spear phishing we haven't done only
company company executives but you know
the likelihood are is that you know if
you're a company executives so what are
the things that we've been talking about
is how do we take this index and figure
out who gets admin privileges like who
gets more access to databases for
instance and what we find is right now
the system we have is based on your role
so if you're the CEO you get access to
things which you may or may not need
access to but you force yourself into it
you sound to see I can do this I need
access to the accounting or the billing
system maybe we don't but how do you say
no the only way to say no is if you have
some quantitative metric that says you
know what you are too risky for us right
now and maybe you shouldn't be getting
access so that's kind of like where
we're trying to take this and say we
need a quantitative metric here of some
sort that tells you know the IT guys out
there
to say wait a minute no let's let's come
up with an index let's use this index
and let's give access based on that
thank you yes all right
out of time thank you so much thanks for
coming