it's my very great honor to announce our
first conference guest today
our distinguished guest of honor her
excellency
madeleine albright 64th secretary of
state
of the united states of america
professor author
businesswoman diplomat she was the first
female secretary of state and became
at that time the highest ranking woman
in the history of the us government
dr madeleine albright will be
interviewed by her excellency marina
calderont i'm very curious to hear your
views and your insights please go ahead
welcome
good morning madam secretary and good
day to everybody who is watching us
from japan to us in different time zones
dear madeleine it's always a great
pleasure
to see you and listen to you and i'm
really thrilled and honored
to have today a discussion with you
i'm delighted to join you i really am
and
have the opportunity to spend time
talking with you
madam minister my good friend marina so
we will have a good discussion thank you
for inviting me
uh madeleine we're living through
challenging times
besides covet pandemic there are other
worrying developments
yesterday for example the european
parliament adopted a very critical
resolution on russia's aggressive
behavior
the russian relations are at its lowest
u.s administration expelled russian
diplomats
and russia retaliated also china is
becoming more assertive
powerful and vocal dear madeleine you
are known for thinking out of the box
and you are known for bold ideas what is
your take on the present international
situation
and more precisely on transatlantic
relations
what is your advice to us and european
leaders
because needless to say europe was
excited and happy
after the last presidential elections
president biden has a standing
invitation to come to brussels
we're waiting to see him here and i know
that he will do it soon
well i you have asked many questions
that really show
i think the world is a mess that's a
diplomatic term of art things are bad
i really do think that if one looks at
the various
issues that are out there beyond the
ones that you mentioned
in terms of what russia is doing what
china's doing
the challenge of climate change
obviously the kovid
but also that there are issues
throughout the world
in different countries uh every
continent there are some
issues that need to be dealt with and
part of the issue frankly is also
that we don't have the international
institutions
that are in many ways up to speed in
terms of dealing
with them they need to be rejuvenated in
some ways and we need to decide which
ones
are the ones that really are operational
i do think that what has made a
difference in the united states
is the election of president biden who
has a very different approach
and by the way he's somebody that i know
very well because
we worked together when he was a senator
uh and i
was secretary and we knew each other
even before that and
he has a very broad understanding of
international issues i think
um and frankly probably more than any
president we've had in
in in a very long time and a deep
interest
and he understands and it started with
his inauguration speech
that we america had to be back america
had to be
a part of the system and that we would
re-enter
the system with humility and i think
that that is the way he is approaching
things
um he gave a very interesting speech um
two days ago two nights ago in congress
in which he outlined a very different
approach to the
uh the issues in the united states and
that have to be dealt with
but at the same time i think made clear
to the american public
as he talked about the national security
issues how domestic and foreign policy
go together
which i think is a very important part
um in a democracy
by the way i think that one thing
that i have been reading the
intelligence community our
our intelligence community has just put
out a document
global trends 2040. it's unclassified
and they have made very clear what the
various issues are that have to be dealt
with
um some that are immediate but some that
are the longer term ones
that need to be dealt with now in a very
specific way with
partners which leads me to one of the
things you also ask the transatlantic
relationship
is absolutely essential uh and i think
that
it's something that was very important
before
um and as a result of what happened in
world war ii
but we now have to make clear that it is
a crucial aspect of how we
work and live together uh thank you
madam
you are known for being a very strong
supporter of transatlantic ties
and it's really encouraging to hear from
both sides of the atlantic ocean
that there is interest there is
willingness
there is a commitment to have new or to
restore
the work of nato to give more impetus to
nato
and to have closer transatlantic ties so
from brussels i can only say that we're
looking forward
to president biden's visit to brussels
but coming to another topic i'm really
happy and honored to be part of your
group of exes well who don't know
that's the club or group of former
foreign ministers but then you keep us
busy
you keep us busy about learning about
new topics
discussing new topics you keep us busy
about
thinking about the world today and
making that suggest a big making
suggestions to the better world
to come so recently we had series of
presentations and discussions about uh
cyber security
uh pandemic has brought digital topics
to the center of political attention
everybody is discussing digital
everybody's going digital
but if we look from the perspective of
cyber security
how do you see the biggest challenges
for international community
but also for our transatlantic
i think it is at the basis of
what the future is bringing to us and
yet
i have to say i think that even a lot of
experts don't understand all the
ramifications of it
and uh average people in countries do
know
that there's the internet of everything
and that that
you know their refrigerator talks to
them or um
that things are very automatic but they
don't uh see
the other side of this what what are we
learning what
um uh who is in control uh what do we
know
and again this particular report our the
this global trends
i think um has a whole section
on the impact of technology on our daily
lives
and the importance of understanding and
especially
i think issues to do with artificial
intelligence
um the whole issue of cyber
of whether cyber is a friend or an enemy
and so and it's very interesting because
one of the things is that what has
happened as i mentioned
there is the internet of things but it
is actually
also led to fragmentation in our
societies
because it exacerbates the divisions
and i think we need to know the social
effect of all of this
and then the other part if i may say is
that you
are in brussels and the eu makes rules
and we don't yet have norms that really
govern
how the cyber systems uh how artificial
intelligence works
and even though the euro atlanta the
transatlantic relationship is the most
basic one in terms of values we need to
figure out
how to use the systems to develop some
norms
that we understand what is really
happening but it has affected it's
affected our elections it's affected
um how we see what the russians are
doing
um in uh central and eastern europe to
undermine democracy
it affects how the chinese are operating
so it is a a new
it's some in some ways it's a gift and
in another way
it's kind of the genie out of the bottle
trying to figure out
uh what we do with it and therefore
having
these kinds of discussions uh whether we
have it among the former foreign
ministers or
we have it with people that are in power
now as you are in the parliament
um and then also that the average people
understand
what is going on with this it's a very
very big assignment
i very much agree with your emphasis on
international law
norms because we need clear
understanding
what are the rules of behavior in
cyberspace
we've been seeing we've been saying that
international law applies to cyber
but unfortunately we do not we do not
see that the whole words
world acts according to the words
unfortunately we see in the united
nations
and internationally division ideological
division between different
different states so how to continue
discussion on multilateral level
multi-stakehold the level level in these
difficult circumstances well i think the
hard part is
that we do come at it differently i mean
the
i have to say democracies we believe in
free speech and freedom
um and the opportunity to exchange
information and to understand each other
the authoritarian governments are able
to use this tool to control people
and to undermine the way that we
understand each other
and so developing those norms and it's
very hard
in organizations where everybody is
represented but we need to
understand this and this is going to
take
a lot of effort um in order to
develop the norms and the truth is um
you know i always say this i
i was born in prague and i just happened
to have been raised in the united states
so i'm the example of the transatlantic
relationship and we disagree often we
disagree
in terms of some of the rules on privacy
a number of ways that we do things
and yet we have more in common than any
other group of people and so i do think
that we are going to have to be take a
leadership
role in this and you have frankly
i think it's been remarkable and also
you come from a country that has been um
uh really uh modern in many ways for a
long time
in terms of being an e-country that
really understands it
but you have also been the victim
of attacks from the outside uh
through this new uh tool and so i think
there's nobody better
than a representative of estonia to
really be leading this discussion
thank you for your kind remarks but
still i'd say that we need different
voices
we need people coming from very
different backgrounds
and coming from the cyber security
community
i'd say that we also need globally
strong
and committed u.s voice when we talk
about digital topics
when i talk about cyber security we
missed it
hopefully it will be now back on
international arena
i we are we'll will be back i have to
say
there's a great desire to be back and
president biden
has made that clear but what is also
interesting
is that there have been commissions that
have been looking about what to do
something called the solarium commission
that had a set of recommendations about
how to strengthen
the internal structure of the u.s
government
in order to be able to deal with this
that it's not just the defense
department
that is really a whole of government
there has now been somebody
who came to speak to our group um last
time cresingus who's been named
as the chief officer to really deal with
this
out of the white house um and there is
going to be an approach how to work this
the other part that makes this both
interesting and complicated
it is just it's not just governments
it's the private sector
and that relationship between the public
and private sector
is something that also is a challenge
for you
and for us and how we do this so the
more we do together
the better i i i can completely agree
with everything you said
uh dear madeline you know what day it
was yesterday
it was the 29th of april and
europe celebrated the day of solidarity
between generations
it was first introduced in 2012
and i have to say that it is becoming
more and more popular
among different generations and i'm
proud that i have at home for
generations
my mother 95 my grandson seven months
old
so i do have i have the privilege of
living with different generations
dear madeleine you are always known for
being inspiring
to all generations to different
generations
and especially to women to women in
politics the woman in diplomacy
the woman in cyber security but then
what would you like to say
today to women and maybe especially
to young women who are watching you
well i do think that we have been
watching how there have been more women
that have come into places uh in the
political world and the business world
and the educational world scientific
world
and and i can believe very strongly the
most famous thing i ever said
was that there's a special place in hell
for women who don't support each other
we need to have more women in the room
it always helps
and when you became part of my group of
former foreigners we have now have
more of us there but i also
do think the cross generational thing is
so important
because i think it is accurate to say
that the younger generation understands
technology better
than the others and one of the we have a
very famous
poet robert frost who said the older i
am the younger are my teachers
and that is the way i feel now about the
younger generation
men and women how they work together and
they
really have a better sense of the
technology but i am delighted to see
uh women and by the way there was a
great picture
i talked about president biden's speech
to congress
it was the first time in history excuse
me that two women
were sitting behind him the uh speaker
of the house
nancy pelosi and our vice president
kamala harris
it is a big step forward america always
wants to be first in everything we're
not first
in terms of women prime ministers and
women
presidents but we are working on it and
we all have to work
together and the support that women give
to each other
i think is very very important which is
why i love having you
as part of my group thank you so much
for your kind words
and the quote was excellent i remember
it and i'll take it with me
unfortunately we're running out of time
i hope that we'll be invited to a
talk show on cnn or anywhere else where
we can have more time to discuss all the
interesting topics but i'd like to thank
you
for for being always available
for being open and frank for your time
you are dedicating to international
affairs to
interesting topics to cyber security to
women of
all generations uh thank you so much
for letting me to talk to you today
because i know that in the audience
there are hundreds who would like to
talk to you today i was privileged
hopefully next time there will be
anybody else dear madeleine
thank you so much dear marina thank you
and congratulations on
everything you're doing and your
leadership role across
so many different subjects all my best
to you
and good luck and we'll see each other
soon some way
thank you bye bye
thank you so much bring your in your
insights to the public
thank you her excellency madeleine
albright and thank you also excellently
marina calgarant
[Music]
you