I'd like to start off today this is
going to be a talk about security but
I'm going to look at it from a slightly
different perspective it will be
technical a little bit but I'm talking
more about an overall objective now as
before I got into the information
security space I was a software
developer i wrote kernel code device
drivers a number of applications for a
variety of operating systems including
the unix space and this was even before
linux my work started off in NASA at
Cape Canaveral and it was there where I
really got an understanding of what
software development or secure software
development really means and a lot of
people think about secure software
development simply a sanitization or
preventing buffer overflows or some
context like that but it's in my opinion
it's actually a larger issue in in the
concept of true risk management from a
software perspective your code the code
that you wrote today and that it's just
went out to production if you look at it
from Cote five years from now it's going
to be most likely a completely different
animal now take a look at the ipad for
example back when it was released i
think in 2007 there was as all this
chatter that Steve Jobs did not want a
stylist he did not want to use a stylus
so what is that what did that will do
today they made a stylus and it became a
controversial issue in reality though
Apple released it because their
customers were saying or especially the
artists we would love to have a stylist
to draw on it customers use the iPad in
ways that even Apple didn't dream so
Apple decided to satisfy their customer
needs and implement a solution they saw
a market they took advantage of it now
that's great from a business perspective
you're in software development you've
got to worry about the code you write
and that is going to be changed over
time so you've got a
have the foresight to know that what is
unexpected and to be able to make the
appropriate changes without breaking
your back or breaking your company or
causing so much havoc and I'm going to
use an actual example from my personal
experience so let's start off with the
design the concept of flexibility in
this context and it just simply means to
be able to modify code within a
reasonable perspective to maintain a
secure state now in older versions it
was more quality but we're not just
talking about today about buffer
overflows or cross-site scripting or
anything like that the fact is you've
got to write code today as I showed you
in that previous page that what you
probably going to expect five years from
now is almost completely different and
there are a number outside influences on
this there could be excuse me got to go
back jump the gun on that you can have
customer requirements you can have
competition you can have regulatory
issues such as PCI if you've ever
written software that is for pc i use
you know that pci changes their
requirements and auditors often change
their requirements within the pci space
so you've got to have the foresight to
expect what i'm writing now is not going
to be acceptable five years from now
I've got to be a little willing to make
changes you have competition that might
make bet code better than you and more
secure than you now since you just
walked to the room i'm going to plug
clear for a minute and i'm going to use
clear as an excellent example claire
gave a great presentation on two-factor
authentication especially like through
biomedics you write code today because
your boss wants fingerprint
authentication in comes clear into your
business now if I saw clear walking into
my office or my comp
x it all depends on what the situation
is if she's professionally dressed and
talk to my CEO guess what I'm going to
be doing only modifying code because the
boss who screamed at me saying why
aren't you doing this is not going to
change his mind and say you need to
change it now if coats if if Claire is
more casually dressed wearing jeans and
wandering around the back then I really
get secure because she's up to no good
for good reasons and as the old saying
goes Claire's Claire's opinions on
authentication carry a lot of weight
around here I just carry a lot of weight
period okay so let's now that we have
that so let's say for example you have
to worry about authentication Claire
comes in and tells your boss you're
doing it all wrong guess who your boss
is going to see next and guess what he's
going to demand so if you have in the
initial design thought about that
anticipation and thought about the
concept you're going to be changing your
coat over time it can make make a
difference between doing it right and
making it fast and good while
maintaining a secure state or rushing it
from the very beginning and doing it
wrong which turns out to be a major
hassle I'll give you a couple examples
you know SSL is being phased out well
somebody has to use SSL or somebody used
to use SSL now it's going to LS and now
it's not even a pci requirement anymore
if you're using SSL in your code you are
not PCI compliant it was effective last
June md5 now I'm having as soon as clear
shows up now my stuff starts breaking
okay so it TLS is the same thing but i'm
going to i'm going to continue as it was
but what there's one other factor that a
lot of people don't talk about your
career I've been around long enough to
know how to move and improve your career
a lot of developers make the mistake of
not really understanding what their work
can do in
long run if you're good you are expected
to change your job within the next five
years good software development means if
you can write code better than your
co-workers that is easier to change less
time to modify and more secure and you
have the metrics to show it or at least
reasonable metrics to show what you can
do you are the one is going to be hired
over your competitors or in fact if all
of you in here are vying for the same
job and you did it better than everybody
else and you have reasonable amount that
you can show it I is the boss I'm going
to hire him all of you are just going to
be ambiguous oh yes I writes a cure code
big freakin deal everybody writes secure
code but you wrote code that reduced the
known vulnerability rate and reduced
errors in your testing by thirty percent
and the changes you made line by line
were faster by two weeks then you're
conveying your coworkers that's what
people want to see and I'm actually
going to focus on your career a little
bit because a lot of you are probably
going to want to change jobs over time
okay so when you look at the concept of
flexibility as the way it works into
security it really works very well and
may not look like it from the very
beginning fact is going to be extra work
in the very in the beginning but study
after study after study after study have
all concluded the same thing if you
design it right from the very beginning
it may be the most hassle at the start
but over time it is easier to implement
easier to change your boss is going to
scream at you probably why you aren't
done with your code why it's taking you
so long but that very same boss if you
have to make any changes is going to
scream at you six months later screen
why isn't it why hasn't the change has
been implemented yet so you as a
software developer if you really want to
get into the security space it's more
than just thinking a buffer overflows or
anything like that you've got to look
long term plan ahead think about what
she
just can be made and how you can design
your architecture so that those changes
can be easily implemented if you look at
architecture from any other perspective
in the physical world whether it's
airline structures like bridges or
towers or anything even ships any good
engineer has the concept to understand
that that structure that he or she
builds is going to be subject to change
due to nature's effects skyscrapers do
not believe it or not are not that rigid
they bend with the wind you may not tell
it but they do because a good engineer
knows that they could only resist
outside changes so much bridges will be
built with the anticipation that the
ground below it will change so they
design it with that change in mind there
was a article may be about 10 years ago
an engineer was flying with a seven year
old son and they were experiencing some
modern some mediate medium turbulence
the Sun was terrified being seven he
said dad the wings are going to fall off
because they were bouncing like this and
the turbulence thatthat said no you
should be happy they're like that
they're not fighting against nature it's
bending along with it and because it's
flexible and not being aluminum is so
low density it is able to adjust
accordingly rather snap off it's able to
adjust with it with the current
environment and go on that's one of the
reasons why the Titanic growth because
the the meta was so rigid and so
inflexible the weight just eventually
sheared the ship off when you take a
twig for example a healthy young twig
you bend it it will be flexible when you
take an old tweak it breaks same concept
so there are a lot of advantages to
flexibility but there are some
disadvantages and I've listed some of
them here okay you will impact your
performance a little bit but it's not
that much as it much as it used to be in
other words because of processing speed
and compiler
it has reduced somewhat your until
you've got to think of your integrity
because you are probably going to have
to change your internal structure or
your eternal data elements as you go
along so you've got to focus that into
consideration so there are there are
general there are some general
disadvantages but overall if you plan it
if you plan it well you can put
something you can design something
really well so that when your boss comes
to you say we makes we need to make this
change you can make that Jan I'm not
talking about a minor change I'm talking
about a comprehensive major change which
I will show in a moment now the concept
of flexibility is not new it was
actually thought about back in 1977 and
I have references at the end of this
talk and this will be available to the
public okay it was it was from Griffith
Air Force Base and General Electric
where they wanted to improve the quality
of their software development in the
military flexibility was one of the top
eleven out of 55 requirements for their
design and flexibility breaks down even
to further as such as accessibility
adaptability and so forth ok flexibility
is not just whether you can expand your
buffer to accept the larger string but
your customer is using your software
right now what are you designing in it
so that if you have to make a change to
expand that buffer what are you doing so
that it doesn't impact your customer are
you designing in a way so that if you
think if I have to increase that buffer
size is my cut is it going to impact my
customer if it will what does my
customer have to do to make the change
so you've got to think of something like
that right you know you got to think of
something like that too and
unfortunately in my opinion software
engineering is becoming a lost art I
attended a threat analysis class at
black cat last year and I was the only
one over 35 and they were including
three software developers and none of
them could do reverse engineering none
of them could reassemble
or none of them could even understand
the basic concept of the stack none of
them even had a basic understanding of
what registers do if you are going to be
a good software engineer and really
excel unique just like any other
engineer has to understand the
environment which he or she works on if
you're building a bridge if you're
dealing with high-level water or high
velocity water you've got to think about
that if you're building an airplane
you've got to think about the stress
factors involved so for engineering is
becoming nothing more than just a
buzzword I'm a software engineer I write
java and PHP whoopty freaking do ok I
used to write an assembler I had a
debugging assembler and I hate it in the
beginning but you really understand the
architecture if you don't know they
architecture which you're building on
fine that's one thing but don't call
yourself a software engineer your
program you may be good at what you do
but if you're going to go into device
drivers if you're going to go into
kernels if you're going to go into low
level security if you want to reverse
engineer you've got to understand it
because whatever you write I can break I
can go in with a kernel debugger and
modify your code change values and make
it Whitworth the way I want so you've
got to think about that and we need
these type of people we don't just need
PHP program against PHP or java but we
need people really understand the
architecture I've seen a lot of crappy
code by so-called programmers who write
it in this static viewpoint but when
things have to change it all becomes a
major undertaking and a lot of things
break the the paper that I just talked
about it's just like every other report
the longer you wait to really implement
good software design be flexible enough
a change the more expensive it becomes
over time doing it the from the very
beginning is best but you're going to
run into a lot of business resistance
you're going to want your boss to your
boss is going to want to be the first on
the market the next boss who tells me
that he wants to be first I swear I'm
gonna hit up I mean it I am sick and
title we want to be first on the market
so what how many times have you probably
heard of an of a news article that we're
refers to report it yeah they were all
wrong okay is your objective to satisfy
your customer needs to be secure or is
the first to say you were first on the
market great you were first on the
market but your coat sucks I broke it
everybody broke breaks it and now it's
on the wall of shame in every hacking
website known to man okay sometimes
first is not always best another concept
will sell it now and we'll fix it later
a lot of managers make the mistake of
architecture being something like I will
just flip the switch later okay why
don't you just flip the switch now when
you build a house you design your
windows you design your electrical
systems you design your lighting while
it's on the paper with your architect
you don't build a eighty percent done
and then say oh I want to change this I
want to change this I want to change
this you're our protector will hit you
why because there are stress factors
involved in building a house you've
designed it on paper and then build it
same thing with software design it's no
different the processes may be different
but you've got to go with the same
general concept a lot of managers think
we'll flip a switch will that change a
value and is done the very first
question I asked that boss do it now
what's the big deal and they later find
out it's not as easy as it sounds
they're quick they want to be out we'll
fix it later but think about it your
your help desk will have higher costs it
will probably cost more to implement
good software development in the longer
run when os/2 was released and I'm going
to go into OS to in a minute IBM had a
higher a lot of help desk people and how
to get software developers to do a lot
of the help desk including me because it
had so much problems in the beginning
same thing with your code you may think
it's great they were first on the market
we're out but there are impacts your
don't want angry customers calling you
limited budgets if you write so if
you're releasing a product that's Pete
for pci or HIPAA and I think Claire
knows what hip what I'm talking about a
HIPAA is if it is not right or if it's
poorly made the regulators are going to
be coming after you and you do not want
that trust me on that you do not want
them your business is going to your you
may have a bunch of risk that you
understand what are going on with your
code your business however has four
general types of business risk and I've
listed them all there if you need to
communicate an issue to your boss you
can talk about technology all day he's
not going to care he wants one of these
four types of risk that's going to
impact him if you can address why you
need to do a better job and if you can
address one of these four issues you
have are more likely going to get your
bosses but your boss to change his mind
don't even bother talking about tech now
he's not going to care they want to they
have to run a business you need
customers in order to get money you need
a paycheck don't you and don't tell me
that you're a secure software
development company because security
does not sell products and services do
so you've got to think about that if
you're so if you're if you sell security
and your reputation is impacted or your
liability is going to go up then your
boss is going to start seeing your point
of view okay so let's now I was talking
about the architecture I'm going to go a
little bit about what it's been like in
the past and there's a reason for this
obviously I'm going to you can see the
table on here of the microbe it's poor
for each microprocessor in the old days
a mile I'm going back I'm dating myself
but we used to have to deal with near
and far pointers and that type
for complex mathematical operations we
had to go into special assembler
routines in order to do that because
this the 16-bit architecture alone just
did not have the capability so when you
you are writing your code you may think
ok we're fine it's running fine we don't
have any problems now when we did it was
to the original one point 0 version of
OS to was 16 bit now we're going to two
point O an IBM to say hey we've got
these new machines let's make them
32-bit oh that sounds great except that
there were a lot of there was a lot of
impact from the 32-bit perspective and I
have one example for example a lot of
developers used to write if they want to
start off with negative 1 even if it's
an unsigned integer in c you can do ffff
that's fine but what happens from the 16
to the 32-bit look what happens because
an integer is implementation dependent
it is not a fixed 16-bit value it
changes with the microprocessor so if
you have of ffff this is what it becomes
it is now a different value but if you
maintain the minus 1 the unsigned
integer minus 1 it changes and changes
and when it goes eventually to 128 bit
it will change as well because a
compiler they're smarter not even in the
old compilers they will automatically
change if you did it the old-fashioned
way you have to go into your code now
and make changes if you did it this way
even as an unsigned integer you know to
worry about it you just saved yourself
some time you had major code a little
bit more secure and your boss may be a
little bit happy to find out it took you
days rather than weeks to make the
change this is what I'm talking about
this is just the beginning we're talking
about pointers we're talking where you
can talk about between a ski and unicode
you're talking we're rather than strict
ascii strings what about you need coach
strings you're going more international
you got to worry about that and you may
think okay I write in Java whoopty
freaking do again
used to write the Java Runtime compiler
in the AIX operating system that was
written in C and I am surprised we had
it running because even if the AIX
operating system change it could impact
the Java Runtime environment so don't
think because you run java you're secure
you're safe everything's fine no you're
running java on top of another library
which is running on top of your
operating system and that operate that
library runs c and assembler and java or
excuse me AIX is not an intel based
system it is a power based system which
uses an entirely different architectures
not just for regit for general purpose
registers we're talking like 16 general
purpose registers it's an entirely
different animal altogether Apple used
to be a power environment they moved
over to an Intel evalu that was a
complex long and costly change which
impacted Apple but they eventually got
it right so as you probably notice I'm
going to be talking about it was to a
little bit and I worked on the os/2
operating system for a number of years
all the way back from the 10 days and
I'm going to go over one specific
component that I worked on with us too
and this was from 102 from from 10 to
two point oh and later to 2.1 now this
does not impact security per se but this
does impact data integrity and this was
the os/2 postscript driver what you're
looking at on the screen is a visual
representation of what the old OS to
postscript driver day we supported
printers that's it we did it we did our
little thing we print a duplex or use
color fit supported that type of thing
no big deal so we had a little but there
was a little bit of a problem number one
we had to go to 32 bit so we had to fix
all that first and that was a
complicated mess because a lot of the
coders weren't thinking long term they
were just thinking very short term if I
needed what negative 1 and believe it or
not 0 can be a valid value if you're
dealing with age 0 can be a newborn that
is a valid age
so you might want to use negative one as
an uninitialized value so what was
happening was aside from IBM printer
manufacturers were coming out with these
brand-new gigantic multifunction
multipower printers that could do
everything except make coffee and so at
that time when I was working on the OS
to postscript driver my mind manager and
his leader said run simple rule if
you're not backward compatible with
those 2.1 oh don't bother coming in to
work again you've got to be backward
compatible this was the old version then
what was happening is that was prime
directive number one prime directive
number two is Louis this was at the time
when os/2 was going directly
head-to-head with Microsoft remember NT
always too wanted to compete with
Microsoft head-to-head and prime
directive number two is make os/2 as
usable and flexible and powerful as
possible so that as many people can buy
it as a while so what was happening I
have management here telling me one
thing I have the os/2 vendors like the
printers telling me another and I'm sort
of caught between and I think I screamed
a lot like that I have the sound turn
off but I think I screamed a lot like
that during my development days okay I
actually had to get the printer
manufacturers to come and help me out
going to IBM management to say if that
they wanted this feature and they
threatened OS they threaten IBM saying
if you do not add these new features
we're dropping you in other words exit
now think about that for a second you're
you you've written this code and you
have these current security features
let's say ssl but now everybody's saying
you've got two btls and if you don't
implement TLS we're dropping you now you
can say wait a minute that you know
we're fine as it is it's not going to be
a big deal no you need your customers
for support so what are you going to do
to make the change quite easily well
in this case it wasn't easy it was
difficult no correct it was extremely
difficult because I had to maintain the
backward compatibility for 10 I had it
before compatible with these new
printers and to make things even worse
some person in IBM decided to let some
vendors allow them to directly modify
specific printer features by themselves
like aldus pagemaker so I had a focus on
that as well and then to make things a
little bit better I was moving from Boca
Raton to Austin ok and so thanks to this
I missed a great fishing trip and I
missed a great shrimping expedition
because I really wanted to do that when
i got to mobile so here was the new one
that we finally came out very
complicated it took there were a lot of
failures there were times I didn't think
it was going to work this page right
here would change with each printer
manufacturer we finally got it to a way
where everybody was happy if we were to
manage it ourselves the data segment
would grow exponentially imagine 255
printers each with four or five of their
own features and maybe a later version
could add another four or five features
do the math you'll see what I mean what
we did here is we let the printer
manufacturers you just make a selection
you don't care what it is the printer
manufacturer will send the appropriate
come hand and in order to make things a
little bit worse you can't really tell
but skips the the last one that could be
something like what you want duplex but
what if you have a transparency you
don't want duplex with a transparency so
you have to turn this off so we have to
add that into now that in all reality
this was not IBM's fault seriously
because when they originally designed it
they never anticipated this to happen
they just anticipated we just want to
make
simple print driver it was the printer
manufacturers who had all these new they
had their own ideas they wanted their
own support the bankers wanted the old
version of OS too so as I showed in my
previous life you can see all these
outside forces that are coming in and
stepping on you and telling you we we
want this we want that we want it now
and guess who your boss is coming too so
what do you do as far as thinking from a
more flexible and more encapsulated
perspective thinking about that long
term well going to the standard section
it's obviously designed a framework and
you can use something like a July
methodology now some companies still use
waterfall more companies are going to
add jalen I'm going to go a little bit
more into agile in a minute
encapsulation is important encapsulation
is not only great from a object-oriented
perspective but it's also great from a
seed perspective you can do good
encapsulation from a sea perspective
minimizing your global variables because
your customers your customers are going
to take advantage of whatever
opportunity you give them whether you
give it to them or not they will take
advantage of it you want to design
something we're saying I know I'm going
to have to make changes so what do I
have to do from the very beginning to
permit those changes I don't know what
those changes are but is there something
that I can do that makes those changes
possible in the in the almost to example
what I did was use a very primitive
version of XML I allowed multiple
selections various multiple data links
and send it across the network and i
also updated the old version i had to
make sure that both were working fine so
even as these new printers grew it
didn't make any difference it was
flexible enough where you could just add
the new feature that you wanted and it
would just work as is and we would grow
the buffer accordingly it was a very
tedious complicated procedure but it
finally got to work you want to want to
rely on polymorphism on common
interfaces a lot of people think well
I'm going to rely
on this interface for this in this
interface for that what we did with os/2
is we relied on one common interface for
all the drivers we actually simplified
things and if you were a printer
manufacturer you want to add your own
special features we enabled that very
easily by designing that in from the
very beginning it became so easy for
people to meant to add new features HP
for example one a special color support
tektronix wanted their own unique way of
handling their output and we were able
to give it to them now again this is not
dealing with a security per se was more
of integrity but you can see what I mean
that when all these outside forces come
in and expect you to make changes are
you going to be ready for those changes
if Claire comes walking in your door he
says your two-factor authentication is
at work and you're using RSA how easy it
is for you to move to the gemalto model
of two factor authentication your boss
is going to want it now no he wants it
yesterday and he wants it cheap and he
wants it done professionally I mean and
he's going to tell you everything you've
got to make that work so if you design
it right from the very beginning saying
knowing full well I might have to change
this so what do I have to do to make it
portable and encapsulated be modular so
that I can easily go from point A to
point B this may seem obvious to most of
you but believe it or not I come up to
this a lot a lot especially with the
younger developers they create something
and they don't bother to initialize it
or they don't bother to set default
values and then like right up here in
the third bullet point setting all their
variables to a non defined or not not to
you stay I come across this a lot they
define something and they forget to
initialize it appropriately both in
creating and removing now let's let's
make one point clear I can go in and
modify anybody's code here I can go in
and modify the colonel I can go in and
do a lot of things there's only so much
you can do well the one mistake a lot of
software developers make they think that
attackers are
all experts they think they're all
godlike and they can do all these
wonderful things a lot of attackers are
idiots okay I may not be smart enough to
modify your fingerprint but it doesn't
take a rocket scientist to see what you
were doing with your four-digit code as
you were entering in the phone the phone
I was in Singapore one time and I had
lost count because every single time
when I would go on the train to work and
from work I caught no less than five
people entering their four-digit
passcode in front of me I don't need I
can just steal their phone I don't need
any technical expertise I steal your
phone I remember your four-digit
passcode I'm in so you need so when a
lot of people often forget that part
they they set very they forget to
initialize variables at the very
beginning and they forget to reset it to
a non you state at the end that's
important because when you free memory
if you're freeing you from the heap
that's out of your control now but it's
not out of the operating systems control
it's not about somebody else's control
it is just out of your control when you
use it you have to verify all data
before modifications one person told me
I had a great idea in a see you in a sea
program you can write you can create a
hash value for your data structures that
are not modifiable that's an idea or you
can define everything as private by
default and then go to a less secure
state as you're using it that's
important that's more from a
psychological perspective because if
you'd if we have a tendency to think i'm
going to define X as an integer but what
if you define a private value of x as an
integer and that goes with your mindset
it is easier to go from a secure state
to a non-secure state than vice versa
because if you go from a less to a more
secure state you're going to forget
something you're going to make mistakes
and if you're going to make a mistake
why don't you make a mistake on being in
the more secure state a lot of people
make that that error they forget to
define it that way and when you go
through your code analysis you fell you
should have defined this private oh
sorry let me do that get into the
mindset of defining everything
in the most restricted most secure state
known to man it's easier to go out to a
less secure state than vice versa again
it's a it's a it's a psychological issue
think of it from that perspective get
into that mindset improve yourself
because if you do that and you think
that way and you get into that routine
and you go to your new company and you
say I have been able to have less
vulnerabilities than my other co-workers
because that is the way I think and I
can show it with fewer defects with your
problems your new boss that your future
boss is going to like that they see that
lease they see that they like that just
being varying bit all yes I write secure
code no you don't if you can't tell me
what type of what type of work you're
doing writing secure code you're not
writing secure code you should be able
to have metrics with that you should be
able to show something I had the least
amount of rewards from IBM because I was
always the slowest but I was always the
mall so had the fewest number of defects
per line of code and I'm sorry if i'm
selling a boasting myself there were
people who want huge awards for all
these new features but it broke so
easily I had the minimum amount of
features I but I also had the least
amount of defects so I mean think about
it like that you may write a chunk of
code that note that your boss doesn't
see it a big deal but that code you
wrote maybe that mean the difference
between successful implementation and
getting sued for ten million dollars
because you did something stupid people
unfortunately don't get rewarded them
but if you want to be a secure software
developer you've got to think with that
mindset you can write secure code that's
flexible enough that will bend over time
and be adjustable
while maintaining a secure state in the
deletion part its most of the same as
creation you don't have to do everything
the same but what we used to be able to
do and this was even with the old kernel
debugger you would free some memory and
this is even with Java you free some
memory in the Java Java garbage
collection kick said sure I can probably
find a way to bypass it but you need to
make your due diligence effort in order
to implement it you can't be perfect but
regulators are not looking for
perfection they're looking for due
diligence and if you're the manager of a
company and you're not promoting this
with your employees you're not a manager
you suck I'm serious you do because i
had many arguments with boss they just
wanted it now they wanted an immediate
they didn't care about anything else
we'll fix it later I guarantee if later
never comes do it now you must control
the data at all times you own it you
must maintain a secure state once it's
out of your control it better be god
because I will find it so why are you
doing with standards this is I like this
page and I added this because think
about what is on there once customers
use your code they're in now Apple has a
lot of clout they can change
environments they can make a lot of
changes and you just bend with it that's
what Apple has the your product may not
have that much clout so if you're going
to make changes 10 your customers react
to it you may be more secure but if it
breaks your customers I don't even care
who you are your manager is not going to
want to release a product that breaks
customers they want something that works
they want to offer a solution customers
may be a little understanding of you but
if you if you are too inflexible or you
don't adjust properly and it causes too
much impact on their end they're going
to just drop you and go to your
competitor great you're secure but
they're using
your competitor you're on an unemployed
secure developer but you're still secure
changing products will be expensive so
what are you doing from the very
beginning don't think that you can think
about our design flexibility later it
won't happen for those of you who think
it's going to happen it won't okay so
one common area in the in in looking for
flexibilities through the static code
analysis now what I usually do when i'm
looking at a static code I never I don't
I never I never liked the idea of giving
an end user the ability to access data
directly it's always through an
interface like for example in the 1980s
the drinking age in many states in the
country was 18 okay eventually it was
bumped up to 21 you are you on the code
that confirms if you're within a valid
range to drink so if you if you give
your customer the direct the direct
ability to read what's in your date
what's in your data structure or
variable and he can change that now that
impacts you but if you work through an
interface you can just bump up if it's
less than 18 or let you can go up to
less than 21 much simpler and it doesn't
impact your customer of course your
custom rule has to do a little bit of
reasonable development on his or her end
but at least you're doing your due
diligence think of the change and again
I've worked with PCI enough and what
used to work rate and PCI doesn't work
right anymore the companies that
survived the change with PCI are the
ones that role with the new changes of
PCI don't be so inflexible that when pci
makes a change you're scrambling to fix
what's inside your code okay now i
mention about yes i'm still going to go
into code analysis now one of the
problems with coded out of static code
analysis is you can miss something like
heartbleed or shell shock a lot of code
analysts just miss that remember older
versions of encryption work but newer
versions didn't another problem with
static code analysis
is that you can look at a problem from
an immediate perspective and say yes
this is good or no this isn't but if
you're doing interactive evaluations
over time how do you know when you
started here is going to get over here
you've got to keep that in mind too so
you need to understand the big picture
static code analysis tends to be more
small but it's still very useful because
you can at least identify immediate
problems and correct them before they're
released now in the in the area to to
make yourself more flexible oh wow I
forgot okay you've got to be more
modular you have to think about
modularity encapsulation create a
component sort of a black box if you
will that does a certain function test
the hell out of that make sure it works
in and move on this is more like the
agile software development rather than
method rather than the waterfall
development method I hate people who
don't document and nobody seems to do
that anymore I want to know why you did
it like the way you did and I'd be
people of all the time for failing to
document if you have to have a
dependency or you have to have a
limitation and you don't explain why
your code sucks but you may have a valid
reason why you had to be limited or you
had a dependency if you give me an
explanation I can understand why but if
you don't explain it and I will not
permit any soft soft static code
analysis without proper documentation I
don't need you to write a book but I
want you to understand I want to know
why you did what you did and in every
static code analysis I've ever done
every type of code review I BP and they
hate me for this they don't think
documentation is needed anymore in the
old days we had a document very well you
had to understand what you're doing and
you had to make sure that the person
who's going to take over your position
understood it as well okay and I'm again
any data that is public or protected as
be considered untrusted you must verify
at all times now going into the
modularity perspective what I like to do
is I have
vertical functionality in here and then
I have sort of like a buffer because
when you change it over time from one to
another it's easier you're still doing
this a poor process but if you if you're
more flexible to your customers needs
and to regulatory needs at least it
gives your customers and it gives them a
little bit they have to do less work
it's easier on you it's easier on your
code or overall there may be a cut okay
a case where you might have to deal with
characters that might be an impact in
your database as this cartoon says that
was Sandro is a legitimate last name my
sister's friend was last named
Alessandro but if you have to move it
over to a database environment or have a
somebody read it from your buffer are
you giving him the opportunity to
transfer these characters to something
that's more satisfactory to that
person's perspective so you need to have
cross-functional teams that's why you
need to get your database people in you
need to get other people on your team so
that you know what they need so you can
provide it to them because if they have
to make the change more or less they're
going to do a poor job and I'm not going
to go into this example because we don't
have a lot of time but the example on
the top is something more the way I like
to do it because if you change undefined
age that can be an uninitialized value
minus one can be an undefined value or
non an undefined eight in this case you
can use the current status in this code
but what if undefined age is changed
will it work in this environment maybe
maybe not this is more this may be a
little larger but it's a little bit
safer and it's a little bit easier to
change if you're forced to change your
values for some reason okay in modular
and flexible code development you need
to focus more on the agile methodology
the waterfall method you can use it but
it's complex and it's hard because
you've got to make small iterative
changes over time you've got to think of
it from a class perspective
or if you're doing a non object-oriented
you've got to think of it from a
component perspective if you want to
learn how to do some good software
development read NASA's documentation
zon software seriously they really take
software development seriously okay so I
am at a time and I know I've got to give
them but i will make one more thing
career this not only helps you in your
development think about it from your
careers perspective I guarantee if you
come back five years from now you've
probably change jobs be the person who
is more provides more metrics who
provides more flexibility who is more
aware of the long-term development and
you will do better in your career you're
welcome to take any welcome to connect
with me are there any questions and
thank you very much thank you for
attending Thank You Larry thank you for
your time