alright so today the title of my talk is
managing certificates and TLS endpoints
so you know kind of inspiration for this
Henry and I who's right here in the
audience we work on the security
engineering team at Rackspace we're in
charge of managing a large number of
product in points44 ssl/tls stuff so you
know we kind of have an inside look into
some of this at scale beyond you know
maybe you have one website whatever we
have very many to tracks so and since
heartbleed everyone's kind of paying
attention SSL or paying a lot of
attention to us a cell so all the all
the little things that maybe you got by
with in years past where your config
wasn't perfect now those are those are
heavily heavily scrutinized so many
headaches later where we have a tool
that all kind of talk about a little bit
more in a minute but that helps us
manage all the endpoints that we're
dealing with so let's just start with a
quick very quick primer so TLS SSL you
know obviously used for all the good
stuff CIA confidentiality integrity and
authentication its encryption for data
in transit and so it started off there
was SSL v1 which was never actually a
thing that you could install and and run
with it was more of a spec so what we
have is SSL be two and three and TLS 1
11 and 12 you get it on just about every
device your phone is probably talking to
Google over SSL right as we talk so
there's all kinds of stuff that that's
using it and it's it seems very simply
get set up with because it's you know
there's there's a couple config changes
and you can get that sell very quickly
but what we're going to talk about today
is kind of what you have to do once you
get over that first step what do you
have to do you know when you've been
managing a certificate and a server for
you know for a while so TLS adoption is
increasing browsers are starting to call
out explicitly like in the past e a
regular site without SSL looked like
is just fine this is totally cool now if
you go to you know you go to any site in
firefox or chrome that doesn't have ssl
they're going to tell you about it which
is totally valid i'm happy about that
but it means that there's going to be a
lot more ssl endpoints that you're going
to have to start managing so again it
can't just be turned on and left alone a
lot of times but you know at least some
of the things you know the cost has come
down a lot in fact i'll talk about this
a little bit later but let's encrypt
which is a kind of a community
certificate authority they have actually
just gotten there first their first
certificate trusted and they're free so
again TLS is going to just keep going up
so what is it used for obviously web
services but email IRC all kinds of
stuff epns they all they all kind of use
ssl/tls some extent so there's a lot of
moving parts certificate authorities I
don't want to go into too much detail on
this you guys probably know most of it
but there's a lot there's lots of little
pieces that would have to be configured
and can't just gotta be left alone so
certificate authorities protocols
ciphers all these things kind of add up
to having a secure TLS SL entation it's
like I kind of said earlier we've got
you know multiple protocol versions to
work with you've got certs of varying
you know issuing dates with with
different expiration dates etc so you
know maybe one endpoint you can kind of
set a little reminder and outlook for
yourself to go you know hey i need to go
renew my ssl cert you know on this day
but you're going to have a very full
calendar once you get enough of these so
there's a lot of other you know miss
configuration running on outdated
hardware having having a large number to
manage as i've said is also fun so
intermediate certs expire so people
they're actually signing your cert
sometimes that can happen certs can get
you know revoked for various reasons
maybe somebody checked them into github
oops time to delete it revoke everything
start over redeploy so you get that
you also get some every once a while
you're actually see a will get
compromised and they have to take all
the certs away and do it all over again
so that's fun and self signed cert
spacek alee get rid of a lot of the good
security principle of ssl so they're
kind of useless in a lot of ways but
they get deployed a lot so so there's
always new vulnerabilities poodle is one
of many but there this is an actual ssl
protocol itself so poodles a an attack
on sslv3 specifically you get bugs in
the actual encryption software basically
as you can already tell right the point
of this is not to delve deep into a lot
of these different issues right it's
just to simply say that there are a
large number of things for which you
will have to renew your ssl certificates
change the configuration etc regulation
compliance so TLS v1 is going to be
deprecated for PCI at some point and
sha-1 signed certificates are flagged as
insecure if they're signed through
january first 2017 and the browsers
telling you about it now all right so
maybe you're getting a sense now of how
we all feel about this right a little
little humor to brighten things up right
so there's a large number of things that
can go wrong but the idea here is that
like eventually you can get it all under
control and it's it's normal it's fine
it's normal all right so let's get the
cipher so just quickly brushing over
this but basically when when connecting
the client had server have to agree on
how they're going to talk to each other
and unfortunate well kind of from a
security perspective it's a little
unfortunate that the client can
essentially dictate the terms under
which this is this takes place because
they they can essentially say I only
support one thing do you support that
one thing no okay well I only support
this one other thing now and so they can
basically go along a list of insecure
and you know it's bad ciphers and that's
that's kind of what happens in in the
log jam attack where a man in the middle
can actually force the force the client
to connect to the server over an
insecure
channel basically again very simple
simplified here so this is what this is
what you might be familiar with you know
if you've dug into setting up engine X
or anything like that to set different
ciphers SSL cybers this long string here
it actually has a meaning it's not just
a bunch of in cahaba incomprehensible
words so the first bit here is your your
key exchange algorithm so this would be
elliptical diffie-hellman you've got
your authentication algorithm which this
one's RSA and then you've got your key
attributes so aes-128 bit CBC mode and
then you've got your Mac hash algorithm
at the end I don't want to get too
divisive on this but this is kind of how
I feel and I'm sure lots of other people
have different opinions about it there
are lots of fun elliptic curve things
that you could support they have varying
supporting clients so you can you can go
way down this rabbit hole the things on
the left there are pretty sane and
pretty agreed upon again you can go a
lot further you can go a lot less but it
kind of depends on who what clients are
you going to support if you have if you
have to as part of your business support
really old hardware or really old
operating systems it may be the case
that you have to use some of the stuff
that you're not totally comfortable with
but in general you should be pretty good
as long as you tend towards the stuff on
the left hand side of this so that's not
all you have plenty of other
configuration things to to worry about
so again you know that table but but
this also mentions openssl so you want
to you want to be up to date on your
version of openssl that was the
everybody remembers the fun time that we
had in April last year that's heart
bleeds so we we want to be running the
newest openssl unfortunately it seems
that the ssl landscape is further
fragmenting so update your openssl g and
you TLS libre SSL boring ssl and all the
other ones so
let's see yeah sometimes you're kind of
unfortunately hardware sometimes put you
in a bad spot so you might have Hardware
load balancers or firewalls that don't
support the protocols or ciphers that
you want to support so sometimes you
can't even go in there and just you know
twiddle some bits in your configuration
sometimes you got to call your hardware
provider which is unfortunate when that
happens in the out like I mentioned
sometimes you know the business wants to
support ie6 and so you got to support
ie6 and that comes with compromises so
here's an example of configuration I
won't go too far into this other than to
just kind of show you what you're
dealing with you know there's there's
more there's more in-depth examples of
this and I'll get to this a bit but
there's a great site called cypher list
and they have configurations for lots of
different things so yeah you can get
again this is kind of just hammering at
home you can get a lot of things wrong
right so CA bundles ciphers the honor
cypher order is is worth mentioning
that's that's talking about how
essentially when those clients and
servers are negotiating how they're
going to talk to each other honor cypher
order says generally I want to use like
as the server saying generally I want to
use the things that I have have chosen
let's see oh and this is a fun one if
you've got several servers and a load
balancing let's say in a round-robin
configuration or something you hit it
the first time everything looks great
it's all wonderful and then you get some
some reports from somebody that oh wait
actually you know I looked at it and you
know I'm getting this horrible you know
export create encryption whatever so you
have to make sure that all the servers
have been to picture the same way
perfect forward secrecy is another fun
fun thing that you can enable so
basically the idea what this is to
prevent a compromise of the ssl private
key from being able to be used to go
back in decrypt sessions that have
already been encrypted with it so you
think state level actors if they're
sucking up all this data if they ever
get your key they can go back in
read everything but the idea here is you
use ephemeral keys that are used for
shorter lengths of time and that you
can't get back from the private key to
those ephemeral keys strict Transport
Security is something in the web realm
so this basically tells your browser hey
this site should only ever be on SSL
don't hit it on anything else we good
cool and then your browser basically
from then on knows that at no point
should anyone tell me that I should be
hitting this on port 80 without SSL I
always want to head ssl so so let's just
go over some of the vulnerabilities
heartbleed was kind of a wake-up call
I'm sure for for more than just me in
this audience that was that was that was
what I would characterize is a bad day
and then we got you know we've gotten
several since then that haven't they've
all they've all wanted to be as bad big
and bad as heartbleed but they haven't
quite wowed us as much but there's a
number you know there's things that
poodle affecting ssl three there's an
anachronism of the american system which
is the the export ciphers which which
were kind of rediscovered this year so
there's this there's a mechanism for
protecting against TLS downgrading I
won't go too much into it again but
essentially this is just to prevent any
sort of monkeying with with the
connection by a by a man in the middle
for TLS so export ciphers are a fun fun
thing that are still around today we had
laws at some point excuse me saying that
essentially you couldn't export crypto
if it was a certain level of strength
more or less and so what they sort of
agreed on was you could use these really
short keys and that would be okay right
so you would have what they consider to
be sort of civilian level encryption but
the government always knowing that they
could probably break it right and so if
you ever see for instance if you're if
you're looking at your ciphers or
whatever you're testing an endpoint and
you see export you don't want it you
don't want it at all we're not under
that
that that legal restriction anymore so
get rid of it throw it away if you're
building a new ssl library build it out
throw it away we don't need it right so
this might be kind of what you're
thinking at this point like it seems
like a lot right I mean I thought I just
kind of plugged in my certificate and
was ready to go but certs expired
servers are reconfigured if you're in a
you know very fast-moving chef you know
managed ansible managed thing things are
changing daily maybe more than that you
know you get new vulnerabilities coming
out fairly fairly frequently whether in
the protocol or in the actual software
and you know just as the slow march of
time goes on we get better computers as
we get better computers we kind of have
to reevaluate wait a second it was
supposed to take this long at this time
but we actually got there faster so I'll
crap actually we have to go back and
read you know rework all these
assumptions that we built in over the
years of oh well sha-1 may not be
perfect but it'll be good until this
time and that time just keep seen seems
to keep sliding backwards so to drive
home once again you need to constantly
monitor your endpoints it's like
constantly like all the time all day
every day I have to be doing this like I
have other stuff to do SSL is not at the
top of my list here so we've got a
couple tools thankfully that you can use
this is mostly getting geared towards
the the unix linux folks but the openssl
s client is is actually pretty great for
just debugging stuff it doesn't it's not
security focused it's purely for getting
the raw information it will give you
some information about as the handshakes
happening it will monitor that traffic
it can just give you a lot of detail
there test SSL about SH is one of my
favorites personally it's it's a free
command-line tool you can read that but
basically it has no setup it has very
few dependencies other than openssl you
can just spin it up on any box basically
any linux box and run it and it's ready
to go and it's it's more security
focused so
you can kind of see this that could fit
the whole screen shot in here but you
can kind of see here you've got you know
ssl b2 b3 not offered that's okay so
you've kind of got it'll tell you a
little bit about you know what the you
know what the good what the good
configuration looks like and what you
know if anything if you know something
is enabled it shouldn't be it'll tell
you it's handy and then we've got qualis
ssl ads so many of you are probably
familiar with this one it's very popular
at this point and actually we utilize it
for the the TLS manager that's coming up
soon but basically they they hope you
condense all this information down and
they give you a nice little score and
score is really handy if you're if
you're passing this off of somebody that
doesn't care about ssl but you hand them
a big red f they know they don't want
the big red f right they might not know
what it takes to get away from big red f
but they know they don't want the big
red f so this is kind of how the the
score system breaks down you can you
know you can kind of debate some of this
stuff maybe this is more important than
that but in general it's a pretty good
picture of if you're getting an a-plus
you're pretty good right there maybe
maybe a little nitpicky things you can
change here and there but if you're at
an A+ like for all intents and purposes
you're pretty good but then it goes all
the way down to f you know like i said
if you're using md5 or you know you're
using you know 768 bit keys or something
or you're you know maybe only ssl to or
you know something like that then it'll
it'll very explicitly tell you that
that's wrong so every once and a right
you want an a you want an A+ so this is
another one cypher list I kind of
brought it up earlier but they have they
have a lot of good configurations for a
lot of different different server
software so H a proxy postfix openssh
Apache an engine acts are usually you
know whenever anybody is recommending
something about ssl they have something
about that but you know you have to go
fix postfix and you know that's not
that's not as widely distributed so you
know it's helpful for making
recommendations product teams but i will
we'll have this one little caveat so a
copy and paste part is really nice but
before you send it off to all your devs
i would go take a look at it and make
sure it's actually what you want because
there you have to make trade-offs like
i've said you you have to know who the
clients are that you want to support
right and so this this list these these
these configurations are geared towards
giving you reasonable compatibility with
again some security trade-off so you
just have to decide for yourself whether
that's reasonable for for what you're
trying to support but you know in a lot
of cases if you're just going to use a
copy and paste format you don't want it
to be something that the implementer has
to go and like twiddle you know little
bits here and there like you want it to
just kind of work and so that's this is
helpful for that that ssl is as i love
it honestly it's it's pretty simple but
basically they have a bunch of a bunch
of subdomains set up off of their site
and if you just go to the bad ssl site
they've got them all listed there but
for you to be able to test so if you've
got some tools or whatever that you're
trying to work on I mean trying to make
sure that you know they catch this issue
or that issue they've pretty much got
every way that you can get an ssl cert
wrong they've got they've got an end
point for you to test on so it's handy
handy handy for that so this is Putin
laughing at you for wanting to manage
all those endpoints manually maybe none
of you do but if you do this is what he
thinks of it anyway so this is what this
is what we use in our team to kind of
keep up with some of this so I'll get to
a video of it in a second but you can
kind of get the idea so you know we've
got all these endpoints that are
associated with a product and then on
the side you've got that helpful ssl
labs score so what what TLS manager does
for you is once you've kind of set up
all the products and end points that you
want to test you can scan them daily you
could scan them weekly you can scan a
monthly whenever you feel like you need
to and it will tell you the ssl
vulnerabilities that it finds as a
result of that scan it'll tell you when
certs are about to expire it'll email so
the other nice thing is it's it helps
you be even lower touch excuse me you
can
not you can put in the product owners
email addresses and it will actually
send automated reports to the specific
product owner if you want to do that and
it keeps a history of everything so that
you can kind of track things over time
so let's hope and pray that the video
works sweet so right now we're just kind
of on the on the main page so you can
see we've got a couple bad ssl endpoints
and they're not scoring very well
because they're bad obviously so you can
sort you can sort by any of these
different fields so if you're trying to
figure out you know when was what's the
oldest you know what's the thing that we
we checked least recent their most
recently whatever you can check the
scores out so how many how many failing
certs do we have etc so you can go to
the details and this will tell you what
specifically gave it that score what's
wrong with it that made it you know made
it in half whatever and so you can see
how it did over time so you can see you
know let's say for example that that
somebody just did a deploy and oops we
you know fat fingered a config option or
we forgot to ship this config or
whatever it is you can see well we were
getting an A until you know this day and
then something went wrong so you can
kind of go back and that helps you trace
back what it is that may be caused
caused things to go wrong for you so I
think that's about it on this you can
see on the side there the the different
kind of stuff that you can that you can
do here so setting up a product etc I
think you guys probably get the point so
I'll go ahead and move on so you can go
get it on aunty on github on the rack or
lab / TLS manager it's apache license
and pull requests are more than welcome
i think there's probably room for us to
support more ssl tests and stuff like
that like i said we're mostly working
off of the the qualys ssl labs api right
now but for the most part it covers
almost everything so
so let's uh just just to kind of tie
this into real life right because
everything that I've said so far is kind
of in an imagination land a little bit
so there's there's uh there was an
announcement let's see I guess it's been
a couple days now but google has decided
that all of their products chromium etc
Android everything they're going to
ditch openssl they're going to take on
boring ssl why does that matter what you
know why do we care about that well as
the you know you can you can say what
you like about how openssl has been
managed over the years it's probably not
a code base that everyone in this room
has contributed to and reads frequently
you know if it can be a bit of a beast
but you know as we start as we start
fragmenting the landscape you're just
adding more and more and more potential
for things to go wrong and so this is
you know it's potentially a good thing
right i mean you getting rid of some
cruft basically their idea is to take
the little pieces of openssl that they
want and rebuild everything else and so
again it has potential to be good it
also has potential to go but go wrong
and the more the more ssl
implementations and so on that are out
there the fewer people that you're going
to have looking at any individual one of
them so you know maybe a win maybe a
loss but it's another thing that changed
and this is all stuff that's changed
since i started working on this
presentation so this isn't you know the
whole year in ssl this is like the last
couple weeks so i think i mentioned this
briefly earlier but let's encrypt which
is a free CA for for issuing ssl
certificates they just I think this week
got their first certificate trusted by
most of the major browsers and so what
this is going to do is you know they've
been they've been kind of spinning up on
this for a while but they're finally at
the point where they were to hand you a
certificate through their process they
don't they don't have at this point I
believe they've gotten away I don't
think they have any other dependencies
they are trusted so they can start
ripping off search whenever they want
basically that's probably a good thing
right that's probably a good thing
there's a you know it's always good that
there's more ssl ssl sites you know
personally I use an extension called
HTTPS Everywhere so this makes me very
happy because I hate when I go to a site
and even when I when I try they have no
ssl right so this this just lowers the
the barrier to entry but again going
back to what we were saying earlier more
SSL and points to manage right so sha-1
is totally broken everyone scream and go
crazy well so this this was a was a
paper that came out that essentially
said like I said earlier the sha-1 sort
of deadline of who it's it's very scary
after this point that deadline just
keeps seeming to move back a little bit
more and more and so this is this has
taken from Bruce Schneier blog they've
got a they've got a full paper about it
but essentially the thing is they were
able to find a collision in the
compression system of the algorithm I'm
not going to stand here and pretend like
I know exactly what these guys are
talking about but what I can tell you is
a lot of people see this and they go ah
you know they go crazy but but really
what this means is that that that sha-1
window for browser trust and everything
else it's just moving back and so I
wanted to highlight at the end just just
to kind of dial it back a little bit
final line is free start collisions like
the one presented here do not directly
imply a collision for sha-1 so you know
you can go back to you know you don't
have to start fighting the fire today
but it's it's coming it's on the horizon
we can see it from far away we can't
tell when it's going to get here but
it's getting here quicker than we
thought so yeah always fun then you have
the diffie-hellman apocalypse which
seems to have come down on us and the
NSA has apparently broken trillions of
encrypted web and VPN connections and
that it but this is all based on is
essentially the NSA has a budget big
enough that they could build a computer
could maybe break diffie-hellman and so
a lot of the again the assumption is
that all this stuff rests on their not
fixed their never fixed and so one of
the assumptions that this is that this
is challenging is for the longest time
basically everybody packaged up the same
sort of primitive pieces for
diffie-hellman and they'd ship it out
with everything right so everyone had
the same one but because of the way that
the math works and how diffie-hellman
works etc everyone was like yeah that's
fine that's cool because you're not
using it directly you're using it to
seed something and derive something from
it so everyone kind of thought that it
was fine but what they've realized is
well if you have an 11 billion dollar
budget you can actually do some things
that lessen your security there a bit
and so like for example like like engine
X and a lot of things a lot of times
they will just come with excuse me out
of the box support for the sort of
standard default very widely replicated
set of diffie-hellman parameters and
that's great news for the NSA because if
they can build one machine this is what
this all rests on they're going to build
one machine that breaks one set of
parameters right so they're not going to
break everything this this whole this
whole you know doomsday scenario relies
on the fact that everybody's using the
same diffie-hellman parameters begin
with it's actually pretty easy to
generate your own it does take a while
because it needs a lot of randomness but
it's not the end of the world as ours
might have you believe so yeah these are
just these are just like I said tying it
back to the real world and very recent
history so closing thoughts um basically
it's hard right i mean it's it's really
not that hard right it's really just
there's a lot of it but but if you can
actually keep up on it and it's not it's
not a customer calling you and saying oh
hey i can't get to your site because
it's broken or my browser says that it's
insecure it's you know your way out
ahead of it that's where you want to be
because at any given moment
one of these fun things like you know
sha-1 or whatever can drop on you and
then you get to go really fight some
fires so ssl/tls library bugs cipher
cipher suite bugs protocol bugs all
these things can happen and so it's
really really handy we found to manage
it in an automated way to keep from
going crazy anybody have any questions
and Henry I want you to come up here so
that you can you know help us do some
Q&A he's my co-presenter everybody not
very interested in the presenting
everyone gets it cool all right sweet oh
yeah sure I can Bobby speak up the
question is could you maybe talk a
little bit more about ephemeral private
keys because what we are used to using
in our environment is just private keys
in there out there with every Apache web
server that is right employed so I
personally don't like it in him I don't
think any of us like it yeah so what's
the way out or yeah so it's actually so
if we go back go back in my slides a
little bit get this guy again so if you
look at what this slide is calling out
is essentially that on the on the cipher
Suites when you're configuring your
server or whatever so in genetics Apache
whatever you're running the little ease
at the end are supposed to signify that
that use uses ephemeral keys so it's
actually not I don't think that you have
to do anything super special to generate
new keys it's something that's kind of
handled on its own and so if you if you
look out for those ciphers if that's
with all that you want to support then I
believe actually ssl labs and some of
the other ssl tools and tell you if
perfect forward secrecy is enabled if
there are ciphers that support it and
you can you can kind
go through the list and make sure that
all of them do if that's what you want
to deploy unfortunately I can't get too
deep into the crypto on not a
unfortunately not an expert in it but
yeah it is actually thankfully fairly
easy to get set up with so good stuff
always good when it's just a toggle
switch right anything else so I have one
last little bit I've been asked get to
the last slide here real quick so like I
said I work at Rackspace and I am also
working on the OpenStack security
project which is the name of kind of the
group that does things like
vulnerability management they do stuff
like they issue advisories if there's
something an OpenStack that needs a CBE
etc and so if any of you guys work with
OpenStack and are interested in getting
involved come talk to me after there's
there's a IRC channel that you can get
in touch with us on on freenode and we
have weekly meetings if you want to come
tag along and see you know kind of what
we're working on there's a couple cool
projects bandit which is a Python static
analyzer and actually this might this
might pertain to you there's one called
anchor that's for doing a femoral pki
management and so I unfortunately can't
go to too deep on that but it's it's an
interesting idea i'll say that got a
mailing list as well so if you're
interested like I said come see me or
join out so thank you
you