and today we are going to be talking
about allah's dependency track
so uh again real quick about me and then
we'll get to the the actual meet of the
of the conversation but uh
i'm the creator and the current lead of
the dependency track project um i'm also
the the co-lead as well as the chair of
the cyclone dx core working group
co-leader and co-author of the owasp
scvs project
and i do just a tremendous amount of
work i guess in the software
transparency space and in supply chain
space but what i actually get paid to do
is software security architecture
at a leadership level at servicenow
so um
real quick background i guess um
dependency track is a flagship oas
project it was started in 2013.
uh it is highly mature there's a really
big community of of adopters that that
use it
if you name a commercial vendor or
organization
they're probably on the list of people
who have either tried it or or are using
it today as of now i think we've got
about four million docker pulls uh to
date so it's it's fairly strong
and uh it's apache 2.0 licensed
um
so dependency track is really
uh centered around this concept of
software bill of materials and uh me and
patrick dwyer will be doing a um a
separate talk for os cyclone dx in about
90 minutes uh which is yet another
flagship owasp project but that
particular project is uh specifically
designed to be a software bill of
materials standard
um and dependency track is kind of um
based around the this this whole idea of
a software bill of materials so real
quick what is a software bill material
well an analogy would be the list of
ingredients on on the back of the food
label right on the back of a
of an energy bar which is what this is i
have a list of ingredients and by
by providing the the list of ingredients
i as a potential consumer can make
risk-based decisions for example if i am
allergic to to nuts for example well
this tells me that this ingredients list
tells me that i have peanuts and as a
potential
you know
allergy to that
that allows me to determine whether or
not i want to take that risk or not well
in the software world the analogy kind
of transfers to something like this
right
i as an organization might have an
allergic reaction to uh to apache struts
it's a it's a really easy project to
pick on just because there's been so
many different types of the same classes
of vulnerabilities
but it's it's along those lines right so
if i have a list of prohibited
components that i just don't want in my
environment
list of projects for example that that
maintain those or just uh want to
identify if a particular component has
known vulnerabilities this analogy
allows me to to do those types of use
cases
so dependency track is really again it's
centered around the concept of software
building materials
again patrick dwyer and i uh in 90
minutes from now are going to be doing a
talk on cyclone dx which is a another
flagship oas project it's the deleting
software build material standard it's uh
it's interesting uh in that it is the um
it's basically a standard that
took uh individuals and vendors that are
you know were experts in the security
space or in the security space creating
a a bill of materials standard for
software security use cases and of
course backed and and and
and what not by the leading uh
security foundation which is owass so
huge amount of credibility there
and uh i i
highly encourage everyone who's
interested in the subject to also catch
the the other talk 90 minutes from now
so what exactly does dependency track do
well
it consumes analyzes and produces
s-bombs at high velocity
okay
what does that mean
well it's ideal for use in modern build
pipelines so whether or not you are
doing continuous integration continuous
delivery that sort of thing it's ideal
for the for these types of uh these
types of use cases
it's also ideal for procurement and m a
case um if i am procuring software from
a
maybe a vendor or if i am trying to
maybe
investigate um if i wanted to acquire a
company um s-bombs are a really good use
for those types of use cases and
dependency track although it's it's
optimized for highly automated
environments it does support manual use
cases so you can get s-bombs from your
vendors from your from your
organizations that you might want to
acquire and ingest those s-bombs and
analyze those manually as well
and it's really designed dependency
track is really designed to answer the
question what is affected and if so
where so imagine imagine i have 10 000
assets in my environment and
a shiny new vulnerability with a brand
new logo comes up and i want to know if
i'm affected by that thing or not um
if i have s-bombs for all of my assets i
can very quickly identify which assets
in my environment actually have
that particular
component that vulnerable component so
then i can you know maybe proactively
put in mitigations in place maybe wafts
or maybe i just have to pull the plug
for that particular you know uh asset
for until it can get patched whatever
the case is at least i can quickly
identify what that thing is
so
conceptually i have an asset it could be
a microservice it could be a monolithic
application it could be
it could be a an iot toaster or an uh or
a camera uh it doesn't really matter
what it is but i have an asset and i
have a bill of material that describes
the software stack and potentially the
hardware uh for that particular asset
and then conceptually i would analyze it
so that's the 30 000 foot view uh coming
down a few thousand feet though and uh
let's look at a typical workflow
so the first thing that i want to do is
actually
create or acquire the s-bomb and
creating s-bombs is fairly elementary
there's plus tools in the cyclone dx
tools center that allows you to do it
it's not hard
and of course you can acquire those from
from vendors as well
regardless of how you get one
that's the first step
the next step is to consume it into
dependency track so you ingest it into
dependency track either through
automation whether or not it's in your
ci cd pipeline uh or you can manually
upload it in the user interface if you
so choose but the the goal is to get it
into the dependency track
and then dependency track from there on
is going to analyze the contents of that
software builder material
so it's going to break down all the list
of components right and start analyzing
all of the listed components it's going
to analyze them for security risk it's
going to analyze them for operational
risk maybe things that are too old for
example and it's also going to
analyze them for license risk so if
you've got licensed policies created
that sort of thing it'll analyze it for
that type of risk as well and it's going
to going to con
it's going to do this on a continuous
basis so
even after you've uploaded your your
software bill material at a minimum that
project that you uploaded it to is going
to be analyzed every 24 hours so um if i
have a asset in my in my environment
that i got a bill of material from
a year ago um it's still that inventory
for that asset is still going to be
continuously analyzed every 24 hours and
guess what if a new vulnerability comes
up whatever the case is
i'm going to get notified of that
in my environment so um keeping the
information
about what's potentially wrong with with
these assets isn't very useful i need to
create some streams so that i can create
actionable things based on the
intelligence that dependency track is
providing so there's a lot of
finding information that dependency
track provides with these with these
streams
uh everything to know everything about
the vulnerability for example
uh what assets what things that that are
uh affected by that obviously the
severity and that sort of thing as well
so that you have enough information to
make real-time risk-based decisions so
if i wanted to uh page my my operations
team at two o'clock in the morning that
might be one of the things that i do or
maybe i automatically create a jira
ticket right whatever the case is these
are things that you can potentially do
and we also integrate with uh with
various types of chat ops in in those
types of things as well so we can
integrate with slack microsoft teams uh
you can create your own if you so choose
email is still a thing i guess uh so you
can you can do that as well but the idea
is is to get the data in and out of
dependency track as efficiently as
possible so that organizations can make
better risk-based decisions
so with that let's let's actually take a
little bit of a demo of of what
dependency track does and kind of how it
does it
so let me share my my other window here
and that's going to be
let's see this browser right here and
let me go back to the
to the dashboard here so when you first
log into dependency track this is kind
of what you're going to see is is your
dashboard so at the top here you've got
a lot of time series metrics for the the
number of vulnerabilities that exist in
my project portfolio which is basically
the aggregate of all things that i'm
tracking
uh all the different different projects
that are potentially at risk
the number of components in my
environment that i'm tracking and some
risk scores it's basically a weighted
severity score is essentially what it is
but uh again there's a bunch of time
series metrics here uh we were really
true believers in time series because we
really want to know are we doing better
or worse over a given period of time
maybe it's over a given release or a
given quarter whatever the case is not
only for the portfolio as a whole but on
a per project basis right so if i'm
tracking
the a new development of something i
could i can track the how well are we
doing uh in that particular project over
time
um
like i said everything is kind of a
project so a project could be an
application a microservice
could be that iot toaster that that i
that i threw out there earlier a project
is just a container of some sorts and in
fact it could be a container as well um
here i've got a couple different
projects identified and we'll go through
a few of these to kind of show you show
you what they are in fact um i'm gonna
i'm gonna choose web goat just because
it's an oas project
and again you'll see the time series
metrics uh am i is it doing better or
worse over time uh looks like uh looks
like it's about the same
you'll see any policy violations if
there are any i don't think i've
actually set up any policy uh
criteria in this particular case the
number of components you can you can see
so if i'm increasing the number of
components uh i can actually see that
because it might be important to me one
of the deming principles who was a
supply chain among other things guru
is really about using the fewer and
better suppliers so
do i really want to increase the the
number of components in my project
unnecessarily probably not
but this this allows me some
visualizations on am i doing that or not
because every component obviously
introduces potential risk
um but going into these some of these
tabs here this is basically the list of
of ingredients right this is this is the
contents of my s-bomb right here so this
tells me i have 136 components and it's
going to tell me the the name of those
components the version this little
arrow thing over here is going to tell
me whether or not it's out of date or
not and this little warning says
that it that this particular component
is out of date a little green one just
says it it's the current version
uh the group if one exists not all
ecosystems have the concept of a group
but we we all kind of have the concept
of internal components and internal
components are these first-party
components that we as an organization
might actually create so we can we can
separate out the third party from the
first party components if the license
could be identified or not it's going to
be here and of course if there's any
known vulnerabilities in here or not
um
[Music]
you can also so you can go into like the
component itself for example this is
like looking at bootstrap uh 337 and i
can see over here that there's a number
of vulnerabilities identified
but let's go back to the let's go back
to the project here and i want to show
you the dependency graph because when
you import the software bill material
yes it's a list of ingredients which is
great but how did the list of
ingredients actually get there well the
dependency graph actually tells me how
it got there so this is my direct
dependencies for example and then going
on from there these are kind of my
transitive dependencies and it it it
keeps on going it keeps on going from
there
so this is one visualization that exists
today in the dependency graph there's
there's more visualizations coming in
the future
but not every
third-party component
even if it's vulnerable
it may not necessarily be impacted by
the application right your application
may not necessarily be impacted by by a
vulnerable component just because
something is vulnerable doesn't mean
your application is automatically going
to be vulnerable sometimes it may but in
many cases it will not so we we
typically have to um to take a
risk-based approach and actually look at
some of these findings so this allows us
to do that
so if i wanted to look at this critical
uh jackson data bind
issue here i can see that a i have a
description of what the problem is
and uh like a lot of static analyzes
like a lot of static analysis tools i
can actually make a comment as well as
an audit decision about am i exploitable
to this thing or not so maybe i am
exploitable or maybe it's a a false
positive or maybe
and this is going to be a lot of the
case sometimes maybe i'm just not
affected by this particular
vulnerability right and i can make a
comment about why
i'm not affected by this thing and it
becomes part of my comment trail my
immutable audit trail and then of course
i can suppress it and when i suppress it
metrics will be reflective of that
because at this point
this particular vulnerability i'm no
longer impacted by that so it's it's not
a risk to this particular application
so you have the complete audibility in
there as well
um let's actually choose a different
project though
um let's actually choose
uh let's actually choose this test
project because i i threw out the
concept of an iot toaster just because
it's funny
and
this is a test project it has one
component
not very exciting
but you know what this component right
here it doesn't really do anything it's
it's a java client that fetches stock
quotes
well you you typically have to reach out
to the internet to to be able to
retrieve what the stock quotes are right
um i don't know about you but i can't
remember the last time that i actually
used a standalone piece of software that
didn't have a self update that didn't
phone home to the internet to do
something right so
with cyclone dx and with dependency with
dependency track we actually treat the
the entire stack uh not just the the
actual software components themselves so
in this case it actually depends on a
service
again this was part of my software bill
material
and i can go into my service here and
actually see you know what uh what the
what the service is
who the provider is uh what were the
endpoints that this application is
fetching and maybe even some of the data
classifications as well as the
directional flow of data there's enough
information in here to
for me to program to create a threat
model a a data flow diagram used in
threat models which is which is really
really
interesting but again let me let me go
back to um
to one of the core concepts of
dependency track which was
am i affected and where
so let's find out where
uh jackson databind is at
so if i do a search for jackson data
bind i'm going to see that in my
environment i have three different
projects
that uh that actually use jackson data
bind uh there is this this project right
here web goat and drop wizard so think
of a typical uh enterprise with tens of
thousands of assets
really really quickly here i was able to
figure out which assets in my
environment are potentially impacted by
by this particular vulnerable component
now i can also search for other things i
can search for package url i can search
for cpes
i can search for it
by swift tag ids
which is useful for commercial software
and i can also search for it by hash so
for example if i know that i'm using a
component but maybe there's a malicious
variant of that same component floating
around on the internet somewhere i can
actually search for things by hash which
is also a really interesting use case
uh the other way to come to it though is
is through this way and actually let me
let me just find a vulnerability real
quick we were looking at jackson data
bind yes
so let me just let me just pull this
vulnerability right here
because you can also come to it from the
other way
so
imagine that a shiny new
a new vulnerability comes up gains a lot
of press has a logo has its own website
and i want to know if i have any
projects in my portfolio that are
impacted by that thing so i do a search
for that vulnerability i go into the
vulnerability and i have automatically
here a list of affected projects so
right here i search for a vulnerability
that's making a lot of press
and right here dependency track is
telling me which projects are affected
by that so that's immensely powerful
so let me um let's see we've got uh five
six minutes left uh we also support um
you know security isn't the the only use
case uh it's the it's the one that you
know that gaining the most uh um
um you know it's the one that it's the
one use case that has board level room
discussions constantly
but license intellectual property and
some other use cases are also important
um dependency track handles those uh
with uh as well so we support all spdx
license identifiers
and we also support a policy engine that
you can
create different types of policies so
you can create license policies you can
create prohibited component policies or
or
you know that sort of thing so there's a
number of different types of policies
that that you can create that's also
available to you
[Music]
let me go ahead and stop this share and
go back to my deck here
so isn't essentially what we're talking
about sca
kind of but yeah no not really
sca is really about looking at a
specific application with a very
specific type of lens
what s-bombs do
is not only the transparency of that but
it looks at it with a completely
different lens in a much broader lens so
it's it's definitely not sca although
what you've seen here
does have some sca-like qualities right
known vulnerabilities license compliance
outdated components these are all use
cases that most sca products have today
but we did it
not using sca we did it using software
bill materials
so software build materials are going to
give you inventory use cases which
surprisingly is is very very difficult
and especially for sca products to to
get it right
much more easier to get it right with
software builder materials
but we can think of
not only the the components themselves
but you know what components include
other components maybe in the java world
for example we have these things called
shaded jars where a jar might actually
have 10 other products and 10 other
other components in there that's really
an assembly within cyclone dxn and
dependency track supports that
we can tell where we got a component
from so whether it's a country of origin
whether it's a repository that we
retrieved it from that sort of
providence use case is is what we're
also targeting we can target pedigree
and this is a future use case that we're
going to be working on where open source
is the ultimate supply chain and we are
going to modify components and change
them and rename them and we can track
all these modifications across our
supply chain that's that's pedigree
ultimately these things are packaged and
distributed somewhere sometimes we we
put them in the cloud for production
sometimes they're downloaded from
customers on the internet but packaging
and distribution are cases
remediation and disclosure are also
other use cases and of course we also
support hardware because this is a full
stack solution we're not just looking at
the in application we're literally
looking at the full stack
and that full stack does include
services
and in fact like i said in the in the
demo we have enough information about
services in the s-bomb to actually
programmatically create a data flow
diagram that could be used for threat
modeling which is really really
interesting so this
this in my mind is a really really big
win and a huge step forward into being
able to make better risk-based decisions
we have a lot of integrations with
dependency track obviously the software
build material format of choice is
cyclone dx
but we're tool agnostic and we're vendor
agnostic so we support multiple sources
of vulnerability intelligence everything
from the nbd to npm advisories vuln db
from risk-based security of course
sonotype oss index and there's some
other ones coming in the future as well
support a number of different ecosystems
and repositories i mentioned microsoft
teams and slack
and of course we have a bunch of
different types of integrations both
native integrations like
defect dojo and fortify and kenna as
well as some community integrations like
from code dx and security compass and
thread fix so
pretty big
ecosystem and it's it's being used in
hundreds of thousands of organizations
today so a little bit about the project
this is the github repo that where you
can find more information we do have
some social media accounts and a
dedicated youtube channel i need to
update the content on that it's uh it's
kind of lacking
documentation is pretty good and of
course there is our public website so
again thank you all wasp congratulations
on 20 years and um i will see you in the
um i'll be in the slack channel so catch
me in the slack channel for the next 30
minutes if you have any questions on
dependency track cheers