[Music]
the asvs is literally a standard it's
designed to be testable um a lot of the
other things that we do
for example the os top 10 it's more of
an awareness and training piece the asvs
is designed to be used by developers and
many others
when we first did the asvs um i think
the overall use was more or less as a
source code review checklist
but over time
it's actually been used for a whole
bunch of stuff including architecture
and things like that
the problem is that over time 4.0 is an
example of this 4.0
has so much in it should it have that
amount of stuff
so the other thing that we would
recommend i'm going to let jim talk
about this is how to fork the asvs
because the asvs is huge and maybe it
doesn't meet your requirements and we
encourage forking so yeah so andrew the
reason why my opinion is more issues is
better is because i don't expect every
team to use asvs out of the box i expect
no one to so we're adding all these new
sections on json web tokens we're adding
sessions on web sockets
but if your system doesn't use web
sockets drop that section and if your
section doesn't use json web tokens then
drop section so the whole point of the
standard really is to have a base of
requirements that is complete as
possible that we hand to you as your as
a different development team or security
testing team and for you to fork off it
to make it relevant and i've helped many
teams fork asvs the most common fork
andrew is to drop authentication and
session management requirements and
instead have a list of requirements
around how to integrate with our
identity provider that's one example of
how you can fork the application
security verification standard so it's
more relevant to your team
absolutely
so who's leading the asps well obviously
daniel cuthbert and myself have been
long-time
co-leads
jim and ella and josh are actually the
most active co-leads right now and elr
is one of our newest leaders
we
really do appreciate all of the work
that he's put in for us and he's been
amazing uh getting some of the stuff
corrected and stuff like that and just
simply moving through the tickets
let me talk about a lot i've worked with
him a lot the last six months alar came
at me a few months ago and said
jim
this the leadership of asvs is not being
responsible in their duty we have a lot
of pending comments and active people
and the leaders are not doing enough
work here and i got really angry with
him and thought about it and went back
to him and said
yeah you're right and i'm going to
change that and i jumped in as but josh
grossman's been super active when he can
i've after getting lectured by alar
you're getting getting getting slapped
by alar i became more active and he is
hyperactive he was right so he was he
was a little he's a little punchy about
it but he got me active again and he got
me excited about asvs again and his
comments are some of the most astute
comments
for uh for all
some of the most astute comments we're
getting from contributors so as
punishment to alar for all of his like
attacks towards me i we made him a
co-leader as his punishment so now
so i'm just saying
why why awar is so important to the
owass foundation is because even when
leaders weren't active even when
communication died he'd never stopped
volunteering and kept pushing because of
how important the standard is so i just
want to celebrate him doing that alar
lang is critical to the owasp foundation
and the work of the asvs standard there
you go apps 100
and actually having
healthy challenges to leadership is
actually a really good thing one of the
things i did when i became the co-leader
of the top 10 is immediately appoint
more leaders and that is actually saved
the old's top 10 2021. um
[Music]
lives change and we get busy i was doing
the top 10 2021 during the time that
was basically saying no one's talking to
me well
there's only so much time so yeah no
it's fantastic and it's healthy to have
new leadership coming from time to time
as well i i agree we and a quick note
like when when
uh
let's let's charge ahead never mind i i
digress the beginning of asvs was mike
burberski and jeff williams in 2008 and
they were pioneers when it comes to
application security standards it was
earlier designed so only a small percent
was verifiable and 80
was more for pen testing there's eight
levels at that time and
why this is so important is at this time
there were no standards even close to
addressing application security details
and even out now in 2021 there are no
application security standards that go
into this level of detail so mike and
jeff dave wickers was involved in this
as well they pioneered a standard that
we're going to still be working on a
decade from now in my opinion and it's
really really a great project that i'm
really excited about
so the interesting thing is almost every
single item that mike and jeff put in
there and dave
is still in there oh it's still in there
now
oh the very few things were i thought
you're going to have a direction
no they got it right it was fantastic um
essentially the the first version only
had 120 something controls in total even
though i had eight levels but the
reality is is that almost all of them
are still there i love to give jeff
williams a hard time it's like one of my
sports but it was jeff was doing apsec
like at the before the industry was
named after same with buberski so
they're some of the real early pioneers
in our industry and their work still
helps us today but again i still love to
give jeff a hard time just a sport it's
just a hobby let's move on yeah okay
so the numbering we are coming up to a
breaking uh change and we're going to be
calling the next version 5.0 and we'll
show you some of those changes coming up
if we have some time
but yeah jim did you just want to talk
about the difference between
non-breaking and braking and why we
decided 5 was the correct choice as
we're going through the different like
4-0 is is an acceleration of activity
more volunteers we have like five or six
volunteers that are like reading this
meticulously
commenting on on different changes so we
were gonna release 4.1
but we we want to make a breaking change
and what that means is we want to
renumber the whole standard so a
non-breaking change is when we're
honoring the version number of each
requirement and we'll leave if we're
going to remove a requirement we'll
leave a gap where that requirement used
used to exist now when we go to 5-0 this
could be a breaking change we're not
going to reference any of 4-0 4-0 is is
is old and 5 is going to be a whole
fresh so we're not going to mention
where we change something or add
something or modify something likely
we're going to cut a whole new version
with all new requirement numbers so we
can start fresh and have a complete
standard and we really we didn't plan to
do that we wanted to release version 4.1
but the activity that we're getting for
changes and their astute changes
is so is so much
we have enough activity that really
mandates we we push out 5.0 and if we do
push out 4.1 which are still a little
bit debating i think that's going to be
a distraction to getting four point of
getting 5.0 out because at this point
even if we do release 4.1 it's going to
be pretty much close to 5-0 the changes
are so dramatic and this is a this is an
indicator of two things an increase of
volunteer activity of this key standard
and just an increase in the use of the
asvs i've run into users of asvs all
over the place now way beyond just the
you know the owass community this is now
something that's that's out there a lot
and i know that as a consultant i used
to charge a lot of money to write
standards for companies a lot and it's
insane and this is not this eliminates
that part of the consulting world which
i think is good we now have an initial
standard requirement and as a consultant
we can all help companies fork and
fine-tune their standards but with a
good common base so again the changes
are so much it's so used now
that we have enough changes pending in
our working directory the working
directory is the 4-0 english directory
the changes are so much
it mandates we release 5.0 next i think
yeah and i think honestly we probably
need to sort that out and maybe revert
the four to four so we've got a history
of it um because it's getting to the
point now where it's very hard to work
out what is still for
um but yeah we've got we've got to i
think we've got to get better at doing
git
we're getting better at andrew every if
you look at some of the new pro we've
added significant new process in the
last few months we have a labeling
system so we can keep track of all the
issues is the issue like waiting for
further discussion are we awaiting a pr
is it close but there's still lingering
issues so we believe alar set up a big
labeling system for all our issues
number one and every requirement change
we make now we're labeling it as added
new deleted um modified or moved from a
different number so
we're not sure what 5.0 is going to look
like completely but we're in the
requirement in the english 40 directory
every time we've changed something away
from 4.02
we've labeled it so we do when it comes
time to make 5.0 we know if that
requirement is new did we modify it from
402 is it is it been removed did we
merge did we split a requirement all
these activity but we're labeling every
requirement with that activity
so maybe we can we can cut a 401 and a
five oh please no but we can if we need
to we have the metadata ready for when
the the new version is going to be cut
whatever that might be
okay
so that that completes on the next slide
which is great
um we roughly released everything
roughly keyword roughly andrew keyword
yes
and so it's released in march 2019 so
theoretically a good time to release it
would be in the first half of next year
uh which is why we're working so hard on
it right now but will it be released in
the first half of next year we don't
know i think i'd prefer to have a really
solid release that's a little late which
is what happened to the os top 10 um
than to have an early release that's a
bit rough uh jim thoughts
there's another meta thought is like i
really think that when someone
approaches owasp especially developer
who wants to get into secure coding it's
hard to find that knowledge i would
start by
reading the oauth top 10 and then put it
down and then go read the asvs
requirements and then go to the cheat
sheet series to look at those up to read
about those details but this is a great
progression after you read the oauth top
10 which is a great way to start this is
a more complete just more complete
discourse and
i also i also hear that no con one of
the best conferences on the circuit go
to no con i hear really good things
about their organization and similar
and and and
i'd rather have a late deployment of of
asvs 5 than than hitting a arbitrary
time right i want to get it right and
finally i really think that not finally
i think we have the team and i don't i'm
not i'm not commenting on older teams we
have so many people active from a lot of
different um uh areas
that it's we have like critical mass in
terms of like necessary technical
diversity to get this done
and another quick note one of the other
main contributors is
the gentleman from the netherlands i
don't know how to pronounce his name
well sjord jord
s-j-e-o-r-d
he corrected my inc so i had a gentleman
from the netherlands who's natively does
not speak english correct my english use
of grammar in one of the requirements
and i was like that we've hit critical
mass at this point so
yeah well function
i digress andrew go ahead i'm sorry
hey i can definitely back no con has
been a great conference i had a really
good time there it's one of the best
ones i've been to
did you dance on the beach in goa andrew
did you
well i was actually staying in a hut on
the beach a few kilometers up the road
and it was fantastic i definitely will
go back it's it's definitely one of the
beautiful places in this world
um but also
um
just going back on that torsten uh one
of our co-leads on the is top 10 he is
one of our grammar people and he's
german and he doesn't speak english his
first
language
that makes sense right english is really
just german anyways right all right
i did not say that whatever i love i i
love
i do love it when my european allies
correct my use of the english language
it's a special moment
yep okay i just want to really just go
back on this fork thing just real brief
because we are actually running shorter
time i would suggest
if you are going to fork it
you can delete things no problems but if
you're creating new things that are
unique to yourself
um that aren't related to the ones we
have please use 50 plus because we'll
never get there and that means that you
you can actually then just keep your
stuff around as you see fit and keep on
merging with us
so what you're saying is if you're going
to fork asvs step number one it's okay
to delete item requirements just delete
them but if you're gonna add a new one
don't overwrite one of our numbers add
it to add it as a new number at the end
of the standard and then contribute it
back to us for consideration to merge
back into the standard you're not
allowed to fork asvs and make your own
requirements without giving it giving it
back as a pr or an issue back to the
standard is that what you're trying to
say absolutely one hundred percent yeah
yeah and if in fact that's how we got a
lot of the web service stuff uh the
gentleman from the netherlands gave it
to us because he needed it and he felt
that this was a contribution and that
became the web service
he's he's one of the most epic
contributors as well he's the ninja i
i'm not pronouncing his name right he's
one of our main contributors out of
netherlands you can see his
hyperactivity in github and he's another
like ninja surgeon helping us clean up
small mistake big mistakes that we look
overlooked so excellent yep
okay so we've got 5.0 in development now
we've got seven minutes so we'll just
get through the rest of these slides and
we'll have a look at it um
if you're interested in helping we are
very interested in getting help
particularly if you code because one of
the things that really interests me is
are the things we're suggesting are they
still relevant and are they still
effective because there's nothing worse
than actually having something in the um
in a standards such as for example some
of the um
itgc controls that you get asked in
supply chain questionnaires is what's
your password rotation uh value and it's
like why the hell are you even asking
this it's not an effective control but
it's part of itgc so what we would like
to see is make sure that people
are validating our work and make sure
that it's relevant but also as more and
more folks get into the cloud and we
we're trying to address in
agnostic way
all of the new cloud stuff but obviously
if you're a practitioner you may know
something we don't please help
okay so mappings
there's a team at ios called
the
project integration standards and one of
the pieces of work they're doing is the
crv which went into beta today i believe
um
i am very interested in this outcome now
we also have torsten working on the osib
which is a very similar mechanism but
it's generated automatically from the
owl's top ten this is more of a
mapping to make to match
all mappings i like the fact that it's
actually about requirements which is
roughly where the asvs lies
weaknesses aren't a good way of
developing software because there's
billions and an infinite set of
weaknesses but there's only probably a
very limited number of requirements
and so
i love the idea that there's actually a
common requirements enumeration if you
are interested in getting involved and
helping map stuff around this will
actually help us in the long run too jim
because it allows 5.0 to be mapped back
to form
if this is something that mitre is
working on or a cre and owasp project or
there's a few people working on it that
are actually not part of the os um
uh
you know
this is basically like a cve list or
like our cwe list but a list of actual
requirements like things you must build
in software for security as opposed to
discussing vulnerabilities did i get
that right
uh it's not so much like
the asvs as it is a mapping technique
okay i got you i got you
so if you're talking about sql injection
and as you know um
cwe79 what is that in the asvs
that helps this mapping 5.33 5.33 i
think anyways i digress it's not we
don't discuss sql injection wait a
second sql injections attack we discuss
parameterized queries in the asbs so my
ask is cre are they discussing
like sql injection or are they
discussing parameterized queries that's
all that's a really great question that
i don't know the answer to because i've
not been heavily voiced i would
encourage everybody to get involved
including us
this is the record because we're not
really giving a talk andrew and i andrew
and i are just convincing here sorry
about that
so
the team does actually have a leadership
meeting that this is actually how it
goes we we have this back and forth
discussion and we bring up the issues in
github and
we go bam bam bam bam make decisions get
it done
it's fantastic we do need to keep doing
that um so yeah development of 5.0 is
underway right now we're targeting a
late 2021 but more realistically early
2022 release
um we're going to have when we're
releasing our early version we're going
to be really loud to announce peer
review and qa but you can do that now
again if you go to asvs go to github go
to the 4.0 en directory english
directory and you'll see all the
activity we're working on so you can
wait for our release or you can do it
now
um june of 2022 we're releasing an upset
dublin i'm going to be there with a
guinness in hand post release we'll do
dot releases as necessary to correct
mistakes but this is our plan right now
uh appsec dublin oh and kerry i'm gonna
see you there
and we're
i'm looking forward to having our final
5-0 release
absolutely
um
okay just zooming through the last
couple of slides because i do want to
show everybody um
if you want to write a companion guide
from scratch from us around asvs there's
several others who have this interest if
you let us know i'll connect you with
the other folks who would like to write
a companion guide either and you know it
basically should be a reference to other
os material we have some ideas what do
we mean by this verification how can we
expand on it sometimes we'll point to a
cheat sheet sometimes we'll point to
another wiki page sometimes we'll write
a new guide for it either way this is a
great side quest for anyone who's into
asvs and wants to help us explain the
requirements beyond a one or two
sentence requirement
absolutely
okay so
if you've got questions i'll be hanging
around for the entire day at this one
here with the 20th anniversary flagship
project but let's go directly and have a
quick look
at the github repo um
jim can you see it i sure can so let's
let's go look at code andrew
let's go to 4-0
and there's let's go to english ian
just ian boom this is where all the
active work is getting done you should
see some check-ins for me
last night right so go look at
authentication
18 hours ago there you go andrew
yeah it's actually really busy there's a
lot of check-ins happening and this is
you know you don't often hear about this
work but it's really important that you
understand that it is actually going
ahead and we
love contributions and issues and pull
requests
um so
the way to influence us is through
logging issues and the best way to
influence us is the pull request
yes
and we like discussion first we like an
issue first we discuss it because we've
done we've gotten a lot of prs without
explanation we need to discuss this so
an issue is best first but
especially if it's minor
we'll take a pr directly as well but
however you want to volunteer and help
us
i'm open to accepting your volunteerism
any way we can so if you're interested
let us know
yeah the other thing i really want to
just highlight is that we did
in version 4 although it's got a good
renumber here as well
we have a separate section for api
call-outs now we're actually in the
middle of a
leadership discussion about architecture
and what should happen there do we
sprinkle it amongst everything else
personally i think we come up with the
right answer here which is sprinkle it
amongst everything else and have a much
shorter version one
i agree
yeah that's kind of my view well there's
a lot of duplicate requirements
it was a good effort but it duplicated
things we ended up like ripping them all
out anyways in the deeping process
anyway so we'll see architecture level
one that should really be about threat
modeling process i would dare say more
than anything else
i love rap modeling andrew love it
yeah i i'm if we pivot architecture to
be about secure design and the things
that would enable software to be built
securely i think v1 will be a much
stronger section that's a volunteer i
need strongly right now because all the
other sections we have an idea of our
plan architecture we want to rewrite it
to sync up with threat modeling and
secure design instead of having another
list of requirements so that that's
something a threat modeling expert
could really sink their teeth into and
help us for this next version but i
digress absolutely absolutely
um so if you are interested in getting
involved there is an asvs slack channel
obviously come and talk to us at the
github repo
which is a uh os asbs
you can download the last version from
our project home page but that's
starting to get a bit long in the tooth
which is why we really would appreciate
your input and help with getting 5.0 out
the door
and that's about all that i really
wanted to talk about jim is there
anything else yeah i got one more thing
to say andrew in the last like year i
watched a lot of the toxicity that was
part of the oaus foundation fade
staff are not like traumatized as much
every day now and like people are
getting along better at a time when
society is like having a lot of problems
i feel a lot of cohesiveness in the os
foundation or at least less toxicity
that's because of you and your
leadership at the foundation here
and it means
and it's changed so much around the feel
of the organization from the way i see
it i'm grateful that you took on an ed
position and that's working for you
because i know for sure it's working for
the foundation thank you