[Music]
hey and welcome to the session everyone
so today the topic that i'm going to be
talking about today is
the basics of how to conduct a security
code review so is the process of
how to find vulnerabilities by looking
at source code and you might notice that
the title says for both developers and
penetration testers this is because i
believe that this will be a very useful
skill for you no matter which side of
security you're on right so if you're a
developer learning how to find
vulnerabilities in your own code can
enable you to
write more secure code in the future and
if you're a penetration tester then by
learning how vulnerabilities manifest in
source code you can learn to conduct
deeper and better analysis and source
code would be another way that you can
uncover vulnerabilities in the programs
of your auditing
so let's get started
so first hi my name is vicky i am a
developer and a penetration tester and i
currently work at a company called shift
left as their developer evangelist
i'm also the author of a book called bug
bounty boot camp which aims to help
beginners get into bug bounties and web
application hacking and you can find me
on twitter at vickiely7
and so first of all before we jump into
actually reviewing some code let's first
talk about the agenda that we'll be
we're going to be doing today
so we're going to be talking about
manual code reviews that is
you're diving into code yourself and
trying to find
vulnerabilities in the code without
using any tools
and we're going to be talking about why
you might want to learn how to do that
despite you know all the automate
automative tools available to you today
and then we're going to jump into how do
you actually
prepare for a source code review um what
kind of tools do you need
what kind of prerequisite knowledge and
you need to study up on before you jump
into your first security code review
and then we're going to actually dive
into the process of reviewing code and
i'm going to show you some examples of
finding a few vulnerabilities in the um
an example application that we're going
to be looking at
so first of all let's
talk a little bit about why security
code review is such a valuable skill
so um
a lot of application security issues are
actually derived from
insecure coding practices right like um
sql injections for example is caused by
a lack of or improper input validation
and issues like cross-site scripting and
different kinds of injection can be
caused by
a lack of output encoding or a lack of
input validation
and issues like insecure direct object
references
or eye doors or information leaks are
often caused by
missing access control
and issues like server-side request
forgery they're often caused by weak or
missing reg extracts
right so all these vulnerabilities
actually have
root causes there are very easily
identified in source code itself so one
of the easiest ways to
actually find these security issues is
by diving into source code instead of
you know using
dynamic testing
tools or using penetration testing teams
it's much much easier to just look at
source code and
see if any of these vulnerabilities
their signatures are
happening within the source code
and this is like one of the easiest ways
to find vulnerabilities
and second of all i'm also a huge
proponent of
learning to read source code and
learning to identify vulnerabilities in
order to become a better penetration
tester or a better developer
right because
throughout the process of reviewing the
code manually to find security issues
you'll learn a lot about different
vulnerabilities as well as how they
manifest in source code and how they
manifest
in so different programming languages
different environments and so on and as
a result
you'll learn very deeply about security
issues and you'll learn to write more
secure code in the future right and if
you're a penetration tester you'll
understand the root causes of the
vulnerabilities that you're looking for
much much deeply and that will enable
you to
conduct deeper and more comprehensive
analysis in the future as a penetration
tester as well
so let's get started preparing for a
source code review
and so first of all
uh what are the tools that you need in
order to conduct a source code review
efficiently
you actually don't need that many tools
one of the absolute essential tools is a
good code editor or an ide that you can
use to interact with the code and there
are three things that you should be
looking for for a good
ide
for a source code review and one of them
is that you want an id or code editor
that allows for global searches across
the code base you'll see why later
because we'll be
searching for vulnerable signatures in
code across the entire project and a lot
of the times
um
that's that's how you find
vulnerabilities right so you want the
ability to be able to search for a
particular signature or a particular
function across the entire code base
and when you're searching for vulnerable
vulnerable patterns in code you're not
always
looking for a specific string or a
specific like a very fixed thing right
sometimes you'll be looking for patch
string patterns instead and that's when
regex searches come in handy so you'll
want a code editor that comes with the
regic search functionality as well
and then third of all
is that you want the ability to be able
to cross reference multiple files at the
same time because a lot of the times
when you're trying to confirm that a
vulnerability actually exists you will
need to crash reference several the same
several occurrences of the same
functionality or you'll want to see
where the data is going where the code
is going so you'll need to open the same
your you'll need to open several
different files at the same time and
that really make things easier for you
so these are the three basic criterias
that you should be looking for and it's
really not that hard to find i'll be
using sublime text
today but you're free to use any code
editor or an ide that you like
and second i'm also a big fan of having
some sort of scripting tool or the
terminal on hand just so that i can run
tests on the code base and really verify
my hypotheses about how the code is
actually working
and so before we go on let's first
discuss a few code analysis concepts
that you need to understand
so in the code analysis world
a source refers to the code that allows
a vulnerability to happen
whereas a sink refers to where the
vulnerability actually happens
right let's illustrate this by looking
at a vulnerability take a command
injection for example
a source in this case would be a
function that takes in user input
whereas a sink on the other hand would
be a function that executes system
commands
so if
untrusted user input can get from this
source
to
the sync
without proper sanitization or
validation then a command injection
vulnerability exists
so many many common vulnerabilities can
actually be identified by tracking this
data flow from appropriate sources to
their corresponding sinks
and so
the second thing that you should prepare
for is that before you actually start
reviewing code for vulnerabilities you
should start by learning what the most
common vulnerability types are for your
application type so that you know what
to look for right for instance if you
are reviewing an
application with many different users
then information leaks might be an issue
and if your application lets the users
interact with the database via their
user input
then you might be looking at
some sql injections for instance
so knowing what the
major vulnerabilities are and getting
familiar with the indicators and the
signatures of those vulnerabilities will
really help you
look for similar patterns in your source
code
so um
also be familiar with what are the
common sources and common things of each
type of vulnerability
right for instance
the signature for uh xml external entity
or an xse vulnerabilities
is
um
passing user supplied xml into a parser
without disabling dtds or external
entities
so
uh you should be
arming yourself with the knowledge of
what these vulnerability looks like in
your applications context
so um
although
like vulnerabilities have these like
very
common very vague
patterns and code these patterns can
look quite different depending on the
programming languages or the libraries
or the frameworks that you're you're
using so learning what the common
vulnerabilities look like
in your specific context would help you
a lot in you know actually spotting
vulnerabilities very accurately in your
source code
so next up this slide is for the
penetration testers if you did not build
the application yourself you should also
try to get familiar with the
functionalities and the components of
the application right what are the
important where are the important
functionalities as well as um what are
the important fun components in the
application
so first you should probably figure out
who the applications users are
what can each user do
what kind of data the application is
processing
as well as you know what are the
business impact and the business
significance of each functionality and
each component
so this will really help you prioritize
your analysis down the line because you
understand what can realistically go
wrong as well as what kind of data
that's the most important for you to be
protecting
because a lot of the times during source
code review it's not very realistic to
read every single line of every single
component in the code right so you
really need to start with the parts of
the application that poses the highest
risk to the applications user as well as
the business itself
so let's start analyzing
some code
so first of all if you are short on time
focusing on searching for the most
common and the most of your issues will
give you the highest roi right and the a
quick way to start doing this is by
searching for the strings the keywords
and the code patterns that are known to
be indicators of common vulnerabilities
or a misconfiguration
for instance
hard coded credentials are a huge issue
right that you can very easily identify
in source code
and
hard coded credentials like hard-coded
api keys encryption keys and database
passwords
they can very easily be identified a lot
of the times by searching for keywords
in the code base just by searching for
keywords like key secret password and so
on
and another vulnerability
that
you can look for this way
is by
searching for unchecked use of dangerous
functionalities so search for the code
based form the use of dangerous
functions and see if they are reachable
by user control data right so for
instance you can search for strings like
system and eval since these are common
sinks for command injection
vulnerabilities
so
let's um
look at an example let's actually jump
into a vulnerable code base and search
for some vulnerabilities there
and the
repository that we're going to be
looking at today is called target java
and here's the link here feel free to
download it and follow along tribal java
is a java application that's seated with
a lot of common vulnerabilities such as
the os top 10
several business logic flaws as well as
data leaks
so let's get started
so we have target java open right here
in sublime text and let's start
searching for some vulnerabilities let's
first look for a hardcoded credential
for instance
so remember i talked about a lot of
hardcoded credentials they can actually
be identified by searching for common
keywords like key or password or string
or
um api key right this is because a lot
of the times when developers hard code
their credentials in the code base they
actually name the variable or global
name after these strings right so a lot
of the times you can simply do a global
search on the entire code base
and see if you see any results
and you can see here that
just right away we find
a pair of
aws access keys right here because of
their global's name global names are
named after
uh the keyword key
and so another thing that we can be
looking for
via like um
my keyword search this way
is that we can search for dangerous
functions and see if there are any
there's anything suspicious there or if
there are any uh vulnerabilities
happening there right so i talked about
uh how come
the use of the function eval
is a common signature for command
injection vulnerabilities right so let's
look for the keyword eval
so
we can see here that
in the file called servlet tarpet.java
and
here is
the use of the function eval
let's go to that line and code right
here
and so a signature of command injection
vulnerabilities
is the use of eval which this function
takes in
input and actually executes it as code
right so a common uh signature of
command instruction vulnerabilities
would be user input being passed into
this eval functionality and you can see
here that this is exactly what's
happening here in the code base is that
the
uh
user user parameter user
provider parameter called module is
passed into eval without any
sanitization or
any sort of safety measure so this is
actually a command injection
vulnerability right here
so let's go back to the slides here
yeah so um using this method you can
very quickly find
a lot of different issues security
issues in your code
um but
what if you have more time
right this kind of string search will
not show you all the vulnerabilities
that is happening in your code base and
it's actually quite insufficient if you
want to find more subtle
more subtle security vulnerabilities
that are happening in your source code
so
what if you have more time right what if
you want to do a more comprehensive
manual code review
so remember i talked about getting
familiar with the functionality and the
components of the application right so
after searching for obvious issues like
hard-coded secrets or the use of
dangerous functions in code by keyword
search
start by analyzing in detail the
different parts of the application that
poses the highest risk to the users and
to the application's business so these
are usually places where the client or
the user gets to interact with the
server because these are the places
where malicious input can enter the
application
so first you can examine the client-side
code for security issues your
client-side code is always something
that you should pay attention to first
because that's where the users interact
with the application first right so
after analyzing client-side code you can
focus on code that deals with user input
on the server side
and so any time the application takes in
user input like
http request parameters http headers or
http request path
these functionalities provide the entry
points for attackers to exploit the
application's vulnerabilities right
so you could dive into these
functionalities in detail and then trace
the data flow of user input from these
functions
to other functions and see if they can
reach dangerous sync functions
so tracing the data flow like this could
um
really help you find more subtle but
common vulnerabilities like stored
cross-site scripting sql injections
um excess ease and so on
and then
you should also review code that
performs
critical functionalities in the
application so this includes
code that deals with authorization you
know authentication
or functionalities that deals with
sensitive data or
any other
logic logic that
that's critical to the business
functions like payment
right so dive into these functionalities
and look at the protection mechanisms
implemented on there and think about how
you can bypass them right so this is
when
it will be really helpful if you think
outside of the box and really think like
an attacker how would you attack your
own code and
could any of the protection mechanism
implemented on your code base be
bypassed in any way
at the same time this is also a good
time to
look at the code and check how business
and user data is being
transported and is any sensitive
information being transported and stored
safely
so
let's look at another example right i i
understand that this is all quite vague
and the best way to really showcase how
you actually do this is by looking at
some code so let's jump back
to
um to
our code base here
so i talked about diving into the
sensitive functionality in code right
and the sensitive functionality that
we're going to be talking about today
is
in this file called orderstatus.java
so what this file is that what this
functionality is actually doing is that
first it's taking
a request parameter from the user called
um called the order id here
and then it's passing it into
a sql statement
in order to retrieve the order details
associated with that order id
and then finally
it is returning the order details to the
user
so it's called the order status.java
right this
enables
users to check their order status by
submitting a request to the server
so let's just take um a quick like three
to five seconds to think about what
could go wrong in a functionality like
this one
so first of all
um because the
because the uh this this functionality
is using user input and inserting in
into a sql statement we could suspect
that it might be vulnerable to sql
injection right
and so this is exactly what happens here
you can see here
that the user id is passed into a sql
statement without any sort of
sanitization or validation
so
this functionality is actually
vulnerable to sql injection right here
and a second thing that we should think
about is that since this
uh since this functionality is dealing
with sensitive user data like the order
status actually contains the user's
credit card number
as well as their street addresses and
their phone numbers
we could um try to see if there are any
sensitive info leaks going on
so
here you can see that the order status
including the user's
shipping address credit card number and
email address
is stored into this order right here
and then eventually
underneath that
declaration here we can see that it's
actually this entire object is actually
getting written into logs and this is
really bad because this means that
whoever has access to the log files
would have access to these user info
right here as well so this is really bad
because this is a sensitive info leak
into logs and
the very obvious vulnerability right
here
so tracing the application
the tracing the applications code
from uh from user input and from the
sensitive data points to uh trying to
trace these functionalities to sensitive
syncs would actually help you identify a
lot of different vulnerabilities are
hiding in your code
but as you can see
the process of manually identifying
vulnerability in source code can be
quite tedious and quite time consuming
right and it's really not possible to
review every single line of code that
you write and if you don't look at every
single line of code you can very easily
miss something in the source code or
miss some critical
vulnerability they're hiding in your
source code right
so that's why first you need to really
prioritize your analysis by really
identifying what are the most important
functionalities that exist in this
application and what are the riskiest
functionalities that exist in the
application and focus your analysis um
on those functionalities
and the second thing you can do is
using automated tools right you can use
things like sas tools or static analysis
tools to speed up the progress right
good static analysis tools will help you
identify the vulnerable patterns that we
talked about in this
session so that you can focus on
analyzing the results of the tools and
really analyzing the impact of or the
exploitability of the vulnerability
instead of you know manually finding the
vulnerable patterns yourself
so you can use sas tools
to speed up progress instead of tracing
code yourself
and automation can help you with other
components of the source code review as
well like one of the other things that
we do in source code review is that we
look at all the applications
dependencies and see if there are any
disclose publicly disclosed
vulnerabilities that exist in those
dependencies right
and
software composition analysis tools
actually automates that process it will
keep track of your applications
dependencies and see if any of them are
outdated you can also utilize tools like
secret scanners to help you identify
hard-coded secrets that we talked about
in our code right
so
use these tools wisely can really cut
down on the time that's taking you to
conduct the manual analysis
but the issue is that these code
scanning tools
are never 100 accurate right so the best
way to
secure your software is really to use
these tools first to identify as many as
possible the the suspected
vulnerabilities in your code and then
you can conduct a manual code
review so look at the
the areas of code that seem that are
deemed suspicious by
by your tools and then validate those
results via manual code
manual code analysis and this way you
can ensure that as few bugs as possible
make it to production
so uh congratulations you made it that's
the basic framework that you can use to
conduct your very first security code
analysis but i would like to say that
the stuff that i talked about in this
talk is really just an intro
um it's very basic and it will
definitely not it's a good framework to
get started finding the most common
vulnerabilities and the most severe
vulnerabilities in your code but it's
definitely not um
all that you can do in order to secure
your applications
so if you're interested in learning more
about the topic i welcome you to check
out the os code review guide it is a
very extensive
extensive document on the topic and you
can learn a lot more and a lot more like
vulnerable patterns how do you actually
find different vulnerabilities and code
that way so check out the document and
thank you very much