[Music]
for the introduction and uh also a warm
welcome from my site quite excited to be
here on this stage and present this uh
gateway that i
originally
initiated this project
but we'll see um
we have quite a bit the team and now
behind this project
so we're already quite a bit behind
schedule so i try to keep it short and
concise and
[Music]
yeah so just let's get started
um
before i get into the details what the
application gateway project exactly is i
want to quickly highlight and what's the
reason why we started developing this
gateway
so first of all as a matter of fact many
organizations moved to microservice
based architectures and this is true
from large-scale
companies like
banks for online banking and also for
more smaller for example a new
innovative project of startups
but when it comes to security
microservices tend to make it
harder compared to monolithical systems
main reason is that we have more
services more interactions between those
services the attack surface is larger
and those are all security
considerations that one should do
compared to a monolithical system where
we might only have a
much clearly small attack surface
attack surface
however
security is still a bit afterthought in
many organizations and from my own
experience i can just tell if you try to
patch security at the end onto a
architecture it is so much harder and
more costly than when you start with the
security mindset from the beginning
but however there's still not so much
talk about security when it comes to
microservices so this is one of the main
challenges when it comes to
microservices but there are also some
other challenges especially in larger
systems
one is that open id connect which is
today the standard protocol for
really for um federated authentication
it's still quite complex um it's much
easier than for example all the
protocols like summel but still there
are a lot of different flows and you
need to know what what you do when this
can get quite tricky and it's not really
something that um
that is really um part of your app you
want to focus on your business logic and
not really on the authentication part
and then when it comes to large systems
then you often see that those micro
service architectures are really closely
coupled to
the the way you authenticate uh your
users and uh from architectural point of
view this is really unfortunate because
you have this um this bit uh this is
really tight coupling and if you want to
change something on your authentication
system then you really need to change a
lot on your back end and this makes it
hard to to keep up this
modern with modern authentication
so
the os application gateway project was
initiated due to those uh challenges and
uh yeah i'll come to in a minute to
what what it exactly is but before that
maybe a short view on the team behind it
and we have a few open source
contributors and uh the lead of the
project is a colleague between patrick
stigle
who is a
principal security architect also at
tulk engineering and my humble self who
i am a security engineer and security
testers also at silke and yeah by the
way we also hiring so if this is
something interests you then yeah just
say write me a note
so what are those challenges with those
micro services
um
here we have a sample
micro service architecture
and this is really a typical
architecture
um as you might see the browser client
the mobile app then there are some
services uh which are exposed to the
internet and the reporting service who
is uh
not really needed to be a reachable from
the internet
so
i just wrote here a lot of different
questions that might come up but they
often
quite
just to simplify to the main questions
how can we integrate authentication uh
in this system because we have a lot of
different
needs for example these services are
most of the time implemented in a
stateless way so we want to keep that
stateless and however we still
might want a server-side log out
and also security considerations
and on the left side with the clients we
have the challenges that the browser has
way less of possibilities to safely
store credential than for example a
mobile app where you can store a
long-term credentials
in for example the ios keychain and
there you want really to have a
long-term login and don't want the user
to log in every time when he opens the
app
so this is about the authentication and
then you so often have an external
identity provider this type might be for
example uh a social login this might be
your own erm system this might be your
actual active directory um
whatever it is uh main question is
always how can we integrate this
identity provider
to
this architecture
and this is now where the os replication
gateway comes into place
so what is it
the gateway itself it's it's a
standalone application and it's a
reverse proxy
that sits between your web public or
your clients and your backend services
so it's a typical http reverse proxy but
compared to for example api gateways as
you might know it um there are a lot of
products it has some some kind of
special features and it's focused on
that we talk we
call it application gateway and not api
gateway because it does quite a lot of
things for you
uh first of all it does session
management and uh login with with a
federated authentication provider so it
implements open id connect
and
takes kind of this this responsibility
so you don't need to do that on your own
so
the idea is really that it gives you a
head start when when try uh when setting
up your
security architecture
which which leads to a really um secure
architecture
which is ready for from large uh from
small to large scale systems like like
for example online banking systems
because we believe that that every
application also small applications
deserve
good security
and from an architectural point of view
the most important feature is that it
decouples your backend service from your
single sign-on integration
because this was the point that i
mentioned before that we have this tight
coupling often between the backend
services and uem and gateway is kind of
a thing between and can make that
or decouple that
so if you would want to use
the gateway in your architecture of
course there's some advantages and some
disadvantages with every like with every
architectural decision
um on the advantage side we have
clearly that it comes with a lot of out
of the box functionality when it comes
to session management and then login
so you really need to write almost no
code in the backend nor into front-end
to do any kind of login related stuff so
at how uh you know in a large extent it
reduces the complexity in the front and
the back end and you can really focus
only on the business logic
from a security perspective it's also a
single point of entry
which
means that you have a clearly defined
attack surface and it also makes it
much easier to for example implement
trust zones with network policies
because you only need to expose your
instance of the gateway
then also from from a developer
perspective
or from an architectural perspective
again
the api is the contract so
it allows you to make changes in the
back end without uh changing anything in
the front end
this is a clear advantage um
this pattern is also called back and
forth from them
if you wanted and of course it comes
with a lot of best practices when it
comes to security so it for example it
implements request tracing according to
uh w3c standards it has uh it locks and
all the requests that the
forwards it comes with sea surf
protection you can modify headers and so
on and so forth
but also of course there's some
slight disadvantages first of all it's
like that's the most important one it's
obviously a bit more complex
architecture
uh but on the other hand you have a bit
less complexity in the front and then
backhand so this is kind of a trade-off
you need to do um and then also because
it's a single point of entry it's also a
single point of failure uh we will
cover later how how we address this
problem with horizontal scalability
and then of course um
while the oit is is really uh
configurable um
it's still opinionated in some areas so
we have a kind of idea how an
architectural vision uh with the zero
trust approach um but
um if if your vision doesn't match that
at all then the ohe might be not a good
fit for you
so um this is now really theoretical
um i'll do now a short demo of an
application that is implemented with the
gateway and you see here the
architecture so
this is all deployed on azure but this
doesn't really matter for the demo
the only thing the client talks to is
the gateway itself and then we have
three back-end systems first is a a host
for the front-end this is a simple azure
blob storage and then we have two azure
app services one for the backend api and
one is a special echo
service that is just here for debugging
and
demonstration purposes
but before i show you that i want to
quickly show you how this is now
configured because this
is a very good impression um
how how ohe works
so
let me quickly uh change
the
window
then i need to stop the share and do it
again
so what you see now is the
the configuration file of this ohe
instance
and
you can see it's a yaml file so it's
easily human readable and this is also
the idea that you can read this file and
you directly get the impression what is
going on
there are two main parts um there are
routes definitions
um so here you add the different
backhand routes and uh you can have a uh
a
pattern that matches the request and
then it gets re forwarded
to this request and you can have for
example additional settings like if the
this route can be accessed in an
enormous way
so this is the first important part
second important part is here the login
providers here you tell um
the the gateway how exactly users can
log in
and
we have also three methods here so the
first one is a login with google
this is a simple open id connect login
and those here are the values that i got
from google when the retro thing is
logging with google
and then we also have a login with
github github doesn't implement openid
connect uh this is kind of uh
unfortunate uh they have their own
protocol so we also uh built that
directly natively in to their
application gateway
and just for demo purposes we also have
a third we say private er
there are a lot of
additional things you can configure
uh for example
how this chat token looks like that is
sent to the backend
but this is optional so you don't really
need to configure that
if you just want to take the out of the
box version
um so now let's go to my browser window
and
then i can show you how this looks like
and so this is the url of the demo
oht.azurewebsites.net
uh feel free to also go here um it's a
simple blocking application currently we
don't have any articles here if you want
to
create one
uh let's sign up for that
um and here you see now these three uh
login uh links this now
needs to be of course implemented by a
frontend developer um because we don't
really know
how you want your login page to look
like
but when i click here on the button
this is a simple redirect to a special
url and this is called old
google
login for example
and if you redirect the user to that url
oh he knows that you want to log but the
user wants to log in with google
so let's do that
and then we start the openid connect
flow
i'm already logged in at google so uh
there's no password prompt but i can now
select my account let's take my oversp
account i get redirected back to my osg
instance and then you can see i'm logged
in
also
i have my
nice little profile picture
if you want to know what's going on on
the back end you can now use the special
echo route
what this service does it just reflects
the http request
as he gets it
then you can see what the gateway does
what's interesting is
most of all this authorization barrel
header this is now added by the gateway
and here we have a shot token that can
be uh
validated by the back end in a stateless
way
and if we take a closer look we see here
now and that we have the information for
example which provided the
user
use and um also for example uh here the
subject claim which tells the backend uh
unique id of the user
there are a lot more things that you can
configure
also for example you have a session id
directly in description token this is
the session id we have here with our
cookie-based authentication and if we
take a close look at that and we can see
here that we have a few cookies set
most important here this session cookie
this is a encrypted cookie so um
but this is kind of not your business
this is a ohg internally
so there are also a few other things for
example uh here the transparent header
this is
an id which is generated by oit itself
and it's used with every lock statement
about this request and then forwarded to
the back end so if you also lock this id
then you can really achieve a nice cross
service lock coloration and especially
for larger systems or in larger systems
this gets really important if you run
into issues and i need to debug
something
so that was it for the demo feel free to
check it out by yourself um i'll go back
to the presentations and i think because
um
we started a bit late i'll need to
jump over a few slides
um
but
what i wanted to to show you is here
this
this overview over the designed
principles behind
the overs publication gateway this is
kind of from a user perspective what's
important for them so the first and in
my opinion most important one is that
it's secure by default this means the
default settings default functionalities
and so on are built in a way that they
are kind of follow current best
practices
and lead you as a user to a
kind of zero trust architecture which we
think will be
a good fit for the future it doesn't
mean that if we
add a new feature we
try to design the future in a way that
is uh
hard to misuse
but this sounds really easy but it's
actually quite complicated
uh it also means that we are the gateway
itself is kind of opinionated in some
areas
uh but we know of course that uh there
are always special considerations
especially when it comes to larger
systems
then it's really important for you that
it's built to be extended uh the gateway
itself is based on the java spring stack
so you can
add your own beans if you want
and
add your own functionality and whatever
you want for example if you want to
change the logging system you can do
that if you want to add support for new
authentication provide methods something
else then open id connect or github you
can do that
that's that's very simple i think really
important for for larger systems
the last design principles be behind the
gateway is
um that
um
that it's it's really configuration
based or the whole configuration is
based in this one file i showed you uh
this is important because it allows you
to just take a look at this
configuration file and you know what's
going on so there's no login where you
can lock yourself in and for example add
routes in a graphical way
we believe that this file based
configuration is much better for
transparency and also allows you for
example to add this file to
a kit repo and then for example
automatically deploy it via cicd and i
think this is a really
good way to avoid misconfiguration
vulnerabilities
because the the changes are really
transparent
um
so we have five more minutes so um
just very briefly to mention uh
internally we have a non-blocking
network stack this is important for when
you have a lot of concurrent requests uh
we didn't implement it by ourselves this
is based by on on-screen cloud gateway
um which is really a major
module um
a module
gateway product that provides this hdpf
or warping functionality and we have a
stateless architecture
wherever it works there are a few areas
like server side lockouts there for that
we still need a little bit of state
between different nodes but
we keep that we try to keep that minimal
but that's one topic we really are
working on right now
if you would want to use it the two
usage models
the first is that you run it off out of
the box and i think for
small to medium sized project this is
totally fine
then you just can run the docu image or
there's also a java char release if you
want to use that
then you just need to tell
the gateway
where to find the configuration file and
it will start up if you want to extend
you need to use java and springboot
then you can create your own
project and
use this this annotation enable bus
publication gateway
and
then directly add your own functionality
add your own spring filters can add your
own spring beans and whatever you want
about the current state um it's still
working progress need to say that uh but
we expect to to deliver a first um
a productive usable version as soon as
we have built this clustering mechanism
um the latest version it contains all
the features that i presented right now
in this abstract um except of this
cluster support i mentioned so if you
want to try it out feel free uh pull it
from docker hub or the
check out the github page
um also if you want to find out more um
check out our github page there we have
a lot of code samples documentation
even documentation how to extend it and
so on and how to integrate it um
please also store it on github that's uh
something which really helps us to get
some more recipes visibility
and also you can check out the overs
website uh there there's also some
additional information about the project
um at that uh
point i also want to mention we're
always looking for contributors uh that
doesn't only need to be a coding um you
can also just write us a note what you
like maybe feedback maybe ideas what
what feature you would expect from such
a
gateway
and if you want to code feel free we are
always happy if we have new
open source contributors sometimes you
also have or even though even if it's
just a little thing but that that's
really exciting if someone
develops something that's a feature uh
so please
if you have questions about the
development uh please don't hesitate to
contact one of the project leaders zoe
to me or potty
uh yeah that's it i'll hang around in
the slack for questions um
feel free to join and uh yeah we'll be
happy to answer some questions