[Music]
so hopefully in this talk i can convince
you to go for
automation uh t he bad pun dad joke um
yeah i want to tell you the some of the
lessons i've learned about trying to
automate security make things go faster
so you can look awesome and you don't
have to tell your boss right this is
just like look awesome and get a raise i
think that's all a good thing
so who am i i'm uh i like to call myself
a reformed programmer i started out life
writing code as a full-time job and then
got the security bug and never looked
back uh i've had 13 plus years in the
west community like martin was saying
the leader of several projects i was on
the board i've i've been on an employee
for owasp i've done a whole bunch of
things
i have 20 plus years of using free libra
and open source software as well as uh
linux
as you notice the gopher on the intro
slide i'm a go fanboy that's what i like
to write my programs in these days and i
do have a second degree black belt and
edon in tongsudo miguel which is a
korean
um
version of karate
so the money shot right everybody loves
the money shot and this was me doing my
board break for my second degree black
belt
what was that two years ago three years
ago two years ago i think i don't know
this whole covet thing is completely
ruined my sense of time
uh but everybody loves the money shot
right
no one really talks about the anti-money
shot and and i'm going to be real honest
with you there's going to be some work
here like it will take some work to do
automation you're not gonna push an easy
button and just have it
but
you do get the money shot if you put in
the work so it is worth the effort right
so there's gonna be
a little bit a little bit of uh effort
right to get this done but there will
definitely be a payoff as well
so let's briefly talk about traditional
appsec and i kind of in this deck i i do
devops devsecops appsx security i mix it
all up it's all kind of the same to me
so if you if you see the terms shifting
around that's really what that is i try
to keep it loose because my background
is obviously very heavily in appsec but
this applies across all the different
security disciplines
so there you go
what to me it feels like when i'm
running what i would call traditional
apsec tooling right it's like jousting
with snails it is painful it's slow and
it's usually not particularly effective
right run this thing it's in a server
off by itself i got to get the results i
got to take it out as a pdf i gotta
email that somebody it's just awful like
i i i don't like that um
and i quite honestly think that
traditional apsec
was died and buried many years ago
we hardly got to know it and i'm kind of
glad to see it go because i don't think
we were serving
our constituency very well
and in fact to be really honest
i think we weren't doing very well by
the developers either and or any kind of
infrastructure team right where you run
a security tool you generate a pdf and
you throw it over the wall right this is
the same problem that devops was saying
they wanted a fix of developers throwing
code over the wall well we threw pdfs
over the wall at the developers and it
didn't make things better right so yes
like management still likes to have pdf
reports but that's not really the way to
care and feed your developers
the other thing is what do people think
when they talk to security they think no
right i'm going to talk to security the
answer is going to be no
and it really can't be no there's that
is
no way
to make things right right it's not a
good idea
instead think about it the purpose of an
apsec program or any security program is
to evaluate the security of whatever
that domain is right it could be the
suite of applications for the business
it might be your cloud infrastructure
maybe it's a it's a a whole bunch of
desktop computers right it's your it's
your normal corporate land so to speak
whatever it is that's really the goal of
a security program
you can give informed information back
to the business to guide them in the
right direction right you shouldn't be
just the no person
so
what i like to ask and i'd ask is if we
were in a physical environment it's like
raise your hand if you have fueled the
full view of your application landscape
and i think this would be the
traditional security answer of no
most people don't i've actually worked
in worked with an ad a bunch of
different companies and so far i have
found one
in 20-ish years of doing this work where
they actually had a good solid list of
all of their applications everyone else
it's like we have no idea we have maybe
a thousand we have two thousand we have
no idea
so there's one more thing you need to do
in security to do right by your
constituency and that is provide a clear
and direct path for teams to follow and
if you're automating security and making
it quick and easy you can actually
provide the right feedback loops to keep
the uh the whatever area your the other
developers in the case of appsec right
on that correct path right you can
notify them when they deviate quickly so
they don't get way off the path before
they have to do a course correction
so
let's talk about security automation
what are the key things to be aware of
well
i don't have time to talk about them as
much as i'd like to
but deming is fantastic
um
and he said one of my favorite quotes of
his is spending time optimizing anything
other than the critical resource is an
illusion the idea being is if you're
optimizing something that isn't the
bottleneck
you're just making new bottlenecks in
new places you're not actually fixing
the problem
and my supposition is that people
particularly in the security field are
your critical resource i have yet to be
in a security team where they had too
many people
and not enough work right you the ratio
of an apsec person to a dev team is
usually one to a hundred ish
um even traditional security is a
terrible uh ratio of them to the assets
they need to protect
right so
people are going to be your critical
resource
this is why automating things is vitally
important right you have only a limited
capacity of sort of people brain time to
get things done
um and if you don't if you can automate
the things that are the brainless parts
of their job
you can make sure that at least for most
of the time your employees are doing
good human being
you've been thinking sort of things
right and uh just did a talk on this a
little bit ago in a different uh
uh
topic or topic whatever it was session
uh in this 20th anniversary with my one
of my co-leaders but defect dojo is kind
of the heart of that automation
effort right it allows you a single
source of truth right all of this effort
you're doing you can combine in one
simple place which is also a fundamental
uh thing that needs to happen so quick
aside what's defect dojo
it's an open source security
orchestration platform for vulnerability
management it'll take
over a hundred plus tools security tools
in just the output of those tools
normalize and dedupe those consolidating
them into one view of all of your
security findings
from there you can push them to jira
there's notifications to slack
it gives you a place to list an
inventory of applications and also
endpoints in dojo speak which is your
computer assets
and then you can maintain those lists
you can understand what technology what
regulations are tied to which particular
application or infrastructure
so i said security personnel are your
critical resource this is why you need
to optimize their work right if you can
automate the non-human brain things
because let's be honest when i'm doing
the drudgery stuff i'm actually thinking
about like what i have to do this
afternoon or oh shoot the tires are
really low on my car i got to stop for
air i'm thinking about something else
right so let's automate that drudgery
stuff
and not have the human brain have to
cycle on that right this is going to
drive up consistency a lot you'll find
that a lot of these automation tasks are
those drudgery things that if you
automate them they're done consistently
and quickly and they're just off your
plate
it will definitely increase the tracking
of work status this is particularly if
you're using something like defect dojo
to manage how those assessments of
security are happening and track them
if you normalize things and sort of make
concrete paths for them to flow on
you're also going to greatly increase
the flow through the system
you will increase visibility and metrics
because you have one place where all of
this security work is happening so it's
very easy to report we've done so many
assessments or we the last time we
assessed this product was on march the
4th
right you can do all those kind of
things in one nice place and
reduces friction to the dev teams if
you're doing things like speaking their
language and pushing results into jira
right now so like i just said talk to
your constituency in the language they
speak right so if you're talking to
developers put findings in jira right
you need to
give results to people in a way that
they want to intake them not in a way
that works for you
um i wish i had more time i could do 30
minutes on each one of these books so
instead i'm gonna do the old professor
thing and this is an exercise left for
the student
right but if you haven't read
any of these books just pick one and
read it and i'd honestly say you should
read all three all of these books are
fantastic
the phoenix project it's a fictional
account of a company and some of the
problems they had and how they sold them
using devops the devops handbook is much
more of an instructional guide
to how to do devops and then product to
project project to product
is a great book on how to take these
concepts from devops and turn them into
real world products because at the end
of the day if we're working for a
company a company needs and wants to
make money
and so being able to do it in a way
that's productive for the overall goal
of the company is obviously going to win
you some friends and positively
influence people
so let's talk about apps like pipelines
like
um because
years ago aaron weaver and i came up
with this idea of like hey cicd is
really cool and it's been fantastic for
developers why can't security do
something like that so i don't want to
let devs have all the good ideas i want
to steal the ones that work for me and
cicd and the idea around that of having
a pipeline
was one that i think is fantastic for
application security and security in
general
so how do you think make things fast but
customized right because the whole
reason your company has a dev team
is they have something special for them
if they could just go buy it off the
shelf as a canned piece of software they
would but they can't right so they need
to make it so how do you make something
custom but also fast
and i think uh like your pick your your
favorite vendor burrito place has solved
this problem right
i can go down there and i want to get a
burrito with chicken but double cheese
and no uh
sour cream whatever right i could do
that the next person they've narrowed
down the choices to a handful of
well-known choices in a path that all
things follow if i get a second burrito
i start at the front of the line and i
walk down if i get a third burrito i
start at the frontal line and i walk
down it all works the same right so if
you can make your security operations
function with a bunch of well-defined
steps and choices
you can greatly speed up things
and still allowing it to be customized
so what do we get with this uh apsec
pipeline thing like i mentioned earlier
you get much better visibility into work
in progress because
just like in that burrito line there are
stages right there's the pick your meat
pick your beans pick your sides wrap up
the burrito and hand it and off you go
right if you have those same kind of
equivalents for your security program
and understanding your assessments you
know what the state of all of them is it
isn't like i started testing on monday
in two weeks i'll be done
you can actually know exactly where
you're at oh i've done the two sas uh
two i've run the two sas tools but i
haven't run the dash yet and i still
need to do a manual pen test i know
exactly where i am with that right
and as you're doing this and
particularly one of the things that
defect dojo allows you to do is break
out individual tools underneath one
assessment is you can understand and
track
where the time is actually taking where
are those bottlenecks that you need to
go optimize right as you're
understanding that wow that's really
weird we can do a sas assessment in a
week but a dashed assessment takes two
why is that right i want to look at
those dashed ones they're taking longer
why are they taking longer those kind of
questions can be answered
and as you've made your security work
these well-defined stages and steps and
choices
right it's going to
shockingly increase consistency because
you're forced to choose i'm going to get
black beans or i'm going to get refried
beans or i'm going to get charro beans
right those are my three choices it's
going to be a b or c i don't have a lot
of
other choices right which is fine
that's all you need to do right oh
you're a middle middle risk app you only
get dashed we don't do sass right maybe
that's your policy whatever it is the
specifics are much more important for
your business and in general but
that's the idea of increasing um
consistency
another interesting thing that grew out
of this when i did my first steps like
pipeline that i i would have bet against
was the fact that
we got
way better understanding of the cost of
switching
uh particularly at rackspace when i
worked there there was a lot of like omg
drop all your tools and go solve this
problem
well if i understand what everyone's
doing and what state that work is in i
can have a very good conversation with
management of okay that's fine but if i
take sally off that engagement that
yesterday you told me was crucial
that work will stop and it's like oh no
sally needs to keep working on that
engagement right you can have those
conversations instead of having to
remember
or like ask the team on slack what's
going on you can just answer
and the the the i found the pipeline to
be flexible enough to take everyone from
a a fresh green intern down to a
seasoned tester
and just hand out the the work a la
carte based on what their skill set is
so this is a very flexible sort of way
to do things
so let's talk about the first generation
of appsec pipeline and the real core
idea here is to look at your team's
purpose and those processes with agent
this is a quote stolen somewhat out of
the phoenix project
but really
you want to look at your
team and say hey there's there's these
fundamental steps that happen
when you're doing security work i have
intake right requests are going to come
in for you to assess something right you
need to triage that work which is the
next step i need to understand what i'm
being asked to do what's the right level
of testing what tools make sense for
this level of testing or the risk
inherent in this particular app or
infrastructure right i'm going to go run
a bunch of tests that's the next phase
the testing phase
and then i'm going to shovel those
results into a single vulnerability
repository hopefully not excel
hopefully something like defect dojo
and then you're going to deliver right
we're going to push those results out to
something like a grc tool you're going
to run to a default you're going to push
individual findings out to developers
via jira or whatever defect tracker they
use
you can use the rest api of something
like defect dojo
to do metrics right and do reporting
here's a real world example of the the
first one i ever really built myself and
aaron did this at a large education
company uh the bag of holding was an
internally developed application
it was open source but honestly we
wouldn't do that again and we didn't do
that again when we did newer versions of
those we moved all that functionality
into defect dojo so really defect dojo
can now handle intake as well as
being a vulnerability repository
but the idea is here is you're moving
left to right all the tools go through
this when you're triaging we're deciding
okay you're a very important tool you're
going to get varicode burp suite zap
um
white hat and qualis right you're you're
a low-risk tool we're only going to
throw maybe check marks and qualis at
you right you can make these decisions
you can base the the amount of testing
you do on the risk flow all that to
defect dojo
and once you have everything going to
dojo then you only have to solve that
how do i get it to x
constituency party uh problem once right
i don't need to worry about
how to uh push out results to jira to
to
the developers for every tool i only
have to do that one time for dojo which
is a big efficiency boost
the whole point of this gen 1 pipeline
is getting your house in order right
it's really hard for you to tell other
teams how to do stuff better if you
can't even do it better yourself is how
i like to view things right so make sure
that your internal systems that you use
to get testing done
work and are functional before you start
reaching out and trying to do things
with other teams
but
when we get to the gen 2 pipelines this
is where you look outside your team's
purpose
right and see which there are places you
can hook in to now start to have little
feelers in different parts of the
business that are outside of your sort
of normal testing flow
obviously great place to do this is if
you have some devops or pipelines
running
in the development side of the house why
not stub a little test in there does it
have to be breaking maybe it just runs
and reports back to defect dojo right
what happened in that last pipeline run
but now you have visibility in what's
going on in those pipeline runs right
depending on how you do dev work maybe
this is running in a death branch and
you can get early warning of issues that
are getting added into dev branches
before they get merged to master right
you have some interesting visibility
chances and opportunities with this kind
of a pipeline
and then let's talk about the third
generation of pipelines this is where
you scale your teams
um and try to dramatically increase
speed and visibility because you've got
your house in order you're now starting
to reach out to other teams and
integrate with them now you want to go
fast
um when you get with the 3rd gen
pipeline it's a great way to conduct
automated testing
it's run by the appsec team kind of for
the appsec team but honestly those those
feedback results are going to happen
through the normal path if you're using
something like defect dojo right out to
jira or whatever kind of place that
developers keep those findings
and it's a great way to scale your
coverage right
and the big difference is a lot of sort
of security purists will say well you
can't do really rigorous testing with
full automation and i would say
absolutely 100 totally agree with you
no no complaint what you will get is
breadth you will get a baseline across
if you run the same tools across all of
your repos that have source code you
will have a baseline and understand
which ones are really good and which
ones are much more scary
what it won't do because i also like
giving you the other side the good and
the bad it's not going to fix all your
problems automation won't make your code
better it'll just let you know it's not
good at a faster speed right
i would not make these tests blocking
and gates that never wins you friends or
influences people positively
particularly with dev teams and i like
to think of it as if you think about
pipelines pipelines create artifacts
right so cicd
if you're doing it right is going to
give you a deployed app at the end and
apps like pipeline is going to give you
findings and then you have to do the
same kind of work with any other finding
of getting it to the team making sure
it's addressed re-testing etc
so
first get the cake then do the icing and
gen 3 uh pipelines are really my idea of
the icing you've got to have those other
pieces in place before you can really go
there to be quite honest
so here's an example of a gen 3 pipeline
this is really more event based now
right so you have an event happen now
that event could be it's time for the
quarterly pci test or it could be
code just got checked into a repo
doesn't really matter but it's an event
so an event happens an abstract pipeline
reacts to that event to launch a bunch
of containerized dockerified tooling
right this is one of the places where
containers and docker
and kubernetes for that matter gives you
a lot of flexibility right so now i can
launch
on the fly
one or more tools pointing at a whole
bunch of different targets that could be
source code repos that could be apps
running in pre-prod it could be a bunch
of things right all those tools are
going to run
it will take those results push them
back to the apps like pipeline which
will then forward them on to defect dojo
where they get stored and normalized and
deduped right now if i want to run three
very similar tools against the same
target it kind of doesn't matter i get
better coverage and i let defect dojo
take the heavy lifting of merging and
understanding what's really actionable
out of those three different tool runs
even though they cover the same kind of
space
so why should you build an apsec
pipeline
well here's another real world example
just to give you another idea of what
you can do with this with this where we
have the developer checking in code
the into stash
right that stash is going to send a web
hook an event right to an apps like
pipeline docker is going to launch a
bunch of containers
those
results will go into defect dojo we'll
give a summary to the slack channel for
that dev team and then push those
results out to jira
now with this exact layout um
a friend of mine who was doing this was
able to look at 15 repos
over four months they had 5 100 runs of
that pipeline and 25 000 container
executions and those numbers are awesome
and they're very impressive but what it
really tells you is they made testing an
easy button right it's not this
onerous process of
days or got help few weeks to get things
done it's quite honestly an event
happens i run a bunch of tests i now can
get some feedback on what happened in
that event
and if you remember this guy that we
talked about just briefly a little bit
ago
this first sort of appsec pipeline that
we created what did that buy us
well in 2014
uh the this is a apsec team
did 44 assessments
we started building the pipeline in 20
in the in the early parts of 2015
by the end of 2015 for reasons that
aren't really important we lost 3.5
people
three orgs and whatnot
but we bumped up 44 to 224
and then two years later in 2016 we took
44 to 414
and lost two more people
right so we almost 10xed
the number of finding the number of
assessments our team could do while
losing people and most of this was due
to automation
so yeah that's an 8
increase
almost
10x
so in one final little bit there's this
really interesting uh
uh talk there uh
i guess was a blog post
maybe it was a youtube video i honestly
can't remember but it was called the
iceberg of ignorance and it was speaking
to how problems get hidden
the the further away from the front
lines you get right staff are going to
see 100 of the problems they're in the
front lines they're interacting with the
customers or your software or whatever
it is they see all the problems the team
leads are going to catch a good chunk of
them 74ish percent of the problems team
managers maybe 9
and the executives are going to see
about four
so how do you get
that bottom two thirds or more of that
iceberg
up to the level to where management can
see it
well you do that with security
automation right
it helps you push that visibility north
and the way you do that is if you have a
security baseline and i can say i'm
scanning all of my repos
and of all of the repos
10 of them are green
and six of them are red
that's that is if there was ever
something designed for executives
that's the kind of results you can do
when you baseline right how many meter
baseline how many don't meet our
baseline those are very simple easy to
consume metrics that make sense to the
executives who quite honestly have
bigger problems to to fill than knowing
that this library is out of date by one
version they don't
necessarily need to worry about it at
that level but they need to know that of
their suite of applications 20 of them
don't even meet the baseline right
that's how you get resources allocated
to fix those problems
and uh quote from my one of my favorite
movies brazil
listen kid we're all in this together
right
if you can have that attitude with the
teams in which you interact with
you will find that you will get a ton
more security work done than being the
no people
um and with automation and
writing that automation not only to make
your life better but to make the results
easier to uh consume for the
constituency whether that's your red
green on the baseline for executives or
here's something dropped automatically
into your backlog in jira right that's
how you win friends and influences and
have people believe that you're really
all that together
um and that's it
uh
happiness
we're all in it together another great
uh uh poster that was in that movie
brazil
um i will be jumping into the slack
channel to answer any questions people
have