[Music]
thank you so much and i am honored to be
following the og jeff williams
um yes that this is what shall we do
with a vendor s-bomb and it is early in
the morning for some of you for me too
we'll try to get through this together
uh you are going to hear and you have
heard a lot about s-bombs already jeff
touched on them as well in his talk
and
um
there are so many smart people working
on the first line problems of s-bomb how
do we standardize how do we generate
them uh here at cisco we've been
generating s-bombs for internal use for
several years
and we're still working on issues there
um the distribution and everything
i'm going to take a step forward and say
let's pretend that we solved all these
problems
and you are a ciso and you've asked your
vendor for an s bomb and now you have it
in your hot little hands
and it is integrated into your you know
favorite dashboard now what are you
going to do with it
so that's the point at which i want to
start this talk
now you can sing along with me every
section goes with the song use it before
you buy this software
let's talk about
pre-procurement what are you going to do
with an s-bomb
in the pre-procurement phase
you're going to want to insert it in
several places but let's talk about this
first
now there are some things that don't
even necessarily have anything to do
with security
uh that you're going to be using s-bombs
for like avoiding licensing conflicts
like yeah we cannot use we can't
incorporate uh con
something with this particular licensing
into our own software that's an
immediate no
uh or you may have a bunch of business
units that you discover through
duplicate s-bombs that they are all
procuring software from the same vendor
and you might want to go back and
renegotiate that deal to save some money
so again these things don't necessarily
have anything to do with security but
they could be very useful from a
business perspective in your
organization
another thing is to check provenance
there may be some sources that you
absolutely will not take software from
and that's an immediate no as soon as
you see it before you sign the po you
say nope sorry we can't take this
that's also very straightforward
now if you start looking at
vulnerabilities associated with the
s-bomb this is where
you're going to start delaying things
you're going to start holding up the
procurement you're going to have some vp
saying look i just want this software
can we just get it first and then argue
about it later
so there's going to be negotiation
you're going to go back to the vendor
and say well you know there's this
associated with your s-bomb and they'll
say no that doesn't really apply because
blah
so it that's where things are going to
slow down in pre-procurement and so i
would urge you to be very careful about
what you want to
put here as a gate in the
pre-procurement process that has to do
with vulnerabilities maybe really big
you know show stopping ones
but if you cannot get all of your
management to agree that yes this is a
case for stopping the procurement
then you're just going to make yourself
miserable going forward so think really
carefully about this
now some people
wonder whether
you could use s-bombs instead of
today's favorite
pen tests or sdlc questionnaires
and my answer to this is no that pen
tests discover very different things
from what is going to be an ns bomb at
least you would hope so
and sdlc questionnaires are aimed in
general at gauging the maturity of the
vendor
and you're not going to find that with
an s bomb except that yes it might be a
sign of maturity if they can generate an
s bomb
uh
you might set that as a low baseline at
some point that at the very minimum your
vendors all need to be able to generate
s-bombs if you're going to do business
with them
but
again i don't think s-bombs are going to
take the place of any of these that's
going to augment
the information gathering that you're
doing about your supply chain
not replace anything
so for pre-procurement i would encourage
you to focus on what you can
automatically stop or flag the the very
unambiguous parts of the s-bomb either
either it's there or it's not either it
says this or it doesn't
and then you know you can log the rest
for notifications later
and uh don't forget to come join me in
the slack channel after this if you want
to argue with me because i love a good
knock down drag out slack so this will
be fun
next verse
use it for risk and bone disclosure
talk about vulnerability disclosure now
we already know a lot about
vulnerability management so what can we
learn from it to apply to s-bombs
first of all someone else's criticality
rating isn't always going to be yours we
know this
and
uh in fact if you are using different
different methods of prioritizing your
vulnerabilities for remediation i urge
you to look at a report series from
scientia institute and canada security
and full disclosure kenna was acquired
by cisco earlier this year
they have a great series called
prioritization to prediction
and in the first report
they
revealed what i thought was some very
interesting data in research that
if you compare all the different methods
that you might use to prioritize
patching
if you use any one of them
whether it's criticality or exploit
available or blast radius or whatever
that method is likely no better than
patching randomly and i thought that was
just mind-blowing now they did find that
if you use all the methods and combine
them
you might get a better result in in
terms of coverage and accuracy on your
patching
but
this is something that you need to be
good at
uh before you start using s-bombs to
decide uh because prioritization is
still going to be a thing
you're going to have to annotate what's
really definitely affected
and what isn't
so you might look at an s bomb and a
vulnerability associated with it and say
yes that's the real vulnerability but
it's only you know
it only affects these functions and
we're not calling those functions
so you're going to want to annotate that
somewhere and say yes you know
not affected
because we don't call those functions
wendy signed off on it on this date
you're going to need to show it to
auditors you know you're going to have
to pull it up you might want to flag
that
later if you change the code and you end
up calling those functions then you
definitely are affected
so all of those things and again this is
not new we we have this issue today but
just be prepared to do even more of it
you got to annotate what the disposition
is of the s-bomb
do we patch or do they patch
and again here's another issue that we
have to try to figure out it's going to
be more with s-bombs
depending on whether it's open source do
we find somebody else does the vendor
disclaim all responsibility if you patch
it
what is the timeline does it require
recertification
all of those things
and so if even if you have good
remediation and update processes right
now to estimate how much it's going to
cost and how long it's going to take to
remediate something
you're going to need even more of them
when you start getting s-bombs in the
door
so you can't just bring in s-bombs and
let them sit and not decide what to do
with them
that's going to be a big problem
also we can learn things from threat
intelligence when we're looking at using
s-bombs and consuming them
here's a good lesson do you even trust
the s-bomb
i can certainly see in the future where
organizations are going to say yes we
trust the s-bombs from these vendors but
this vendor
uh yeah it's always it's always really
dodgy they don't really know what
they're doing they just kind of wave
their hands and and spat out something
that looks like an s-bomb but we don't
trust it
um the same thing with threat
intelligence today with iocs that have
been sanitized and they don't tell you
enough the s-bomb is going to be as
brief as it can possibly get away with
being and so if you have questions about
technical details yeah we see this in
the s bomb and we got questions who are
you going to ask
about it make sure you understand
how to do that
another thing i want to point out is
that there are plenty of organizations
out there today who insist on getting
the source code from their vendors and
scanning it themselves
and if you can get the source code
that's great
you can imagine that a vendor might say
well now we have an s bomb can we just
give you the s-bomb
and i expect that those who prefer to do
their own scanning are going to say no
that's not good enough
we need the source code still
if you're going to do your own scanning
please be very careful what tools you
use if you're going to use binary
scanners if you don't have the source
code
according to our own data inside of
cisco checking our binary scanning tools
against our source code
we found that the binary tools are only
about 60 percent accurate in what they
find
and i have heard other people ranting
and raving that actually the tools are
closer to producing like 99 false
positives sorry for for you know binary
scanning tool vendors out there but
anyway from our own data from the tools
that we use about 60 accuracy yeah not
great
so if you're scanning your
the um
if you're scanning binaries on your own
and you're going back to the vendor and
saying you know i'm seeing this
and uh you know i don't you should have
listed this in your s-bomb
this is the same problem that we have
today
when people are reporting
vulnerabilities through a bug bounty
program or anything else there are some
researchers who bring in great bugs and
we go yes we absolutely agree good find
have a t-shirt or whatever
but then there are others that will
bring in uh you know some assertion and
we'll have to go you know i think you
really misinterpreted this
or you didn't use the tool right this
isn't really a thing and that
negotiation is going to take a long time
it's very annoying for both sides so
please
don't do this unless you're sure you can
really find
worthy
issues to take up with the source of the
software that you've gotten
because otherwise there's going to be a
lot of confusion around the use of these
s-bombs and we'd like to try to avoid
that
now remember to everybody blocking is
breaking
now there are many
organizations out there that will say
well we're just going to automate
because there's so much data that's
going to come in with these s bombs
and and we're going to automate you know
matching up the vulnerabilities and
we're going to match up all the exploits
with threat intelligence and then we're
going to automatically block anything
that we see
no you're not and um even if you were
perfect at
detecting active exploits
in the data stream and blocking them
your organization your customer is not
going to trust you to do it
which is why i remember 10 years ago
i think the figure was that only about
10 percent of wafs out there actually
had any blocking rules enabled i don't
know what the figure is now
somebody can tell me in the slack
channel but i'm guessing it's not much
bigger than that because the truth is
that a lot of customers don't
know enough about
their software especially legacy
software to know
whether it's going to be safe to try to
block something i did hear about an
application that purposely used sql
injection to update the database
purposely
and i'm sure the developer was very
proud of themselves for having come up
with this really neat trick
so you can't just block things and so
don't assume that when you have an s
bomb it's gonna
you know automatically add more rules
for things
which leads us to the question of who's
going to need this information and who
simply needs an fyi on these s-bombs
think about who in your organization is
going to need to see them and who just
needs to know that they're there or who
just wants to look at them you know
every six months or whatever there are
going to be some people
in your team who are going to want to
look at them in depth trace them uh
validate them and all sorts of things
and there are people who are just going
to dabble like they may want to do
random sampling and go to a vendor do
you do you have the s-bomb for this yeah
okay i was just checking
think about that
and what is the risk and the impact of
partial remediation let's say we have
this
particular component in 27 locations
and we can remediate one of them right
now but the others are going to take six
months because of reasons
again how are you going to track that
how are you going to
make sure that you follow up on things
how are you going to explain the
timeline
and how are you going to estimate the
risk
of that remediation
is anybody getting depressed yet
sorry
and then finally everybody who talks
about us bombs almost without exception
gets really excited about the idea of oh
we're going to make social graphs and
we're going to find out where
components are widespread and where they
came from and trace them all the way
back and we're going to do social graphs
and it's going to be so cool
and i agree they're really cool but what
are you really going to do with them
let's say that we build
amazing research and social graphs and
we discover that some vulnerable
component has now infiltrated half of
the known
civilized world
that's going to make a great owasp talk
and it's going to make a great black hat
talk
but what is your customer really going
to do about it
what what are they going to do with that
info are they going to throw you know
that component out is that going to be
any different
from how they would have
disposed of it you know not knowing
about the social graph as my colleague
helen patton points out
there is no terminal point at the end of
a
supply chain
there's no one end where you say okay
now we've stopped and we've traced it
all the way back
so be careful when you start graphing
things because you may be adding
visibility
visibility i'm going to go out on a limb
here visibility isn't always good yeah
it's it's not always good sometimes it
just confuses the issue more so be
careful and think about what visibility
you need
because you're going to do something
with it
now the final verse good look like using
it for
forensics
yeah forensics
know the limits of this s-bomb you know
when you're when you're going to start
using it
let's say that you
hear about a vulnerability six months
down the line
and
it was in a version of software that
might have been in place but you have to
figure out whether it was do you really
have logs
on every component
and how long it was installed in which
locations from what date to what date
again i'd love to hear about it in slack
if you really can produce those from six
months away
i'm guessing the answer is no for most
people
so
yeah this is going to be tough and
furthermore
do you know enough about how each
component is used to know whether it was
really exploited
again
from my work in organizations there's a
lot of software that they don't know
very much about anymore
either it's legacy and it hasn't been
touched in 10 years
or
it belongs to another vendor
they're not allowed to look inside it
it's not theirs
they inherited it with from an
acquisition
and all the people they acquired left
there are so many reasons why
just getting an s bomb and getting
information will make you have to go
look at the innards of an application
for the first time and go spelunking
and
i
am guessing that you don't have people
sitting around waiting for these
spelunking assignments
so you're going to have to figure out
resourcing how important is it
for us to get to the bottom of this and
really track it down
and really either prove a positive or a
negative
so um
think about this
when we think about consumers of s-bombs
we and and a lot of application security
we tend to use as example the the top
one percent of security organizations
like
um you know financial services
and that we think of them as the end
consumers of everything like they sit
there and they
you know consume everything but what's
really going to be more important
are the people in the middle of the
supply chain if you are receiving and
you are sharing and you are distributing
uh you're incorporating and you're
passing things on
as an entity in the middle of a supply
chain you're going to have to know what
you want and what you're going to say to
other entities downstream about these
things
so you're going to have to decide to the
depth at which you can investigate
something because you're going to owe
answers
to your your recipients to your
downstream customers and to your
partners
so
the downside to this is that
if you have incomplete data
and you can't find the answer you can't
prove a negative
it usually means that you you know to be
on the safe side you have to do a breach
notification
so suddenly you're in the position where
your
legal people are saying well we have
this concern because there was this
vulnerability announced with this
associated with this s-bomb we know that
we had this at some point
in our systems but you're saying that's
all the information we can get on it we
cannot say for sure that we weren't
affected
and they're going to hate that because
everybody hates incomplete information
you get just enough information to give
you more reasons to worry and then you
can't assuage that worry
this is something you're gonna have to
talk with your with your management team
about what are we going to do if we
can't answer it
because i predict there will be a lot of
that
uh what about sass
what if you are using a sas provider do
you go to them and say we want your
s-bombs and your s-bombs of your s-bombs
and your s-bombs of your s-bombs and
they will probably go
uh no no we are not doing that
so
is it going to be s bombs all the way
down at what point are you going to be
satisfied as a consumer
with
uh the number of s-bombs that you get
and again
this is all the limits of the s-bombs
and the limits of the knowledge that
you'll be able to get from them
so think about those as well
here are a few more thoughts about
s-bombs and that is that
i think when we all start using them and
and i'm sure we will
uh it's going to prompt a big initial
flood of data that will cost time and
effort to sort through and to make
decisions about and that's as if we
didn't already have enough or too much
data that we are trying to wade through
most organizations have more threat
intel coming in than they can deal with
and they have more log data
and alerts coming in than they can deal
with
so s bombs are just going to make that
worse because we are going to get
visibility which will be great but it
will be at a next level down
a granular level that we may not be
prepared to look at
and uh once again decide who in your
resource
pool
is going to have the time and ability to
to trace these down who is going to be
consuming them
uh not just how is it going into your
infrastructure
because again i'm going to warn you
you're not going to be able to automate
all of it you may not even be able to
automate any of it especially at the
beginning you're going to have to
annotate the disposition and the
analysis of those s bombs and you're
going to be
have to answer questions based on them
especially if you're in the middle of a
supply chain
so
it's going to prompt a big initial flood
of data think carefully about this
i really want to hear what
what the public sector is thinking about
this
in light of the executive order
now if you don't already have a
vulnerability management process working
for what you learn about today
please don't add s-bombs to the mix
again i think it's just going to make
your situation worse
and i'm willing to to fight about that
but and here's an idea
that my colleagues and i had
if you are a small business and you've
never been able to assess the
vulnerability of your infrastructure
before
s bombs might be a good place to start
with you know the assistance of a
consultant or mssp or something like
that if you don't have the expertise to
analyze it yourself but just to collect
s-bombs from your vendors
and again you're probably going to be
more reliant on those vendors than
larger organizations are
but you just kind of want to know
what it is that you're using and what it
is that you're dealing with it's a good
exercise
to go through and see
not only
what is in the s-bomb that you get from
your vendor but what's your relationship
with your vendor
it's even more important to test that
part if they hedge and say well
you won't understand the s-bomb so we're
not going to give it to you or
oh sure here it is no we're not going to
explain it to you
then you may want to reconsider your
relationship with that vendor
this is going to be a new level of
relationship between customers and
providers where they have to figure out
how to have these dialogues and these
negotiations around s-bombs
so these are my predictions
for when we start using them whenever
that is
and then finally i'm going to share some
resources and i'm going to ask martin to
do me a favor and copy and paste these
into the 20th anniversary oh wasp
standard classification
classification
slack channel
so that you can click on them and look
at them yourself
if as
uh if as a
um
as a consumer you decide you want to use
s-bombs and you want to ask for them in
a vendor contract the ntia has a really
good paper on how to do this so i i
recommend that here's the kenneth
prioritization to prediction link it's a
i think it's a group of seven papers but
the statistic that i was quoting was
from the very first one
and also if you want to hear about how
they're discussing labeling programs for
consumers
here's a nice link to one of the the
workshop sessions
so i want to thank everybody for paying
attention here
and for singing along if you sang along
with me
and
i will see you over in the slack