[Music]
so hello everybody um as john said my
name is stefan
and um i'm going to talk about devsecops
in 2031 so it's gonna be a bit of a
futuristic talk and
it's a bit of an experiment as well so
let me know how you like it
um
my background is
like i mentioned i've done a lot of
hardcore security testing which means i
was actually in the early days doing
security
security tests in networks all of these
things when there was no tools around we
had to write everything ourselves
and after being on the offensive side
for many many years i got sucked into
the secure software developments and
later on into
devops and devsecops which to me was a
complete game changer because
it changed my perspective on security as
a whole
and while i was consulting with a lot of
different organizations around the globe
for introducing the devsecops practices
i also realized that the security
automation piece
is completely broken in my opinion and
set out to fix it
and so
since then i've started a company called
guardrail and i'm now the cto there
and just a quick blog
plug
we are actually
uh just hiring dramatically so if you
are
a hardcore security folk as well that
wants to help millions of developers
secure their applications and make
security a better place please do send
us an email to careers gardeners i hope
all right
so now
let's dig in
we're gonna have our protagonist called
sam and sam is a security lead for a
very hot
new fintech application
and she got like
full buying from
from the top level management and she
was there from day one to make sure that
this project is gonna be
top-notch secure and that everything is
going to be
the best possible outcome
and so she was able to bring to bed to
get a dream team of other security
engineers and is working with the best
of in the industry that are developing
and architecting this this application
and they have an unlimited budget which
is great
so sam was able to implement the best
possible security approach that is state
of the art for this application for this
project and yeah same is really awesome
same also knows that sharing is caring
and as as part of being a community
you have to always make sure that you
can bring these new new approaches to
your peers and as such she decided to
share this in the local
chapter
her security approach looked something
like this
first of all
we understand that security
starts with developers starts with the
operation teams and so sam actually
decided that every engineer every person
writing code no matter if it's for the
application for the content for the api
for the mobile app or for the
infrastructure
they have to get through some form of
traditional security training which
means understanding what is important
what is the important
security what are the important security
goals of the application what are the
reason the risk we want to avoid what
are risks in general and then of course
we also started they also started doing
gamified security training which makes
sure that they could actually take
existing vulnerabilities that they had
in their application
and they also were able to actually use
this in a gamified way to learn what are
the problems they had how do they fix it
and so this was to ensure that everybody
at a at any time has a good baseline of
security understand what they want to
achieve and that really helped just make
sure to set the stage
then in addition to this of course
because of the financial application
threat modeling and agile threat
modeling has been done for
every sprint making sure that the new
features that are coming in are
completely secure and all of the adverse
test cases are being considered and the
threats are being modeled out in
addition to this every user story also
has to have security acceptance criteria
which may be something simple like what
are the different
authorization issues that we have to
cover what are the requirements for
inputs validation and normalization etc
and there are also dedicated security
stories for example how do our how does
our our authentication framework look
like and how do we make sure that this
is done properly to authorize people etc
etc
when it comes to selecting open source
libraries
there was a very very
minimalistic approach taken
because we all know that um open source
software there's a different level
of quality there's a lot of parks being
discovered and we're building our
applications on this foundation
so besides making sure that only
respective uh respectable approaches are
being used and languages being used that
are you know um
uh more minimalistic and lightweight
there was also an automated security
patch process in place meaning not just
when like every time there's new
security vulnerabilities available
automatically the pull requests would
have been created to make sure that this
has to be merged before the next
iteration
will come
will be deployed to the uh
as part of the application and of course
we also understood sam also understood
that license compliance is very
important
so there was also of course um
gate like a gates in place to make sure
that only libraries that are in line
with the
legal requirements that we have for the
application could be actually
introduced
in addition to this we also made sure
sam also made sure that in their team
every single commit that was being
created would actually be scanned with
with static analysis tools covering
everything from
infrastructures code configuration
your normal application code secrets you
name it
on top of that only prs can be merged no
code can be committed directly to any of
the repos
and they would require peer review so at
least two people would have to actually
approve a pr before it gets merged to
reduce the risk further that any of the
violent like any malicious code may be
introduced or maybe some attacker gets a
coding that could cause a supply like
could cause an attack against the
application
because everything was containerized in
microservices there was also of course
policies around containers making sure
that only containers with uh no high
risk of critical risk
cves could be deployed and once
everything was done
the deploy to the test environment would
automatically trigger dynamic scanning
and of course the application in the
test environment have uh is enabled
which means you get a very good coverage
that's also further orchestrated and
exercised with the functional test
suites that are running against it
in addition to this we also of course
had functional security tests that are
running against the api so in addition
to the acceptance criteria that you have
you would also have good and bad
security tests and every security test
was ever every security vulnerability
that was ever identified
would have been coded as a failing test
and only when news was passing it would
have been
able to continue
in addition we of course also had manual
security testing in phase which is
penetration testing internally and there
was also security acceptance criteria
testing which means when a ticket gets
approved a security team member would
have to make sure that all of these
things are there and working as expected
not just from the functions functional
side of things but also from the
security side of things
and in addition
chaos security experiments are being
started making sure that
the
the uh the system is not just reliable
but also secure and that injecting
failures would allow everybody to make
sure that the responses is ready that
these these
events would be identified and
everything would be managed the way it
is intended to be
there's also a continuous validation of
the product environment following the
three hours of enterprise security which
means rotate repave and repair
rotate means that all the credentials
would never be static they would always
be automatically
recover
rotated you also have of course the
repave making sure that your production
environment is reset to a known state
and so there's no long-running
containers which also reduces the risk
of making sure that attackers that may
get in there that they don't really have
a foothold
of course we
the the systems also have random
application self-protection and next
generation valves in place
and on top of that micro segmentation
was being used ensuring that every
system can only communicate with another
system in the approved way so all the
firewalls on these local machines were
orchestrated to make sure you only have
communication that is approved even into
services
and there's also a stock in place to
make sure that there was extensive
security monitoring and they started
looking at behavioral
analysis which actually just mentioned
in the last part of his talk as well to
make sure to see that not just people
doing stuff is fine and they have the
credentials but also that doing the same
things and the right things uh in line
with the behavioral profile that we had
and finally there was the bug bounty
program making sure that there's
continuous security testing from third
parties that make sure that everything
else is hopefully identified as quickly
as possible before hackers come in
so that was the beautiful thing that sam
has come up with
and sam has been so happy with the
results the project was a huge success
they're in a really good position
there's almost no security depth
and not just the project members and the
company is really happy her peers that
she has presented this to are amazed
with what what she has brought up
here so really happy and content with
herself
sam is now heading home
getting ready for bed when suddenly
her future self appears
and her future self has a message saying
that um
the world is at risk because
something is happening and hackers are
threatening to take over the planet
sam is really confused with that and
just a disclaimer we are not going to
look into time travel paradoxes because
they won't apply to the story
so
what happened
in the future 10 years from now
specifically
a semi-sentient continuously evolving
hacker ai
has escaped the lab and has been
successfully attacking 95
of all the critical apps out there
because they were not secured properly
and now future self says hey i know you
have a lot of questions but there's no
time so come with me to the future
and i will explain everything to you
so sam is coming with her and they
arrive
in 2000 in 2031
future self is continuing to tell the
story
so first of all
first of all you have to understand that
you have done a great job with the
approach that we've just mentioned
which has led to amazing opportunities
for you in the future but
it was also the main reason why i was
allowed to join this task force to
battle these uh sent to battle this
sentient a
ai and make sure that we can actually be
in a position to get ahead and change
the history because we are losing the
battle
so in order to continue now we have to
understand
even though the project that you have
just set up and you've just released it
everything is looking great you have to
understand that it's actually a bunch of
really important issues with the way
that this is being done even though
you're state of the art
the scalability of securing this
is actually
very very difficult
you have secured one application
but you know this application is just
one product of the entire organization
that you're working for
and this approach that you have stream
like that you've pioneered
works really well here and you spend a
lot of time
over a year actually securing it however
what about the rest of your portfolio in
the organization
what about other organizations
out there
not everybody has the same uh
access to talent all of these other
things and
budget to actually make that happen
so while it's a great reference it
actually is not allowing you to do this
in a meaningful way and actually help
everybody with this approach
in addition yes you have done a lot of
automation on the tools
but lots of these tools are still very
noisy and do take away a lot of time
from developers to realize what is the
problem here and they do require a lot
of tuning which takes away a lot of time
of making these things actually useful
escape as well
in addition
we actually have uh there's a different
set of tools
even sometimes for the same scanning
techniques
and they're not well integrated together
so you have to actually write a lot of
integration code and glue to make sure
that you can get these different tools
in there that you can actually make sure
that these results are the same
you you have to de-duplicate the the
issues if this is the same kind of tools
with the same focus on certain
techniques
and that's also a big challenge to
actually scale it up
and furthermore correlation
you have been able to have like all of
these different
uh results for applique like for issues
and codes at run time in infrastructure
but it's not very clear how these things
actually go together how can you
actually make sure that an issuing code
correlates with this
report from a bug bounty program
that actually addressed it at runtime
here
and how you get all of these things
together is a big issue because
applications are getting more and more
complicated infrastructure is getting
more and more complicated so you have to
be able to actually
make sense of this in a meaningful way
that allows you to address the risk in a
way that makes sense and you can
actually
do the right things and focus on the
right
fixes
and finally the adoption
so only high performing companies with
the right access to talent can implement
this approach that you've managed that
you've mentioned mentioning and that's a
real issue
so besides these things
a lot of these things that we have been
talking about like
that we have been addressing the last
decades
um
will be something that is really
important to actually get this battle
sorted with the sentient ais so let me
catch you up on what we have achieved in
this 10 years
as an industry and as a soft development
community to make sure that we can do
the best
in terms of securing applications
so first of all in 2031
only typesafe lightweight programming
languages
are being used
which means
languages like golang have really won
because they were able to
you know give you a very good safe
environment they're easier to understand
they're easier to compile and check
against and they're super lightweight
and this is really important because
you want to be able to make sure that
your applications are
very well maintained and it's very hard
to write something that's that's diffic
that's uh not clear from a type
perspective etc etc
another thing that was a huge change
in that we have
influenced over the last decade
is that open source software
is not being used the way it's used
today
you know like when you look at your node
modules and you have like
hundreds of megabytes of libraries to do
certain things this was no longer viable
and um
so what has been done is we have
actually started incorporating open
source software in generally recognized
as safe
lists which means there's like a
hierarchy between open source software
that allows you to select
high quality well-maintained
well-secured
open source software to do certain
things and this was important to reduce
the problem with
supply chain risk etc etc and also quite
important is that a lot of organizations
that use this open source software that
is considered as safe they actually give
their own employees and full-time staff
members to make sure that they actually
can contribute in making this secure so
there's a lot of more work happening
around securi
and source software and funding that
because that's really what a huge attack
vector was was to to secure
in addition serverless and event-driven
architectures
have actually started coming up more and
more
because you don't actually want to
manage the infrastructure host or
network security concerns and you just
want to be focusing on writing functions
as a service and have this event driven
architecture to be in a position where
you can just make these changes you can
just focus on the features and you don't
have to worry about patching the
underlying application
and most importantly we have made huge
strikes in ai pair programming and this
has led to a huge improvement in the
quality and security of code
and sam interjects
hang on
ai pair programming
isn't it like this openai codex project
that it just released in august 2021
but this was like really bad right it
created vinyl and buggy code so how did
that actually happen how did that
actually evolve
and so yes that's exactly like that
remember that in the early days
initially the gpt3 was not able to code
at all
but there have been very quick
changes and improvements where they
started fine tuning this gp2 gpt3 model
based on public github repos
and even within a very very short time
they were able to actually solve 30
percent of these
programming challenges
and you know going from 0 to 30
it was just a matter of time to go to
100 and even
beyond that if you will
so ai
power pair programming and
was just really one of the key things
and yes initially
there was a lot of
ai generated code that was quite bad
because actually there's a really cool
article that i've linked here as well
um
of all of these scenarios that were
created by let's say github autopilot in
this case
they had contained security flaws
and this may sound really scary because
if people don't know what they're
looking for and they're not able to
understand what this code is being
generated for it actually is going to be
a big issue and we will have a lot of
insecure code
but funnily enough
this is the same bias that we have seen
with um racial racial um
buyers where you know facial detection
works really well for caucasian people
but not maybe for people of other races
because the data set was mainly focused
on white caucasians the same is true
with um
with open source code and code that is
being ingested by this model so this was
actually something where you can with a
lot of um with a little bit of fine
tuning you can make a huge strides in
eradicating a lot of these
vulnerabilities and actually this will
be a result of eradicating entire
vulnerability classes
so let's take a look at oba's top 10 and
how it's going to look in
2031.
so i've just put in the picture here
where you can see 2017 to 2021 a lot of
changes have happened right and more
importantly the three new areas such as
insecure design software and data
integrity failures
and and others
but
in 2031
there are no more cryptographic failures
there are no more injection level
vulnerabilities security
misconfiguration is gone vulnerable
outdated components no longer an issue
because these things are where actually
i can really help out making sure that
code level issues are being addressed
and secret injection has been around for
way too long for example same like
crosstalk scripting and this something
way ice can be very very strong in
actually reducing these vulnerability
classes in total however when it comes
to designing applications broken access
control institute design
and these kind of high-level business
logic issues are very very important and
they will still be a big issue where
humans have have to work
but yeah great news finally those pesky
secret injections are gone
who would have thought
all right and other things that have
changed now in these last 10 years
auto fixing of the most code level
vulnerabilities like institute
configuration has been has been mastered
but with the help of ai like we said
but get this
there are no more dedicated security
pipelines or actions or whatever you
want to call them
what has happened is that there's full
stack scanning that is triggered by
relevant workflow events so think think
about it this way you don't have to like
every pipeline you're looking at
besides maybe they're using different
tools from different vendors they look
exactly the same your checking code you
do something that looks at the
code level vulnerabilities you deploy to
a
test environment you start your runtime
testing so all of these things are the
same sometimes you use action for sub
things like only secret scanning etc but
actually that doesn't make any sense
because it's a source problem you just
have to integrate it into the right
eventing workflow events such as code is
being pushed a system has been deployed
a new instance in your cloud environment
is coming up and based on this the right
tools will actually be triggered
automatically so you don't have to mess
around with pipelines you can't just
really get started and focus on building
great software and these security tools
which are scanning and give you the
relevant feedback in your workflow
anyways
and finally education is also fully
integrated into the workflow which means
every time the security issues being
identified
there's nurturing campaigns that
actually make sure that developers learn
about these mistakes until you really
get it in a meaningful way
and make sure that these things are
being eradicated
on an ongoing basis
so that sounds really great actually so
what is the problem what do you need me
for to change in 2021 to make this
problem go away
so
the problem is that even though in the
future we have much better solutions now
many organizations small and big still
have a very very hard time adapting
these new technologies
which means automation and isi we still
need a lot of people to help
organizations improve their workflows
and actually actually implement the
change we still need people understand
exactly
what the problem is and how to address
it even though it will be augmented with
automation and ai
so i need you
to help spread the word
we gotta make sure that there's smart
automation and work for integration
we can't be wasting time with pipelines
and you know we gotta have seamless
feedback for developers at the right
time
also auto fixing and repairing of code
this is something that is just going to
be
boosting the productivity of any team
you're on and helping with the shortage
we have for talent already and this will
start with using rules to make sure that
you can actually fix very simple
patterns but then over time the eye will
be able to leverage this so make sure
that you can actually work on these
things and then and then and make sure
that this auto fixing is being really
streamlined and fast tracked in
combination with the smart automation
make sure that generally recognize the
safe list for open source
software projects will become something
that the community as a whole is working
on
because then we're going to have to keep
projects that are backed and secured
back uh backed and secured by companies
similar to all of us flagship projects
the same thing should be available for
open source where you can really focus
on building high quality open source and
have like a pre-filled list of things
that you can actually select with a high
level of confidence that there's no
surprises in there
and finally embrace machine learning and
ai
it will make our jobs easier
but we still need a lot more people and
talent to help secure our world and this
is like i said to make sure that they
understand applications they understand
security understand what the product
actually does and make sure that ai and
automation is being used in a meaningful
way so that we can focus on the high
impact issues
that actually are fun to work on and
we're not wasting time looking at yet
another cross-site scripting
and with that
i leave you back to the future to the
present in 2020 2021
and i wish you all the best
anyways thanks this was my presentation
i hope you enjoyed it it was a bit of an
experiment like i said
so if you have any questions ask me on
slack or shoot me an email at stefan at
guardrails io thank you very much