[Music]
so thank you all for being here uh so
the title of my talk is a little bit a
long one so it's everything you always
wanted to know about fingerprinting
browser extensions but we're afraid to
ask so hopefully you learn and you can
also not be afraid to ask afterwards in
the slack channel so uh in short i'm an
associate professor at stony brook
university in long island new york
i work in all types of web security and
network security and privacy
you can see there a few of the areas
that i work in working online tracking
which is the focus of today's talk uh
dns security web application
fingerprinting mobile browser security
so how are mobile browsers different
than desktop browsers in terms of the
security attack surface reduction can we
take large web applications and shrink
them down to the parts that we want to
keep uh and get rid of the rest and the
the vulnerabilities in in that rest of
the code um how can we use honeypots and
deception technologies for defenses in
web applications and finally anti-bot
technologies so
uh as i mentioned the talk will be
focused on online tracking but
please feel free to to look me up and
see all the other work that we've done
in all these other spaces so
i'll start by just mentioning something
that should be obvious to anyone who's a
web user the browser extensions are very
very popular right so
browser extensions allow us to customize
our browsers in a way
that we want to do it and it's not
supported out of the box by by browser
vendor and so
probably the vast majority of the people
attending this uh talk will have at
least an ad block excuse me an ad
blocker installed right and then
probably some a good chunk are using
some form of online password manager
right so such as lastpass uh and then
there is really you know the sky's the
limit in terms of extensions so you have
extensions that check the text that you
type and make sure that your syntax is
nice and clean right they have
extensions that are searching for
coupons when you're trying to purchase
something so you get a better price
right you have extensions that
if you're a pinterest user you can save
things your pinterest right and uh
you can even interface with antivirus uh
software that has trouble otherwise
looking into your browser because of the
end-to-end encryption these days so
browse exchanges are very popular and
many many users are using particularly
power users
the from a privacy perspective they're
also considered to be somewhat private
right so if you if you're not familiar
with browser fingerprinting it's this
idea that
you can extract information from a
user's browser
combine that information um
into a fingerprint and that fingerprint
turns out to be quite unique so if i if
you come to my website and i use
javascript for example read your screen
resolution uh extract your list of fonts
that are installed on your machine uh
draw a complex 3d object in a canvas and
then read it back as bytes
uh it turns out that all of these right
have effectively uh characteristics that
are very dependent on your hardware
stack on your software stack on your
choices as a user so this fingerprinting
idea is well known right and so um
plugins right such as java and flash and
so on you could actually read this when
you were doing this fingerprinting and
incorporate them into your fingerprint
and
a few years back plugins were quite a
big source of
um
of uniqueness right so there was they
were considered a powerful
fingerprinting vector however as you may
already know uh plugins
are going or have gone the way of the
dodo uh so we don't really like plugins
anymore we think they're buggy right
there's like third-party code running
natively into your browser with high
privileges
so
flash is deprecated
java
kind of in your browser right so most
users these days don't really have
uh plugins anymore but they do have
extensions right and so
just to make it clear extensions are
built using javascript css and html
right and they that's it you just build
an extension uh you have access to
privileged apis so that you can access
cookies across all websites you can
access tabs you can do all sorts of
things but you're not running code
anymore native code in the way that
plugins used to right so
um
if you compare plugins to extensions
extensions are not
there is no way for a page to list the
browser extensions that a user has
installed and the reason for this is
that extensions for the most part are
not meant to be there to help the page
right so a page in the past would check
if you support flash in order to show
you a flash app
but when you have an app blocker all
right obviously the page kind of doesn't
want you to be using an ad blocker right
but these are installed by users
to um to augment their experience and to
better their experience of browsing
they're not for the most part again
they're not meant to be somehow
collaborating with a website to better
your experience so the long the the
short story of this is that there is no
api that a web page can use that says
give me your list of browser extensions
that doesn't exist okay
so that would lead us to the question
are these extensions undetectable so is
it
is it not possible really for a
web page to discover what extensions you
have installed
and if you've been using the web for
more than a day
you most likely know that no that
doesn't seem to be the case right so
there's a lot of websites that are
actually able to detect that you're
using an app blocker for example right
and then they ask you to either pay for
a subscription or turn it off or do
something else right and
so we know that clearly it's possible
but the question is how is it possible
right if there is no api that a website
can use to inquire uh into your browser
how is it that the website knows that
you're actually using an ad blocker
right so that's part of what we will
cover today
the next question is okay so what are
the implications of a website knowing
that you have extension installed right
so if you have an ad blocker installed
they can force you to
disable it or pay them right but other
than that what are the implications of a
website knowing what it is that you're
running right the first one is sort of
the obvious one uh is that if i know
what extensions you have installed i can
actually tailor my exploits so maybe i
know i have a vulnerability for a given
extension i know that you're running
that extension i being the malicious
website uh so i can now launch
that uh exploit against the extension
that you know have installed right so
that's problem number one uh problem
number two is that it turns out that um
because users choose to install
extensions
your list of extension reveals something
about you right and about me so for
instance if you look there at the bottom
of the screen
if you have an extension that
does like gpg in your emails
that means that you are technically
savvy and a website if it's able to
detect the presence of that extension
can actually already put a label on you
about what it is that you know and you
don't know right if you have some sort
of coupon finding extension
now as a website i know that you're
price sensitive right i can place you in
a certain socioeconomic category right
um if you have a favorite politician or
a hated politician
chances are that someone has built an
extension that whenever they find their
name on the internet they will hide the
article or they replace it with some
sort of swear words such as the two
extensions there on the bottom
so
again if i if i'm able to discover that
you have such an extension installed i
can immediately peg you
uh and peg your uh your political
leanings right uh and the same goes for
religious leanings and for for all sorts
of other things that i can infer about
because of your choice to install a
given extension or not right so that's a
problem number two and the third problem
which is also in the privacy space has
to do now with actually using this to be
anonymized right so if you see there on
the right we have a bunch of users and
on the left we have a bunch of
extensions and the whole idea now is
that if i as a user
have chosen a unique set of extensions
to install
and the website can
can figure out that i have this
extension installed
these effectively become a fingerprint
of me right so if no other user for
example if i'm user one and i have
installed ghostary adblock plus and
smart video let's say and there's no
other user that has installed this
specific combination of extensions now
i'm again unique so i can leave this
website i can delete my cookies right i
can do all the all the right things
let's say from a private perspective but
then when i come back the same three
extensions are installed the same three
extensions are detected and now the
website can detect that it's actually
still the user from yesterday but now we
deleted cookies right so uh and even if
it's not unique right now we're actually
placing users into so-called anonymity
sets so maybe there's only 100 users
that have your specific
combination of extensions installed
uh and now i can use other
fingerprinting vectors to to uniquely
identify you within the group of 100 as
opposed to trying to identify you within
the group of you know billions of chrome
users or billions of firefox users all
right so these are our issues from a
privacy in a security perspective so now
let's discuss how is it that an
extension can be fingerprinted or can be
detected rather
even though there are no official apis
for a website to use
and we will look at two types of uh
attacks or two types of techniques
the first one is related to web
accessible resources and the second one
is related to the
to the artifacts of an extension running
in a page so let's focus first on the
web accessible resources
so
if unless you have tried to code a
browser extension you may not know that
you have a number of files like i
mentioned earlier your extension is
comprised out of css html and javascript
but these files are part of your
extension so they are not meant to be
accessible from outside your extension
right that
actually originally in in the first days
of extension frameworks this could be
done and this led to all social security
problems so by default all the files in
your packaged extension are only
accessible from within the extension
right however
uh developers so browser extensions at
times need to be able to refer to these
packaged objects from outside their
extension right
and you can make
uh you can consider various options for
that if i for example if you just
donated my extension
excuse me if you just installed my
extension and i want to ask you for a
donation i can open up uh a website and
then i can actually reference files from
within the packaged extension but if i'm
referencing these files outside of the
extension somehow i need to be able to
access these files so we have this
special tag for extension called web
accessible resources you can see it
highlighted there on the slide
and there a developer of a browser
extension lists all the extensions that
they want to be available outside of
their browser extension so websites
effectively can reference these extents
these these files that are part of their
extension right and this can be
javascript libraries right this can be
images like i mentioned earlier
so this is what the mechanism is
supposed to do it's supposed to allow a
developer of a browser extension the
ability to reference objects of that
extension outside of the privileged
extension space right so that's the
intention
um and you can see here how that would
work out if i'm building a page right
i can reference
for example an image i can say chrome
extension instead of let's say https i
have my package id and then i'm
referencing the specific file that i'm
trying to include into that page right
and the same thing for a script
underneath so that's the intention the
problem is
that browsers do not differentiate
between the links
that somehow your extension has created
and is injecting in public pages
referencing its own files
versus links that are just part of the
page itself so you now visit
attacker.com or tracker.com and now
tracker.com can actually try to be
referencing files
from popular extensions right and so you
can see here the problem that the page
can just try to load a given war if i if
i want to know if you have an ad blocker
installed
i can just try to load web accessible
resources of popular
ad blockers
and if the resource loads so if i
actually do find you know an image from
a popular ad block ad blocker then as a
page i can straightforwardly conclude
that you as a user have actually
installed that ad blocker right and now
i can show you that banner that says
your ad blocker is installed you need to
disable it or pay me money right and so
this actually leads to a very
straightforward and somewhat easy i
would say attack right so you can see
there are the steps of this attack so we
can first collect as many extensions as
possible from an extension store so we
can go out and crawl and collect a few
hundred thousands of extensions right
and we can then statically analyze them
and look in their manifest files like i
showed you earlier look for those that
use at least one web accessible resource
and just isolate that and then we just
write the script that pretty much just
loops through a giant array trying to
load
a web accessible resource from each of
these extensions on the public page
and then i have an event handler and if
if it's an on error i know that this
object was not present therefore the
extension is not installed if there's no
one ever firing right then i know that
actually this file was present therefore
you have that extension installed right
and there's been a number of academic
studies here that i'm referencing at the
bottom
where you can see that people have
actually found like for example the
first one in 2017 uh charleston at all
they found that
half of the extensions that they
evaluated actually had web accessible
resources and they were there for
fingerprintable and then once people
have started looking at larger and
larger sets this number drops but it
still is a quarter of the extension so
it's really a fish in a barrel kind of
situation right you just it's a very
simple attack that anyone could just sit
down and do
right so that's web accessible resources
as an attack that can be used to unmask
browser extensions right a second one is
related to the extension side effects
if you think about this the reason why
you're installing an extension is
because you want it to offer you
something right so for example you want
the tab manager that your browser
doesn't have present you want a password
manager that will nicely auto complete
your passwords and will sync them from a
cloud that you prefer right
you have reminders that will just add
things to web pages you have
proofreaders right like the grammarly
extension that will look at your text so
you really expect extension to do
something right and typically in this
category you expect it to add
functionality that you like right
other extensions remove things that you
don't like right so for example
obviously if you're running an ad
blocker you wanted to remove things from
the pages that you go to um or you want
it to be you know to remove bloat in
general you want them to be more
readable right so you sort of align the
text differently
and finally we just want changes right
you may want to just do simplify things
you may want to change background colors
for whatever reason right so that's why
people install extensions because they
expect these extensions to offer them
something and that something is
typically manifested by changes in the
page itself right so i have here an
example so you can see here a trailer of
the hackers movie right and this is just
loading youtube with no extensions
present
and here on the next slide you will see
that we have the same
video roughly the same timestamp with an
extension called magic actions for
youtube which has more than a million
users installed right and i have circled
the differences so if you look here uh
if you compare the before and the after
right we have that light switch on the
top left
which actually allows you to sort of you
know go dark and just make the page
black so i guess it's a nicer viewing
experience right and you have an extra
menu down here that allows you to do
things like find subtitles potentially
download movies all sorts of things that
users may want right so this extension
does exactly what the user wanted to do
right it has added functionalities
augmented the ui of youtube the question
is however
are these changes now discoverable by
the page itself right and the answer is
yes and we will we will we will see this
together another example is lastpass
right lastpass will add special buttons
uh in your in the forms of websites that
you go to and again these these extra
buttons are part of the pages dom right
so if it's if a website just knew where
to look it would say oh look there is
this button in that form and i know that
i didn't place it there therefore
the user the current user has lastpass
installed right and so it turns out that
extensions have visible side effects
right because that's exactly what you
install them because they offer you
something right and so with what we did
in 2017 is we sat down and we built a
system that will automatically compare
a page with and without an extension for
a very large number of extensions and it
will tell you whether an extension makes
changes to a page that could be used to
fingerprint right and so i won't go into
too much detail in this talk but
effectively you can see here that
we are loading pages into chrome we are
analyzing the doms we have honey pages
that allow
uh extensions to manifest themselves so
there will be pages with images and
pages with phone numbers and pages with
links so that different extensions will
discover them and sort of do things to
them because again that's why you
install an extension and then we have an
automatic module that just compares the
before and the after dom and it finds
what are the unique changes that we can
attribute back to the current extension
that we're analyzing right
and there is a paper that you can find
online with all the technical details
with that same title uh so the results
for that experiment was that for the top
10 000 extensions
we found that 10 of them roughly
introduced detectable changes on any
arbitrary url right so if you would go
to any website on the internet that
website had the power to fingerprint
roughly 10
of extensions
however if you were actually looking at
popular sites such as twitter.com and
you know gmail and so on these sites
could actually unmask 16 of extensions
and the reason for this is because
these websites are very popular and you
have a lot of developers who are making
browser extensions specifically for
these websites so these are extensions
that are only
revealing themselves on gmail.com on
twitter.com and therefore these sites
now have the ability to fingerprint
extra uh extensions right and you can
see there on the graph on the bottom
that we have actually
a positive relationship between rank and
fingerprintability so the more popular
an extension is the more fingerprintable
it is and as you go down in popularity
you go down infinite ability and the
reason for this uh has to do with
offered functionality right so the more
functionality you're offered the more
popular you're offering the more popular
your extension will be
and the more functionality you're
offering the more chances that the
extension will be fingerprinted right so
um and what we discovered is that from
all of these extensions 86
actually had were making at least one
change that was unique to them right so
you didn't have like two extensions
making the exact same change
for 86 percent of the extensions they
were making a unique change which means
that if you detect that change you can
attribute it back to a specific
extension right and you don't have to
sort of try to guess which of the ten
extensions that do this exact same thing
the user has installed and we also
checked the same extensions after four
months
and we saw that
you have roughly the same percentage of
extensions in the store that remain
fingerprintable four months later after
many updates so the thinking probability
of an extension is a stable property of
that extension and won't go away unless
the developer does something to that
extension right and you can see their
statistics at the bottom in terms of
what the extensions did such as 78
removing dom nodes uh and so on all
right so let me now contrast the two
types of fingerprinting that we talked
about on the left we have more
fingerprinting web accessible resourcing
and printing and on the right we have
behavioral fingerprinting right so on
the left we see that okay for wars
it's easy to extract signatures you can
do it statically uh it's easy to perform
in the user's browser there's no user
interaction necessary you just cycle
through a long list of words but the
developers could just straightforwardly
stop this right they can start
referencing images and css from the
websites or from cdns and just stop with
this all together right on the right we
have behavioral fingerprinting that's
easy to perform in the user's browser
and it's actually quite more difficult
to get rid of it because you really want
these extra ui buttons and you want the
ad blocker to be removing ads so how is
it that you can stop these changes that
are the same changes that make that
extension fingerprintable right on the
negative side it's more difficult to
extract signatures now you need a system
right that will exercise the extension
will reveal what it does and it may even
need user interaction that we haven't
accounted for
so
what we did this year is we introduced
the third way which we call here the
middleway which at least uh you know in
our minds this combines the best of both
worlds in beth's best for the tracker
right so we have easy extraction
fingerprints we don't need user
interaction and it's difficult for
developers to make their extensions
nothing incredible
and our tool our technique is
quite deceptive it's obvious in
hindsight it's css based extension
fingerprinting and so again if you're a
developer you love css or you don't but
you still have to use them and extension
developers also need css right when
they're creating their own buttons and
their own menus and their own forms they
also need css to make them look the way
that they want to look right so actually
what's happening is that extensions come
packaged with their own cascading style
sheets which are then injected in the
page right so that when the extension
adds a button or does other things that
button and these other things will be
styled according to that css
you may see where this is going now so
here we have an example extension called
dr web link checker and the whole point
of this is that you know you're visiting
websites and if this extension discovers
a link on the website that is malicious
it will
add you know this little flag there this
little shield that tells you that okay
that's something that is going on right
and you can see here that effectively
the extension when it discovers
uh a malicious link it will add
this simple
uh div element right
uh and if you look at the css
effectively that's you know how that
element is styled right
and so we have the injected element
and now we have the injected style for
that element okay
now let's talk again about the problem
again no differentiation between things
that the extension did and things that
the page did right so
what can happen is that the page itself
can have a div with the right class
and if it happens that the css of that
extension is present that div will
inherit all the styles from that css and
so you can see here we can we have this
empty div
if
you don't have uh that specific
extension installed if you do have that
specific extension installed suddenly we
have that nice style diff with the
shield okay so again now we have a
differentiating or a diverging behavior
and we can use that as uh as a building
block for an attack right so pretty much
you can see here on the left
we can focus on the extensions that
inject css the pages and we have found
experimentally that
more than 98 of css is inject statically
so you can actually detect it again at
the manifest file
we can identify what are the css rules
then the tracker can build decoy
elements empty elements that just have
the right class names that ask the the
right tag names the right class names
the right ids and then just sprinkle
them into a page that the user will
visit and so once the user visits that
page and his extensions add to the dom
all the css rules now now these elements
will actually start inheriting styles
from this is injected css
and now the tracker the page can
actually use quite a large number
of methods
to find out that the size of that div
has changed right this used to be a
blank empty div and now suddenly it's
100 pixels wide why because it inherited
some css and something changed within it
right so we can actually use this to
again find out that a browser extension
is present
even if uh no nothing has been injected
from the page no buttons nothing's been
removed just the css is there right but
now we're actually
abusing the css to uncover the presence
of a given extension
and i can tell you quickly about our
results so we evaluated this attack on
116 000 extensions
6000 of these inject style sheets on all
websites that you visit
half of them have at least one
css trigger that's unique to them so
again if you get the specific element
styled it can only be one extension that
has styled that element all right
and
you can see here on the top right we
have this venn diagram where we compare
different kinds of uh extension
fingerprinting so this is the web
accessible resource post message
fingerprinting that i didn't talk about
today due to lack of time
dom so the side effects on a page and
css and what's important to note is this
number here right so we have 1074
extensions that we can uncover using
this css fingerprinting that we couldn't
do before right so these were
effectively invisible extensions by all
the prior methods but now our tool and
our method has actually been able to
figure them out and on the bottom you
can see a performance graph of the
number of extensions on the x-axis and
the time that it takes to detect them on
the y-axis and so you can see here that
even if you have a user who's a little
bit on the crazy side and has like 20
extensions installed we're talking about
you know 15 milliseconds that it takes
for the page to just run through all of
your uh dom elements
find out using these methods that they
have been styled and infer the presence
of a browser extension right
i have a video that uh
you know i think i actually we do have
some time so let me try to do that uh i
was thinking of skipping it so let me
quickly share that video
uh and
yeah i've split it up a little bit you
can see we have a page that pretty much
shows you that we are currently
detecting 20 browser extensions
uh and again we're just abusing this css
fingerprinting no apis there for us to
use and now what we're doing here is
we're actually these are the 20
installed extensions we will go in and
we will disable uh three extensions
just to prove to you that this is you
know that this is all working well so
we're disabling three extensions and we
go back and we can refresh and you can
see immediately that we've dropped down
to 17. so we were quite
uh quickly able to discover that uh an
extension is no longer present because
the decoy elements that we're injecting
are no longer inheriting any style
sheets right so that's that's the attack
really so let me go back to our slides
all right so let's talk about defenses
and then i'll wrap it up
the most realistic defenses in terms of
adoption are access control based
defenses so you may have noticed in the
last couple of years probably two at
most that you actually have the ability
to tell it to tell your browser that the
extension should not be
available
kind of by default everywhere you should
first interact with it in order to make
it available right it's still something
that's opt-in it's still something that
you have to do it's not there by default
uh but it is the right the right a step
in the right direction right and the the
example that i'd like to give is that
yes you probably want your ad blocker to
be enabled in general when you're
browsing the web but do you want it to
be there on your banking website when
you're logged in do you want to have
you know a code base of hundreds of
thousands of lines of javascript that
someone else has provided do you want it
to have access to your logged in page
in your banking site i think the answer
is most likely no so we need better
access control and some way
of syncing
site preferences
with
a developer extension developer
preferences with the user somehow being
the arbiter and it's very difficult you
know all the user study
parts are missing for for uh sort of
deciding that this is going to work but
i i think it's the right way forward
right and then we have deception-based
defenses that are more academic at the
moment but pretty much what we can do is
we can just fake the presence of
extensions by just having decoy css and
decoy elements so that the next so that
the page thinks that you have one set of
extension installed but you actually
have a different set of extensions and
stuff right so again i'm not saying that
this is ready for you know for prime
time but it is a direction that at least
academics are investigating
uh and with that i want to conclude so
user customization has driven the web
a lot right and so the ability for users
to really customize websites and
customize their browsers
but the effects of this customization
unfortunately can be used against users
uh through browser fingerprinting uh
access control like i mentioned is the
right way forward and on the right there
of that slide i have three papers that
have my that have come out of my lab on
fingerprinting browser extensions over
the years that i would encourage you to
look into uh if you're interested and
i'm happy to take questions uh
in the right slack channel thank you