[Music]
thank you so much for this uh
great
intro so i'm very happy to be here today
with all of you
in this great celebration of os 20th
anniversary um
i guess uh us has one more year before
they can drink in the us but
you are more than welcome to visit us
all over the world
so let's start talking about the big
challenges
from the past
and unfortunately
also the present that's trying to hold
us back and how we need to make sure
that we're moving forward
to the future
so to be honest we are
in the future already we live in the
future at the moment how do i know i
know because
our previous generations told us
for example this is what
was
thought in the 1960s
how a car would look like as you can see
it is self-driving car
um
i guess that we're definitely in the
future in that term
um here is another
a way in the 1930s
how schools were imagined
i guess we are almost there where
were we using more podcasts
and i think this is just a step from the
current
let's call it studying from home or
school from home that we have in this uh
era
and the last one my favorite probably
that proves that we're in the future um
again from the 1930s
i guess this is the first people who
thought about smartphones um facetime
so we're definitely in the future
so why do i care about the past and the
future or how the future looks from the
past or the other way around so much
so um as introduced i'm the head of
security research in check marks i'm a
security researcher i used to be a
developer until i found out that i'm
better at breaking things than building
them
i lead several oas projects including uh
the api security one that is moving
towards uh a new addition um in the next
year
and also i'm the founder of the apsec
village in this court
but to be honest i have one superpower
and the superpower
that is fueled mainly by my research in
checkmarks is the ability to see
mistakes
and to look at the mistakes
in the eyes of
a researcher to see them how they look
like in real life in the industry
trying to think what changed from past
mistakes to current mistakes
and definitely thinking about
how we're seeing the trends move forward
and what we can do to avoid these
mistakes and problems in the future
so let's take a very quick glimpse on
memory boulevard
how we got from
around 2000 from the non-virtualized
however to to where we are uh today in
the very modern cloud native era
so
after having uh
actual hardware in actual rooms with
actual shelves from ireland usually and
making sure that we have all the fire
extinguishers and air conditions
um
fixed to that to the lowest temperature
we moved forward
to
the era of virtualization
virtualization did not really cut all
the cables
we moved later to infrastructure as a
service i think that amazon is is
probably the best example for that in
this era
obviously
and
others followed later
um then around 2009 we saw the wake of
platforms as a service
followed by open source
infrastructure
as a service like openstack
later we saw open source platforms as a
service and then um just to make sure
that we managed to bounce into the
future
we saw containers right in time for all
the micro services that we needed
and this is obviously a very very big
portion
of how cloud native architecture is
built this day
um i think there is
another way to look at this history um
this is my way of looking at it
and this is the buzzword of the year
along the hills
you think that buzzwords move business
more than modern technology these days
so let's see the buzzwords of the year
so around 2005 application security was
the buzzword of the year um around the
time that uh checkmarks was founded
and it's not a mistake i think that
every buzzword brings a lot of vendors
around it
um around 2010 open source security
became the buzzword of the year around
2015 container security
um
around the same time also serverless
security 2019 brought the api security
to become a very very common buzzword
and this is
uh this was one of the reasons that um
the
osp
api security top 10 was founded
and then the last
component
at the moment is uh infrastructure is
called
or some people say everything is code
basically and the security around it so
every buzzword along along the years
brought many many vendors with a similar
challenge
all of them wanted to give
a very good solution for the security
they are
handling
but they had to choose they had to
choose if they want to give
an early solution
or an actionable solution
and let me explain what i mean here
um
the shift left approach which is also
known as the developer first approach
this is something that a lot of us is
automatically moved towards these days
and there are very very good reasons for
that we see that the results are shown
early
early means easier easier means cheaper
to fix
and also it's better for security
education now a developer did something
very early finds out there is an error
or a mistake and they can still fix it
and learn from the experience which is
great
but
not everything is great with early
because there are very high
percentages of false positives everyone
who ran who ran
solution knows that
and also the reason the results are a
big general and i will show in a second
what i mean about that
the other option
is to go for actionable results this is
kind of the the right the
the shift right approach when you have
results that arrive much later in the
process sometimes in runtime
sometimes when it's too late and
obviously not a very good solution
the good thing is that they have a very
low of relatively low percentage of
false positives and the results are
specific and actionable this is the
first challenge this is the first
challenge of every vendor and obviously
the first challenge of every company
that uses a security product they need
to choose if they want something early
or actionable
and here here's an example of how early
versus actionable looks like in real
life
um let's say that the code was written
not it did not run yet not even all the
code just out of the code it was written
tested and got this result the result
says the open source package in your
applications
manifest is found vulnerable to cve
something something
this is not a real cv i hope anyway
um
i have a lot of questions after this
message is my app really exploitable
do i really use that in an in an
exploitable way how do i prioritize the
fix of it maybe it's okay maybe it's not
should i wait for a patch should i fix
it myself
maybe i should use something else
these are many many questions that i get
but i do get the result early
now on the adult side of the spectrum
there is the actionable result
for example i'm running a solution it's
not in the code anymore it's in runtime
running solution tested and i actually
get the following message your method
let's say important stuff is getting
tainted data from the exploitable open
source vulnerability the same one
obviously i have much more information
here it is definitely a problem i know
that i see that it is getting data data
i should definitely patch or fix or use
something else but
maybe it's months since i actually wrote
this code it's the first build we're
doing the first time we're running it
it's the first detection
back to the drawing board what does that
mean for me it might be a huge waste of
time and obviously money
so this is a very very clear challenge
um
this is a polling question that i give
to a lot of
people i meet
and what kind of results do you prefer
i'll be happy if some of you will write
your opinions
in the
in the slack channel so we can see it
later
but i'm going to tell you the results
that i usually see
so
when i ask people what kind of results
do you prefer early in general latent
specific or maybe not sure
usually most of the answers are around a
and c
a is because we learned that being the
very very early in the process of
shifting left is the right thing to do
i tend to agree
and not sure
also it's a good answer because many
people are not really sure there are
pros and cons for each of them
i can tell you that for big
organizations where they have dedicated
professional personnel
most of them prefer to start
to have results early in general just
because they have the
the firepower to handle that
the triage and false positives etc
other organizations that are sometimes
smaller or less professional around
security or have less
manpower around
this type of task you usually
tend to choose
more latent specific
um no surprising
so that was the first challenge the
second challenge i want to talk about
is the fragmentation in the market
so we saw along the history of the
technology how things move so in the
past we had our applications later we
had different services or even micro
services that's fine
but we had a very very clear solution
for that we had a sas solution or we had
some sort of a code scanner that is
going to take
take a look at my code and tell me
what's wrong
and what should i fix
that was great for the past
what happens now when i add open source
i have a lot of open source components
now and these components need some sort
of dedicated tool to check them
obviously
we call that software software
composition analysis
also we have containers
how do i know that my containers are
fine this is somewhat related to open
source but i still need to know that my
containers are okay that i'm using
clean containers
also there is some sort of orchestration
layer that is running everything because
everything there is okay i need to check
that also
what about my apis api can be handled in
the code in api gateways and the
infrastructure so many places
is my api cq
and uh the last building block that we
see is the infrastructure that now moves
to become an infrastructure as code with
uh
with tools like uh terraform and cloud
formation etc we have everything in
there
i need to somehow test that as well
so
each one of those needs some sort of
dedicated tool really
so we all know the joke of how many
engineers you need to replace one light
bulb
my variation here is how many vendors
does it take to secure a cloud native or
modern architecture architecture these
days this is a real challenge
which brings me to the next polling
question how many security vendors
either commercial or open source
solutions
do you need to cover the different
components of your cloud native
architecture
again this is a question that i ask a
lot of time when i'm giving lectures or
even talking to
csos or other upset professionals in the
organizations
um
i'll give you 10 seconds to think
okay so most of the answers are uh c and
d usually uh i think more than 50 of the
answers are usually around more than
five or they don't even know i'm not
sure
um the lucky ones that somehow manage to
aggregate things are around b
and those who say one to two are very
very few and usually very very wrong
maybe not all of them i don't maybe
there is some sort of magic solution
but
this is what we see usually and this is
this is a really issue this is a real
problem in a real pain
i think that everyone hates to to juggle
between very
various tools and different approaches
and different solutions
for problems that are part of the same
issue
the third challenge the third challenge
is known
both to parents and children
we call it legalization um
i think that every parent knows that the
the how the substance uh in the universe
is a lego brick
but it doesn't really matter how hard
and secure it is
every child and to be honest
every malicious malicious attacker also
knows that it's not the brick that
important but the way you build it
and the way the other bricks hold it and
support it
so um
here's an example
here is a brick
application code this is one of the
bricks i'm going to scan it like in the
past
and i see that the sensitive data is
written to an s3 bucket
this is the the knowledge i have about
this brick is it okay is it not okay i
mean
this is where data is written to these
days right into some sort of bucket or
storage device
um is it supposed to be there
i guess so i mean what's the problem
here no problem that i can see
in a different scan
of a different block of the of the
infrastructure i scan again and i see
that an s3 bucket is open to the public
um
okay i don't know if that is an issue
i'm looking at this specific brick
i'm seeing that the bucket is open to
the public
that's fine i mean some buckets should
be open to the public obviously for
example if i hold
i don't know the graphics of the logo of
my company or it can be profile pictures
or whatever
some buckets are open to the public and
that's fine
where is the glue between that and the
glue between them is some sort of
correlation if i correlate these results
i can see that sensitive data is written
to an open s3 bucket this is obviously a
very very problematic
leak of information
another example
in the first case we have
application code
this is my first brick or my standalone
brick and i see the data is read and
written to and from mountain storage
if i look at kubernetes configuration i
can see that the storage has
uh
read and write permissions
i mean when i look at them um
separately it looks fine to be honest
even if i look at them correlated it
seems fine
but in a very very similar case i can
see an application code that the data is
read from mounted storage
and i've seen the core in the kubernetes
configuration the nostalgia has read and
write permissions
so i agree this is not as serious as the
data leak we saw in the first example
but if i have the glue between these
bricks the mesh up the correlation
i can definitely see that there is an
unnecessary write permissions
in case two and this is something i
cannot see
in the way that
we're currently testing and looking at
our
applications and this is the third
challenge
what we see here is that application
security is not only application code
security separated from infrastructure
as good security separated from third
party components etc
we need a holistic approach here
and i'm going to propose a vision here
that we're currently uh playing with
and this is a single repo to hold them
all
we know that git today holds everything
right all the components we saw before
we want to create some sort of
application security testing platform or
measure player or correlation layer or
whatever we want to call it
to scan and to make sure that we see not
only the components but the glue between
them everything between each and every
component
should be meshed up
to have this correlation in results and
understanding of what's happening though
the mesha player can give me
the connection of different things for
example exploit explainability of open
source vulnerabilities this is the
example we saw in the beginning with the
made up cve so now i have not only open
source and software composition analysis
but i can mesh it with the sas results
and see how it actually affects my code
i can look at overly permissive docker
configuration for example when i scan
sas and docker and i mesh the mesh
results
ssrf that affects kubernetes for example
kubernetes management api suddenly if i
scan all of them i have the scan of code
by sas i can look at my kubernetes files
i can look at my api security
if i can mesh them together and
correlate them together i can find that
kind of specific
complex to detect issues and find them
quickly
um it's important to say that it's how
to detect but these are exactly the
vulnerabilities that malicious attackers
are looking for they don't really care
about how things go behind the scenes
behind the scenes is our problem their
problem is to try and just find a weak
link and they usually do
more examples overly broad permissions
or unprotected sensitive resources if i
have access to my infrastructure's code
files and also to the code itself
i can make these connections
um and the examples go on and on
obviously and we see that the
exploitability of imported container
layers vulnerabilities
become suddenly simpler when we have
vision into code and open source and
containers
and a lot of
things that run in lambdas are also
relevant we can see serverless
vulnerabilities and misconfigurations
when we look at the code of the lambdas
and the infrastructures code
configurations so basically
we see everything we have not only the
code we suddenly have the context and
the code is something that we always had
when we shift left but the context
was always missing and only appeared
when we shifted
right
so a unified ast mesh up solves these
challenges because we have a single
polymorphic engine that points to a repo
with all application codes and
infrastructures code
we see different engines running behind
the scenes and connecting everything
and the the first challenge we talked
about the stubborn trade-off of early
and actionable it disappears all is code
so the mesh up is the glue that combines
all results and supports both
requirements of shift left and
actionable
results
the annoying market fragmentation we
talked about it's not needed anymore
because the mesh up aggregates or even
unifies the results to give us
better context and also new results that
we never had before
and
this vision shows
also
a kind of a bonus i think when we look
at the stakeholders and the time it
takes so if in the past we could look at
an application code
after it was coded and builded
by developers then we could run some
sort of vulnerability scan
um then maybe the devops would need to
run some sort of container security
protection or testing to check the
containers
and then until production we need i.t to
make sure that the net network is okay
again it's multiple products multiple
processes multiple stakeholders and
we're missing the correlated results
that we saw earlier
in the future um
i'm hoping that and not in the next 20
years but less than that
we're going to see
um
a one click and one click that starts
everything and all the and all the scans
and testing done in the same place
so we can see uh
as soon as the code is built or
or
started to be built by developers we can
look at the application code for
vulnerability scanned by sas or sca look
at the containers look at the
infrastructure's code
and have all the information in a single
product in a single process
by a single stakeholder and basically
have here the synergy that we like so
much
to talk about
um so
just to summarize i think that we
definitely see a vital future
and
i think that our summary needs to be
what the developers and security staff
wants
and we know that we want seamless
integration because we don't want to
handle so many vandals we want very
intuitive point and go point at a single
single repo
and go
we want early results shift left we want
actionable results shift right and to be
honest we want to eat the cake and have
it too especially if it's an awesome
20th anniversary cake
so
thank you so much and i hope to see you
and your questions
in the slack channel that is currently
on the screen thank you