[Music]
so as podemo mentioned the topic is
blockchain based security framework for
cyber physical system
as we know that cyber physical systems
are very very complex systems and these
are also known as a class of automated
systems
which are basically working as a
lifeline of our smart cities
and
cps are transforming the way we interact
monitor and control you get it together
physical world around us i think you
have to go on mute sonata
okay
you have to mute yourself
don't need
this
[Music]
where i want to be yeah okay
so the security aspects of these systems
are in high demand as these systems are
involved in day-to-day life of people
and the national economy and compromised
cps can harm the day-to-day operations
of the people and cps systems are very
complex in design because very
heterogeneous devices are involved in
working of cps systems and these are
more prone to cyber attacks so in
today's talk i am going to discuss that
how we can introduce blockchain
technology and i am going to share one
framework also which i have decided
that i am going to work on as a future
aspect and future research aspect and
which is basically a mechanism to
gaining trust when we are sharing the
data when the data is transmitting from
cps to the other devices so in that this
is the uh table of content which i have
decided
so a little bit description about the
cyber physical systems
risk evaluated risk associated with gps
security how we can introduce blockchain
and what is the framework which i think
that we can go ahead with
so
so i was talking about cyber physical
devices that these can be considered as
a systems which integrates sensing
computation control and networking into
physical objects as you can see in this
slide also physical sensing is there we
have a strong network through which all
the devices are connected and
actuation information also so in cyber
physical system we can sometimes like
integrate or we can say that uh iot is
also quite overlapping in that because
the line and the distinction with iot
and cps is little blurred so we can say
that the advancement of cps is very fast
including we can say that electrical
power generation and delivery
personalized healthcare traffic flow
management and emergency response and as
well as in many other areas now just
being envisioned so as you see in this
picture many millions of connected cps
devices will be communicating
over the public network and will be
providing services to their respective
applications uh many applications of cps
the identity of devices is very very
important and data
generated from these devices
uh
from an important part of the overall
ecosystem they are integrated in because
when we are giving a cyber capability to
this system the cyber capability is
basically working on the data which is
collected from the various devices which
are connected in the system
if the data which is coming from these
devices is not consistent if the data
which is coming from these devices is
not secure then how the system is going
to function because these kind of
systems are known as a backbone of any
country's economy because these are the
bigger and complex systems
so
in the uh
challenges in the situation we can say
that how basically the actors are
gaining the trust in the integrity of
identities and the data in an explicit
measurable and testable way because
whenever you are receiving a data from
any device how you are going to trust
that this is the data which is not
hampered or this data is real data so
this is the main uh
you can say that the challenge when you
are talking about the communication in
the cyber physical systems
now detection of safety and security
deficiencies and as a fundamental
building block for creating a security
framework for cps at different various
level we have a physical level
we have another logical level then we
have a different layer
users are interacting so various levels
are having various security and
safety deficiencies so we need to work
on a framework which can target all
those uh deficiencies maybe not all the
most of the time the cyber physical
systems internet of things and digital
frameworks are we can say that generally
the cases of embedded devices
in which the basic requirement is to
provide the flexibility to the various
applications because we have devices
from the heterogeneous vendors so we
want that flexibility that as and when
we need a device we can add or we can
detach that device but the system is not
going to deviate from the normal
operations that will not affect the
working of the complete system that we
know and also we want the higher
adaptability of those devices which are
heterogeneous in the nature which are
coming under the cyber physical system
to provide a reliable communication that
whatever data is flowing from these
channels
all the data we can trust and we can use
for the analysis purposes or for taking
the decisions for the other purposes so
that is very very important and the
existing platforms use the centralized
networking and now according to me and
the research which i did is suffering
from security scalability and big data
problems so
security and privacy is a significant
challenge in cyber physical systems
as you see in this slide mirai botnet a
ddos nightmare turning internet of
things into botnet of things
what's happening is ddos attacks target
the cyber physical system resources and
the launch uh from a large number of
locally infected devices so a huge in
network of cps devices
will be targeted by the ddos attacks and
these are exploited by the botnets uh
and whereby the large number of infected
devices simultaneously launch ddos
attack so multiple devices will be
compromised and all are basically
targeting
a cps system
now in this case as i mentioned the
mirai uh
so you can say that ddos attack can take
many different forms like black hole
teardrop while ddos can take the like
forms like thing of death smurf and
black energy series so i'm not going in
the technical detail of all these
attacks tcp sync flood which exploits
the tcp handshake process uh by
constantly sending requests without
responding back to the server now
causing the server to constantly
allocate space or waiting for reply and
because of that that server is not able
to respond to the request which is
coming from the legitimate clients and
this is basically leading to the buffer
overflow condition
where the situation can come in which
the cps system can crash or shut down or
deviate from the normal operations
malware is most of the time used to
compromise cps in order to steal or leak
data or harm any device or bypass any
control systems because we know that we
need a human less automated process so
there is no human but the human is
operating the system so we have to take
that when any human is operating a
system how secured this system
which is operated by a human what kind
of security measures are taken care by
this system which is handling the data
which is coming from the various devices
so the attacks which we discussed like
mirai
attack was very very huge attack in 2016
uh mootbot attack in 2020 while pressure
and victory gate attack in 2020
these are very very large scale and if
i'm not going to mention the ransomware
attack i think i'm going to miss a big
name
so ransomware is a malicious software
that basically holds and encrypts the
cps data as a ransom and this is by
exploiting the cps vulnerability as i
told you that there are number of
devices in the cps system as you see
over here so we are not sure that how
many devices are secure how many devices
are patched with the security how many
devices are basically working as for the
requirement of the system so because of
those kind of vulnerabilities the
attacker is able to gain access and they
are targeting oil refineries they are
targeting power grids they are targeting
manufacturing facilities so we seen that
these are the things and if we want to
see the examples of ransomware
siskiy in 2016 wannacry in 2017
bad rabbit in 2017 these are the few
names which are the big names in the
ransomware attacks econs in 2020 so
these are the attacks which are planned
so these are the challenges facing by
the cps like heterogeneity in the device
resources as we discussed multiple
attack services are there because there
can be a physical attack there can be a
cyber attack so in cyber attack because
they have a heterogeneity in the devices
sources and these devices are having
very less
uh power to compute or
process so these kind of problems are
there scale is very huge because we are
talking about millions and billions of
small small devices number of sensors
which are attached everything is
centralized if one thing goes wrong the
complete entire system is going to be
shut down
lack of control over how data is shared
because when we are talking about this
scale
we can control but up to this level it
is difficult to control and manage
so audit facilities also needs to be
take care that how we are auditing the
things
also the
software stacks and hardware how you are
updating the things like if you are
using a software how updated that
software is is your hardware is capable
enough to matching with the current
security requirements
also the poor implementation of security
and privacy mechanism so these are the
main challenges which are faced by the
cyber physical system
so is there another way forward through
which we can implement the security or
through which we can think that okay now
my data is safe so i can say that
blockchain is the answer so blockchain
as a name suggests is a growing chain of
blocks
so in this these blocks are containing
the data of various kinds like the data
can be financial transactions related to
exchange of assets
or linked together using the
cryptography
like in blockchain transaction these
basically these are recorded as
like chronologically and these are
forming the immutable chain and that is
basically creating a trust because in
that process data is verifiable and
auditable now the ledger is distributed
across all participants in the given
network
right and what is happening in that is
because of this immutability property of
blockchain and a clever mix of
cryptography and a game theory everyone
in the network agrees with a single copy
of
blockchain
now
in addition to like being a system of
records where you have everything
recorded you have a chain of custody uh
basically we can say uh that
blockchain can also be a platform for
smart contracts
now uh we can if you want to describe a
smart contract so it's an autonomous
agent which is stored on the blockchain
and is encoded as a part of spatial
transaction now which introduces the
contract to be blockchain
now one can also view uh as a smart
contract as a state machine
with its current state
like represented on the blockchain so
any transaction invoking a smart
contract stored on the blockchain and
will trigger its execution
now once it finish executing all
renewable actors in the network
uh agree on the new state of the smart
contract so whenever there is a change
in the state trigger will happen and all
the actors in the network will be
notified and will be agreed with the new
state of the smart contract now
the blockchain is offering a different
path towards the greater security
and
that is like we can uh
we can say that we can trust the data
which is coming from this chain of
custody because this is immutable and
the approach is basically reducing the
vulnerabilities and provides a strong
encryption and also more effectively
verifies data ownership and also the
integrity
so this particular basically giving an
advantage uh that use of distributed
ledger and everybody is agreeing with
the new states whenever it's coming so
this particular public key
infrastructure model reduces many risk
associated with centrally stored data by
eliminating the most obvious targets and
that is basically comes where the
everybody is trusting with the
blockchain
which is the chain which is immutable
blockchain contains many non-traditional
features also uh it take advantage of
one of the most important cyber security
tools which we all know and which we all
agree that is encryption so this is the
traditional security feature which is
used by the blockchain also distributed
laser can utilize the public key
infrastructure to secure communication
also to authenticate device
now 98 percent of the iot device target
was unencrypted a recent study of polo
alto network reports this issue and also
say that low hanging fruits for the
attacker because when you are not
encrypting your data
in rest
and in transit
you are inviting attackers to come and
attack you to access your data
so if we say so what are the blockchain
challenges we are so happy that okay we
are going to use blockchain or we are
going to have the uh facilities of
blockchain so what kind of challenges
are there when we talk about the
blockchain so
organizations from multinational
corporations to governments are
uh basically adopting blockchain
security and
basically this is not simple as updating
the existing toolkit because these are
the big smart systems and as a whole
like we cannot say that now i'm going to
change everything i'm going to uh
redesign the complete system entire
system using the blockchain so there are
a lot of challenges which are involved
in that so and the challenges we can say
is the data privacy scalability so data
privacy we can say that if in the public
blockchain anyone can see and retrieve
data in the transaction right and that's
a concern for businesses so blockchain
is providing security but we talk about
the public blockchain so anyone can see
and retrieve data in the transaction and
concern for businesses that want to
closely control what information is
publicly available so that is the main
concern of the business when they wants
to switch to the blockchain scalability
is also a concern and it's so basically
uh become a constraint when implementing
blockchain because due to block size and
the response time
now we want to work on the security but
then if the latency is much if the
response time is very very low uh high
then it is difficult to implement that
so in this technology basically every
node
is storing
and processing
and maintaining the transactions in a
block to ensure security and privacy now
as the number of transaction increases
small and medium size businesses i am
talking about that struggle to
accommodate a growing number of
transactions in a block
so that's a challenge in terms of
scalability if we talk about the
regulations the organizations and the
businesses are still trying to
understand that how blockchain structure
complexity fits within the evolving data
privacy compliance and regulatory
landscape because we know that gdpr uh
is basically telling that if you are
dealing with the public uh pii you have
to comply with certain standards so how
these things will be matching with
blockchain that is also a big concern
interoperability like some blockchain
platforms use a very ecosystem
for their smart contract logic
transaction scheme models but weak
interoperability because we know that we
have the heterogeneous systems now if
there are no not interoperable then
what's the point of implementing a new
technology for giving security because
then you have to do a new work for
providing the interoperability amongst
the devices
so these kind of roadblocks from the
developer perspective also taking a back
from the businesses
by implementing the blockchain as a
security now technology risks are also
there as improper key management and
access control also like blockchain is
offering lot of benefits as we discussed
the efficiency the optimization
reduce control improve security but then
improper key management and access
control needs to be taken care because
this is not going to be a traditional
way this is going to be a different way
where the
keys will be mapped with the user
ownership and unauthorized access or
theft of cryptographic keys may lead to
total loss of the data so we need to
take care about the improper key
management and access control also
unintended forks and chain split attacks
which are there
that is also a concern in adequate
encryption scheme selection and insecure
operations are also a risk which is
there in the technological area and the
api integration is also the important
point
because uh third parties are always
required for api integration whether
it's a private or public blockchain now
that leads to trust issues because now
you are having the different verticals
to trust you are implementing a new
technology but then also you have to
trust on the third party services so
these are the few challenges but then
also i think
that if we are going to uh introduce
blockchain as a security for these smart
systems uh cyber physical system
that will provide a more impact on the
security as you see in this particular
diagram
the basic design of blockchain-based uh
cyber physical systems uh is that cpas
are basically linked to blockchain
leader
which is distributed amongst the actors
in the ecosystem
then what happen is the key blockchain
features which we discussed like which
are providing efficiency which are
providing the security
uh will achieve the data stored on the
blockchain and
smart contracts executed by the
blockchain are trusted amongst the
actors which are there
and everybody is going to agree on the
new state which is coming after each and
every transaction
now in this process a cts devices are
trying to send something to client and
client is ready to record the data so
whenever client means it is representing
the actors those who are working to
collect the information so whenever
these actors are ready to collect data
from cps what kind of steps will be
happen which can be managed and monitor
with the help of the blockchain so
basically if you see in this diagram i
have three components which i have taken
the first component is cps device this
is the first component
which is able to compute and to
communicate and which is having a
cryptographic identity using a symmetric
pair of keys now the second actor which
i have is the time which is representing
one of the actors who aims to record the
current process of data
from the cps devices with the help of
the blockchain and the third
uh which i have is the blockchain system
which stores and execute smart contracts
so this is how my framework work and i'm
going to share these steps also that how
it's going to happen the scenario is
that client wants to record process of
data uh from this device and taking the
help from blockchain because whenever a
data is stored on the client from the
cpas we want to have its security and we
want to have an authentication that okay
this is the correct one
now the first step is
the first step is the uh basically
client wants to record process data of
the cyber physical device on the
blockchain now this what he's doing is
he's sending a transaction to the
blockchain that requested nouns now what
is the nouns if i uh in brief if i uh
share the detail about nounses uh
is it to make each request unique
because we want to have a unique request
like nobody is able to use that nouns
again this is unique for this request
and it doesn't matter if the attacker
gets the older nouns uh because that
data which is happening in that nouns is
older and not of any use now so it is
important to have a nouns in every uh
kind of request which we have because it
is making a request unique so that
attacker cannot replay a request in
different context so this is the first
point when client is uh wants to record
the process data from the cps with the
help of the blockchain
so second step is blockchain is
basically processing the transaction and
sends an
announce back to the client that this is
a unique
particular request now client requests
the cps device to sign its current
process
now this data and the nouns together so
this particular cps device is uh
combining the nouns with the data and it
is sending back to the client
now if you see this fourth request the
message is built
so sign
uses data and nouns so now this is
signed and we are sending it back to the
cloud client now what is happening is
cps has sent the sign
process data and nouns to the client
now the client is building a transaction
for the blockchain that contains the cps
device id
the complete transaction this complete
uh transaction is having the cps device
id that from which
this particular things will be taken
device id sign data
and also it is going to have the nouns
as its payload in this transaction these
things are an action also it can be
mentioned that wants to store it so
these kind of a thing in the fifth step
the client is going to send to the
blockchain and the action is to record
the data as i discussed also in this
sixth point if we talk as a six point
also so in the sixth point the
blockchain executes a smart contract
and uh yeah to check the authenticity of
identity data and time with the steps
like it is going to uh
as a step if i want to say so verify
that the sign process data was signed by
the claim cts device also check the data
was signed with the correct nouns which
is generated for the current request
also if all checks are true then save
the data against the id on the
blockchain so this is how the system
will work and with this system i think
we can claim that this is satisfying the
security requirement and this is how we
can say that we are providing the
security to the devices in this cyber
physical system and we can say that
trust is going to be generated now there
are a few concerns also with this
particular thing like data
authentication and data integration like
in the proposed system if i talk so few
points i wanted to mention data device
identification also non-repudiation also
the secure against the deeply attacks
also so how this framework is working so
these are the few challenges on which
i'm working uh protection from spoofing
attacks so i'm working on these
challenges and i hope that very soon i'm
going to update this particular
framework so that my this framework is
able to answer such challenges which are
there when we are going to implement the
blockchain
and these are the few references which i
have referred for uh preparing these uh
framework and my slides and
i'm going to thank
again for giving this opportunity to uh
share my experience and my framework
with everyone
so with this uh i think i have completed
on time and uh let's see if i can start
yes yes so thank you so much for uh
wonderful participants in the audience
for listening me if you have any
questions i'm available on slack and if
you want to collaborate with me on such
framework and such things please message
me on slack i'll be happy to work with
you all thank you once again thank you
demo for nicely introducing me and
managing this session thank you so much