[Music]
hello everyone
hi
uh this is uh
ray and malcolm
and uh malcolm's actually gonna run the
the slideshow so but i'll talk for this
part
um i'm the director of f5 labs and
malcolm is a researcher with f5 labs
we've both been with f5 for a long time
malcolm
many many many years as you've heard
f5 labs is actually the threat research
wing of f5 so
we uh got a bunch of cool data to share
with you today so let's just get on with
it should go to the next slide please
so we have a partnership with effluxio
who's run by many different names lorica
baffin bay now they're called deflexio
but it's essentially the same folks that
we've been working with since 2017 and
they have a
global honeypot network
and
we collect a lot of data from them and
various things and one of the things
that we really single
our attention on is their web sensors
their web attacks so we actually have
um it says variable number of sensors
it's easily to say in the hundreds
uh all over the world
and we see as you see 11 000 events per
day on average and that's just the web
attacks and we actually are able to
capture a bunch of data uh what these
honeypots do is they actually simulate a
a web server in the most basic sense
they see an incoming connection
and they kind of answer like yeah yeah i
speak port 80 here's here's you know my
http and then we grab that session
and then they shovel all that data to us
and so we've been doing various stories
and analysis on upcoming attack trends
and things like that and kind of
interesting events so we'll get into
that as we go along
but we also decided we were you know for
the special 20th anniversary we wanted
to do like a big picture let's look at
all the data we had so we have 8.5
million events
and and malcolm crunched through it and
found some really interesting things
and we're also going to talk a little
bit about the process that we did
because i think that's also interesting
and useful to you especially if you want
to be doing some of this stuff on your
own as well
uh go ahead to the next one
which i think
uh yeah that's where i took over yeah so
i i can talk a little bit about some of
the tooling that was used for the
analysis um
we use a pretty standard set of data
analysis tools uh python uh including
libraries like pandas and numpy
jupiter jupiter notebooks um some are uh
and most recently elasticsearch and uh
elasticsearch has been really
extremely helpful when uh when i
approach this project to not just do an
analysis of a relatively limited time
period like say a month or a quarter but
instead tried to look at this
entire data set that covered years
that gave us the scaling that we needed
originally the data was in comma
separated values and now it's in json
there's pros and cons to both uh some
tools work better with some and others
with others
it's been relatively easy to to
transform the data between the two as we
needed to
but if you were designing a system like
this yourself i would probably
recommend that you
consider json as being the more flexible
uh format for it
we've managed to come up with automated
ingestion uh it's approaching real time
we're at about a day now um about a day
lag uh we're hoping to be able to get it
down to hourly or even just direct
pipelining into our analysis
infrastructure
so that we can start doing some really
good automated analysis on it um we've
obviously done a fair amount of trends
over time looking at different attack
patterns but what we would like to do is
to
use this as a source to be able to
profile the attack patterns for example
urls that we're seeing um
you know get request urls uh that we're
seeing and start to
uh
in a probably using some sort of machine
learning you know classify them
automatically and detect anomalies as we
go forward so that we can see new attack
patterns coming forth
that will also uh using some of the
other fields that we have allow us to do
some attacker profiling where are they
coming from what time are they coming in
from what asn are they coming in from
that sort of thing
and we also have geolocation data which
would allow us to do uh more regional
reports both on where scans are coming
from and where they're heading to
some of the challenges that we've faced
uh is essentially that over time when
you're looking at a data set this large
um we were looking at different pieces
of data earlier than we are later we've
added the things that we are capturing
we've uh changed around some of the ways
that we captured that data
so there was a fair amount of data
cleaning and and uh coalescing that
needed to be done
um obviously also as ray mentioned we
have a couple of hundred sensors minimum
but that number has actually gone up
significantly and the more sensors we
have
uh the harder it is to ingest the data
that we're getting um the web data set
is
as these things go relatively small but
we also have some other data sets that
are probably in order of magnitude um or
two
larger
um and that starts getting a little bit
difficult to do without some pretty
serious infrastructure behind it
it's just quite a lot of data
uh right now the classification of the
web attacks that we're seeing uh in
terms of like what does this
request represent in terms of an attack
is a mainly manual process
uh and we're hoping as i said to
automate that but that was a bit of a
chore to go through
even the relatively limited set that we
had here
uh and come up with some sort of
reasonable classification scheme
and there are of course costs associated
with maintaining the sensors storing all
the data in a way that you can get to it
easily and do your analysis
uh and also just preserving it over the
long term i think an awful lot of
companies have much of the same sort of
data
from say their web application firewall
or their logs even but they don't
necessarily keep five
ten years worth of it to be able to do
this sort of trending that we're gonna
do
so we started off by classifying the
attacks and in order to be able to talk
about this i think i need to define a
little bit more about what the sensors
can
do and what they also what they don't do
none of these sensors have dns hostnames
they're not pretending to be a specific
company or a specific vertical or
you know um
bob's uh
happy fun web
site or whatever it happens to be
there's there's no particular thing
they're really just an ip address
hanging out on the internet waiting for
traffic to arrive to them
they additionally don't pretend to be a
specific platform they're not pretending
to be an apache with php or an nginx uh
or something that has you know
javascript on it or anything else like
that they're really just a listener
listening on port 80 and port 443
able to receive an http or tls
connection negotiated properly and
record the request that comes in
that's literally it um so what does this
give us in terms of the visibility into
what's happening on the internet and the
web
it gives us the ability to see
scans that are
widely and non-specifically targeted
these are scans that are probably going
and traversing a large section of the ip
space
they are not targeted to specific
companies they're not targeted to
specific domains they are really just
going and perhaps scanning
you know a class a at a time or
something like that that probably dates
me a little bit but
a large number of ip addresses at a time
and so it's reasonable to conclude that
the attacks are automated and are done
at scale
and are probably done therefore uh by
attackers who are looking for easy wins
they're they're not necessarily
targeting a specific
industry or site they are just trying to
find things that they can
break into
or
install software on which we'll get to
in a little bit or
retrieve information from
that classification
is uh
the next thing really that we looked at
um and as i said um what we've generally
seen and and i think this is actually
probably true
for a large amount of attacks on the
internet
is that attackers are going to target
technologies and not necessarily
industries um they are
picking up public vulnerabilities
quickly
those get weaponized automated and start
being used
and they continue being used for a very
long time as we'll see
um the most apparent goals that we've
been able to determine from what we've
seen and this is mainly from
command injection payloads is they are
interested in
uh installing crypto miners uh or
building botnets uh and
probably the most common botnet that
we've seen
uh
general classification of botnet i
should say
is for doing denial of service attacks
such as the xrd does
um
many of these attacks can be automated
completely you see that you see a get
request comes in that uses a command
injection that issues a curl command
that downloads something from some
server somewhere untards it somewhere
and starts running it and and you can do
that all on one get request
secondarily we see a lot of attempts at
going and looking for files that would
reveal credentials
dot env for example where um
unfortunately you find a lot of database
credentials
or general configuration files that make
may include passwords or key data
and so from this we conclude that um
at least this particular subset of
attackers are going to be using
the shortest path to their goal and
their goal is
widespread
and information theft
so they're not going to be particularly
picky about what tools or technologies
they use
so now we can talk a little bit about
what sort of attacks you might be
expecting and we can say generally that
any http or tls endpoint will be scanned
probably within less than one hour of it
being visible
um and your authentication endpoints
will be cred stuffed and brute forced if
it's got a login box on it that can be
exercised by a remote attacker it's
going to be exercised by a remote
attacker
any data that's in the open is going to
be found and taken
um
specifically php
will be enumerated for command injection
vulnerabilities
uh we see a ton
of requests for common test script names
you know for example test.php
or shell.php
or
aaa.php or temp.php any of these sorts
of things which i assume is attackers
looking for
people
coming up with a quick little test
script
leaving it out in the open and perhaps
being able to find something that they
can exercise to
to do a command injection most likely
interestingly
api specific api urls in other words
ones that comply to a format that
indicates an api endpoint uh slash api
would be the most common one obviously
but there's many other patterns that we
see
are being actively scanned for they're
going to be found and they're gonna get
poked at quite uh sufficiently
and finally uh
any public web vulnerability any cve
that comes out that anybody has any idea
about how to actually use
are going to be picked up quickly
turned into an automated
uh tool and you're going to see those
all the time
i'm just going to pause briefly okay
thank you for the time warning
so
in order to take a look at this data
over this large chunk of time
we use the hauling approach
we looked for the top 50 requested uris
per month
uh 2017-21 inclusive uh until just a
little while ago in mid-august
actually um yeah a little while ago
mid-august
we normalized it for the number of
sensors so that we had comparable data
sets
and we did some manual classification
we broke it out this way we came up with
apis
specifically the enumeration and
attempted execution of apis
authentication
um which is request for login pages or
specific login attempts post requests
with credential data in them
we looked for code and content inclusion
which i'm defining here as cross-site
scripting local file inclusion remote
file inclusion and several other
techniques
information theft and recon which is as
i mentioned looking for for example env
files or
dot password files or dot hd access
files those sorts of things
injection and remote command execution
specifically command injection most
often but also specific remote code
execution vulnerabilities
and then finally
sql injection which we separated out
from injection
more generally because we saw in the
data
a really interesting pattern emerge
so here's what we saw
over obviously on the left we have 2017
all the way to the right 2021.
the green color on your screen is what
we observed for sql injection attacks
and as you can see they were by far
the majority of the attacks that we saw
from when our data set started in 2017
until
about july of 2018
and
they were ubiquitous
there was just so many of them
um code and content inclusion did have a
representation in there as well as
authentication some of the other
categories here
then we saw a really big shift there was
a sudden spike in injection
rce classified attacks and
i think we're going to figure out
exactly what those were here in a couple
of slides
but after that point you'll notice over
on the right side of the graph
especially with the orange which is off
and the blue which is api a significant
and ever-increasing trend
for scans that we're targeting those two
classifications
i think this is really really
interesting um
what we may be seeing here and this is
speculation but what we may be seeing
here is
a shift from using traditional sql
backed web architectures to perhaps ones
using nosql
or perhaps just people fixing sql
vulnerabilities
which made those attacks less
likely to succeed
and at the same time we see an
increasing amount
of api usage
uh and also
attackers just pivoting to what they can
reasonably conclude that they can get in
with uh in other words api cred stuffing
password spraying
all those sorts of techniques
the infos the info theft and recon
category has been growing as well
um and the injection rce has uh
continued to be something that we've
seen a lot of
but i'm really want to call out that
specific trend of increases in off and
api traffic because i really think that
that's actually where
that's a major shift that we're seeing
um it may be
that
uh
some older techniques that attackers are
using are less effective
um but they are definitely keeping up
with the shifts in web architecture that
we're seeing where apis and
microservices and that sort of thing are
becoming
more common
and they are definitely arising into the
uh the targeting that attackers are
doing here
so
we found a couple of just to call out a
couple of different things that we found
that were kind of interesting um cve
2017 80 9841 apologies was actually
found in 2017.
it emerged strongly in 2019.
um we caught it uh about halfway through
september in 2019.
um
it's been continuous in our data set
since october 2020.
now um it peaked somewhere in there
but it still continues to this day
and uh it's still quite significant
which i think is interesting because one
would assume that uh such an old cpe
would perhaps fall out of the data set
that attackers are using but it's not
happening
uh they continue to use it now whether
this is because it's easier just to
leave it in
or
whether it's actually still being
effective
i don't actually know
my suspicion is probably more than
latter
generally speaking attackers are pretty
good about optimizing
what they're doing for efficiency
and when you're scanning large chunks of
the internet that becomes an important
thing
so um i'm expecting that this particular
cde is probably something that they're
still finding some um instances of
cv 2019
11510 does actually tell a slightly
different story which is this was a
a vulnerability in the um
pulse secure ssl vpn it was a critical
uh the cvs score of 10.
um we saw it first at the very beginning
of august uh it had a huge spike
right after that in mid-august
um scans continue to this day but at a
much lower level
and uh just to correlate that a tiny bit
uh that might actually be corresponding
to that august
um
some of these actually
oh no i'm sorry i'm getting this a
little bit confused
some of this definitely accounts for um
the spikes that you see actually that
first blue spike there
um especially the 2019 11510
was definitely present within that
two-month span where you see the first
big light blue spike
now with that i'm going to hand it over
to ray to talk about a few other
interesting things that we've found
ah thank you i'm going to kind of go
through these a little quicker because
we're kind of running out of time here
but uh you know also you can see the
links in the bottom of the site here's
or the
video so you can actually go to the site
and see the longer versions of these
little stories
um one of the things we did when we
first started analyzing this data is we
saw this huge spike of php attacks now
we see a lot of php
um but actually starting to
one of our other researchers uh sander
vindenberg who works on the uh protect
report found was these are actually
coming just from two servers
uh two particular servers at a north
american university and just targeting a
couple of cves but these things were
pretty much swamping our data to the
point where we actually had to take them
out of our data set and separate them
just so that we could see everything
else because they were pushing
everything back down
but it kind of goes to show that like
you know there are boxes out there that
just go crazy and they just run crazy
for months we did try to contact the
owners
um
that could just you know spray across
the internet constantly as it's a loud
horn
uh go on to the next slide please
i was gonna say these are some yeah so
another thing that we saw another big
spike in scanning and we also look at
these things globally and this is
combined both web traffic and some
non-web traffic
so we it was kind of funny the analyst
came to us and said hey there's this
huge spike of scans against singapore
coming from russia
and this week what's going you know
what's going on i said president trump
is in russia right now meeting with with
the president of north korea and i was
like oh
oh wow well these are all sip scans and
iot scans so you know are we looking at
some sort of interesting
espionage action it's like who knows and
who knows if it's actually russia i mean
you never know when you're looking at an
iap address uh go on to to the next
slide i was gonna say we started
following this data and next thing we
know we saw the same thing in finland
except for now the scans were coming
from china and he was meeting with
vladimir putin
so you know you just see some kind of
interesting weird stuff in the data
go on to the next one please
and lastly we were looking through the
data and just uh noticed there was a
coffee pot a coffee pot was hitting our
network just scanning away and you know
some of the people kind of went oh my
god it's a coffee pot bought you know
it's it's the end of the world i was
like oh maybe somebody just
misconfigured something or i don't know
it was beaconing but it was
uh if anybody's got any theories as to
what this was about i'd love to hear it
because it was it was pretty bizarre
um and we have not seen it since because
we're definitely been looking for it
go ahead to the next one malcolm
and take over please okay so if you want
to do something like you're like this
yourself um it's probably probable that
you can um
in my experience web blogs and wife logs
can be treasure troves if especially you
um
maybe do some pre-analysis and store
perhaps even just some counts of what
you see
for the long term and then continue that
over time you're going to get some
interesting trending data
you can use a similar approach to your
network edge uh you can sample um
it doesn't necessarily have to capture
absolutely everything because i know
that can be challenging especially with
uh the sort of
amount of data that we have flowing in
and out of our networks uh but even some
random sampling can can yield some
interesting results
uh and it's actually really interesting
to see what's hitting you even if it's
getting blocked uh or even if it you
know never reaches uh anything in your
infrastructure because it's stopped at
the firewall
um i think that that actually while you
don't want to spend obviously tons of
time analyzing it and tons of space
storing it
occasionally checking in on it or
gathering some summary data is actually
pretty useful to kind of figure out what
sorts of things attackers are trying
and when you see a shift in their
behavior it can give you a little bit of
a distant early warning like maybe
you're not using apis yet maybe your
company is not quite there yet um or is
you know trying to figure out if that
should be your strategy well maybe you
could
make the case that you need to invest in
some api security before you roll that
out given the fact that you might be
seeing a lot of api traffic getting
something uh even though you don't
actually have it
yet picture takeaways here um attacks
against api and author rising those are
the the two things that i would
recommend anybody really be looking at
are does your authentication endpoints
have adequate protections in terms of
protection against brute force
credential stuffing
obviously good passwords password reuse
all of the sorts of things um that you
need to do to protect your off
infrastructure and i know for a fact
that the oauth website has a huge amount
of data about many of these techniques
so i would refer you there
sql injection is falling off
certainly it's still an issue if you use
sql
to back your apps but
it does seem to be falling off but
command injection remains very popular
so basic app security stuff to protect
yourself against demand injection is
absolutely there
one interesting question that i had was
since the oauth top 10 combines sql
injection and command injection into one
category is the falloff and sql
injection
and a steady state in command injection
the reason why
injection has fallen a position or two
within the os top 10 that was just
recently released
i think it might be but i'd be
interested to hear if anybody has any
data on that
info disclosure
is
on the rise people are looking for
places where people store passwords or
leave authentication keys around whether
that's dot e b or dot git files or
anything like that so having some
hygiene around how you store things
is extremely important
uh and then public vulnerabilities of
course you know attackers pick these up
as quickly as they can which is often
very fast within a week or two
um and they use them heavily for about
three months um and then they don't go
away
they last for sometimes years
uh within the tool sets of the attackers
so with that we're done um thank you
very much for uh your time and uh if you
want to get in touch with us um you can
hit find us on twitter linkedin
we have a great email newsletter as well
ray do you want to say anything else
come to f5 labs.com there's it's just
all material you can download it there's
no advertising or anything it's for the
security community
thank you absolutely
thanks very much