[Music]
happy friday everybody i know i'm in
between you maybe i'm in between you and
happy hour hopefully we'll keep you
engaged here
i also would like to get to happy hour
so let's let's have a fun get through
this presentation talk a little bit
about
why developers struggle or seemingly
struggle with apsec and some ways we can
make it easier
on our developer partners
again i'm scott garlock and uh
introduced me a little bit cso
co-founder here at stackhawk
uh i was the cisso at cengrid for about
three years uh i did many many roles at
godaddy for almost 10 i'm also a husband
golfer
guitar player tinker brewer like you
know you name it i got hobbies man i got
hobbies um if you want to get a hold of
me you can definitely reach me at
on twitter and on linkedin there i would
love to talk about appsec and and apps
like programs with you if you want
uh really quickly let's talk about this
appsec problem overview uh
obviously we're in the owasp channel
here we're in a wasp event so appsec is
really good in theory
uh but it's super tough in practice and
look we're going to talk about why that
is today but let's level set a little
bit and talk about some of the things
that you can use to test application
security and application security
postures just to make sure everyone's on
the same page so there's a there's a
handful of things that we can test with
one of them is static code analysis so
you've got static
application security testing which is
looking at source code you've also got
software composition analysis what
libraries am i using to build my
application
those things just look at written source
code
library versions they don't really have
a good context of how the application
works but they know exactly the line
items where things work so that's really
kind of interesting and awesome powerful
sometimes that can be a little noisy
because of that lack of knowledge of how
the application works so you can get a
lot of false positives or
a wall of alerts
we've also got dynamic code analysis
often referred to as dast so dynamic
application security testing and this is
a little bit better at looking at the
app uh the context of the application
and understanding how it works and what
is being presented to
end users and potential threat actors uh
it's still somewhat noisy most of these
are really hard to use
so they're really hard to kind of get up
and running and figure out how to make
work how to consume the output how to do
lots of different stuff
um
there are some good ones out there i
know of one at least
uh rasp i asked and laugh
these are awesome tools but i think of
them as the
backstop for production so if you do a
good job through the development process
of making sure you've got libraries in
good shape making sure you're writing
the right kind of code doing good
testing these kinds of tools are meant
to be out in production helping you
prevent unknown bad things from
happening hopefully and
not blocking legitimate users and that
last part is where it gets a little
sticky sometimes so legit activity
happening uh in an application rasp and
i asked and waff can sometimes identify
that as illegit activity or the other
way around and sometimes that's a little
difficult
but i want to talk about some of the
problems with
a lot of these tools and and
application security programs and how we
are as security professionals making
this
maybe harder than it should be for our
uh engineering partners
so problem one is kind of this idea of
the benevolent security team and i know
no security team thinks of themselves
this way but uh this is kind of how
sometimes they present themselves and
that becomes a problem uh and the the
hard truth of the matter here is you can
never hire as many apsec people as the
organization can hire developers the
security team
often makes this kind of whole thing a
lot harder in the name of accountability
but really what they're doing is
making people go slow or causing
interruptions because they can't scale
with the business they can't scale with
engineering teams
um and it turns into a bottleneck it
turns into a blocker or a gatekeeper and
it's not good and a couple of the things
that are causing this thing
trust issues being one of them so
way way way
before covet pandemic i don't know if
you guys remember the time before kobed
i barely do uh charlie actually tweeted
a thing about he's talking to my good
friend colleen about i'm not sure if a
new hire dev is in a position to
evaluate risk for a feature product or
company i think professional security
people can do this better
and i mean sort of right sort of the
hard truth of the matter is a new hire
developer isn't making these decisions
in a vacuum anyway
they're making them with the input from
their other team members or people they
work with or engineers or leadership in
engineering and so they're not doing
this in a vacuum already
it's just that we as security folk think
that they're doing that in a vacuum and
we don't have access or inputs to how
they're making those decisions so we
don't trust them to make solid decisions
and when we do
oftentimes we lack the context of what
they're doing so they come to us and go
hey should we do blah whatever that
thing is and we sometimes lack the
context of why and what are we trying
what's the goal we're trying to achieve
and it just turns into a yeah don't do
that
and so both of those things turn into a
thing that is not healthy not good
does not uh create collaboration in fact
creates silos
the way that i think about this is a
little bit more like
this uh i wouldn't want to put a new
higher developer in the position of
making an uninformed risk decision and
this is much different than what
how charlie phrased it maybe not what he
meant but how he phrased it
and so the whole point here is if i can
get you enough information for you to
make somewhat of an informed decision
that's a much better position than
making an uninformed decision or
not making a decision at all so both of
those things uh they're a little bit
similar but they're a little different
at the same time
uh the other thing that happens here is
sometimes to combat this trust issue
oftentimes security teams come up with
this awesome new idea and it's called
let's teach them how to do our job
at best it's misguided at worst
uh it continues to drive division
between
dev and security teams
and it kind of sometimes comes off like
this hey you don't know how to do your
job very well but i can teach you how to
do my job so that you i can scale out my
job uh and you have to learn all the
things that i know already uh because
you're not doing a good job at
engineering or something like that it
just comes out weird
uh and then what happens is we teach
them all these new acronyms and
terminology and then we go to the wait
wait uh did we level set what do we do
you know about risk and how to calculate
risk and
also you know the internet's bad don't
you
and then
like it's just this circle of
out of context it's not what we're what
they work on on a daily basis
it's not relevant to the things that
they're trying to do the goals they're
trying to achieve
and if you ever have done one of these
developer security programs
have you ever noticed who gets selected
by the engineering team to go to these
things so usually the engineering
leadership is like i'm going to send my
top developers to this stuff we're going
to do a train the trainers kind of a
model they're going to come back and
teach everybody all the stuff they learn
and at the end when you talk to them
they say it was really informative i
learned a ton of stuff
and then you come back a month later and
go who did you help
help teach this these concepts to or do
it in practice or things that you fixed
in the code base because of what you
learned and they almost always go
oh nothing i actually went back to my
real job of doing features and bug
fixing and pushing stuff out the door to
create value for the business so
oftentimes this is really really
ineffective there is little tidbits of
good things that happen in this
but the hardest part of this is we're
teaching them in these vulnerable apps
which are good to learn in
but they're hard to teach developers in
because they don't work like regular
apps they don't get built like regular
like regular apps
they don't have the context of what the
business is actually trying to do
like the applications that they're
working the things that i've seen work
best here are
take
a found application security issues in
code bases that you work on
and teach the development team why
that's bad in the context of their thing
and show them
what a better way is or collaborate with
them on how can we fix that and go that
way that really keeps them in the
context of here's what i do for a living
when we do this out of context thing it
sort of feels like this sometimes
it's kind of the equivalent of the
accounting team saying to leadership
after leadership goes hey we want to
model a new price increase the
accounting team going
we can help you with that but first we
have to teach you how the gl works now
the gl is a really complicated but easy
system of debits and credits and
everything equals zero at the end
and the accounting team or the exact
team is just like okay cool uh i just
need to be able to make decisions
quickly with the right information so
i feel like we as security professionals
need to do a better job of giving them
this information so that people can make
informed decisions quickly
we also have this chase to perfection
mentality uh we have it's kind of a
nasty habit right often we think about
things in totalitarian terms like let's
eliminate all of the risk let's patch
everything
don't do anything in the cloud
and the hard truth and matter is
businesses exist to take risk and our
job as information security
professionals is to help guide the
business on what risk to take
and what risk to maybe not take
even thinking you can solve a customer
problem is in fact a risk as a business
like the whole beginning of a business
is like a risk
so the business needs to be able to take
measured and informed risk to operate
and security teams should be no
different we need to help our
development engineering partners
understand and take these measured risks
as we as we're trying to get features
out the door attract customers grow the
business
uh deliver more features and all kinds
of good stuff
uh the other thing that happens here
uh
ticketing as the primary interface so
if you're evaluating a security tool of
some sort or fashion and your first
question is can i push all of these
issues to jira
you are not thinking about prioritizing
fixing at all you are thinking about
documenting
uh and so this is
the wrong way to go about thinking about
how to help engineering prioritize stuff
so if you're not getting closer to the
in context finding delivery of
information and helping people
understand
so as people are writing code as people
are testing code in ci cd you're getting
farther and farther away from that
context and it makes it harder and
harder and more expensive to be able to
fix those things and prioritize them
necessarily
tooling should at least give you
feedback in the command line or in ci cd
and invest in ids so that you can
consume this and you know whether or not
you consume it or how you consume it is
a whole different thing if you can't
start here
you have you have a really big problem
enabling uh engineering teams
now that's all if you have a security
team if you don't have a security team
you're small business uh you're still
growing you
you know you don't you haven't afforded
the capability of a security function
it's really hard to understand where to
start any of this stuff so
you kind of land in this realm of like
okay there's a hundred different things
i could do which one should i prioritize
as a cto or a vp avenge or engineering
manager
or even a developer
um so what kind of happens there is like
i got other stuff to do or
hang on maybe this devops team that i've
got knows something about this and can
help me
uh so those things aren't great but
enabling process and tooling that can
easily get people started quickly
enabled into
i'm testing my application security i
understand what i should be doing with
this stuff
and i'm making active decisions is super
important
problem number two
appsec tools are built for security
teams uh
this is really complicated and sometimes
hard to understand the context of what
you're looking at
because of who most of the
products are built for
so we're going to talk about the context
of why that is but
a ton of security tools out there look
like this it's i know you've seen a tool
that looks like this it's got all kinds
of options all kinds of buttons all
kinds of switches
there's a training program that comes
along with it when you buy a tool
and if you gave an engineer access to
this thing
they probably hit the x or the little
red circle or whatever operating system
you're using really quickly on this tool
or
they make fun of it for a little bit and
figure out how it was designed and who
built it and how it was designed by
committee and
why they exposed everything and then
they closed it so none of those things
is is what you want from your
engineering team or for your engineering
team you want to engage them with those
with tooling and information
and sometimes some of this stuff doesn't
work very well
the other thing that happens with uh
tools being built for security teams is
we play this game we have invented a lot
of really great new words to talk about
application security issues
and how to
and how to fix them a little bit uh
mostly we just have a lot of wall of
text about what an application security
issue is
and this one is my favorite because it's
the same thing but two different terms
or two different
initializations of the same term so
that's even confusing to security
professionals think about that from an
engineering perspective
and ultimately the real thing here is
using anti-csrf tokens are same site
policy for browsers
but none of these things talk about that
and if you were to give this information
to an engineer and they went how do i
fix this the answer to them is probably
oh the library or the framework that
you're using probably has anti-csrf
tokens turn them on and use them
which is not in any of these things so
that's an interesting thing that we we
try to do to our engineering teams is we
try to invent new terminology and words
that already describe problems that
they're used to dealing with input
sanitization cross-site scripting sql
injection command injection input
sanitization
output sanitization um
tendency filtering so broken object
level authorization all these things are
terms that exist in development land but
we change them
because they're in security land
now there are good appstack tools out
there that work in kind of this
developer native flow in the context of
how they work where they work when they
work
there's a couple different ones on here
that are really good that was dependency
check is obviously a good one um
pr bot depend-abot sneak fossa npm audit
is a good one
that last one is awesome um but lastly
and worst of all probably all of these
tools or most of these tools suffer from
problem number three that i want to talk
about and that is
the production bias
so the production bias is all about
testing in production and testing when
you get to production and all kinds of
good stuff and let's talk about why
first of all
first of all the reason why that is is
because of the first two things we
talked about security uh tools
application securities tools are built
for security teams security people
and production is just where they know
the application the best or if they're a
pen tester it's the only place to have
access to the to the application so
understanding that uh production
application and its risk in production
is
how they work most of the time uh and
both of these groups are very focused on
finding vulnerabilities and their value
is driven especially in pentesland their
value is driven out of how many things
did they find
if you hired a
pen test firm or had a pen test
engagement and they came back and said
we didn't find anything
what would your initial thought be
we did a great job or
probably not doing their job very well
here uh-oh
so that's that's an interesting thing
that happens with this production bias
uh is we're more focused on the number
of things found than finding and fixing
the right things
it's also very inefficient because the
find the people that do the finding are
not the fixers of this thing so there's
this whole process and loop
about how to get this information back
to people who can fix
it also reinforces the adversarial
relationship in kind of a when we find
stuff as that as security professionals
we go oh look at it i did my job really
good i found a problem
and it comes off to somebody else's
uh you broke i broke your thing or you
did a bad job doing the thing that you
do
isn't that awesome
um not awesome doesn't make people feel
great doesn't establish and uh back up
that team mentality
so what that looks like often is this so
i'm sure there are people out in the
audience today that have done one or two
of these things at some point i have
done both of these things so don't feel
bad if you are like looking at this
going wait i do this i've done both of
these things
uh and what they look like is hey before
you release this software i have to give
it the okay
and what that what happens there is
my development team goes way faster than
my application security person or a
couple of people
and i can't keep up and so then
eventually
uh leadership and managers in the
company go okay don't do that anymore i
don't know why you're doing that it's
not doing anything good for us and it's
delaying our release to production
so then we go okay cool you just push
that out into production and we'll come
back around to it at some point
and then we play catch-up and we're
playing catch-up with
application security problems in
production
which is
not awesome
uh it's super inefficient again we still
play that big loop game of i found stuff
i made a ticket i got it prioritized i
got it back to the dev the dev didn't
understand how to recreate the issue so
i had to teach them how to recreate the
issue now they've got to get the app
running on their local machine again so
that it actually runs and
oh okay now i fixed it and it's still
like six months three months six months
nine months years later
uh but the biggest problem with this
particular thing and the one thing that
i dislike about this methodology is the
bugs are in production
so you necessarily have to push security
issues into production to find them
and that's terrible because hopefully
you find them first
hopefully someone else with nefarious
activities or
your bug bounty program doesn't find
them before you do because either way
they cost you money uh and hopefully
they're not super easy to find
those are the worst kinds of things to
pay out bug bounty on uh and to respond
to security researchers and threat
actors and all kinds of stuff is stuff
you could easily find
before you got to production
this is also very frustrating for
software engineers because the security
team runs infrequent scans of code
that's already in production and then
they engage in that ticket shuffling
again and the engineering team has long
moved on to another sprint or another
epic or another
something else by the time they get this
information back and again we have to
restart this whole like what was i even
working on when we did that
how do i get this running again all
kinds of good stuff
super ineffective and inefficient now
there may be times when you
intentionally ship
a bug or security bug to production and
that isn't as a good informed decision
with product and engineering and
security being able to go
hey i know that there's a security
problem here the risk is low the
likelihood is low
we should ship this anyway and we'll
quickly come back and fix it as a fast
follow
that's an awesome informed decision to
make that is much much different than
i'm pretty sure it's good let's ship it
or
don't ship it till i check it out and
i've got a lot of other things to do so
i'm going to be pretty busy for the next
week so i'm going to hold up your
deployment for a week
that doesn't help you meet customer
demands or customer commitments
and turns into this blocker process
again
let's talk a little bit of how to get
started kind of the right way or
what i think is the right way
and the very first thing about this is i
think
uh
security tests and security testing
should work the exact same way other
software testing does and that is
uh you know when a unit test breaks you
know that the code's not working because
the unit test doesn't work and the
integration test doesn't work and
something's broken because the compiler
can't make a binary out of
uh out of the code that you wrote
there's lots of ways to do testing
uh whether it's unit tests functional
tests integration tests compiler tests
security testing should be just like
that should just act like that you
should be able to recreate these tests
locally so that when you
get code into
a ci cd system and you're doing security
testing there as well it's not a black
box you could recreate this locally if
you wanted to to be able to test and do
it locally
just like unit testing and integration
tests it shouldn't be a black box thing
that exists in in development that
doesn't give you feedback doesn't tell
you what's happening you can't reproduce
it
but it breaks your build that's never a
good thing
um and so when a
team introduces a vulnerability they
should know because it fails a security
test in some form or fashion and what
that looks like on our devops mobius is
over this is where the shift left term
comes from right on the left side of our
mobius here during
coding and building and testing is where
security testing should
primarily live like you can test in that
deploy and operate space
but that should not be the first place
you test the first place you test should
be back there in that code build and
test part of this loop
instrumenting those tests in ci cd
giving immediate feedback and the
ability to for an engineer to stay in
context of what they're building when
they're building it how they're building
it
and differentials so if i make a new
code commit and a new issue shows up
it's probably in that code that i just
wrote or could just committed so i don't
have to go looking all over the app
necessarily i can look in what i just
added
lots of uh our customers check for
security bugs on every pr or mr or
whatever merging strategy you
particularly have and that gives the
test information directly back to those
engineers as they're working on it
engineers are smart people that are
writing software for businesses and
companies to create value are really
smart let them be smart
security teams tend to want to approve
everything
and what that means is other people
can't make decisions you've taken them
out of the whole entire decision loop if
you are approving their decisions
they're not making decisions they're
making suggestions and you're approving
it
allow this kind of technology to spark
collaboration between development and
security but enable devs to do their
work enable them to do
self-serve figure out and fix problems
and if they make the wrong decision
that's okay too
but they've made a decision and
documented it so that is really really
good
now you can have a conversation as an
abstract professional about it with a
development team about decisions that
they made
and why you think they might be wrong
and why they think they might be right
that's a good discussion to have and a
good partnership
business risk is all collaboration and
no one team knows the answer to any of
these
questions or outcomes
if you're doing this remember you might
end up in a therapy session it might get
a little rough for a little bit
um but it's doable it is totally doable
to partner with the engineering team and
change their perception
about the information security team as a
partner and someone who enables them as
as opposed to a blocker and or security
ninjas who are like
you guys made a mistake i dropped out of
the ceiling don't do that
uh
lastly the most important part here is
just start like if you've got an
application security program and it's
not making good headway restart
if you don't have an application
security program and you're trying to
start one start start with a small team
a small engineering team help become
their partner help give them information
choose an application and their ci cd
pipeline get them the information they
need
choose a technology i personally like
sca and dast because those two things
are actionable in two different ways
and they both give you really good
information
once that's working iterate and expand
out to the other rest of the
organization they'll probably be your
champion as engineering teams if you do
it well
they'll talk to their other development
partners and friends and say hey
actually the information security team
is helping us application security team
is helping us and we're going faster and
we're producing better code you should
talk to those guys
or girls sorry no i don't mean to be
exclusive i mean you know
general guys
uh lastly that was that's it for my time
everybody thank you so much for
listening to me hopefully you're
enjoying your late friday afternoon i
know i am it's happy hour time time to
get down uh if you're already past happy
hour then you know drive safe