[Music]
okay hello everyone and welcome to my
talk about drag native security
addressing typical mistakes
actually this is my first time speaking
at such a large of asp event so let me
quickly introduce myself
my name is julia i'm a security software
engineer at cossack labs
i'm also a leader of ospregetomer
chapter in ukraine and i am a huge huge
fan of wasp mis-vs and msdg projects
uh cossack labs is a data security and
cryptography company we have
products and expertise in different
platforms and languages
and my personal specialization is mobile
application security for is for android
and for react native
like we do not
break stuff we build it
and today i want to talk about things
you need to consider to build a secure
react native application
now we will talk today about the
architecture in general about
platform-specific things for is for
android for react native we'll talk
about dependencies and about security
testing
and i would like to start with this
phrase that choosing react native and
its components means that you understand
and accept potential security
consequences
to understand what it means
let's take a look at the architecture of
the react native apps
it's just a general overview
react native is a cross-platform
solution from facebook
that allows writing
applications using react javascript and
you can also use typescript
so we have
native platforms ios and android we have
javascript engine it can be custom or it
can be a native one
and we have these components the bridge
written by facebook that handles
messages between native platform and
javascript engine
when you write native apps for ios and
android
you choose to trust apple and google
with their systems with your apis you
believe that they are secure enough for
your
applications
and when you use react native you add
facebook to this list
and if you decide to use typescript you
also add microsoft
the problem here is that each new
third-party component makes the attack
surface wider
if the breach is broken or facebook
stops supporting it or something else
happens your react native app stops
working as well
and the same problem goes with
javascript engines if you choose using
custom javascript engines you will need
to deal with it as well
for example facebook uh has a
javascript custom javascript engine for
ios and android called hermes to make
react native applications more efficient
but you know there are already found
vulnerabilities
in this hermes javascript engine of
course they're already fixed but still
these are vulnerabilities for
uh hermes for android and
hermes4is was just released this year
and there are still like it still looks
good for now
uh
okay moving forward
uh with react native developers deal
with security for all three platforms
for with ios with android and with react
native
uh i'm pretty sure you're familiar with
uh mobile top 10 from overs
like similar to just of top 10 but for
mobile applications
and the first item in it is improper
platform usage
and
the set truth is that uh if it's hard
for ios and android developers to use
platform-specific security controls it
is even harder for react native
developers because again
you need to deal with specifics of all
three platforms
i will show you multiple examples
of this
i just love this phrase that react
native is a leaky abstraction
react native allows you to abstract from
the details of each native platform but
sometimes such details are very very
important from the security perspective
let's take a look at several examples
the first one is secure store
it is a library from expo that claims
that it stores
uh data encrypted and well that is true
it uses a keychain on ios that is an
encrypted storage and uh for android it
uses keystore to create a key then it
encrypts the data with this key and
stores it in shared preferences regular
storage
like all good here it stores data
encrypted that's right
but
you see keychain persists its data
across apra installs while shared
preferences do not
and you know there is an msvs
requirement
that you need to
erase the data across a pre-install so
here we are missing this requirement
then
for ios we have hardware backed
encryption
uh starting from iphone
5s that was released several years ago
and for android there are
there are still devices that do not have
hardware backed encryption and probably
you don't want to run your application
on such devices
then
if you use keychain
your data
is decrypted when your device is
unlocked meaning
you use touch id face id or passcode and
then your data is stored in plain text
until you lock your device
while on android this library decrypts
the data just right before usage
and you see uh there are differences in
the behavior of this security control
and if you follow mobile security best
practices standards you want the
behavior to be similar
uh you want to raise data across april
installs you want to have hardware
backed encryption and you want to
decrypt your data just before use
so
uh here you need to understand and fix
platform specific things
another example of platform-specific
problem
is about
managing and joint permissions
you know
on android you specify permissions in
manifest file
and each dependency may have its own
manifest file adding new permissions
it is a common practice for react native
applications to have multiple
dependencies i'd say sometimes your
application may have even more than a
hundred of dependencies and each of them
may add
new permissions to your project
and it becomes a headache
because like yeah you can remove some of
these permissions uh you can take your
main manifest file and remove these edit
permissions
but it does not guarantee that the
library can support it like it may just
crash if you try to remove its
permission
so dependencies are a headache and we'll
get back to this topic a little bit
later again
one more example now it's javascript
specific
it is
maybe one of the most popular questions
i hear is that
is xss is possible in react native and
the generic answer is
its possibility is decreased by design
if you read some articles you can see
some explanations why
we consider
uh it why we consider the possibility to
be decreased like in react react.js and
for react native it it is decreased even
more
but
let's not go way too deep into this
topic because xss is still possible
it's a very trivial example but still
there is there's still
this evil function
uh and here is an example that if you
use async storage you can pass this
another library for storing data in
mobile applications now you can pass
these lines to the evol
function and uh
these lines will take all the data from
a sync storage and send
and send it to this address
so yeah
that is possible
and
another example
things are getting even harder when we
talk about jailbreak and root detection
like you know this topic is not easy for
regular ios and android teams meaning
native teams
and
it is even harder if we want to talk
about react native because
you know there is no ready to go
solutions maybe there are some
you can purchase some solution but i'm
not even aware if such exists
uh you can try to implement your own
but i'm almost sure that it's not
possible to use just javascript to do
that you will still need to go to the
native code
and
like
the second option is to use some
third-party solutions that are already
available for native platforms and to
write breaching code for them
it may sound easy but still this there
are some
challenges
for example
this is a very very good library
for
ios security to detect jailbreak
to detect jailbreak and it follows all
the recommendations from os about
protection against reverse engineering
and tempering
it's called is security suit
this library is written in swift
and i really like it and i recommend it
but
the problem here is
that
okay you have this library for ios
it's written in swift but by default uh
react native applications use
uh
objective c so you write bridging from
swift to objective c and then you write
bridging from objective c to react
native a lots of work and it's just for
one platform
it's just for ios where we have such a
nice library and i am not aware if there
is any such a good android library you
will have to use a couple of them or
maybe even write some
code on your own
and again bridge it to react native so
it is a lot of work a lot of pain and
requires a lot of platform specific
knowledge
okay
getting back to the dependencies topic
a typical situation on react native
project
a lot a lot of dependencies and they
bring a lot a lot of vulnerabilities
this is a real life project i worked on
uh yeah we've created a task for the
team that you need to update
dependencies you need
to review these vulnerabilities and to
do something with it maybe remove some
libraries or to do something
and
sometime later they have updated their
dependencies and we
received that
well and
you know it it is after the update and
you know i'm
not pretty sure what is better to have
16 000 low vulnerabilities or 2 000 high
well so
like the next recommendation is just to
remove these vulnerabilities with
unfixable high issues
so monetary independence is
is not that easy for react native
they're just
you are forced to use a lot of them
you will have a lot of additional ci
work
for example dependency checkers are a
must
and then when you'll need to update your
dependencies you should consider that
one update triggers another update you
may need to do some architectural
changes to your application
updates may be incompatible
and you may face some vulnerabilities
that just do not have a fix so what
should you do in such situations
first
we suggest you to understand the scope
of such vulnerabilities because like
sometimes these are just false positives
if you
use react native for ios and android you
should consider that it is also used for
web and probably you do not use web
parts so maybe web vulnerabilities are
not
relevant to your project so you need to
understand the scope of the
vulnerability document it share with
your team because if you leave the
project someone will need to start
reviewing this huge list from the very
beginning
and of course monitor uh monitor and
book time for updates in the future
and
uh booking time here is really crucial
another situation is when
some
vulnerability is fixed
in
the platform main
native platform
in ios or android
for example when
ios decided to remove support
of the ui review because it was way too
vulnerable
and
you know
so you wait for the update for the
native
part then you wait until facebook
releases the update for the react native
then some teams have
a forked version of the react native
repo for example to remove a part if
they're not using it so they need to
update their fork
then they wait until all the
dependencies are updated and only then
you can work and update
your own source code so it's very very
time consuming and the main rule here
is always plan your time for updates
uh now it is
uh the last section of my talk about
uh security testing of react native
apps because just a lot of people are
asking me well how we do this
and uh of course my common answer for
mobile applications
is using a vespa svs and a vast maze tg
yeah hello again to carlos and swan
here
uh
it is mobile application security
verification standard and mobile
security testing guide and if you open
the second one you will see the note
that it actually focuses primarily on
native applications and
doesn't does not have a lot information
uh for react native for submarine
cordova flutter and other so-called
hybrid applications
but
the good news
is that you can still use msvs because
it is language agnostic it is almost
platform agnostic
uh all requirements are relevant for
react native applications because
like react native applications they are
like native under the hood and you can
still use msdg because general ideas of
the test cases it is
still similar uh like
the major difference is that you may
need to read javascript code but in
general everything is still the same
you will still need to test
keychain as you've seen
key store shared preferences ssl pinion
tls pinion is still implemented in
native code the same way as before
like
settings to allow
http traffic is
are still mentioned in info plist file
or
network config like a lot of things are
still similar
so testing is not the different for
react native applications
and a little bit to sum up this uh how
do we do this how do we test react
native application security
uh
first of all yeah we use msvs it's our
it's very convenient because it is a
sort of checklist and it can make
our security measurable more visible
then
as i mentioned before we need to take a
closer look on dependencies
uh we need to take these javascript code
of dependencies and like written for
react native application by us and
uh look deeper to understand what native
api it uses what security controls it
uses so it requires more effort here
like to go deeper
a challenge here is that
okay now we have
javascript code and by
default
the native code for react native
applications is written in objective c
and java that
are not
the
latest tendencies let's say
and
the truth is that it is very likely that
you will also deal with typescript in
together with the javascript and
it is very likely that you have to deal
with swift and kotlin so you see instead
of having like two languages like in
many other projects swift and kotlin you
need to deal with six languages
and yeah it's an additional challenge if
you do
security review
reviewing the code and given some
suggestions for secure coding for
developers so it's another challenge
and the last
part of this is javascript javascript
specific vulnerabilities
uh you can just google them i think you
will find some information about xss
mostly
uh
and but you can still take a look at web
security testing guide and asvs to find
something that will help you to
understand what javascript specific
vulnerabilities may be present in direct
native applications
and
some final thoughts from me
so facebook names dear approach as
learn once right anywhere
but for me it sounds more like learn
once and ask
mobile security people for help because
yeah you've seen why
and
a couple of
useful links from me
the first one is my article about react
native application security uh it has
some additional details to my talk so
you can go here and read it it has more
details on architecture
um also the second link
is
security guide from facebook
on the official page
it's just interesting to read what do
they recommend and i can say that mostly
it's the same things that
you've saw from
you've seen from
improper platform usage these are all
platform-specific things not that many
react native like javascript specific
things
and the third link
uh
is
uh four of waspimas vs
uh you know
like as i mentioned it does not have a
chapter or recommendations for hybrid
applications hybris applications
uh but uh there is an ongoing discussion
and feel free to join it
uh
we'll be glad to see your to hear your
thoughts uh like how do you use it
how do you use my svs for react native
applications what are your suggestions
please feel free to share your thoughts
uh okay
and
generally that is it from me this is my
twitter you can follow me i will post my
slides in twitter sometime later
and of course i'm here in in slackchat
so i will be glad to hear your questions
thank you