[Music]
we'll jump right into well thank you
everyone um and thanks for the owasp
committee for
uh allowing myself and ethan to present
this friday afternoon we're super
excited and my co-worker alex is going
to be joining on the presentation as
well
so i'm going to go ahead and get right
into it so data theorem we
focus on api security web security
cloud uh security and mobile
um but a couple years ago uh i've been
uh a pen tester and before a pen tester
uh in the 90s i did some other things
that didn't really have a cool title but
i've been in the hacking scene for quite
some time
and about two years ago uh i noticed
some attacks happening on apis that were
i thought coincidental
and it turned out it wasn't it was some
pretty cool techniques that are still
happening today uh so that is the topic
of my talk is not only how to hack your
apis in 15 minutes or less how hackers
right now are doing it in 15 minutes or
less so this is more like a case study
of what i identified from some
reconnaissance and some of my friends
still in the industry uh with uh unknown
titles uh so hopefully it um and then
i'm gonna just dive right in
so
so one thing i want to talk about the
main
importance of this slide is 15 minutes
or less the hacker community and i'm not
talking about the research community or
even the professional community like
data theorem but the hacker community is
quite efficient they have a lot of
things to do uh whether it's hanging out
with friends uh trying to get their
driver's license or even that bag of
cheetos uh they're very efficient crew
and so 15 minutes for a target unless
you want to take down that target or
unless it's a nation state 15 minutes
it's about the maximum of time you're
going to have a hacker going after you
uh for like a drive-by attack uh and
then and that's what my first thing is
hackers hack right that's what they're
here for that's what they want to do uh
they do it for fame sometimes it's for
chaos sometimes they entertain
themselves and their friends and
sometimes for money now later uh when
you know in the past decade it's become
monetizable but in the 90s no one was
really making money off of hacking
organized crime was always there but
it's gotten even more efficient um but
this is something that you know hackers
are here to hack
um
but uh but it's different from
research um research is very different
from hacking uh security research that
is uh so one person on our board uh who
doesn't need an introduction dan bonnay
he's a professor here at stanford um
he's a true researcher he has taught me
so much
about the information security community
army
information security
market
and his students over at stanford his
phd students they're great research they
produce great things but it's research
of security it's not hacking and so
because i grew up in this world uh in
the 90s
the researchers are what i call
the diet coke of evil like uh many
researchers would never ever uh break a
law would they would never maybe even
hack itself which is uh which is
actually pretty easy with test
environments and the cloud these days
you don't really have to choose a target
to learn there's so many other places to
learn but it is not an evil thing to do
in security research um you're not
breaking any laws but when i was much
younger in the 90s
we didn't have that luxury uh it was a
hacking community there were no test
environments and so my friends because i
kind of call out post 2015 security is
really strongly and more technically
research based but sometimes i'm known
to be a grumpy old man saying hey if
you've never hacked anything um it's a
different mindset of hacking uh it's
about efficiency it's about
data and it's about you know getting in
and getting out it's not for the
intellectual stimulation it's not for
the researchers they're very different
reasons um and this is what i identified
with this api hack that that we'll be
talking about today
all right so before i talk about that
let me talk to you about some of
dr dan bonay's research and other
research from the academic community so
this i thought was pretty clever and
kind of distinguishes a hacker from a
researcher here is a great paper uh from
some universities of how
machine learning can be defeated
essentially so you and i and everyone
probably watching this is probably
seeing a stop sign it's pretty
international maybe the language changes
across the globe
but the the stop sign is pretty
at least here in the united states
pretty known to all of us we all would
say this is a stop sign believe it or
not these stickers on the stop sign make
certain um machine learning algorithms
not recognize this anymore as a stop
sign so this no longer
looks like a stop sign to some machine
learning algorithms and the great
students of these universities basically
did this intellectual research to
basically prove machine learning can be
defeated yes machine learning can be
defeated with four stickers on the stop
sign very impressive very impressive so
as someone like me
when i was much younger or maybe even
today
what i would do is probably not take
months of research from
very intelligent students from great
universities wow what i'm going to do
to defeat machine learning is i'm going
to take a stop sign and i'm gonna go sit
on 101. um and if you're here in
california near silicon valley 101 is
our major highway here um and i will
just stand um
in
you know the middle of the highway with
a stop sign and you can see a tesla here
i'm not picking on tesla um it could be
any smart automobile that recognizes uh
the uh the promise of self-driving cars
which i love and i will happily do one
day but self-driving cars will see stop
signs and they will stop
so what happens if they see a stop sign
on a highway
will they know that
a immature adult like myself is holding
the stop sign and just ignore it which
is the safe thing to do or are they
going to continue and listen um to the
stop sign and stop on 101.
um and so you might be saying or
something maybe on someone on tesla
saying wait listen listen we figured
this out we know we're on one on one we
know we're on sick we're going 65 miles
per hour we know there's no way there's
a stop sign here because we know this
highway this will not be possible and i
don't know if that's true maybe someone
in the audience does in the slack
channel afterwards i would love to hear
about more uh but let's say you know
let's say that's true right let's uh but
we'll look at this construction worker
this construction worker is on a small
highway somewhere probably in the
midwest here in the united states um and
they're doing some construction work uh
it might be emergency
instruction work so
what's the difference of me on 101
with a stop sign and this construction
worker on the stop sign right um do this
you know this is this is like real time
emergency road work and this
construction worker is obviously
stopping cars right so so this is my
my my answer to like the 15 minutes when
you're a hacker you're not trying to
defeat tls that's like multiple months
of research if not years you're trying
to hack and get data um
so so the the the point i'm gonna make
next will really come full circle with
api security because of the recent data
breaches we've seen in the last three
years with apis um it's not
sophisticated it's hackers running wild
on api security and here's what they're
doing
um so don't listen to me don't listen to
data theorem look at the news look at
the data so uh two years ago there's
this app called 63 red safe it's a
mobile app and essentially
it was in the news
because an api that the mobile client
was connecting to
had no authentication required uh so
this happened in march 12th of 2019 my
company data theorem we found out about
it because it involves mobile and api so
we're like oh interesting now we
obviously look for that con constantly
since uh 2016 but it was cool to see
that the awareness of api security was
getting out there as it pertains to
mobile or not mobile but here's the
interesting part
later that year the exact same thing
happened with the exact same researcher
here's an app in australia with an api
search operation the other one was a a
different operation this is a search
operation also in a mobile app and the
attacker was able to get that first name
last name email data birth facebook id
and phone numbers all through an open
api out there on the internet right
september 19th or september 9th
september 27th three weeks later same
attack different app same attack
different app this is heyo this is an
elastic search database embedded in the
mobile app also identified by a hacker
also publicized here in the news
december 23rd of the same year again
same attack api uh api response
operation embedded in a mobile app um
and also compromised first name zip code
basically location information um just a
couple months later so at this point
it's not a coincidence to me at this
point i know someone either a group of
hackers uh or researchers what they call
themselves now are figuring stuff out um
they're they're putting things together
either as a group itself or as a copycat
attack but there's too many attacks on
the api targeting mobile clients and
successful all at the same time right no
one's that lucky all the time um so it
goes on to the next year our favorite
year 2020 the year of covid um and uh
june of 2020 it could go on and on but
here's something just two weeks ago uh
mom this is also in the news on
september 17th so this uh this paper um
this article came out saying api's
lacking authentication controls can
allow anyone including threat actors to
potentially hit sensitive information
and two-thirds if you read the title
called this article two-thirds of um
misconfigured api i'm sorry two-thirds
of cloud breaches which is why we're
also a cloud company not as api
two-thirds of cloud breaches are because
of misconfigured apis
and i'm going to show you how that's
successful that's the whole point of our
talk today is that is something we've
been known knowing about 2016. this
hacker group in 2019 knew about it two
years ago and now the rest of us are
catching up um obviously this article
and one thing if you're into api
security you're probably something aware
of the bola attack bro broken object uh
something authentication it's a great
attack i love it very sophisticated
very research oriented right um and
that's why i'm not going to talk about
it today because it's not the cause of
data breaches data breaches are
happening much ha much easier uh than
bola and ebola is great i love it but
it's a researcher exploit um apis uh are
being breached in a much easier way and
you can see from this article uh
two-thirds of cloud data breaches are
because of the api so i cannot agree
with uh that more okay so how how did
this happen all right so this is uh this
is the cool stuff right so
um this is what i rece uh that i figured
out back in 2019 was happening so this
is what uh that you can do yourself and
we're going to provide some tools to
allow you to do it yourself as well so
um what we're going to do is we're going
to go to the app store um there's a lot
of ways to do this but i'm going to talk
about how to do this how the hackers did
it in 2019 we're going to go to the app
store we're going to download any app we
want
i'm choosing amazon because it's a
random name that i remembered this
morning there's nothing wrong with
amazon there's nothing wrong with the
app this is just just an app on the app
store so the first thing we're going to
do is take an app from the app store and
we've got to decrypt it
that's step number one
and here's a screenshot of us decrypting
it and i'm going to now share um
a video of us doing that so you can see
it in real time so i'm gonna switch back
and forth uh for your uh pleasure um so
so this is us decrypting uh the amazon
app the amazon app is on the right side
on the ipad and then the left side is
our code and when we're decrypting it
which is um depending on what
technologies you have or how comfortable
you're with it's not very difficult
right so decrypting the app from the app
store uh removing the drm something
pretty standard so so that's done here
um so that's all decrypted and now we're
going to take the decrypted app and put
it on our analyzer farm so i'm going to
go back to the powerpoint
all right
now step two is detecting uh and
basically decompiling the app to get to
its source code remember this is a
binary in a public cloud we call it the
app store but it's still a public cloud
so we took amazon's app from the app
store it could be netflix could be
anyone and we're going to decompile it
and now we're going to go and hunt for
apis so my co-worker ethan who's going
to take over in a second wrote this tool
called api hunter we're going to release
it to you all uh uh to use and play with
afterwards um he wrote a tool called api
hunter that essentially is going to look
for apis in the amazon app right very
simple so i'm going to show that in
action so give me a quick second
all right so here's ethan's tool uh and
so now what he's gonna do
is you can see at the top uh api hunter
is gonna be executed on the amazon app
um a little typo there and now he's
hunting he's uh not threat hunting he's
api hunting so all the apis that he has
identified on the amazon app from its
public binary are showing up here in uh
light green and uh and again we're gonna
show you how to automate this together
but so far we've done nothing special
nothing new no bola attacks
all very simple stuff right um going
through it step by step just so you all
know and so i'm going to go back to my
slides so so far we've taken the app
from the app store we ran api hunter on
it and we got some apis right all good
now here's the clever part this is the
clever part and i applaud this hacker
group that do this two years because
remember what i said about efficiency in
the beginning of this what they did is
they took
the amazon or any app today and they sat
on it they didn't do anything and this
is clever this is why hackers are very
efficient and then the next release of
the app or maybe three releases now they
did a diff
um and they looked at the app from three
months ago to today and then they
figured out what's new what are the new
apis and this is why hackers are so
clever the reason they were targeting
only the new apis in a big or large
organization or big or small
organization what's usually going out
the door
has a liar six a higher success ratio of
being hacked
than something that's been in the app
for years right and the reason about
that is because developers have a lot of
control now they can push out code and
the security team
may be behind if it doesn't have a
product to look at that code in real
time it could be missing new apis are
happening or they're being released out
to the public so if you're a hacker and
you want to get in and get out and not
waste your time you're going to target
the new apis only
and not the old ones because the success
uh rate of a targeting new apis is much
higher than something that's been there
forever so so um ethan has done that as
well
so let me go ahead and show that
sorry let me just share
that slide
all right so this is a demo of his tool
and now he's uh basically finding the
new apis the brand new apis uh from
um diffing the old amazon app here in
april to the one from today and so the
only thing that his tool is going to
show is the new stuff from today and
this is what you're going to target with
your attack script to go basically get
some large amounts of data so this is
all automated like this is all the new
attack surface bam i have a new attack
surface and the likelihood that i can
attack this is much higher than
something again that's been there
forever
all right
all right so at this point all you have
to do is connect to the apis you connect
to the apis now this is the sample part
the next part i'm showing you is all
sample uh this has nothing to do with
the amazon app but this is the type of
data those hackers are getting in 2019
and 2020. they were getting first name
last name username password password has
social security number all they did is
do a diff of the binary found the new
apis immediately connected to those new
apis and bam they compromise large
portions of data so that article i
showed you have two thirds of data
breaches are happening on the cloud
because of apis this is how it's
happening it's not some sophisticated
multi-step triple bank shop bola attack
it's hackers targeting the brand new
stuff the stuff that's straight off the
assembly line connecting to them at
scale and getting data
at uh uh that can be sensitive not all
the data is going to be sensitive but
the data that they're getting uh one out
of ten and they just need to have it
once is going to be uh is for their case
sensitive and so the beauty of this is
attack is if you're a hacker um what did
you do you decrypted you differed you
connected you extract you can script
that like i showed it to you one by one
but you can script that to do it
automatically and then you can target
literally millions of apis millions of
mobile apps on the app store and play
store millions of single page app and
serverless the attack target is so huge
that if you don't target one company you
can target thousands and millions with
this script and again this is what the
hacker community was doing for api
security um so i'm going to shift gears
a little bit and i hand it over to ethan
to talk about the science of these tools
we're going to release these tools right
after this talk so ethan would you mind
talking about the details of these
please
thanks so much
so what we're looking at here is the
python script that performs that initial
analysis that you showed where we find
all the apis within the decrypted
application bundle and like you said on
launch this is this is really easy stuff
there's nothing complex here so what the
script is doing we look at every file
that's within an application bundle
applications are made up of a lot of
files binary files sdks text files
images we'll search through every file
of the netapplication bundle and use the
strings command to dump the list of
streams that are in each of those files
so that gets us the entire list of
strings within each of those files in
the bundle
now from there we're going to use a
regex expression against those strings
to narrow that full list of strings down
to items that look like they might be
apis uh they have http https cool and
they follow the general url format now
we don't need them to have api or any
specific keywords in there to look for
the regex expression is pretty
comprehensive in that so when we run
this against the application bundle it
prints out the list of every single uh
url within the bundle it looks like it
may be an api but keep in mind this is a
simple regex expression so we we don't
expect the results to be perfect we
expect some of the findings that we get
out of this to
um you know maybe they're not reachable
or anything so that's why it's important
to follow up this step by attempting to
connect to each of those apis that you
found
so what we're seeing here is um you know
kind of a flow chart that describes
uh you know given a potential api if a
connection is made to that api and the
resulting status code is 404 not found
that means we can ignore it it's not a
real api it's not reachable it's a waste
of time right
now if it redirects or we get some other
type of server error those are also
indicators that this is not a real url
or a real api
now if we get a 200 to 209 that's all
good right that means that we were able
to connect successfully no problems
if we get a 403 which is an
authentication error that's still a
green light if we get a 403 that means
that we found a real api and we tried to
connect to it and it just told us no you
can't connect here without a password
remember we're doing api inventory here
so we only care about figuring out which
apis are real and valid not necessarily
worrying about the authentication scheme
of them those can come later
all right so another example of running
that python script that i just described
against an app bundle and you can see
here that pointed it to
an application called apollo.app and it
printed out all of these streams that
look to be
uh apis these are in specific for the
reddit website but um you'll notice not
all of them contain api some of them
have
weird formatting some of them may not be
urls so again that's why it's important
to connect to these to validates
sorry
all right so what we're looking at here
is the output like like montre said
shadow apis are a great target if you
want to uh you know save time and only
target impactful new apis and the way
you find these is using that same script
i just described to dump the list of
apis out of uh you know one version of
the application you're going to do the
exact same thing but with a different
version of the application so there is
requirements here that you've held on to
uh you know a decrypted version of this
app it's a little bit older than when
you have now and you're able to run the
script against both of those bundles
and then with the resulting
urls you get from each of these you diff
them and the diff is the net new apis
apis that have been recently added to
the application and i like a month you
said there was a probably a lot less
scrutiny on the apis that just popped up
in apps yesterday versus the apis that
have been in the application since it
shipped a few years ago so if a hacker
is really trying to save time and you
know root someone in 15 minutes or less
targeting these shadow apis is really a
great strategy to go towards
yeah and thank you ethan and and this
technique is not new um emma what ethan
and the team observed and what we found
from this hacker community and what we
do at data theorem is cool stuff on new
api tech but this technique actually
came from the 90s like uh
if i can date myself when a microsoft
and yes that used to be an operating
system everyone used um when they used
to come up with a service pack what you
do is you take that service pack and you
essentially
look at what the service pack is
updating in the os and that's where you
know to look for if there's any security
changes in the os and that's how you
know there's an exploit and if you're if
you're a gray hat um you're essentially
right a worm in the 90s and that's how
all these worms became successful
because service pack 2 service pack 3
would patch a security issue and um and
no one upgraded service packs for six
months and hence you have a worm so this
technique is not new it's just being
applied on apis now within 15 minutes
and you can see from 2019 to all the way
to two weeks ago it's still successful
so so in summary um the way to to make
sure you as a researcher uh can find
this use our tools or use this technique
uh uh and and and implement this don't
stop doing security research we do it
all the time but don't forget about the
efficient hacker they want data they get
in they get out and they do it at scale
and if you're on the other side on the
protection side inventory your apis just
like the hackers are doing and test for
authentication authorization as much as
possible um and that's that i think i i
think we're out of time and so if
there's questions uh my coworker uh
um alex uh uh we'll all be in the uh
slack channel and if you want to contact
ethan uh the mastermind of this
presentation um and get his tools feel
free to email us uh at data theorem um
at this point uh i guess we'll uh hand
it back over to the moderator