[Music]
thank you so hi everyone and uh thank
you for joining this session it's hardly
a secret that the development of secure
software can be a formidable undertaking
the application software can be riddled
with
many security vulnerabilities and they
can pose a significant and serious
a risk a to organizations and their
clients
but a
vulnerability remediation consequently
become a cardinal part
of the overall software development
workbook if you will uh but that being
said the remediation of all the
vulnerabilities a in a proprietary code
is not only an
operos process but at times it could be
downright unfeasible and the reason is
that contrary to a vulnerability
detection that over the past few years
has largely become a
an automated process
a automatic remediation is is not so
so the purpose of this session is to
unravel if you will a some of the
important aspects that underlie the
concept of auto remediation and in doing
so they helped help clarify
how organizations can
not only a promote and help their
developers and boost their productivity
but rather help the developers
realize a first-rate experience where
they can alleviate the remediation
burden ameliorate the process and
accelerate the remediation completion
we have three main parts in our session
here i'll start with the the challenges
some of the challenges that concern
manual remediation and it will be a good
start to underscore the value of auto
remediation then i'll move to highlight
concepts and the a number of examples
concerning a the workflow of auto
remediation and finally we will bring up
a couple of
challenges
with regard to auto remediation
some of the people i know
i believe that
considering the question that is brought
up front they they would probably say
that
now
there's probably no reasonable way to
expect this to happen but obviously that
would have nothing to do with
remediation they simply have no
familiarity with the concept of
developer happiness but seriously i
think that when anyone wishes to discuss
the
idea underlying remediation and auto
remediation in particular one needs to
fathom when
does vulnerability remediation begin
many would intuitively and spontaneously
say that well
we have some a fix already in hand and
then let's apply it and that makes
perfect sense unless of course you
consider that in many cases dealing with
remediation starts much earlier when you
have this strange and the unsettling
sensation that something went awry and
you need to deal with that well
i would argue that remediation should
basically start from that point and
obviously any guidance that we would
have in our disposal could be extremely
helpful but regardless of the level of
help that guidance would provide
it still places the onus on running the
actual change alteration or update a
remediation in other words with the
hands of the developer
the apsec personnel or as the evidence
shows us commonly in both hands and
that's in a way contributes to a level
of noise that
doesn't necessarily help facilitate the
overall process i think this sets a good
stage to highlight yet another question
at this point is remediation strictly a
technical matter we will discuss that as
we move through the
the process of this presentation but i
would really appreciate if you could
keep that in the back of your heads it's
definitely one of the themes underlying
this session
so what are the key
challenges that one could associate with
remediation in general i think that
basically one could highlight them as
being three main issues scale knowledge
and clarity or perhaps lack thereof with
regard to the first item here i think
that one of the items that pops to mind
has to do with the fact that there is a
discrepancy between the a bandwidth
associated with development compared to
that of apsec now
some people will probably consider
having a ratio of 10 to 1 to be pretty
optimistic and they would be right but
in most cases this is really an
optimistic case because the ratio
observed is more likely to be something
in the neighborhood of 50 to 100 to 1
and i must say that even 1 000 to 1
extreme as it may sound is not
unfortunately an outlier
moving on to the to the question of
security acumen i think that it gets
accentuated here because given the
inexorable amount in march of technology
security is a moving target and
it is not a given to possess the
knowledge associated with security that
would be of demand whenever we need to
deal with remediation so relegating such
a responsibility to people who might not
possess this type of knowledge is not
only a daunting experience for them but
they could prove to be extremely
ineffective let alone inefficient
and finally when we look at the last
item on this list noise well noise is
probably a byproduct of having yet
another facet that incurs a
certain level of overhead and that is
whenever we have false positive results
they definitely do not contribute to the
process of remediation because even
though we might end up with a proper
remediation so to say to such a case
what way what did we manage actually to
solve it's a false positive and it adds
more noise rather than reducing that
i think that to complement this picture
it would be of extreme value to a look
at some of the operational challenges
that developers are most likely facing
and the
even though
probably some of you may not necessarily
associate each and every one of the
items in this list is something that
they're more familiar with
i i would contend that for the most part
there is a lot of similarity and i'm not
going to discuss each and every one of
those items i'm probably going to just
run through that hoping that you will
find some way to get yourself immersed
in the process here because
unfortunately this is something that
many many developers if not all need to
spend time over at some point from
reviewing an issue when it pops up and
hopefully being able to prioritize that
in a sensible manner trying to validate
the issue that they have just to make
sure that it may it
is not necessarily a false positive then
and this is a a critical part
researching the correct fix approach
this is anything but a given it's not
straightforward and it requires an
immense amount of focus dedication and
as i already mentioned knowledge now
this
by all means is not the most difficult
part because in my opinion once you
happen to have something that looks good
enough then you need to establish what
would be the preferred way to fix the
issue at hand and finally if this were
to be the only issue then comes the next
one which is confirming that the fix
just being applied is actually the
correct one if there is any any stamina
left at this moment one would be
expected to record the fixed details so
that not just for posterity but even for
the particular case of that user in
order for a next issue coming up and
happening to and and just a having the
similar enough profile would not require
us to go through all of this profit all
of this process this regular rigmarole
again
what is the effort for a single fix now
i know that some of you just inspecting
this figure would
go back and say come on this is not a
realistic figure but as it so happens
studies may show that this is actually a
very viable indication of the time it
would take should you actually
encapsulate the time each of these
processes that are outlined here
are a provided and then concatenate them
into a single chunk that is a very
optimistic thing because as most of you
obviously know there is a very diff a
very large difference between the time
it would take to deal directly with an
issue at hand and the time it would most
likely take for the issue since it to a
go through the process from where it was
discovered and up until it is fully
solved in such a case we're not talking
about half a day we're not talking about
half a week we're not even talking about
half a month and to be honest and
unfortunately in some cases we are not
even talking about half a year this is
probably one of the more uh deplorable
aspects of dealing with remediation
without using some kind of a process but
rather a betting on a best practices so
to say that might enable us to deal with
them in what is hoped to be a mostly a
mostly optimistic approach
i think that part of the key problem
here is that even though it is presented
as a list there is a lot of creativity
associated with this thing and this is
really the perfect place to move to the
next item here which is well what
automatic remediation is all about
in my opinion
it's really about transforming what i
consider to be the art of remediation
into a best practice
yes indeed dealing currently with
remediation has many facets that are
redolent of re of art we need to be it
we we are subjecting the process to a
sincere level of interpretation it is
not consistent it is also
unpredictable and it definitely does not
give you any guarantee of the end
results now some of these facets might
not seem that alarming but when we are
looking at the organizational scope of
the issue we would definitely prefer
there to be a process that would provide
us with some level of guarantee here
so what is the promise of auto
remediation
aside from outlining what you see here
as the three main items i think that
first and foremost it's about better
software security and it's not really
just about providing a point solution to
a given problem if you look at the first
item here that is captured standardized
fixed approach it's about providing some
way to facilitate the process of
remediation not just to provide an end
solution or something that could be
simply pasted on top of the problem that
we have why is it because it is
ultimately believed that we are not just
carrying out a mundane effort or
remediating issues but we would like to
get more and more into a state of mind
where remediation is really something
that accompanies the developer it's not
a one-off it's not just something that
you do occasionally it happens to
command a significant part of the
developers or whoever is involved in
such a such an effort of their time and
standardized fixed approach concerns
triaging prioritization things that auto
remediation is definitely associated
with obviously the ability to reduce the
number of unattended issues comes with
comes to no surprise and of course prior
to release agility and productivity are
mainly about combating the security
knowledge gap that was mentioned earlier
but also better allocation of the
bandwidth that is associated with
resources now this is not necessarily
the resources that you may have thought
about and not necessarily pointing at
the developer a developer team here i'm
actually talking about apsec app apsec
is much more restricted in terms of its
bandwidth and being able to focus to
funnel their effort on things that
matter in terms of their complexity
there are many uh security related
facets that do not necessarily
necessitate a a processes that often
take their time and being able to
concentrate their effort on those very
issues would be of extreme value to an
organization and finally it goes without
saying that better team efficiency is a
byproduct of what we have here in order
to reduce the overhead but
i would be a miss if not to mention the
matter of trust here trust is an
important thing because developers even
though the pro the promise of auto
remediation is alluring it is enticing
developers let's be frank
might not necessarily
accept that easily let alone countenance
let alone endorse it and the reason is
because there is a trust barrier
there would be some concern about
whether or not a a process that
autonomously pushes changes into our
code would not
perhaps inadvertently wreak havoc in our
cherished code base that is something
that developers are less likely to er to
cope with and
auto remediation must
must be designed to accommodate that
requirement can that be done most likely
how here are some of the ideas that
could probably give you foot of thought
how auto remediation could consider
making a contribution on the
trustworthiness front
it starts from being there simply being
there it should not be just on demand as
a reactive approach that many might
consider to be sensible it needs to pop
up and to be proactive whenever it
senses that there is something that is
worthy of providing some insight i
actually went ahead of myself because
inside is part of the items that you
will see in a moment accuracy is not
just about providing the right fix that
would be really go it goes without
saying we're talking about noise here
not adding noise but actually being able
to reduce noise
an ambiguity is a critical part here
because
providing more than just one option for
a fix is not necessarily bad as long as
they do not compete with each other and
as long as they make perfect sense as
far as what they aim to achieve is
understood by the developer
i mentioned insightfulness earlier and
the idea here is that when when you look
at a human a advisor
you would probably make
make a point that the
trustworthiness of a human advisor lies
to a great deal in an ability to give
you something to think about that you
may not have necessarily thought about
earlier that particular genetic genes
acquire that is a one of the a i would
say the low stones of a trustworthiness
that's interesting i'd like to use that
i would like to actually approach that
person next time because their way of
thinking is is very collaborable it
actually connects very well with what
i'm trying to achieve having that
ability as part of auto remediation is
not science fiction it's actually
something that goes hand in hand with
the experience that a solution can come
up with because when you observe what
took place from the earliest point in
time when the solution was brought into
play having that perspective could
provide you with the ability to provide
suggestions that garner more trust from
the end user
but all of this would really be
worthless if not for the ability to
drive results and that's why it's
captured as it is
let's see a couple of examples here the
first example is a concerns injection
and you can see here how the
how a a particular piece of data the
user name has been entered and is
expected to be used as part of a sql
query to the database another another
example which is
similar in spirit although here we have
something more closer to a path
traversal a vulnerability is the case
where still we have something that is
obtained from outside of the application
but here in this case the file name is
to be sent to a certain target now
despite the similarities what actually i
would like to point at is the fact that
in both of those cases we have something
that entered the system and is being
used the big question here is whether or
not the developer placed the proper
neutralization of the potential damage
or vulnerability what is otherwise
commonly known as sanitization
as part of the process here in this
particular example which is really
pseudo code you can see that it is not
so and from the source to the sink a
critical part that is missing is the
sanitizer the sanitizer would be
expected to be something pretty
straightforward right at least with
those who are less familiar with the
overall concept of a remediation however
when we need to deal with automatic
remediation this issue becomes much more
significant because here there are much
more questions that need be not just
asked but answered as well how should
sanitation sanitization look like
importantly where should it be placed
how should new arguments be inserted how
should sanitization be annotated and can
sanitization inadvertently changed the
logic of the application
most developers don't really or perhaps
even can't give a second thought about
preserving such a knowledge and that
actually comes into play when you look
at the approaches that are currently
used leveraged
to provide remediation facilitated
remediation in a traditional manner goes
from explaining explaining the security
issue to highlighting the issue a
location then comes the key part
guidance how you should really address
that and in many cases i would say that
it is an apotheosis of you know the
the
a
when you when you want to provide
something uh that explains the issue but
it ends up confounding the person and
providing something that is not
necessarily helping which is actually
something pretty similar to what i
inadvertently did right now finally we
have the example the example is
something that is expected to provide
the highlight here here is the aha
moment here is how one needs to deal
with the issue however
i call this the training approach
because the training approach bombards
the end user with a lot of information a
virtual flashlight a
virtual a magnifying glass
presentations research material
everything which is unfortunately and
honestly irrelevant to what most of the
developers would be looking at that
point their aim is not to become an
expert their aim is to solve the matter
at hand and the way things need to be
adopted and this is how automatic
remediation
is sets out to do is
is embracing a developer's standpoint a
developer perspective
where you actually aim to have some kind
of understanding what the issue was what
the impact is projected to be and
importantly and it's not just placed
here on the top of the head it's
actually confirmation that we have
something that will work
the high level view of the process here
would look very familiar to most of you
it starts with the coding moving to the
build process then having the system
automatically run a scan which will then
divulgate to something that combines
triaging with a generation of tickets
the remediation process and finally
ending up with the details that we see
on our screens
the detailed view of that would have a
detection facility next to the
remediation and more particularly the
auto remediation part
the purpose of the detection is to be
the source truth for cwe detection which
is another way of saying that the
details concerning the variables the
sources the sinks and the metadata
associated associated with them needs be
provided to auto remediation or
remediation is a consumer of such
information and as you can see here the
way things could be extracted from
detection here could be through a
variety of formats serif being just one
mere example for doing so with the
details concerning profile code location
code race among other things the main
purpose of auto remediation would be to
come up with the analysis and
recommendations not just for the
solution but for the annotations for the
placement and for what kind of actions
need be placed in order to streamline
the process into fruition and finally
the information will be passed on to
whatever choice the end user made
whether it is ide integration or through
the ci cd like a integration where you
have a pull request and there is an
optional item here which is to actually
carry out validation for the recommended
auto remediation fix so that you could
make it you could be sure that
everything was closed very neatly
let's now move to a slightly more
detailed example than the one we've seen
earlier in this case this is no longer
pseudo code now we're seeing a java code
where it is very similar in spirit to
what we've seen earlier but with a bit
more detail to it and here again we see
the external part that needs to be
neutralized in this case it's called you
name and we have the connection object
that
happens to be the a focus of the query a
method on top of that now as you can
tell here
there is no proper sanitization of
anything
the main objective of an auto
remediation would carry out changes that
will end up being
modifying the exhaust the code so that
some of the items would be removed other
items would be added now
those of you who may not
probably give a second look at the
details here might say this looks to be
pretty straightforward right well even
though this is a pretty simplistic case
i would like to point you at some of the
nuances here that are anything but
trivial for instance first of all
thinking about the approach even though
in this particular case we see the use
of a prepared statement which is a way
of using something that could sanitize
by virtue of a pre-compiled statement
that then could not be uh could not
could not be exploited by the external
input because it would only be limited
to the
parameter that is in question and this
is by the way a means that could be used
not necessarily for sanitization
but for performance reasons as well but
there could be other approaches here one
could consider sanitization of the
external input one could even focus
their efforts on authorization
mechanisms that could reduce
significantly the likelihood for
vulnerability exploits in this case but
let's go back to the example that we
have here and look very closely into the
details you will see that not only were
just mere sentences removed and replaced
by other things there was a very careful
attention here to make use of similar
variables and those variables need to be
placed in some cases within parenthesis
of a methods that were not
trivially or made available earlier so
the decision that needs to come into
play here and again keep in mind this is
an automated process so being able to
make sure that this is done and here
comes the real crux in a manner that
will not look as if a machine did it it
must look as if the developer actually a
developer suggested those changes
so
i think that by looking into such an
example and understanding by the way it
might appear as a casual thing but even
the placement of this of of the new
lines of code here is not just a
serendipitous it just happens to reflect
the particular way of thought that the
application was expected and that is
part of the reason that you can see line
112 here which really serves no purpose
other than than just saying that the
application should be able to look into
the workflow and make a conscious
decision where exactly needs a to place
the actual new a
code of course there are cases where
auto remediation would fit better
than others
and among the
usual suspects we would find cases where
standard sanitizers are being used
obviously that would definitely lift up
the chance the chances for having a
better a remediation because it would
obviously and arguably at least in my
opinion a lift the chances for accuracy
uh the more accurate the solutions are
from the detection system the less
likely remediation could falter but
there are other aspects as well if it is
possible to constrain or to at least
focus the remediation effort on the area
that could be detected prior to build
not that the value of auto remediation
for dynamically detected issues is gain
said it is not so at all but
being able to run processes on things
that could be statically analyzed gives
a very sensible a and decent a
percentage for success here and aside
from that there are some other things
such as remediation location if for
instance there is a preference by the
organization to have a sanitizer that is
located external to the component in
question and the reason being that they
opt for an approach where they have a
central sanitization mechanism instead
of sanitizing wherever there could be a
vulnerability that's a viable approach
but in order to have that addressed by
auto remediation auto remediation must
be smart enough if you will to
consider that or to
fathom that as part of its process and
finally definitely not least we have
here the
consideration of running auto
remediation as close as possible to the
detection phase obviously as time goes
by changes will lurk within the code and
no longer the results from the detection
step may apply
so
there are actually also more client
consideration just very quickly i would
say that the time of a timing of auto
remediation is a pretty critical you can
opt for having it done as close as
possible as part of the environment the
user is actually leveraging the ide but
of course you would probably lack
context and the later you could provide
it even though you're still shifting
left would be of enormous value here
another thing is implementation would
you prefer an ide or a pull request
these are preferences
i mentioned earlier that one of the key
ideas in my opinion for all remediation
kind of transforms us from art into a
best practice this is by no means a
statement that says there should be no
no sense of art or if you will
interpretation or creativity within the
process and i kind of use this
this
reference calling it a concerto in a
major for keyboard and orchestra sorry
orchestration it would be more a apt in
this case and similar in spirit to a
concerto we have three parts here
starting with the quick one where we run
the automation then we move to some
place which is a bit
more imperturbable it is with the advice
you consider that and finally to the
alternatives automation or movement one
if you will is really about avoiding
noise the advice phase or movement is
about not dismissing the value of
remediation guidance and ability to
annotate changes this is definitely a
part of what we would like to provide
here and alternatives well this goes to
the preferences being allowed for
remediation application style and
preferences of display as well as the
ide and pull request
to summarize
remediation of security issues is indeed
one of the most challenging aspects of
development but
it is so because it demands security
acumen and substantial resources that
are anything but given auto remediation
can enable a significant amount of
productive
impetus but
it will also increase hopefully and
likely the team productivity
and finally auto remediation can realize
and that was probably the most important
thing better software security and it
will do so by reducing the unattended
issue count significantly
thank you