[Music]
um hi again my name is miguel a cayez
i'm here to share some lessons learned
of costly ones from serverless computing
so first let's just start with sharing
who we are and a little bit about our
serverless journey
so veritol is a startup in the tolling
and transportation industry we believe
in bringing innovation to the industry
by leveraging
mobile crowd source and cloud-based
technologies
in order to bring this innovation to the
industry we also need innovative
technologies and that's how we landed on
serverless
with serverless we're allowed to focus
on application development and
develop rapidly and deploy rapidly we
can do it with less
infrastructure than typically done
with server-based approach we can also
reduce our maintenance overhead
throughout the software development life
cycle and if properly designed we can
lower our costs as well
so some of you may be wondering what
serverless is serverless is a technology
that allows you
to
deploy applications without having to
manage the server
some wonder well how can you have
technology without a server and i agree
there's got to be a server somewhere
within the technology stack but the
point is
we don't have to
provision it we don't have to configure
it we don't have to manage it we don't
have to secure it
there's underlying technology there that
we just need to upload our
function code or our configuration
and we can then focus on developing the
application putting all the pieces
together
so it makes development a lot quicker
um so just give you an idea of what
serverless looks like
we built audito one of our platforms
using amazon web services so we have a
serverless website and a serverless
backend
so for the website we're leveraging
three
major services on aws or route 53 for
domain name service dns
s3 for
hosting our object storage
and cloudfront for a content delivery
network or cdn
so what happens when
a
user goes to our web application
autotold.io
route53 resolves that to an ip address
that ip address
then gets redirected to
cloudfront to does cdn
if the desired content is already been
cached at the edge then it just serves
that cache content
really quickly back to the web app
in the event that it's not cached it
goes to
s3 obtains the content and then serves
it back to the web application
now our website also needs a backend
and our mobile app
uses a back-end as well
we do this by leveraging three other aws
services api gateway for defining api
endpoints using the rest restful designs
lambda for serverless functions and
dynamodb for serverless database tables
so what happens when the mobile app or
the website need to get data from the
backend they make an api call that gets
set to api gateway
api gateway will then forward that
request event to a lambda function
the function will process the event and
do what it needs to it may need to read
or write to a database and send data
back
so once it does
its execution it sends the data back to
the gateway and the gateway sends it
back to the mobile app or website
so hopefully this gives you a feel for
what serverless looks like and how a
typical service serverless design
uh
is is implemented
so here's the bulk of the talk i'm going
to share some some lessons learned so
there's going to be a structure to this
we're going to have a category and
describe the scenario the lesson we
learned
the remediation we put
in place to address our finding
and conclude with some risk and
mitigations you you can
take away to avoid similar scenarios
the first category is inputs of oauth
serverless top 10
identified
input injection as the number one uh
top security risk
so in this scenario what we had is we
had
an api endpoint that
gets uh sends data to lambda function
and it reads from a database
and we found that this database changes
very frequently so it doesn't change
very often
we implemented api gateway cache so that
once the api request comes the gateway
can serve it right back similar to what
a cdn does that way it doesn't ever have
to
do a lambda function call and a database
read in
for most situations but there were times
when the database did get updated and we
don't want to serve old cache data
so we had a different process in place
where when the database is updated it
would send an update event to a lambda
function
the lambda function will then say oh i
got an update i'm going to click i want
to send a request to the api gateway and
have it clear as cache
seems pretty straightforward right what
we found was that there was accidental
injection attacks that we weren't
expecting
for whatever reason sometimes aws would
send the lambda function old events so
the table had not been updated recently
but yet it was still sending all the
events
uh that the london function uh that
shouldn't have should have not
happened so the function was saying oh i
got an event and send the
a a clear cash request to the gateway oh
got another one clear cash player class
it was happening so many times in a very
short period of time
and the api gateway ended up getting so
overwhelmed i said
i'm not making any more i'm not
accepting any more requests and even
from api endpoints over http using the
restful protocol
ended up turning into a self-induced
denial of service attack
yikes
so we had some outages that we were not
planning
so to remediate this what we ended up
putting in place was uh we've had the
function do input validation according
to
the number one risk
recommendation to mitigate that so the
only process the newest events we also
had to land the function keep track of
when the last
cache clearing happened and limit it to
every five even five minutes so that you
can only clear the cache once every five
minutes to avoid
overwhelming the api gateway
so this kind of describes how you can
avoid input injection
attacks even accidental ones
just as a side note we ended up
determining that the lat the database
only gets updated during the release
process
based on some configuration parameters
and build specific changes
so we went away from this paradigm that
we have here in the diagram and started
using serverless plugins and when there
was a release in the cicd pipeline
the the serverless plugin would make the
api call to the gateway and say clear
the cache
because the database was being updated
at that time during the release
so we mentioned some of the risk
so code injection it could be sql
commands
aws
commands uh graphql if you're using like
the appsync
func
service
that there's a nested uh recursive
attack this really
awesome demo from the oauths
uh ca uh hapsac cali 2019 that shows
that demo how it turned into like a
couple minute long execution and a
thousand times it ended up being several
thousand dollar cost
um so regular expression attacks and
if there's a bad input it could result
in an unexpected 500 error if if not
planned properly so to mitigate make
sure you always validate your inputs do
safety deserve it and deserialize your
inputs like json
and make sure you have safe regular
expressions if in the event there is
a code ejection attack that makes it
through make sure you have the lowest
identity and access management
privileges so that it cannot execute any
unintended functions take advantage of
great tools that are built into ides or
as plugins put them into the cacd
pipeline to do linting and static code
analysis and
take advantage of try catch blocks you
can
exit gracefully when
a
bad input makes it through
so the next one is on rate limiting
well typical for most multi-factor
two-step verification we had a we had
implemented a mobile app for client so
user needed to log in and send the api
request to the gateway
then it gets sent to the function the
function then verifies the username and
password against the identity provider
awesome
if it's successful that any provider
sends a two-digit code via sms to the
phone the user then
entered the six digit code
sent the api request function verifies
against the identity provider
cool all successful the user is logged
in and gets the json web token back uh
to have the session
on the application
well uh we found during penetration
testing that uh
the process the business object looks
good but there was a
unexpected flaw in the design someone
could do a brute force attack try a
million codes and
bypass the
two-step verification
yikes
what we did to remedy this is we did a
rate limiting at the api gateway so only
a certain number of requests can make it
through in any given minute and also do
lockouts if it fails let's say
after three failed attempts either the
username and password
or the
verification code then it would do a
lockout and you couldn't log in for
do another attempt for a period of time
we also decided to do a moving target if
in the event that the incorrect code was
sent uh it would then send another
six digit code so that there's always a
moving target you couldn't just
pick uh try to get the same code
so
but i'm not having
limiting
your application could be vulnerable to
brute force attacks bot scraping or
analyzing your application
and
various denial service attacks um and
the costly part is you could have a cost
spike that could
increase your cost
and if it's an extended period time it
can be very costly
so the way to help mitigate against
these things is to have web application
firewalls you can put a waf in front of
your web application and also in front
of the api to help reduce
brute forcing bots
and all service attacks
also wanted to mention that you should
be monitoring um usage
errors
uh and all uh just understanding what
your application is doing and your
billing so that you can
know when something anomalous is
happening you can uh
address it right away and avoid an uh a
surprise bill later on
all right so over provisioning um just
for simplicity and just to keep the
configuration on our assembler
serverless framework file looking clean
we had defaulted to
default
compute size default timeouts and set a
standard read write provision for the
database
well
what we found was if
sometimes bugs sneak into releases
and
when and when they go live all of a
sudden you have all these errors popping
up and it could be
many
error errors being
realized
and if you have the maximum compute and
the maximum timeout well you're going to
be paying for all that execution time
and it gets more expensive the longer
and the bigger the compute size is
and same thing with provision read write
capacity if you
just for simplicity make it a big
amount of provision that well you have
to you're going to be paying for that
while it's happening so that can get
really costly as well
so to remedy these situations we
understood how each function
executes
and try to optimize it so sometimes
having low memory or low cpu
is fine if the function does very simple
things but sometimes it's better to pay
for more compute and memory
uh
uh if the function is intensive
yeah so if yeah maybe more costly at the
compute side the execution time is
smaller and so it kind of offsets and
ends up being more cost efficient
then also understanding how long a
function typically executes
and then understanding
uh how long
what's the maximum amount of time it
should need before it
it times out sometimes you can do it
during unit testing or integration
testing that
in certain
bogus or erroneous inputs to see how the
functions execute
with an error so then that way you can
if a function
typically takes two seconds maybe you
could cap it off four
seconds uh so that's usually the longest
it would need to execute for an error
for a database
we decided to move to on-demand we had
very spike key traffic so there was no
need to have constant provision
resources
read write
so
the having
to pay more per write and read requests
ended up being more cost efficient
and
then having a dedicated amount um
something to keep in mind though with if
there is
if you're not doing rate limiting on
your functions that read and write
against database
a cost spike or an attack could be
expensive so something just uh tying it
back to rate limiting
that's a mitigation for on-demand
database region write capacity units
so we talked about the risk
for just the mitigations understand how
your application functions and size it
appropriately
so for over privileged policies again
this is a a risk in the serverless top
10.
so what we've
what we what we're doing again
you know just developer simplicity all
the
required
im privileges uh
for every function were put in the
default role and so what that resulted
is functions were now being
given overly permissive policies they
were allowed to do things that we're not
supposed to do so for example this one
function is meant to just read a
database
but we found that it could do something
like
modify the im's password policy so you
see on the left side of the function
there's a overly permissive
policy there i made it admin just to get
the point across
that
if you have
overly permissive or admin privileges
some bad things can happen so what we
did is we crafted some malicious intent
a remote execution attack we were able
to successfully
modify the im password policies that's
that's not good
um so what we decided to do was to stop
using the default role and do one i am
role per function so that the policy was
limited to what it was done so you see
the
the the the change on the left hand side
in the json that it it's this function
is only allowed to query and it's only
allowed to query a specific table
so that way when we tried the malicious
remote execution attack again we were
not able to modify the i am
the i am password policy
uh so the risk of having over over
permissive over privileged policies and
roles is that a malicious actor can
do execution attacks get do lateral
movements
through out your aws infrastructure
could need to account take over
take account takeovers and data leakage
i believe the
capital one breach from a couple years
ago was a result of
over permissive
i am policies
so we mentioned
some uh i mentioned the
remediations those are mitigations you
can put in place
i highly encourage leveraging
temporary credentials of aws has a
service called security token service
where it could issue
a limited lifetime credentials rather
than having an an access key that lives
on forever until revoked
and it's set let's say to
uh has wild cards all over its palace uh
policy
you can just do
if you can least privileged uh but even
if it's admin or very permissive
it's short-lived like 15 minutes now
that way and your ci cd pipeline and
even on your own developer machine you
can keep the policy
short-lived uh active short and
short-lived
another thing we found that was really
costly was failure
not keeping track of aws
service outages and failures in our
application
as great as these cloud providers can be
they they do experience outages um
and
so if we're not aware that there's an
outage and we're not keeping track of
let's say 500 errors as a result of an
outage or 500 errors as a result of a
bot attack
it can have cost implications it could
affect uh result in data loss
in one of our
client applications we found that it was
an aws outage in for over an hour and we
were losing pricing data so we couldn't
our bill our customers accurately and
that's bad
that's not good
so we started monitoring
when when aws went down do some internal
monitoring as well to see if we see if
we can detect it before aws reports it
officially
uh keeping track of one 500 errors and
we started exploring
multi-region design so if let's say
north virginia was down in aws and and
ohio was functioning our application can
still keep running
that comes in handy when uh let's
if uh so related to multi-region you can
do multi-cloud designs as well um
summer of 2020 azure had an outage in
every region i think for
you know an hour or two
and so if you if your application was
solely hosted on azure your application
would be down completely but let's say
if you had uh design it so that it can
run on google cloud and also on aws
your then
can still be running maybe in a degraded
state but it'd still be up
uh so some of the risks we mentioned uh
we experienced data loss uh an attacker
can use
uh 500 messages
for reconnaissance so if we're not
tracking that there are spikes in 500
messages we may we not may not realize
that our applications being investigated
um
but i just recommend using monitoring
and learning to be aware of that this is
happening and for your clients
leverage local storage a web
the web browsers and mobile apps have
local storage and session storage and
secure storage you can put your data
there first and then make the api call
and if the api call fails it'll still be
stored locally
so that the next time the server is back
up you can try again to write the data
lastly i want to conclude with cost
engineering so it's just
cost engineering is the exercise of
understanding your costs understanding
how your application works and how you
can keep your application functioning as
efficiently as possible with the lowest
amount of cost
so it's related to
many of the things we've
already
presented earlier
so in this example we launched a
serverless
application
and when and it went operational and as
we started
adding more customers we
we started seeing slight cost increase
and then it
noticed the cost was increasing
significantly by june
of that year and
by about time we
started look thinking about doing
something about it it was july
so it
our peak this is relative cost so the
the peak is in in june and that's the
highest cost so we decided to understand
what our application how our application
was designed and how we can keep our
costs low
so we started doing a cost engineering
exercise in july and by august it's that
we started seeing lower costs and we
kept contin continuing to do that over
over uh
two to three months
and and by
uh
by october we were
at 98 of the cost from the peak in june
so we found this to be very powerful
that
we didn't have to change very much in
our application
just with some optimization
we can still have the same
level uh same design and same
level of quality for application but at
98 of our cost and that's huge that's
that that can be a game changer
especially if you're trying to run lean
and mean
so just uh just as mentioned there's it
can be expensive and cost
by
not doing cost engineering you may be
paying for more than what you need to
so some things you can do to help with
cost engineering is to do price analysis
now there may be
some services that
similar enough
either within the same cloud provider
across different cloud providers and one
one may be cheaper and still provide the
same
benefits and may still meet your
requirements
so you can just choose the less
expensive one
recommend doing stress tests on your
system before
making it
live putting it into production that way
you can see how your system reacts when
it's under a load and you can catch
potential cost spikes in advance and
actually potentially mitigate them
ahead ahead of time before they even
happen
and as mentioned before just
monitor your application monitor costs
make sure you understand how it's
operating so you can catch anomalies
so in the spirit of 20th anniversary we
want to think
what is veritol trying to achieve for
the next 20 years in the tolling
industry and how to how do we
do that securely
so our goal is to reduce the total cost
to collect for a toll operator so that
they have to only spend a few cents to
collect
their tolls
costs from customers
and so we believe we can do that through
cloud computing especially especially
serverless technologies
serverless allows us to scale up
very quickly and as you saw from cost
engineer we can aim to keep costs
much lower which we can then pass on to
our customers and allow the tolling
agencies the tolling operators to pass
on their cost savings onto their
customers as well maybe in the form of
lower toll payments
we also want to
provide a way a secure way a private uh
uh
to uh people to work off their tools uh
so that
they can use mobile apps and cloud-based
services to
to to earn income to help offset their
total cost
giving them opportunities
maybe for a better job that's further
away from where they live
so as you may
wonder there's going to be a lot of
transactions a lot of processing in the
cloud it's going to be sensitive data
like license plates names addresses
billing information gps data
and so we believe we can do that at
scale with serverless and also do it
securely by leveraging
proper cloud
security principles
so there are many resources out there
for those of you interested in
serverless and serverless security and
how obasp has the top 10. the cloud
security alliance has their their 12 top
12.
there's many good blog posts
on serverless best practices serverless
security there are books on
serverless from a press and o'reilly and
there's the cloud provider documentation
i find it really helpful i read through
that a lot because they in many of their
configuration guides have sections for
how do you configure it how do you do a
proper architecture and even some
security things you keep in mind and
there's github repositories also that
have compilations of serverless content
as well i noted one of them here
so i'd love to hear from you i'll be on
the slack channel to answer any
questions
but do
contact me via email and linkedin
and
uh
i am a published author and i do write a
write i post content on my blog so
check out my site
thank you so much i hope you found this
presentation helpful
and i just want to share that a press
has agreed to do a book giveaway for
serverless security so if you're
interested go to my website go to the
owasp20
address and
enter your email for a chance to win
thanks again