think we're at the time I don't think
well I don't think I'll be introduced
like we're just good to go I'm Ben hey
guys
I really liked reversing stuff with Ray
dare to and I'm really excited to be
here and talk to you guys about some
right air I hope it's gonna be good this
talk was like originally delivered at
Def Con yeah yeah hey hey we're starting
the other talk guys yeah Mel C beaucoup
oh wow okay so this one was originally
like at Def Con car hacking village it
was like a 25-minute talk but you're not
all car hackers I mean actually show of
hands are there car hackers in the
audience oh no so I I can't
everything no no okay well there's gonna
be some
no so i expanded this to an hour so that
there could be some like introductory
material into just how to get into
vehicle hacking relevant references
things like that okay so it'll be like
first half is gonna be nice and gentle
and here's all the good things you can
do and then the next half is just me
like fly bitch
yeah because Raider 2 has this very
steep learning curve and if you want to
get into Raider 2 highly recommend it
but there's a lot of material out there
that's that initial initial look at
radar - and what I really wanted to do
was do a like how do you take right
there - and use it on arbitrary binary
for Ammar file which is something that
like you know the author of radar has
done in a talk which is great to watch
but there's not a whole lot that's like
do the hard thing and so this is really
do the hard thing in the second half so
fair warning the second half is not
friendly but I will try to be friendly
in the first half okay there you go
that's what I was supposed to say at
this slide we're good so first up is
just you know vehicle buses now there's
a lot of different buses going around in
vehicles these days but still one of the
most common is the can bus this is
controller area network it's a pair of
wires it uses differential signaling
differential signaling let's the the
ECU's that are you know on this bus be
resistant to common mode interference
right so like if you receive radio
signals if you're doing differential
signaling both of the lines get the same
EMI the same electromagnetic an
influence but because you're doing
differential signal you just subtract it
out and you'll see differential
signaling a lot of
protocols like HDMI things like that but
this is of course you know from the 80s
and it runs super slow and the size of
the frames is super small but everything
still kind of works they pack it like
this they add another really interesting
arbitration mechanism so like if you
think about Ethernet it's kind of got
that collision detection and back off
what they do here is the arbitration IDs
are prioritized so like arbitration IDs
zero if you're to send that out that's
the highest priority arbitration ID
these aren't like destination addresses
like MAC addresses you would find an
Ethernet these are more like functions
they're more like what the frame is
supposed to represent like a semantic
marker okay and what happens when you do
these transmissions is the person doing
the transmitting sorry that no doing the
transmitting is responsible for actually
reading whether the bit they asserted
was the bit that was on the bus and in
this way all of the transmitters can
actually detect if two are talking at
the same time because you can see zero
will always be like dominant and you can
detect if someone is asserting a zero on
the bus when you're trying to send a one
and if so you just you back off and that
way that's how they manage you know
multiple access under the same medium so
that's important remember there's like a
really dumb attack on can buses where
you just send arbitration ID zero and
because that's the highest quarry thing
you just dos the bus I mean boss is not
very interesting but this is kind of the
way that you know can works and it was
designed to work if you want some super
cool details it turns out that if you
are going to like mess with these cam
frames because 0 is a bit that can
overwrite other bits on the bus these
guys here a grim built a tool called the
Kant and it will actually GPIO toggle
the bus fast enough so that it'll
actually corrupt a frame in flight so
you can make these little pattern
matching 's and say if I ever see this
arbitration ID with like these
particular bits just as the last bit
comes along it just clobbers the frame
and denies it and they can do
man-in-the-middle attacks on can by
having a note on the side by corrupting
the messages so if you really want to
get into the gory details I highly
recommend their talk from I think it was
use Nick's last year super cool so these
can frames are flying around your
vehicle you have a whole bunch of ECU's
all connected together and it's
important remember like why did they
even bother putting a canned bus in a
vehicle so
before canvases needs to use you would
have you know multiple sets of analog
signals going back and forth in the
vehicle okay and these analog wires
would carry individual signals like
whether whether your windows are up or
whether your door is closed or like
where did you have your foot on the
accelerator pedal in some cases
otherwise a vacuum pressure but in some
cases it's like measuring a particular
signal okay by putting CANbus in these
vehicles they took like the 32 or 64
wires that are necessary and just turned
them into two it's like a weight saving
thing right and then the time division
multiplexed all those signals into
frames okay so what I'm trying to show
you this picture here is like there's
these time varying signals that people
want to capture and do processing on in
the ECU's because that's kind of how
cars work and they want to be able to
have multiple signals going down the
same canvas so these arbitration IDs can
identify groups of signals and then the
actual signal is represented in the same
bit fields in the same arbitration IDs
over time and that's how you like
realize these canned signals this part
is important because that's what we can
try to extract from open XC and that's
like the second half of the talk you
know why would you bother because
manufacturers don't tell you what these
signal mappings are there's a lot of
different ways you can reverse engineer
them some of them is like you get an
instrument cluster and you just see what
the dials do when you send it signals
some of it is you know you take
something you control and then look at
the look at the traffic and you can try
to do correlations and if you want to
learn more about stuff I'm gonna give
you a resource here more ways to do that
but one of the ways doing a ton in the
second half reverse engineer some
firmware and look at the mappings in the
firmware to figure out where the signals
are alright that's why it's relevant
okay so let's say you want to get
started in some vehicle research it's
kind of fun where do you start
honestly you got a lot of reading to do
I'm sorry but this one is free now right
so Craig Smith made this seminal book
it's a free pdf if you want to get if
you have a research and you haven't read
it you're doing it wrong you should just
be reading this book it's wholly free
okay also there's a lot of really good
references out there Wikipedia is
obviously a wicked reference for
everything don't forget it
there's also an automotive wiki and has
like some nice details for example I
don't know if you're here in the morning
we were doing like this riskier
challenge and part of it involved UTS we
got like all the reference
we needed for the UDS protocol just in
the automotive wiki so great resource
with lots of details
I also recommend for learning stuff like
take some classes can bus hacks classes
this is Robert Lee Ali who teaches these
for the most part at blackhat they're
excellent classes totally worth the time
he's a really good instructor and of
course there's a lot of def con video
videos out there you should watch them
shameless blog on I got one of those you
know watch mine too
I appreciate that you're gonna want to
one okay especially you have a vehicle I
don't want to connect to it now if
you're the kind of person that really
wants to live in Windows and like like
kind of likes to connect to our dimino
consoles over cereal and stuff like that
you could totally get Arduino shields
that are can bus adapters and you can
like have a little Arduino serial
connection and do your can but see
things you can also do like the the
Linux option where you actually have a
can adapter in your Linux VM and these
are USB to candidate afters the two that
I really like are USB to can and the
peak can they're not like they're not
cheap not sub $100 but they aren't they
are worth the money and then you can use
Python or Ruby or you know whatever you
like to do your can traffic right there
in your Linux host that's kind of your
two options in Windows as well if you
want to have like the nice Wireshark
kind of view of things then you're gonna
want to like buy some software like
Intrepid's beetle spy and get some value
can't adapters and that's that's like a
path you could take as well if you like
that wire shop kind of you also get
yourself a logic analyzer right like
celaya logic analyzers are not really
that expensive and they will decode can
and sometimes you're gonna plug your
canvas adapter in and all you're gonna
get is just error codes back you have no
idea what's going on and there just
isn't enough debugging tools out there
other than a logic analyzer to save you
so if you really want to like be able to
figure out why you can't capture can
traffic you're gonna need to go to a
logic analyzer so get yourself one of
those and of course a multimeter just
because you know what don't connect your
can adapter straight up to 12 volts it's
just a bad idea so you know test the
wires and you're gonna connect up to
first safety tip great what else should
you do if you want to get involved if
you're a student there's a lot of really
great things for you to do and learn
okay car hacking village is at a whole
bunch of different conferences so I
highly recommend go to cons go to the
try to mess with stuff there's also two
challenges that go on annually that are
specifically directed at teaching
students that maybe aren't necessarily
cybersecurity experts how to become
vehicle cybersecurity participants like
people that can contribute okay the
first one is the cyber Auto challenge
and the second one is the cyber truck
one of my personal interests is in heavy
vehicle cybersecurity so I have the
pleasure of teaching at cyber truck
every year it's really fun I love that
event and if you're a student and you
want to just get involved with vehicle
hacking the technology between heavy
vehicles and passenger cars is totally
interchangeable so I would just apply to
both both of them have travel stiffens
you just need to get like a letter of
recommendation from one of your profs
you do have to give up like a week of
your summer which is maybe not so great
if you know your student but it is
really great learning opportunity and
really it's the same thing for the pros
even if you're not like a vehicle
researcher you know a lot of the people
out here I see some of them already that
are you know subject matter experts that
could totally be contributing to to
vehicle security and teaching kids like
for cyber truck in particular we have
kids come in that aren't necessarily CS
majors at all some of them read just the
mechanical engineering students but they
want to they want to be at the
intersection of both you know vehicles
and cybersecurity so you can go there as
someone that you know is really good at
doing that network penetration testing
and I will assure you I can't give you
any details but network penetration
testing is a hundred percent relevant to
vehicle cyber security with trucks and I
can't give you a whole lot of details
but it is so like if you just want to
get involved teaching people is also a
really great way to learn so I highly
encourage you to go and volunteer
yourself as a mentor at one of these
things too because you'll be surprised
what you learn just being involved in
the exercise and they need your help
they do right so now you know everything
and you got all your tools and you're
ready to go what are some things that
you should like try first first up is
head units all right so head units and
vehicles are are really really soft
targets I'm showing you here like an
example architecture that we kind of put
together that that exemplifies a whole
bunch of common things that you find in
vehicle head units they're often built
on Linux they often have a whole bunch
of user space processes running under
same user communicating over something
like d-bus or some other internal IPC
they have a whole bunch of peripherals
some of them at high privilege levels
like you probably maybe you can't
resolve that but sometimes you run into
things like cellular modems that are
connected to the SOC / PCIe right that's
a bus master capable device so like the
opportunities for like exploitation and
privilege escalation are right and if
you just want to be like take your IOT
hacking knowledge or you know you're
you're kind of just penetration testing
skills you could probably get a head
unit and just start poking at these
things and stuff will follow so these
are easy targets and you don't have to
do a whole lot of CANbus stuff just
still get involved in vehicle hacking so
I recommend you know head units on your
tribe another great thing if you really
want to understand like you know vehicle
networks and this is like right out of
the car hacker's handbook is try to
simulate or drive a gauge cluster you
know write a piece of software that'll
move the needles based on traffic that
you see or move the needles on a cluster
that you get from a car wrecker by
sending traffic to it and this will just
teach you about like what are the
relevant signals how often you have to
send them what happens with error codes
you know you do learn a lot doing this
and then force you to set up a canvas
okay or you could do the amazing thing
and like wreck a car or get a wrecked
car and actually extract the whole
vehicle and this isn't the only instance
of it this one's really cool it's like
putting a vehicle on a board and they
did another version of this recently
that's Grimm where they got a car and
rather than having the wrecker extract
the components they went and took the
wiring harness out themselves because
the the pro tip is that if you have a
record give you modules out of cars they
just like take a hacksaw to cut the
wires and then give you the module and
then you have to figure out how the
wires go back together but if you get a
car and actually take all the wires out
yourself you will save yourself time and
you'll end up with literally an entire
research station on a board that is a
vehicle we're just kind of cool so you
could check that out as well
finally is you know messing with
authentication so these ECU's there are
some unique features they allow reflash
you can dump memory on them you know you
can kind of like look at key material
but they're not completely wide open
well we'll get to how wide open they are
or not but they have this mechanism for
unlock it's not a password it's a
challenge
mechanism called UDS and if you're gonna
try to do something like interesting
with these ECU's you're gonna have to
deal with unlocking UVs which is unified
diagnostic service and I'm gonna talk to
you more about strategies for how you
might defeat UDS so that was like the
easy introductory material and now
already had a bit technical the first
thing I'm going to talk to you about is
how you might deal with attacking UDS if
you just have an ECU in your hands and
you want to unlock it and then remember
after that I'm gonna go into open XC
reversing with raid air 2 so UDS is a
Diagnostics protocol it also specifies a
transport protocol so if you think about
like how ICP is built up out of multiple
fragments on whatever medium it's it's
being sent over part of UDS is something
called is OTP and is OTP knows how to
reassemble the really small can messages
into a stream of bytes so remember that
you know UDS is now like a stream
oriented protocol and not those little
frame oriented pretty girls it kind of
makes things a little different and
pretty much all vehicle diagnostics and
passenger cars actually rely on UDS so
like if you have one of those little
Bluetooth adapters and you have like the
torque app for your Android or something
like that or maybe you have a scan tool
those things are all using UDS to scan
the fault codes in your car
that's why UDS was created this for
those you know fault codes for emissions
tests but it's grown because once you
put a feature in there that's kind of
extensible and has that transport layer
the automotive engineers just start
adding things on top of it right so now
UDS has things like reflash and and
dumping memory locations so all the fun
stuff right you're gonna want to unlock
this thing the the authorization is is
done with something called they call
cede key exchange I think if you if you
know cryptography you're gonna recognize
it as a challenge response mechanism ok
I go I got the you know the hex values
there if you're those right now and it
will tell you if you got the answer
wrong which is kind of helpful right
makes it easier here's a nice diagram of
how the C key exchange works you kind of
tell the ECU that you're ready for a
seed that seed is supposed to be like a
totally random number and then you're
supposed to do a calculation and send
them the thing to prove that you know
the secret they do the same thing on the
other side and then they compare it and
if if you knew the secret then you're
good right we're gonna get into
that kind of goes wrong so remember why
you care about UDS attend occation is
what you really want to do is unlock one
of these ECU's these unlock mechanisms
are very usually inside diagnostic
software like running on a Windows PC
connected to some scan tool in like you
know a service shop right so you're
really trying to like pirate the ability
to unlock these ECU's so I like attack
trees
kind of making the tax right here just
to break down all the different ways
that you might go about pirating the UTS
session I want to bore you with a
notation but you know the red stuff is
easy for attackers and the blue stuff is
like kind of hard for attackers I'm
gonna go all the way down to the weird
things like glitching pass the checks
when we're talking about how you might
kind of bypass her or unlock UDS so
first up is like UDS is a 16-bit
challenge/response which means that you
know you you can't actually extract the
lookup table for this thing right I mean
you can if you have a diagnostic
software you can fake being an ECU and
just keep sending different seeds and
actually just extract the entire lookup
table and then take that and anytime you
want you get a UDS session but of course
you need you need that software and the
time this is a great example of a
student who just set up a four-way
extraction of all the challenge
responses to get it done in like a week
which is pretty cool you can also
reverse engineer that algorithm right so
diagnostic software you know in your
garage knows how to take a seed a
challenge and turn that into a key your
response so you can just open that thing
up in DN spy cuz it's probably written
in C sharp or something and you know get
that hug rhythm there you go now you can
unlock it yourself or you can kind of do
the dumb thing in brute-force it so you
know brute force um sounds like it might
be kind of hard but remember this is
just a 16-bit child response and maybe
you can control the seed or maybe the
seed isn't really random so this is this
is actually a picture of the the X 2 X +
1 relationship of seeds ok so what you
should see for that is like a block of
blue if anyone's ever seen like you know
random number generator tests when you
look at the random generator that's good
it just covers the entire square right
what you see here are these like
extremely strong linear relationships
so if you saw our relationship like this
coming out of the seeds on an ECU you
might even be able to you know do like a
linear regression and modulo a certain
number and just get the answer back out
so brute force sounds like it's not a
great idea the truth is that you know
the actual crypto that they put in these
ECU's is not really cryptography so
you're you're not in a really bad place
to try that approach okay another thing
that happens is people who make these
ECU's will have the same algorithm but
then when they do different models
they'll change the parameters in the
algorithm so if you know you've run into
the algorithm before you can just go and
kind of solve for unknown parameters
there's a great blog post from ending
Mattos where they did exactly this and
they found they could just take ten ten
C key exchanges so that meant that they
only to take their car to the garage
like ten times capture ten exchanges
from the garage tool and all of a sudden
they knew all the parameters right
remember that's the thing is you can
install your you know can bus sniffer
and then bring your car to the garage
and you will see the C key exchanges
from the tool right so ten is a is a
totally reasonable number for this and
then of course you can glitch past and
if you saw my talk this morning I love
to do glitching and hardware
modifications and stuff so this is like
my favorite thing to drool over but it's
kind of weird right because remember
it's a seed key exchange you have to you
have to like send the response but then
there's all this processing that happens
before you really would know where you
could apply the right that right glitch
when you're trying to do glitching you
really want to have determinism of where
you can put it so trying to glitch from
the context of like I sent the response
and now I have to wait this amount of
time will never work because the jitter
adds up too quickly
the smart thing that riskier did and
they talked about this year instead of
trying to glitch passed the
authorization step in C key exchange go
to one of the really important functions
you want like read memory for instance
and just glitch at the read memory
operation is somewhere in that code the
read memory operation is gonna go and
check a bit that says am i authorized
just glitch the am i authorized check in
the function you're interested in don't
glitch UTS itself right
so in summary UTS is not really locking
down easy to use as securely as maybe
they should be your mileage will vary
there are oems out there that have
much more sophisticated protections
under ECU's than just UDS so be careful
pay attention what you're looking at and
don't then waste your time when you run
into something that's weird and try some
of the cool stuff okay
so we're into the second half and it's
not gonna be as friendly I'm gonna just
dive right into our trade error and
we're gonna look at a lot of disassembly
and stuff so this was at DEFCON before I
made just a tiny couple changes but it's
pretty much the same thing first up is
open XC right so I said I'm gonna
reverse engineer some open XC binaries
what is open XC Ford makes these dongles
they're kind of like we talked about
socket can adapters except that showing
up in Linux as a USB device these things
show up as a Bluetooth device and then
they define a protocol over Bluetooth
using JSON so that you could develop an
app say for your phone that knows very
generic names for certain signals like
tire pressure or velocity or something
like that and then the app could be the
same but you could have different cars
right so I got the same app but totally
different models afford and the app
would still work with all the Ford's so
it means that you know these these
dongles actually know how to decode a
whole group of messages and they know a
mapping from like a very specific car
models thing to a really generic name
like tire pressure which really if
you're trying to figure out what a can
signal is that's the info you want so
it's a hardware platform and a software
SDK it's actively developed they're kind
of cool like I encourage you to check
them out they're a neat little device
right there's a different firmware for
every car right so that's another flag
to us that means that they are actually
encoding in these firmware loads very
specific details about you know the
vehicles that they support and finally
yeah they're communicating this over
JSON so that also means that in that
firmware is a mapping that's like this
particular bit field has this really
descriptive name so all the things we
kind of want for a signal are they're in
the binary right what is raid air - so
show of hands has anyone heard of radar
- here excellent has anyone used radar -
great okay
good awesome so the use Raider - you
know that you know if you open a normal
elf file so here's like I'm showing a
session of me debugging reader - I kind
of wanted to do like the live console
thing but the more people to watch me
type the slower I type so I think the
presentation would probably take like
two days with all these people watching
me time so I had like this fake
PowerPoint me typing thing so I opened
up this binary it turns out to just be
one of the ones from the binary samples
repo in github it's you know just LS and
I do AAA and AAA is the radar command
for analyze mostly everything just the
basic stuff and then all of a sudden it
says made these flags okay remember that
so I did an analysis and all of a sudden
it created Flags not the flags that we
love
CTF players great err flags okay and
then I'm s main so that's me seeking to
a function called main and now after I
do that you can see that my address
change see the red thing there the red
prompt it's kind of like you know your
ps1 output of the console it tells you
what address you're out of the binary
because everything you do is contextual
you have a cursor and the red thing is
telling you where your cursor is and
then I aspirate air okay ax so show me
cross-references tilde main but grep the
output of ax for main so the Tildy
that's the grep operator right so i'm
grepping the output of a command ax for
the string main and then i really just
want to look at the top and rate air
does have a way to just do head but I'm
showing you also that you can just use
pipes if I put a pipe in the rate air
command it will do like the shell thing
and spawn out to an executable and pipe
it through a pipe so it did the normal
thing right and what I'm looking at here
that first four cross references from
the binary to the function main any code
and the function main so this is like
this is like you know the the bread and
butter of Ida it's hitting the X button
like show me those xrefs that's all I
really care about I just did that here
okay and then Q I'm out
so really the point of this talk is that
when you open up a flat binary file and
what I'm looking at here now is Ford's
open source firmware for the open XC
it's it's an armed binary file we're
going to talk about this at length but I
gonna try to analyze it right and it
says it made some flag
but it really didn't you know I can't
seek domain this is a flat binary file
it doesn't know main there's no symbol
information here so really you know when
you're using rate air to reverse
engineer like a flat binary file the
best you can get is clippies help this
is a fun Easter Egg you can do request
from our capital e and it'll show you
clip e in case you feel lonely while
you're reversing ya might come in handy
someday
raid air also does some really gorgeous
stuff like when it's doing disassembly
of stuff that knows about it can show
you the control flow graphs in your
terminal which I love because it's copy
and paste able and you can actually
change the sizes and it's using n curses
so when you change the size it changes
how big the things are and you can zoom
out so you know the control flow graph
view and rate air is really great to use
unfortunately I'm not gonna talk about
the control flow graph graph you but if
you want to use right there this is a
good reason to do what I am going to
talk about are all these commands so
I've gone through the presentation I
kind of like extracted all the commands
I use and I'm just gonna go over briefly
because really these slides are
available later and so is the recording
and you can totally go and check this in
detail but some of the important things
to take away from this slide is that all
these commands are grouped
hierarchically right like the first
letter in the command is a category and
then the second letter is usually like a
specific invocation of that category
sometimes it gets deeper than that and
the actual command is like you know four
down and it varies because Rader is
complicated but there is category so a
is obviously like analysis right the
peas or for printing things the T's are
for your type information the question
mark is like you know inspection like
give me information back we have I for
information about binary x' CR comments
there's the Tildy thing for grepping and
i'm gonna show this slide again right at
the end so that like maybe the one that
you saw that you want to know about it's
gonna be right at the end of the talk as
well ok so funny picture break you guys
have been a great audience this is going
slow I know that and it's not gonna stop
getting technical so what I'm gonna do
for you is I'm gonna give you three
funny picture breaks in the middle of
all this disassembly ok all right so
remember open XC
is taking like Jason definitions of what
a signal is like tire pressure and
encoding that into some kind of a binary
structure that's in those flat binary
files what we want to do is like reverse
this arrow because if we can reverse
that arrow then you know we can drive
our own custom cluster or maybe like you
could make one of those cool oil
temperature gauges or turbo gauges that
you know you pay like an extra 20 grand
for an ST or something like that just
make your own right okay I didn't do
this by myself you know there's a whole
bunch of prior art that that went into
this kind of work standing on the
shoulders of giants and all that so I
want to mention some people this guy
bsmt he did some reversing of open XC
that's totally relevant if you're
talking about just doing firmware
reversing you know Craig Hefner has
taught me a lot of stuff and his blog is
amazing if you want to learn about
reversing firmware and of course raid
air I didn't write radar I can't take
any real credit for that the guy who did
has given a talk on reversing binary
firmwares that I recommend you watch
because he's brilliant okay so our plan
again if you're gonna like reverse an
arbitrary firm or someone gave you to
get some information other but you're
gonna have to sort of go through these
steps and I'm marking in blue the stuff
that you know we're not gonna do in this
talk because in the talk be too long and
also the stuff that's in blue is like
from a different talk so you can go back
to that prior art and bsmt blog but I'm
gonna talk about the stuff in yellow so
you're gonna like get that firm where
you're gonna figure out what
architecture is you want to figure out
where it's loaded like what's that
offset you know and then actually get
that on the right offset you want to go
and find loader loops like if you've
done any C programming or the CRT common
the C runtime it goes and finds that
data segment and copies their RAM for
you and you want to actually emulate
that because if you don't put your data
stuff in the right location you don't
get xrefs if you don't get xrefs you
will not be happy and then finally
because we're trying to figure out what
these can signal definitions are from
the Jason we want to pretty print these
structures because we're humans and we
want to look at like human readable
things it stands to reason okay first up
how do you just take a binary file and
just load it in an address so that's
actually pretty straightforward with a
radar command there's a dash M that will
change the load address so here
an invocation I know it's armed because
we already figured that out I know that
it's thumb mode that's what b16 means
and I know where the offset is because
you know we read the datasheet we did
the right homework and now we fitted it
up so you can totally just load your
binary in like that and you're done you
don't necessarily want to do this
iteratively the reason being that like
as you're trying to explore this binary
you're gonna find that you need to make
little tweaks like I knew all this
invocation from like you know hard work
where I kind of learn the mistakes but
when you do this with a brand new binary
you're not gonna know right away so what
I recommend you do is make like a dot or
two file make a file that's like saving
the session setup for how are you gonna
do reverse engineering so what I did is
I translated that command-line
indication into some key commands all
right the e command and radar is all
about setting configuration values so
I'm setting up read air with all the
right config values it's armed the
processor type is cortex 16-bit in
radars context means thumb even though
you know we all know thumb and 16-bit
are exactly the same thing we're setting
up the binary address and the flash
address giving it the file at the bottom
I have like Oh N and this is where I'm
actually opening a specific file and
with raid air you can open multiple
files so like if you have this weird
firmware that came in like multiple
segments you could have one of these
config files and save the multiple
segment files as individual files we
don't have to use DD to put them
together a weird way you could just put
them in the virtual address space using
this config file right you set up VA
Iove is all about virtual addressing
you're gonna want that because remember
we're doing weird segmentation with the
files and then asses for a section so
finally we're just telling right there
you know this part of memory has
executable bits and it's this big and
let's go ok so you can see that now
we're gonna like evolve this dot r2 I
went from stage 1 r2 9 to stage 2 and
I'm gonna use stage 3 as we go on you'll
see it evolved also from previous work
we know like the loader loops this is
kind of like the C runtime stuff I know
that it goes into that flat file in
flash and copies it from this yellow
address to this blue address and I also
know the length of it is orange so I'm
gonna put more stuff into our config
file oh of course
and you see
yeah bummer it's okay it's in my reasons
I'm sure we'll be fine
yeah
one second blues I think this happened
before and I had to actually skip the
slide because it kept crashing again on
the same slide so this time I'm gonna be
smart I'm not gonna make that mistake
maybe we'll find out right so I'm
looking at a little icon you can't see
the icon but I just want to say what we
did was augmented age to our to our
little r2 session file with the
information that's copying that file
we're remapping the same file into a new
location so you're like emulating the
loader liberate the loader loop copies
the data to new location you just turn
it into a raid air command that's like
open the file and put it at this address
from a certain segment that way now when
you're done it's almost like you're
analyzing the state of memory after the
loader loop is executed and that way you
get your cross references okay so I'm
gonna skip that slide we're gonna go to
one that won't crash hopefully okay so
now what we have is the binary is loaded
into the right base offset we have our
little piece of the data segment now up
in RAM and so ideally because this is
what we love in reverse engineering we
want our cross graphs right I want to be
able to look at a value somewhere in RAM
and see who's referencing it because
otherwise how am I gonna figure out
where the relationships are so let's
look like kind of inspect what's going
on in this current state so I've invoked
right there with - I and that like runs
that session file that's it everything I
did up there is now safe so you can
imagine you know as you're exploring
this binary file you could just
iteratively be running rate air with - I
tweaked the file rerun it and that way
you know you're not gonna lose your work
we know where the signals start from
previous research so let's just put that
in I'm using the F command this is flags
so remember these aren't CTF flags right
air thinks that flags are the namespace
that's just what it calls them and it
does this interesting thing where it
puts like hierarchical names so strings
are like STR dot something and symbols
are sym dot something but everything is
a flag and all I'm doing here is just
making a flag called can signal start
and then the S is I'm changing my cursor
location to the can signal start okay so
remember the can signal structure is
like this it is first a pointer to
another structure and then a pointer to
a string so I know I'm right one of
these device at one of these instances
of this structure so let's like look at
you know memory let's like look at the
hex values there but I know these are
pointers so I don't want to look at like
the normal byte wise hex nut I want to
look at the word wise hex tub so it just
looks like a pointer to me so I did pxw
print hexadecimal words and I want to
print eight bytes so that's what that px
w8 means and you know we know it's
32-bit so we know we looked at two
pointers so I look at these things and
you know one of them looks like it's up
in RAM and the other one looks like it's
down in the flash kind of interesting so
let's do a normal hexadecimal print of
16 bytes just one line of a hex dump at
the first address because remember we're
think we think we're looking at a
structure that first has a pointer to
another structure so yeah I mean that
kind of looks like structured data if
you knew a little bit about the vehicle
bus you might even be like oh I think
that's probably the arbitration ID I'm
looking for you know we're doing the
right direction let's look at the other
pointer see I just changed the value
after the act so that at command is all
about changing the temporary value of
the pull of the cursor just for that one
command so you can have like jump around
temporarily as you execute and then you
can see here that in fact there are
strings there right so we're pointing at
a string which is great except if we try
to look at the cross rafts remember a
X's is analyze cross crafts
Tildy means on grepping for something so
I'm like grepping for the particular
string I don't see any cross reps right
and that's a problem because if I don't
see the xrefs then I can't make that
association between like where is that
bit field encoding a that's mapping to
the thing called signal one I want to
know that mapping so that I can tell
where the tire pressure is for example
okay and then there's another problem at
this particular location in memory if I
just print 8 bytes it shows up as a
disassembly right and if you use radar
sort of hughes Ida Pro you recognize
this as like marking things as data or
marking things as code right ray ter
thinks that this particular location in
memory is code but we know we're sitting
at the beginning of can signal start
which we know is a structure so like we
haven't set up the right details for
analysis to work here because if Raider
thinks this is code and it does auto
analysis it's gonna like pretend that
I'm doing jumps into things I'm not
doing jumps with and all my extras
make sense either so we're not quite
there there is a really useful command
it's called it's like I like to call it
the telescoping command if anyone's used
like gef or home bug or any of those
cool debuggers it takes like a value and
it just treats it as a pointer and then
just keeps dereferencing the pointer it
until it can't dereference anymore so
you can like find linked lists you can
find pointers to strings and all that
kind of stuff so pxr right here you can
see I'm just doing the 8 again but it
shows me in what segments it's at it's
like yep that's a can signal I know what
that is because you told me that flag
and it's in the data segment and these
are the permissions and that value
points to another value and that's also
in data and so you know we could just go
on with our life using px R and if you
don't want to go through the trouble of
setting up xrefs px are super powerful
but what we really want to do is have
like a pretty printed data structure at
the end because we're trying to learn
you know how all these commands fit
together to win right okay so the final
problem is strings so there's an eye
command for information one of the
things I like to do if I don't remember
a command is this I will put the command
category then the question mark and then
I'll grep for something so I want I
could remember what strings was so I
said ok information question mark is
like the help for that and then I want
to grep the output of the help for the
word string and now all of a sudden I
remember that you know the string
command is eyes it or eyes a J or I said
Zed or I said Zed Zed Zed and that's a
common pattern to where you just repeat
a letter and it gets like kind of more
detailed and of course I run eyes ed on
the binary because I want to see signal
1 and signal 2 because we saw them next
up we know the strings are there so
great air should know about them but it
doesn't eyes ed tells me nothing
I said Zed is a variant that just looks
in the entire file and yeah they're
there you know I said Zed like that's
kind of like what strings would give you
if I ran strings on the da bin file it's
the same kind of thing but you can tell
from the offsets they're not in the
right place right we were dealing with
we were dealing with things that were
like 10,000 hex offset and they're not
there so these are the file offsets what
we really want is to have the strings in
the right locations that when the code
references then we got our xrefs so we
have some work to do one of the easy
ways to do this is in Python so raid err
when the command line isn't good enough
for you can be scripted through
than called our two pipes so here's like
a really simple I promise it's pretty
simple a Python script where I'm using
the output of I Zed Zed and then I'm
just iterating over the output of I said
and running a couple other rate air
commands just to make new flags and
remember flags are like names for things
so I'm like creating the strings and I'm
adjusting their location in memory by
you know the the hex 10,000 offsets that
they're in the right spot
so I run that to now if you've ever done
any firm reversing or followed like
Craig Hefner's blog one of the things he
does with flat binary files is he kind
of grooms them so that all the data is
just 32 bits excuse me and all the
things that are code sections are all
marked as code the really big benefit of
doing this with any kind of an arm
binary is you know if you have something
in memory that's a pointer it's almost
always gonna be 32 aligned so just
assuming that everything is a pointer
gets you nice data data cross references
that you might have missed if everything
goes assumed to be a byte so I really
like the look of unit it causes spurious
references I like the look of having
those references so I made a short
little script to kind of groom all of
our data area just to give us the
pointers you could do this for code but
we're really looking at you know like
pretty printing you know structures so
we don't really care so much about the
code this time and of course the way to
do that is more Python right so you can
see that with our two pipe it's totally
easy to just augment the way you analyze
these binaries with some some quick and
dirty Python scripts so here you know
I'm seeking to a particular location and
then I'm printing something you see the
pfj J on the end of the command will
actually make it print out JSON right so
I printed this thing in JSON and then I
can actually use like the the parts of
the information and then like axd
creates a data cross reference so I'm
going through here I'm marking CDs or CD
makes it as a four point pointer and
then a XD makes a data reference so I'm
making everything a pointer 32 bits and
I'm just creating a data reference of
whatever that value is at that location
out to wherever so right where are we at
we did a lot of stuff let's look at the
tail of our session now we're in like
stage 3 ok we know we stuff in gray
we've already kind of done and I'm
running these two are two pipe scripts
so the map strings
thing remember that's taking the strings
that you find in like the flat file and
giving them the right offset and then
codifies taking everything the data
segment and turning to a pointer so that
we have our nice refs and this will give
us a much better environment so that
when we look at cans signals and ask
where the cross references are to the
strings and such we'll see the cross
references okay that's a lot of that's a
lot of you know disassembly and code and
stuff like that so here you go here's
your funny picture break you know ID min
admin okay I think it's pretty funny but
I'm easy I'm easy to amuse that's okay
okay okay
so remember we were looking at you know
that location in memory where the can
signals were and I did all across refs
and everything was missing let's kind of
do that step again but this time let's
like see how it's not broken so we went
to the can signal start and I can
immediately ask what cross-references
are there this thing and bang I have a
cross-reference right there and I can do
a disassembly of the location see I did
PD so I'm disassembling right of the can
signals thing and it didn't show me a
disassembly of code it showed me all the
nice you know like assembly markups for
for data sections just like you would
like to see if you're an Ida pro when
you mark something as like a quad word
right so now our sections are marked
correctly and you can see that coincides
basically with what we looked at with
the telescoping print option before so
you could have used telescoping print
and in a pinch telescoping print pxr is
awesome but if you're gonna be looking
at stuff over and over and over again
getting it right so that PD works like
that is really relevant because because
one of the modes of raid err is called
its visual mode and the visual mode was
a lot like that one disassembly view and
Ida Pro we're just kind of scrolling in
an address it just shows you stuff so
when you get it set up the correct way
for this and means you can just go to
visual mode and page around and explore
and it removes that you know
disambiguation of whether this is code
or data you want to ask yourself
questions anymore it just becomes
apparent okay so remember we're trying
to go from the JSON we know that it goes
from the JSON to the structure we want
to go backwards right that's what we're
trying to do okay so to do that we
really could actually take advantage of
the fact that that structure is in a
header file somewhere right we have this
open source project and we can take that
header file and start to use type
information in rate air to start
pretty printing the structures so
radiator knows all about you know see
header files it has a whole collection
of tight commands under T and you can
see I'm using that question mark to get
details about a command and I'm just
looking at like what kind of stuff does
it know about listing so great if I do T
by itself to list the types it tells me
no I don't know anything about types and
this is a side-effect of using a flat
binary if I used an elf file it would
know all the types because it knows what
architecture I'm dealing with and what
the calling convention is and all the
types just come in but it doesn't know
anything so flat binary file even if I
ask it for like star which is like you
know the parsable version the rate error
commands it still doesn't know anything
so what I do is I go back to this thing
of LS I know this is roughly the same
binary so I'll just open up that elf
file I'll do T star here and then I can
save the output of T star because those
are just rate air commands right and
then in the other one when I'm in the
flat binary file I can just load those
right air commands and it'll change my
session so I can like export all that
type information and then import it
where I want it just like that it's
pretty useful and then of course what I
really want to do is you know use the
header file and I'll just like ask Rader
to read the header file it'll be fine
right no it's not fine rady air can read
header files somewhat but it always
needs massaging and pretty much every
time I try to throw a header file at
rate air just to read it in it ends up
kind of crashing or not reading it so
you know be careful what you're probably
gonna have to do is take the header file
and you know remove things like Const
and you know use structured instances
and so the type deaths and you know
manually correct some packing in
alignment just to get it all to fit and
then when you're done you know it ends
up being a big change you see how many
deletions there are like a big part of
massaging header files is just kind of
removing spurious includes and the
include guards and all the little stuff
that doesn't matter just to get down to
what you need for really so it's not
very complicated at this point you can
see it's kind of what we would expect
all right so now we remember we ran our
our two pipe commands that we built with
Python and that kind of groom the data
and now we have the strings and now
we're doing a couple other things we
know where the can messages start
because we saw that first pointer from
that structure array and we even know
where
first bus is because that's reference
twice and now we can actually source all
that type information that we exported
from the elf file right so that's what
we're doing here with the dot so dot
types 32 that are two that's the type
information we just exported from LS and
we can just import that and now we know
all about the dice type information and
we're gonna read in that can util header
file and now all of a sudden radar knows
about all the structures that are in
that header file so you know like the
canned buses and the canned messages and
the canned signals right there and knows
how to print those now right one of the
tricks here is that we used to think
about everything as being 16-bit and
that was to convince rate err you know
to disassemble things in thumb mode for
deep for default particularly when
you're looking for function preludes so
I don't know if you remember a bunch of
slides ago we did a a p2 search for the
beginnings of functions that really
depends on thumb mode because if you're
in 32-bit mode it won't find thumb
prologues so let's go back to 32 because
if you're not in 32 all the pointers
will be the wrong size and your
structures and then you can't pretty
print anything so that's that's a little
gotcha and here you go so we're there we
can go to this can signal start we can
aspirate air Haiti can signal what do
you know about this structure and it
says ok I know some stuff and what it's
showing you is actually the print
command so when you ask great air what
do you know about can signal it says
this is the print command that I would
use to pretty print that can signal so
PF p z vb on and on and on and then all
those names and it's kind of more than
we want right because remember all we
really care about is like what's the
message what's the generic name one of
those bit positions so let's just like
of course more seg faults ok
it's not just radar the seg faults it's
also PowerPoint okay so can you see this
I'm afraid to like show it yeah let me
zoom in a little bit I'm afraid to put
in a presenter mode because that seems
to be when it crashes so let's just look
at it like this all right you can see
that you know we ask it would have knows
about the signal and it says here's this
weird print command but we can also do
is add a dot in front right so a dot is
just like in shell language like in bash
its sourcing an output right so what
you're doing is telling rate air to eval
that PF line and that's what it did
we're sitting at can signal start it
took that PF print format function and
it just executed it and that's why you
see all this nice pretty printing coming
out of you here with the message and the
name and stuff like that but it is quite
a bit of information that we're gonna
we're going to try to simplify that a
bit because PF is very very detailed
like this is the help output for PF so
you can pretty much do any printing you
could ever imagine more than you ever
need so yeah
let's simplify that a little bit I got
it down to like this : X dot and these
are like ignore me or just treat me as a
pointer and then when we print it we can
just give this D reference to an
arbitration ID so here's your funny
picture again you guys have been very
good I like this one it's the College of
Architecture and planning are you gonna
crash again no good okay so we know our
cans signal we kind of know how to print
it this is very good what we want to see
is avoid this you know another glitch in
raid err I'm just gonna accelerate a bit
cuz you know this is getting very
detailed for you guys you can see here
that we're just kind of skipping one of
the can message arbitration IDs we just
want to look Curtis it as a message so
this is what we got we're all the way up
to the point where we have all of our
type information loaded we know exactly
what our car can arbitration signal idea
is and we can actually print this stuff
which is great once you have done all
this hard work here you go this is what
you get so if you can have a look we
actually know the factor 1.0 so we're
printing the
floating-point value of the scaling
factor we know exactly where in the bit
position in the bit sizes 56 and 8 and
we know what the arbitration idea is so
we know like what can frame this would
be in and you can compare that to
exactly like the jason that you know
built the binary file and they do line
up so the point of it isn't to like to
show you that like I flex my rare top
rate air muscle is to show you that all
these commands aren't there and with the
right amount of tweaking you can
actually like extract all this info out
of the binaries and these slides will be
totally available for your future
reference and I also have the command
reference I think coming up so as I
prepare to close does anyone have any
questions in the last couple uh I know
probably a lot of questions maybe too
many great air questions I hope good
that's not a problem thank you so much
for your time guys thank you