like
hopefully give you an insight into what
security is an OT and what I see is some
overthrew that term around lop so just
give some background to that and it
security about that so a little bit
about me I worked as a Technical
Architect in the design of secure
systems for operator technology
primarily in air and rail transport so
the type of technical talk that we had
previously on the first round we're not
getting that deep at all because simply
I don't have the skills to do that as
the agenda is what is ICS pretty
standard one there is some touching on
legislation and regulation simply
because it kind of needs to be spoken
about but it'll be very very quick and
then about the challenges within
security and ICS and loads of things
that are easy tarik to that particular
all those industries and then some of
the stuff in defense and design and for
the attacking side which I'm sure many
of you be more interested in so it is
ICS you'll see these a lot
anytime that anyone brings up some
slides on ICS got a lot of pipes and
chimneys my favorite one is anyone in a
hardhat pointing at some equipment
although it wasn't until this morning to
our writers that he's quite gently
caressing that PLC while hiding an iPad
I don't know what he's doing or why is
doing that but there we go so this is
kind of what it looks like a lot of sort
of industrial type technology really of
ICS is a blanket term for a whole lot of
other systems you see this is this is
SCADA or SCADA over here is there we've
seen the high level controls of that but
it's no factories and power stations
actually operational technology covers a
whole host of other things so everywhere
that you see within this building itself
if you came through an airport it came
through a train station you use the
roads all of these things are a whole
host of devices that are
linked together in some way and managed
you know so they are the kind of the one
of the main differences between
enterprise IT and OT is that the number
of people per device so you look at a
typical airport in space I work in you
might have run in excess of a million
end devices with you know less than a
hundred people looking at those so
there's that kind of eyes on two screens
that you'll see within if you work in
the banking industry is you may have
like a two device per person ratio its
fact there's a whole load of stuff going
on behind the scenes behind what was in
riser cupboards in data center somewhere
else what that means for you especially
if like people who want to get into ICS
security cuz it seems to be a bit of a
everyone's riding it bow wave at the
moment is that you don't have to go and
work in a power station you don't have
to go and work in a wastewater
distribution which sounds exciting but
you've got all of these other areas
which are managing large amounts of
process control systems or distributed
control systems or some way that we are
looking at what the physical environment
looks like so this is a pretty standard
kind of picture you see it's taken out
of NIST 882 vision - and this kind of
shows where you've got this low-level
controls down here some form of actuator
or sensor or something that's happening
something managing those and they come
up to hope it's got high level control
so you've got this kind of management
layer and that's where the SCADA server
sitting and people sit up there so these
are out in the field where there is a
valve or a pump actuator that kind of
thing and that's a pretty sound picture
you see its massive oversimplification
of what a control system looks like
whereas this is far more bottle talking
about so these are groups of functional
areas within an ICS system and how they
communicate and that's simply that's
still quite a high level of abstraction
there's a lot of complex or complex
systems and it's worth noting that
actually between complex systems and
complicated systems are two different
things a complex system is one in which
everything in here every single
interaction or device is generally quite
simple and easy to understand they
operate in complex
manners none of it's perfectly
complicated at what level of a
distraction that you enter into so
you'll it all may look untoward at the
start but actually as you kind of pick
that heart and pick it apart you
understand that a lot of this is
actually fairly simple and non so much
as the dumb kick so this is these are
the things that we're seeing so relays
senses of some description and actuator
this is the the point where the system
is touching the physical world and so
the problem with this if you're talking
about in terms of data security or any
form of system security is that there is
no compute capacity in this I can't have
entity authentication I can't get it to
negotiate cipher suites I can't get it
to do anything because it is simply an
electrical input and some sort of
physical output or a physical input an
electrical output so that's where the
first issue comes in is that we have no
way to authenticate that device or its
input we had kind of trust that that the
temperature is 37 degrees or the air
pressure is whatever it's going to be in
millibar so there's that's a first issue
inherent trust which is not an ideal
situation so further up and so this is
moving from the low level controllers
the high level controls we have PLC's
HMI which is human machine interface
which you'll see panels on kit around
the place and this is this is guarded so
this is a view of the physical system so
we do have some compute capacity at this
point we can do things like encrypt
communications have entity
authentication but as we said before
that there is a you know we have no
authentication on the input to that so
everything here is done on trust that
that particular propane tank is not
going to blow up you know if you look at
mr. robot when he takes out the the data
center in that he is basically fooling
the system into thinking that it's a
particular temperature the one of the
issues with a particular one I know
other people have you know they're done
talks about that particular attack is
that the fact that there are hundreds of
thousands of n devices the fact that
trying to fool one is very
but to undo that 500,000 times there's a
lot of hard work so it's looking at what
the actual risk profile of that is what
is the chance that something is going to
attack all 500,000 end devices probably
Louis you have some control of risk
around there so all of these devices
took on some proprietary and open source
communications there's an issue here is
that these are all very much plaintext
so you know the the simple attack on
this is to just intercept that of
man-in-the-middle and write whatever you
want to write into it so this one here
is Modbus which is writing a single
register which is out of PLC and is
writing some data into that there is
nothing that's happening in the stack
above that is authenticating any of that
tools this is just taking that on trust
on an arms up hammering that point home
but it is very important to know that
there's a telnet session and we have D
mp3 which is another one there's a whole
host of protocols which simply take that
data on trust it's okay because you
wouldn't put those facing internet until
you have a look at showdown and I will
actually have real admit so out of those
18,000 systems that are showing back net
502 work on part which is a honeypot one
of the things I've done is some of the
slide notes of this I've great to github
repo and there's a link to the end of it
and living into this that actually shows
you some of this data as well as some of
its direct links to that so you can have
a poke around and and see what this is
doing so not all of these actually
that's from port 478 not all of those
are back net but enough of them are for
you to be a little bit worried about
that so the fun one legislation and
regulation there's lots so it depends
what industry you work in and there'll
be a whole load of legislation and
regulation that doesn't directly apply
to security but would determine what you
need to do so you look in the nuclear
industry power industries they've all
got their own sets of constraints you
need to just not blindly apply a
technical solution to it there needs to
be in context with what the weather
regulators say that you must be doing so
it's a bit like if you work
pci-dss world is I'll make a whole lot
of policy decisions that you have to
abide by regardless of whether they're
correct or not you can have that fight
out with legislators it's entirely up to
you so you should be aware them and how
they apply to your organization you're
not by yourself they're all of their
technical solutions that go into these
systems will have the same constraints
so it's a case of understanding where
that fits in and which ones apply so
challenges which I've put in it's a
horrible term challenges so I put it
into tallix because it's it's one of
those ones where really it means that
why is this so difficult to do all the
time one of the major concerns
especially in areas where if you're
looking at power distribution that
you're looking at airports or you're
looking at road networks all of these
things have a high operating time so in
the interview that I work in at the
moment we have a four-hour maintenance
window every day and that's not four
hours shut down the systems are still
running the the facility is still
running but we've got four hours in
which to make any changes so things like
patching cycles the reason why we might
sit a quarter or half a year behind
everyone else at Patrick cycle it's kids
can't get to the kit fast enough to
upgrade that or to update their in some
way or to make those kinds of changes
the other factor with maintenance as
well it's things like physical access to
the thing if you're looking at North Sea
oil rig then it's all very well saying I
need to replace this bit of kit or I
need to update that it's the fact we
physically have to get to that or you
know you're long oil pipelines it's
getting to those so there is a
maintenance issue within that next one
as a legacy kit is because this
maintenance issue means that you are way
behind any form of bow wave of stuff
that you should be patching is that all
of your kit or replacement of that kid
as well goes by the wayside
you know I had about I put a couple more
slides in here with just certain horror
shows that all horror shows I've got kit
that's been though it has a runtime of
eight years so it's been up it's not
being patched I know this and here's a
lot of wanky term light challenges which
is compensate
and control was its if I'm aware that
that kid is not gonna be patched it's
not gonna be powered down can't be taken
out service it's not gonna be new then
we need to have a look at what the
controls are around that and that's a
that's a very simple auditor term I'm
afraid and I'm sorry to bring that to a
room of actual professionals but that is
the unfortunately the reality of the
situation next one is systemic
complexity and I've touched on this a
minute ago around systems and they reach
a point where they become complex in
that the interaction between components
is not necessarily difficult to
understand but on such a grand scale
that it becomes difficult to do that
so looks say it's not complicated
because you can build this up to that
point where you understand system but
it's what is the capacity of your brain
to understand what a 500-thousand advice
system looks like it's it's a difficult
job so actually abstraction is your
friend here so you say I you know I
don't need to understand the entire
tcp/ip stack to say that that server
talks to that device I just need to
understand at this point that is the
interaction that I'm interested in
obviously as you get further into some
of those sort of designing around and
understand how it works you'll want to
dive into that further so this is the
this is a real kind of unique kind of
lecture one on systemic complexity so
it's not stem complexity is not solely a
security issue it's a system operation
issue so this has been picked up in
great depth and there are three primary
kinds of failures if we look at the
reason I'm talking about failures here
in not security directly is because
security is generally in this case only
is is a case of it's a factor of the
reliability and availability of the
system trusted device is secure
and of what it's saying is true then I
can act on that if I'm not sure that's
true then that affects whether I trust
that and the availability of that input
or output or whatever it is so look at
three particular types cascade failure I
break one thing so I break you know we
lose power then we hit over to UPS as
you have got four hours in which to shut
everything down or to continue working
that's kind of a knock-on effect there's
a very simple one interactive complexity
is
a this is the one where you didn't know
that something else was going to break
as the result of you know you spectacle
all done this where you go in with a
change we're gonna patch this particular
device that removes a TLS 1.0 cipher
suite off of that and the monitoring
drops out and you didn't realize so this
is largely that that's a very simple
approach that really it's the kind of I
didn't know that thing was going to
happen because I did something that I
thought was correct from a security
point of view this is good from
attackers view because you might not
have the view as a defender what is
happening further down the line as a
result of the loss of this server or or
any other component has caused the net
effect further down the line and that's
when is tight coupling which I'm not
really sure who came up with the term
it's not it's not the best ones but what
it is is that the speed at which a
failure occurs and this may be the speed
at which compromise of servers occur
during a you know an attack is that the
first time that you notice that server a
has been affected or compromised in some
way exact has way down the line now and
you hadn't noticed so that's an issue
with monitoring in your response to that
kind of event and the last one it's
brilliant Security's not biggest concern
which is once again I'm aware which
audience I'm in because I really like
that to be the case because it makes the
battle much easier some of the reason
why you'll see resistance to putting in
additional controls making any change
with the system is because in this list
of this is actually a reduced list of
things from a Dutch researcher who was
working out here at Cascade failures is
looking at the origins of threats to
particularly national infrastructure
actually the only thing in here
somewhere is we've got cyber which is a
horrible term but it is there it is in
amongst and whole number of other things
that exist so when you're trying to sell
this security you need to be in a
context of if we you know upgrade that
operating system I don't care but
actually our biggest threat is you know
wear and tear or any of these other
things
so generally safety is king in this
especially in you know you're looking at
chemical plants power plants all these
kind of things where there is going to
be a major effect of you perhaps
shutting down a connection because you
thought it looked a bit dodgy so you
need to make sure that any decisions
that you do or any response times or any
delay to a message while you check
whether that's true or not is having an
effect on the security so it's almost
it's on the safety of the system so the
available and reliable operations come
next is really the case of where a so
that security is an element of
availability is that your job there is
to ensure the correctness of the system
so there is operating correct way if it
is not that you aware of this and that
security needs to complement and support
safety and operations basically you are
there not as a as a Department of no but
to say this is how we're going to make
the system better than it was previously
than when we turned up generally looking
at a lot of these places where up until
in the last ten years they didn't even
have an IT operation so the fact you're
coming in with security is yet another
thing on there these are the kind of
old-school engineers who are terrifying
and don't care what you do with the rest
of is quite passionate about it so
understand that it might be a bit of a
fight for this but you need to put on
your big diplomacy pants and understand
how it's done so I've been in a comms
room where we've walked in and within a
rack itself was one desktop PC and I
said what is this PC and they said
that's a fire alarm interface so when
that goes off that's between the fire
alarm and the access control system when
the fire alarms off goes off that all of
the doors on forex escape routes open
and it's on this desktop PC running XP
that's sat there forever
what's the inside your mind this is
this shouldn't be a thing why isn't this
why isn't there more than one of them
why haven't we tested this but the other
point is that you could go around and
say but one of the issues there is that
the people are putting this in so your
engineers are checking this in don't
have the same knowledge of security they
do don't have the same knowledge of IT
so it's at that point despite the fact
that you're screaming internally your
one job is to go okay well
is the requirement when do you want how
long do you want us up for what is the
effect this so as to really kind of not
berate anyone for doing that unless it's
egregious and horrible but but to
understand that a lot of the time these
decisions are made because they don't
have the full picture of security that
you do so it comes of really selling
security maybe hard is that they don't
care and they don't care because they
don't know enough so you have to do a
bit of a an education program why you
know we're looking at we shared a load
of passwords and that's the most simple
of it the reason why we don't share
passwords because we want to know which
operator did this particular thing by
sharing passwords that we don't have we
don't have that audit trail for that
so it's case of taking what they know
and building up on that so the next one
is the you know what does the estate
look like there is no point in you
saying we'll implement all these
controls and they will implement some V
laning we've put some some firewalls
here and there if you don't know what
kit is out there stealth IT in an
enterprise environment happens
occasionally someone will come in with
their own PC and I'll plug it in to the
network and do something in engineering
it may well be that all we need a PC to
this thing or actually I've like to look
at my emails on the shop floor up like a
PC in here or don't have Wi-Fi coverage
up it in a 4G network
sorry 4G hub and connect my machine to
that there which connects the rest the
rest of the system and then relevant
threats some risk to the organization is
that those things if you're coming in
with you know here's all of the controls
we should put in place which of those
are relevant to the organization of the
organization that you're in and then the
effect of implementing those and how
that changes operations and one of the
biggest resistance changes is if you
look at particular engineering staff
seem to have this thing but they will be
engrained in the process they do they do
they press button a then they look at
output C and then do these things and we
say oh actually before you do that I'd
like you to enter your password here
that is always a fight with them
I know if the chances are we won't be
doing any of that but it's a case of
that once you change their routine that
becomes a horrible horrible fight
so I do work in design
I don't do pen testing I don't do I
don't sit in a sock and it's case of
understand that whatever I do makes the
bread team's job as hard as possible but
the blue team's job is easy as possible
but it doesn't mean that you know
anytime that all of the people here that
doing some red team stuff they're off
doing CTF
I have no idea how much of that works
simply because I kind of I understand
that I can use net cap to receive a
shell but I have to look up a TV every
single time so bear in mind that my view
on this especially is coming from in the
design side flow I absolutely love to
talk to people who do this in defense
and do this in attack and what are they
poking at so yeah in the design as well
it's that logical of physical
segregation a lot of this it's a
horrible flat network and they simply
because what the engineers need is a
connection between point a and point B
and you put that in regardless of
whether that's traversing a large
geographical area or between systems
system that we shouldn't be talking
coffee machine probably shouldn't be on
the on the engineering network those
kind of things where to understand this
time to kind of split that up so into
integral and physical areas within there
there are some I know mentioned about
regulation and legislation these are
outside of these these are standards is
a six two three three four so I'm overly
familiar with once you look at actually
the terms within that there also seem
very obvious to you when I say this is a
security in engineering is a relatively
new industry so although they're all
fairly simple to us let's get up that
step first and get basic controls in
Kelly's understood before we go and do
anything flash like let me try some dark
traits are doing things like that
there's no point in doing that if you
don't know what sort of what what's in
your site out there NIST is very very
far they're probably the best place to
go for some of this information and then
there's ncsc which is poly UK's cyber
defense six which is unfortunately it's
been two years out of date so far I have
a check
this week it could be better I'm waiting
for them to to to revisit their
understand the environment
it's just reiteration on the one above
and consider what is the applicable
configs and towards it controls you
putting in place you might say I want a
secretive firewall between a and B and
you go we don't really need that kind of
the thing is working out what things
within that are applicable to you so
because you've got half a million
devices the only thing that were you
doing from your point of view is they're
talking to each other so from a defense
one of you you need to understand what
that communication pattern looks like
and what the all of these things here so
you know who talks on which direction as
well so if you've got a masculine slave
set of devices then when I should only
be sending rights down and I should be
sending reads up that's the only thing I
should see so if a write is coming from
a an end device that you weren't
expecting it to that's a red flag for
that that where is this data being
aggregated so where we showed earlier
these sensors and those PRCs it's what
we're doing is becoming from five
hundred thousand devices down to maybe
five thousand PLC's and down to one
SCADA system at what point of it is that
data aggregated what point we verifying
of that data that's hitting that server
or hitting that PLC is correct it's a
flow Direction frequency of volume
generally within the engineering system
actually chatty is good we should see
constant chatter it's when things are
quiet so we see this in our in our sock
for example once that calms drops off we
see that cliff and if that is the point
where we start to worry something's gone
terribly wrong we've lost a link or if
nothing's failed over to one side and
what's the expected content so we have
the quick look at what Modbus looks like
on the on the wire is that what we
expect to see is there any XML that was
seeing out of that but the engineers
that we've already said are idiots when
it comes security they know this data
they know what good looks like know what
bad looks like and I want something
is about happen looks like so work
with them don't berate them for not
knowing Scootie because you don't know
engineering I mean some of you make or
do but invariably you don't
so detection in action it's often
difficult see and I've been in post
mortems that take three weeks four weeks
to work out what went wrong we have
recovered from the failure of some
description and we're still four weeks
down the line trying to work out what
happened for this for that particular
one it was the fact that there is a EMC
Isilon Shadow Copy
job running at the same time as the
sequel housekeeping we hadn't realized
that those things occurred and then we
were testing failover
which we do after last flight which is
at 12 midnight those three jobs sorry
the two jobs and failover testing was
run exactly the same time because far
too long to understand that so
understanding what your communication
patterns looked like what's in the
estate gives you at least some
understanding of when something go when
something is going wrong logs it says
good luck up there simply because you've
got two issues one is if you do have a
device with some compute capacity it
largely has no storage capacity so your
logs are maybe 10,000 events but if
that's as far as it can go and that
10,000 events in a failover takes five
minutes to fill up you're not going to
see anything useful over that so the
indicators compromised in isolation this
is this is not new to any of us here
they don't mean anything there give us a
picture of what's going on so if you
understand what the system looks like in
its entirety to some extent you
understand what expected behavior looks
like once something strange comes in
that's when you know where to start
running down that particular rabbit hole
and one other issue particularly in
operation technology safety insulated
systems where what I need to happen is
that if there is something safety
related such as I need to open those
doors in the event of a fire I don't
want that to be delayed by some form of
IDs I don't want there to be connection
spiking to have on that or automate
decisions that will get in the way of
that so to understand where you can do
those things on where you should not do
those things
so from an attackers point of view
because these systems are complex the
disruption is easy but a planned
existent disruption is much harder to
understand what the system is doing and
how it's doing it if you're part of the
security team for that particular
company it's hard enough already you've
got access to the engineering your
access to the diagrams you can work
through this you can test it on the on
the pre prod environment should you have
one you see what that looks like if
you're coming in from the outside you
may have to take wild guesses this and
so on the plus side is a lot of it is
configured of convenience so because
what I need is point A to point B and
these way to do that is just have a
flight between point A and point B it's
to look at once you understand what the
environment looks like is that those
things where they're configured for
convenience become evidence but from a
from a tax point of view if you're doing
a red team engagement on there is that
chances are its default chances are it's
a direct line chances are it doesn't
traverse a firewall these kind of things
and with that comes inherent trust so
that device that is talking there's
bridging that server is not based on any
authentication it's just simply that
connection so you could replace that PLC
with your own device or you could you
could session hijack and do what you
need to do to say you should talk to me
instead I've got the data that you want
and when you get a scarlet level it's
two things this one called loss of
control which means that they will send
a commander nothing will happen the
other one's loss of view where they will
read something and it's not coming back
or that we've changed the output of that
and say this device is up default
hard-coded and common credentials are
everywhere so you can go to a BB or any
PLC manufactures Schneider and just so
give me a list of your default passwords
or give me a list of where there's no
access cameras access cameras have the
admin password sorry that admin use name
is always route and there's no
enforcement on the password so there's
no lockout so you just just hammer that
until you find it and everything's in
plain text for the most part there are
some other controllers or configurations
such as if anybody come across OPC which
is a
it's previous iteration when it's using
decom where you had have the same
account on the machine as the as the
client and it was horrible OPC UA which
is a new version has a whole load of
different security controls around there
I've not seen those implemented yet in
the wild because it's designed by
engineers and engineers don't get that
it's a another education issue
so those attacks on communications these
are taken from the security research
with the best name which is Ian
Turnipseed their number of attacks you
can take place on those on
communications interception it's not
like from having interruption is we hold
that message back modification of
fabrication self-explanatory and then
the different scenarios that they they
have is the response injection which is
I will it's a bit like the previous
talker with it
you know we're going to fuzz what's
happening here and try and get gain some
information from the system they're
attacking the complex one is where we
understand what the system looks like
and we want to make it do this
particular thing and then there's
there's the other ones there which is
obviously denial of service and easing
one reconnaissance which probably should
come above complex militias response
injection but it's to understand what
the system looks like and then all the
devices not all of these devices many of
them just have firmware that PLC's are
will have some firmware on there which
really if you want to take control of
them we want to understand what they're
doing and how they're wired and how they
communicate is to really sort of dig
into those so you can go by one there's
one's an eBay there's Siemens do it like
an education kit which includes a s 1200
which is uses s 7 communication which is
I don't if you've read countdown to zero
we have a look at Stuxnet that's that's
their baby they're getting a bit a kid
out check what ports are on their fuzzy
iOS check for jtech headers check for
you are get off the chip legs and have a
look or you know remove the flash chips
and done the EEPROM without blowing it
or the other option is we don't -
Siemens we come and get the firmware and
we reverse it in reversal from there
this is not the only full Siemens into
this this is not the only one that does
this don't go and find them there's lots
of them and really sort of quick talker
so I realized when I was doing this
previously I've got 45 minutes for a 33
and I think we're pretty much done there
what I've done is all of my notes of
this and some of the stuff that was
added into it I've created a github repo
for that it's pinned this morning is the
top post under Tunney traffic and also
part of net sac focus which couple of
guys from here are as well if you want
to come and join us on there's just a
the community for discussing security
and getting on with stuff so that's fit
about it from me so sorry it's short and
sweet
[Applause]
were there any questions at all look
these 100k so the question was when
we're testing these environments do we
have a separate test rig and what is the
cost of that and the cost is huge
because what we tend to do for so work
in critical national infrastructure at
the moment on the site then working on
we have an entire different building in
another town in which there is at least
one of each of the systems to do that
the cost of running that is about five
million pounds per year the cost of
putting that up was about 50 million
pounds so yes we do so our pre point
environment looks very nice and we try
and kick the living out of it
before we put anything production money
because that maintenance windows so
short we haven't got time to do a deep
dive at that point but I'm quite blessed
I'm aware with that kind of environment
it doesn't happen very often sorry sorry
say yes okay yeah I think anywhere where
there's some human risk involved that
people tend to like doing in tests
before we do in live otherwise Yolo but
just get it on with it there any other
questions which case thank you very much
your time really appreciate it thank you