okay so first and foremost I want to say
thank you to the entire hackfest team
for letting me come up here and speak
it's always a little difficult not
really knowing any French so excited to
be here and congratulations again on ten
years it's it's fantastic so what I
wanted to come up and speak about today
was you want to be a consultant okay
quick show of hands who here is a
consultant right now okay
anybody new to the field that is
aspiring to be okay few of you good
we're gonna learn some things today some
harsh realities so obligatory Who am I
slide my name is Justin Ryder I'm the
vice president for the security
operations center in an incident
response for a company that I promised I
wouldn't say their name for but if
you're the least bit savvy with LinkedIn
you know my name you can probably figure
it out now they didn't think that far
former Red Team an instant response for
a company called CBI based out of
Detroit Michigan I also did consulting
for a few different companies as a 1099
employee my record with Marriott hotels
was 307 nights in one year if you do
that they send you this nice little
letter that says thank you for spending
all this money with us please do it
again next year and if you're really
lucky you'll get like some little card
from somebody's daughter that says thank
you for keeping daddy employed or
whatever I also do a lot of lockpick
Villages specifically I've done three
out of the last five lockpick villages
here so if I looked familiar to some of
you I see some you know lightbulbs
turning on like that's right but he had
hair back then yeah so I always look
forward to it's a great time Cameron is
the guy who's running it this year
absolutely go down and talk to him great
guy great at teaching so try to pop down
that way when you have time and then
lastly if you want to follow me on
Twitter you know shameless personal plug
that's
my twitter handle there hop on let's
talk if you need any help if you're
trying to get into the field and you
want advice on a resume or anything like
that feel free to talk to me send me a
DM follow me and let's talk about it I'm
always trying to pay it forward there
were a lot of people that helped me get
to where I am and it's only right that I
do the same so getting started in
consulting there's a couple different
paths but they're not really mutually
exclusive one side is education and
education is obviously very important if
you're just coming into this you may not
really know a lot for me personally my
background was I was an industrial
welder before I got into information
security yeah those one of these things
it's not like the other but I was also
the only guy who could fix a printer jam
in the entire company and set up certain
fibre switches from the company that we
acquired over time so we had we had
these Cisco switches with a fiber
backbone and nobody knew how to set them
up so what happens you know the
industrial welder has to take his mask
off in his gauntlets and you know go set
up this switch College is very important
it's going to teach you a few things I
don't want to say it's the only thing
especially in the United States right
now I apologize for everything you know
not my fault but we look kind of dumb
it's not the only route to take but you
will learn a lot of the basics in there
you know things like the OSI model which
you know we still occasionally used
subnetting which we use a lot
certifications are also another very
important thing because if you look at
any job posting what's listed there a
degree and probably ten random
certifications that don't go together
because you know Bill and Mary from HR
read this thing that was a link from a
Pinterest post somewhere and this is
what your cybersecurity
we'll need to have but it's always good
to have some of those they do teach
certain things myself I just finished
the sands forensics 500 windows
forensics awesome class you know
shameless plug for them as well and then
of course Sands itself they teach a lot
of amazing courses as well as having a
graduates program now if you have the
funding and mental fortitude to go
through that it's a great program the
other side is networking and this is
really more for me personally what I
leveraged networking is amazing because
it gives you a way to circumvent that HR
screen because let's face it when you
look at the postings for certain jobs
specifically with consulting they're
gonna want a ton of certifications none
of them make sense and you might have
three out of the ten they're just it's
the most random stuff in the world and
for somebody like myself who again was a
welder I got myself on LinkedIn which
you know let's face it LinkedIn is like
professional Facebook and then there's
Twitter twitter was great because it
gave me an opportunity to follow people
that I met at a conference that I went
to on a whim and here was this one
person and I started a conversation with
them and then I was able to watch the
conversations that they were having with
other people and introduced myself to
them and before you know it your your
area of your network starts to grow
immensely the other thing is
professional events certain prevent
professional events like network after
work is a huge one at least down in the
states they're in every major city
there's a couple of them a month and
it's an opportunity just to get together
in an open venue like this have some
drinks talk to some people get your name
out there exchange some business cards
and start to meet other people in the
field that's gonna open up some doors
for you conferences why are we here
we're here to learn things we're here to
talk to people right that was really how
I got my start was besides Detroit the
first year it was held in a vegetable
processing plant
yeah yeah we were top-notch and I was
scared to death I was you know again a
welder who grew up in the sticks out in
Michigan West Michigan never seen a
parking meter in my entire life and I
was in downtown Detroit pretty certain I
was gonna get shot but I figured it was
a risk I was willing to take got a
ticket because again never saw a parking
meter didn't know what it was therefore
it was quite an experience but I met a
lot of those people there that kind of
helped kick my career off so as you go
through and do that you start to meet
people you're gonna get some interview
set up in my case the people that I met
at the conferences and on Twitter were
actually the people who were setting up
a lot of these interviews for me that's
how you know you're networking with the
right people because they want to see
you succeed because if you succeed you
go work for them guess what you're gonna
help build their success as well but if
you fail the plan you should probably
plan to fail if you'd know nothing about
the company that you're interviewing for
it's not gonna go well
LinkedIn again is gonna be your best
friend you have the opportunity to go in
look at the company who works there did
you meet somebody from there at one of
those networking events or at a
conference can you ping them on the side
and say hey I just applied at this
company you know I'm supposed to
interview with so-and-so on thursday can
you put in a good word for me for me I
kind of like I like to liken that to pen
testing if you're gonna do a social
engineering engagement do you just walk
in there or do yet you know do a little
background research try to do a little
open-source intelligence and learn a
little bit about your target it's the
same deal you're gonna fail despite all
your preparation you're still gonna fail
it's gonna happen in it and it's great
for me a personal story of mine I
interviewed with a company out of Grand
Rapids Michigan and I had on my resume
that I was a
proficient Linux administrator and I was
just beaming when I went in there
because this was a job for a Linux
administrator so I thought this is gonna
be great and I went through answered
everything correct you know did all the
right things sat up straight had a smile
all that and then their current Linux
administrator asked me what does the
command Chone do dead silence I couldn't
for the life of me think about it you
know I did that you know you look up
like you're like indexing your brain
like that's gonna help you and nothing
happens
dead silence the most Awkward time in
the world probably sweat a gallon a
sweat just sitting there trying to think
of it but that's stuck with me now what
are you doing you're changing ownership
duh it's right you know it basically
tells you but in that moment I forgot it
happens
I didn't land that job and I landed the
next one that actually launched my
career and you know really kind of sent
everything along if I'd have taken that
job I'd probably still be there and it
wasn't all that great yeah
networking still more wasn't getting
most of those opportunities are gonna be
from those acquaintances and those
people that you meet it gets you past
that dreaded HR screen I try to do this
all the time anybody that I know that is
looking for an information security job
I'll take their resume and I'll bring it
to the hiring manager and get it around
HR because HR is gonna be looking for
those silly things that nobody's can
have that's gonna check all the boxes
you're never gonna find that Unicorn
they don't exist
if you don't have all those apply for
the job anyway because guess what
neither does anybody else I am a hiring
manager so I can to see this very
regularly I don't need anybody with
COBOL but it still says it for some
reason in the job posting
we have no mid-range systems I don't
know why it's listed there but it is
listed and if you do need help
or you're just not feeling confident
about applying for a job again hit me up
on that feel free to reach out LinkedIn
Twitter if we've talked here at the
conference and you reach out to me on
LinkedIn
I will network with you hundred percent
and let's talk we'll set up a you know
Skype session whatever whatever is gonna
help so if you made it through all that
and you've made it to your first gig
your first real consulting gig you've
made it right yeah no I like to think of
it as allow me to show you everything
you don't know because in consulting
you're never going to find the systems
that you're familiar with one really
good example of this was the first
off-site customer that I got to go see I
walked into their server closet it
wasn't a data center or anything like
that of course you think your big-time
consultant now you're gonna just see all
these great you know collocations and
data centers no it was it was a closet a
literal closet and their file and print
server didn't have a cover on it because
they were afraid if they set it on there
it would just shut off for some
something would ground out and shut off
and as I was in there doing a Symantec
endpoint protection assessment a 56k
modem started screaming yeah you
recognize it but it's still not
something you want to hear and they were
passing financials back and forth
between locations over this 56k modem so
that happened and you just never know
what you're gonna run into embrace it
embrace your suck you're not gonna know
but you're gonna learn and that those
are the things that propel you through
your career is the those situations one
of my favorite sayings is from Maynard
James Keenan we have any tool perfect
circle Puscifer ten other bands that he
probably sings in one of my favorite
quotes from him is he was doing an
interview for revolver magazine and he
said you're either winning or you're
learning you only lose
if you don't learn and that's just
something that I've kind of held on to
because you're gonna have some bad times
so let's have storytime one of my worst
times was the the first real big
engagement that I was ever on it was for
a global company and I was doing a
Symantec endpoint protection health
check for them they were on three
continents and I remember very
specifically that they had 12 group
update providers does anybody here know
Symantec endpoint protection okay
I didn't know what a group update
provider was I wasn't even certified in
SAP and I was doing this health check
for them so after a week of scratching
my head trying to figure out what best
practices were and not really being able
to do my job very well the salesperson
said that even his ten year old son
could handle this so it wouldn't be a
big deal it came time to give my final
report it was the most awkward phone
call in my entire life so I'm trying to
explain you know what the best practices
are and they their expert is coming back
and asking me questions about why that
would be the best practice for them dead
silence I didn't have the answers I
didn't know why I was telling them what
I could tell what I was telling them I
really wasn't in any position to be
doing that and there was just a lot of
dead air which is not a good thing to
have on a phone call so that one
experience though of not knowing was
great because it forced me to get into
the product and really propel myself
because I never wanted to fail like that
again and if you get into consulting
you're going to have that moment there's
no way around it okay any of my you know
current consultants you guys have those
yeah it's a bad time but it's gonna
propel you to learn more so don't sweat
it
brush it off your shoulder I was ready
to throw in the towel and go back to
welding it was such a bad time
unfortunately my wife said
how much do you know how quickly did you
make this transition you're gonna have
these times some of the best advice I
ever had so some of the lessons that I
learned during that time was ambition is
great but you have to know when to ask
for help that's not a bad thing in my
case I should have gone back to the
salesperson and said hey look you know I
understand your 10 year old could do
this your 10 year old probably knows
more than me mine does he's a great
great locksmith that's what I should
have done as I should went back to him
and said this isn't working out let's
fix this before we crash this engagement
because instead of going headlong into
it we could have fixed it we could have
got you know a more experienced
consultant in somebody who was already
certified in the product to sit with me
and mentor me and walkthrough together
and make this a good experience for the
customer and a good learning experience
for me as well and then everybody does
better an ambition is kind of a
double-edged sword I like to say that
it's one of those things that I can't
teach you know I can teach a lot of
things but I can't teach ambition people
either have it or they don't they have
to find it I can teach skills you know
you want to learn how to you know set up
rules on a firewall no problem let's sit
down we'll crash course through it I'm
sure I've got an you know some garbage a
si sitting in a closet somewhere I can
throw you in you know we'll figure it
out
but ambition that's that's something
that's got to come from inside it's also
very quickly a very easy to quickly
overwhelm yourself with ambition
I've one of these guys right now one of
my junior guys he will say yes to
everything he wants to be on every
project he wants to learn everything and
sometimes we just have to pump the
brakes on them a little bit because
otherwise he'll take everything on it'll
never accomplish anything it happens so
we talk about ambition being our
double-edged sword double-edged sword of
a thousand truths if anybody gets that
we can be friends
so what's next in your career you've
made it to that first engagement you
survived you've embraced your 'suck what
next
don't settle it's very easy to kind of
get into cruise control and just coast
along in that job because it gets
comfortable my first consulting
engagement I really couldn't do any
wrong because they were always throwing
me the same types of engagements over
and over again and you could have almost
just changed the name of the company on
the front page print it back out send it
out here these are the things you need
to fix because they were the same
vulnerabilities over and over again
where it was the same product over and
over again we'd keep seeing it but when
I say don't settle be appreciative for
the opportunity that you've had there in
my case I knew next to nothing starting
that first engagement at that first
company I very much knew more about
welding than I did
IT security be respectful with everybody
that you work with I can't stress that
enough you never know what somebody else
is working on what they know what
they've experienced and the things that
you can learn from them I also like to
say be humble because one of those
opportunities that's gonna crush you is
right around the corner and they're
gonna happen and you just have to
embrace them and learn from them but do
not settle there's always gonna be
another opportunity out there it's gonna
be better and it's gonna be a way for
you to move Hey
networking once more still very much a
thing here because as you get out on the
road and you start going to other
companies you're gonna start to meet
more people
they're gonna know your face because you
ultimately are the face of the company
that you work for when you go there some
of the best advice I was ever given was
by a guy by the name of Wolfgang
Gorelick a good friend of mine and he
really was the one who got me started my
first three interviews he lined them up
he knew nothing about my experience not
a thing I knew nothing about Windows
servers he got me an interview for a
Windows server admin position yeah
awkward right but he believed in my
ambition enough that he was willing to
do that that stuff's gonna happen but
you are your own brand you're gonna
leave that company at some point the
company's gonna fold something's going
to happen but that customer is gonna
remember your face with the company my
customers didn't know CBI
they knew Justin and they knew if they
had a problem they could call Justin
they weren't gonna call CBI because
Justin knew their environment Justin
knew them and Justin knew that
situations that they were in so just
remember that that you're the face and
some of the things that are gonna come
from that are job offers that's awkward
I would often find myself on residency's
for six months or more probably the
biggest one was about a year and a half
and when the engagement finally ended
they made me a job offer for more money
because they just wanted to keep me on
to run their cybersecurity program it's
kind of a curse and a blessing one it
gives you back a plan if anybody is
familiar with One World labs and the
situation surrounding that it was a bad
time there was some unfortunate things
that happened as part of a fallout from
a talk and all of a sudden there were a
lot of consultants who you needed to
find other places to work when you get
out on the road you get to find some of
those opportunities and you make those
connections just in case you also have
opportunities for raises but I want to
stress a lot of caution with these most
of those job offers that I was given
were also for more money than I was
making consulting because at the end of
the day they were paying the consulting
house a hell of a lot more money than
the consulting house is paying me so it
made sense for them to do it but I
really have to caution that
one if you find yourself in a lot of
engagements don't go back to your
company every month when a new customer
gives you a job offer because then it
looks like you just want to jump ship
but going to them with the occasional
one and framing it correctly I would
often invite my manager out for dinner
and you know we'd meet up and I just
kind of been Jesse yeah can you believe
they wanted to offer me ten thousand
more than what cbi is paying me right
now to stay there
and about a week later he'd be like hey
you're not gonna believe this we found
some more money for you like yeah we
just went out and there's a coffee can
in the backyard we dug it up and you
know we found some money in there huh
strange strange how that happens but be
very mindful of any non-compete that you
may have signed yeah cuz those come back
to bite you cuz we all read the you know
we read EULA's and we read contracts and
all that stuff before we sign them right
everybody ya know it in my case I know I
signed one when I started at that first
company because I was so excited yeah
you don't pay any attention to that
stuff and as such it ended up being a
big process to actually get out there
out of there and move to the company
that I work for now which by the
vibration I'm guessing a few people have
figured out you can learn something from
everyone
beware the janitor one of my first jobs
outside of high school was working as a
custodian will call them janitor so on
and so forth they know everything they
know everyone they see everything for me
myself I was an 18 year old working for
my now father-in-law
hey I'll network out and I would be in
several companies at night seeing all
the papers on the desks seeing
everything that was being thrown away
learning everything about every aspect
of that company and you start to pick up
little things that
believe it or not you can use them later
one of the things that I picked up was
toilet bowl cleaner takes care of the
calcium stains on stainless steel
drinking fountains but you didn't know
that but it also got me in in a pen test
because I went in with the caddy and I
was able to prove to the security guard
right there in the lobby that I knew
what I was doing and I had to get on the
second and third floor and if he wanted
he could come with me it's gonna take
two or three minutes
Bam Bam I'm in and out no problem I was
bam bam in and out no problem but I got
what I needed to get and I got access to
the floor so something silly like that
you can learn something from everyone
don't discredit them I can't stress that
enough
also one more reason to beware the
janitor never screw with the person who
cleans your coffee cup and scrubs the
toilets okay life lesson so fast forward
a couple years you've been on the road
it wears on you have realistic
expectations for what your life is going
to look like when you're on the road 307
nights how much I was home the joke was
I have a great home it's what I'm told I
had to get my brother to basically move
into my house to take care of my dog
because some situations we'll talk about
in a minute
are you an introvert God how many of us
are introverts in this field right you
can't bring your blanket for it with you
on site as much as I wanted to if you're
an extrovert it's great you get to meet
tons of people you get to talk to all
the people it's great introvert uh it's
he'll have an honest conversation with
your partner are you married are you
getting married you might not see them a
whole lot how about kids do you have
kids do you want kids I had four yeah
that's a bad time pets
you know at a dog a cat some number of
fish it fluctuates you know they're like
rabbits all that stuff has to be taken
into account you have to care for those
things I was home a day and a half a
week for three years and I had a
brand-new daughter three months old when
I went on the road that's gonna mess
with you so that's all stuff that you
really have to take into account before
you decide to make that move are you
ready for it
my youngest brother single guy 21 years
old I couldn't kick him in the ass hard
enough to get him into consulting it was
like you're gonna go see the world on
somebody else's dime you got to get to
travel you're gonna rack up SkyMiles
Hotel points everything whatever you
want I bought my ps4 off hotel points
you know why not but have that
conversation because you're gonna run
into some times where it gets difficult
to be very candid and very real with you
guys one of the hardest conversations I
ever had was that same year of 2015 when
I had those three hundred and seven
nights I arrived home and I could tell
that something was bothering my wife my
kids were upset you could see a change
in them over time and she pulled me
inside she just said you know what to be
honest I'm just exciting for the day
when you just don't come home because
there's not a point and I was expecting
her to say you know just don't because I
was at the hotel all the time I was
never home that can happen it can happen
and it does happen to a lot of people
it's a bad time since then I got off the
road you know just well fast-forward a
little bit here everything's cool now
everything's good kids are happy
daughter spends all my money it's great
yeah you know but as far as the self
care is concerned this is probably one
of the most important parts of going on
the road and being a consultant there
are a lot of consultants who
from home and you know that stuff's not
too bad you just kind of shut yourself
away you know do your thing but if
you're gonna be a road warrior and
you're gonna be on the road a lot of
times I would always hear that it's
great you get to see all these you'd
stay in all these great hotels you know
you get to travel to all these great
places and see all these huge cities and
you know do all these restaurants and it
sounds great
but in reality you're at the customer
site and then you go back to your hotel
room and you work from your hotel room
for another five six hours you wander
down to the hotel bar because you don't
really want to go out you're tired you
you don't really want to do that you've
already eaten at every restaurant around
you don't have time to go see the city
so this is what your hotel room starts
to feel like it looks great but
ultimately it kind of feels like a
prison cell over time some of the
recommendations that I can make that I
learned really in the last year that I
was on the road join the gym it's not
for everyone
it ended up being my thing you know I
had more here last time I was here I
also had about 50 more pounds but it
gives you an opportunity to get out of
that prison cell hotel room burn off
some stress if you look for something
with nationwide facilities and myself I
like to go to snap because I can find
one in pretty much every city that I end
up having to travel to but it gives you
an opportunity to get out and talk to
people and burn off some stress take
online or on-premises classes the
on-prem stuff can be kind of difficult
because you may not necessarily know
what your schedule is going to be I did
a lot of residency so I knew where I was
going to be for about six months at a
time there's kind of a staff
augmentation type thing where you'd come
in and you'd launch something get it
going and kind of run it for a little
bit
the on-prem stuff is nice because you
actually go into the class and again you
meet some people you interface with
people
but the online stuff you kinda have some
of that as well look for social or
professional networking events like
network after work
those are great because again you get to
meet more people you might even meet
some people in the area where you're
working and now you've got a reason to
go out you know and leave the hotel and
get dinner you might even make some
friends and make some more connections
with other companies and then your
project manager is gonna be like yeah
you should try to sell them on some
services because that's what they do
last but not least take your PTO does
anybody in here feels like they can't
take PTO guys in the back yeah I get
that a lot
because if I take PTO nobody's doing my
work for me it's just gonna be there
when I get done or whenever I get back
from vacation it's gonna be there
waiting for me and a lot of people feel
like they lose their momentum if they
don't take their PTO or like guilted
almost into not taking it you have it
for a reason get away from the job site
I like to disconnect for five days in
August I go out to northern Michigan I
have a place that I like to go to out
there no phone no laptop no kids just me
and my dog and then I've got a backpack
with a hammock and a few other supplies
and that's it there it is a no tech week
and it's just a time to kind of recharge
my own batteries I would highly
recommend that if that's your thing if
it's not your thing
don't go out in the woods it's not it's
not gonna work out okay there's a big
difference between high brush
cranberries and the cranberries you get
at the grocery store part of that is you
know the amount of time you're gonna
spend with a bad stomach more life
lessons and maybe don't completely
disconnect because let's face it
if you have kids Pokemon go is life and
those eggs aren't going to hatch
themselves I have a little bracelet that
they make meat
everywhere with me so when I travel I
can catch them Pokemon from all over the
place so that that does happen any
questions at this point anybody might
have no is expecting a bit more all
right so what do you do if you actually
do want to make the jump to another
company one of my friends right now is
going through a situation where he did
have that non-compete clause and there
is legal action that was being taken
against him there are several services
that you can buy as a consultant to have
legal on demand if needed so if that
comes in it cost about five dollars a
month 217 dollars a month is what I've
seen for the range but it does protect
you and I don't want to turn this into
an advertisement for them but if you are
working in the field and we do
occasionally entertain some of these
offers I would strongly recommend it we
can talk about it afterwards if you'd
like to I don't want to totally give
them a plug they're not gonna pay me so
not gonna waste the time on that but
that's kind of where I want to leave it
for today if you have any questions
after the fact and want to come and talk
to me about it I'm here for the next
couple of days we can go you know grab a
drink or whatever and talk otherwise
I'll probably be in some of these other
talks thank you very much
[Applause]