all right
hey everyone my name is bobby fyler i'm
a data scientist at elastic working on
the security product
there i'm joined by ed rath and his uh
myriad of organizations he represents
and we're here to talk to you today
about using
passive aggressive methods to combat uh
false positives in local environments
now before we kick off i kind of wanted
to provide a real world scenario
or an anecdote kind of from my
professional life
building a macro malware classifier and
it's really the impetus behind why we
we kicked off this research to begin
with
for those of you who don't know macros
are
pretty pervasive across enterprises for
task automation within microsoft office
documents
they allow you to build forms or
you know buttons and and calculations
and things like that
and they're used quite a bit but they're
also used quite a bit by malware authors
to arbitrarily execute
malicious code and it's become a pretty
uh powerful attack vector for things
like phishing attacks
now the security industry would normally
or historically use like hash based
approaches for
detection prevention or reduction of fps
but it's really really hard in this
environment because
these hash based approaches don't
generalize because the minute you
edit a document again you change that
hash
and that creates quite a a problem when
trying to detect things more broadly
um which is where machine learning
represents
uh probably the best opportunity to
generalize and start to detect these
unknown threats
at scale so what we did is we
we applied you know your kind of
traditional supervised learning approach
to getting this model into our security
products where we
collected a bunch of data from a variety
of sources to get a representative
sample
we employed domain experts in the form
of reverse engineers
threat researchers to help build out
features for future extraction
we trained a model we internally
validated it which is where you get the
uh the marketing
99.9 effective and then we
pushed it out to production now
the question becomes when those start
getting used
by users and you come across
fp bursts and things like that how do
you improve
your model after the first time it's
gone out you can
collect more data that's certainly an
option you can
take time and uh and money to extract
new novel features
that attempt to you know identify new
families or subclasses
of the problem you're tackling you can
retrain a model more often
and or you can wait for a bunch of fps
to roll in
and do a big update then now all of
these take a fair amount of time
uh energy and dollars to accomplish
and at its core it highlights the the
biggest problem with a lot of security
products these days
it's that false positives are are the
biggest concern it's the biggest concern
for me
uh it's certainly the biggest concern
for users who have to deal with uh
kind of alert deluge and these bursts of
fps
and we as a as an industry
have a couple of big challenges to deal
with particularly with ml
and it's once these models get pushed
out to production
how quickly do they start to go bad um
or
decay and once you once you understand
when they go bad
can you can you figure out why um what
causes
models to start to spoil or or cause
these big bursts
of false positives is it like a software
update or something like that
firefox or chrome or a piece of
enterprise software
is it an operating system update like a
patch tuesday
and once you understand that and start
to see that you you see a larger
issue kind of at hand and it's this idea
of
data scientists and machine learning
researchers building these global models
trained on a representative distribution
of data
of what we expect local environments to
look like versus the reality
which is local environments are
extremely noisy
and there's custom in-house software and
proprietary data everywhere
that we will never see anything close to
that kind of in our training data set
and it does things that look inherently
malicious
so we as an industry really have two
options
at our disposal right now and option one
uh is putting the power back in the
user's hands in the form of
allowing them to allow list or deny list
something
and this works they can use like a file
hash or a certificate signer
to basically play whack-a-mole it's this
sort of one-to-one relationship where a
hash
equals a file or sample but this doesn't
really generalize well
and can be very time consuming and very
frustrating from
a workflow standpoint now option two
which is uh called just like give us all
your data
is is certainly the better of the two
options because this could yield massive
improvements over time in a relatively
short amount of time
but it comes with some pretty big
concerns in the form of privacy
you know we as data scientists need to
be very careful about the data that we
uh we use or leverage for things like
gdpr
or other proprietary data we also have
to
you know look out for end users to make
sure that we're not hindering
uh performance um you know
taking too much bandwidth shipping data
back and forth across the wire
degrading performance on the endpoint by
packaging up these files or samples in
in order to send them back
these are these are things that we we
really need to be mindful of
and that's really what ed and i were
talking about a few months ago
when we came up with this idea we wanted
to
explore alternatives to kind of the more
traditional
fp triage approaches and we started
hovering around this idea
of leveraging the security worker as the
as the domain expert but the domain
being their local enterprise
their ability to know what belongs there
and what doesn't belong there
and take that knowledge and turn it into
kind of an iterative human in their loop
active learning exercise where we give
them the tools
that data scientists bring to the table
in the form of feature extraction and
model training
and allow them to just capture the files
that they're interested in not alerting
on anymore
and updating the model locally um
and i'm hopeful that this kind of
tailoring or customization would lead to
a better overall security experience for
the end user while maintaining the
privacy of enterprise data that data
never has to leave their environment
so how did we do that i'm going to have
ed take over now and he's going to walk
us through it
so in order to fix these problems to fix
these errors
we think we're going to need a linear
model
and part of this is because for tree
based models which is what the current
method uses there's not a lot of good
ways to update a tree-based model
there are approaches to it but they
require multiple errors
in order to cause the model to really
change its decision surface
and we need to be able to correct an
error
and immediately know afterwards that it
is no longer an error
and that's much easier to do with a
linear model where we can just
know that the hyperplane is now adapted
and we also want to fix the likelihood
of future
false positives or make those less
likely
and that's also easier with a linear
model we could force a decision tree to
carve off a little tiny hole in the
world for just the false positive
but that reduces back to basically
a blacklist which is not what we want to
be doing
uh one approach might be to
take the false positives and create sort
of a radius around them
where you decide this is what this
this area now becomes a benign area
rather than malicious but then it
becomes confusing on how do we pick this
radius
because we don't want to rely on the
local information
because that local information according
to the model was already
somewhat wrong by the nature of having a
false positive
and this could also map to one-shot
learning
which we'll test as an alternative
approach
but we find it doesn't work as well so
what we ended up using
is what's called the passive aggressive
algorithm
which comes from online learning
and the goal is that we want to make
a change in the hyperplane to
correct a current error and
the naive passive aggressive algorithm
attempts to fully correct this error
while making the minimum possible change
to the norm of the weight vector this is
sort of a good mental trade-off like we
want to fix it
but fix it by changing as little as
possible
now normally you wouldn't ever actually
do this
and the original passive aggressive
paper introduces a regularization
penalty c
to prevent it from fully correcting on
errors
because if you get one mislabeled data
point and you
fully correct it you could end up
destroying the model
but in this case we need to fully
correct after one update
so we're going to do something weird and
use the unregulated version of the model
now let's go through a toy example to
show why so you have some false
positives
a few come in and you want to correct
them
so if you do the naive approach of just
stochastic gradient descent
you end up with some move type of plane
which
induces many new um
false negatives which is not as good so
what we're going to do instead is the
the passive aggressive update where the
new vector
or the new weight vector is the minimum
norm change
and then this gets us a better overall
solution
that corrects the errors with hopefully
minimal
new false negatives
and now we have a model that's been
adapted to the local user
so that's basically the strategy and our
initial solution
um some inspiration for it we
use malkov so malcolm will convert the
macro code into a
fixed dimensional feature space where we
can then use
the linear passive passive aggressive
approach on top of that
when an error occurs we update the
passive aggressive model on top
not malcolm but then we have this
question of how do we
prevent users from creating false
false positive updates so they say it's
a false positive but they were wrong
and that could potentially destroy the
model and the hope
is that all of the difficult things
are on the border and so
wouldn't need large changes to the model
to
fix them but we still need to address
this scenario
and what you see here the black x's mark
particularly difficult false positive
files
from production real live data
so in order to solve this second problem
what we do is we use k means to estimate
the impact
to a model's accuracy if the model's
been altered
so we can use the weighted centroids and
their label purity to estimate the auc
this is actually a pretty good estimate
and it's not hard to compute
and that way we can share these cluster
centroids rather than sharing the
original data
which also helps maintain privacy
and avoid sharing proprietary data
for evaluation we'll have 650
0009 files and almost 5 450 000
malicious samples and a special held out
hard false positive set of 58 files that
i mentioned previously
the baseline results is that
the gradient boosted decision tree is
the most accurate
on the data which is not that surprising
it's on the
engineered features produced by domain
experts
malcom with passive aggressive or
stochastic grading descent on top
doesn't do quite as well but does
decently
in particular it's got okay true
positive rates
at a fixed 0.1 percent false positive
rate
the malecon plus prototype is testing a
one-shot
algorithm approach to dealing with
the false positives and you can see it
actually learns degenerate solutions and
has really poor performance
so that makes it a no go
we also attempted the passive aggressive
algorithm on the domain
knowledge features because we want to
actually have a reason for using male
conf we don't want to use it just to say
that we're doing deep learning
and so training the passive aggressive
algorithm on the original features
at first glance seems to have comparable
accuracy in auc
but when you adjust the decision
threshold to get a
false positive rate of 0.1 percent the
true positive rate drops to 2 percent
and the kernelized version of passive
aggressive really doesn't do much better
so these three options sort of are
immediately off the table
so the hard false positive results so
that that was on the
training test set now we're looking at
the results in the hard falls positives
so gradient boost decision tree gets all
of them wrong
that's the fixed column here passive
aggressive approach gets
60 of them wrong uh with sgd it actually
seemed to learn a decent solution and
started off with only
38 percent of them wrong
but what we're going to test is an
adaptive scenario
so 200 random trials of a false positive
comes in
we update the model if it's making an
error
and then the next one comes in
and see is it still making an error on
the next false positive
if not if so we need to fix it
if not good we're doing a good job at
reducing future false positives
and in this adaptive scenario the
passive aggressive approach gets our
error rate
on these hard false positives down to
four percent
um whereas sgd barely changes down to 26
and the gradient boosted decision tree
can't be updated at all
and looking here we can see that the
passive aggressive approach
works sometimes with often with as few
as one update
only one false positive had to be fixed
we can also see the impact on global
performance
as we do these false positive updates
we can see that auc is actually pretty
stable
and the estimated impact to auc is near
zero
which is good the true positive rate
does decrease over time as we do more
updates
which is understandable
and the fact that the true positive rate
decreases but auc remains stable
means that we can actually fix this by
just sending the model back
to elastic and recalibrating the
threshold for decisions
and then we get exactly the same
performance as before
but no hard false positives
so though true positive rate does
decrease by
up to 50 percent the uh
false positive rate drops by 23 times
so it's actually still a reasonable
trade-off especially when you have
an issue that is false positives and we
can also see
that by testing our auc
impact estimate on the test data
by randomly swapping the labels to force
errors to occur
that we do actually do a good job of
estimating the auc
impact and we see a linear relationship
between our estimated impact
and the true impact so we can actually
use this to help correct for errors
and now i'll take it back to bobby
what environment we hope that we present
an alternative kind of option
to help start to mitigate some of these
fps locally
without relying on on current more
antiquated techniques
and we also believe that approaches
similar to this passive aggressive
will encourage kind of a safe
customization
and also allow us to start to
establish transparency between the
vendor and the user of this software
to give them an ability to reduce false
positives locally over time
while safeguarding them from doing
anything catastrophic
and yeah that was it um
thanks everybody for watching and uh
yeah take care
you