okay uh good afternoon everyone uh today
I want to talk about WS links virtual
machine uh so WS link is a malware
loader that we discovered last year it
is likely linked to Lazarus and all this
presentation we will focus on the VM
edus to obfuscate these samples and we
will discuss our approach to the
obfuscate it
so let's start I'll skip this
introduction slide as I already was
introduced and let's take a look at the
agenda so we'll begin with an
introduction into VMS in general and
also simple execution because we use it
frequently uh throughout the obfuscation
after that we'll cover internals of the
VM used in WS link
and after that
uh explain our approach to deal with the
obfuscation and finally demonstrate it
on a piece of bytecode to prove that it
works and I'll also mention that after
starting our analysis we discovered a
sample that is not obfuscated so we
weren't motivated to fully deophoscate
the sample and we'll present it just on
a piece of by code
so now let's take a look at the VMS so
we know that there are two types of VMS
or system and process or system VMS are
for example a VMware or virtualbox that
virtualize the entire operating system
and memile process VMS are for example
Java virtual machine that allows us to
execute
application on different operating
systems so how do
oh sorry
let me find laser pointer
okay so actually um
virtual machines work sort of like
standard machines for example they both
contain this sort of byte code but in
standard machines is like machine code
and it consists of op codes and operands
where operands are like parameters for
instructions and there are some handlers
that basically Define the behavior of
individual instructions
and when we have bytecode like this we
somehow need to transfer the execution
from one virtual instruction to the
other and we use an interpreter for this
and here's a example of how it can work
so we have a function that accepts a VM
context which basically just like in
standard machines contain some for
example registers and program counter
and things like that and apart from that
byte code that is supposed to be
executed
so here we fetch an OP code from the
byte code based on the current program
counter after that increase that and
execute one of the handlers
and this can be actually performed in
multiple ways this is actually called
direct call trading because we store all
the handlers in this table and depending
on the value of code execute the
particular one that is supposed to be
executed
and when we execute one of them we can
see that for example the instructions
can do whatever they want so the first
one
fetches to operands from the byte code
base on the program counter increases
that and then chooses a general purpose
register based on that
operand and performs an operation
sorry
yeah and this uh as I said it can be
implemented on multiple ways for example
instead of this direct call trading we
can use for example a simple switch case
or another technique is called direct
threading where we basically move this
call into all the handlers at the end of
them so basically each virtual
instructions execute the one that is
supposed to be
executed after that
and The Interpreter only executes uh the
first virtual instruction
so how can we use this for obfuscation
basically the strength of this
obfuscation technique resides uh in the
fact that the instruction set of the
virtual machine is unknown and reverse
engineer needs to
understand all the instructions and
somehow develop a custom disassembler to
remove the protection and it's a really
time consuming so how can we achieve
this so
let's say that this entire part these
four blocks are actually located
in a separate section inside of a file
that PE file that is supposed to be
obfuscated so we need to have there our
custom VM and then when we take a
function we need to translate it to the
instructions set that our VM understands
and generate bytecode of that and then
store address of the bytecode somewhere
inside executable and replace the
original function with a call to our
custom VM and remove the rest of the
original instructions
and after that when the VM is executed
we need to choose the byte code which is
supposed to be executed we can determine
it for example based on the caller's
address
and then switch our context to Virtual
because we were running like in the
native one like we used registers like
eax e BX and so on and we now need to
move them to our virtual context and
after that we can execute The
Interpreter that understands this
context and does some operations on it
and after that we switch it back to
Native so we just move on the virtual
registers back to Native ones and then
continue in the execution and we can
apply this obfuscation for example on
only specific functions that we need to
um
hide from some reverse engineers
okay so let's look at symbolic execution
we'll focus on the implementation in
miasm because
we'll use it in our code
and so what it is it actually expresses
a code in mathematical formulas
registers and memory are treated as a
sort of symbolic values and it
summarizes codes effects on this
symbolic values inside of a basic block
so here we can see it on an example
which should make it clear
basically when we simply click execute
this as a basic block we'll have in the
result something like this so right away
we can see what the resulting
instruction pointer is which is like a
almost the same as this IR DST which
stands for intermediate representation
destination which is sort of a program
counter in miasm and these two can
actually sometimes differ for example
when we have instructions such as
conditional move we translate it to
multiple blocks in ir and
basically we need to add a conditional
jump inside of that that differs from
the EIP
and then we see that they are explicitly
defined uh Flex
and
apart from that the
semantics are sort of clear I think this
is uh the reference or effort to build
value and this expression might be a bit
more difficult to understand it's called
composition and it basically says that
the first 16 bits of the resulting eax
register are set to reference the value
of ESI and
the other 16 bits are set to the value
of ebx
yeah and how we can use this so it
allows us to Simply Implement some no
known concrete values so for example uh
if we know that edx was set to 96 and
the memory value at 96 is what's set to
fit we can just tell it to the symbolic
execution engine and after that we can
right away see for example the
destination address
and that's it for introduction
so after the publication of uh our work
we found out that the VM used is
actually code virtualizer used also in
temida but uh still uh the structure
hasn't been discussed publicly before
and
our theophisication technique neither so
still interesting and when someone finds
a
unknown VM or he can use a similar
approach to get over it
okay so let's take a look at the
virtualized sample so we open up the
sampling either and look at the entry
point we see this function and basically
all the symbols that are in these
examples are basically ours they are not
original they were removed and we
decided to call this function mm3 so
this is a virtualized function and we
can see that the prologue is basically
the original one after that there's this
code to BM entry and there there are
just some gibberish instructions
and either recognized seven uh calls to
this VM entry which means that there are
at least seven virtualized functions now
before
we jump into what VM what happens in
vmn3 I will say that uh all over the
code uh
the VM uses a giant code which is
basically insertion of instructions that
are supposed to obscure
the code so basically in the right
picture we see
or a part of the first basic block
decompiled by Ida and we can see that
it's a really difficult and hard to
determine what's going on uh meanwhile a
symbolic execution emails and the loved
one helped us to simplify this and we
can right away see that everything which
what's happening in the block is pushing
off some
registers onto the stack
now let's get back to the VM entry so
what's going on so what's going on after
that
uh basically there are seven VM entry
vmpra init entry functions and they are
called from a VM entry and they are
chosen uh based on the
caller's address and they are supposed
to choose the bytecode address that is
supposed to be interpreted
offset of the first virtual instruction
that is supposed to be executed and
store a CPU Flex after that all these VM
Pro in it are called one common VM in it
which is supposed to save the rest of
the Native contacts on stack and
optionally wait for another running
virtualized block to end because all the
threads actually share one common
virtual context so they somehow need to
manage and synchronize
and after that they relocate internal
constructs and finally execute the
virtual instruction based on the offset
and in the in this VM there are actually
45 virtual instructions and they used
direct threading as I said every
instruction is supposed to execute the
following one
and what we discovered is that each of
these 45 instructions is again
virtualized with another VM that uses
the same construct again some VMware in
it one common VM in it and after that
there's more than 1000 another virtual
instructions
and the reason is
that they are actually duplicated and
they will get to it more freely after
this
and I forgot to mention in Via minute
that it actually also sets a virtual
program counter or register
and stores Base address uh that is later
used to relocate uh structures and apis
when they are supposed to be used or
called and it also sets instruction
table register to hard-coded value
and all these registers are used by the
virtual instructions later
and now I will look at the first vm2
virtual instructions that are executed
in the bytecode
so if we look at the structure of the
first one here we see some RBP in it
which is basically the context pointer
and at the offset A4 is actually the
mentioned instruction table
and
at least of the 28 it's virtual program
counter so here we actually fetch
sorry the next the ins address of the
next instruction that is supposed to be
executed after that uh increase the
virtual program counter and set a
register to zero and actually these
operations are Atomic so they happen all
at the same time
now the the other the next two
instructions the second one Set uh
several virtual registers to zero and
the third one just stores RSP in a
virtual register
and now the fourth one is interesting
for the first time it uses multiple
basic blocks and if we summarize it
using symbolic execution we see an
interesting expression actually these
two virtual registers were set earlier
to zero so we do know
what their value should be and we should
be able to simplify it and when we
analyzed multiple instructions that are
executed after this one found out that
actually this construct is used
repeatedly
and it is supposed to encrypt operands
and parameters of the
virtual instructions and it is actually
called rolling decryption and it's used
also in VM product and this technique
was
described publicly before
okay so if I manage to lose some of you
now I'll explain uh how we uh the
opuscate this so we should pay attention
now
okay so this is the first original block
and we want to apply the known values we
use symbolic execution and just tell the
engine that this memory places or should
be this particle values in our case zero
and after that we can see that the
engine simplified into the following
form uh now we see this construct and
again if we think about this this is
actually a pointer to the bytecode so we
access an operand and sort it against a
value and again this complicated
expression can be simplified because we
have access to the byte code so
we decided to make values that are
relative to the
virtual program counter or
bytecode pointer or concrete and we
apply the engine on it we can further
simplify it and now it's not only the
first block but we were able to simplify
the conditional jump and now all these
three or four basic blocks do is
actually this in these four lines
so here we actually uh fetch the value
of the we get the next instruction that
is supposed to be executed after that
increase the virtual program counter and
at offset one for one is actually the
RSP distort RSP that I mentioned earlier
and
at the end we actually
store a value that is on top of the
stack uh inside of a register
oh which basically means that this is a
pop instruction because here we
increase the the stack and here we pop
the value and it is actually atomical so
it happens at the same time
so how can we use this studio and
terabyte code so basically this is
summary of one of the instructions and
we want to
build a control flow graph out of this
to see what's going on inside of the
byte and terabyte code and we during
that treats and values as concrete are
particularly rolling decryption
registers and memory accesses relative
to the bytecode pointer
and we preserve only decryption
registers values between blocks to have
the actual value that is supposed to be
inside of the registers at the time of
execution of that particular instruction
so this is a result of the first
bytecode
basically we can
summarize the results into three parts
like some intro outro and body of the
instruction and actually here we see the
virtualized virtual instructions from
the first VM and in the beginning we see
that there's a register set to zero then
there's empty block and actually it
contains the
initiation of the Rolling decryption
registers that we just skip because
their values are not interesting after
that we store RSP and then there's a
series of Pop instruction
s and basically we remember that the VM
in it
start or the native registers on the
stack and now we are actually getting
them back to the virtual context
now let's take a look at the outro
and we can see that in the beginning we
push the virtual registers onto the
stack after they pop them back to Native
ones and then transfer the control uh to
the next virtual instruction this is
actually sort of jump to a register
which is
which looks just like the
virtual instructions in the second VM
and yeah this uh larger empty spaces
actually separate individual virtual
instructions of vm2
okay now let's analyze the byte code of
the first VM so the first three
instructions behave just like those in
vm2 but the fourth one is again a
different uh it contains
lots of basic blocks this is just a
small part of it
and when we inspected the code like more
closely we found out what was the cause
and the reason is instruction merging
basically it can perform multiple
operations and
the operation that is supposed to be
executed is decided based on the
operands
so in the fourth instruction there are
for example these blocks and we can see
that here's sort of push again we can
see the RSP
oh
is decreased actually minus eight and
a virtual register is stored on the
stack
and apart from it it can also perform
pop here we see that the stack pointer
is increased and
the value at the top of the stack is
stored inside of a memory
and we can again simplify this by making
this memory addresses and operands
concrete and actually use the same
approach as in vm2 we build a graph from
the same summaries sheets certain values
as concrete and preserve certain values
between blocks or particularly the
rolling decryption registers and we can
actually process both VMS at once
because we know what memory range
belongs to the VMS that we know the
context and we just trade them as the
concrete values like the entire vm2 and
ignore assignments into its context and
now if we look at the results of the
application of the entire virtual
instruction of the entire bytecode of
vm1 we expected a series of Pops again
but there are some weird conditional
branches
and if we look a bit more at the
branches we noticed that there's
comparison of
the
virtual context pointer against a
hard-coded value and there were like two
or three patterns like this and we just
we can just match them and eliminate uh
these conditional jumps because we know
what value belongs to RBP in it and this
is actually sort of OPAC predicates
and when we applied these values we
actually the office get the byte code
like completely
and the question is does the approach
work so before we compare
our results against uh the discovered
non-obfuscated sample we will look at
some statistics
so
in the second VM
or the most important thing is the third
line uh actually we were able to
simplify around 17 000 executed native
instructions
two three to about 300 or IR
instructions and it took us like 10
seconds and in the vm1 we were able to
compress uh more than 3 and 0.5 million
or native instructions into like 400
lines of ir
and since we wanted to
analyze only one interesting sample this
is perfectly fine
considering that otherwise we would have
to analyze all the 1000 instructions to
know what's going on and if we use this
approach it simplifies our work and
makes it much faster
so let's look at the comparison so in
the left side there's
the virtualized function and the right
side the normal fuscated sample so the
prologue is the same but there's then
this difference in this assignment in
the second image there's there are
friends and in the first one or not
but if you look at the results
okay
we see that the reference is applied
later on
and actually we can simplify these
Expressions into a form of pseudocode is
not supposed to be arm
to compare it against the original
sample or easier
and we see that actually
there's there are two same lines in the
beginning
and
now we will continue the comparison we
see that Texas is this service status uh
structure and in the simplified view we
see that we load uh service status
structure into register and now we use
uh the Base address register that I
mentioned we use it to find the current
address of the structure
now we see that in both there's a loop
and if we inspect the body
uh we see that registers is being
decreased and
then we set a memory value or based on
the decreased register to zero and it
happens in both picture in both pictures
yeah
when we continue again we see the Base
address register used and this time we
find address of a function and store it
inside of register and then do simple
move
and after that
we call a function and in the bytecode
we do it in a bit more complicated way
again use the Base address register to
find the current address of the
API call
and store it inside of a special
internal internal register
oh at offset one three three and now if
we follow uh the register at the end we
see that we actually jump into into its
address and this basically performs the
call and before that we set the return
address of the code
to function again uh
relative to the Base address register
and actually we choose a certain VMware
in it uh based on the operands and when
the call is after the call is executed
we actually jump again to another VMware
in it which means that there are certain
blocks of functions virtualized like
this
okay
and to the office get the entire
function we would have to follow the
next VM prayer in it and
continue like this
now what are the limitations of the
approach basically they are the same as
simple execution
um since we use it
and basically
we cannot uh
process instructions with unbounded
loops using this approach and we need to
address such instructions by other means
for example some heuristics or manually
but it's not such a problem because
uh most of the instructions do not
contain such loops and for example moves
or and everything
you can usually imagine is it can be
processed like this
and what is the takeaway
we can use a symbolic execution to the
virtualize some Advanced unknown VM or
in arizonaable time if we treat the
right values as concrete by Advanced we
mean
VMS that we use junk code duplicate and
merge handlers and encrypt operands
okay so that's it so you can find the
wall by white paper at our site and the
source code which is roughly like 400
lines uh is in our git Repository