hey quick quick announcement from the
operations team uh there will be a
television crew walking around for this
talk so if you do not want like the back
of your head filmed
um go towards the back thank you
oh okay
uh hello everyone thank you for joining
this talk uh we are tnt5 today our topic
is cloud dragon's credential Factory is
powering up its Espionage activities
again all the policy makers
and shindeer also known as Stark LL now
I work at tnt5 as a senior 3 intention
researcher I have been invited by
International conferences such as
blackhead hrtb hikong and Kabul also I
am the core member of UCCU hacker
I work at Team divide as a straight
intelligence researcher my research
focused on Cyber Street in Apec region
okay
so
this is our agenda first we will briefly
introduce the basic information of cloud
dragon
second we will introduce the key point
of this talk credential Factory
sir we will share a real world case of
from our instant response investigation
finally in conclusion we will give some
key takeaway and medication
thank you
I'm going to make an introduction of APG
group claw dragon
before starting we should know apt group
kinsuki first
kinsuki is very active North Korean apt
and Cloud Dragon is a subgroup of
kinsuki defined by identify
we found that cloud dragon uh
launched not only uh several Espionage
campaigns but also cyber crime
activities
they engage in a lot of phishing attacks
they developed a lot of our unique
malware such as Jam Park baby shark
piano store and kgh grade
in the past we see that cloud dragon
mainly charges South Korea
in recent years
we have observed that cloud dragon scope
is expanding including a text and at the
United Nation the United States and
Japan
the targeted industry include government
education Research Institute NGO media
and technology companies
next is today's key Point credential
Factory
foreign
workflow of cloud dragon's credential
Factory
we believe this credential Factory is
cloud dragon's special attack cycle
cloud dragon can use this credential
Factory to keep feeling its massive
attacks
we build a specialized cyber kill chain
to illustrate credential Factory
you can see that there are three small
cycle from top to bottom
daily cycle campaign cycle and policy
story cycle
next we will introduce each cycle one by
one
first is the daily cycle the core of the
daily cycle is efficient
actor get a lot of mail credential
through fission
lost content from compromise account
will be the next Target
what will be the next Vision Target
can use compromise account and private
document to do social engineering and
deploy malware
so next we are going to introduce three
kinds of vision
basic Vision proxy mirror and vision bot
in the past we observed a lot of vision
Targets on the two Korean portal number
and down
and now there are more fishing websites
decide for to be used on International
targets like Google Yahoo and L
it's a basic Vision we continually
observe Advanced fishing techniques
here we have an advanced fishing
technique called process mirror
process mirror is a fishing skill used
by cloud dragon
the Pagan our fish inside will fetch the
patch from the real website immediately
this technique can make fish inside
after automatically and make lost Vision
side since legitimate
also the fish inside can take the
account and password entered by the user
to the real website for verification
and other Advanced fishing techniques is
a fishing boat
the fish inside passes users input to
bot wire address the bot wrong the
linear to control a browser
all users operations will be
synchronized to the bot browser in real
time
let's see how the fishing part works
when the victim improve their username
and password to the vision patch
the path will open a browser and try to
login
if it's successfully logging the real
website in let browser will show the OTP
patch
after part conference the victim will be
redirected to affect OTP patch
the victim will input the OTP code
received from their cell phone
the part will enter the OTP code into
the browser and login successfully
finally the part with the red the user
page to the real website
so if the return is already logged in in
the real website the victim cannot
identify the login step was done by
fishing bot
the fission bar can easily access the
account protected by two Factor
Authentication
more about Vision you can see our credit
are our Cloud dragons research operation
fisherman published at hittb last year
okay uh let's tackle to introduce the
next part
okay then this is the campaign cycle
when cloud dragon starts a targeted
attack the first step is reconnaissance
the target they target employees use
malicious document and deploys mower
or they can develop a customized
efficient site to get some credentials
if targeting employees doesn't work
they will Target external service such
as mail
VPN mdn and website
if no relevant vulnerability are found
the actor will transfer the target to
the vendors of those service
if those vendors are compromised actors
may get the credential oh sorry actors
may get the maintenance document
maintenance documents and review the
source code
finally with those credentials or the
rotate variant ability to invention the
original Target
so we will show what kind of the code
they used and introduce two new mowers
F Mill and dust
as we mentioned in campaign cycle cloud
dragon delivers uh mowers with efficient
documents
the actors will discuss themselves as
journalists and send the fiction
document to the victims
the content of these documents might be
professional questions interview
manuscripts and study reports
here I'm going to introduce baby shark
one of the top movies used by
cloudragon's fishing documents
the fission documents are usually filled
with Scarborough tax
and ask victim to enable the macro
let me grow first downloads the cleared
koi
then the Explorers the process running
process and detects antivirus software
it detects antivirus software for
downloading corresponding components and
these components use different file type
and different persistence to bypass the
detection
finally they fetch another VB script or
pet file from the C2 server
and usually they are used to to install
another mower
in baby shark cloud dragon use a unique
transfer position Cipher
this encryption might use on strings
payloads or communication
the value of the key D might change in
different in different case
in this picture we could see how the
macro detect antivirus software
the maker checks the running process
then
to find out which antivirus software is
running
then it downloads corresponding
components
this year we found a new mower F Mill
deployed by baby shark
F Mill is a malicious browser extensions
since the web mails since the Webmail
becomes more and more popular
clothes we can develop develop this
small world for male labs
usually F mail can still mail attachment
or browsing history
at the beginning
actor gathers some information for f
mail installation
they deploy a VB script to handle this
information gathering
it downloads Powershell script like get
Chrome the PS1 to collect browser info
these browser info will be written into
several.net file
and finally upload to C2 server
the process stores extension meta in
preference and generates a signature in
Secure preference
so in order to install the extension in
order to install the extension actors
must modify the preference and secure
preference
in this picture
get chrome.ps1 will upload these two
preference files to C2 server
after the malicious preference files are
ready
actor deploys F mail with baby shark
the installer transfer change preference
files and launch a Powershell as a
watchdog
this Watchdog will open that tool page
therefore fmail can capture the network
activity through Dev tools
the two JavaScript will fetch additional
payloads from C2 server
this is the Manifest of fmail
we can see that it sets up a background
script and devtool page
we call this more F mail because of its
name field
we also observe let extension use effect
icon of BNS
okay this is the cd2js which is fetched
by Dev Js
if users active page match the white
list data will be sent to cd1js
in this picture
the wireless is Gmail and Outlook
the cd1js is faced by bgjs it will
extract the male meta contents and
attachment from the raw data
in this picture
the function get mail underscore Google
use a hardcore index to find
corresponding elements
thank you
next we will introduce
dust the new Vector of call dragon
we discovered it on this February
dust is a show called best modular
backdoor this is the first time we
observed that cloud dragon use Circle
base vector
it's named from its pdb strings
and you suppose different communication
modes sorry it suppose different
communication method by changing models
there are two versions of dust
DNS and http
dust will be start by by our registry
server 32. this is a user method of call
trigger just like jump back
after startup it will launch a show
called loader
the circle loader will decrypt the
embedded payload with one byte xor and
run dust in memory
thus will initialize lots of runtime
variables and stores in structure
with this structure thus can dynamically
dynamically call Windows API easily
in the DNS version
thus communicates with C2
by our DNS tunnel
the different type of communication will
take different prefix
all the data will be encrypted and
encoded with back 16.
here is an example
the data will be put on the sub domain
okay the data encryption is as follow
it is a simple one byte operation
addition with a key and less result
the HTTP version only differs in
Communications
dust will put the PHP code in the HTTP
header and then csrf token
the encryption is sent is the same as
DNS version
but the encoded method is changed to
back 64.
the C2 server of dust will execute the
PHP code in the HTTP header
this is a very weird design
from the PHP code we can summarize the
logic of dust C2 server communication
there is a spatial mechanism in the
communication of task HTTP version
more will check the existence of a
specific session file on the C2 server
data will be transferred if only the
section file exists
and the data will delete itself after
few minutes
we summarize that this is a dial and
connect mechanism
the controller and more must connect to
C2 at the same time
if one of them disconnects the
communication will be terminated
this ensures that
commands and victim data will not be
left on C2 server
the pector function of thus is as
follows
include common factor such as show
command and file operations
it also supports communication with
plugins through pipe
in addition to that Spector we also
found the actor combined cobal strike
with related components
besides
we observed the actual abuse Public
Service like using GitHub as a download
site and hiding the real IP with and
growth
and final one is the pulse is polycycle
it shows the operation after actor gets
the excess of Intranet
we have seen cloud dragon in this cycle
get more credential and data through
lateral movement
in this stage
call Dragon prefers to use hacking tool
rather than their spatial vector
Karl Dragon used lots of hacking tool in
policies policycle we divide them into
three parts
they are Public public hacking tools
Cloud Reagan develop tools and remote
desktop tool any desk
we found public hacking tools they are
tgcd port forwarding tool
and grog a reverse plastic tool that
allows actors as a machine in private
name work
and the last one is SM reek it's a
crippled uh it's a crypto Miner
we also found that they view their
hacking tools with script language
they are screenshot tool keylogger and
credential stealer
the Powershell loader will decode the
payload and run the snapshot tool in
memory
this tool will text screenshot and
upload to C2 server
same as screenshot tool
the Powershell loader decodes and SQ key
logger
this key logo just write key log files
and the key log files will will be
uploaded by another VB script
the credential stealer is triggered as
user logging
if it pops out a dialog box to ask the
victims to enter their credentials
now I'm going to introduce the Third
Kind of hacking tool remote desktop tool
any desk
people can use any task to access the
computer without public IP
we observe that cloud so you can abuse
any task as a backdoor
that develops some related components
like installer loader hiding tool
Watchdog and modify config files
here I'm going to introduce the tool
used by cloud dragon to hide any desk
there are two components I observed and
I update
I absurd will reduce the I update as a
service for persistence
and I update hides any task uh height
any desk Windows system tray and notify
icon
as the picture shows I update codes show
window function to hide the window
and this picture shows how a high system
tray and notify icon
the Watchdog deploys customized config
files and launch any disk
besides it can fetch additional commands
from C2 server
the Watchdog will put two config files
system config and service config to
program data backslash and desk
we can see the ID is in system config
and the paste work password H and the
salt are in service config
okay we summarized that actor might set
up the ID and password in their any desk
and therefore
the existing ID and customize password
will be written into the config
then they deploy these config files to
victim's computer
finally
actor might use any text to access
victim's computer with known credential
okay
I will show the case study
okay let's take a look at the real world
cast how cloud dragon leverage
credential Factory to launch a series of
attack
this is cloud dragons campaign through a
VPN zero day this campaign happened last
year we divided this campaign into three
parts fishing operation zero de
vulnerability and malware main zip rate
and sorry that in the following talk we
will skip some technical detail because
the cve number is under the application
process
last year Korea Atomic Energy Research
Institute k-a-e-r-i
published an announcement that has been
hacked and found some suspicious VPN
access
and I believe that attacker is from
North Korea
at the moment we got a case of instant
response using the same VPN product
we will disclose how our plan how our
planner was gone compromised by the same
VPN product but it is important to know
that we didn't know the detail of attack
against Kei the following investigation
is not related to Kei
it inch it is interesting that we have
seen a fishing attack again a VPN vendor
and the fission side is related to cloud
dragon C2
and after two months the VPN 0-day
Instinct uh instant happened
after our investigation we found some
some suspicious web assets a web show
named session underscore
check.csp was found on the VPN server
this is a very simple JSP web show
attacker can easily execute show command
on the website what is the worst is that
the permission of web service is the
root
the root account can access all the VPN
data such as password hash as a slog and
database
of course the VPN can access the
internet of the company attackers can
leverage the VPN server to do little
movements
foreign
[Music]
after reviewing the source code we found
a zero day vulnerability
the source code is shown us below
there is a file upload function but
without Authentication
this is a very common web vulnerability
arbitrary up though
and there's no file check in this
function the actor can upload a web show
with this vulnerability
based on the version information
there may be 117 public server
with this vulnerability
most often are located in South Korea
a new better mainly Brave was also
discovered during our investigation
this Vector is used in lateral movements
the C2 server augmented Ray is actually
the compromise VPN server
the installer will drop the loader and
write a zip file as a blob to the
registry
the loader will read the registry value
on zip and load the main deep rate
will also read the configuration which
is unlocked from the same resource
in communication
data will be encrypted encoded and
packed to a zip file
the name augmentative is from is debug
log get module from CND main zip
all comments impairments are packed in
this format
in addition to show command and Egyptian
function many different
supports lots of modules we observe much
some modules such as injector key locker
and kilogram screenshot and remote
desktop
let's recap the campaign timeline
cloud dragon built a customized Vision
site for VPN vendor
from the fission side actors
successfully got some credentials from
employees
using those credential
feature can access the internet of VPN
company
after lateral movements they reveal the
source code and found a zero day
vulnerability
let's use this to use availability to
break into customer of the VPN product
the the deployment display and sound
hacking tool to control the compromise
host
okay in conclusion let's quickly recap
our talks
we introduce cloudtrack's malicious
activities
we found that their recent targets are
international policy maker such as Think
Tank universities and media
the credential Factory consists of three
Cycles in Daily cycle they like to use
fishing and social engineering to get a
lot of credential and private documents
and using those private documents in the
campaign cycle
we understand their tactic and malware
they used
Import Cycle we can see variance hacking
tool and overuse of remote desktop tool
finally we present how to use credential
Factory to establish a critical Campaign
which is a VPN zero day vulnerability
campaign yeah
so here we provide some medication
first phishing email may be sent from
trusted contacts people should verify
the information when opening some
special file or website
browser have become the confidential
place on our computer
so there will be more and more apt
groups developing malicious browser
extension
therefore it is necessary to check
whether any malicious browser extensions
are installed regularly
it is recommend to bend the use of
remote desktop tool in Enterprise
the remote desktop tool may become a
Chrono will hacker height
ensure that the maintenance account and
password are changed a vendor should not
design a backdoor for maintenance
you should update all the service and
device to the latest version
let's finally following our research for
update apt activities
okay this is our reference
uh oh okay so this has been our
presentation today may you have any
question please contact us via email and
thank you
[Applause]