Thank you.
I'm sorry, but when this talk is over, I
will upload this presentation CD, so
if there are parts that were too early
, I hope you can read it slowly later. If
you search for the keyword "getub Yamamoto Security Presentations"
, I think it will come up
later.
I think I'll share the link on this Daiwa Security Twitter account So what is the flow of this talk
?  For those of you who want to contribute to something,
I would like to provide some reference information Let's introduce myself. My name
is Zaku.
Since then,
I've been in the Kansai area, and I've been holding regular study sessions since I'm a manager of the Kansai community at
Bodentia.
First of all, before we talk
about the importance of event log analysis. First of all, it is included in all
terminals and
Windows terminals, so
it will be the basis of Windows fringe investigations
.
EDR, which costs a good price, leaves
detailed
evidence.
Now
, let's talk about the Nog setting problem.
Windows'
default tool settings aren't good at all
.
About 80% of the tools you want aren't recorded
in the default setting,
so as far as I can see, among the tools that are recorded.
Approximately 70% or more is already noise  It's not
very useful for Feldench investigations or incident response.Also,
the log size of Difford on Windows
is
small and
only 1MB or 20MB is
left at most, so if it's
a domain controller or a server, the
tools will fill up quickly, and it's important evidence.  It will be
overwritten
Again, the video is failing.
Execution and
prostik's
very important tools do not remain by default,
so
it is necessary to improve animal settings using GP and intune startup tickets.
The ideal
thing would be to introduce Microsoft's question.
I'll
talk more about sigma later,
but there's this
open source
attack detection rule called sigma, and
I'm going to look a little bit at what Windows DOG that rule is
looking at.  I made a
simple analysis like this, and only
10 to 20% of the reform rules use
the default tools.  If you
enable it with weak,
you can use about 75% of the new model, but
if you want to use the 100% rule, you
need to introduce a question
.
In the first place
, it is necessary to ask questions such as whether tools are not read as read by default,
so I made a video about improving
agricultural settings
.
Today
I made the ultimate guide for Windows event log settings for
dfir and teacher hunting.It's been
published since the week before last.There were quite a few responses from people overseas
.
This is part of the document.
Enable this category after default settings or recommended
settings  When
enabled, it stops what kind of attacks can be detected.Also,
if you enable it, which event is
good, but
it will be effective.I'm resting up like this
,
so when I study Windows event videos,
I also
tune the agricultural settings.
I think it will be very helpful when you do
event tag
analysis
problems and
solutions
.
In
fact, there are more than 300
different tools scattered around, so
it
was really hard to check the square tools
manually
.  Also
, even in a small-scale network, for
example
, even if the data is less than 1 gigabyte, the
number of events is
over 100,000
.
I think Frenzik has been around for quite a few years now, but
mainly this information gathering method,
for example
, copying only the necessary data instead of copying the entire hard disk of a
Windows terminal,
has become mainstream.  But from now on, I think we have to create a tool for this passive screw company
, not only as an information gathering tool, but also as an
analysis
tool.
It's usually done within half a day or a day,
and the
attackers are incredibly fast, so the
blue team will
quickly detect it and respond immediately,
and lose trust in the response
.
It's a tool called Ueda, Hayabusa, and Takagi
First, a tool called weather.
Me,
Derailment Dark, and others
.
I think it can be fixed. Various functions
are included, but the best  What
I think is a good function is the function to create this movie
inside the
body.As I will explain later, you can also analyze the use of ntim,
etc.
So, when I thought about creating the time of this movie
It
is necessary to extract information from tools, and it
is quite difficult to do it manually, so
I have automated all of the extraction and analysis
.
And since a lot of videos are turned
off, there is a
lot of noise, so this
technique tool ignores all that noise
.  However,
since it's a very theme price, it's also done automatically.
It took a theme, but
if you use this middle path,
you don't have to say anything about
that
kind of theme.  The GY comes out, and the
paper time,
labor type,
authentication entity Adam, Carlos authentication,
source IPS timers, etc.
come out.
Lateral deployment Which terminal deployed
next to where? Passion
attacks, etc.
Just by looking at this, many
attacks are very
conspicuous, so
I think you can easily distinguish them.
This is a video type
aggregation
function.
Recently
, I think ntl has become as dangerous a protocol as smb version 1, so I think you should
definitely
turn it away.
Since I won't be able to use ntim in my old age, I'll first enable the
tools
of ntim.It would be nice to take a picture of that tool for about two weeks or a month and analyze it.
Even if
I contact you, please disable it, and if it doesn't work, please
re-
enable
it.
Hayabusa This is the strong sword I'm most proud of
. It
was released last
Christmas.  I'm just
designing tools
and gathering people who are much smarter than me.The
actual development is all
done by the amazing programmers on this side
.
It's written in , so
it
's possible to create a memory-safe, C-like buffaloes very quickly,
but I don't
think it's possible.
You can also improve the binary for the OS. Also,
since it's a stand zone
, there's no need to install Dot Dead, Python, or anything like Party Lifeline. All the
rules are based
on Sigma's
scenery, which I'll explain later, so
anyone can easily
make room for it.
It can be expanded.
This hiyabusa appears over
300 Windows
event tools and extracts important logs and
traces of attacks.It saves
important information to the
timeline in CSV or JSON format.
If you import the CSV into,
for example, exced or
Nexpolar Anastack Stack
Spank within Time,
you
can analyze it there.The
JSON format
can be analyzed with the JQ command.
This
data reduction is the most unnecessary
event tool.
Not only does it ignore the event, but it
also accepts the data that it extracts
.
More than twice as much
data is destroyed each time, but
it's already
necessary to explain the event so much.  If you only want the Menema information
like this on the right side,
you can do it with 69 times more
.  Also,
I'm doing my best to make this very long
Microsoft
Windows Windows file somehow a
long channel name, and I'm simply
accepting it as a
file
.
When you look at the timeline, you can fit everything on
that one
screen
. If you don't do this, the analyst has
to scroll from left to right every time
, check the feed information, return to the left, and
scroll left and right for a long time.  It's not good, so it's
going to be very slow,
and I think everyone gets irritated quickly and
gets a lot of stress
. I'm already trying to make Windows video analysis
fun.  Combined with over 3,000 posts and discontinued departments, it's
updated every day
So
Sigma
Sigma I didn't know how many people
are there?
The project is
open source, and
the very famous bull teams from overseas
are investigating new attack methods every day,
and they are releasing
this Sigma architecture in this form of resignation for
free.It has become
the global standard for log-based IOCs.
In
addition to Windows,
there is also a version that communicates with the cloud or Mac, but
I haven't used Windows
events
yet.  But
another great thing is
that Sing can be converted to
any team
query.  Even if you use spank
MicrosoftDefe  Even if you use nder,
it's
probably possible for any team to use any language,
so I think anyone can use cymbals
.
So, what's important is
the logic of this
technique, and I'm looking for synnetures that
are roughly in this structure.
You can easily create rules like Condensation Suduction and Not
Fiotar. If you want to try a little more than the new model,
I recommend this test site.
Hayabusa Duel is
a service set called Sigma
.
If it's compatible, it'll be destroyed, but in the same
way
you can convert it to a different team like Spankferry, but
sometimes we're expanding that single a little bit,
so sometimes
you can't convert it, but it doesn't matter,
but most of it can be converted.
It's a very
long story, so if
you want to know more
, read the lead of this Hiboost Roots repository D.
Well, the main difference is
that if you're a singer, you define tool loss in this tool source
category.
It's
called
Hayabusa, but it's defined as a
channel name and an event ID
.
I've also listed the source of this tool, so if it detects a detection, I'll
also
use this filter condition. The
falcon
actually
has a lot of options, a lot of options so that it can be highly customized,
but I usually
use this green option.  That's
why we've made it so that everyone from beginners to frame check processors can use it in a wide range of
ways.  i
think i have an opinion  So we've
made it easy to customize the
data
that's output.I checked and found that the
processing time doesn't change that much, but if
you save a lot of data, the
output file will
more than double.
You need to select a profile that you think is correct.
Then create the distribution result and import it into Time
Inex
Expo World,
and you will see a French timer like this
.
Just by looking at it, you can tell what kind of attack it is, when and
where it's the accessor.
If
you can
use the feed information and judge whether or not it has been detected,
you can create a stack or a
spank, and
you can also create a dashboard or a timeline like this
with the latest functions.
We can also provide a summary of the results of that HTML At
the end of the test, the
date on which you had the highest number of
incidents, when the incident occurred, which
devices were
compromised, and what kind of
attack was
used.
Just by looking at the defaults, you can generally
understand, so
I think the Bull Team will be able to respond to the incident very quickly
, and this single update
is all
thanks to Mr.
HB and Mr. Takai.
Of course, if there are more etymologies than necessary,
it will be difficult to
confirm,
so
it's better to tune it or something like that, but we scan it so that it
can be detected to some extent.
Without it
, I think it would be possible to detect Tao attacks and behavioral attacks.So
, in the end, it
will be necessary for an expert to confirm it with the monasticism.A
simple example is
the creation of an administrator
account.  or whether it
is
an account created by an attacker or
not.
I'm often asked what it is, so
I compared the main features and
stopped here
.
As for reversal advice, first of all
, I think it's better to go through the whole name in Rome because it will
eat up in the order of your level.  There are people who spend their time
digging deeper into your technique or something about you, who appears
first, but
it's very important that you put on your overalls first.
If you come up with a file name or something like this Peppet keyword,
if you create a word that matches Inders and
search Grape, you will find
other
evidence.
I think that there are many people who are in charge of Excel if possible, but it's
not for frenzied research, so I use
time eye nex borders and other
stags as much as possible.  I think it's better if you contact me, and I'll
fix it.The
function I'm thinking of making from now on is to do
periodic tests on a square terminal
and send the results to cm, or something like
Windows.  In addition to event talks, we are
thinking about cloud tools and communication and guidance log attack detection, etc. Today we will officially
release a new tool
.
It's developed in an interesting language. It
's a simple ticket language like Python,
but
it can be compiled into C
, so it's
very fast and
safe like Dust.
I'm thinking of creating an analysis function
[Music]
For example,
a timeline of videos like weather,
a process tree visualization of malicious processes like edr, etc.
If possible, I'd like to use machine learning to analyze their behavior.
with analysis  And
finally, if there are
people who want to study more or want to contribute in some way,
there are many
things I can do for them.
The team's
C2 framework and other such attack
tools are by far the most numerous, so from now on,
if we don't create more Blue Team tools so that we won't lose to attackers, I
think we'll be in a state of losing forever
.
If you don't mind, please join us. Yamato: If you
don't want to contribute to Shige Security and want
to create a tool that you
can use yourself, I think you should
definitely
create one.
So, I'm open to the public now that it would be nice if I could make a lot of things.I think that
it will not only contribute to the community,
but it will also be useful
for me.It will take 30 minutes
.
Thank you
very much, everyone.
[Applause]