[Music]
[Music] Hello everyone. Welcome to
the 10th Cyber ​​Security
Conference Code Blue 2022.
On
behalf of the Executive Committee, I would like to
extend a warm welcome to all of you who have come to the Shibuya Parco Building and to all of you
who have participated
online.
I am currently staying for a long period of time at a university called
urv
, located in the city of Tarragona in the
Catalona region of Spain, on an overseas music research program starting in May of this year
.
Many of the ruins of the island
have been designated as UNESCO World Heritage
Sites.  Thank you for your support.
First of all,
there are more than 30 companies, from top management to horses
.
Sponsor companies,
thank you very much for your support
.
Thank you very much to Yuji Ukai and all the other reviewers who have given
us the samelevel of review.
Also
, as I'm sure you've all seen, there
are many student volunteers who have helped with the operation of this
event. Thank you very much.
I would like to express
my
gratitude to all
of you who participated.
Shinoda
: If
you ask me
, it's been 10 miracles.
From
the proposal of the latest scientifically advanced technology
to the highly social topic of fake press releases, everyone agrees that it is filled with a wide range of fields and a high level of expertise.
Among them, I had Neil Wire
, a regular customer with a 20-year career who has blown away with Black Hat, for the
keynote speech at the plenary session.
At this time in October,
he sacrificed that, and he came all
the way from the United States and Lake City to
Japan for the plenary session.
As a family conference
, I think this Code Blue has grown sufficiently.Congratulations to all of you,I
wonder how long it's been since you've had a face-to-face meeting like
this.Until last year, as you know, it was held only online due to corona measures.
I missed the machines.
This networking party
will be held for the first time in
3 years. It seems that there will be an exhibition booth for the first time in 3 years. Please enjoy it.
I don't think
so.The 18-meter LED panel you're
looking at is a large device that can withstand the outside light,
and it's the first permanent installation in Japan
.  It was 100,000 yen
, so if you are tired from the meeting,
I would like you to rest your eyes on the scenery of Shibuya while enjoying a free cup of coffee
.
I hope
everyone will enjoy the face-to-face Code Blue for the first time in three years
. I hope that
your network will expand on this occasion
.
[Applause]
[Music]
Hello everyone. I'm Kana Shinoda, the founder of Code Blue
.
Thank you, Mr. Kikuchi. Thank you very
much.
It's been 10 years since Code Blue raised its voice in the air that the Tokyo Olympics were decided.  Since it's our
10th anniversary,
we talk about various things on various occasions and in various places, and
this year we have 30 student staff members
.  I got a sticker from , but it was
worn out, so I got a new one this year.
He told me with great
joy that it's been that long
.
With that kind of feeling, Code Blue has been held by gathering all
kinds of young people and
various people.I think it's been 10
years.  I think there are some people
who have been able to meet face-to-face
like this, and there are people who are
online.
I would like Mr.
Motokawa from Hitachi Systems to take the podium.  Hi, I'm Carr, a former employee of Hitachi Systems
. Good morning.
I would like to start with a strange analogy
.
Around the year 2000, there was a war in the Middle East.
Boots on the Brown When I was asked not
to come to the scene, it was
the members of the Self-Defense Forces who went to the scene.At
that time,
I thought that everyone had to go to cyberspace,
so I started Black Hat Japan.
The first year was very difficult, and from the second year,
Kana Shinoda, who I mentioned earlier, joined
Blackout Japan and managed to continue several times
. After a
while, Code Blue
started.
I
couldn't continue, but
Code Blue is already in its 10th year this year
.
Mr. Dobleu is a
Japanese person, and there is Japan's first cybersecurity
conference, but I think it's a meeting
where everyone on the earth can say goodbye to the cyberspace field, because it's a boots-on-the-cultivation area
.
It's still early in the morning,
so the
venue may feel a bit disorganized, but
I hear that many
people are connected online.  By
all means, I hope that everyone here and everyone
participating
online can protect cyberspace.
The speaker is Mr.
Millwire, who
was a staff member of Blackout Japan
and has been active for a
long
time
.
giving a speech
[applause]