uh welcome to scaling the security
researcher to eliminate open source
security vulnerabilities once and for
all
um my name is Jonathan lychu I am a
software engineer a software security
researcher I am the first ever Dan
Kaminsky fellow
um I'm a GitHub star get up security
Ambassador and you can find me on
Twitter at jaylaichu and uh on GitHub at
the same handle
um so before I uh start I just want to
put a brief disclaimer up
um uh first off I'm sponsored by GitHub
they give me a little bit so I just have
to state that legally and then also we
do discuss a SAS tool in this talk but
it's available for free for open source
and you can use it in your open source
research as well
um this work is supported by the Dan
Kaminsky fellowship at human security
um for those of you who don't know Dan
um uh Dan was best known for a massive
vulnerability that he found in DNS back
in 2008. he was also known for his
kindness and compassion in the
information security Community he
tragically passed away last year and the
Dan Kaminsky Fellowship
um I also never got to meet Dan
unfortunately and the Dan Kaminsky
Fellowship was created to celebrate uh
dance memory and Legacy by funding open
source work that makes the world a
better and more secure place and so this
is the work that I've been doing for the
past year under this Fellowship
spoilers
I uh generated a bunch of pull requests
to fix the vulnerability zip slip across
the Java ecosystem in particular I
generated 152 pull requests across the
Java system
um but there's uh there's a lot to the
story so uh let's talk about how we got
here
um this story of bulk automated pull
request generation to fix
vulnerabilities at scale started with a
simple vulnerability
um and the vulnerability was this
vulnerability it was the use of HTTP in
my company's Gradle build to resolve
dependencies and I found this code and
I'm like how did this code get here and
the reason that it got here was I'd
copied and pasted this chunk of code
from an open source Repository
and the reason that HTTP is or https is
important is because if you don't use
https in your build infrastructure you
can result in an attacker in the middle
uh vulnerability and they can compromise
the contents of your artifacts in flight
and compromise the your supply chain
your CI CD pipeline for your for your
project
and this is an example of that same
vulnerability existing in um uh Maven uh
where it exists in the download for your
dependencies that are used for the
compiler and test dependencies and so if
that jar file is compromised mid-flight
it can result in it being
um uh you having malicious code executed
in your CI CD pipeline or on your
developer machines
this is an example of where it exists in
artifact upload which usually is
associated with credentials and so an
attacker could use those credentials to
replace artifacts on your artifact
server and this vulnerability was
everywhere across the Java ecosystem
it existed in projects like spring
Red Hat kotlin Apache jet brains Jenkins
Gradle groovy elastic Eclipse Foundation
um it also impacted Oracle the NSA
LinkedIn and stripe so organizations
around the industry
when I so Maven sonotype is the npm to
the JavaScript ecosystem or the PIP to
the python ecosystem sonotype is that to
the Java ecosystem and when I reached
out to them they said that 25 of their
traffic was still using hdp to resolve
dependencies instead of https this is in
29 June of 2019.
so how do we fix this vulnerability
I reached uh pushed forward an
initiative that on January 15 2020 all
the major artifact servers in the Java
ecosystem would decommission support for
HTTP in favor of https only
and
um the major artifact servers uh decided
yes we will do this and they published
their blog post announcing that they
would do this
um in a coordinated manner
however
uh I reached out to sonotype again and
in January of 2020 only a few days
before the plan decommission of support
of HTTP in favor of Rage GPS only they
said that 20 of their traffic was still
using http
so
you can imagine what might have happened
on uh January 15 2020
broken software everywhere because uh
suddenly people's builds stopped working
um but
they stopped the bleeding
sorry
hang on
we stopped the bleeding but what about
the other repositories so these are the
only the most commonly used repositories
in the Java ecosystem Maven J Center
spring and Gradle plug-in portal other
organizations in the Java ecosystem host
their own artifact servers and they're
unlike npm or pip where there's one
Central repository the Java ecosystem
has been around for a long time and so
multiple other repositories have have
evolved to be used by organizations
around the world to host artifacts
so how do we fix the rest
and he said well let's just go to the
source of the problem and let's just fix
it in the repositories themselves let's
try bulk pull request generation to fix
this vulnerability
so how well the first thing that you
need to do is you need to find the
projects that are vulnerable because I
knew that it was everywhere but how do
you need a list of vulnerable projects
and so for that I wrote this code ql
query
um and it's very simple little bit of
code but it finds this vulnerability in
mavenpom files codeql scans hundreds of
thousands of Open Source projects
um and you can use it to find
vulnerabilities across open source
and for this very simple query
GitHub awarded me a 2 300 Bounty and so
that gave me a list of projects that
were vulnerable to this particular
vulnerability and then I wrote a pull
request generator to generate the fixes
to generate the pull request to fix this
vulnerability
and so the first pull request generator
was python based it was a wrapper over
github's Hub CLI it had one nasty
regular expression and a lot of logic
for bouncing off of github's rate
limiter
and this is the logic
um at a high level it's got an
underlying engine
um but it has all the logic for the
commit message and the regular
expression that's doing the
transformation
um and the file yeah fixing the
vulnerable files and this is the regular
expression and the reason that I used a
regular expression to fix XML files is
that if you use an XML parser
any XML parser that you parse your
source code into that XML parser and you
make a modification
will result in when you dump back out
will dump the source code dump the code
back out in the format of the parser not
the format the file originally came in
as
and so if you don't use a regular
expression unfortunately
the XML that you'd end up having fixed
the code in would end up with a massive
white space change across the entire
file and the maintainer who'd receive
that pull request would be like great
thank you so much for the contribution
you fixed a vulnerability
but you've changed the rest of the file
so we can't accept it so you need to
make targeted changes and so that only
leaves you with regular Expressions
unfortunately to fix this problem
but the problem is if you regularly use
regular Expressions to fix a problem
now you end up with two problems the
regular expression and the problem you
originally had
um regardless though it worked
I generated pull requests
um lots of them
um and here's an example of the diff
that was generated you can see the
simple replacement use of HTTP and https
in in the correct locations in this
Maven Palm files and I generated 1 596
pull requests across the Java ecosystem
and this was back in 2020
um as of 2022
um there's been about a 40 merge rate of
all these pull requests at this point
which is a pretty significant uh number
of vulnerable projects fixed across the
Java ecosystem
and for this work GitHub awarded me a
four thousand dollar Bounty from the
GitHub security lab bug Bounty program
so I got hooked on this idea of bulk
pull request generation as a solution to
fix vulnerabilities at scale across open
source
um this is my GitHub contribution graph
for 2020. and you can see there's two
major Peaks where I did these campaigns
um and you know had a and so
um it's just it's really cool to see the
you know the visual representation of
the work you're doing
so I have a problem
and the problem
um I have ADHD and that's not my problem
I don't believe that ADHD is a problem
but the problem is I love chasing
squirrels I love chasing vulnerabilities
and learning about them
um I will read GitHub security advisory
feeds or advisory feeds and I'll be
curious about a vulnerability
and I can find if I use GitHub codeql or
if I use GitHub code search I can find
those vulnerabilities everywhere so the
problem that I have is because I chase
squirrels I find too many security
vulnerabilities in open source
as an example this is a list of
vulnerabilities called zip slip and
we're going to get into what zip slip is
later I know I've mentioned it twice now
I'm going to mention a bunch of more
times we'll dig into what zip slip is
for those of you who don't know but this
is a pretty critical security
vulnerability and there are pages and
pages and pages of this alert for this
vulnerability in open source that you
can find just by going to lgtm.com and
punching and zip slip like you know
there's more of this than I can
reasonably report in open source so I'm
finding too many security
vulnerabilities so how do we get these
vulnerabilities fixed so they don't just
leave they don't just linger there we
need automation
to fix these vulnerabilities actually
get them fixed and not just be alerts
and so this is where
um I need automated Transformations at
massive scale
and so this is where open rewrite comes
in
normally when you're compiling source
code you have an the compiler produces
what's called an abstract syntax tree
it's a code or tree representation of
the source code
um and so if you want to make
modifications to that AST
um you can but the problem is that if
you were to dump that AST back out into
source code you'd lose all the
formatting you'll notice that the
spacing the tabs the comments all of
those things are gone because the
compiler doesn't care about those things
and so what open rewrite provides is a
format preserving abstract syntax tree
and so the source code and the tree map
back and forth to each other they are
the same thing you can transform back
and forth between the two of them
and in addition you can generate new
code that looks like the surrounding
code because the as the parser is
running and as the formatting is is
getting grabbed you're also capturing
the white space the tabs what the style
is from this code base and so it learns
what the code base is and so it can
generate new code
that uses the tabs or uses spaces
and it's also fully type attributed
um so the reason that's important right
we don't know just looking at this code
is that log4j slf4j log back right that
might be really critical to know what
type that is I know I can't imagine
there ever being a massive security
vulnerability in a logging framework
that impacts the entire industry
uh log4j anybody
um anyways uh so and also open rewrites
AST is both syntactically and
semantically aware
um that graph that grid on the left side
is the amount of data that's Inc there's
actually 6 000 nodes missing from that
image on the left because it would just
be fuzz so with the amount of data you
end up with a lot of data and a lot of
ability to un um to manipulate that data
to do uh cool transformations
and then if you want to add new code
into the AST to modify it the problem is
that even simple little changes in code
create complex asts so let's say that I
want to inject this little bit of code
to fix a vulnerability the vulnerability
zip slip this is the code that you want
to fix this vulnerability
well you need to place this in the code
in the context of the surrounding code
so open rewrite
has a templating engine
and the templating engine allows you to
have variables and it also comes with a
coordinate system that lets you state I
want to place this chunk of code into
the AST
after this statement
and that unlocks us the ability to
specifically Target a specific location
in the AST
and generate and add that fix in and
this is the fix for zip slip and again
we'll go into what zip slip is in a
little bit later
so what's possible now
what other vulnerabilities can we fix
with the unlock that open rewrite
provides
I'm going to talk to you all about three
vulnerabilities
um temporary directory hijacking partial
path traversal and zip slip and how I
applied openrate to fixing these
vulnerabilities across open source
so the first vulnerability we're going
to talk about is temporary directory
hijacking
temporary directory hijacking
um the temporary system temp directory
on unix-like systems is shared between
all users so
um and the impact of that is if you
write sensitive files to the temporary
directory and you haven't set the
correct posix permissions on those files
any other local users can view the
contents of those directories those
files or directories
and this is temporary directory
hijacking as it appears in the Java
language or well what you'll see and the
reason this pattern appears is that
prior to Java 1.7 there did not exist an
API to create temporary directories
so people created temporary files using
the Java's temporary direct file
creation API which does create a a
csprnj g generated securely generated
name for the file but then they'd call
delete and then they called maker and
this has a vulnerability in it and the
reason that you'd find this code again
and again and again is because if you
said I need to create a temp directory
how do I do that and punch that into
Google
if you'd ask stack Overflow you'd get
vulnerabilities
and why is this vulnerable well the
reason this is vulnerable is because
there's a race condition here
the race condition exists because maker
if it fails because another user has
beaten
you to creating that directory
then it returns false it does not throw
an exception
so the fix or one potential fix that
you'll see is people putting this maker
into a guard that throws an i o
exception however this is insufficient
still because that maker call does not
set the correct posix permissions and so
the contents of that directory are still
exposed to other local users and so it's
still this vulner this is still
vulnerable to what's called temporary
directory infra local information
disclosure
and so what's the real fix well the real
fix is to use the new well very old but
the one point Java will introduced in
Java 1.7 Java 1.7 is very very old it's
been around for a very long time you can
safely use this API and this both
creates a directory and also sets the
correct posix permissions on the
directory
and so I've gotten a couple several cves
for this vulnerability and I figured
okay let's see what I can do you know
I'm sure I've gotten a bunch of CVS for
it but let's try to just fix this
vulnerability across open source and so
that's when I applied temporary
directory uh pull request generation and
for this particular vulnerability I've
generated over 64 pull requests across
the Java system to fix this
vulnerability
and so what does this look like well you
can see that we're deleting the
vulnerable lines and replacing it with
that one safe line but also remember
when I was talking to you about
temporary directory information
disclosure we can also fix that by
deleting those if blocks and replacing
it with that one non-vulnerable line
um and that's all due to the power of
open rewrite
so vulnerability number two is a
vulnerability called partial path
traversal
and partial path traversal exists let's
assume that you have two users on a
system you have user Sam and user
Samantha
and you want a Sandbox as a developer
software developer you want to sandbox
your logic
to user Sam
um partial past reversal allows an
attacker access to a sibling directory
with the same prefix so starting again
we have user Sam and we've tried to
sandbox our logic to only that and use a
Samantha the reason that you an attacker
could access user Samantha is because
they share the same prefix
and so this is the partial path
traversal vulnerability
well why is this vulnerable well the
reason this logic is vulnerable is
because when you call
um when you call uh
the method get canonical path on a file
it returns a string
that looks like this and you'll notice
there's something missing from that
string
it's that trailing slash that was
originally passed
and so when you call starts with so get
canonical path does what you normally
wanted to do it normalizes the path
um uh it normalizes the path so you
remove the dot dot slash the path to
versatile payloads
um but it has this characteristic where
it removes that trailing slash that you
need for starts with comparisons
and so when we have this Parent
Directory this intended sandbox
directory user Sam
um and then we have an attacker payload
come in past reversal Samantha slash baz
when get canonical path gets called on
that
we end up with user slash Samantha slash
baz starts with user Sam and that does
indeed pass so this i o exception does
not get thrown
and so what's the fix for partial paths
reversal
well the fix for this is that you one
solution is to re-add the file separator
character back into the string for the
starts with call
um but the better fix is to use
um the Java path API which was
introduced in Java 1.7 which does these
starts with comparison correctly on the
correct path
so how do we find this vulnerability
so the way to find this vulnerability is
to look for the Java string starts with
call and then look for the subject and
argument where the get canonical path is
the argument being passed
but we want to make sure that we're not
fixing non-vulnerable code so we also
want to look for cases where that file
that separator uh character is passed
and not fix it in this case
but it can't be that easy right
well developers write code in a lot of
different ways so what if the developer
writes their code like this
where they extract that get canonical
path to a to a variable
or they put the parent into a variable
as well how do we or they put the safe
version like this how do we determine if
this is vulnerable or not in this case
well we need this New Concept it's
called data flow analysis
data flow analysis allows us to track
the variable assignments of the data as
it flows through the application as
we're looking at the AST in the source
code as we're making the modification
and it lets us track you know this say
that this this variable is safe so we
don't need to fix this vulnerability and
dataflow can even handle intermediate
variable assignments as well
so data flow uncovers hard to find
vulnerabilities and helps us prevent
false positives
and
um as a show of hands have any of you
written code ql
okay so if you've written any code ql
um this is designed this API for data
flow analysis is designed to be very
similar to codeql's data flow analysis
because I've written code ql before also
let me translate my knowledge easier um
but hopefully your knowledge can be
transferred easier as well by using this
API
and so when we put all this together
um you can find that this is vulnerable
this logic and fix it appropriately
because of the data flow analysis
um I want to talk about an example case
um there was a vulnerability in the AWS
Java SDK
um and this is the vulnerable you can
see the partial path to versatile
vulnerability right there because
there's that starts with call on get
canonical path
um they were using this logic to
determine if a as you're downloading the
contents of it sorry as you're
downloading the contents of an AWS
bucket to your local machine
um the entire contents is that is the
AWS bucket key a past reversal payload
that is attempting to escape the
destination directory
and so they were using this logic leaves
root as a guard
that tries to make sure that that does
not happen
um and so they did fix it there is a cve
they they're but of course a little bit
of vulnerability disclosure drama plays
out uh in any good story
um the AWS team said we'd love to award
you a bug Bounty however we need you to
sign a non-disclosure agreement
and I said I normally don't agree to
non-disclosure agreements can I read it
before before potentially agreeing
and the AWS team came back to me and
said we're unable to share the bug
Bounty program non-disclosure agreement
since it and other contract documents
are considered sensitive by the legal
team
um
for any of you who played Pokemon
um so yes that was a little bit of I
still have not been paid by them
it's an ongoing story
um we'll see what happens
um so the third vulnerability is a
vulnerability called zip slip
um now zip slip
um we discussed a couple of times zip
slip is a path traversal vulnerability
while unplucking zip files zip files are
basically a key value pair where the key
is the director of the file that you
want to unpack to and the value is the
contents of the file but the key if it's
a controlled by an attacker because
you've been provided a malicious zip
file
could be a path to versatile payload
and so this is zip slip this bit of code
well why is this vulnerable
it's vulnerable because you're using
this entry this named entry in the zip
zip file as the the way to create a file
and so if that uh is a past reversal
payload it can escape this directory and
overwrite the contents of uh you know
bin bash or something similar and that
can allow an attacker to achieve remote
code execution so ziplip is a critical
vulnerability in the right scenarios
zip slip is complicated and the reason
that it's complicated is that
this is a valid fix but the problem is
that although this is a valid fix
this is also a valid fix
and again we don't want to fix code
that's not vulnerable so how do we
determine if we we're looking at this
case or this case when we're looking
just at the abstract syntax tree
in code and so we need this New Concept
again which is called control flow
analysis
so control flow analysis allows us to
differentiate between these two bits of
code that vulnerable and the
non-vulnerable code
and control flow analysis is a graph
it's control flow analysis is
represented by two data or two primary
data structures basic blocks which make
up the set of contiguous operations that
are going to occur in a program without
a jump occurring
and then condition nodes where
conditional logic will occur and there
will be a branch in the execution of the
program
and so by generating the uh the control
flow graph
for a program like this we can look at
the graph and determine that there is a
check in place
for this vulnerability and so we don't
need to fit we don't need to generate a
fix for this vulnerability
and so when you put this all together we
can determine that there is a
vulnerability here
and that we need to fix it and so
generate the fix for the vulnerability
and then we can even do more complicated
things due to the power that open
rewrite provides and you know even clean
up the surrounding code a little bit too
so let's get to the pull request
generation part of this talk
um if you have security vulnerabilities
everybody gets a pull request
so let's talk about the problems with
pull request generation and one of the
problems you'll run into is how fast you
can generate pull requests across uh
GitHub
so when you're generating pull requests
uh you need to do three there's uh six
steps and there's three main three major
categories file i o which is basically
free because it's happening on your
local machine git operations which are
free on GitHub and do not incur rate
limit and then GitHub API calls which
are rate Limited
so the first thing you need to do is
check out the source code and download
the code Repository
and then you need to branch and apply
the diff that was generated by open
rewrite and then commit the change
then you want to Fork the repository on
GitHub
rename the repository on GitHub and the
reason that renaming the repository is
important is because when you're
generating tens hundreds or thousands of
pull requests you're going to end up
with name collisions and GitHub won't
let you Fork repositories when you
already have a repository with that same
name so you need to change every
repository's name to something that's
unique
and then you need to push the change
and then you need to create the pull
request on GitHub
and so you'll notice there are three
three API calls and GitHub asks that you
wait at least one second between each
one of these
so that's three times the number of pull
requests you're trying to generate
number of seconds but then there's a
secondary and tertiary rate limit that
they document which is one of them is a
header that says please back off until
this point and then a third rate limit
which is basically
just stop for right now and it's not
documented like how long you're supposed
to wait so
throw a sleep in there and hope for the
best basically is what your what's your
best option is at that point so GitHub
if any of you are in the audience uh if
you could stop Rave limiting or limit
the rate limiting of your API it would
be great and make my life a lot easier
um so yes
so we've made it this far
the vulnerability has been detected the
style has been detected the code has
been fixed the diff has been generated
and the rate limit has been bypassed
um at this point I'm going to enter so
how do we fix this for all the
repositories across open source
at this point I'm going to introduce you
to Modern
is free for open source projects
um they've indexed about 7 000
repositories
um and it lets you run open rewrite
Transformations at scale and it
generates and lets you update those pull
requests
um there are over 800 recipes that
modern and open read write contain
inside of it and it lets you generate
pull requests one of the use cases for
example is let's say you need to update
your version of uh spring you can do
that but the problem is that if you want
to use the latest version of spring and
we all you know security practitioners
know that running the latest version of
spring in your Java applications is
really important well for a lot of
developers if you want to upgrade your
version of spring you actually also have
to upgrade your test framework
and the test framework the latest
version of spring will only be tested by
junit 5.
and there was an API break major API
breaking change between junit 4 and J
unit 5. and so you may not think of your
testing framework as a security uh like
what version of the secure testing
framework you're using is a security
um you know blocker to security but it
really can be when you can't upgrade the
version of spring because you're running
low on running your old tests so there's
a different there's a open rewrite
transformation for migrating all your
tests from the a previous June version
to the latest version of junit
and it also enables bulk pull request
generation
for across either your organization or
across open source
um as an example if you have a list of
this is an actual result set that I was
going to generate pull requests for you
can say I want to generate this pull
requests uh as a fork from a fork you
can set the commit name you can set the
pull request title you can provide the
get the commit title you can supply your
gpg key and then off to the races it'll
it'll generate
all the pull requests for you right
within the SAS
um and uh so this this is how I
generated all these pull requests the
most recent set of pull requests
but there's more than just seven
thousand repositories in the world how
do we find the other vulnerable projects
well this is where code ql comes in
code ql index a hundred thousand open
source projects and thirty five thousand
Java projects so you can write a code
Cloud query and get a list of vulnerable
projects
and then using that list of projects
that I you now know are vulnerable if
you provide that list into this CSV file
in uh that's uh in uh under this GitHub
repository
modern after they've ingested this list
will begin to index those repositories
and you can run your recipes that you've
created across these repositories that
you've identified this vulnerability in
so finally let's go generate some open
source pull requests
that's what I did
um and some of the statistics for
temporary directory hijacking I
generated 64 pull requests with a 25
merge rate
50 pull requests for partial past
reversal with a 22 merge rate and zip
slip with 152 pull requests with a 20
merge rate now I looked I haven't
updated these statistics for about a
month but I did this campaign in August
of this year so the 40 merge rate was
from 2019. so hopefully we will see more
things get merged as maintainers notice
their notification feeds and start
merging pull requests it just takes time
at this point
um but in 2022 I've generated 600 new
pull requests and in my history I've
generated over 5 200 pull requests to my
name
one unlucky project was the recipient of
all three pull requests
um uh yes and this is my cam this is my
GitHub uh uh profile uh for this year
um
so let's talk about some best practices
of rock pull request generation
the first thing is messaging
you're reaching out to the so there's
this saying
all software problems are people
problems in disguise
and we are automating the generation of
pull requests to fix a vulnerability at
scale maintainers don't like Bots very
much developers they like real people
but yeah so you need to be considerate
of communicating both why you're doing
this but also the impact and then I
think that you're a real person willing
to communicate with them
um so very important to maintain that
human element in this in this Dynamic um
even though you are throwing an
automated solution to the problem
and so some simpler lessons sign off on
your commits
um and the reason you want to sign off
on your commits this is what a git
commit sign off looks like
um you just put this in the commit body
and you might ask well why do I want to
sign off on my commits well there was a
bunch of lawsuits in open source a few
years ago tldr
lawyers
um
otherwise you'll get your commits
rejected by evil dragon bureaucrats
um
be a good committee
gpg sign your commits
um this is what it looks like it just
adds that verified badge otherwise
you'll end up like Linus torvald who has
been impersonated on GitHub several
times
um c-com seacom is a commit format for
commit messages
um for vulnerable ability fixes so
um if you want a way to lay out your
messages this might be a good thing to
use
there are uh Lesson Four there are risks
to using your personal GitHub account
by show of hands is anybody here
familiar with github's angry unicorn
no okay only me this is what gets what's
what shows up when you've broken GitHub
or something's gone wrong
this is my GitHub profile for most of
2020. I broke my GitHub account I
although I did break my GitHub account I
still recommend using a personal account
for this as it keeps that human element
involved in this Dynamic and maintainers
are less likely to be upset if it and
they're more likely to be upset if it
looks like it's coming from a company or
a bot than it is if it's coming from a
real person
lesson five coordinate with GitHub
before attempting reach out to GitHub
that's what I did
um and let them know that you're going
to do this they want to know they want
to help you out
lesson six consider the implications
shortly after beginning this campaign I
received this issue against my GitHub
account uh jaylaichu security research
is this responsible disclosure
now I use the new the more nuanced term
coordinated disclosure but the answer is
no this is not responsible disclosure it
is full public disclosure of a security
vulnerability in an open source project
you are odang a maintainer potentially
unfortunately the the alternative for me
is to not report the vulnerability at
all because there's only so much time
that I have in my day
and I am overwhelmed
and so I believe that this is a solid
solution to fix these vulnerabilities at
scale and best use my time
to fix the to actually get these
vulnerabilities fixed
so in conclusion
as security researchers and security
practitioners
I believe we have an obligation to
society
we know these vulnerabilities are out
there we've seen them in pen test
reports we've written them up ourselves
we've been on the receiving end we know
how to audit this code
spoiler
most software developers don't watch
black hat talks or Defcon talks or code
blue talks
most developers are focused on
developing the code to the features that
they've been asked to develop
there's this assistant there's this
statistic that GitHub provided for every
500 developers you have one security
researcher
we are heavily outnumbered as security
practitioners
and so I believe truly that automated
bulk pull request generation is the best
way for us to scale our knowledge of
math science technology to fix
vulnerabilities across open source at
scale and actually see
these vulnerabilities
fixed finally
and so with that I want to leave you
with one final quote
this is from Dan Kaminski it's on his
Twitter profile and it's there to this
day
we can fix it we have the technology
okay we need to create the technology
all right the policy guys are mucking
with the technology
relax
we're on it
and so uh just some final things uh
learn code ql it's an incredibly
powerful language
um contribute to open rewrite and you
can deploy your security fixes at scale
if you want to discuss this with other
people join the GitHub security lab and
open right slack channels and
um then also if you're interested in
open source security at in general
consider becoming involved in the open
source security Foundation there are
working group meetings not necessarily
in the right time zone for everybody in
Japan but there are working group
meetings that are happening on a daily
basis or on a weekly basis to discuss
the biggest issues facing open source
security around the end around the
industry
and with that I want to thank human my
employer for enabling the Dan Kaminsky
Fellowship modern for working with me
Lydia Giuliano the speak black hat
speaking coach that I worked with and
Sham my intern who came up with some of
the graphics you saw for control flow
analysis
um and this is me so thank you all