okay my name is Anya Pittman I'm from
the technical university in Munich
Germany and what I'm going to talk about
today is what are the kind of a nicer
way of abstracting and kind of
representing and realizing a Squatch
routing policies for your BGP routing so
this kind of goes back to some of the
things that we've been talking about
here today or yesterday that a lot of
people should be doing filtering and if
you leave out one session then you screw
up all of your filtering and what is a
way to actually get around and doing
some of these things in a right way so
let's get moving with kind of just
briefly reviewing what do I mean with a
routing policy here so in some sense if
you have your a is over here then really
what is the routing policy all about
well it is all about what woods should
you actually accept here and you should
probably make sure that you don't accept
routes that you shouldn't be accepting
and then you probably want to manipulate
them then they need to be sent out then
again manipulated them and then you need
to decide which routes you actually want
to set out and all of this the way that
it has done for all of the various
different bgp sessions is what your
routing policy is now the problem was
the way that routing policies are
currently handed in my view at least
I'll that they are unfortunately often
is specified because think about it if
you are operating a network well do you
have your documentation is it in all of
the various different bgp statements
that you have outer on your reuters a
div is to actually write them down and i
think that that is one of the major
problem that the root policy is ill
specified and really the database is a
network itself and then you have some
kind of a problem on one of your
customer links you go in to manipulate
it and suddenly the routing policy
changed again a lot of the things our
customers
you have to go about think about which
kind of BGP statements to tweak in order
to figure out ah this is how I do
various different aspects of it now the
goal of this work here is that we get
away from some of the manual
configurations here and actually go
about in being able to kind of take
apart the AS Byatt routing policy into
various different pieces so that we on
the one hand racing abstraction level
but on the other hand you are still able
to actually automatically generate all
of the different pieces of the
configurations for not just one word a
vendor that actually multiple out the
windows and this is what I'm going to
talk about today so what do I mean by
wooden policy and I have some various
different examples that actually
contribute to a routing policy what are
they well on the one hand you need to
make sure that you actually wanna all of
your business relationship which means
that you get to peering right then you
probably want to make sure that you have
to write kind of preferences set so that
the customer odds are preferred over the
peering rods it's at her but there's
another kind of a trend going on which
is that really btp policy has gotten
quite a bit more complicated and that is
some of the peering customers transit
customers actually do want some amount
of control about a routing and actually
that's possible that's what all of this
community hands on is all about so that
you can actually give some amount of
control about the traffic engineering to
each one of the customers we've seen
that earlier today when we were talking
about the ipv6 would you humming and
then there are additional services and
that is maybe you want to be able to
actually do some black holing in order
to get around adidas attacked IP address
but of course they are promised that
because really what you have if you have
new customers that want all of this you
need to kind of see arm this is what is
customized man maybe not just one maybe
this one and this is something that
everybody has have so what we really
have is that the policy doesn't just
consists of one statement of BGP sets
but if we
is a set of policies that should apply
network-wide like but bogan filtering
Martian theaters earnings etc and then
you have some maybe value you added
services or maybe services that
everybody is supposed to have so really
the routing policy is a set of policies
and services so let's take an example
and let's think about how some of these
services are actually realized so let's
look a black hole or do you might want
to do it whether it all comes down to
the point that you probably want to have
some kind of your trigger in order to
say okay now I want to black hole all of
the traffic for this specific IP address
how do you do it well you use the
community as a trigger then on the
rooters you actually rewrite the next
hop so that all of the traffic is
dropped to the death knell interface but
the problem is of course you don't want
to allow everybody to do that because
otherwise you have a nice new details at
hacky so you actually want to make sure
that you have some amount of
authorization here and you also want to
deploy some other safeguard here which
is were no expert so how is it realized
what they are various different steps to
it you want to make sure that on the
ingress you actually allow this black
hole community only for the specific
customers that actually are supposed to
be able to use it you also want to make
sure that root for which it's being used
are only the ones that are actually in
the authorized set then you need to be
able to rewrite the next hop and you
want to make sure that you actually
don't advertise this row to any further
so on egress you have to make sure that
you do featuring of all of these black
holes so what is it what I mean with an
atomic unit of a BGP policy or a service
here so willing what you want to be able
to do is probably say for this specific
set of BGP sessions that I actually want
to identify in some kind of a network
specific independent way but let's say
ah those are the one sessions at
after service selected we all that have
or appeals all those that are customers
and I basically want to be able to
select them but I want to be able to do
this in some kind of a vendor
independent cut of a boy and then once I
have identified the set I actually do
want to apply some kind of a fair trade
what future do I mean where you may want
to say is this really the community
being said here or is this part of a
specific asset or is it part of a
specific prefix here now if you want to
apply this video that is again vendor
specific you can't apply for the spinner
independently and then you want to do
some actions let's say if we write
parameters like what we just had where
we wanted to rewrite the next hop or add
the community to it and this is again
vendor specific so one of the questions
that we were asking ourself is how can
we split this wing vendor-independent
part from the vendor specific pieces
down here and the way that we wanted to
slice and dice the soil problem of BGP
configuration is to say let's take the
elements that are network specific and
put them into an LED fog database here
so we have a network module which
contains the description of our various
different network elements and then we
wanted to help her policy and service
module which basically takes the
abstract definitions of the various
different individual routing policies
and services and this can be done now in
a way that is completely network
independent and vendor-independent and
then we wanted to have can't of course
will as any of this without any specific
kind of her Brenda treatment and so we
needed to have kind of a library of
vendor specific code fragments that can
then be combined to actually realize the
set of policies to be used for specific
sessions and all of this is actually
then accomplished via a configurator
which takes these various different
databases
imports and then produces various
different pieces of configuration
convicted or actually produces our psl
now you might want to ask why didn't we
just use up here cell and the main
reason for that is that what we are
doing here is actually adding another
layer of abstraction on top of the kind
of wave capabilities that are psl has
because really what we wanted to be able
to do is we want to kind of separate the
process of BGP configuration into the
various different steps that can be done
by different people like the network
module that can be maintained by the
staff that is actually responsible for
selling our and configuring the network
you don't need a BGP expert for that the
BTB expert should be able to kind of set
up the device different policies and
services here and maybe help us actually
putting together the configured road
that is being stored over here but they
should not be involved in actually doing
the day-to-day kind of maintenance of
the various different sessions and so
this is why we choose this let's
actually go in and kind of get away from
this high level description into a more
concrete description so let's take a
look at the network module one by one
and the idea here is if we actually
wanted to capture the current state of
the network and also the current service
subscriptions and so the elements that
we have over here are Rooter beauties
neighbor session and services now why do
we have our neighbor intercession here
well most of the peering sessions most
of the customers are not realized we are
a single EGP session but actually we are
multiple ones that usually have the same
kind of characteristics and you want to
be able to that to kind of formulate
that you want to have the same kind of
policy on every single of these sessions
and so that's why was the b2b neighbor
and set policies for all of them so how
does this look like let's say we have a
Rooter but just being our houses our
name loopback IP address is located in a
different city and has a certain system
specification for example in this case
or June OS was a specific ions on OS
version here now why do we need this
information about the location but
because maybe you want to actually
tagged any kind of a word that has been
originated from this route are busy
location information that it comes from
the region you are almost specifically
Germany and so this is where you can get
this kind of information for later on
now a b2b naval is being set up over
here which has certain labor is so this
is then being used to actually generate
the BGP statements one then you have a
certain Ava type that can be used to
finally figure out how to realize the
BGP peering policy and then you have a
set of sessions that is associated visit
in this case only one and here we have
Fletcher import and export statements
now these feet are important export
statements are being not realized by the
system itself but here we take advantage
of the fact that will see existing
databases and off yourself we have a
nice way of manipulating filters so we
actually will be use this and it also
gives us the ability with access to the
data bases here that if you put our
changes you don't have to go about and
to change the configuration here but
actually you just as a customer can or
change your element in the database and
then this is being picked up and updated
on the rooters automatically at some
later point how does the session look
like well you have over here your name
which is being referenced above you have
the location on which rather it is you
have the remote address and then you
have a set of services over here which
may apply
to the session over here now you have
services that can be specified on the
neighbor or you can have it on the
session now if it's something is
specified on the neighbor that is then
it is automatically inherited by all of
the sessions alternatively it can be
overwritten and you can have the ability
to kind of say okay let's say we want to
actually half a specific lid over here
and for those worlds for that which this
video applies we want to set in net
value of 2000 for a different theater a
different Matt value and a different
kind of a default value if none of these
filters over here actually applies now
given that we know how a network is
being specified we can go about and
actually worried about our policy so
what did I say about the task here well
what we really want to have is some kind
of an abstraction so that we can express
the policy what do we do when we say a
policy what you usually mean with the
policy is actually that you want to
select the session set and then we want
to apply certain vgp operations on them
and so this is exactly the kind of
elements that we have support for in
this kind of a data basically
description that we are proposing here
so we have two top level elements policy
and services and here's an example of
how such a service could actually look
like and the service that we have here
is black hole so what did we say when we
were kind of looking at the service we
said that we want to have an
authorization here and so one of the
things is you have a parameter here
which is a black hole set for which you
can this is the kind of data that
restricts you on to the kind of prefixes
for which you can actually apply this so
this could for example and tell all of
the more specifics of the world said
that that Kozma may actually have or be
defined in some other kind of a break
then for all of the English direction
over here you want to be able to kind of
say if this
customer or the spear has actually
subscribed to the service black hole
that's the condition that we have over
here then you actually want to be able
to perform a check for the black hole
community and if so then you actually
want to realize the black hole service
and for that we are using two different
fragments over here that actually
realize the necessary bgp filtering and
the necessary bgp manipulations here if
it's not the case that the service over
here is being sent then just think that
you have to do is actually figure out
any world that might have this black
hole community said and this is why we
have this apartment over here which says
ingress Blackwell community deny which
means that this world will not be
accepted now there's one more thing to
point out and that is this service black
hole over here was actually kind of
conditioned on the fact that the service
black hole was actually booked by
somebody of course you have other kind
of sell policies that you want to
definitely realize and this is the
distinction that we are making up here
when we are talking about end force
policy which could be peering or Martian
pooja or bogan builder which will be
well as automatically for all sessions
independent of what the subscription
model would be and then you have the
available services which can be booked
and specified on a per session or foyer
neighbor basis now all of this of course
depends on the fact that you have a way
to actually realize the various
different bgp operations and that is a
task of the background model which
actually calculates the vendor specific
elements and such provides kind of just
a list of different aim fragments which
can be used to actually realize the
various different services and policies
and so how do we do this well we have
basically another kind of a database
which contains these and of course in
order to then customize
any of the various different statements
you have to be able to cross-reference
goes into the policy model as well as
into the network model in order to
figure out what are the specific values
to be used and since this is fairly
abstract let's look at an example again
in this example here what does it do
it's for cisco iOS and it actually
filters out the black hole community
here so what do we do we have a part
over here which actually sets the
neighbor statement over here based on
the remote IP address and the world map
route map in now the road map itself of
course has to have certain elements
which are being highlighted here so you
have to put it in some kind of a
relationship then you have to cut a
filter on the black hole set match the
community set the next help IP address
over here and then set the community no
export now there are various is specific
elements over here one is a road map
priority which is being used to actually
then combine the route maps into the
various from the various different
fragments into the right kind of
priority order so we're in terms of
prioritization the thing to keep in mind
here is that this system doesn't take
away the need to think about in what
order do we actually apply the various
different b2b statements but it helps
you to be able to do this once and not
have to redo it for every single PL for
every single session that you have to
set up now the continued means that this
is not a final decision so this wouldn't
be a denial or final accept but that
maybe you want to do some education and
manipulations here you of course also
may have to have some kind of theater
here and again we are taking advantage
of the fact that these photos can
actually be paralyzed param planetary
so for example you have the community
names that are being actually
constructed via an external database and
so you can even change those values if
you wanted to now of course what I've
shown you over here was only the part
for the cisco iOS but for juniors we
have a similar version as well as for
our psl and it's easily possible to
expand this for other would have enders
now once you have all of these various
different databases you can actually go
ahead and combine them and generate the
config lengths and so what does the cost
of this configurator it actually goes
ahead takes all of these three databases
checks for consistency combines the
various different atomic units into the
appropriate routing policy for every
single b2b session and then actually
generate the conflicted parts that can
now be uploaded to the various different
route us to actually configure it and of
course if you combine various different
bgp session police's you need to kind of
make sure that actually a good overall
routing policy is a result and we can
either use the cisco continue feature
here or we can actually fold it into a
single route map or western nepal we
take advantage of the next policy
feature with our psl to define
statements for this and this is actually
not just wave of where this is actually
a well implemented system and just being
used by deutsche telekom at the moment
how does this look like well this is the
kind of output that can be generated so
you have the BGP statement for this
neighbor over here with the various
different parts here here of the alt
route map the inward map you have the
various different filters the prefix
list etc and if you don't want to if you
aren't able to use the continued feature
that cisco iOS well then you actually
have to combine the various different
pieces so that what do we have here well
on the first hand we have a Martian
swelter
the next one over here checks what are
the woods whether you actually have the
authorization for the black hole or not
if not then it may actually be rejected
and only if you have it then you can
actually set the community and three
right the next hop etc etc and one has
to keep in mind that this is only a
small subset and example over here and
the same kind of output can be generated
not just with Cisco but for juniors and
obviously itself too so what do I think
the benefits of a system like this are I
think the benefits are that we can
actually now have an explicit
specification of the routing policy and
it isn't just kind of a in the brew
token piglets anymore but it really is
independent of the network itself also
what you gain is you gain your
separation of your routing policy into
the various different pieces so that
it's clear what are the additional
services that you offer to enable
customers or appears of transits cuz our
customers more control over their own
traffic it also allows you to introduce
new services fairly quickly because you
can actually do this in a counterfeit
two-stage manner first you most of all
have to actually set up some preparation
meeting because for example if you want
to do have allow prepending to specific
a SS when you first need to be before
you can sell the service you have to
prepare for all outgoing sessions that
the service is going to be supported and
so this is the first step and once you
have enabled it for all the outgoing
session then you can actually enable it
for some incoming ones and also you can
easily take advantage of new water
features because the only pieces that
you need to change is the back end
module and the necessary are fragments
over there you also respect to knowledge
domains because you really
that one person can now focus on the
various different policy they don't have
to worry about the specific speaks of
the network anymore so let's get away
from actually help King bgp configs and
of course you can automatically generate
the appropriate how to config let's for
this and I'm curious for feedback from
any of the people here and be more than
happy to talk with them about what they
think about it what could be the kind of
way of moving forward to is it what the
bias different policy should be and the
exchange experience questions thank you
very much I have a question you're going
to encourage me to stop using VI to edit
my router configs and or sitting at the
console yes out of my cold dead fingers
or I'm sorry rüdiger well there are
operators that actually manipulate the
XML that was shown as the definition I
like to say of services or network
connections using VI or whatever editor
or graphic queefing they want to do and
what what's what's the trade-off in the
number of routers or number of
configurations that you need to maintain
I if I've got two routers is this an
efficient use of my time if I've got
2,000 routers as you know where's the
break point well with to Reuters I
somewhat suspect that you probably will
have so simple requirements that it
doesn't justify the learning curve on
the other hand if you are doing if you
are implementing something like 50
policy and signaling elements in the
service that you are building across 100
Reuters and you want to have the
ability to add another 12 over the next
quarter year well I think I think it's
worthwhile to consider this thank you so
basically it depends on the complexity
of your network you're right for towards
as it's probably not it but if you want
to stay the tour route as to a hundred
rotors you probably want to think about
some kind of an automated system to
generate the config let's photos okay um
I'm going to ask for a straw poll how
many people in this room configure
routers themselves not having somebody
on their staff keep your hands up how
many people are for the people that
would use a tool like this keep your
hands up if you're not wouldn't use it
to like this put your hands down do you
guys with your hands up have tools like
this now big hum yes hmm how many people
are going to go download this code
immediately okay get those guys right
there right all right again thank you
very much it's break time