so welcome to the service provider
vulnerabilities panel that is not the
right slide but will have the right ones
up there in a little bit I am Martin
Hannigan and obviously i work for
verisign my work in the network security
and architecture group in Dulles
Virginia and we're here to just share
some experiences with some of the recent
vulnerabilities that have taken place on
the internet and how they've impacted
operators basically the abstract says it
all so I'd like to go ahead and
introduce my panelists hopefully I have
the right slides here okay we got
Patrick Gilmore from Akamai Technologies
myself Aaron Hughes from Terremark crisp
a later from tds Chris tomorrow from NCI
and Richard steenburgen from n layer we
have a commentary shut section that
we've invited Jerry Dixon from us art to
speak and we've also invited Robert
Matthews from the University of Hawaii
to speak and we're going to stop here
for a second because now we need the
right slides
how'd you get it yeah bill huh bill how
did you get that
my laptop's dead
fun fun fun
should be on my computer
sandisk instilled with still loading
we got
so much porn you have on this drive bill
okay we've got it haha yeah thank you
Bill okay so we're back to the abstract
slide so the only thing we left out is
this is hopefully a precursor to an
additional session in 35 in Los Angeles
or has that been announced well wherever
35 is going to be problems worthy of
attack prove their worth by fighting
back and I think this is something that
rings true with most operators I'll
quickly go through the introductions
against us we have the bios up packing
Wars direct our network strategy and
supported Akamai he's been there for the
last five years helping to build the
largest CDN in the world patrick has
experienced a large network design
deployments in both the ISP and
enterprise spaces and prior to working
in Akamai he was chief network architect
for onyx and he worked for concentric
and was director of operations of
priority my x was a little wordy but
i've been around for quite a while and
and been involved in quite a few things
and I'm still here Aaron and I'm also
lucky enough to help run the mailing
list Aaron Hughes is currently the vice
president of technology at aramark a
leading operator of internet exchange
points mr. Hughes is responsible for all
network and system tech topology
planning and design prior to terremark
misty uses vice president operations at
yellowbrix where he led operation sales
engineering planning and design errands
are also worked at certainly solutions
quest technologies ICN alternate chen
chen o1 communications and i actually
knew Aaron back when he worked at
Channel One which was about ten years
now Chris malaita we all know he's a
data networking engineer data network
engineer at TDs in Madison Wisconsin
he's held a number of roles there and
his current position he's responsible
for designing engineering
and running the data networks that
comprise TDS is internet business Chris
was a primary player and the redesign of
the TDA TDs nationwide core network in
addition he's responsible for all the
internet pairing coordination Chris
tomorrow he's network security engineer
with MCI for the last five years and
real life he's a chemical engineer while
at Union nmci he's been responsible for
a team of engineers helping the mitigate
dos attacks against our customers
additionally he's been responsible for
evaluating security issues and their
relevance to you unit ginas public IP
backbone and other MCI networks Richard
steenburgen joins us he's the founder of
n layer communications he currently
serves as the CTO previously he was a
senior network engineer for several
large NS peas and a senior software
engineer developing routing technologies
at net VMG Jerry Dixon he joins us he's
deputy director of operations for NC SD
I us computer emergency readiness team
you have start prior to joining NC st he
was a director of the Internal Revenue
Services computer security incident
response capability IRS csir see as
they're known including and it's scary
to get email from them when you see that
IRS okay including having served as
director of information security for
Marriott International a global private
sector company mr. Dixon is currently
cssp cissp and actively engaged with
public and private sector efforts and
the information security community
professor Matthews joins us on the
telephone he is a distinguished senior
research scholar on national security
affairs and us industrial preparedness
at the University of Hawaii a domain
specialist and ultra complex systems
professional professor Matthews for
professional concentrations over the
past three decades include non-linearity
and highly distributed large-scale
systems and emergent behavior as those
found in command control communications
and telogen telligence surveillance and
reconnaissance c3 is our systems
additionally he serves as senior policy
and programs analyst to the United
States government on a variety of
national security matters which include
us critical infrastructures national
technical
sets the intelligence community
counterterrorism and domestic security
professor Matthews holds advanced
degrees in both management and economics
and welcome to everybody so the way that
we've set the panel up today is we have
each panelist is going to answer one
question and we're going to have a
little bit of debate amongst the
panelist if needed after the last
question Jerry Dixon is going to address
the audience and then professor Matthews
is going to address the audience so with
that I think we'll get started the first
question is and this question is going
to be answered by Patrick Gilmore if one
company discovers a vulnerability and
the impact is in its infancy is it worth
announcing it to all customers and or at
the operator community and the follow-on
to that will be does that create a
larger vulnerability hello so I'm going
to answer the second question first
because it's easier the answer is
obviously yes any time you have a secret
and you give more people the information
of that secret it's higher likelihood
that the secret will leak out I don't
think anybody's going to have any
problem with that people might have a
problem with my answer for the first
question the first question can be
broken up into two subsets there's
obviously vulnerabilities that aren't
going to do any damage to the Internet
those kind of vulnerabilities I honestly
think should be announced whenever they
come out if it's not going to do any
damage let us know we'll work around
what small effects they can have don't
worry about hiding them the second type
of vulnerability is kind of do affect
the internet on a large basis can take
out large providers or entire swathes of
the core of the Internet as they say
that type of vulnerability can further
be broken down into two more sets the
kind with workarounds and the kind
without workarounds kind of with
workarounds is going to be addressed as
a later question so I'm going to let
that go the kind without workarounds
personally and I need to stress this is
me not my company not my CEO not the
rest of the panel but personally I think
that that should not be announced I
think if you found a vulnerability if
you're a router vendor and you've
noticed a stack overflow that there's no
workaround for this should be kept
secret it should be worked on internally
until there is a
answer you should not let it out you
shouldn't let anybody else know about it
obviously if it becomes known for
whatever reason if somebody else finds
it or if it leaks out of your
organization that's a different story
but as long as you do not think there's
a vulnerability I'm sorry I exploit in
the wild for this vulnerability you
shouldn't let anybody else know talked
about this with a few of you out there
and lots of people who aren't here today
and there was a suggestion which I think
it might be helpful um and that is if
you are a vendor and you found that
there is a vulnerability and there's no
workaround you start working on the bug
most people can tell when they're going
to be able to have code available for
the fix it's not an exact science but
most people can tell most vendors can
tell when the bug fix is going to be
available it might be useful if what you
did is announced to the community that
there's going to be an upgrade path for
you know iOS Juno s whatever the bug is
in in a week two weeks whatever you know
friday at four o'clock on May 26th or
whatever is available this was asked
from several people because they did not
want to find out on Friday at four
o'clock after everybody in Europe had
gone home that they may have this
massive vulnerability and they need to
help create all the routers today they'd
like to schedule maintenance windows I
found that to be reasonable there was
some comments about well what's going to
happen are people going to assume this
is a bug of course they're going to
assume it's a bug but a lot of times you
don't have enough information or it may
not be possible to give out information
without giving away the vulnerability
and even if people are going to assume
it's about or notice that they're up
streams are upgrading their routers or
anything else it's still nice to know
the information ahead of time so that
you can schedule have resources
available and get ready to do this
upgrade once you know what's going on
and you can make a decision at that time
it's a lot better than trying to
scramble so that's my answer to the
question any questions from the panel
thanks Patrick that was too easy
question two is too crispy later and the
question is is announcing the
vulnerability putting tools into script
kiddies hackers angry people's hands and
could this be prevented with a follow-on
of should vulnerability announcements be
restricted to a selective group to
prevent this I think that the first part
of the question is yes and no I don't
think that there's a clear-cut
definitive answer from everything that
I've read in everybody that I've talked
with there's definitely different levels
of sophistication of vulnerabilities
some vulnerabilities are easy to
reproduce and create a tool set to take
advantage of that vulnerability and some
are not some are very easy to exploit in
the wild while others are not so I think
the first half but the question is
really a common sense how easy is this
going to be to exploit and how much of
an impact is it going to have if it's
not going to have much impact then that
probably changes changes it to be yes to
the second half I believe that I believe
really strongly in this we actually went
quite quite a few rounds with vendors on
this this year that releasing
information to a subset of the people is
just definitely not the way to go when
vulnerabilities are released generally
they're fixed inversions of code that
are already out or there's already
workarounds that are available to go to
go with it regardless of what the
community the small community that holds
the information thinks once that subset
group is receives a vulnerability
information and what the workaround is
or what the patch versions of code are
generally the other operators in the
operator community that didn't get it
aren't very far behind getting the
information through backchannels the
whispernet of sorts so would you would
you say that your opinion is basically
within full disclosure I would say that
if you're going to give it out that you
should that we should look at some form
of opt-in system
two to get trusted people within
corporations the information that they
need I don't necessarily know that
giving it to the general public is is
the right answer but I firmly believe
that giving it that limiting it by
whatever k to score or whatever subset
of determining factor that we're using
as to is giving a competitive
differentiator to a commodity based
service so you're and this is definitely
something that happened you had you had
large providers who was marketing the
fact that they were getting information
before other people and I don't believe
that that's fair and I believe that that
definitely has to be avoided Patrick
would you say that your opinion on us on
the previous slide would be more
responsible disclosure okay I could just
talk real loud okay i'm not sure that
they actually overlap because i was
saying that i was asked whether or not
the vulnerability should be released at
all and the answer is I don't think it
should unless there's a workaround and
then that's going to be covered
elsewhere if it is going to be if it is
going to be released although I haven't
thought up my complete answer this I
certainly don't find any fault and what
Chris is saying it does give a
competitive advantage to the people and
I do know that some of the people who
got you know ignoring the press release
incident I do know that sales guys from
the big networks we're telling their
customers you should go with us because
if anything happens you know we get it
first this wasn't necessarily written
down but the sales guys are saying this
in sales meetings and that's you know
that does do something to my sense of
fairness not necessarily the world
should be fair but it is a problem okay
thanks question 3 this question is going
to be addressed by Aaron Hughes what if
routers switches and network objects had
a smart update feature much like windows
update or software update for you Apple
users with this end the continuous a
massive spread of viruses IRC BOTS open
relays could the average enterprise deal
with the regular 3am reload
approximately a five-minute outage so
and this is a controversial issue and
it'll certainly at least raise a bunch
of opinions about ways to implement it
and definitions of knobs or if it's
possible so leaving that aside this is
my thoughts on on the issue I've not
completed the research on this year so
so there's no empirical evidence the
next statement is a hundred percent
accurate I'm sure if Casey Claffey were
up here she bumped me on the head that
being said I'm making a general
assumption that ISPs and I X's and
carriers deal with amplifiers
continuously and those amplifiers are
generally downstream of the ice pzi X's
and carriers so this slide really
focuses on the enterprises and alike
this is proposing that we change the
default on the routers to be more secure
that is block the majority of the
inbound traffic change the default so
that we somehow detect the public inside
space and and by default install anti
spoof filters and of course the big
controversial issue is is we somehow set
up some sort of auto update where
routers much like windows and OS x boxes
check for updates and some regular basis
and automatically fix the routers how
great would that be so that says lots of
questions that come out of this first
you know ken enterprises deal with the
five-minute outage on a somewhat regular
basis can they modify customer SLA s to
allow for this kind of maintenance and
on the other extreme would some
enterprises even notice and and what
will this really solve so perhaps will
will reduce the number of viruses or
open relays or attacks on unsecured
hosts I believe it will I also believe
that this would be enough of a change
that the impact is some of a similar
regular code upgrade and a reboot would
be far less impact than the average big
attack you know whatever the next one
maybe that's it for this slug part two
one quick question so
I'm not sure how router is having some
auto update feature is gonna do anything
for BOTS or open relays at all but
personally I just don't see it because
they're not generally bots or overlays
sign for some cases I'm sure Rob
Thompson III absolutely agree that it
that auto update won't necessarily fix
those things which is which is why I
also mention the sort of default config
on the router I really like to see that
out of the box it's it is secure it's
it's hard to get packets in and out of
your network it should be that you know
you should only have inbound permitted
for things that are normal services and
and if anti spoof were implemented by
default if we can magically figure that
out for somehow on all the edges are big
core fabrics wouldn't be amplified and
attacked constantly by these hosts on
the other side of them the last part was
that often times the fixed code isn't
really fixed so I mean auto update for
your mac OS box when like oh crap my OS
is down I get that recovery CD at
reserve that's good but when it's mighty
640 or actually we don't have those so
that's why I'm 160 that's that's not
good sure there's a whole region that's
a big big problem and and you know and
as I was making this sort of assumption
right that this is not for ice bees not
for I axes yeah maybe it's maybe that's
maybe that's a fair statement for the
home user cable modem dsl up to a
certain size enterprise customer maybe
that's an acceptable solution and I know
what the sizes but if we had the knobs
to control and we could at least propose
something that was sort of the standard
and you can turn this all off of course
but you know it's it's a it's an idea
it's an idea for for dealing with this
what's the difference between this and
how to update something that we recently
what was that called tada secure auto
secure what would be the difference you
know I really haven't looked much into
to how auto SecureWorks and I I so I
don't know the answer i don't believe
that that downloads code i think that
that the
helps you close out known
vulnerabilities I'm not a hard Center
about auto update auto secures features
I'm sure there's a cisco person or
somebody who wants to say so hold on a
minute where we cannot no no no don't go
away we can take some questions but
we've got a lot to talk about we were
hoping to take the questions at the end
but if there's not going to be if we're
not lining the microphones up but Steve
Wilcox and then I can take a question
for you you ask the questions before so
I thought I'd give you some assuming
that you're not going to use this for
large eyes peas and surprise or access
or talking about end-users it may be
worth comparing remember the the netgear
thing where they had the ntp dos built
into the firm code firmware and when did
the fix for it there was like a million
boxes deployed virtually none of them
got the none of them could be contacted
or updated because the boxes were just
deployed in dumb end-user sites and were
configured and didn't tell anything so
I'm not sure when you get a network
device in and use of sight you would
actually have this feature enabled
because they the boxes wouldn't be able
to call home just looks like who are you
in who you with joel crouse go work for
cisco what if it wasn't managed by the
company your vendor but it was something
you could manage internally and it helps
you roll out your software updates
across from network you know the feature
should be customizable that you could do
that I mean if you're a Microsoft
Customer you're not getting your updates
from Microsoft direct if you're a big
enterprise you have an old your own
internal server where you choose what
updates you want to push out
okay Bruce Campbell do you trust the
update mechanisms or would you can you
trust the update mechanism I see these
shakes their heads the real fear is the
evil hacker getting in control of the
auto update mechanism and banging
they've got control of your router's
what you could just as easily ask the
same question about your hosts and
operating systems right i mean do you
trust that the next windows update or
OSX update is going to is going to cover
the next vulnerability or fix some
problem or cause more problems than you
had to begin with yeah criminal versus
thing of the scope for update auto
update and routers the scope for damage
is much greater than auto updating
operating systems
thank you
what no Aaron also took question number
four his code red ninja have proven
blended threats can wreak havoc on
enterprise security because they evolved
more rapidly progressively more complex
and occur more frequently than past
attack methods the worst threats are
likely to come so with that context why
are the most affected companies
enterprises not managing bug fixes and
vulnerabilities until they are reacting
to an attack is it too hard to manage
those changes and are the network
engineer is simply too expensive and has
marketing lead enterprises to believe we
are living in a self-healing world
that's a good one area so this is great
ad campaign i'm sure most of you seen on
TV I believe it was put out by IBM where
or they tied the self-healing server
technology they even go on this as far
to say you know they sprinkle this sort
of self healing magic pixie dust on
their servers and all their engineers
leave with smile on their faces with
confidence that everything is going to
work great I they go on to clearly tell
you that there's no such object but that
there should be better reliability for
for servers and so this is the point
that I want to make here is that is that
there are several ad campaigns which are
marketing attempts to educate the
enterprise's about server reliability
but I very rarely see commercials
advertising self-healing network or
encouraging reliability on network and
switches I would even go as far as to
say that enterprises pay very little
attention to routers and switches and it
may not even realize that they're
susceptible to vulnerabilities or know
that you have to upgrade them in a lot
of cases so the lack of education
happens for a lot of reasons generally
smaller companies don't have network
engineers but rather have em I ask
managers who run servers and and the MIS
managers may know how to put in a basic
in failure at or may even know how to
upgrade our router once in a while but
they're simply too busy or focused on
other things or it's not tied to revenue
and their their managers and and CEOs
aren't hearing it enough that they know
that it's important to spend the money
in time
22 take care of these objects and that
when engineers are too expensive for the
average enterprises even even if they
were less expensive and full times
network full-time network engineers
probably just not needed for the average
enterprise and would likely to be bored
with though the one router and four
switches that they have you've got
something to say there but i'm thinking
i'll take not sure I'm clear on on how
network engineers are too expensive for
the enterprise's since they get the how
ok so you know the average enterprise
and typically on the enterprise you see
ccie CCNA and they tend to I think draw
a little bit more money than your
average not necessarily nana's p guy but
i mean if we're talking economics i
think yeah I wish I would have done some
more research for the actual average
numbers but i'm thinking somewhere along
the lines of the the company that has
small server farms and they provide
services to people and and have a router
because they need to connect to the
internet and have switches because they
need to connect all their servers to
their their routers and i would think
that that's probably more average than
it is you know that i think there's a
smaller number of very large enterprises
that that have good internal expertise
so so mostly like SMBs small to medium
businesses yeah okay and i do not
believe we as an operator community
sorry i do believe that we as an
operator community frequently come to
the conclusion that educating people is
generally a good thing and is needed to
help secure up the internet but i would
also like to see our focus changed
somewhat into looking to looking at
automatically securing and changing the
defaults to make it harder to be
insecure so that that's generally what
this is about i'm feeling no matter what
the defaults are someone will find a way
to be insecure
okay question 5 is directed to Richard
steenburgen on April twentieth 2004 a
vulnerability was found in md5 service
providers were required to react swiftly
to enable passwords on BGP sessions
globally in question is if there is a
workaround available before the software
fixes in EG bheegi bheegi PMD 5 should
it be announced publicly before the
vulnerability or should affect the
parties be notified privately I'm sorry
who are you in who you with sandy Murphy
from Sparta the first line on April
twentieth 2004 vulnerability was found
in md5 it wasn't md5 it was TCP it
wasn't found it was publicized it wasn't
a vulnerability it was a well-known than
somewhat unfortunate feature got the
date right well that's a good point but
roll with this air I think we'll get to
the point Joel did you want to say
something good thank you okay go ahead
Richard well that basically what I was
going to say regarding this specific
issue you know as far as the answer
should they should the worker bound be
be published really the answer is it
depends it depends on how easy it is to
reconstruct the the actual attack it
depends on what the attack is how how
easy it is to to exploit or in the case
of the TCP vulnerability if it's even an
issue at all most knowledgeable
engineers with regard to the TCP reset
vulnerability already knew that was how
TCP work that was how it was meant to
work there was nothing new there it
wasn't a vulnerability it wasn't a
serious issue and the fact that the the
information was was leaked so slowly and
with so much secrecy really caused a lot
of people to run around deploying md5
where they didn't need
resulted in a lot of pissed-off
engineers later some other instances you
know some some historical examples the
vendors have given out a little bit too
much information there there been work
arounds but they disclosed so much you
know here's what the filter and here's
exactly why it why it happens and they
provided so much detail that it was
immediately easy to reconstruct the
attack and within you know you would see
months that the code had been fixed had
been built into various releases and
then within 48 hours of the the notice
being put out they'd given out so much
information for the work around that you
were seeing exploits in the wild so
that's that's where you're going too far
on the other side so really the the
answer is you need to use some common
sense we need to get the information out
there where it makes sense where it's
not going to be so completely obvious
that that you can reconstruct the attack
you know if there is a workaround and
it's it's reasonable enough to do you
know you can you can tell your customers
that if you're not running mpls you're
not going to be affected by this bug
instead of leaving them all confused and
bewildered okay guy ask it just a couple
of questions for Richard so unless you
had something go right ahead to first
often often times unfortunately with
some of the vulnerabilities the details
about the vulnerability are relevant to
the fix so the fix for patricks network
might be different than the fix for your
network might be the different
fix for my network or from Woody's
network and knowing how the actual
problem exists and what you have in your
network oftentimes helps arrive at a
better solution for you aside from
upgrade code and pray that that code
actually works which sometimes it
doesn't the you had a point about you
know the md5 issue did cause a lot of
folks to run around in Holland b5
passphrases on bgp which i agree at the
time seemed sort of nutty but you know
if i tell you to jump or you actually do
that you know you have to have some
comment you said common sense the
operators need to have some common sense
as well as to what possibility you know
what they're doing what their implement
i think at the time Patrick actually and
he should probably comment on this he
was saying that he had people requiring
him to do md5 is that correct no no III
thought that you had actually set on the
mailing list that you had some of your
providers requiring you to do md5 oh
yeah at the time we we did have actually
upstream providers requiring us to do
md5 or they were going to shut down our
our links and we didn't have any didn't
have any information on why didn't
understand it and once we figured it out
we turned it off yeah we saw a little
overreaction to yeah and when I
afterwards when I went to ask those
providers the answer was they didn't
know either that somebody at the tack
told him and in fact in some cases that
old attack didn't know any better but
they were doing it anyway so how many
people did the upgrade or the fix just
because any hands or anybody willing to
admit that so I mean maybe that that
specific specific example is good for a
number of reasons but maybe it's also a
bad example because people just reacted
I think like people with their hair on
fire for no particular reason there's no
one for me to have some to get it on
fire maybe that's
happen to your hair and also richard has
a they said that something that I do
actually more often than my wife would
like I imply people's knowledge about
stuff like you imply you're implying
that people really understand how TCP
works and I I don't think that's the
case by and large if you go back to the
example of the network the standard
network operator at an SMB or apparently
we're sorry okay I'm i just wanted to
point out the person who pointed out the
slide that the terminology was basically
in error I think that was a good
demonstration of it so this panel is
basically made up of operators the
people that deal with this stuff on a
day-to-day basis and sometimes we don't
always completely understand the things
that we're seeing and we're under so
much pressure that we have to react with
a snap and then come then circle back
around so thank you for pointing that
out Steve Wilcox speak up I can't hear
you I point2 Chris you were just picking
on Patrick that was because just because
he he made a point that's all doesn't
everybody I we went enrolled md5 out
based upon what we were told from a
number of different vendors and agencies
we were told we needed to do it with old
was a vulnerability and this is a bad
example for this reason but it was
sometime afterwards quite a long time
afterwards when we actually found out
the specifics of the vulnerability and
realized there wasn't the vulnerability
so it's unfair to say that people
reactive we were told category two there
was a major issue and we reacted to it
as we've been told to react
Steve Feldman this works oh I would like
that coupler point out that from my
point of view which is a content
provider we were being told to do this
by people that we trusted to be right
and the feeling was we trust these
people if we don't do it we might be in
trouble so he better do it it wasn't
terribly difficult for us and I don't
regret doing it in hindsight yeah maybe
wasn't needed in hindsight maybe I need
to question the trust that I have for
some of those sources but I think I
reacted correctly based on the
information I was given and I suspect
most of the people around here would
agree with that so they really be it was
an issue then of who do you trust to
tell you to jump and deciding if we
trust them before you jump hey so so
overall your you didn't really care
either way about the end of the problem
I mean and you don't have the same
problem that patrick has about
maintaining keys all over the place or
like we have maintaining keys for god
knows how many customers who want
password is there cake well I'm just
saying that this is a good example
because if everyone knows what it is but
it's not a good example because it
really wasn't handled very well it
wasn't island maybe that's a great
example it wasn't handled very well but
I think looking over the last the
history of incidents that that I've been
involved with they're getting better
this one maybe was a step backwards but
no they're getting better to some extent
like the SNMP issue that came out was
just that was a complete nightmare so I
guess there are several sentences but
okay we're going to move on to question
six questions sexist for chris morrow
there are multiple methods of
vulnerability announcements that impact
the operator community those include the
whisper network and basically the
whisper network is you work it tier one
isp in you call me and go i just heard
about this thing and i'm letting you
know about it nsp sec nanog and I
knocked DBA and also vendor reporting
methods like peace are so the question
is what is the most expedient path to
get
the information to isps to collaborative
collaboratively determined mitigations
in the absence of a patch we feel
compelled to share the mitigation of the
same outside of the US region and is the
network is the whisper network a good or
bad thing so i will talk not ramble so
much my answer but so the collaboration
issue at my feeling is that that like I
said to Richard everybody's networkers
architected differently everybody made
design decisions during that that
impacts every vulnerabilities effect on
there but their level of risk from that
vulnerability so i'm not sure that
collaboratively meet calling up somebody
and saying I heard about blah you should
do this is helpful because I don't know
what their network looks like so me
telling them that isn't going to be
necessarily helpful it said maybe that's
a little bit difficult I do think that
if you have information about some
particular vulnerability and you you
know you need to be careful who you
share it with there's a lot of people in
the world you wish harm on other folks
or other networks that's difficult so if
you find something and tell the vendor
about it running around and telling all
your best friends and putting up a man
list maybe is not the best option and
also in many cases that would be
violating an NDA which is not such a
smart thing to do right right that's
true piling NDA's gets me in trouble so
so I think that's the first question
sort of the the compelling compelled to
share it outside of the US region as a
multinational corporation I don't really
have a whole lot of choice if some
vendor tells me about something I have
parts of my company that are in asia pac
and amia that I have to make aware of
the problem and make aware of the fix
that we plan on implementing in the u.s.
at least our operations group doesn't
necessarily dictate operations
everywhere and that goes by the
operations group as well which is always
fun so I don't have a lot of choice now
did I tell the Indian government about
it no no don't tell my customers about
it either so I mean there have been
plenty of incidents where we prepared a
customer state
we prepared a statement to the
government because we knew they were
going to ask us about it but you know
it's not it's not our responsibility to
tell the customer anything when they ask
we really just say hey you should go
talk to cisco about this here's a web
page and we give them a little primer on
what the problem is and how do your
customers react when you tell men
typically most times they call in and
they're just confused they don't really
understand this what I was think about
the implied knowledge didn't necessarily
know so they you know they they don't
understand what the problem is they're
just looking for a heads up and and what
did we do a lot of times like are you
fixing this yes we are so when when you
get a large vulnerability that gets a
lot of press does your call center or
phones ringing off the hook and your
ticket queues load up really heavily and
yeah I think it depends on the
particular incident but we definitely
have had those where the call centers
got very very congested and so that it
caused us headache and so that's why we
prepared a statement and said hey here's
what we can tell you know we prepare
something that they can email the
customer something they can speak to the
customer about some talking points that
have some more detail and then we say
and by the way the vendor documents for
this are also very good so I'll say yes
okay I thank you I said my last point I
didn't get to oh I'm sorry go ahead
that's okay it's what I don't answer but
um so the is is the whisper network it
is it good or bad and I think it depends
on how its run you know having a system
that's like the telephone game is
difficult because I tell you you tell
somebody and by the time it gets back
around to me it's still a different
story so it's very very challenging to
do any kind of secure quiet
communications on something that's it's
going to be very public do you think in
the case of the tcp / and d5
vulnerability md5 vulnerability that the
whisper network may have contributed to
the overreaction of most of the people
that overreacted yeah I think that if
you if you look at that incident that's
why I kept saying to say maybe this
wasn't the best incident to use yeah and
that in say it before you prepared your
slides unfortunately
I think that if you know if I hear
something as bad night tell Chris and he
trusts me and he doesn't ask why is this
bad explained to me the problem explain
to me how this is bad for me and then he
makes an educated decision about and
again i'm just using Chris as an example
not to poke fingers at him but you know
just don't feel bad um if he doesn't
fully understand it and he just goes
implement something and turns around and
tells his engineering and operations
group to go and implement something then
we end up with a situation like the TCP
md5 issue or that TCP issue I don't
think that's actually what happened
because I know everyone I talked to and
I know what I did when I was told which
was why should we do this what's wrong
can you tell me more and the answer was
no go do this and since people like your
vendors you know Tony telling me well if
you don't trust your vendors you know
how we write the code you have to trust
us or people like our transfer providers
telling us well you need to do this
we've done this on our network I mean
who are you going to trust and what's
going to happen next time there really
is a vulnerability and this is the only
information you have i I really don't
think it's because people just went oh
wow I heard about this you know somebody
mentioned it over dinner one day and i
think i'm going to change my entire
network because of it yes I made an
overly simplified example but you did
say in what you said in your statement
earlier that that your provider told you
do this so we're going to shut your link
down your session down and you ask why
and they say we don't know why and then
later on you ask the next person up the
lion they said we never really did find
out what was up with that that's right
so mean these are all doing it and they
all told me to do it what rights are you
going to do but but that's what I'm
saying is it you know if you if you
can't make an educated decision about it
then maybe that's also part of the poems
you can have the information the last
little point about that is that
oftentimes the folks that get involved
with that are non helpful so when my
execs hear about it I have to have like
twice daily calls with people about
stuff so I don't get anything done
except preparing for calls you know but
the government people hear about it they
want twice daily calls about this
incident and again no work gets done
same with PR so there's a there's a
point when all those people do have to
get involved but but early on is not the
time and during the actual fix is not
the time
as much as possible okay thanks Joel
when your vendors and people in your
government come to you and say install
TCP md5 or else that's not disclosure
right and so of course that's going to
hit the window with the whisper network
right people are going to expose that
and yes they're going to overreact react
because they have no way to make
intelligent decisions about deploying
functionality in their network so it
shouldn't come as a shock to anyone that
that sort of information would leak out
or that without disclosure disclosure as
to what was actually going on that
people might overreact I think it goes
back to slide to that I spoke to that we
I hear it from Chris who tells me about
this and he tells me that I need to put
md5 on all my sessions and since my
vendor flat out refuses to tell me
what's going on I take what is the next
best hope that I have to protect my
network if the exploit comes out into
the wild without the vendor disclosing
at us before it comes out into the wild
and I take my friend here Chris who
called me up and said you need to do
this I'll take his word over the vendor
who won't I don't have a word from the
vendor because they won't tell me
anything so I think that a lot of a lot
of the especially in this case the TCP
md5 stuff came came from vendors
following their their clothes practices
and and the web of trust of sorts of
operators responding responding within
that we also have a minor well not so
minor issue with with lack of a single
definitive source of information there's
a bunch of different communities all
over the globe that all have to deal
with these kind of issues and figuring
out how to disseminate the information
and you know we don't know if it should
go to that
gorai not DBA or come from sir or MSP
sec or Homeland Security or what this is
this big question so all these sources
of information we all keep up with sort
of when we can get through our mailing
lists and everything else and come to
our own conclusions about what we think
is is appropriate to responsive and we
need to come up with some way that says
this is really important to everybody
this is really important to people
running mpls this is really important to
people still running here grp or
something like that and and and and
instead of having this big noisy list
have something that's rather selective
and directed okay thank you we're going
to next we're going to bring up Jerry
Dixon from the Department of Homeland
Security us sir and he's going to
address a question for us Jerry you here
ok yeah you can do it from that
microphone the question for Jerry Dixon
is what role should the Department of
Homeland Security us-cert have resolving
issues surrounding vulnerability release
Jerry and I had a discussion a little
bit earlier and I told them to feel free
to kind of vert off a little bit and
shape this to a little to something a
little bit more general so guy Jerry I
think there's been a lot of good
discussion on you know how to
communicate vulnerabilities you know one
of the just add on to you know what
you're talking about you know who do you
go to and you know how do you you know
I've got a question I guess it's a
little bit higher level how do you kind
of triage that vulnerability how do you
know you know you're the severity of it
you know how do you know how many of you
all have like a vulnerability scoring
system you know within your organization
whether you're an operator or a vendor
you know just to show of hands ok bit
heavier I'm not sure everybody heard
that because I'm having trouble hearing
you so maybe you can do that again how
many of you have a mechanism in place to
you know score of vulnerability or
assess the criticality of it from a you
know whether you're an operator or a
vendor just by a show of hands ok one of
the challenges and I think you know from
a us-cert perspective
in a situational awareness and these
kind of things are kind of key based on
you know we deal with a lot of national
loved ones and response teams with
foreign governments we've got
partnerships in place with those
organizations and a lot of times more
often than not they'll come across
exploit code or they might have a you
know find a vulnerability being
exploited but don't yet have the code
but they're at least communicating that
information and if we've got somebody
you know on the US side whether it's an
operator or a group that we can kind of
say hey this activity is going on you
know we need to ratchet up the the
criticality of it to determine you know
what makes sense on communicating it you
know I use an example it comes up quite
often as we were you know DHS was
talking with the DNS community and in
trying to determine you know what should
get reported to you know say US sir and
you know one of the folks there you know
said well you know would be interested
DNS is being attacked well of course the
DNS community said well you know we're
getting attacked you know every few
seconds so what is the right threshold
you know for what constitutes a national
level event to determine you know what
should get communicated how does it get
communicated as well as take into
account for when is the vendor going to
have a patch available for folks and one
of the things that we're interested in
working especially with the you know the
NAND all community is trying to figure
out how to we you know reach out to find
out you know in the absence of a patch
but sometimes it takes a couple of weeks
but there's a lot of malicious activity
taking place what are some of the steps
to mitigate it how do we get that
information into us a you know I think
on the previous slide it mentioned a
couple of different closed mailing list
the I knocked DBA one of the things that
you know another thing that us-cert
would be interested in is what makes the
most sense in communicating things in a
secure fashion as well as also keeping
in mind you know the interconnected
nature the internet and dealing with the
international community as well so again
it's just you know it's just some
general things I know you know we'll be
here over the next couple of days
there's a couple of us you know if you
have thoughts on that be interested in
here in the
one of the things I wanted to point out
too is how many of you know exactly what
us-cert does outside of the
vulnerability context okay well
basically just to give you a quick
rundown we're responsible for incident
coordination across the federal
government so something's happening
within a particular agency say within
the department Treasury say like IRS if
they identify you know a new piece of
malware that's not currently being
detected or if they're having a an
intrusion set within their environment
that gets reported up we help bringing
additional resources or help with
analysis if they request it but it gives
us a general picture what's taking place
across government we interface with the
the White House of the National Security
Council Homeland Security Council and
the office of management budget on a
regular basis to let them know what's
happening across the federal government
space to determine impacts and you know
if there's any trends there that need to
be identified the other piece that were
charged with is infrastructure
protection working with companies at a
you know like chemical companies oil
companies financial sector banks that
type of thing in providing cybersecurity
guidance also helping them with the
understanding what the threats are out
there the other piece that we deal with
is a lot of times we deal with a lot of
getting direct calls from private
citizens state governments local
governments request an assistance if
they have a major intrusion set
providing on-site response if needed
also if we've had organizations contact
us with regards to if they're not
getting traction with their local law
enforcement we're able to get federal
law enforcement engaged and get them
assistance to help with attribution or
to stop the pain that they're feeling
one of the things that uh you know we're
excited you know the last couple of
years that providers have been doing and
actually I need to grab a drink water
because I'm kind of going dry here
one of the things that you know the
providers have been doing is providing
anti-spyware antivirus you know kind of
helping with you know where a major
problem lies you know a lot of times
with the end user either clicking on
attachments or you know initiating a you
know where are more those types of
things it's a constant battle you know
we're going to you know there's a lot of
large providers that are providing the
anti spyware the antivirus software
enforcing of the acceptable use policies
a lot of times when we get contacted
about botnets on either a you know a
drone or a the command and control and
being able to reach out the highest fees
to let them have been very responsive
and enforcing their acceptable use
policy would like to see that trend
continue on because it helps one you
know reduce the amount of systems out
there that are causing everybody
problems so Jerry when you actually you
call an ISP and ask them to enforce
their IEP do they typically cooperate or
when what's your typical response
basically we typically will reach out if
we don't have our own direct contact you
know you kind of touch on the whisper
network you know we use that vehicle you
know based on folks that we know but we
also reach out to abuse departments in
the last couple of months we've been
passing information to Internet service
providers and they you know have gotten
back to us rather quickly and have you
know basically they tell us of their
voice in force in the acceptable use
policy however you know if there's a
trick for us is because we have embedded
law enforcement is to make sure that
we're not also trampling on something
that they might be working if they are
working something then there'll be the
conduit to reaching out to that Internet
service provider under you know
basically the subpoena process or the
other mechanisms that they have to to
enforce getting that system either set
aside for evidence or for monitoring
purposes so you know in general I mean
we've had very few providers that have
you know not pushed back you know I can
only think of maybe every once in a
great while we'll have somebody pushed
back and again depending on the severity
of you know the issue that we're trying
to tackle that will either go to the law
enforcement channel or we'll figure out
another way to tackle that problem
so you know basically you know in
general it kind of covers you know just
some high-level topics that you know
we're interested in and also you know
one of the things that we wanted to
focus on is a general situation
awareness you know we're interested in
general trends trying to determine again
you know what are the right thresholds
what makes sense of what the US
government should be aware of from a you
know a cyber attack or an event that
might be taking place within your world
that's impacting your customers or your
organization thanks Jerry for the next
person the common will be professor
Robert Matthews from the University of
why professor Matthews you with us ok we
need to get the speakers turned up a
little bit ok how can you hear us now so
that's not sounding 2 good audio folks
Bob you can you hear me now now we have
you so the question I'd like to pose to
professor Matthews and by the way good
evening professor Matthews in a global
network operator community one has
certain local responsibilities
specifically in certain communal
responsibilities at the global level
both of which are essential parts of
responsible responsible practitioners
manual in an operational context what
are the distinct boundaries major themes
for each area as we understand and
accept universally
nice boundaries so uh did we drop the
call that figures on its knees stayed on
for almost an hour on you Marvin canary
yes anyone mr. Matthews all right thank
you very much for having me first of all
my colleague and respected to be heavy
well yes seems to be losing you in and
out boy first I'd like to a certain
flavor what I intend to share with you
here has not been sanctioned in any
manner by any arm of the United States
government he University of Hawaii or
any of its research can bend the
strictly my own now we may proceed I
guess I cannot speak specifically about
any ongoing government program or those
in the pipeline therefore if there are
questions from anyone regarding specific
issues in that vein it's probably best
directed to someone else Martin
suggested that that I participate in the
forum so that i may share with you some
concerns from a high level as in the
30,000 feet view if you will in my
opinion the nature of network security
concerns in the Nano communities a
subset of a larger security concern of
the national domain which respect to
information systems and of course as
Jerry Dixon just mentioned these systems
encompass various layers I sort of
divide it in in the context of civilian
and military civilian to include banking
and finance transportation electrical
power telecommunications or gas medical
services cetera and the military systems
to include command control
communications and systems those systems
that provide battlespace awareness for
command and control
this is combat identification
intelligence surveillance and
reconnaissance systems and again with
respect to those moving concerns within
this particular session I think
consequences from failure in the
National domain involve very very large
consequences obviously the compromise of
national security command structure
military command political come on
infrastructure failure all leading to
loss of life compromise national
security and loss of public confidence
of course sick I mean we have now large
industrial concerns associated with
various aspects of information system
security I attempted to suggest that the
application security domain is is a is a
mu one that's most familiar to everyone
operation system security and there is a
interface point and system security
information systems or information
security comsec all of these are
individually large concerns that have
come up when in reality we must really
consider that overall security is a
multi-dimensional property of the entire
system and as practitioners we we
perhaps ought to step back and consider
that and understand what one's role is
in in their multi-dimensional in
assuring a multi-dimensional property of
the entire system with respect to the
pervasive nature of information systems
i tend to submit that going beyond what
is known today with respect to getting
more understanding of end-to-end system
behavior if you will they will require
significantly large research
breakthroughs that which it is not being
assaulted by any government research
organism like NSF DARPA and others
presently methods to strengthen one
dimension can easily compromised another
and
we find that routinely and one of the
things with respect to trying to assure
system components by virtue of applying
finely tuned composability techniques
has resisted determined efforts it this
is this is something that we found out
through government research and another
aspect of government research that that
we've come to understand so well is
commercially available off-the-shelf
technology and either provide a high
level of assurance no functions required
to meet specific government needs this
is the this is the ugly duckling that no
one wants to talk about and it's a high
assurance operating system rd in the
commercial sector is more than simple
let's consider another fact for instance
department of defense for instance has
to play significant resources to
analyzing each attempt to penetrate
their network on a routine basis every
day there's involves very intense layer
of forensic protocol and these costs are
enormous simply staggering I think it
was in two thousand the year 2000 art
money then DoD CIO stood in front of
DEFCON eight and said we spent 25
billion dollars in 1999 alone to track
into I qualify and quantify 22,000 too
obvious attacks against DoD systems that
averages out to about million and a half
per attack so the instituting friends of
forensics and going through that
forensic protocol with respecting into
those attempts to penetrate systems is a
significantly cost a matter none which
we can just set aside when you talk
about agency budgets the other aspect
from a operation security perspective we
ought to consider it
you know we foot we focus on network
security metrics and security metrics in
particular is sort of a vague topic we
start talking about from one community
that next what we what we think of them
as and what we understand them to be
what we need is holistic system metrics
that which we don't have at this point
when I mean by holistic system metrics
I'll give you an example by way of
medicine we know this relationship in
medicine for instance and we know it
because we know the cyst the systemic
aspects of the system so well that the
interrelationship between this the many
factors involved we've studied we've
assessed with qualified quantified and
there there's their complex maps to that
that that relationship I wish to say
that for every dollar cut in polio
immunization costs for instance costs
ten dollars later later in medical costs
and that every one dollar cotton measles
mumps and rubella immunization programs
cost fourteen dollars in medical costs
later and we know the relationships from
a systemic perspective we don't
understand it very well yeah when we
talk about for those practitioners of
quality of service or those lovers of
quality of service for instance quality
of services a is a wonderful tool in as
much as that is a case it doesn't help
us understand end-to-end system behavior
when I mean by n2 in system behavior
it's not a no denote behavior I'm
talking about the network end points to
the end power if you will in that
context and you have to be when you have
to be concerned about a qualitative
context you really must have those sort
of measures at hand very significant
problem this is not this is not
something simple and we have yet another
problem with respect to DHS
is role evolving Roland and other
government entities were evolving role
you consider such things from a policy
perspective like presidential decision
directive 63 in its advancement and the
Homeland Security Department cyber
security enhancement act of two thousand
four for instance there is still a very
large void in the industry specific data
on critical system component
vulnerabilities the likes of which can
adequately result in mitigation of vast
resource services we don't have any
detail on we do not have sufficient data
on critical information system
infrastructure interdependencies for
instance so therefore again I mean you
in as much as we're talking about
large-scale complex information systems
in the United States government or
critical infrastructures those things
are equally applicable to the Internet
as well and it's impressive when you
look look back researchers resulted in
understanding this we for fifteen
percent of the vulnerabilities we have
liberal vendor acknowledgement for
twenty percent of the vulnerabilities we
have we don't even know where to look
for vulnerability of vulnerability
information and in government this is
this is a sort of problem that we're
faced with its it's impressive and so
when we look at a practitioner versus a
network owner network manager and these
these these domains of specialities we
also have common lexa Cala tea and we
ought to have standard terminology on
how we go about understanding defining
qualifying quantifying and and and
enforcing security paradigms we did we
simply we simply have a great deal of
inconsistency in this regard
so that is those are the pieces of
information that I wish to arrest with
and maybe take questions and perhaps
engaging some dialogue Thank You
professor Matthews does anybody have any
questions okay let him off easy so what
how can you let him off
ok so we're running a little bit over
here and I'm looking at Steve and Susan
and saying we have a couple of questions
on the IRC you I'm gonna take them or
not okay I need am I I don't have do I
have a limb here
yes
okay this question comes from joel i
can't pronounce your last name at you
oregon dot edu yay glee okay why are
most affected companies and enterprises
not managing bug fixes that's the
context and if is if as the panel has
advocated disclosure information is
limited in time frame in scope how can
companies make intelligent decisions
about management of their infrastructure
mop mop in fact I think that we quite a
battle I think we answered a part of
that in at the end in terms of we
there's obviously the whispernet that we
hear a lot of information and I think
that a lot of us base a lot of trust on
people who get the information before us
and pass that information along so I
think we're making assumptions that thus
far have panned out all right that the
information that we get is reliable
hello hello hello hello go home from
Matthews hello hello hello do we hello
are we still hooked up hello not anymore
only because I don't know what's going
on and I'd wanted to keep saying hello
hello over and over ok the next question
is from jay patel how do you determine
which providers should receive a really
notice critical router vulnerabilities
for example the recent juniper ldp /
mpls related explain i think this comes
back to what we were talking about
earlier in terms of how do you actually
get these things out there and avoid the
whisper network yeah I'm not sure that
there's a easy or rights of answer to
that question here we don't have enough
time to discuss that one here yeah
there's there certainly the belief from
from some folks that there's some
networks or some customers that like the
government for instance will want
answers about the vulnerability as early
as possible because they like asking
those questions I don't think they ever
really do it useful with it but they
they sure to act like to ask the
question for operators though there's
some folks that other networks will
depend upon in order to get the fix so
if you have to go across tds telecom to
get to Juniper you probably want to make
sure the t-test telecom is okay I mean
you might also look at Martin and say I
hope is dns server work so I can look up
or you have your etsy host primed right
I mean then there's that there's no
unfortunately it is a very complicated
answer and I'm certainly not qualified
answers but not completely
yeah I think I'll stay with me too
Martin I'm sorry that I lost you for
another time back on ok professor
Matthews did you have a question as well
no I if I've failed to answer anyone's
question I just wanted to let you know
that I departed from you for a short bit
there a line got dropped and added out
back in ok we've actually gone to the
point where we're taking the last
question that we've received and it's
directed at one of the panel members how
do you make sure I'm sorry go ahead i
play it's not a question that's just a
recommendation speak up please for the
next panel you have I'd like to hear the
devil's advocate position for example on
slide one I know we don't have time to
discuss that now but I know it's a
controversial
just a stretch up this
so you're suggesting that we what take
somebody who has different views I don't
understand yeah and there is there are
obviously several people who think that
full disclosure immediately should be
done that's why the audience is here and
you you are who from where Tristan horn
from collabnet thank you ok this is the
last question that we can take and it's
from Jay again how do you make sure the
providers which represent a significant
amount of traffic and customer base but
which are not on the radar because
they're not tier ones and I believe he's
referring to skitter or purchase
refurbished network hardware and
therefore do not maintain support
contracts or are otherwise trying to
remain solvent are informed in a timely
fashion so that they have an opportunity
to upgrade their networks before it's
too late and I don't really have an
answer for that I think that goes
towards the first question although i
think discussing the skidder gator and
its use is applied to this is useful but
again another topic that yeah i think it
is probably a lot more detail that we
can go into right now yeah there was
just one quick comment as an important
point in its question those who don't
have support contracts right if you
don't have a support contract the vendor
really has no obligation to tell you
anything and I mean I hate to say that
because I have lots of stuff my own
personal things I have some or contracts
but you know that's the vendor if you're
looking for the vendor to tell you
they're not going to tell you unless you
have a support contract except for a
couple of vendors who do public releases
of information and fixes and provide the
fix for free and
anyone do you think they love it well
not all do you think though that them
there could or there may be an issue
that much like Microsoft gave sp2 out
that a hardware and network hardware
vendors should give a release of kodell
to solve a major problem regardless of
your status but yeah I think they both
do chris is Right most do i think i
really want to speak out of turn cuz i
don't work for the company i think that
least we're not swinging that radar
doesn't but that's some of the vendors
that have to hash out among themselves
there's ok reasons why they want to keep
support cut support contracts around ok
i don't see is I think we're done so I'd
like to thank all of our panelists I'd
like to thank professor Matthews for
joining us Jerry Dixon I'd like to thank
Randy bush and Steve Bell oven for some
consultation on this panel and I hope
that we presented a rounded and well
balanced opinion from multiple sides of
the house this is for the most part
pretty unscripted and hopefully we gave
you something to think about thank you