good afternoon or actually not quite yet
good afternoon eastern time anyway for
me my name is Todd Reil Kaplan I'm from
a company called acne packet which makes
session border controllers for the
carrier space and I submitted a
presentation in to Nana because they'd
asked for presentations about white
security architectures issues and
analysis from the field and the reality
is most carriers don't want to talk
about it and for a lot of good reasons
and some that aren't so good but so as a
vendor I thought that we could represent
kind of what's happening out in the
community and from a vendor agnostic
viewpoint of course and so that's the
purpose this presentation with 30
minutes there's only so much you can do
on VoIP security it's a huge topic there
are sessions that go on for days at some
conferences and certainly vendors have
tons of slides around it so there's only
really so much I can talk about today
but I guess I want to start with how
many people here at least know basics of
SIP protocol raise your hand
least know how to spell sip okay so yeah
but half the room you know I've been to
Nanog before and I kind of figured that
it's a fairly data centric meeting in
terms of the attendees so I try to make
this less wipe specific or telco
specific but something that just can't
be helped
but I guess yeah I guess I'll just get
right into it really so in terms of the
overview this is sort of a Sakai Genda I
really cover greatly but the problem is
that wiped carriers are kind of seeing
today or starting to really show up
today the solutions that they've been
deploying and some one notes from the
field and this presentation is gonna be
from a VoIP service provider large
service providers sort of viewpoint not
from an enterprise viewpoint per se
although some of its also applicable to
enterprises I have about 27 slides in 30
minutes so I'm gonna speak fairly
quickly
I apologize who vote for those who are
not native English speakers and maybe a
little hard to follow
so sort of a quick marketing overview of
VoIP world today from a security
perspective so free peer-to-peer voice
is very nice a lot of people use Skype
they claim some 100 million use
well 100 million downloads it probably
represents about a million users and but
the reality is most people really need
to reach wireline and wireless sets so
pots and cell phones still dominate the
planet Earth cellphones certainly are
not going to go away their utility
function is far too great to go away so
people still need to reach those devices
and grandmas not going to keep her PC on
if she even has a PC on all the time so
a peer-to-peer type protocol with
software based solutions on PCs is
really only applicable to the kind of
people who are in this room frankly the
geeks and the rest of us is the general
consumer market is not as interested in
that and certainly the enterprise
markets not as interested in that from a
carrier enterprise perspective obviously
VoIP is being deployed in huge
quantities today are very fast growth
rate today for a lot of different
reasons classified replacement peering
IP Centrex
cetera et cetera there are several
standards bodies for those of you who
are in the void space know already
there's the PC mmm the packet capable
multimedia market which is the the cable
MS O's there's IMS theis fan working
groups which have defined more the large
carrier telco vision of how sip and
other protocols will in a work for voice
services and not just voiced by the way
it's video it's all multimedia and then
the MSF multi service switching forum
there's some other industry groups as
well but essentially almost every tier
one two three every Tier one tier two
two or three character day is doing VoIP
in some basic sense of wait whether it
be for what I call appearing or
wholesale transport or whether it be an
access a subscriber type model or a
class five replacement they're all doing
it in some way or shape or form some of
them are only in the research stage they
have been that way for four years and
other them not so what's the problem
that I'm going to address in 30 minutes
which is again kind of an unreasonable
task the problem really is that VoIP
service is becoming our problem the
target for attack the service provider
infrastructure is very susceptible to
attacks really soft switches proxies
gateways app servers they're all
software based platforms and in most
general applications they run either on
Sun Metra's or large Sun boxes maybe
large PC based platforms the end of the
day they're mostly really just software
very easy to attack
as you all well know from the website
from HTTP perspective or email
perspective SMTP perspective and even
the hardware so-called hardware based
boxes such as gateways really have a
software component to them as well they
still have either a sip or an mg CP or
h.323 interface let its software based
it's running software on a local
generalized CPU and that's really it's
the port that can be attacked very
easily even the hardware side of them
the DSP side of them so to speak the
part that converts the white bar TP
packets to audio on on the CLEF nice on
the PSTN side is still open to attack
because DSPs actually have a certain
rate at which they can handle are to be
tagged packets and it's not just attacks
its overloads in fact to date most of
the outages so far and the carrier
networks have been really overload
situations unexpected overload
situations we'll talk a little bit about
that later on
the big problem for the these carriers
and one reason I don't want to talk
about it much outside of in just in
within their own organizations and to
their vendors is that it's it's a lot
more than just loss of revenue and have
a service outage due to attacks first of
all their customers will defect they'll
get very scared to voice over IP and
that's a that's a big deal for these
carriers because they're investing
obviously billions of dollars secondly
they can get varnish brand reputation
there are legal responsibility issues as
we've seen recently with 911 get sued if
they don't provide none when one service
that one wasn't exactly an attack
situation it was attacked on people's
family but it wasn't an attack that
caused 911 outage that was more of a
operational or administrative issue I
should say so the real problem though is
that sip over UDP is open open to
everyone and we want it to be right we
want it to be an open communication
medium there is movement for TLS based
whether it be over TCP or the DTLS over
UDP service for sip movement going on
but really that's not available by most
endpoints today and if it's not
available by endpoints and carriers
don't really care about it that much
they want to move there but they just
don't have much equipment that can do it
today even when they have TLS support or
if such support depending on which
flavors you like that doesn't have
anything to do with the hell of service
attacks TLS is not a denial of service
attack protection mechanism it's a
mechanism for encryption and
authentication an authentication can
provide you some
attack protection but the reality is
that people implement those protocols
either in software or where the hardware
accelerator off the CPU at which point
it's really too late in this in the
multi stage process instead of the
equipment you can already attack it long
before it ever has to reach the encrypt
decrypter chip essentially so it doesn't
really provide Dass attack protection in
any form depending on how you implement
it if SEC wise in the 3gpp world the
third generation partnership program the
which originally was in the cellphone
side of the planet which is now being
moved into IMS or the wireline side for
telcos if SEC is still in the standards
bodies there and it's been deployed with
the gg SNS for cell phone communication
but is not really being deployed for the
wire line people don't really want to
implement it for a number of reasons and
the complexity of it per se and then of
course the natural problems with it so
even though I know there is a extension
to use GDP based encapsulation so you
can get past that the service provider
really rarely knows or limits the source
addresses of packets coming in from
their subscribers or peering points
mostly because they don't know where
they're going to be coming from they
know maybe there would be from class B's
or class C's or from a certain address
range but they don't have such provision
per subscriber which address should be
allowed in and which address should not
and even for peering connections so to
speak which a white perspective are
between two white providers they may
know that the source address is but
still gonna be a range because it's a
range of equipment that's talking to
them and of course it can be spoofed
unless people do what Vijay was talking
about in AOL where they try to limit at
least with ACLs at the borders some of
those even if you know unicast RPF which
is a pretty huge performance set on most
routers today there's only so much you
can really do to stop spoof attacks even
with digest authentication so in sip
there's this digest authentication
mechanism which is actually fairly
common to it commonly used today it's a
very basic type it's HTTP digest
authentication it's not hard to attack
has nothing to do with preventing an
attack it's just about some simple very
simple authentication mechanism and so
again it's very easy to overload that
sip server whether it be a soft switch
proxy you name it
and then of course thoughts attacks may
not bring that server down a lot of
vendors today are talking about how
their boxes Dass hardened or das
protected what they really mean is their
box won't crash it won't reboot just
because they get a das attack but the
service is still down
you're still flooding their CPU with
bogus attempts to make calls and other
legitimate users can't make calls that's
so the users that's the same as being
down they don't really care that your
box didn't reboot
they only care that they can't make a
legitimate phone call or video call or
whatever so the first solution which
started happened about three years ago
was to centralize the VoIP equipment
into a data center essentially or one or
two data centers and it put a firewall
in front of it
they also implement some router ACLs
very basic router ACLs to try to stop
some simple attacks but the problem was
that das attacks on overloads would
still flood their internal equipment or
flood the firewall it didn't matter and
so in fact made it a little easier
because everything was coming in to one
point much easier to overload a single
point that it is multiple distributed
points of course it also had problems
when they try to use multiple paths
outside connectivity to their central or
sorry to their data center because if
the return path couldn't be guaranteed
to go through the same firewall and that
firewall couldn't that much try to open
media holes has nothing to do with that
return path of the media from the other
side and then it's fairly inflexible in
terms of design constraints I think
everybody understands that enough to
explain it to you what did firewalls do
or what I even still do today mostly is
they really provide very rudimentary
screening of sip one of the big issues
with deploying firewalls for sip is that
the reverse is really the firewall model
so to speak the connections which
normally enterprises think of as
starting from inside the enterprise
going out so you using your PC for web
browsing or email whatever what started
me out from the inside going out in this
model it really coming from the outside
coming in subscribers making calls into
the carrier so the firewall model really
reversed which meant there was no way
for them to always allow people make
calls from the outside coming in you
basically had to open up holes you
opened up the hole the firewall is not
doing anything other than stopping
people from using other port numbers
so it's really a fairly simplistic
almost trivial method of security some
of them did have built in a LG's
application layer gateways to learn the
RTP pinholes so if you don't know sip
very well or any of the protocols NBC
PhD 23 one of the things they all do is
they dynamically assign UDP port numbers
for the RTP traffic the actual media and
rtcp to the control traffic for it they
decided to dynamically assign those
during this call set up stage so they're
not known ahead of time they're not well
known port numbers ahead of time and of
course a firewalls primary purpose in
life is to block port numbers so one of
the things firewalls had to do very
quickly was learn sip a little bit
enough to open dynamically those
pinholes that the media could actually
flow in and out but again without that
return routing path coming the same
direction they were stuck and the other
interesting point is they had
specialized hardware to handle creating
those open pinholes but really that was
only used for media and not for
signaling the signaling and the
firewalls was still done in a central
sheet view of firewall or maybe
distributed CPUs and that's the actual
attack point media is not really the
attack point those UDP port numbers may
be but RTP traffic itself is not seen as
a major point of attack today it's
really the SIP or run DCP your HT 23
ports that can be attacked because then
you could take down the whole service
forget about the single media call so
people tried to start deploying
firewalls at the edge and actually have
a slide on that yeah so the second
solution but also about three years ago
maybe two years ago that you started to
put firewalls closer to the borders of
their actual data network so to speak so
it obviously provided a little better
protection from simple dos attacks or
even DDoS attacks because you're
dividing the problem space off so
obviously the more you can segment up
the amount of traffic that's coming in
they're trying to overload you the
better off you are very simplistic you
know very basic concept of no brainer
but they still couldn't stop an overload
on the internal sip infrastructure in
other words the firewall doesn't have
enough sip intelligence to know that a
certain number of calls should only be
allowed versus just all sit traffic
also when you add up all those firewalls
even if they're configured as
rate-limiting ACLs you if you add up all
that traffic at once the internal
infrastructure becomes overloaded very
quickly and of course it created these
routing problems even if you tried to
put them in line you couldn't really put
them in line because firewalls don't
perform that well signalling plane only
in the media plane so to speak and and
so you couldn't actually have a min line
for every traffic you had to have them
offline essentially almost like a DMZ
type on a specific location and
ultimately the soft switch and soft
switches and gateways we're still
publicly addressed so they could still
be attacked if you could find a way in
that's not through a firewall and
obviously the more you have with these
on the border the harder it is to
control that make sure that all packets
coming in for those traffic would always
go through a firewall and vice versa
anyone coming through a firewall in the
reverse path as well so again some had
built-in parsers to verify sip packets
even simple simple parses just to verify
sanity of a packet the in terms of the
actual a be enough though the ascii
encoding of the sip packets but they
didn't have any throttles to actually
slow it down from overloads and more
importantly they couldn't tell the good
guys and the bad guys because really the
firewall has no true intelligence at the
SIP layer it really only knows that it's
a sip packet therefore it should be
allowed in at a certain rate let's say
but not that this user is a good sip
user and this the users a bad subuser
they also didn't provide any screening
of the RTP media itself
they simply open media holes they didn't
actually verify that the media was
conforming to what the call was supposed
to allow it to do and of course they
couldn't hand all home users Nats which
is probably the first that was one of
the first applications really for
session border controllers was enabling
people to use sip phones behind their
home Linksys or d-link or you know any
of their local favorite NAT boxes at
home because again for those of you
don't know sip inside of the sip
messages or actual IP addresses for
opening the media holes as well as for
contact information and if you're behind
an act and you're using private
addressing those are all gonna be wrong
once they make it to the carrier so
somebody has to fix that for you there
are some protocols and that are trying
to get deployed today to fix that from a
protocol perspective but up till now
really that's always handled by session
border controller that fixes that for
you at the carrier side in terms of the
firewall attacks I'm talking about I
don't know if you can read this slide
but this is really just a generic list
of your usual everyday firewall
protected attacks session where
controllers can do this - these are your
generic attack types and you'll see that
I put it down than the public names of
some of them because of those those are
the public names of the scripts that you
can download from about 20 different
sites on the web that you can attack
somebody with very easily you don't have
to know anything about IP TCP anything
sip you don't the only thing about any
of those protocols you just download
this little thing some of these even
have a Windows based version of the
attack tool some of them can only run
through a Linux based OS but in terms of
spoofing certainly the real problem
though are these because these are the
actual attack threats that the carriers
are now worried about they can already
protect themselves from the generic HTTP
style or not style but the same attacks
that impacted HTTP and email and other
services those they've already got a
handle on the ones they don't have a
handle on are these the good thing is
you'll see that there aren't that many
public tools to test these which means
there aren't that many public tools for
people to actually attack them the only
well there are a few but the most
well-known one is the pro dos test suite
from the university of oulu and finland
which was just a verification engine
really to test conformance to sip in
terms of the well-formed packet
essentially and that's that's been out
for a while now and there was asserted
vizor e about equipment that didn't pass
these tests essentially easiest way to
explain it so what's happening today and
actually has been happening for about
two years about two years ago session
border controllers started hit the
market they virtually dominate the VoIP
peering role now and again by peering
role I mean the inter carrier connection
for VoIP
whether it be wholesale or even between
two local subscriber providers that want
to exchange VoIP traffic between each
other without going through the PSTN
when I say dominate I mean I'm greater
than about 80% of the market
at those connection points are all
through some session border controller
or another some vendors session border
controller they're starting to dominate
the access role and by access I really
mean the user local user consumer users
subscriber model that Vonage style for
example would provide or an ATT call
Vantage or any of the ones that are
starting to be deployed today and again
the reason that they dominate that role
as one is for security and two is for
the NAT
issue and also interworking problems and
they're about over a dozen vendors that
offer some form of session border
controller for almost every market
whether it be enterprise market carrier
market you name it so what is it because
we talked about even the presenter
before me talked about a session border
controller well and I guess in the most
basic terms I'll break it up into the
words themselves for the acronym so
session meaning real-time interactive
communications using SIP HP 23 MDC PhD
48 you name the call control protocol
most of them support them all border in
terms of an IP to IP network border
whether it be from a service provider to
another service provider or from a
service provider to their users because
even if they own that last mile that
broadband connection they still can't
really trust that user per se not to say
that user is malicious but they can
essentially be used as a malicious
zombie for a DDoS attack and then
controller the control part of it so
authentication authorization submission
tack protection itself overload
protection lawful intercept interworking
protocol fixing all those things are
done by session border controllers today
from almost every vendor that makes them
you know they each have different
features of course but in general those
are the features that most them provide
so at the basic level they control both
signaling and the media and from a sip
perspective they're called it back to
back user agent that's the most common
term used for them for H 823 they're
called it back to back gateway or back
to back gateway gatekeeper for HT 248 or
ng CP they're called it back to that
college and endpoint there's a lot of
different names for these ultimately
though they're really offload some of
the work from the proxy or the saw
switch or the gatekeeper or whatever it
may be and they provide a lot of non
security benefits but since this talks
really about security and it's not
really talk about those frankly
so the idea seems simple enough and
you'll probably hear out there that
session border controllers have a have a
limited lifespan because they'll be
implemented on router blades or on
implemented in other boxes and that
people said that about firewalls too by
the way right when the firewall sphere
started coming out and there our router
blades that do some basic firewall
functionality but nobody really deploys
a router blade as a full-featured
firewall for a carrier they do some
simple ACL certainly but not a true
firewall because it takes a lot of state
to be honest not just special hardware
but a lot of software too and that's
something that states certainly state
memory has rather limited usually
routers so of course it could be done in
a in the firewall or router but only if
it had the right hardware and software
just like the Linksys router for example
could be a core router if it had the
right hardware and software but that's
the brub it doesn't have the right
hardware software so what's so special
about this hardware let's just talk
about the hardware first first of all
such a mortar controllers do twice net
meaning they not both the source and the
destination they do it for thousands and
thousands of flows because they do it
for the media RTP pinholes themselves
not many boxes other than session border
controllers can do that today in
hardware and of course for the media you
want to do it as quickly as possible so
you don't introduce delay they also
perform udp-based das attack protection
and hardware most firewalls really
provide tcp-based thoughts attack
protection not unity based sauce attack
protection because most protocols don't
run over UDP except now we do have
something not say that the aren't very
good protocols run of UDP but we're just
talking about generically from a
importance perspective and then of
course they police they have the ability
at least in hardware to police tens of
hundreds of thousands of those media
flows as well as signaling flows
themselves and then they can do a lot of
other things they can measure the audio
of video quality of that RTP because
they're in that path and they have
special hardware to do that measurement
they can also monitor there are TCP
reported values they can perform 2833
translation 2033
by the way is the ITF RFC for doing DTMF
dual-tone multi-frequency tones those
are the buttons you press on your phone
that produces those little sounds you
hear those in sip land are usually
transported in the RTP stream a special
RTP packets called 20:33 packets
but an HP 23 side of the planet Earth or
even a lot of boxes today they don't
support that method for those tones
transport so somebody has to fix that
for them because they supported as
out-of-band signaling instead of in ban
media statement and then Kalia or lawful
intercept
I don't usually call lawful intercept
the security feature because it's not
really security for the provider it's
more about except for maybe securing
them from from lawsuits I guess but
ultimately really lawful intercept is
usually thrown together with security
for some reason so I threw it in here as
well and that's usually done in hardware
as well for copying both the signaling
and the media plane you have to make a
mirror copy of that send it to a very
special box that allows you to collect
that function and send it on to the
government agencies so that's the
hardware side what about the software
what's so special about session border
controller software well first of all
they are back to back user agent which
is a fairly heavy stack means you have
to have a full stack on both sides of
the trusted or untrusted domain that
means they actually keep some session
state call state essentially they don't
have to depends on how you configure
them but in general for the most secure
model you usually configure them for
session state so enforce it behavior and
then they can do call gapping which
means they can prevent overloads from
your from attacking your infrastructure
there is no deeper packet inspection
ability than when you actually is that
10 mean 10 minutes or do I get a score
of 10 means 10 minutes huh Wow all right
this will be very fast 10 minutes or
very long 10 minutes so there's no
deeper packet inspection ability than
being the packet receiver originator
clearly that is the most deep way you
can get when you actually go through the
mime attachment and actually recreate it
you are doing deep packet inspection you
get a chance to remove headers modify
headers do all kinds of cool things
which some people think are evil things
but carriers think they're cool because
it allows them to control what goes in
and out of their network and then you
can do complete topology hiding and
that's the part I'll talk a little bit
about very quickly and again you can do
a lot of other things too overlapping
addresses tax signatures for our
protection etcetera so I'm running out
of time gonna go very quickly through
this
sowhat's twice that and why is that so
important
and I know a lot of people think that is
the you know
mother of all evils in the planet earth
and it and it certainly would be if it
weren't for the fact that so many people
use it and actually provide some very
rudimentary but useful security features
so one of the first problem is session
border controller solved was how to fix
or peg really make sure that the path
coming in is the same path going out for
sip calls and for the media because
ultimately they're the ones that I can
be opening those pinholes the easiest
and fastest answer to do that is to
replace all the IP addresses on one side
with different p addresses on the other
side essentially you can think of this
from an enterprise perspective when you
have that HTTP proxy box that you have
to talk through an HTTP proxy to make
web connections outside it's kind of
like that model where you have to talk
through a session border controller to
reach into the core and vice versa to
reach out of the core you have to talk
through a session border controller is
your destination and your source the
cool thing about that or the very
important thing about that is it
actually provides a complete separation
in terms of IP addressing and routing of
the internal sip infrastructure or mgcp
or HT 248 or h2 323 whatever again I'm
gonna talk to start a sip here but it
can be any of those protocols provide a
completely separate internal addressing
scheme than it is external which means
you can use a private address space
internally or you can use a public one
that you never advertised out either
through BGP or any other routing
protocol that means nobody can attack it
not only do they not know what those IP
addresses are because the session border
controller will replace all those
headers that they go in and out so that
you can't even discover what their
addresses are you can't reach those
addresses from outside their unreachable
even if you knew what their address is
worth and that's the primary security
function of a twice net feature so what
well the important point is when a call
gets made into your sip infrastructure
the call can move you can move around
all over the place you can move at the
sip layer you can move at the RTP layer
firewalls can't handle it because they
don't really understand sip they're not
a full sip lair if they have a full sip
stack and they do b2b way then
ultimately there are session border
controller they don't they're not so
what do they have to do they need a DMZ
they actually send everything to a
default they also can't guarantee they
return path we talked about there before
so doing that twice that also provides
some other interesting features
number one is you always know your
packet
where they're coming in and going out so
from a security perspective its provides
some very nice spots to look at I guess
is a way to say it monitor it also
simplifies your IP routing an MPLS
infrastructure because your effects are
now those a session border controllers
addresses you have to worry about all
the external dresses
we're internal dresses it also means you
don't have to advertise them we talked
about that already and again really what
it provides is that that singular point
and it's enough to be singular and from
the sense of your whole network
you usually deploy multiple session
border controllers but that call that
comes in or goes out through a session
border controller stays at that session
border controller doesn't move around
and that provides a whole bunch of
advantages so what about router ACL is a
lot of people say well I can do some
security with router ACLs no you can't
it's virtually useless it's very nice
but the problem is you have to keep port
5060 open to make calls just like you
have to keep port 1719 1720 open to make
calls for eight to twenty three or
twenty seven twenty seven for mgcp etc
that the problem is that's the exact
port that's going to be attacked
nobody's gonna care about attacking port
6000 unless have some you know Microsoft
made product uses six thousand people
then people will attack it all the time
but if it's only fifty sixty that's the
one people are gonna attack so you can
throttle it but then you're just
providing an easier way to attack
because if you throttle port 5060 people
don't have to send as much traffic to
overload it because they'll just
overload your throttle your ACL so again
it's not as good and then of course for
the media side those are all dynamically
discovered ports dynamically created
signal ports for RTP so as Microsoft is
set on their knowledge base since 1999
to establish an outbound net meeting
which happens h.323 but can do sips some
day to the firewall must be configured
to do the following has to pass through
primary TCP connections and 520 to 389
1503 1720 1731 and it has passed through
secondary TP connections on everything
from a thousand to sixty-five K which is
about as secure as as I guess nobody
this is not at all secure what's that
five
so a new security model so most
firewalls are public device agnostic
again the model is reversed for this
protocol because the users on the
outside the untrusted side not to say
that the inside is fully trusted either
by the way
most security experts will tell you that
the inside should be just as untrusted
as the outside of your network but
session border controllers can control
both sides of that equation so they can
actually make sure the both sides are
really untrusted to some degree so again
this is reversing that role whereas
session border controllers can actually
create a trust relationship with those
devices here's one example of how they
do it that session border controller is
actually the address that you gives your
endpoints users fuse as their sip proxy
address or the sip registrar address
that register message from sip actually
goes to the session border controller
and that session border controller can
actually look at the register and make
sure that that user gets authorized as
with a 200 ok response that means he can
discover and learn and use that as a
trust relationship for allowing calls or
denying calls in the future something
that firewalls don't do that's just one
example so I have five minutes I will
very go quickly go through some notes
from the field so again these are kind
of generalized nobody really wants to
talk about their security issues outside
of their of the vendor community and
carrier community peering notes the
traffic volume is growing but it's still
not that huge really per pop it's about
one to four thousand simultaneous calls
average per pop sip and 8023 are still
used a 323 is still a fairly large chunk
of the VoIP traffic market despite what
everybody may want to think and trust me
I'd prefer it weren't the case it's it's
more complicated to have to support that
as a protocol as somebody earlier
pointed out most dialing plans are still
configured statically there is no enum
it's not to say there isn't any enum but
very few enum services out there for
private enum even for public enum it's
not used much trip which was supposed to
be this bgp based nice inter domain
protocol for exchanging phone numbers
and reach ability has not been
implemented we're actually it's deployed
by very many nobody really nobody's
appointed and then the nice thing is
attacks and parent points don't happen
very often first of all because they're
they allow for some very simple security
model because usually you know exactly
what the source addresses are above your
peer
also sip is not often done I'm sorry it
is often done over TCP with IPSec were
some TLS is starting to show up today
but mostly still if say and that if SEC
is really done by a VPN tunnel box not
native sip if sex support and the nice
thing as most people don't know the
address is there so it's hard for them
to attack and usually they can't attack
it anyway because those addresses are in
the corn advertisement outside of those
two peering connections from an access
perspective sip is definitely growing
very very fast 8023 though is still in
existence for enterprise customers
because PBX is must be - I'm down to two
minutes this would be very long two
minutes so the traffic volume is booming
but it's it's there's a great variance
in the traffic volume of different pops
you most I guess the average which is
not to say that the bounds of the
average are very very tightly
constrained but the average is about 20k
subscribers and 2k simultaneous calls
today per pop but some pops have 10
times that amount so it's a great
variance in that number there's still a
lot of home user net issues I know
people want to do stun turn ice and sis
UPnP amid calm and 15 other protocols
they haven't really been deployed some
sip endpoints now have stun support but
stun doesn't work through symmetric
restricted Nats which unfortunately are
large portion of the Nats in existence
especially at enterprise customers so
you have to do turn and there's almost
no turn deployments today and they add a
lot of complexities frankly so they have
a lot of issues let me go try to go
quickly through yeah I'm trying to be
right up wrap up so I guess the good
news is there haven't been that many
reported attacks at least other than
overloads like apartments coming back
online or American Idol Believe It or
Not American Idol is an overload event
today even for the TDM side which is why
they have to publish more and more
numbers that go through different pops
to get to them and then the only way to
do the recorded vulnerabilities have
really been malformed packet handling to
date and a lot of this is really I'm
gonna be a marketing issue this carriers
aren't gonna want to report them
publicly so again where to go from here
you didn't you talk to vendors you have
you're gonna get these slides anyways
you can go through this the last piece
is just on the test tools
there are some testicles available today
already that can do some pretty clever
attacks sit pee which is an open-source
test tool which wasn't me to do attacks
but could easily be run as an attack
tool can do about 2500 n bytes per
second which is about a nine million
busy hour call attempts which is most
more than most soft switches can really
support I actually personally wrote an
attack tool that does about 25,000
invites a second which is about 90
million busy hour call attempts which is
more than the u.s. gets and that's just
off this laptop that I'm doing this
presentation on with its fast ethernet
interface it's about the max of fast
ethernet faced can push 25,000 unique
calls generated per second and I'm not a
programmer that was very simple
programming in C++ and and again all the
publicly available attack scripts can
also fill port 5060 if they can attack
using UDP in port 5060 they can fill sip
and that's the problem so any questions
sorry for the very condensed you know
these are Cohen's what you can do in 30
minutes no questions
this answered all your problems
excellent I guess we're done then okay
there it is thank you