right so my name is Rob Beverly and I'm
here to tell you about some work that
myself and some colleagues at at MIT
steve bauer in particular did called the
scooper project so as i'm sure many of
the people in this audience are well
aware of spoofing but i'd like to take
just a couple minutes to talk about it
briefly in order to motivate the work
that we're doing here so obviously
spoofing is the process of a host that
forges parts of the headers of IP
packets in order to do something usually
for a malicious purpose so why do i do
attackers or compromised hosts or people
like that do this so the first reason of
course is anonymity in order for the
host to hide behind a spoof source
address there's also more sophisticated
attacks that people can employ for
instance the reflector attacks that
Paxton has detailed and of course from
the bgp tcp resets that we've heard
about in the past so there's been a
string of high-profile spoofing based
dos attacks particularly like in
2000-2001 we had a tax against yahoo
eBay etrade there's worms that have been
floating around for instance the shaft
reno etc and I tried to get some more
recent data I just did a quick scan of a
ddos website and noticed that this stuff
still goes on even in 2004 so a bunch of
us that were back essentially at school
thinking about architectural level
issues came up with this question of
like well in essence does spoofing even
matter in 2005 right is this still a
relevant interesting problem should we
even consider whether this is a problem
in the architecture or not so the sort
of high-level you know devil's advocate
is all ISPs do filtering right so they
do RFC 28 27 or unicast RPF the second
reason it may not matter is because a
lot of these attackers these days are
relying on huge zombie farms that
provide little additional anonymity when
you actually do spoofing and then the
third reason of course is the prevalence
of gnats as we've heard other people
talk about the headers are rewritten and
so it essentially makes spoofing useless
however when we look at these network
telescopes that people have installed
around parts of the internet we
the continued strong spoofing activity
as recently as 2004 and I know people at
kata have even more recent data so as we
know from other as you know operational
people obviously no tracking spoof it
spoofs is an operationally difficult
problem there was a talk at nana auger a
few years back from some of the folks
that you unit steve bell oven has come
up with proposals for icmp trace backs
other researchers have looked at things
like hash based IP trace back all these
are designed in essence in order to
track where the source of these spoof
packets are so in order to sort of
answer the question of well you know how
prevalent is spoofing or how how well am
i able to do spoofing we started the
spoofer project and the idea here is
this is quite simply just an internet
wide act of measurement project where
we'd like to quantify the extent in
nature of source address filtering on
the internet here's the ural for the
project website the again the idea is
quite simple clients simply run a
spoofer binary we also have source
available and many of you have may have
seen my advertisement to various mailing
list such as Nana kada some of the
firewall mailing lists etc I'm going to
get to all that in a bit so the idea
here is that the client sends a series
of spoofed UDP packets and it sends five
of each type the type of UDP packet we
send is we specifically craft them in
order to figure out and to infer
specific ISP policies I'll get into that
in just a few slides and we use in a
random inner packet delay between
packets in order to try to mitigate any
effects that might occur from from
normal loss of UDP packets in the
network each packet contains a 14 bite
identifier which uniquely identifies it
and all of these packets go to a server
that sits on our campus as they received
the packets are thrown into a database
after the client finishes sourcing all
of these spoofed packets it runs a
traceroute to our server this lets us
know actually the forward path that the
spoofed RIMPAC
traverse in order to get to our server
and then it establishes a tcp connection
that reports this tracer out and it
sends essentially a summary of all the
different packets that it attempted to
send in the course of doing spoofing two
things that we do do we use UDP port 53
which is obviously DNS this lets us
hopefully get around any secondary
filtering effects that people might have
in place usually DNS can get through we
use port 80 for the TCP connection and
again this is to his most accurate view
as possible so the identifiers that are
in each of these packets allow us to
disambiguate which one's made it through
all the analysis and the web pages are
driven off of these this database so I
alluded to the fact that we send a
series of different spoof packets and we
try to do this in a somewhat intelligent
fashion so the first three that you see
here the first one is actually a a bogan
address which is means that it's a
legitimate address but it's not actually
existing in the global BGP tables the
second address is a valid address in the
BGP tables except it exists it belongs
to another organization the third one is
an RFC 1918 private address which of
course is not supposed to be routable or
to traverse organizational boundaries
the the last one here is the neighbor
spoofing which I'll go into in more
detail in a few slides as well so here's
an example of a client run and I'll go
on to some results because this is
perhaps the most interesting part of my
whole talk so from march two thousand
five which is approximately when we
announced this thing we got about 570
client reports of those about 440 were
unique and when I talked about the
believed unspookable net blocks or
believed unspookable portions of the
network I'm actually talking about
portions of the network from from which
we did receive reports but we see no
corroborating evidence that spoofing
exists we use the University of Oregon
rat views table to determine things like
perfect size and asses do all the
mapping and I should note that we do
exclude a number of different classes of
reports from our results one of the
things that we find
is that although we have windows clients
windows xp service pack 2 specifically
actually explicitly forbids creating raw
sockets with spoofed IP headers we saw
about 118 of 209 reports where they were
blocked this way other operating systems
can also block creation of the raw
socket for instance of your running ipfw
or something like that we saw 19 of
those and of course there's going to be
hosts behind Nats where the packets make
it through but obviously the spoofing
had no effect so in sum total
approximately two-thirds of the client
reports we got failed to spoof any
packets whatsoever so this is some some
pretty pie charts which may or may not
be misleading depending on how you
interpret them this is on our website as
well there's a continuously actually
hourly updated web page that tries to
provide a view of the entire you know
view of the world as we've seen it in
terms of spoofing the major thing I
guess to takeaway here is that no matter
what metric you sort of slice the
problem on today whether it be net
blocks IP addresses or autonomous
systems we see you know anywhere from 23
to 24 about you know quarter of each of
these where we actually see that one of
these packets that we tried to spoof
actually made it through so this
corresponds to you know approximately 65
you know net blocks corresponding to
about 208 million IP addresses and 45
autonomous systems the numbers at the
bottom here are actually if we try to
extrapolate that out to the entire
internet space and I can talk about
later offline if you'd like some work we
did to try to say whether or not that's
a reasonable assumption or not I
probably won't have time to talk about
it and just talk though so the as i said
we send a number of different packets
try to infer the policies that are in
place so it's very easy for an isp to
for instance simply block all the RFC
1918 this is a static policy it's never
going to change and it's fairly easy to
administer there's also as I'm sure many
of you are aware other automated methods
for doing various filtering for instance
some providers may only allow packets to
be sent or routed if there is a
corresponding
valid BGP route for that source or for
instance the Bogue on route server
project from Rob Thomas and his crew so
here's a table that tries to capture
this this notion of the frequency of
inconsistent filtering so we see that
for instance there's 17 of the sessions
where the valid address was not filtered
but the bogans in RFC 1918 work and we
see an even larger number where bogans
and ballads made it through but RFC 1918
did not and so again this is an instance
of a very specific policy so again I
looted to this this web page this is I
hope you'll take at least a quick look
at it this tries to summarize the
current state of IP spoofing as we've
seen it so of course our goal is to
continue collecting reports in order to
improve our accuracy to get a wider view
of the network and also to detect trends
so of course we need operator help to
expand coverage and and gain more data
here's a quick view of what that page
looks like you can go to it on your own
so I also talked about this notion of
the neighbor spoof that our test does so
in general as you might expect you're
probably always going to be able to
spoof your maybe immediate neighbor
ip-address so this would be your address
plus or minus one there it's usually not
a problem the exception of course being
on some cable modem head ends and things
like this so the idea here was to
actually figure out what granularity
policy you know is applied by ISPs so
what we do is we try successive
successively larger boundaries we start
with a / 31 which is going to correspond
to your immediate neighbor go to / 30
and go all the way up to the /a to see
at what at what granularity policy is
applied and this summarizes this is the
probability distribution of the
filtering granularity we see spikes as
we might expect at some of the classical
boundaries so for instance we see a lot
of people are applying their filters on
/ 24s and / AIT's a full forty percent
are on the / 8 which is indicative of
the fact that if you're intelligent
about your spoofing you can probably do
a fair amount
damage so the last thing I wanted to
show was a visualization actually of
looking at the spoofing what I'm going
to call the spoofing perimeter so the
idea here is that you know all this data
and tables is nice and all but it would
be even better if we could get some
reasonable idea of what the geographic
spread or what this sort of extent of
the of this crucible portion of the
network was so what we wanted to do was
to overlay the spoof abul portion of the
network on top of the amount of the
network that we observed from all of our
different clients so we use one of
katie's tools it's a called otter from
Bradley huffaker to build the a s graph
and each node actually on the graph
corresponds to the a s for which the
client belongs to and then we also have
nodes for all of the asses along the
path from that client to our server each
edge of course is defined by the a s
path and we use a semi geographic
coordinate system again this is similar
to the the skitter a escapology graphs
you may have seen from kata our server
is actually at the center of this graph
it's the root and the AS hop distance is
represented by the radius of each node
finally the node degree represents the
longitude of the a s of the organization
of a s4 which the client belong to so
here's a picture this sort of looks like
soup here but again at the center is our
server the one portion up to the right I
believe is the US the other is Europe
and we have Asia sitting over here and
if we overlay that with the portion of
the network that's suitable we can get
some sort of cool visualizations and so
I think amount of time so I'll wrap up
with that and take any questions you
might have
oh ok thanks