well good morning everybody and thank
you for joining us welcome to Toronto
welcome distinguished government
representatives ladies and gentlemen and
the entire i kin community on behalf of
syrah canada's ccTLD CA i welcome you to
canada and certainly to i can 45 i'd
also like to take a moment to
acknowledge and thank i can for
entrusting syrup with the hosting duties
for this very important meeting this is
fadi chehade 'he's first I can meeting
as its new CEO and I'd like to extend a
very special welcome to him I think we'd
all acknowledge that it's not an
exaggeration to say that the Internet is
at a critical juncture right now the
global domain name ecosystem is about to
radically change with the introduction
of many many new gTLDs and over the past
years we've witnessed a number of
challenges to the multi-stakeholder
model for governing the Internet the
model that i can has more or less used
successfully since its inception these
challenges are becoming more varied and
more frequent and as a result i can has
found itself thrust into an ever more
public role with a stronger global
acceptance of his of its mandate as a
basic requirement these are busy and
complicated times for i can and i
commend fatty for taking on his new role
as CEO earlier than expected it goes
those sayings the critical juncture and
it's incumbent upon you fatty to do a
great job not only is the leader of a
global organization but in ensuring
ICANN's operations are carried out in a
manner that is beyond reproach and above
all we look to you to lead us in
developing and championing the
multi-stakeholder model so no pressure
fatty
no pressure but let me be the first to
say that from everything that I have
seen to date in your brief tenure it's
very promising very promising but I also
know that you can't do it alone so I
think that it is our collective
obligation those in this room and online
those who are invested in this space to
act as ambassadors for the model and in
an effort to support the important work
of I can and its leadership together we
need to support body and I can as it
moves through this inflection point into
the next phase of its existence we need
to work together to create a strong and
stable foundation upon which I cans new
leadership team can succeed over the
coming week please approach this meeting
with a commitment to openness and
transparency and with recognition that
what we are discussing has global impact
it behooves each and every one of us to
work together not just to advance our
own personal goals or those of our
organizations but with the recognition
that what we are discussing has serious
global impact with that said I welcome
you to Toronto mild hometown and to
Canada my country Toronto is one of the
most wired cities in the world and
Canadians are among some of the most
engaged internet users in the world
we're very much a tech centric nation so
it's only fitting I think that I can
hold a meeting here we're tremendously
honored to be your host and hope you
have a chance to really explore Toronto
this wonderful city I promise the
weather is going to get better in the
next couple of days so you can explore
it without a without a rain jacket I
dialed up the better weather but it's
coming via snail mail not internet
speeds so
please also take the opportunity to come
to our booth which is right next door to
get information about the city and dare
I say it get your free beaver I look
forward to hosting the gala on Wednesday
night at the CN Tower which is just down
the street and is the fairly obvious
building on the graphic behind me will
be our pleasure to welcome fifteen
hundred of our closest friends from
around the world over for dinner that
said the discussions that are going to
be held in this building over the course
of the next week will literally be felt
around the world and that level of
importance is not lost on Sarah and I
hope not on this crowd although I'm sure
it's not so have a great week enjoy
Toronto and thank you very much for
joining us here