when we have some new interesting things
that are happening we're going to post
them on the homepage and in that first
home page I'm going to show you
something that I want to bring to your
attention and this is interesting
because when Sally and I joined I can
one of the first things we asked for can
we get a picture that describes how
internet governance works and generally
we got horrified looks what do you mean
a picture that tells you how the
internet governance works ok how about a
picture how I can works well yeah here's
here's forty pages go read them maybe
we're simple people but I think a
picture would be really helpful so we
started putting together an effort and
we actually reached out also to the rirs
and other I star organizations to get
their ideas so here on the right is
literally a doodle the initial doodles
and we're offering them to you so you
can go and give us input on them so
here's the first doodle we're working on
which is how the multi-stakeholder
Internet Governance works who's who what
do they do right this is just an it's
not the finished product it's just a
sketch but we're starting to work on it
this is now on my I can so please go
because at the bottom of this form you
can give us your comments your insight
your ideas but it would be great if all
of us in the next few months when we go
to wicked to various environments we
mean government's who are explaining to
them what I can is we have a picture
that we and the other I organizations
agree on hey this is how it works ok I
think it's already very helpful it'll
help my mom to who's still at 86 trying
to figure out what the heck I do all day
and we did the same thing for and I can
so this is I can how does I can work
what is inside I can what do we do this
is actually a tougher one than the first
one but please again it's out there on
my I can go in look at them scrutinize
them give us your ideas and tell us all
the things I still don't know and Sally
still to discover this is why it's there
for you