good afternoon everybody so our next
speaker today is Jeremy Rasmussen the
title of his speech is election hacking
getting ready for the Russian onslaught
in 2020 a little bit about Jeremy Jeremy
Rasmussen is chief and technology
officer in a pact owed a Florida based
company that provides managed cyber
security services to growing businesses
across all industries ABBA code employs
global thought leaders and industry
experts in ethical hacking corporate
governance and incidents response to
provide its clients with a holistic view
of cybersecurity he is also an adjunct
professor at the University of South
Florida and founder of the USF white
Hatter's computer security Club since
2000 he has taught us F courses in
cryptography and network security
ethical hacking digital forensics and
investigations and mobile and wireless
security he has more than 25 years of
experience in performing R&D and
developing cybersecurity solutions for
government and commercial customers
Jeremy is a certified information
systems security professional certified
ethical hacker and project management
professional he was named the 2017 Tampa
Bay technology leader of the year for
his presentation efforts to protect the
integrity of the u.s. voting system had
become a national priority following
allegations of Russian interference oh
all right well his I have a Kabat of
just going on too long okay with 20 2019
warm welcome for mr. Jeremy Rasmussen
[Applause]
really appreciate it
sorry for the technical difficulties I
think we got everything sorted out now
so election hacking this is kind of a
big deal right we've heard about it the
last few years and I got a cool
opportunity to go behind the scenes in
fact here's my shout out so first of all
AB code cyber I'm the CTO Phil buck is
the one from Canton news who got me
interested in this in this whole area
and it was kind of funny because he was
like I'm gonna hand over the keys to you
you get to do the interviews I'm just
gonna stand by and shoot you know shoot
video and so I got to actually do the
interviewing and ask the questions I was
thankful to our pinellas election
supervisor della Clark for letting us go
behind the scenes and actually get on
those systems and try to see you know
look at them some of these guys are
really out there Andrew Appel verified
voting and some of these resources these
guys actually have you know gotten the
systems into their labs and being able
to do the hardware hacking and so forth
I haven't done that to that extent but I
have you know definitely studied some of
the issues around that the other thing
I'd recommend to you is a DEFCON voting
village this is Matt blaze and some
other folks who have have tried to try
to bring the awareness out there to the
public about what are the issues around
electronic voting and how can we
implement best practices and of course
as he said white hat or shout out to my
lads and ladies there who you know
that's our local team here of students
that we're trying to you know raise up
for the next for the future of
cybersecurity here at USF alright so the
first thing I actually do is show the
video it's like two minutes long and
then we'll talk about you know basically
expanding on what we found in that video
to talk about you know history of cyber
attacks on voting and what are the
threat vectors we're gonna go into five
of them in a particular and how we can
come up with countermeasures for those
to reduce risk and then you know I'm
gonna ask you some questions but I think
you know I'll give you what my
conclusions are but maybe we'll open it
up at the end for questions as well all
right so first thing
cross your fingers and see if this will
actually work all right let's do that so
right now it's playing out of the that
thing so we're gonna we're gonna bring
it back here and I'm gonna play it out
of my computer sound that's gonna be
internal and that's a good idea we're
[Music]
how Florida's election system stands up
to the cybersecurity test I'm Phil buck
and I'm a registered voter here in the
state of Florida but I'm also a
journalist covering the 2018 midterm
election cybersecurity is a huge concern
in elections today so I wanted to see
just how secure our election systems are
here in Florida
oh and instead of asking the questions
myself I brought a few hackers along
with me are the communications encrypted
between the the client and server the
multiple layers of encryption there's no
such thing as 100% secure system there's
always gonna be ways you can figure out
how to get in we also use something in
some of our penetration testing called a
rubber ducky what actually which
actually has it looks like a USB thumb
drive but it actually has the capability
of doing keystrokes have you do you have
physical security protections against
somebody coming up and doing something
like that our culture is changing at the
Supervisor of Elections Office we are
talking about cyber security we're
thinking about cyber security and we're
constantly teaching about cyber security
everyone in this building is always on
guard for potential threats whether it
is picking up the USB in the parking lot
are potentially clicking on an email
upstairs we have spent a considerable
amount of time making sure that these
systems are all accurate and secure and
prior to Election Day we have k9 units
come in from the sheriff's office to go
through the machines to know no internet
connection no internet connection at all
overall I feel pretty comfortable with
how the elections are run the equipment
they're using is 10 plus years old but
they have some fail safes in place they
have risk management in place they have
layers of security a place that would
make it overall a difficult task if
you're gonna try to manipulate that
system I feel as a voter I feel
comfortable walking into the polling
place and casting my vote and that it's
gonna count you know the way that I
intended it to rasmussen and other
cybersecurity experts agree it would be
extremely hard for hackers to actually
change vote tallies here in Florida but
they say just solving mistrust in our
election system and creating doubt in
voters minds could be enough of a
victory or our enemies the polls are
open from 7:00 a.m. to 7:00 p.m. if
you're in line by 7:00 you can still
vote well done team
all right so I kind of stole my own
thunder at the end you know I I don't
know if I'm that comfortable as I came
off on that we had done this right I do
I was very great it was very gracious of
them to even let us in with all that
they had going on but here's so the
first thing I want to do is let's talk
about you know history of cyber attacks
on voting and the thing we're not going
to talk about is what I would call pre
voting cyber attacks so we know we're
well aware that you know Hillary's
campaign manager John Podesta his email
was hacked we know that there was
coordinated information warfare where
they're disseminating some of those
leaked documents to DC leaks and
WikiLeaks we know that there they were
trying to manipulate public perception
through fake you know bot accounts on
Twitter and you know collecting data
through Facebook and all this you know
fake news stories and all that we know
all that was going on what I'm really
concerned with though could somebody
tamper the election account itself so in
the history of the United States the
answer is we don't think anybody has
ever done it as far as we can tell there
have been attacks there have been
attacks on voter registration databases
we know that people have tried to tamper
systems but as far as we know the
fail-safes up till now have been good
enough to keep us secure but to no
reason this researcher maybe we were
just kind of lucky up till now or maybe
somebody's suppressing things that's the
other possibility but as far as we know
nobody's ever you know being able to
change the election results the u.s.
this is not the way it is worldwide
there was a book written about ten years
after the fact about how somebody
cyberattack
you know when Nelson Mandela with an ANC
we're trying to come into power 94 there
was a cyber attack to try to keep them
out of power
we know the Russians have come after the
Ukrainian elections the Estonian
elections in 2014 they did a DDoS trying
to discredit the Ukrainian election
results Estonia does their voting online
which is really a bad idea for a number
of other reasons but they you know
that's yeah they've been hacked
no continuously and then the 22
tene Indian elections I was reading
about that this is just in the news like
a couple of weeks ago basically they
were saying that hackers manipulated
those results that they got some of the
some of the candidates running for
office to pay up to like a million
dollars u.s. to buy into this system
where they would paste these microchips
under the voting machines and then sit
out in the parking lot and wirelessly
control them now get to thinking about
that I don't know what kind of chip can
do that per se pasting it and in fact
when they asked the hackers to do like a
proof of concept they were never able to
like show this thing in action so they
also made all these claims like they
were saying people were killed to cover
up the story there's big IT firms
involved in the scam and all this but
none of those claims were ever proven at
least according to the Indian Election
Commission all right so the things we're
going to talk about in particular are
places that an attacker could tamper an
election to change the results and then
so chaos or distrust in the system
that's in registering voters
provisioning the voting systems the
voting collection of votes themselves
counting the votes and then reporting of
the results those are all the places
along the way and I just want to put
this up here first anybody familiar with
this anybody seen this snippet of code
before no oh really man I thought I
thought we'd have like a lot of people
like into this this is this is good old
favorite piece of code JIRA's warming up
the stack the the point of this piece of
code is if you look at it closely if I
don't know anybody you know if you're
you do software development or if you
know about anything about software
security but you can see there's a
variable called cookie and there's no
one it's a character buffer 80 buffer
character just do we ever input the
value of cookie here no we print out
what the value of cookie is and we print
out the buff we get see this gets the
string called buff but then it is
comparing this value call cookie and if
it's equal to some value then you win
but we never got the value in so that
means
you have to manipulate the input to this
program to overwrite the value of bluff
with 80 characters and then it's
little-endian so you have to actually
print the hex value backwards and then
push all that into stack to get to the
point where you execute this line of
code you win and if you go on github or
places like that people have done
walkthroughs of this where they solve it
in about 7 or 8 different ways this is
just one way I've shown you here the
bottom line is as long as I get to you
win then you win in the same way here if
I can tamper the system at anywhere
along the way to show the wrong value
then I win
is the attacker alright so the first
threat vector is the registration sites
what are those things there it's really
a web front-end and database back in
right that's what a lot of it is and so
the threat there is exploiting you know
poorly configured database or being able
to do a sequel injection cross-site
scripting attack whatever no bypassing
authentication so that I can get into
the backend database and read it or
manipulate it well a couple years ago
this hacker David Levin who was a pen
tester I don't remember the name is
company I couldn't find their website
anymore couldn't find him on LinkedIn I
don't think he's really around anymore
but at the time he decided he would go
do a pen test on the Lee County
Elections Office website and he used
javi as anybody ever use that sequel
injection tool pretty powerful yep tool
and he was able to access all the user
ideas and passwords of everybody in the
office and he stopped just short of
getting to voter data in like Social
Security numbers he could have gotten
there he said but he stopped the issue
is he didn't offer hey did not have
authorization to do his pen test he was
not brought in by Lee County and so when
he posted his YouTube video about it and
he told the he told the person who was
running for supervisor elections against
the incumbent about it it kind of caused
kind of a nightmare so the correct thing
to do
for this you know vector mitigation is
you know obviously webapp contesting by
having an authorized third party I asked
yeah but they're kind of tight about who
does this stuff I asked the deputy
supervisor elections in Pinellas hey can
we be your pen testing team and she's
like we already have a team is an
internal team external team both okay
all can I talk to your internal folks
just to ask it now who is your external
team can't tell you really is a public
organization so when's your RFP coming
out don't know so like there they were
very tight-lipped about it who wouldn't
tell me anything but it you know one
would hope if they're doing things in
accordance with best practices are going
to be doing a static level code analysis
that's where you're you know search tree
looking for terms that would lead to
indicators of you know unsafe code that
could be exploited and you're doing
dynamic analysis which is actually
interfacing with the running app fuzz
testing it using proxies things like
that to see if you can break it and make
it do something that's not supposed to
do the other thing you want to do is run
routine checks of your database to make
sure nobody's tampering the integrity of
the of the voter registration data and
if something does happen you know
reporting up the chain now I can tell
you the DoD has has laws in place now
the D for what's called defense Federal
Acquisition regulation supplement says
if you have an incident even on
unclassified data but if it's sensitive
data fo you owe PII
export control data you've got to report
that up the chain and there's a specific
way you do that there's no equivalent
for election hacking so you have all
this dispersed elections are taking
place they're not centrally governed by
one Authority they're all pushed out to
the counties of states and so there's no
uniform way that you have to accomplish
security and there's no uniform way that
you have to report incidents of the gene
that's a big issue
the second threat vector is when the
machines are provisioned now this is fun
if you go to DEFCON voting village they
always have a lot of fun with this they
this year I saw them the Diebold TSX
ones they were able to upload like a
custom version of Linux and get it to
play like whatever music and videos they
wanted to this there's three types of
machines we're talking about here you've
got the pull books which are you used to
be you show your ID you sign in and that
that's that's when you're allowed you
know prove you're allowed to vote here
then you've got the actual tabulation
system that's one where you fill out the
thing and put it in and scans it and
then you also have the counting machines
that's the ones that count the number of
votes okay so they've hacked all these
basically the the polling machine the
Diebold one they found out root password
was password alright the a key vote
counting machine they figured out if you
can give me 30 seconds access to that
with the jtag connector in my laptop you
know i can hack in the thing drop in its
shell and you know have admin rights
over the thing so the issue is these
voting machine makers are very close
you know close-lipped tight-lipped they
don't talk about how they're doing
things they don't invite peer review
from the outside there are some
standards in place that say they have to
go through independent testing labs but
i've seen like a couple of there's only
five labs in the country that do and
even vote machine testing and one of
them got dropped off because they
weren't doing it right another one i
think got drops and they there's only
three active ones now the issue here is
you know we've got to do way with this
security through obscurity that's not
that's a losing proposition right think
about advanced encryption standard right
that's when we wanted to have a new
encryption standard we put up a contest
ask for people to put in their candidate
algorithm and then everybody period
banged on it you know once we found it
was secure that became the standard I
would like to see the same thing with
voting machines right not telling people
how you're doing it
may or may not be doing it the right way
not making any of these results
available for anybody to see or inspect
we don't know if you're doing it the
right way or not one of the issues is
ESS which is election systems of
software that's the maker of the one
that we use here in Pinellas Pinellas in
Hillsborough counties it's also the most
widely one used one around they didn't
even have a/c so until last year they
didn't have a security officer some of
these companies weren't using two-factor
authentication for email so that you can
imagine they could easily fished and
then use that as a entry point and pivot
into the rest of the organization and
then what are you doing you can drop
malware and you can there's all kinds of
things you can do so as a company we
always say all right you got to have the
governance in place you gotta have the
leadership
it starts with security policy having a
plan a formalized program you have to
have continuous monitoring to make sure
nobody's in changing the integrity of
your organization environment you have
to catch continuous assessments and
tests and then fix stuff after you find
it remediate you know patching process
in place Incident Response and then you
get a trainer users not to be victims to
to fishing in social engineering if you
don't have those things the basic basics
in place your whole organization could
be at risk
alright the next threat vector and this
is the one where we had fun you know
walking around inside the supervisor
elections headquarters is looking at
these these voting systems themselves so
there are still places in the US and in
fact in this county where we're using
paperless tre touchscreen voting
machines the reason those things are so
bad is they don't have a paper trail
right it's an electronic vote so you
imagine if somebody could hack into that
system they could change your vote you
wouldn't know it and then there's no
paper trail saying otherwise we'd still
use those to some extent for
accessibility so handicapped and
disabled voters still use a DRA a type
system everybody else uses for early
voting and for day of voting we use
something called the DES 200 which is a
system which is an optical scanner
system
des 200 in that type of system basically
fill in a little bubble you send it
through the thing and it counts it and
then like I said you have a paper
receipt so if something should go wrong
at least we can go back to the real
paper and compare it versus what the
computer reported so I was thinking
about this poking around in the back yes
200 systems what are they're called
there's a little side panel that has
like a little barrel lock on it I was
like okay if I approach that thing with
some lock-picking tools I could take
that thing off lickety-split probably
and there's different things that
they're the USBs can either be used to
pull data out of the system
in terms of tally results they're also
used for flashing new firmware so if you
knew exactly how the thing worked and
again you're not gonna find a user
manual probably well you may be able to
phone a user manual out there you're not
gonna find like a tech spec that tells
you the protocols but you probably
figured out though
then I you know maybe I'd be able to
tamper it but what are the
countermeasures to that well
theoretically they never leave these
systems alone
poll workers are trained to watch this
somebody's trying to tamper the system
and you know reported the authorities if
you tampered that system you're only
gonna do that one system you're not
gonna affect the entire election right
so you might be able to see him for some
votes for one system but we always have
the paper ballots is back up so we you
know can if we find some
statistical anomaly we can go back and
check and do a recount what about so
they're telling us these things connect
wirelessly back to the mothership so I
was like woah woah woah 802 11 like no
no doesn't go to access point here it's
a broadband modem really that's
interesting
and that's you heard me on the thing hey
is that encrypted and he's like oh yeah
layers and layers of encryption I don't
know so I have to believe him you know I
couldn't set up a Pecos sure I think
make the thing connect and then you know
obviously I didn't have authorization to
do that or the time to do it but I would
like to know more
so theoretically it is a communication
that goes back and by the way what's the
connect back for it's only for first
night reporting so the official ballot
is not from that that's only for
reporting early results that's not the
official one anyway now having said all
this
the guys from Princeton go to the polls
early every year and they always find
unattended voting machines at the
precinct that they could walk right up
to and tamper they have fun with this
you know especially in Florida we have
poll workers who may not be technically
savvy now I'll say my my dad you know
he's four years engineer at Honeywell he
sets up ozone networks he he told me
things I had to do to set up
location-based services on my phone so
like he's you know accepted from this
but I would say most 80 year olds or
plus probably don't know what to look
for in terms of people trying to tamper
these systems and most young people
probably don't want to be port workers
so that could be an issue one other
thing I'll mention so Pinellas and
Hillsborough use what's called auto mark
which means you fill out the little
ballot you slip it through the thing it
counts it through an optical scanner and
then you're done these other counties
pulk Pasco and Mayo T and this I pull
this right off the Manatee website where
they show you this use something called
Express vote okay this is a weird system
I don't even know why it does why they
have is you take like a blank sheet you
put it in the thing you tap your choices
on the thing it prints them out onto the
paper then you have a button it says
either yeah I trust its system to vote
for me you know to have put the right
things on the air or not or I want to
check it boom so if you hit the one
you hit the button that says I don't you
know I'm in a hurry I don't have time to
check this you're like it's like the
permission to cheat button in my opinion
but if you you know if you pop it out so
here you could think of an attack right
the attack would only take place to
manipulate the vote if the person says
I'm not gonna check if they say I am
gonna check oh yeah very accurate every
time yep just that's exactly what I put
in there and then you have to put the
thing back in again so it slows down
voting I don't know why you would have
that versus just having somebody scratch
anything the next threat vector is
counting votes so think about this
you're either intentionally or
unintentionally misreporting the outcome
the solution of course is auditing so if
the election is very close you're gonna
have a recount if sometimes they'll even
do statistical analysis like if this if
this County went you know 100% Democrat
last time and now it's voting Republican
that's kind of odd we're gonna you know
we're good that's gonna trigger a
recount or if we show under votes under
vote means you have fewer votes for
candidate then you have ballots over
vote means you have more or like
somebody actually bubbled in two things
for one one choice either those are
gonna trigger revote or not rebut a
recount the thing is how that is spelled
out differs from States to State County
to County throughout the United States
we already know that 25 plus states
don't have adequate sampling in place so
assistive sophisticated attack could
maybe trick the system and still get
past some tampering without it being
noticed by these these sampling measures
so they've come up with new thing called
r-la a risk limiting audit they're
already doing this in colorado they're
sampling it or they're trying to do it
in Virginia California we definitely
want to bring this here to Florida
basically says regardless of some if
something triggers a recount or not I'm
gonna do a human inspection of a random
sample of every ballot just to make sure
it's consistent with what the computer
says
that seems like common sense doesn't it
but we're not doing it in the DEFCON
voting village every year that they have
a vote and of course you know you can
imagine what would happen if we reported
the wrong results right this threat
vector of reporting results you know
that's gonna so distrust the foundation
of our society I mean back in the 40s
there was that whole Dewey defeats
Truman thing I don't know if that really
that was wrong and in the paper had to
eat crow for reporting that but I don't
know if it's so distrust but if the
official election results on the state
of Florida website say you know Gilliam
won but it was really to Santos or
vice-versa
that could cause a lot of chaos right
whatever year they they do a vote there
and and of course they're able to tamper
the results this year they had George
Washington going up against Benedict
Arnold
those who got a number of votes correct
votes but of course the dark tangent
Jeff Moss actually won the election
through tampering I know if you saw this
story but they they're like oh this kid
hacked into the state of Florida
elections website in ten minutes not
exactly it's a little bit of hype let me
tell you what happened so DEFCON has
just like we have a kid CTF here it
besides Tampa they have roots asylum
they brought them over the voting
village and had them hack into some fake
sites that were set up just like the
state of Florida election results site
they were set up to have you know
cross-site scripting SQL injection
vulnerabilities and so forth they taught
the kids how to do sequel injection and
this kid was able to land an exploit in
ten minutes
so that made worldwide news oh you know
these are these sites these election
sites are terrible
well the National Association of
secretaries of state not too happy about
that they're like you know we've support
what you're doing here to have safer
voting but we're concerned that creating
mock election office networks and voter
registration databases for participants
to defend and/or hack is unrealistic so
what's the threat mitigation for
reporting
you know good thing is like I said
earlier those first night results aren't
official and the risk limiting audits
are gonna kick in which is gonna trigger
recounts but what can somebody tell me
why
first night reporting is so dangerous or
so significant like especially here on
the East Coast that's right so think of
this say you know Trump was you know
winning the whole East Coast and had
looked like enough electoral votes to
win the whole presidency by the time I
got out to the West Coast California
Seattle whatever people were like I'm
gonna show up I don't even care but it
could have been manipulated to look like
it was a win when it really wasn't and
that could change the whole outcome of
the election that's why that stuff's
still important just as we said before
what's the best best practice for that
type of thing static and dynamic
analysis good web design Quality
Assurance make sure you got the wasp top
ten covered for you know cross-site
scripting cross-site request forgeries
authentication and so forth all right so
to wrap it all up you know just as with
many it's all systems just got to be
layers of security you can't depend on
one thing we saw there's so many
different ways different places of cross
the spectrum it's a complex problem
right it's a it's a whole big attack
surface of many different points I think
with Pinellas and Hillsborough
at least we are using best practices
regarding voting and counting we're
doing the right things here I can't tell
you if we're doing the right things
around the registering provisioning and
reporting because I don't have I didn't
have any access to that yeah I asked
about you know web security best
practices they wouldn't tell me we
didn't get into I wasn't allowed to see
the software being provisioned I don't
see I don't know what their development
environment looks like so there's things
I couldn't report on and of course we
didn't get into you know all this
nonsense beeps County and Broward County
when they have these missing provisional
ballots and ballots that showed up in
people's trunks of cars and ballots that
showed up on playgrounds yeah we didn't
get into any of that so that's yet
another thing
but as far as I can tell at least with
regard to the voting accounting or
pinellas in Hillsboro we're going to
write things alright question time again
I learned a lot about doing this it's
like a you know it's an onion layers and
layers and layers if I had you know if I
to do this full-time I would love to get
some of the systems and I don't think
it's very easy to get the systems and uh
Princeton they were able to do it like
back in the early 2000 a bang get some
of these things in your lab but I don't
you know they're really tight about that
now they don't let those systems get out
into the public so anybody have a
question yes mobile app voting horrific
any kind of any type of digital voting
in it I can even get into that online
voting no way no way because it's so
easy to manipulate systems right there's
no such thing as a hundred percent
secure system if you don't have a paper
trail in place you're gonna be at risk
and we don't have a good alternative for
that in the future maybe we'll see
here's the only thing I might be able to
support in the future so in the DoD to
have something called a CAC Common
Access Card if you went in and presented
all your credentials and hats maybe some
biometric information click on image on
the chip on that card and that's
encrypted and you have like a you know a
private key you know you know public key
certificate and then that is you know
physically used to do the voting maybe
maybe
okay well sniffs no need to use that
that was it
I wouldn't I still don't use Dylan it's
not good enough all right so I thought
huh that's the only like way I would go
that even that route but I still I still
nervous about that
somebody said there's something funny
the other day that he's like you know we
all do our taxes on TurboTax right and
that's like you know we trust them to
hold all our money and like you know
that's the biggest tax thing connected
to the government and all that so it's
like what are they doing right and do
you trust them well it's a good point
it's a fair point but I just don't I
just don't trust that you know audit
trails are too easy to manipulate and
change it's too easy for people and so I
would much rather have something that
has a human fat you know layers of human
factors now that's not even foolproof as
you recall from the last election Rick
Scott sued some of these counties for
not having enough people present at the
recount commensurate with what the law
required so even even the the human
factor of the manual recount can be
messed up right there's all these things
any other questions question over here
[Music]
so again as hasn't I haven't heard over
of and I had it hasn't been proven that
the Russians actually tried to
manipulate tallies tally counts as I
said they're big their big thing was
sowing discord amongst us by
manipulating public perception through
social media in fake news and stuff like
that see if we're all at each other's
throats
that's that affects our democracy and
they win right that weakens America that
strengthens them now following on to
that here's a question where was it
where the Chinese and all this keep them
quiet they're stealing intellectual
property right okay
they realize they have so much invested
in the US like they don't want to see us
crumble because they're gonna lose a lot
of money okay
Russia stands to benefit if we're weaker
China actually stands to lose if we're
weaker because they lose a lot of their
investment that they have here so
they're and now having said that you
know that has not stopped them from
going after companies and stealing
intellectual property but as far as we
can tell they're kind of hands off of
our elections questions back
isn't that incredible yeah that's the
this is a great point some of these guys
from who are doing the research they're
saying the safest way to report these is
just like they did 200 years ago with
the town crier have all the people
together at the pole count the thing
together and say here's the result and
write it down everybody has a copy right
and everybody's using pencil and paper
that you can't get any more secure than
that way than having a whole room of
people knowing what that is versus
having a computer account something
which the computer can be manipulated
that's what this whole conference is
about unless unless they can come up
with a technology that's that is
provably secure so I was having a
discussion with people earlier about
provably secure systems on paper they
look great they're theoretically great
but any system has to be implemented by
a human and design and implemented by
human and operated by human that's where
mistakes can happen questionnaire here
how much they were doing what no that's
an optional feature so some of the es
200s have a landline modem some have a
broadband modem but that's actually an
optional feature that not all of the
precincts used not all the counties use
so we use it I guess they can get some
early numbers for reporting purposes I'm
guaranteed Broward County doesn't use it
so we don't get numbers from them to
like a week later all right thanks very
much Cheers