good afternoon everybody it's time for
our next speaker group we have Michael
music and Kevin Kaminski the title of
their presentation is logging pitfalls
and how to abuse them Kevin Kaminski has
been working at R'lyeh quest for four
years currently as the threat management
R&D lead he currently works researching
the latest threat behaviors and tools in
the wild how they can be detected with
enterprise technologies and how the logs
can be correlated in siem solution to
provide actionable intelligence
Michael music is a USF computer science
graduate and currently works on R'lyeh
quest threat management team he is
currently researching automated threat
emulation red teaming and how red teams
can enhance an organization's security
their subject you cannot defend what you
cannot see a lack of proper logging from
endpoints servers and security
appliances is a widespread issue for
companies in every industry we will
outline the most common logging gaps
mistakes and miss configurations that
we've seen and how an attacker can abuse
them
this can include identifying what
exactly the blue team will not see and
how knowledge of the shortcomings can
allow attackers to evade the blue team
or generally be more lazy and
comfortable in their attack we will also
offer insight on how to solve these
problems air these common problems from
a high level give a warm besides 2019
welcome to Michael music and Kevin
Kaminski
[Applause]
all right everyone so you next make this
video and show up so that's cool it
seems like very relevant topic so what
we're talking about is logging pitfalls
and when we talk about logging we're
talking about taking different devices
in a network and the forwarding of those
locks is some kind of centralized
logging solution so we're gonna show a
good ski and I'd like this for a while
but you guys hear me now oh you got that
great radio voice intro but I'm like
music I went to USF computer science
didn't argue for about a little over two
years now so it's been a good time I've
gone three different a few different
roles and now generally red team and
threat management so
so the origins of this talking they work
never like this work a lot of different
companies and we mainly work with those
Cynthia oh geez
so it's all about sending the logs to it
essentially by morning it's really you
know what's pretty critical for you know
modern Street posture these days it used
to be
you gotta log into every single device
you check out a logger has to get
something yet hugging your firewall that
your AV look at the GUI on that stuff so
the next generation of that is putting
it all into one place and sim or data
link or something like that so how many
people work with those technologies see
the sims are logging yeah there we go
yes it's getting really common and so
we're finding that there's a lot of
these common issues that people have
been experiencing which is reducing
their visibility so you guys might not
like to hear what's going on but we're
gonna kind of be enough to show you all
the different things that we found
tailors and gaps and so this really
began with you know working with
companies and they'd undergo you know
pen tests or experience some internal
breach exhibition havior and you know
the next question is once it happens
it's only gonna find it we can research
it look at the logs and you go on the
simony and you plug in the IPS and
nothing comes back well this guy's in
there doing these things I don't have
visibility I have all these tools what
am I supposed to be doing about this and
we've seen companies are starting to and
have realized this is a
a current issue I'm starting to test
content the alerts that are in these
platforms and so they're trying to test
the same content is off the alerts and
they're also finding that it I've
written MF skin I wouldn't went on to a
box written and that's getting the whole
network nothing shows though so all
you're scanning alerts now are useless
and so this is well this talks about
suppressing those visited areas so
that's the origin and I don't mind me
jumping over it something heaven here
throughout the talk but this will be the
introduction so most organizations that
we talk to you believe they're they have
hundreds invisibility that Network 100%
disability of Everson one point they
know who's running one command they know
you know where the powers being probably
they think they see it all and if you're
in a very large environment it may seem
that way simply due to the sheer number
of hosts that you are logging but
there's there's always something missing
and that's the point if you hear so
warning if you have a sim and you really
want to sleep well tonight
do not continue listening so there's our
cheesy disclaimer in reality there's
massive common gaps logging back
completely unreported for a variety of
reasons a variety of logging and logging
level problems that we're gonna touch on
here but and honestly it affects every
organization we've we see the spectrum
of people who are kind of like they just
kind of sim they're asking us how to any
great things and we've seen people who
had us in for a long time and part this
is not you know a new ballgame for them
you know they've been around the block
in you know there's always something
so this is a quote actually I won't we
can't need to individually this game
from because he didn't want us to and he
use a little bit different language in
this but he basically said the only
people who know what they're logging
know they're logging nothing and that's
probably the truth so this is your
logging level exit there y'all you're
logging coverage expectation it's
beautiful
you know locket cheese here it looks
great from the outside but in reality
and reality there's a lot of holes in it
so what a great metaphor you sent in
your environment right
every laughing he knows true
so Russell Crowe disclaimer you know
you're looking at these issues as we go
through and you're like that looks
really familiar this is so common that
you know this everyone it affects
everyone so it's all hottest and I'm so
we're talking you have a sin you know
that's a really good start you're gonna
get on that correlation but there are
few questions that we're all each live
source that you're integrating that you
really should be asking on frequent
basis
one is your lecturers deployed widely
enough tax recovery from our net so
locate in their cases where you might be
covering this network or this data
center but villain doesn't have the same
time to cover so you gotta think is this
actually deployed everywhere these are
like source even configure properly to
detect the threat so there's multiple
from all levels that give you different
information and are you enabling the
right ones that are gonna tell you when
these attacks are occurring and then
Israel experts even capable of detecting
the strap so there's lots of different
very building quality lock source and
technologies and there's some ways the
attackers can bypass some not others so
you got to be always thinking about how
can attackers bypass this nice upgrade
my solutions on that
and that we put an emphasis on
frequently because you know your
environments are always changing there's
a view service being stood up taking
down all the time
company might make something require
some other companies or spin up remote
offices and there's always no flux in
your environment so you have to keep
constantly addressing how redeploying
this log sources right spots are
figuring them over standing on all the
time
so we're looking at the first one that
we come to is an incomplete Luxor's
coverage I was and you know what this
ruling tails is relaxers actually placed
everywhere that it should be to make
sure that you're covering every party
ever because really with this will have
you watched on the technology but it's
not in the right spots then it basically
doesn't matter logs are pretty much
useless is you're not getting them
covering that have an attack so or we'll
see this a lot is you know missing
firewalls I guess most the time you know
it could be at remote offices maybe you
get there's no company your stamps
offices traffic just not read through
the firewall they're just I open
definitely for internal segments if it
even exists at all so you know that
you're not gonna see any of that
internal standing if teenagers if you
don't have a firewall it especially I
guess they see that too much usually
everyone usually gets the edge but you
know it's those remote pieces and
that's very soft antivirus for you many
kind of easier solutions a black card
strike
are they deployed on every server you
know some some companies know you might
have like you know 70 80 % of servers
but there's obviously there's always a
few that don't get caught it was that
even even already anywhere some people
don't even know how many servers they
have or how many had a TV or are you
supposed to and then there's just you
know a complete lack of certain straight
alliances so if you don't have IDs or
it's gonna be a hot seat that's a huge
lie discovery staff that needs to get a
little about your the Cylons attacks it
there's plenty of your homeland source
stuff out there I guess it's true it's
there and it's enclosed there so just
lots of different solutions on them as
well
so for each problem that we identify
here which I believe we have four we're
going to talk about the abuses and what
this kind of means is it's kind of two
sizes as a blue Timur what are you not
going to see what kind of attacks we
probably get in this because room is
because of this particular problem and
if you're a red teamer upin tests you
know you kind of on the opposite side
this should just give you a little peace
of mind and insight into what some of
the environments received to make look
like in some problems in fine so maybe
it can make you a little lazier I mean
the goal is to be silent but you know
you can at least recipes with some of
these problems so so abuses of this is
being correct log source placement so
I'm gonna go through all of these and
let's see so attacker can perform a ton
of different attacks without fear of
detection or prevention so internal an
inbound scans so inbound scanning is
kind of something that alerting on it
you'll see there's internal scans when
it comes to flat networks and people who
are either missing send up an internal
firewall or network segmentation
altogether they said we can't see even
the noisiest internal in maps and that's
I feel like you know your network if you
have to if you get in with a firewall if
you have like you catch your your flow
data from firewalls you witness see two
beacons and communications so there's a
lot of different ways of CT works but if
you're flat-out missing like a web proxy
or your edge firewall for some reason or
an internal firewall there's a good
change your C twos
you're not gonna see any C two
interesting ideas etc so if you're an
attacker I mean people are really
focusing on finding ways to obfuscate
their traffic you know was using Empire
klaustreich or some type of homebrew mc2
posting exploit framework in reality if
you're dealing with an advanced network
they might catch you if you're using
something custom probably not but for
some of these people that are quite
frankly just missing some common
security appliances it's not a huge
worry
exfiltration of data so I mean if a
company doesn't even have a you know web
box you set up in their or their web
properties matching the right field
hockey be able to even post request if
you're doing some simple HD OSX bill
something like that say you can as a
retinue in less easy knowing that
there's a good chance that you know
this device easily isn't probably not
going to get in malware hacking tools
and when I say hacking tools I'm kind of
prefer you like you know well-known
hacking scripts and partial scripts for
example and generally suspicious process
behavior so if you're you do not have
your log sources and incorrectly placed
or your locks were just missing in
general you're gonna miss a lot of this
stuff so it's not an omen to see you
know for example a V just flat-out not
being available on a box so they can't
get a visibility drop a piece of our
doesn't have to be sophisticated
so some of the fixes that everything
enough for some of these problems so
you'll have firewalls and certain
certain locations and it was try to make
sure that those IDs or firewall can also
regional segmentation equally firewalls
there you have internal segmentation I
think getting the flow logs from the
switch this was his reply insists and
that's gonna give you really good
disability you want to track
actually we were eighty is getting
installed and look at the note pushed
counts in consoles or in the sand just
look at all the devices and just try to
compare that what's the environment just
constantly cycling over that process
that needs treatment
everything's it's had everything needs
and you know when you're provisioning
this new systems will now ask lots of
servers and that in the process to get
that installed by default not going
happy back in front down where you have
all these gaps and then here's
interpersonal centers as long as that
network just make sure that you so love
to complicate in there but really put
your lectures in the right spot but you
have to number two so you have the
technologies that are in the right spot
well they're not sending too soon you
see this a lot you you'll have pulling
out new firewall students in my office
and they'll just forget just send it
already know it's sending some along I
can address and move did it's just not
getting there so really that's also just
kind of a beast of potential in the box
which you're not getting it Advent
coverage so it may still be walking it
basically be doing those activities but
you're not gonna see any of that we
receive about stuff so your correlation
is not gonna be completely sensible if
you're not getting those logs in there
and then your recent analysis
[Music]
so some example so critical assets
pretty much seen it all the main
controllers not logging that's a whole
section in your domain we just have all
kinds of their main have a little
escalation there's agents that you're
just missing in your client that's just
education and firewalls IDs companies
that must have no hundreds of our walls
and it's no hard to keep track of
everything that's logging one net sales
so it's something that you see a lot of
virtual instruction you know not the
same this was Isis so you might have a
really good little image or your
workstations and desktops but you know
what about your video is you've seen it
before where sometimes you guys make
sure that those also sometimes not
forwarding it to the logging platform is
intentional because the logging platform
can't support that ox it's very high
volume typically will seek DNS not too
many people log DNS and also with
firewalls you have all that firewall
trapping this afternoon on the system so
that's another movie Kevin policy
all right so back to the abuses here so
these are some of the attacks that can
happen and just some of the things that
we see I might even tell incredible
examples we've seen in the wild so like
just you say for example your DC isn't
logging which I hope all of your DC's
are logging no matter the size of your
organization is pretty critical but lo
and behold we've seen plenty of
instances where any new tools are not
long as crazy as that is in that case
you know you're gonna be missing a lot
of windows brute-force attacks it's
unlikely that you're logging at the
windows host level and kudos to you if
you are and if you're flat-out missing a
few DCs and there's like some type of
brute-force activity going on in that
domain
you're probably gonna miss it other
things like just general domain
enumeration techniques for example we're
using bloodhound
you're gonna flat-out miss that you sees
different flute privileged escalation
methods I mean if you're not logging pcs
and somebody happens to get you know d8
hops in that box and you know there's
some is Khalif or religious or they
somehow start dumping something I mean
if you're not blowing that AC this
pretty it's pretty bad Linux activity
it's actually a pretty interesting one I
mean there's a lot of value in you know
the different Linux servers that exist
out there a lot of different appliances
it's not where that Robin whatever what
we commonly see is that people kind of
take their Linux boxes lightly and don't
lock them as well as they they would or
don't have the expected long levels they
wouldn't home what windows box so on
there DC's they're like hey you know we
can see we see whenever scheduled tasks
is created we see whatever user logs on
we see whenever you know our education
modified we can see the individual
PowerShell commands running but they
can't see a single command being brought
some their critical thinking servers
they're just flat out it's not that
logging technically isn't there because
Linux does have some logging by default
although there's ways to create that I
think we'll talk about that whether it's
not forwarding loss they just never saw
the value they never considered it so
you're gonna miss all kinds of stuff
there a little pseudo account
compromises you know hash something
you've never persistence techniques and
then personal infrastructure
attack is targeting for effect they can
just be a bit more mobile more noisy so
we've seen instances where for example
like the Hobbesian points that
enrolling on Krim user the image is a
lot different than like the VDI
infrastructure that remote employees or
contractors would be working with for
example like say you pop an accountant
that's like a remote contractors in half
yeah they can basically spin up a VDI
get writing for Hamburg well it's quite
likely that that BGI is not logging into
the platform like a normally in fluently
in that case has an attacker I mean you
can be pretty noisy in a way that's just
food for thought
in DNS speaking exfiltration become a
much bigger option whenever just
different things aren't you know
forwarding this in for example DNS logs
there is a good chance that DNS being
logged and if it's being logged it might
they might not even have any type of
learning on it
so a that makes it so getting caught you
know speaking English you know most much
less likely and be makes it so even if
they are elongated the analysis having
this deep analysis my onion exists if
they're not belonging so and so the fix
let's go through some of these fixes so
audit your inventory or your CMDB and
compared with the law with the console
logging devices in the sims so this is
something we always do with you know the
organization's we deal with we say hey
so we we're gonna go in your sim we're
basically gonna look her log source type
we're gonna look at all the different
host reporting and we're gonna basically
get a unique kind of all the different
host names hype easy reporting and what
you guys need to do is you need to take
this data and map it to you know
whatever your asset inventory is and
compare the two because they need to be
pretty darn identical adllaw
configuration and advice provisioning
process especially pointing toward some
type of central log aggregation server
like a syslog server or I think we have
down here use left just make that part
of your standard gold image for your
your endpoints for your Linux servers
for your Windows servers you know I'm
just make it make make a standard and
make sure it's logging point o host that
you know you can I mean for high volume
logs filter out relevant event types so
if you're scared of logging
you know if different firewall logs or
you know different types of data D in
this data or something so you guys to
high volume it's gonna put you over that
EPS threshold or something just try to
see if you can trim it down a bit so you
can at least get some visibility in
there for your analyst in your coalition
and for Linux the point updates to slot
confidence on all servers with your
automation tool so that is pretty much
tying in with a headlock configuration
device really value your Linux servers
don't just I mean the end point is kind
of the new perimeter but you know
alright so I have everything log to the
same person it's just like aggregators
then you have our birthday publishes you
properly configured logging levels so a
lot of times the default config zombies
devices look at an IP address
it's analogues to the sim a lot of times
that's not the right blog know that you
want you might just be logging system
level and garbage that's not anything
related to security sometimes it's
really delicate exec enough to do to get
the right invest anymore I mean if you
don't have the right logging levels
basically you're not using the locks
lose to the fullest potential again it's
doing actions so see this ton with
especially Windows so Windows as you
have there's tons of different logging
options in there there's a lot of
different event IDs which ones are you
supposed to lock might default a lot of
people lock their to make me full of
odds
that's marina on the a lot of people
don't really take the extra step to
workstations server by default you turn
it on it's got all the object access it
blows up there's a lot of you know
kind of not really relevant information
that allows back to home slut people's
turn it off but there's a lot of low low
volume event IDs in there that you can
configure like very specific registry
keys scheduled tasks that you can log on
a lot more workstations or host and
that's going to catch a lot of different
attacker persistent activity and then
there's also process creations if you
log into that event there's a separate
config for command line which gives you
the whole whole you know commands the
parameters that they're actually running
otherwise without that you just get
summary power stuff we do want to know
what's there so that's a big yet kind of
really nice analysis there
powershell selectable don't log
powershell or if they do they rely on
power something's actually it's with you
our tool or with the process creation in
this but those aren't going to give you
the visibility into what's actually
going on in some powershell scripts
you're gonna get that personal training
may be that but without the native power
saw logging in windows you're not gonna
see what different commands what
functions are running that's the input
output a lot of linux activity so linux
will login authentication saloons but
you're not seeing the command-line
mystery it's an execution juice is false
and you're not seeing any kind of file
body intentions so and everyone's like
the unix logically are very standard so
it's not and web proxies so it's not
really long level but it's something
that's you're not gonna get that
visibility into that web traffic that
will allow you to detect you know
different actually
and or EDR as well a lot of easier to
use here we come with all these
different signatures like carbon black
the CrowdStrike you know maybe they have
like a hundred signatures well the
regular antivirus they have the
thousands tens of thousands of
signatures so if you are just more like
behavioral-based with different
processes but your the problem is that
still there's still so much attackers
can do that we found that a lot of the
EDR tools you know there's really big
gaps in the signature base and it kind
of relies on you just like carbon blacks
like make a lot of those signatures for
your own environment and it can be kind
of difficult to keep up with that
especially all the AV signatures cool so
more easier so attackers can compromise
your Windows and Linux host kind of
undetected example you're probably not
gonna see your different you know file
sheer accesses your service installs
things that would be indicative of
pivoting for example PS executives you
probably not gonna see your registry
modifications unless you have your
logging specifically configured to look
at key registry keys something we
typically give you know you know clients
of ours an organization you work with we
basically and in this massive list very
easily say hey this is associated with
you know different malicious activity
you guys probably need be looking at
this but that's pretty rare see people
monitoring that step right up to that
and persistence in general I mean if
you're using general Windows persistence
methods like let's just say schedule
tasks or reg key mods or something you
probably not going to see that unless
you have your hosts logged in so and
blue team cannot analyze the suspicious
command-line arguments so it's not
uncommon for some type of in test to
happen or somebody to come to us and say
hey this command was written on this box
do you guys see it and we go and we look
at all their process creations and lo
behold they have it logging they have
their 46 88 so I mean just on but it
wasn't really properly to see the
mainline ordnance so you really can't
see anything other than PowerShell dot
exe is launched
it's not really that useful can use
power known powerful and easy hacking
tools about fear of detection so we kind
of touched on this twice now but if you
don't have your powers on script block
blogging or you'll have somebody TR tool
configured properly to actually after at
the powershell script or even powerful
communities being run you're gonna miss
a lot of pretty simple tech stuff
and see two channels with HTTP
compliance approximate engine so if your
web proxy isn't configured for SSL
decryption you're gonna miss a lot of
the HTTP data that's a use for
correlation you can use for analysis and
when i state militia meeting so say if
I'm using a CQ framework our next
billing data using like post requests or
something you're not gonna be able to
basically monitor I don't notice it hey
is this person posting baseman you know
I personally think you should know
that's happening
basic malware tool that you missed by
eer so this is kind of a odd one so EDR
out-of-the-box I'm not a huge PR I guess
expert but I've done more than enough
testing to notice it balls here the
configuration options that come right at
the office of these tools sometimes
they'll have really really common common
power I even said that's not your office
gated or something's just right in the
box there have been many times where I
have different mediums where I'm testing
payloads or campaigns with all kinds of
a beyond it and then I'll drop that on
EDR box the airlocks won't even flag or
it runs I'm talking simple stuffs that
you have to have your configuration on
the stuff
so um fix for the improperly configured
long ones enable logging for important
system events so scheduled tasks or
installed right Richie mods on one side
my if you have some like that enable
your script block or your module
PowerShell in London so you want to be
able to see the actual power films your
people on that
that's highly valuable enable logging
command-line history llamas the oddity
area so with Linux you can kind of get a
few not necessarily influenced the
actual script that's being run national
occurs in a lot of states group is being
on a Linux box but you can at least see
the system calls that it's making me hot
tea hey enable SSL interception online
Fox's so that's not always something
that can realistically happen but if it
is something that you can do with your
web proxy something you know
computationally with that advice then
it's really valuable for analysis
well so now if you like I got my log
sources the properly placed everywhere
and I'm logging there properly then the
next one is is your lock source even
capable to detect you have some of the
attacks that oversee and in some cases
know-it-alls kind of short which ya know
functionality that certain activities so
you know obviously you're looking at
your signature based IDs AV very easy
for attackers to modify the tools to
bypass those signatures so I mean
they're still very valuable to have just
to custom Depot stuff but it's not gonna
stop everything
I'm sorry fire will still you know do
the header inspection even though it
protocol is running on that traffic even
makes it really easy for tunneling
you're not gonna know so if someone's
running some common ports or not the
next default looks not very detailed
like I said they don't really give you a
lot of details to work where that kind
of just it's out of sentence some of
them don't even tell you what the user
was was actually forming the activities
so it's not it's not very detailed
they're trying to lock - history you can
easily just turn that off or like the
file or something like that so that's
not really great reliable and it's not
really gonna tell you like the Power
Cell just rip off it's not gonna tell
you what actually runs inside you
command so if you open up a text
furlong you type in like a basket basket
all your fans and it's just gonna show
up is like just some script was wrong so
it's not it's not really the most useful
thing you think she just shot a script
like what like I said before EDR process
logs and kid you was actually going on
inside that PowerShell script so it's
not so onto the abuse so what are you
gonna miss just simply didn't lack of
detecting capability so customize custom
pools at my past just signature base
maybe your ideas that one's pretty
self-explanatory the use of non-standard
ports your CG connections are tunnel
over existing earth also this is one
thing that that you know we see pretty
commonly so let's just say you're
blocking outbound connections to
destination port 22 because you don't
want people doing out my dad's age well
the protocol the way firewalls can be
free difficult for you to say alert on
somebody has to or somebody hosting an
FTP server out there and for me
FTP California if you don't have enough
piece for a file or you have to be able
to see that says an attacker that
convenient an excellent method see two
minutes
Linux and PowerShell command execution
it's obscured by running them under the
Ninth Circuit aim so like we kind of
said earlier with oddity EOS where he is
healing your PowerShell logging quite
frankly they're just some limited
there's some limitations in terms of
logging especially just know that and
then PowerShell auto-completed
parameters there's a lot of stuff
looking to PowerShell log in terms of
all the odd things different aliases
that it has commandlets a kind of
autocorrect you common theme that you do
this stuff so you kind of had to be
careful about running your regular
expressions with sort of fix so you got
to invest in behavioral based tools that
real tools or relying detection for time
coaching so ultimately you may have a
tool that for example maybe your
firewall is not protocol aware well
maybe you can try and catch the attacker
that maybe do something further along
the kill chain or maybe you have an e dr
- looking may be doing something else
purchase firewalls the protocol
awareness we kind of touched on that
earlier if you're just missing you know
this security appliance I mean if you
can if your budget allows for a purchase
it if your budget allows for it maybe
upgrade your firewall looking at getting
some of this protocol where
enable oddity to capture letting some
insist all's we touch them that a couple
times now partial script blocker module
ah logging to actually capture the
scripts being run once again this is
something that's almost invaluable for
your analysis especially with how big of
a detect director PowerShell is nowadays
it'll absolutely kill the pin testers
that are using Empire so just keep that
in mind and ensure your PowerShell
detection signatures look for the
correct you know partial matches ensure
that you at least have a couple of maybe
for example maybe bring some obfuscated
PowerShell in your network to test it
just make sure your registers correct
make sure whenever you're writing
signatures in your sim or your yard or
something that all of your regular
expressions are accounting for the
different variations in PowerShell
because it's just flat-out a limitation
capability limitation with the tour
customizability with the tool oh so
talked about a lot of things regards to
logging and the real goal of this talk
is to kind of give a wareness for all
these different you know logging
pitfalls logging mistakes that we've
seen in different companies and really
help benefit everyone to go back to
their organizations and go see if this
is the case there and how to fix it so
we really want to use this as kind of
like a checklist for people to think
about you know when they go back in our
my log sources you know they're feeding
into the sim just fine are they covering
everywhere that you my organization is
you know the ones that are out there
that aren't feeding it you know is
everything feeding in try to get those
counts look up in the sin
compare that with your inventory you're
looking at the logging levels so go take
a look in the loc platform go see what
are the event types that I'm receiving
is just what's supposed to come out of
that log source and then you know
potentially look into upgrading or
modifying some signatures to kind of
compensate for the any kind of detection
gaps so then the real question for you
guys for takeaways how can you
proactively discover that these issues
are going on in your environment so
you're gonna go home you're gonna go
back to your relations and how are you
going to be able to get the organization
to constantly you know evaluate this and
make sure that the logging is giving you
guys good coverage alright so as many of
you individuals might have guessed the
solution is testing testing more tests
and so I'm going to kind of go through
the highlighted
you know what I feel like the testing
protocol should look like what we
suggest and I guess kind of what we
typically see and how houses typically
pose so testing I'm gonna go through
yeah kind of kind of what we think it
should look like but let me tell you
what we typically see how this typically
works is it's not very proactive nobody
tests to see you know how their logging
levels are if things are actually
logging and what all is actually logging
and until opinions and they don't catch
something and sometimes a pin test
happens they catch it fine and they
still don't worry about their logging
levels and that's quite frankly not good
typically something won't trigger
they'll come to us and say hey bite into
this trigger will then tell you hey
wasn't logging
no it wasn't logging they say hey we
need to test it and we're all on board
they then go on there they're let's just
say that's a brute-force rule they go
under their own personal Windows box and
they start spamming logins against the
domain controller it fires and they're
good testings done that's not really how
it should be done what if your other
domain controllers not logging did you
run it in maps can can you even seen in
mass gaming environment you know what
you need to do to develop a good testing
platform to verify this stuff is created
a team of internal testers with an
offensive mindset so find individuals
that are willing to test that are aware
of these types of problems preferably
somebody was some type of same
experience and maybe some type of
offensive experience although that's not
really a necessity and just don't
completely devote them to the mom you
see unless you had the time to but make
sure this is a pretty prime director for
them set up basic infrastructure so your
attack machine should not be your
personal Windows in point you should
probably have some type of dedicated
cally box maybe even a Kali VM on your
local on your local machine but just
spit up some type of offensive Linux
distros somewhere in your environment
and use that as your attacker so you
need to spend up victim hosts I don't
think that your buddy across the halls
when his box is your appropriate victim
post nor your domain controller and the
odds of you getting the credentials
provision for your domain controller to
actually accurately test it's gonna be
pretty low unless you're you know DA's
are gonna let you make scheduled tasks
in your DCs which is very unlikely so
spin up your Windows boxes spit up your
Linux boxes they need to be your gold
standard image and you need to attack
them with an actual dedicated attack
host develop a detailed testing plan
don't just wait until something happens
be proactive get all of the different
use cases you want to test common attack
methods and
through them in a cyclical organized
manner until you know you can at least
confirm one path since we descend words
and take its load don't try and rush it
try to make it as dispersed as possible
so you can test all the different senses
in your environment just take it slow
don't rush it
we typically see people rush it because
it's usually a reactive thing rather
than a product of thing but if you take
proactive it's a little easier to take
it slow so questions
I don't think we've approached that
problem yet but yeah we'll definitely
will we definitely will now
you
yeah well usually see like anywhere from
like 30 90 days like the hot warm
storage off the sim and usually it goes
back like a year like a cold storage on
it kind of depends on your compliance to
loosen some because we store like 710
years just depends of you got the budget
for that
[Music]
no nobody else can hear me oops well
apologies
I'm sure there's very insightful but
ultimately I was saying that if you have
like an EPS limit you're looking at your
like localhost logs what should you look
at logging I would start with your AV I
would start with your er I would then
look at you know critical windows log
scheduled aspirations even look at
system on CV and cut out a lot of the
junk and system on find some like config
that suits your needs and keeps your EPS
low but stills allows you like look at
maybe some different process creations
and you know those types of events like
I would start there yeah I mean we do
see that a lot with customers very
concern whether their licensing couldn't
even store enough so we found there's
actually a lot of different like
unnecessary events that you can filter
out to cut down your EPS so we've seen
you know some people log like VMware
logs and that stuff is super noisy it's
a huge chunk of your EPS and there's you
know specific events that you might not
care about low-level system level
logging for your IDs firewall like
there's it's all out there and it could
be turned on so what we usually do is
we'll do an analysis on the sim we'll
take all the different event names per
log source type and see what's actually
relevant to security what do we actually
need to store and then all the Sims or
on the devices themselves you can
actually filter those out before they
hit your license so that's generally
what we recommend there's usually we can
usually cut it down like 10 to 30% I'm
just getting rid of stuff that's not
security related or not does not need to
be stored in Windows events in
particular like on the workstation
authentications are just going to blow
that up all day but you know targeted
registry key mods like run wants keys
people scheduled making scheduled tasks
different service installations those
types of events you know it's those
aren't gonna be happening every day even
if you've got like thousands of
workstations the EPS on that should be
pretty minimal where you can log those
key event IDs and just drop everything
else so that that should be pretty good
ultimately depends on your environment
though I mean for example we've seen
customers were yeah there
fully capable of logging PowerShell
despite having a lower DPS because
nobody in their environment quite
frankly uses PowerShell we've seen
environments where people there their
environment so laden with engineer