good morning everyone
good morning hey good evening well
morning afternoon oh it's been a long
night here my name is Derek Thomas this
is Laurie Brown we're the coordinators
for B side tape we'd like to welcome you
to the sixth annual b-side Tampa IT
security forum now as we look out I see
a lot of familiar faces and I see a lot
of new faces so for you guys who are new
this is your first time coming give you
a quick nickel tour of the whole entire
event
these lights started 10 years ago in Las
Vegas as an offshoot to some of the
larger cons what they wanted to do is
actually have some type of smaller
conference that allowed users actually
deal and speak directly with the
speakers in mostly large towns you don't
really have that opportunity you're in a
crowd of 3,000 and you may see the
speaker maybe once as they walk through
the crowd and leave so what they do they
form what they call b-side conferences
these are smaller conferences that will
allow that particular ability for you to
actually interact with the speaker then
they franchised it so now we are part of
a family over 250 different b-side
conferences which are happening
everywhere in Europe North America South
America I think they just recently had
one in Moscow and and all over the place
so we're one of the few oldest ones but
we still like our presence here this is
our sixth once around 70 years ago
Laurie came to me and said you know what
let's have a conference it wasn't so
much out of yes we want to learn
something new issues that we're lazy we
didn't feel the need to actually travel
all the way to Las Vegas in California
or New York to go to our conference we
had all this technology and talent in
the Tampa Bay area so we threw together
this conference and we had our first one
at South University which actually went
really well
surprisingly considering we have no idea
what we're doing we were untrained
volunteers so if you want complain
remember you get what you pay for we're
but it actually came out well you guys
came back came back for the second one
third one fifth sixth seventh one and
throughout the years we've got a chance
to see everyone grow and this became a
special nerd prom for us where we can
just see friends that we only know
through email or Twitter accounts and
actually interact with speakers and
trade trade information and talk shop so
thank you all for coming out we
definitely appreciate everyone how many
of you were actually at our first one we
had about 200 people Wow thanks you guys
for being repeat offenders a couple of
new announcements here of changes from
last year all right let's talk myself in
the room this is not Stetson
we love Stetson Stetson was a great
place we had a lot of good times a lot
of good memories a lot of good
experiences some good some bad but a lot
of experience is there but throughout
the years our compass is grown this year
we have we're pushing on with 910 DS for
this event as you see we're still kind
of growing now so we kind of had to
outgrow we outgrew Stetson we had to
move it here to a bigger facility even
though it is bigger we still try to keep
everything low as possible so you want
to see all the flash pyrotechnics and
laser license in most cons because we
charge as much as little as possible so
that you guys can come in at in this we
are 500 registered 501 C not-for-profit
so we don't do this for money
even though yes I need to pay off my
student loan we do it for fun so we hope
you enjoyed next talk about lunches when
we had a Stetson we had four different
food trucks because there really was
nothing close body eat but since we
moved here we decided to opt out for
some of the food trucks because we have
a restaurant here and a bar which opens
at two o'clock it's around three o'clock
the giggles will start and we also have
a lot of restaurants on campus and we
because we have such a great push for
the barbecue we actually invited our BBQ
vendor back this year so across the
street you'll see Johnny D's BBQ please
go ahead and
use him he's a great vendor if he ever
had great pulled pork or ribs make sure
you go to him he started cooking today
around 6 o'clock so nice and tender
around 11 o'clock so enjoy next some of
the things that we've done we've
actually tried to save a tree and
started using an app the drift app we
kind of encourage that when they use it
because printouts become expensive and
we want to try to make make it as
cost-effective as possible
yeah and we also wanted to make sure
that from because we have a lot of
speakers who arrived out of town in case
there's a problem with one be able to
change on the fly and with the app we
can speaking of changes we actually have
do have one our good friend evil cat she
will not be able to make it this year
due to snow in Chicago of course so she
was originally scheduled to speak at a
salon at 11 o'clock
she has been replaced by Brian who will
be doing a lot pick talking during that
time if you have the drift app it's all
transparent so download if you have to
next we will talk about different
speakers traditionally a majority of our
speakers came from the Central Florida
area but we've decided to reach out to
expand our scope the reason for this is
that as more and more companies move to
the Florida more and more companies have
different skills and unique skills and
requirements they're looking for so just
by adding the same speakers over know
where it gets kind of old so we've
reached out to a lot more speakers from
different areas so over half our
speakers aren't from the citroen florida
area or even from florida we have them
as far as Switzerland California Chicago
and Israel so all these speakers are
great speakers who took the time out to
come here who battle the snow to come
hang out and warm humidity for a couple
of days so please make sure you thank
you speakers when you go to their talks
next additional tracks when I wouldn't
law school there really was no talks
about information privacy and data
security it was yeah it's computer
that's about it and when I went to
school for IT that really wasn't talked
about law or how data privacy laws
affect us as we see more and more
breaches happen we sit back in our
industry and go that's cool
I see how they broke it but we don't see
the other side of it we don't see the
different laws and regulation
that are being formed that impact us and
are in our industry so because this we
one actually have talks to actually
address those issues so we created our
data privacy track these talks are going
to look at some of the different types
of laws we will in regulation that
affect our industry and give the
opportunity and how they impact us in
the future and how we need to become
more involved in helping making these
type of rules and regulations and also
our finally our CCO track this is our
six talk and I've had the opportunity to
see a lot of folks come to our first one
second third etc and I've seen the
migrate of that career path from college
graduate new employee junior engineer
senior engineer SME so as we've seen a
progress throughout the industry we've
said okay the next stage is to go to at
sea level area that management put area
those required unique skills that you
probably won't find in a sense oh yeah
you always find the same class but you
won't find normally you need to actually
hear from a seesaw or c-level executive
on what some of the skills are so we
created our C so track we invited some
of the top CISOs in the Central Florida
area and from California come down and
give talks which you get that extra
spirits why yes it is a technical track
but it also is a management track so you
can learn about what CISOs do it and how
they actually do it so we hope you enjoy
it
and finally code of conduct okay this is
no prom we all know this it's our one
time the a we can hang out with everyone
talk shops laugh giggle drink do jokes
drink some more etc we encourage that we
want you to have a good time but we want
you to be considerate you know be
provocative bombastic or you know
aggravated aggravated does not make you
a Smee doesn't make you a god doesn't
like Nakia thing just makes you a whole
and that is a quick quick way to get
thrown out
so have fun enjoy self-talk but please
be courteous to everyone even though
they may have different political views
race color creed sexual orientation be
polite and everyone because we're all in
the same same family so yeah have fun
but enjoy yourself
and you haven't no right to have two
minutes with our conference we like to
start everything off with our lame joke
for the year so hey you got to pay for
so lame our lame jokes what do you call
a guy that let his feet cut off what is
the guy who had his feet cut off say oh
no he just defeated me thank you thank
you