quarterman lake in Florida just either
way his scene is response importance in
a responsive and what they termed threat
protection engineering this requires the
blue team to understand both the attacks
in the system they target this method
ensures that they have the right box
with the right analytics to identify
attacker mediated previously he was
officer in the US Coast Guard and acted
in various roles from escorting nuclear
submarines to originate at the coast one
penny it also teaches she teaches
cybersecurity courses having project I
haven't heard that border southern
ecology because several service industry
certifications such as the giac
certified know more than everybody
Bridget thank you so much so quick show
of hands who uses Splunk so awesome
about half of you half of you will be
really comfortable with a lot of my
screenshots because I use spunk
and I gave this talk at the spunk
conference just this past year but I
don't work for Splunk I don't have stock
in spunk and what I'm going to talk
about actually has nothing to do with
spunk it's just regular expressions so
the nature of this is that while I work
for Publix I'm not officially
representing public so I'm not even
allowed to use the logo today
but my point is I work for a grocery
store chain I don't work for a security
vendor
I've got nothing that I could possibly
convince you guys to buy at 11:00 in the
morning on it a wonderful Saturday but
we're going to talk about regular
expressions today so regular expressions
are a engine for doing crazy cool
wildcard searches so show Han who at
least knows what regular expressions are
everybody awesome who thinks they're an
expert in regular expressions one or two
awesome so the experts I'm going to ask
you to bear with me because I'm going to
ask you to tone it down and the reason
for that is everybody else isn't but you
need to work with them and that means
the elements that you write the regular
expressions and the searches that you
create need to be capable for everyone
else on your team so we're going to talk
through some of the prerequisite
knowledge to get through this I'll walk
you through some of the regular
expressions to make sure everybody
understands what we're doing the
philosophy that we developed at Publix
and just ways to develop regular
expressions good enough regular
expressions faster we're gonna work
through some common use cases work
around around parsing errors sequel
injection example cross-site scripting
example and system on example so these
prerequisites IP address we don't need
something fancy right slash D meaning a
digit 1 comma 3 have that digit repeat 1
2 3 times slash period means I want the
literal period everybody tracking with
me pretty easy right field extraction
this is probably the most important part
of the talk if you use spunk you love
field extractions this also applies with
tools online you can do this with I
believe even notepad plus plus the point
is you're going to capture elements with
the regular expression and you're going
to pull it out into a field that you can
now have done
and then there's just all the different
character classes these are good to know
a character class means the lowercase s
is give me whitespace characters non non
word characters the uppercase s the
exact opposite same with the D digits
but an uppercase D anything that's not a
digit so we're going to use this
opposite concept throughout the
presentation and finally the what what
I'm presenting is not the only way to do
this I'm not saying that this is the
Bible of regex not by any means but this
will help you go faster with your
incident response now some of the things
here is if you're yes sir it is
available so it's actually been posted
on the Splunk conference website and
besides is recording the talk so you'll
you'll have access to it so yeah now if
you want to take pictures be my guest so
this is after the alert a lot of people
who are used to working in a sim they're
trying to craft this alert to be as
precise and as accurate as possible this
is after that you know something's
happened now you need to collect all the
data which means you need to be fast you
are in IR mode so speed / precision that
means it's actually okay to bring in
some false positive data because we're
analysts we know what we're looking at
false negatives however are not okay
what I mean by false negatives are I've
missed critical data my regular
expression has not brought in the data I
need to make a sound decision now the
experts in the room they may like to
write things like this mind you this is
twenty percent just twenty percent of
the regular expression that we pulled
off of a Stack Overflow to validate RFC
a two two email addresses yeah sometimes
you get so preoccupied with whether or
not you can you don't stop to think of
you should so I'm going to urge you to
avoid the threat click of the
Tyrannosaurus Rex
alright jokes aside so which of these is
easier to understand
they're both attempting to extract an
email address and depending on the data
set you're working with both of them can
work if the second one works use the
second one just worry about getting the
data so which of these is easier to
understand now unlike the previous
example this one's more specific but if
the nature of your incident allows you
to be more specific choose the more
specific example choose that Microsoft
generic domain if those are the email
addresses you're worried about
extracting this type of self
contextualization self documentation of
the incident can make it much easier for
the other incident responders to follow
your footsteps to see how you did your
investigation and this is what I mean
about good enough so you might have
brought in some false positive data
obviously that middle ones a phone
number so what you're an analyst remove
it big deal you don't need to make this
perfect by the way this was Stack
Overflow suggestion which do you want to
deal with when you're trying to review
somebody's regular expression all right
so good enough regular expressions
faster so we've got a process here and
it's pretty straightforward but unless
you've been working in this in a while
you just may not have thought about it
first identify anchors so what I mean by
anchors are these are those character
sets that are just not going to change
around the field they may be before they
may be after so in the top example I
just want the domain so my front anchor
are going to be the HTTP colon slash
slash and the back anchor is going to be
that forward slash now I could just make
the front anchor just these two
characters right but again self
contextualization I
want the regex to be pretty easy to
understand in the second example we've
got an email address and we know that at
and dot that's always going to be
consistent now set up exclusions so
we've set up our anchors here we want to
do our extraction and then we want to
end the extraction with an exclusion and
I've got a typo in this data set there
should be a in parentheses right here
same with the bottom one as well
lastly you're going to want to set
boundaries on your quantifiers so we're
used to using pluses Stars unlimited
quantifiers because they're easy and
they're fast but sometimes that can be
damaging to the regex engine it can take
a catastrophic amount of time so we're
going to want to finite this thought
process a little bit I mean what's the
likelihood of a normal email address
being more than 64 characters pretty
darn low so iterate through it test it
make sure it makes sense and obviously
there's going to be some of those
ridiculously long email addresses from
the the spam campaigns but for our
incident 1 to 64 may be reasonable let
me prove this to you so I'm going
through a data set here and I'm just
pulling out email right and I'm using a
generic one easy to understand and here
we go
it's extracted it but it's extracted way
too much so I need to clarify this
regular expression right so I'm going to
add in some exclusions but now I've got
this timeout if you haven't seen this
website before this is probably my
favorite website for messing with
regular expressions reg x101 comm you
can change the type of engine you're
working with it's really really
effective you can even save your
extractions highly recommend it so we
got our exclusions in we're pretty sure
right but it timed out so let's add some
limiters on there now we've add that one
to 30 and it's completed
we also want to focus on the negative so
when you're iterating through your
development of regular expressions we
tend to think of all the possible
characters that we want to bring into
this capture this actually makes it
really difficult to troubleshoot because
your expressions get long they get
complicated and then you have to think
of all of those edge cases that just
aren't in a normal instance for example
how many people have a plus and their
email address you kind of do because per
the RFC you're allowed to use a plus and
you're allowed to change whatever comes
after the plus and it's it should still
go to the same mailbox Google is one of
the only email providers that actually
takes advantage of that feature and if
you're not accounting for a rarely used
character in email you might miss it but
if you exclude characters that you know
will never be part of the email address
such as whitespace you're good to go so
let's walk through this one more time so
again I'm trying to extract email
dresses I'm getting too much so I'm
gonna get it right through this to clean
this up so I know that I should not be
capturing any back slashes so that
capture that fixes the back end it's
pretty easy and I haven't had to overly
complicate my extraction to get this
information now when I scroll down even
further I see that I've actually got
multiple email addresses and I may need
a few more exclusions such as quotations
commas square brackets so I've added
those in now I'm going to I don't have
any limiters on here I'm using that Plus
which allows you to go an unlimited
amount of time and right now it's taking
one point two one seconds to complete
with over a million steps if I keep the
same extraction but I just add some
limiters it's now down 192 milliseconds
so think fine knife you're gonna save
yourself and your sim a lot of time now
this was Splunk specific for those of
you who like to use funk you may not
have known that the Rex command has a
max underscore match field so if you add
that to your spunk you can actually get
multi value fields pretty nice pretty
handy all right so let me break this
down we've got our capture group email
I've got the character class for the
mailbox name that's the section of the
email before the @ sign and these are
all the characters that should never be
a part of that including the @ sign
and based on my data set I determined
that there's no more than 30 characters
I've got my anchor my @ sign and again
an exclusion group for the backside that
domain name and in this case I already
have a limiter up here so I used a
unlimited repeater at the end now this
is a weird Splunk thing if you want to
capture a backslash you can't just
escape it you have to double escape it
so it's for back slashes weird except it
will move on all right some of the
things that you may want it to pay
attention to catastrophic backtracking
repeating a capturing a group
unintentionally I'm not gonna go into
these but I highly recommend reading
into them it's rare that you would run
into this but it's worth taking note of
so I recommend this website regular
expressions dot info now one thing I
will talk about is assuming that all of
your results are going to be captured so
let's talk through some common use cases
often times my team has to go through HR
requests where we need to assess what
people have been doing on the on the web
and whether or not as a professional
part of their job so going through user
activity what does their search history
look like so you know in Splunk we're
able to pull in URL activity and this
can be a kind of burdensome to crawl
through now spunk has some features that
can automatically pull out the domain
name but what if you don't have that
what if you want to just distill down
the domain name so again we've got our
capture group we've talked about this
before we've run the Rex command and
we've distilled down all that data to
now 136 unique domains the users visited
- and maybe this person really likes to
drink beer I don't know you know we have
beer buyers of public so that might
actually be part of their job but
another element is what's the users
intent and this one's kind of fun
because this is where you get to see
hands on keyboard can you demonstrate
that the user was wanting to get to the
data that they happen to see well search
history really really helps so it's a
little hard to see here but this these
are all Google results and it's
ridiculously long Google strings so we
start to bring in the information and we
use the Q equals as the anchor run our
search string and we notice that the end
of it that ampersand is that end anchor
so we exclude it and we just bring in
everything else
Splunk has a feature you our URL decode
you don't really need it
and now I've got hands on keyboard what
the person was actively searching
through Google and depending on how your
squid logs your proxy logs are coming in
because of how Google is every keystroke
presenting that and giving you search
results back you're going to get proxy
logs for every single keystroke and
you're going to get as the person's
typing what they're looking for
so big this is an instance where we
developed this query and we said hey we
think we got everything we tested it we
realized we did not get everything so
that's one of those pitfalls don't
assume just because you're getting
results that you're getting all the
results in this case we had two
different elements that being likes to
use so we have two different sets of
anchors we run the search string run it
again and here you can actually see
people hands on keyboard doing their
favorite Bing search looking for Google
[Music]
words near other words so this was
something that I was playing with and I
almost scrapped it and then my partner
who's not here today my partner found a
good really good use for this so we were
trying to find instances for the word
username near the word password because
maybe we've got email logs and maybe we
want to see passwords in the clear or
maybe we've got web application logs and
we want to see if that data is actually
being transited in an unencrypted packet
so in this case we were looking through
SMTP logs and we actually found an
instance of Kay lager fields username
and beer lols
so a little easier to see here so this
is kind of a problem and if this is a
persistent problem maybe we want to
actually extract out the information so
that we know what users we need to worry
about doing the password reset on so we
worked through that
hey based on this email traffic just
username password extract the
information set our anchors set our
limiters and here we actually have K
lager field
beer lols and the extraction decoded in
a large-scale attack this could be
really really useful the previous talker
in this room mentioned the scam that's
going around is kind of old but it's
come right back around again hey
this is your username and I have your
password and I've seen all those dirty
things you've done on the Internet right
I just got one of my Gmail the other day
and like that you'd have mine boring I'm
really boring at home so good luck with
that one
but if that type of scam is coming into
your corporate internet and those are
actual passwords which the one that hit
my gmail was an actual password from
like 10 years ago
pretty sure was from the Adobe breach
that may be something that you want to
start digging through the logs to get
this information because if those
passwords are still legit that you're
your associates are using you're going
to need to go through the password
resets now Splunk has a feature that we
wanted to highlight you can actually do
the due masking because maybe you don't
want to actually give away the password
in the logs that you submit up to the
management so working around parsing
errors for those of you who love Splunk
will probably run into this quite a bit
parsing errors can be the bane of an
incident responders experience so we
were doing some analysis on a sample
data set that Splunk gave us and we
thought we had everything here and we
were a little confused why are there
only three domains in this data set so
when we started digging in we realized
that no we've got some other domains and
we should probably take assess this
fidelity of these logs a little more so
we did our extraction again anchors
limiters I added an HTTPS here for that
self contextualization and now we're
getting a lot more results a lot more
domains no longer depending on
potentially faulty automatic extractions
and in this case one of the domains that
got highlighted right away was this one
server org slash malware - download this
was in the middle of one of Splunk
sponsored CTS sequel injection
so I'm assuming everybody here knows
sequel injection at the spunk conference
we couldn't make that assumption but the
point of this is you've got an alert
you're starting somewhere remember this
is post alert now in this case we found
that there was an attack against this
this function being used and an overload
to that function was allowing a sequel
query to be injected in order to dump
information so after the attacker
submitted this this was submitted back
to the attacker providing the username
so what we're trying to ask him out here
is we've demonstrated we see that
there's a sequel injection attack what
is the scope of this attack how many
usernames how many passwords what else
has been leaked out so we do our
extraction we use that function as our
anchor and we use the angle bracket as
the rear anchor we pull everything else
in just so we can start pulling in these
sequel injections for analysis so here
we can see over and over and over the
subsequent sequel injections that we
have so if you look closely you can see
they're pulling password they're pulling
salt they're putting email addresses
pulling usernames okay that's
information we want to know what about
the results that were sent back to the
user so let's start pulling that
information now we've got the XPath
syntax error as the anchor and now we're
seeing exactly what was given back to
the attacker over here we see both the
query that was given and the results and
with a bit of fancy Splunk foo we're
able to table those results so we can
see how everything was related together
so the password hash the salt the
username all of that jazz so a sequel
injection attack that you were
vulnerable to and now you need to know
what you've been what you've disclosed
much easier to analyze now you're not
going to be able to use these regular
expressions cut and paste that's not the
point of this talk right the point of
this talk is just develop based on your
data set as fast
you can cross-site scripting cross-site
scripting is starting to go away they're
still definitely exposure on the
internet but simply it's a script
embedded somewhere either reflective or
resident and it injects code that wasn't
supposed to be running so skipping paths
that Splunk specific stuff we had an
alert on a cross-site scripting and it
was obviously malicious because that
organization was never going to have
Korean symbols
so the original analysis was just look
for the word alert and filter out alert
je s because that was really really
common and there were three results and
two of them were false positives okay
let's try the regex way so this time
we're looking for our anchors and we're
specifically looking for the script tag
or in this case I'm sorry the code tag
because the code tag is what was being
taken advantage of for the cross-site
scripting so here's our regex code
equals pull everything else so in this
case we actually got more cross-site
scripting it's that our true positives
just because we didn't assume that it
required the word alert in the
cross-site scripting attack now granted
there's maybe non regex ways to do this
but one of the things I like about
regular expressions is that you end up
naming your fields and so with
cross-site scripting your field is now
cross-site scripting so a follow-on
analyst knows what you're looking for
and what you're anticipating in these
results working with sis Mon all right
who here has deployed system onto their
Windows environment I highly recommend
you deploy stencil onto your Windows
environment if you're not looking at
Windows event logs for threats you
should be and system on gives you so
much more data than the natural Windows
event logs the problem is it's not
natively parsed by a lot of Simms even
though it's XML based it's just not
natively done including with including
with Splunk
so before we get here one of the things
that six Mons really valuable with is
it'll give you a hash of the executables
that are run as they're run it'll give
you the command line parameters of the
executables as they're run some of this
information may be available through
amplified GPOs but the hash isn't and
that hash can be really really powerful
so we had a scenario a employees hiding
hiding his browsing history behind tor
so what version of the tor browser was
downloaded so we're working through six
months this month typically looks like
this I don't want to spend the time to
parse this one I've got Splunk engineers
who can get that fixed they just got it
on their roadmap I need to deal with
this incident today and everything has a
tag and a tag now you should not be
using regular expressions to parse XML
do not do that that is bad it is never
going to work successfully but you can
use regular expressions to parse the
information you need in order to get
what you want in this case we're just
looking for we know there's going to be
a tag and we know that there's going to
be the word file and tor either
uppercase or lowercase so let's pull
that information out and quickly we can
see command line current directory image
parent command line these are fields
that have been related to the word tor
in the system on data I've been able to
take all of that system on data which is
a lot and distill it down to six total
categories with about two hundred events
so digging down even further now I can
actually see what was being parsed
through tor awesome now if you're an elk
stack user you can do this an elk sack
as well I am by no means selling Splunk
if you're pulling the wrong logs raw
logs you can do this in notepad plus
plus I'm by no means selling Splunk it's
just what I'm comfortable with
[Music]
so any questions so far yes sir yes sir
absolutely so let me hit think that was
slide 14
[Music]
okay so the key element here is your
regular expression if you just use
natural regular expressions it's going I
forget the term whether greedy or on
greedy I always get those confused but
it's it's going to naturally pull all
the results that's the way just Splunk
happens to do it you can change that
parameter if you really want to but it's
going to pull more than one it just will
only return the first result unless you
set a max underscore match parameter so
if you set it equal to zero it'll pull
in all the the results and put it in a
multi value field the multi value field
looking like this here is one event and
here's all the email addresses that were
in that one event from that single
regular expression max underscore match
equals zero anybody else well as I
typically do I talked way too fast so
that is my presentation thank you so
much for attending I appreciate it
[Applause]