uh hello everyone welcome to our talk
um
our talk is about a security divide into
the dds security protocol
we're here to show you how we break most
of the major implementations and how we
also break this back
so our research team actually consists
of tx people from gx1 networks and try
micro research and also we have vendor
corporations from editing ads
so let's go through our slides
[Music]
so
some of you might already know what is
dds
and in case some don't let's give you a
quick overview of what is dds
dds is basically a protocol with
publisher and subscriber model
and it's been used in numerous
applications and you might as well
already been using it
without your knowledge
for example there's an operating system
used by robots called rust2 it runs on
dds by default
and where is it being used
well dds is being used in multiple
applications such as
transportation
and autonomous vehicles for
as an example
we've seen many autonomous vehicles
using dds for ecu inter communications
and some vendors have been selling it to
some high-speed trains
and for robots like i said before
ross2 uses dds by default
and it's being used in aerospace
and also healthcare is better within
usage from ge healthcare
and defense sector for example
the cf c4 isr from a particular military
uses dds
and we've seen usage in missile silos
almond aerial vehicles
and
missile launchers
above naval muscles
and let's have a quick overview
about how to talk into each other in dds
this is an example
maybe in a factory like you're having a
sensor and you want to talk to a control
app
so you want to implement a publisher on
the sensor and a subscriber on the
controller
then you should define something called
a topic
to define the message types
and the message types can be very
complex and can even contain binary data
like this
and most of dds implementations they are
configurated with xml files
if you like more code than just talk
then this page will be for you this is
an example for how you're using dds
as a publisher
for subscribers you're doing the things
up the opposite way but the general idea
is still
is still the same
so we can say dds is a simple protocol
it has publisher and subscriber models
and our focus our research focus on ddsi
rtps
i emphasize on the word rtps is because
dds can work over many mediums such as
using dds over cambus
as long as the underlying protocols
underlying layers are provided you can
use dds on it
so let's go through the journey of our
analysis
well
what's wrong with dds i must say that
something must have gone wrong otherwise
i wouldn't be here and
talking to you
so in this research we actually
evaluated against six major dds
implementations
and we somehow broke them all and we
also broke the specification in a
process
and in the beginning of our research
we actually thinking about what we want
to see and what we want to find in this
research
so we're looking for protocol
specification box it's because when you
broke this back you broke all the
implementations
and for remote executions it's pretty
obvious because you can take over
devices remotely using this
and for denial of service
vulnerabilities well because dds is
mostly used in time
sensitive
applications so any breakage will result
in great impact
for leakage for key materials we're
looking for something similar to
heartbleed
because that would enable us to extract
secrets from the other side
and for outdated dependencies
because we already know that ics people
they really don't like to patch
so there's a
great possibility that they will use
something very old and allows us to
exploit it
and for our impact we actually found
multiple vulnerabilities across these
six major implementations such as buffer
overall attacks resource exhaustion and
denial of service
and our research actually made a pretty
large ban a pretty loud beam even before
we gave a talk first time in black hat
because we have a
advisory
from ics cert thanks to them that we
have a
chance to remind people to update their
systems
and also we found one network refreshing
attack in the specification
this vulnerability has been reported to
the dds consortium and might be fixed in
the future
so
we go on and tell you how about we broke
all the targets
despite the title of this diet it's
called foster universe but we did code
review in parallel
well
but that dds implementation they tend to
be very big and complex so
we initially thought that code review
would be pretty useless but if
it has proven otherwise
in our first attempt we actually use
airflow plusbox in conjunction with
unicorn engine
and this is very useful because
in before we will assume that frozen
binaries are very inefficient and kind
of impossible
but with this combination we can fix
even coastal binaries and retain control
over program state
while returning retaining
instrumentation abilities so we can
complete the files and binary program
and in our frozen campaign we focus on
network issues because network stack is
the first place any network data goes in
and it's coming from an untrusted source
making it as great fusing target
and it's pretty obvious for deserializer
and serializers because we already know
that humanity always failed to build a
secure serializer
and for our fuzzing platform
in the process of this research we
unscientifically found out that using
amd machines can greatly save your time
and your money
we somehow find out that using amd
machines are
having like two times faster performance
than fuzzy intel machines
however we did not go deeper
about the reason behind this in this
research
and how do you find serializer targets
well
you can use dynamic analysis to find out
that how the function is being called
and trying to mimic the functionality in
your file in your files in campaign
or you can use that you can use static
analysis and to manually find for
a couple of gimmicks while parsing the
headers from
dds
and how to find a file how to find a
parser well
because dds is a
protocol and it has numerous type and
fields so it means that there must be a
parser
and because a parser is usually complex
and big
it makes it a very good fusing target
so very early on into our fuzzing
campaign we actually found out numerous
vulnerabilities
so as shown here is actually one cvs
we reported to the vendor this is a
denial of service vulnerability
this is actually caused by this specific
vendor which failed to implement
input sanitization and also failed to
implement a proper
error handling scheme
so when you send this
junk looking material to this
implementation it will crash it
immediately
and deeper into our fuzzing campaign
well because we already know so much
from the spec at that point so sometimes
you will just develop an instinct that
you know you can break something by
manually changing something
so in this case we unfortunately broke
this back by
changing this one
we did something very funny such as
changing id around changing bit fields
around changing length and port
and what we did is we
one time that we just turn on the
dissector
and see there's an ip address field so
we decided to change ib address to some
random victims
such as
using google dns as a victim
then it turns out that we actually found
a
reflected attack
it kind of scared us because we're using
google dns as a test target at that time
this is a very bad practice
so please don't do so
but the result is pretty scary because
we're thinking that we're
we actually found an
amplification attack
but however after some precise
measurements
we decided to not call it amplification
attack because our amplification factor
is pretty low compared to something like
main crash and redis
so we call it network refraction attack
and how do we how did we find it we
just grabbed an embedded payload from
the network and pasted it to vim as
change a couple of fields sending back
using pawn tools then we somehow broke
this back
so at that point we did we know that we
somehow
find a found an issue across
implementations because the spec
doesn't call for any white listing in
that field
thus it allows arbitrary ip to be filled
in that field
so here's a list of results from our
fuzzing campaign and fortunately most
mentors have fixed it by now
and our another approach in finding
vulnerabilities is that we want to look
for outdated dependencies
like we said before many dds
implementations they use they use xml
files for configuration
well
the best way
that you should use a well-tested xml
libraries
the okay way is that if your company
maybe your company name is google or
apple you have enough engineers then you
can re-implement your own excel library
and test it very often
but the bad way is you should not
use any unmaintained libraries because
they often contain vulnerabilities
so
it's pretty contrary to our thoughts
because we find we we thought the
products shouldn't be doing something
like using very old dependent disease or
even something like this
so for example a vendor actually use a
very old version of xml library
then change the version number to
something newer to make it more
legit
we don't know the reason behind this but
it's pretty
funny
so
the results
we
threw the xml files through the ramdasa
file and broke one of the
implementations
and we achieved local code execution
well
we said it is local but in some cases
that you will use dds to implement some
kind of configuration updating mechanism
when you do this then we have a chance
to update your configuration files from
the remote and what if we are updating
your dds
implementation using this functionality
and with this file then we can take over
your systems
so here's a list of results from our xml
files in campaign
and fortunately that most matters
sorry all vendors have fixed them
so let's quickly go through our
conclusions
some people might ask that
most of the issues found are dos and
code local code executions
is because
some some of the implementations we
actually tested our modern linux but we
know that some implementations they
might be run on embedded systems
that will make our
vulnerabilities exploitable
and also we can have a demo
i think the page
back button isn't working
and also my video is missing from the
slide
so unfortunately i will have to release
the video later
so let's skip a video because i i
i was having a video demonstrating that
we use a
denial of service attack against a
turtle bot and run
and ram it against some cuddly
dogs
so anyway
how our finding makes impact well
uh because of our missing demo one of
the things missed it its point
but however in dds networks controlling
one endpoint is enough to impact other
endpoints
you can see this from the reflection or
our missing demo
and two dds is usually deployed in local
and deep in the control network so
some people would say don't expect to
find exposed endpoints
for exposed
rost2 instances well we've seen lots of
people expose their roster instances on
the internet
and we can say that dds created new
opportunities for discovery and natural
movement and cnc this is very useful for
apt actors
because there's a built-in network
discovery ability for the dds you can
use it to find out every node in the
internet in that network
and because dds allows
complex data
to be attached to the network payloads
and dds is usually white listed in local
networks you can use it as a form of cpu
and some people will argue that you
won't expose dds on the outside so we
did something unthinkable we actually
created an internet scanner
this actually cost us a bit of mayhem in
the beginning because
it's pretty difficult to do so
one is because dds can be configurated
dynamically and it has a very large port
range like
10 000
and also bds has very strict latency
requirements such as you have to make a
response to the other side in 50
milliseconds
but as our scanners are located on the
other side of earth
it will be pretty difficult
ndds itself is connectionless that makes
the issue much worse however we
overcome all of these issues and found
out that there's actually around 23
2300 exposed endpoints in the internet
and a great great percentage of them are
running on outdated dds versions
so
let's go to our remarks
well
in this research we must say that
mitigation goes hand-to-hand with good
disclosure we will go deeper about this
on the later slides
and we know that specs can contain
loopholes for exploitation in sometimes
for example
the speculative execute execution bug
affecting processors
in this decade
the issue can can actually be found
while reading a spec
and
we would recommend using proper network
segmentation or using ips to defend
unpatchable systems or the ones that you
couldn't patch but wanted to patch
so
let's go through a page well
i must say that this page is for
audiences of s4
given how the audience demographic looks
like
in the beginning of this research we
actually approach vendors in a very
friendly way when starting working on
this project we
send emails and even
try to talk to them in person and ask if
you
want to start a security research
project on your product
so in the beginning we actually
explained to vendors that we're not here
to do harm to them and this will
actually make them better in the long
term
and how's that transparency paid back
so i must say that some implementations
some vendors they are very friendly
and even
jump out jump on the wagon and help us
to break their own products
so i must say one of the vendors is
called adlink and we must given a very
large applause
[Applause]
and some of the vendors they never
responded
they either never respond or they
responded in a very
very bad way which make up makes us very
uncomfortable
for example some of the vendors
threatened us with legal actions
and some never responded
even when we found vulnerabilities in
their products and reported them through
our vendor for our vulnerability broker
and even with ics assert
and some vendors they assume that
by remaining their products in closed
source binaries
they are sending out a black boss
and they think that
i'm only sending out binaries so you
couldn't do any something funny to it
thus my product is secure
i call this hiding in the cave
but i say that as a researcher we tend
to think like hackers do
so we will eventually find a way to
crack that cave and still break your
product
so i must say vendors we need more
cooperative security assessments
so that will conclude our talk
if you have any questions please raise
your hand or send email to this address
oh hello
you take question yeah sure so dds it
stands for data definition services
right yes okay
i guess my question would be you know i
haven't done a lot of fuzz testing but
chris systrunk and adam crane and these
guys years ago they
they focused on d and p3 and they hacked
it up pretty good you know and exposed a
lot of stuff on it and
i'm personally i'm in love with the
publish and subscribe model i think it's
the right thing for control systems
i'm discouraged to hear that dds has
these kinds of problems so i guess my
question would be
out of all the protocols you've looked
at which one would you say is the most
secure because dds out of the pub sub
world they are the first ones that i
know of that actually wrote a security
spec called dds secure right that's
probably the one that you found some
holes in maybe right
so i guess my question is um
what's the what's the best protocol out
there https
you know which one has been beat on the
most and what will it take to make dds
um a more secure product in your opinion
so i think that's a very good question
but i must say that
we should not be thinking this way we
should be thinking about how do you
protect the unprotectable you should
assume that
your infrastructures
will somehow come under attack in one
day so how would you against it so
instead by blocking the fire outside
your forest you actually allows the fire
to get into your forest but you still
retain a control of how big the fire
will go
this would be my suggestion
well but even i thought they were one of
the first ones that did what you would
call
uh kind of a zero trust model mtls
and so if that if they really
implemented that well how
you know you you approve identity you um
do encrypted traffic along your topics
uh but it's still broken but were you
testing clear text protocol dds or not
you know or
so our research is actually not against
the dds security protocol but because
dda security requires you to do a
handshake with ordinary dds in the first
place
so our research will still somehow break
dds security but not directly okay
excellent thank you
so any more questions yeah
so
my question is when you broke the spec
uh thanks for not cutting off my head
there um when you broke the spec um
is there a way the library vendors can
take action now to prevent that
vulnerability from being used or does it
require changes to the standard in order
to fix
oh that's another very good question so
for the first one
the spec will actually be fixed in the
next version
and
as our assessments goes that some
implementations they are more resilient
to this
spec attack because they're
maybe they're
more cautious in creating their own
implementations
and
but for now because the spec hasn't been
up hasn't been updated yet so most
vendors they have to actually
not
adhere to the spec in order to fix this
issue
okay thank you
one last question can you describe your
demo because was it a robot
uh yeah so yeah so what did the robot do
i'd like to hear what happened oh so uh
we're actually simulating a scenario
that you have a car
and you have a lidar on it and the lidar
will detect obstacles in the front
and when it detects obstacles in the
front it will send
it will send the pedal telling the
wheels to stop
but we
take out this path in the process so the
car will fail to stop and ram into
maybe other human beings
okay thank you