good morning everyone i really want to
thank dale for inviting me to speak
today because
there's nothing like talking about cyber
security to a room full of cyber
security experts
it's
intimidating and it can be fun
it's intimidating because you guys have
robust situational awareness about the
domains you're experts in
but maybe it'll be a little bit fun
because perhaps i can give you a
slightly different lens from which to
look at the same data as the same facts
the same trends the same events that
we're all looking at every day
so my lens is that of national security
and today
that includes war modern warfare and
international conflict
over the past two decades driven in a
large part by the internet revolution
we have set the conditions for modern
warfare and it's all playing out in the
war between russia and ukraine
now modern conflict is simply going to
be different than anything we've seen
before when most people think about war
they think about guns and tanks and
missiles
not electrons but it's electrons it's
cyber that's going to change the face of
modern warfare and it requires us to
adjust our perspective
there's three ways in which cyber is
changing war that i want to touch on
today there's a lot more but these are
the three that i want to focus on
the first is technology
the second is social media
and the third is data
now
i have this slide up
not just because i love standing in
front of it for absolutely as long as
possible
but also
because the hack of russian car charging
stations was the first time an iot hack
took place in the context of war
and this hack didn't just deface these
car charging stations it meant that
russians couldn't charge their cars it
meant that russians couldn't drive their
cars
this hack also highlights another theme
that i'm going to hit on repeatedly
today and that's the increasing
privatization of war capabilities
okay so let's start with technology now
you guys have all seen some version of
this slide before right by 2025 it's
predicted that we're going to have
somewhere between 27 billion and 37
billion connected devices
you all also know that the growth in iot
devices expands the cyber threat
landscape
now when you put on the lens of modern
conflict
the rate of growth of connected devices
the expanding hyper-connected ecosystem
that we all live in
is inherently fragile more fragile with
each connected device
and this fragility creates the
foundational risk and the foundational
opportunities in modern war
who would have thought that electric car
charging stations would act as an attack
vector during a war
now as we look to the future of smart
cities we can imagine a time when these
attacks are going to be more than just
mere annoyances but
represent the possibility of systemic
failure for our cities
peter singer and august cole wrote a
book called burn-in which explores this
topic and i recommend everyone read it
here's another slide you guys have all
seen some version of before right
it's the expanding drumbeat of cyber
attacks of breaches of ransomware
attacks of ip theft of data theft
what's interesting when you look at it
from the lens of modern conflict is that
privatization is blurring the lines
between criminal and state actors and
actions
are russian ransomware gangs just
criminals are they proxies for the
kremlin
if the colonial pipeline hack took place
today
would that count as an act of war
would that invoke article 5 of nato and
mean that both the u.s and europe have
been pulled into this conflict
we have never responded to criminal act
with military response it's just not how
democracy works
but while our response to crime to
espionage and to war is not unified
the use of crime and espionage as part
of war
as part of strategic global competition
is becoming increasingly unified by our
adversaries
a real-time example of this took place
when early in the russia-ukraine war the
russians hacked viasat
now biden had previously said that an
attack on u.s infrastructure would lead
to a u.s response
and
with this attack we see the complexity
of that decision-making process
does an attack on a u.s
telecommunications company that
primarily impacts ukrainian and european
customers count as an act of war
does it warrant retaliation
does it invoke article 5 of nato
the impact of this attack went far
beyond ukraine's borders does that mean
that the war
now has expanded beyond ukraine's
borders
importantly with the viasat attack
we witnessed cyber war extending into
space for the first time and we need to
move quickly to secure space assets
now speaking of space
what happens when a u.s company provides
critical capabilities to a country
during wartime elon musk with starlink
provides ukrainians with a distributed
and privatized communication alternative
that's much more resilient to attack
than viasat
now
one of the complexities of cyberwar is
this issue of attribution now if you
look on the
left side
you'll see that with traditional
military conflict the ttps for
attribution are well understood when we
launch missile attacks we can tell where
they were launched from whether it's
land air or sea cyber is very different
and you can see that with the cyber
attack slide
the physical location of the attack has
very little to do with who's actually
behind that attack
now here's a video of an attack that
took place actually it's not an attack
it's multiple attacks that took place a
few weeks ago
if you look at this closely you'll see
that san francisco is attacking new york
i actually think san francisco at some
point attacks australia while brazil
attacks the midwest
getting to perfect attribution in cyber
is more like putting puzzle pieces
together
we can do it we're actually really good
at it
but can we do it with the certainty that
you need to justify military retaliation
especially retaliation that's timely
that's proportional and that's accurate
during an active conflict
now cyber attribution is further
complicated by the fact that our
adversaries russia china iran north
korea
they deny that they were behind these
attacks it allows them to operate in the
gray zone below the threshold of war
keep in mind that once attribution is
made then the public expects action to
follow
this is why we sometimes see the u.s
government hesitating to attribute a
particular attack to a particular actor
especially if it's the nation state it's
to manage escalation risk
and you know we saw that with viasat
because while some cyber security firms
have definitively said that russia was
behind the viasat attack the united
states has not yet named russia as the
source of that attack
attribution of that attack to russia
today creates a lot of complexity when
you put on the lens of modern conflict
now i just touched on a few ways that
tech transformation is impacting modern
conflict there's a lot of other ones and
we could spend days talking about it the
important thing to keep in mind is that
the velocity of technologies change for
the first time in human history is
outpacing our ability as humans to adapt
and to gain mastery
harvard professor e.o wilson famously
said years ago the real problem with
humanity is the following
we have paleolithic emotions we have
medieval institutions and we have
god-like technology
and it's terrifically dangerous and it's
now approaching a point of crisis
okay so let's turn to the second area i
want to discuss and that's the
transformation in social media social
engagement and social interaction
what we have today is a social ecosystem
that's dominated by a few technology
platforms that are driving entirely new
types of behavior that it turns out
we're completely unprepared for
some of these behaviors are authentic
but a lot of them are not
and that includes misinformation
disinformation mal information and flat
out lies
keeping in mind by the way
that false and negative news have a
virality that truth can't match isn't
that amazing by the way that we prefer
we prefer
false and negative news to the truth
that's our cognitive biases
and it's all changing not just social
dynamics at a tremendous cost to our
children
but it's also changing the face of war
this new social ecosystem can catch even
the most sophisticated investors off
guard as was the case when we saw a rate
on the securities market coordinated on
reddit that cost sophisticated investors
19 billion dollars twitter can change
history
on may 2nd 2011 a pakistani man tweeted
live in jalalabad that he was hearing
and seeing helicopters in the middle of
the night which was a pretty rare thing
now that was as the us was preparing to
raid bin laden's compound
if either osama bin laden or the
pakistanis were paying attention to
twitter that night
the entire outcome of that mission and
potentially history would have been very
different
now social media can also have an
incredibly positive outcome through the
lens of modern conflict the early
lessons from the ukraine war is that
social media and information warfare can
be a determinative factor in the outcome
of conflict
before russia's invasion of ukraine
zielenski's approval rating was 26
percent
after the invasion it was over 90
percent his selfies his videos his talks
together with all the images that were
crowdsourced and stitched together
showing a united ukraine fighting for
freedom have fundamentally changed the
dynamics of those war in favor of
ukraine which is otherwise completely
outmanned and under-equipped in a
traditional military sense
as a result of this infowar campaign the
ukrainian public became mobilized
germany went from committing a few
helmets to committing anti-tank weapons
switzerland switzerland which had
been neutral throughout world war ii and
in the face of nazi atrocities shed that
historic neutrality and came out against
the war even halliburton suspended
operations in russia
public sentiment has driven
public policy and corporate policy in
this war
and by winning the like war
the ukrainians actually stand a fighting
chance against russia
now of course we have to touch on deep
fakes now you guys have all seen the
obama and the joe rogan d d fake so i'm
not going to share them with you and a
couple weeks ago there was a really bad
deep fake of zelinski conceding the war
floating around facebook but that got
taken down pretty quickly now we all
know that the technology for deep fakes
is ubiquitous is out there anyone can do
it high school student actually middle
school student could probably make a
deep fake these days
what i want to show you is a video that
thrasher magazine made about four years
ago that can help us imagine what could
happen here if you put some resources
against the concept of hey i'm uh glenn
larson today we'll be shooting jeff
doing a 360 inward healed on the
legendary el cabra stair set
[Music]
all right right here
and pop
that's what it takes to make these
things look legit you know
i think i was about 16 or 17 when i
found out the truth about how skate
videos are made
i mean
before i thought the 900 was actually a
real trick
and i figured out it's just as fake as
someone landing on the moon all right
okay
was that real was it a parody maybe
maybe not who knows but the truth is
that the human eye can't tell the
difference anymore and consider what
happens when it's just not an individual
making a deep vape but you actually use
resources you use technology it's going
to get harder and harder
to tell the difference between truth and
lies
and by the way if you think cyber
attribution is hard try mapping
information flows this is a network
graph by the company blackbird.ai
that's tracking a narrative around
russia ukraine for one organization over
a two-week period each color represents
an attribute red is misinformation the
other colors represents communities
personas organizations individuals
traditional social media tools cannot
grapple with the complexity of traffic
traffic tracking these data flows and
how they relate across social media
platforms the sophistication of the
tools that are required to do this are
truly next level
okay
so let's turn to the third aspect
of modern cough link that i want to talk
about and that's data and i really want
to focus on the intersection of physical
and digital data and the fusion of those
two things
it's hard not to be either
incredibly impressed or incredibly
terrified by how effectively china has
fused the digital and the physical
domains
china's social scoring system combines
data and intelligences from a multitude
of sources
correlates them in real time applies
intelligence and analyzes it to generate
a social score that determines in real
time whether someone represents a threat
to the state or whether they're
trustworthy
and if you think that doesn't happen in
the west you're dead wrong
but it's just not driven by the
government
the faces of the riot website was
created by a teenager in washington dc
who used open source intelligence and
open source software to identify 6 000
pictures of people's faces
at around the riot on january 6th in a
complete role reversal from china the
u.s citizens use of surveillance
technology informed the u.s government's
understanding of what happened during
the capital riots
in this case the u.s government needed a
distributed decentralized and privatized
citizen army to help identify these
individuals
and you know it gets more granular than
that the new york times assembled a
clear picture of how the combination of
mobile phone data advertiser data and
social media data can be used to fully
reconstruct one man's participation in
the riot from his home in kentucky
all the way to washington d.c
to his time at trump rally
all the way to the steps of the capitol
building and with precision his
movements inside the capitol building
similarly the ukrainians have been able
to track russian troops using the same
kind of technology that made ronnie
vincent so easily trackable
at technology on phones
has become
targeting technology in war
now on the positive side all of this
data can also be used to establish
ground truth when lies are so ubiquitous
hawkeye 360 is a private company that
uses a constellation of satellites to
track radio frequency signals around the
world
in april 2020 as beijing announced that
the pandemic was completely under
control and that 70 of the ports in
wuhan were back up and operating hawkeye
360 imagery showed that they were not
that the that the port was essentially
still shut down to traffic
basically unmasking beijing's lies the
red dot is is the red circle is wuhan
and you can see the difference between
the traffic and wuhan and the shanghai
ports
once again the power of privatization
comes to life
with capabilities like those of hawkeye
society has access to intelligence and
information that used to be the sole
purview of government it used to be that
only governments could track the assets
of other governments that's no longer
the case and think about the
implications of that from a from the
perspective of modern warfare
the ubiquity of satellite imagery is a
game changer spacex has now democratized
satellite launches with low-cost and
frequent launches you pay by the
kilogram you obtain a quote online and
today the price for launching a
satellite is somewhere around a hundred
thousand dollars with off-the-shelf
components that you can carry in your
arms
you can task these satellites by the way
you can task these satellites with apps
like spy mesat using your smartphone and
as a result close to 8 billion people
have access to high quality space
imagery
prices range from the hundreds of
dollars to the thousands of dollars for
images of vic varying quality and
they're available for purchase to anyone
the iranian government use commercial
satellite imagery to monitor anal assad
air base in iraq
as it prepared to launch
dozens of ballistic missiles against u.s
and allied forces coalition forces now
just think about that the iranian
government used commercial satellite
imagery to target u.s forces
planet earth will soon be entirely
instrumented from space to earth
generating data which when fused with
intelligence fundamentally transforms
modern conflict both from an offensive
and a defensive perspective
we're used to living in a world where
there have been always been places and
activities and locations that have been
invisible to us
we're moving to a world where every
square meter of planet earth is
instrumented and available to purchase
for individuals
this means that secrecy is harder
this means that clandestine operations
are harder
this means that deception is harder
hours before putin announced the start
of special military operations on
february 24th a group of open source
intel analysts in california tracking
traffic flows on google maps
called out that the invasion of ukraine
by russia had begun
ukrainian radio radio watchers is a
collection of private open source
analysts who use software-defined radios
to intercept unencrypted russian radio
communications to identify russian plan
and prevent the attacks making signals
intelligence sigin decentralized
distributed and privatized by the way
there's really good question as to why
the russians are using unencrypted radio
communications and it either means that
they just haven't modernized the way
they'd led the world to believe or that
they're having problems encrypting and
exchanging private keys we'll find out
at some point
now let's play this forward
if you stitch together these three
inputs to modern conflict technology
social media and data what does it all
mean as we look to the future
looking at the russia ukraine conflict
what everybody wants to know is how's
this going to turn out
and maybe there was a time when you
crunched enough numbers and you worked
really really hard you could make
reliable predictions
today
with these new conditions for modern
conflict we need to assume that reliable
predictions are really hard to make one
and we have to embrace the fact that we
live in the world of conditional
probabilities
now anyone hear a poker player
anyone so i play texas hold'em try to as
often as i can i don't like omaha
but you know what makes a great poker
player right it's someone who's mastered
the concept of conditional probabilities
and that's the world that we live in
except the velocity is changing the
cards are being dealt much more quickly
some cards are dealt face up some are
dealt face down but every single card
changes the outcome of any given hand
and requires us to reassess our next
move
and great poker players don't just play
their hand they don't just play the
cards they play the player
today
we're playing russia and putin
their game is aggressive but it's loose
that changes the outcome
the next hand might be against
beijing and xi they play an entirely
different game their game is disciplined
it's professional and it's tight
and they're playing to win the world
tournament
and you can bet that they will reassess
as every card is dealt
in 1945 eisenhower's genius in planning
for d-day was recognizing the fact that
plans don't survive first contact with
the enemy his willingness to adapt to
the situation on the ground unlike say
the french and their maginot line was
the difference between victory and
defeat for the allies
when we don't adapt our thinking
when we suffer failures of imagination
horrible things can happen
when the first world trade center
bombing happened in 1993
we assumed that it was an exception and
that it would never happen again
these dangerous embedded assumptions we
hold on to
get in the way of our ability to be
agile and to adapt it's how we miss the
japanese plantain to attack pearl harbor
it's how we miss the rise of populism
it's how we dismiss the viability of a
trump candidacy over and over again it's
how we miss the threat that al qaeda
represented to the homeland
agile software development is a
methodology that allows us to code with
a mindset of continuous adaptability we
will have to mirror this mindset of
systemic experimentation
with agile conflict response
and we have to make sure that we reduce
unnecessary friction in decision making
as we move toward an agile and adaptive
decision-making model including in how
we organize in the us government
general nakasoni who's the commander of
cyber command and director of nsa
recently testified to con to congress
that the unity of effort is critical in
defending our nation
enabling the speed and agility necessary
to meet the strategic challenges posed
by our adversaries
we have great early examples of this the
russia small group was a coordinated
effort between nsa and cyber command
that effectively interrupted russian
interference
efforts with the 2018 midterm elections
those lessons were carried forward to
the 2020 elections which they also
effectively protected
in the russia-ukraine conflict we have
adapted our approach to intelligence and
it has paid off tremendously
historically the intelligence community
held onto its collections very tightly
it was very close we classify them and
we limit disclosure to a very small
group of allies and and that happens for
a really good reason by sharing
intelligence you reveal sources and
methods and you risk putting people at
risk and losing access that's by
definition very hard to get and very
hard to maintain
real-time disclosure of classified
information which is what we've done in
this war is a stunning change in policy
by disclosing specifics about troop
locations about coup attempts about
false flag operations the united states
was able to claim a first mover
advantage in the information war space
and by doing that we pre-bonked putin's
attempts at misinformation and
disinformation we informed the public
which has changed the dynamics of this
conflict we mobilized the ukrainian
public we shored up faltering alliances
and made it really hard for countries
and organizations to stay on the
sideline and get away with just making
performative statements
we fundamentally changed the extent of
the sanctions that were imposed we armed
the war fighters with the information
they needed to defend their homeland and
we've potentially deterred certain
actors and certain actions
we not only showcase our incredible
intelligence community capabilities but
how those capabilities with a different
approach can quickly change the
situation on the ground
looking at the situation on the ground
ukraine is
so massively outmatched and outmanned
from a traditional military perspective
from their troops that their soldiers
they're outmatched four to one their air
force is outmatched 13-1 their navy is
outmatched 16-1 putin's assumption that
this was going to be a three-day war
wasn't wrong from a traditional military
perspective
but this isn't a traditional war
this is a modern war where cyber
technology social media and data and
intelligence
some of it from government sources
but much of it
distributed decentralized and privatized
has enabled a new set of conditions
where with constant experimentation
amazingly ukraine stands a chance
in this world of decentralized
distributed and privatized
agile conflict response interesting
things can happen let's organize an army
of hackers this can happen either in
coordination with the government or not
in this case it was in coordination with
the ukrainian government
some 400 000 multinational hackers have
joined forces to support ukraine's
effort by the way that's twice the
number of soldiers in ukraine's army
let's use twitter to share lists of
russian and belarusian targets
and just in case you're wondering
whether a hacker army can actually make
a difference don't forget that one
really really angry hacker managed to
take down north korea's entire albeit
limited internet
a hacker army can represent significant
power that is immensely relevant in the
context of modern conflict
and the next conflict is sure to be
different
you can be sure that our adversaries are
watching this war play out and taking
away lessons just as we are
china is not only watching russia and
all of their missteps they're not only
watching ukraine and all of their early
successes
they are watching how the u.s
plays its hand
and what kind of player we intend to be
on the world stage
after watching how the u.s military
performed during operation desert storm
the chinese government realized it had
to overhaul its approach to military
and move from a from a conventional
military mindset to an informationalized
military mindset the lessons from this
conflict will be different
whether it's the effectiveness of drones
whether it's the fundamental issues with
having a conscript army
or whether it's the importance of not
ceding this cyberspace or information
war space you can be sure that beijing
will not make the same mistakes that the
kremlin has
our adversaries will learn
they will adapt and modern warfare will
evolve again
now i want to end where i started the
velocity of change in society is
accelerating at a pace that outstrips
our ability as humans to adapt and to
gain mastery there was a time when we
had centuries to adapt to new
technologies the printing press took 200
years to have global reach the
industrial revolut the agricultural
revolution also took 200 years the
industrial revolution was 100 years
today
arguably we have four simultaneous
revolutions going on we have the energy
revolution we have the ai quantum
revolution we have the biology
revolution and we have the media
revolution and it gets even more complex
in addition to all this technological
upheaval we're going through a period of
intense social change with growing rifts
in society
from social justice and income inequity
to climate change a global pandemic the
decline of democracy and freedom
the rise of authoritarianism and
populism and economic crises around the
globe around the globe
these are seams in society that are ripe
to being exploited in altogether new and
devastating ways leading to forms of
conflict that we're entirely unprepared
for
to protect the values we believe in to
protect freedom and democracy we must be
creative and agile with an altogether
new way of looking at technology and its
impact on society on international
conflict and international relations and
guess what
whether you want to be or not
you guys are the front-line forces
you're protecting our systems you're
protecting our data you're protecting
our people you're protecting our
organizations and yeah you're protecting
freedom and democracy
and you can bet that the next adversary
we face
is taking the lessons from this war to
heart
i hope you guys do as well thank you