foreign
perspective today on organizational
maturity
specific to OT cyber security
now you're probably wondering what
exactly does that mean
well it means a lot of different things
to a lot of people but most importantly
to the leaders they can answer a couple
different things one what happens when
there's a cyber breach not if but when
what are the true impacts and risks to
the organization
who's fixing what
and most importantly where's the return
on the invested products and security
services that were just deployed
several things that the pandemic taught
us
was that expect the unexpected and that
change Could Happen very rapidly
it thrusted digital transformation into
our OT environments like never before
regardless of your belief system around
the word digital transformation
workforces were thrusted into a remote
situation all the while businesses still
having to deliver their product and
services and just like that change
happened rapidly
evolving threats as you're here today
listening to them unfold happen and are
actually becoming more real than they
ever have is it because of the political
instability probably so and we're faced
with having to evolve and change and
respond in a rapid manner
all of this is creating instability
across the world and thus instability is
creating fear uncertainty and doubt and
because our world is changing so rapidly
our mindset must change as well
now I know you're probably looking at
this picture here and for some it might
be familiar for some it might be funny
and some might be wow I recognize this
guy
he's our friendly I.T guy that's now on
the shop floor maybe it's the new CIO
with no OT experience
maybe it's the governance Assurance
teams asking questions of our OT
operators and Engineers on what do they
have here what are the risks and what's
important in this environment
for some these individuals give you
pause as a OT practitioner
why because they're not OT they don't
understand non-productive time loss of
life health and safety hazards
perhaps we can train them and change our
mindset to rely on them because in the
end it really does take a village to
combine business I.T and OT together to
answer those answer those fundamental
questions on Where is our risk and what
is our impact but most importantly a
mindset change so that we can create a
sustainable maturity in our organization
so I'll give you a quick brief history
lesson here on resiliency and how change
made an impact
it's World War II London's under attack
by German Air Raids government thought
for sure London was over and to expect
the worst
you want to know what their incident
response plan was to expect more daily
Air Raids to expect hundreds of
thousands of deaths to expect the
hospitals to be overworked and just
crumble and sure enough chaos would then
ensue
but what really happened
well leadership stepped up and Winston
Churchill instituted a memo each day
called activate memo daily and he asked
and called upon all leaders to do one
impactful thing each day
he also asked and demanded that we all
work together as they were underground
having no choice and left to learn and
lean on each other
he reminded everybody to smile and that
to realize this was a process
but most importantly to have a moral
purpose a moral purpose to survive
London's World War II and the aftermath
is Art critical infrastructure today
while they stayed up night wondering if
bombs were hitting their homes their
businesses and and perhaps result in
death that's us at night as OT
practitioners wondering when the next
cyber threat is going to impact our
environment and how will we respond
but I rest easy because as London
demonstrated the will to preserve and
survive so too will our industry of OT
practitioners
have and will have and demonstrate a
resolve to mature that is why we're all
here today isn't it to learn to mature
so what's holding us back
well regardless if you're an
organization that may have a Federated
decentralized management model meaning
you at the business level at the
operations level own your budget own
your smes are responsible for your
output perhaps you have limited
resources not enough smes with OT
experience to understand and translate
cyber we've seen an influx of
non-technical non-ot cyber professionals
enter this realm
maybe it's all the processes or the lack
of all the regulator requirements you're
cus you're dealing with customer
requirements board of directors asking a
lot of questions and maybe you have too
much technology that you don't know how
to translate and make sense of it
or maybe you're the opposite and your
organization is leading the evolution in
a shared service model where they
recognize that no longer at the
operations level is it just their
responsibility to secure their own
environments perhaps it's a shared model
where organizations at the top
leadership at the top create resources
it just may not be in the shape or the
form that we expect and want them to
it's going to be a collective unit of
individuals that are all after the same
goal and that is to secure critical
infrastructure and perhaps they're
coming with their latest pen and paper
with the latest framework asking 100
questions
but those questions will help identify
where the risks are what's in place and
what's not and then hopefully that
technology that's in place can be
translated and communicated up to the
board level on what the technical risk
is
so
how did we get here and where did the
market influence us along the way
well I have to go back to the early
2000s when we saw an influx of Ip based
asset equipment make its way an entrance
into our PCN scada critical
infrastructure environments I'm talking
about the IP drilling chairs on your
high-spec drilling rigs I'm talking
about the dynamic positioning and
Wastewater Management systems that are
all translating data back onshore I'm
talking about those IP digitized cranes
that are installed at the latest
terminal in ports all of that Digital
Data made way for the guardian solutions
that entered into the market and for
once in a long time we had visibility on
what actually existed
and then it created a visibility around
the vulnerabilities at the node and IP
level
and for our OT practitioners that were
installing it and thought this was the
best day ever they soon realized that
they didn't really understand the full
breadth of the cyber security posture
for which this information was now
telling us how were those OT
professionals to translate the actual
technical risk on up to dollars that the
company just invested
that made way for the service industry
boom so that industrial critical
infrastructure focused organizations
could come in and make sense and
translate this information
so what's next for the industry how do
they get that information at the
technical level up to the boardroom so
that it creates a holistic view of
technical risk and business risk
well it starts with assessments now I
know what you're thinking assessments is
a bad dirty word but the truth about it
is that everybody is doing them and
specific the asset owners the asset
owners are doing assessments each and
every day whether it's through the I.T
Department the business departments or
on the OT floor and they're doing it for
a couple of reasons they have to
communicate up on the current state of
their Union and demonstrate a path
forward to maturity
and most importantly it gives them a
road map of their buying habits of what
to buy next
and if they don't have resources
internally they're going to lean on our
consultant friends our organizations our
vendors that have the expertise on hand
that can come in and showcase a
demonstrated methodology and progression
to a successful maturing Organization
for cyber security
but what you don't realize that they're
starting with assessments and ending
with assessments and so too are the OT
focused products even though they claim
that they're not doing assessments they
start with an assessment why because the
leader wants to know where the return on
investment is if your current state
without their solution is X today where
is the current state for with their
solution tomorrow it starts and ends
with an assessment
so if we're going to do assessments we
should do them right and at the end of
the day we are all just spokes on a
wheel supporting our asset owners to a
level of maturity and desired state for
cyber security
because whoever owns the ass the
assessment is the gatekeeper the
gatekeeper for purchasing power the
gatekeeper for maturity of cyber
security
now I know what you're thinking there's
still probably some naysayers around
assessments because those are viewed and
an internal belief system is that they
are a snapshot in time that they're not
Dynamic enough but Innovation can prove
otherwise on that topic but let's just
say okay we're not going to invest in
assessments and we're going to lean on
the guardian Solutions and the technical
equipment that we've installed how's
that working for you in terms of
Bridging the Gap of your technical
insights into the impacts and the risks
for the business
perhaps you've through acquisition have
ended up with multiple solutions that
are outputting technical risk not only
in CVS scores but CVSs vprs they all
have their own threat
um
algorithms that decipher what the truth
threat is based on the vulnerabilities
at the node points how are you bringing
that together and communicating the true
risk it's probably pretty challenging I
know from the field it is so perhaps you
bring in your Consulting groups that can
bridge that Gap
but really is it ever is it their
responsibility
to bridge that Gap or is it the
challenge of the asset owners to improve
internally and bring in additional
information
so if you're going to do assessments you
should do them right
now I know you're probably thinking wow
where do I start I have every regulation
recommending a certain standard a
guidance and I also have my clients
pushing down our throats their own
internal requirements where do I start
it can be extremely overwhelming
especially if you have limited staff and
your day job is to keep product moving
and prevent loss of life and prevent
health and safety risks you don't have
time for this and so perhaps there are
some resources that are tasked to do
this again remember it takes a village
it's not just the OT practitioner's
responsibility to do this
so with all these Frameworks with all
these recommendations where do you start
what do you pick
whatever you pick wherever you start you
should be aiming to answer a couple
simple things what's my recovery time
what is the true impact what standard is
going to allow me to move from point A
to B on my maturity what threats is this
really going to disclose these are a lot
of great questions that these Frameworks
should do but most importantly the
framework is supposed to create a common
syntax language that the organization
can get around so they can track
progression
so in order to do that effectively it
takes a village itot and the business
working together in a certain layer of
capacity and to do that there are
different assessment models that lend to
that visibility to that holistic
approach to risk and identifying impacts
starting with business impact analysis
at the highest most level it's going to
disclose what are the financial impacts
the risks as well as help you prioritize
what assets to even begin your journey
on maturing your cyber security for and
then you have your Gap assessments also
known as framework base those are going
to allow you to create a baseline after
you've scoped out which assets are
important to the business and align
against a certain set of Frameworks
requirements and controls and help you
communicate effectively across business
lines and we usually see this around I.T
governance teams really getting engaged
and involved at the OT level with this
type of approach business impact we
typically see more on the business side
it can come out of the finance
department it can come out of the
marketing department whichever
department is really responsible and
having resources for that and then
lastly it's the component assessment
also known as equipment we typically see
this in the field and at the OT level
why because these types of assessments
are down to the equipment level the sub
function and having a really depth
breadth understanding of the real threat
scenarios as it relates to the hazards
the safety risks as well as the
mitigating controls it takes a layer of
expertise to dive into that
so where do we start again diving into
the Bia business impact analysis you're
that sizzo you're that leader that has
come in and have been asked by the
president what assets if impacted would
produce non-productive time loss of
Revenue loss of life and you probably
don't know where to start the business
impact is really going to give you good
visibility into what assets those
actually pertain to
think of the latest breach that happened
last year all of a sudden boards were
asking are we subjected to ransomware
and if so what dependencies exist in our
environments business impacts analysis
started becoming extremely popular in
the past couple years to answer those
questions besides it produces some
pretty good visuals red green yellow and
what executive doesn't love and
understand red green yellow
so some of the pros around that is it
really Bridges the gap between the
business side and operations and it
starts that layer of communication to
understanding what's important because
not all assets are created the same
some of the challenges with the Bia
really resolve around the scenarios that
are used in the likelihood of an actual
incident and it is pretty subjective
based on who's doing them and it does
take some time to understand of all
assets where to really begin and execute
on a Bia
and so we typically see this on the
lower scale of maturity of organizations
and when I mention a maturity it's not
based on their revenue it's really
around the resources and the activities
that they're doing to move the needle of
cyber security holistically throughout
the organization
by the time we get to framework
assessments this is really the
industry's sweet spot right now this is
really where an organization is aligning
to a given standard or framework around
a standard taxonomy language of controls
these controls are typically mapped to
requirements oftentimes nist base ISO
IEC and some of the challenges around
implementing framework assessments is
that depending if you're a global
organization you probably have mandates
that transcend U.S requirements you have
requirements that transcend your clients
assets and requirements and how do you
bring it all together what starts with
centralizing and picking a single
framework to bridge that Tech sound and
we Gap and so once that's done you can
start to align your teams between
business and it and OT together around a
Common Language and this allows you to
communicate upward and downward to your
operations teams effectively
the time allocation is somewhat High
because as you know and are familiar
with some of these Frameworks they can
be several hundred requirements just in
one and it takes a lot of hurting of the
cats to get everybody in a room and
answer these questions and then what do
you do with these with these
requirements you all you can identify
the missing gaps you can map threats you
can map risks and this starts to paint a
holistic picture around your risk
posture when it comes to people process
and technology and we haven't forgotten
about those technologies that are
plugged in and giving us insights
when it comes to a more mature art
organization we start to see component
assessments equipment layer assessments
again I would say this is a fewer than
one percent of organizations out there
doing this today and so the reason why
there's so few organizations doing
component level equipment is the
expertise that it takes to do this it
usually takes an OT cyber security
expert to really understand the network
topology of a given control environment
it takes an expert to understand what
controls should be in place what
mitigating controls already map and oh
by the way have a data repository of all
equipment and understand what specific
threat scenarios maybe five four cases
that are really relevant to that
environment and then start going through
a series of scenarios to really truly
identify the risks to that equipment or
sub-function level in a control
environment
this again is on the maturity Arc of
organizations and it's not very common
but those are the Innovative
organizations leading the way today
so when I go back to organizational
maturity we really see the industry
evolving into four distinct phases you
are either in a prepare a baseline an
accelerate or incorporate a phase and
I'm going to dive into each of those
here shortly but at its core if you're
in the prepare phase it has nothing to
do with the revenue of your organization
it really comes down to where you are
from a cyber security program within the
organizations and the resources that are
allocated to it you're typically
planning your journey by the time you've
gotten to the Baseline you've solidified
a framework that you want to try to
create a Common Language taxonomy around
you're aligning stakeholders and you're
establishing a plan of action when
you've transitioned to accelerate and
incorporate you've been doing your
program for a couple years and you've
worked out the bugs you know what
resources are needed
and you're ready for repeatable task and
Automation and by the time you get to
incorporate you've installed so many
technological solutions you've
Incorporated the bias and you're doing
framework assessments and you want and
you're ready for a holistic breadth of
information to sum up and answer those
four questions in the beginning
so perhaps this profile might fit you
those that are in the room that are new
to OT that are a sizzo that are a CIO
with no OT background there is no cyber
security program in place because it
didn't exist before then but you've been
brought in to figure it out your first
year will be spent trying to understand
the business the Enterprise risk
strategy trying to figure out what kind
of budget would even be necessary to
even start your program and most most
importantly getting buy-in from your
business units your operating Executives
your engineers really trying to Rally
them around creating this program and
most likely you're going to start with a
Bia because you don't even know what you
have so the Bia is going to tell you
what assets are most important to the
organization and then those would be
effectively your scope of assets that
transitions you into the Baseline
section by the time you've gotten to
Baseline again you've probably picked
out a framework maybe it's multiple
Frameworks because you're Global
organizations with assets all over the
world and you need to follow some rules
that are subjected to the UK or APAC
region and then you're figuring out how
to control and co-mingle all that
information but the most important part
of the being in the Baseline is that
you're doing assessments and you're
figuring out what exists you're
identifying controls that are specific
to your environment that are either
there or non-existent you're perhaps
sharing some of those insights across
the business unit because you need
support support to implement tools
support to train individuals because
perhaps that's a challenge in a gap but
most importantly you're building your
ecosystem of knowledge and awareness
by the time you're at accelerate this
program's probably been in place as I
mentioned five to eight years
anything below that you're still in
Baseline and that is really truly what
we're seeing from the field those that
are in cell an accelerate phase are
ready for automation they've been doing
the assessments they know what's missing
but the reality is you're not going to
get hundreds of millions of dollars for
your budget each year you're gonna have
to slice it up so that's why
organizations stay multiple years in
that baselining phase because you just
can't assess everything in one year you
just don't have the resources so it
takes several years to get to accelerate
where you finally have assessed
everything and now you know what is
missing and what kind of budget you need
to deploy to affect change
in accelerate you're also perhaps
working with your supply chain to really
understand and mandate requirements to
them because now you understand what you
have in your environment now you know
what's necessary and if you're going to
continue to do business you might as
well partner and make sure that they're
deploying secure assets as well so right
now you're collaborating with business
units and you're probably communicating
to the board so now this is getting
tracked at a quarterly basis so once you
start you can't stop kind of like
getting on that hamster wheel when
you're fundraising for your company
can't really stop
when you get to incorporate again I
mentioned you have a lot of Solutions in
place
you have integrated insights that you
want to co-mingle with framework
assessment outputs and perhaps you're
also pushing down your assessment
programs Downstream in a decentralized
manner because of automation
capabilities you're standing up
validation protocols and you're
incorporating additional specific
business contacts into the assessment
layer
so putting all three of these things
together what this really enables you as
Leaders is to answer those questions
what happens when we get breached what
is impacted that's your Bia where is our
real risk and what are we doing to fix
it those are your framework and GAP
assessments and what is the true threats
that are facing our organization today
that comes down to the equipment sub
component level understanding and when
you have all of that your organization
is maturing at a rate that is
sustainable and then of course things
are going to change
but just like things can change rapidly
for one country so can for this industry
in London's darkest days they thought it
was over but they persevered they did
impactful things each day as Leaders you
don't need the government to tell you
what to do or to wait for a framework to
come out or a client to send you a list
of requirements you action every day
it's the culture that you manifest
within your organization to do something
about it you have intense teamwork and
rally together like they did
and have some fun along the way I mean
we're all here in Miami enjoying this
weather aren't we and so lastly they had
a moral purpose to survive and just like
that they are a shining example of what
can be when working together comes
together
thank you
[Applause]