welcome everyone to the first ics for
ics exercise here at s4
i'm megan sanford vice president chief
product security officer for energy
management at schneider electric i'm
also the chair of the isa global cyber
security alliance i'm very happy to be
back here at s4 can we all say that
[Applause]
two years ago i presented the idea of
ics for ics at s4
isa gca has worked with over its 50
member companies and many volunteers
most of the people in this room they
have done the work it it wasn't me
um but we have developed this program uh
and a lot of preparation for the
exercise that you all are going to be a
part of today so thank you for that
this is the agenda for today i will
provide a brief ics for ics overview and
some key points from the ics for ics
training on the web we will then conduct
the exercise
we will take a break and then finish the
exercise your input
will be needed to help us improve the
ics for ics processes and future
exercises so please we appreciate the
feedback we appreciate the input
ics for ics combined
three mature processes to improve
management of cyber security incidents
that impact industrial control systems
the incident command system was created
in the 1970s and variations of the
process are used in numerous countries
cyber security teams leverage computer
incident response processes defined by
nist and other organizations to
investigate incidents minimize the
impact of incidents and provide
information needed by leadership that
enables them to quickly make decisions
that lead to quick resolution of
incidents
industrial control system experts
currently manage the technical aspects
of many types of incidents including
cyber security incidents their expertise
of their systems enabled them to
identify alternatives to recover
critical business functions they support
ics for ics combines these three
processes and leverages the unique
expertise of each group to expedite the
response and resolution of cybersecurity
incidents
industrial applications are used to
support various aspects of our everyday
lives electricity that powers our homes
offices and plants rely on industrial
control systems
water and water sewage also rely on
industrial control systems
we have seen how a single cyber security
incident impacted the regional supply of
gasoline that disrupted transportation
for numerous states in a single region
of the united states
various gases that power our lives also
rely on industrial control systems to
produce and deliver gases to consumers
building control systems are critical to
maintain offices and many apartments
throughout the world
manufacturing chemical and other plants
are completely dependent on industrial
control systems
incident command system for industrial
control systems ics for ics processes
are designed to help all these
industries manage incidents to minimize
the impact of critical infrastructure
services
nations around the world have developed
critical infrastructure protection
programs because of increasing threats
that can impact their citizens health
safety and economies we are seeing an
increased number of cybersecurity
incidents that disrupt critical
infrastructure this was demonstrated by
the colonial pipeline incident resulting
in supply disruption and price increases
of fuels for automobiles
there are numerous other
incidents that have disrupted critical
infrastructure throughout the world
ics for ics is designed to improve
response capabilities of companies
organizations and government agencies
that coordinate incident response of
cyber security incidents
cyber security capabilities are
are deployed to provide multiple layers
of protection there is no single cyber
defense measure there's no silver bullet
that can absolutely protect against
cyber attacks we rely on layers of cyber
security capabilities called defense in
depth the intent is to delay or
completely prevent an attack an attacker
must break through numerous layers to
successfully attack the environment
these layers include physical security
of assets and the components and systems
that are used to operate those assets
cyber security policies and procedures
including user training
zones and conduits separate network
segments with the protective device
anti-malware solutions prevent various
forms of malware from compromising the
environment
access controls are critical because
weak unauthorized access has caused
numerous cyber attacks
monitoring and detection helps quickly
identify potential attacks so immediate
action can be taken to limit their
consequence and prevent an event from
escalating into an incident
patching has remained an important
measure to prevent known vulnerabilities
in software
even if more than one of these layers of
protection fails the other layers are
designed to prevent or limit the impact
of attacks
most organizations have computer
incident response capabilities this
includes a plan and staff who are
trained and participate in regular
exercises to ensure they are ready to
respond to a cyber incident
detection of events is an important
aspect of any cyber security program
numerous events are identified by
detection tools and log messages from
application servers and network devices
a large company probably has millions of
events occurring daily
a security operations center analyzes
events to identify those that present a
potential risk and require further
investigation and possibly additional
action
the sock takes immediate actions to
contain events to prevent them from
causing additional negative consequences
they also eradicate the source of the
event and if necessary take actions to
restore data and systems
a post incident review is completed to
understand how these cert processes can
be improved and to retain evidence from
the event the security operations center
will escalate to a leader or executive
when an event meets documented criteria
the leadership team has a documented
procedure to determine when an event
should be declared an incident
along with the list of people authorized
to declare an incident that's a key
point
declaring an incident triggers several
processes and commits the company
financially and in many other ways
including triggering government
reporting
the security operations center continues
to perform the cert steps unless the
leadership team instructs them to take
other action
this high level representation of the
purdue model shows how industrial
control system components are organized
into layers that are isolated with
firewalls
the industrial control system is often
connected to the company enterprise
network by using a dmz to host
components shared by both the enterprise
network and the industrial control
system
the incident command system is very
mature and is used by numerous companies
to manage various events like fires
natural disasters and other industrial
incidents the process is often not used
for cyber incidents though
the incident command system is based on
pre-planning organizing and training
teams ensuring they have appropriately
they have appropriate equipment to
respond to incidents
exercises ensure that all staff are
prepared to fill their role and that the
incident command process and tools work
effectively and evaluation is completed
after each incident and exercise to
identify actions to improve ics for ics
processes
the incident command system is used
every day by first responders and is
part of the national incident management
system also known as nems nems was
mandated for the u.s government by
homeland security presidential directive
hspd5 issued in 2003.
the incident command system provides a
standard approach the coordination
process and management strategies are
the same for all responders regardless
of the incident of the type of incident
the system was born from decades of
emergency management activities which
makes it very effective
unity of command allows everyone to know
their role and who they report to
clarity of responsibilities is
accomplished because everyone is
assigned a role a title and a list of
tasks
span of control limits the number of
people and tasks a supervisor is
reasonable is reasonably able to manage
common terminology ensures that everyone
speaks the same language
adaptability means incident command is a
very flexible system it can be used for
in for an incident of any size and
complex and complexity it also can grow
or shrink based on the needs of the
incident
planned and unplanned events can be
managed by the incident command system
the system ensures there is no
duplication of efforts we don't want
multiple parties working on the same
task
accountability is easily achieved since
everyone is assigned a specific role
title task and duty therefore each
person is accountable for their own
actions
accountability during incident
operations is essential the ics
structural will need to abide by company
policies and guidelines as well as any
applicable laws and regulations
the incident command system has a
planning p process to manage all hazards
the planning cycle consists of the
detailed steps necessary to guide the
ics for ics team through the five phases
of the planning process to develop
disseminate implement and adjust an
incident action plan based on the
incident objectives
the all hazards planning cycle provides
a systematic standardized and effective
approach to organizing response to
incidents
after the initial response the planning
p defines the operational cycle which is
repeated the planning p operational
cycle likely will be repeated multiple
times even as a new shift of staff
arrives to man the effort
planning p provides structure by
prescribing the order in which meetings
or briefings occur
and identifying the person responsible
for collecting incident data and the
parties who will make decisions
and defining the actions and work
products that are assigned to each of
the ics for ics teams
we've developed a training video that
explains ics for ics and the incident
planning process if you have not seen
these videos you can view the training
by visiting the ics for ics website you
will receive a link to the website after
s4
i'm going to share information about the
ics for ics exercise and help everyone
understand the exercise scenario
the purpose of the exercise is to help
everyone understand the ics for ics
process that can be used to manage a
significant cyber incident
this exercise is designed to demonstrate
how ics for ics processes are initiated
when an event is identified as a
possible incident
engage ics for ics team members to
participate in response efforts
complete the initial assessment to
determine if the event will be declared
an incident
work to respond to the incident and
limit its impact to the business
demonstrate how key components of the
ics for ics program can manage incident
response
we hope that companies will incorporate
ics for ics program capabilities into
their company processes
ics for ics is focused on cyber
incidents that industrial control system
or other critical infrastructure
is or other critical infrastructure
operations we are performing the
exercise as a single company based on
assumptions of that company not the
individual companies of the people who
are playing the roles of the exercise
i want to briefly review the roles that
are part of the exercise
players are the people on the stage who
will fill the roles defined in the ics
for ics process
the facilitator is my role i will help
provide information and ensure the
exercise stays on track to achieve the
objectives
note takers will document the ics for
ics exercise activities and prepare for
feedback that can be used to improve the
ics for ics processes
observers you are in the audience you
will be asked to provide feedback during
the hot wash at the end of the exercise
we are conducting a facilitated exercise
there are many different types of
exercises but this is known as the
facilitated discussion it's laid back
it's informal and we're using this for
training
we are recording the exercise and we'll
publish the video in the next week
you will observe the players on stage as
they participate in threat briefing and
other meetings that are part of ics for
ics
the exercise is divided into two modules
with the first focus on the initial
activities that trigger the formation of
the ics for ics team and initial
response activities
the second will focus on how we manage
the response to a ransomware extortion
attempt and media inquiries
we will conclude this exercise by asking
you to participate in the hot wash that
will seek your input to improve the ics
for ics program and future exercises
this exercise is designed to help
everyone learn and to improve the ics
for ics program processes and future
exercises this exercise involved
multiple companies so we had to make
some assumptions about a fictional
company for this exercise
please accept the assumptions made in
the exercise scenario
this is often the first rule of
exercises do not fight the scenario
the purpose of the exercise is to learn
and not fix the scenario we have a
limited time for this exercise so we
must accept that not everything can be
achieved today
now we will discuss the specific
scenario that was defined for this
exercise
on day one dhs sisa alert is released
regarding phishing campaign compromising
networks and servers in the usa
on day five a local radio station has a
context and some of the company
employees reporting receiving an email
with the link to sign up
many employees report this as a
potential phishing attempt
one employee states
they click the link
on day 10 employees call facility
management to complain about it being
too hot in their offices facility staff
investigate and determine that the
sensors are reporting normal
temperatures
they contact the hvac vendor who agrees
to send a person on site
on day 11 at 9 35 a.m
a fire alarm in the building is
activated but fire department determines
that there is no fire
on day 11 at 10 a.m hvac staff who are
on site determine the system has been
compromised by malware
the vendor cannot contain or eradicate
the malware
on day 11 at 10 15 a.m
ics analysts for hvac contacts computer
incident response team to report that
malware has been detected in the hvac
system
on day 11 at 10 30 a.m the cert
escalates the event to the cert director
who is also the ics for ics incident
commander
at the end of the exercise we will
discuss your feedback related to what
were the strengths of the exercise and
suggestions to improve the ics for ics
processes and or future exercises
please share your thoughts during the
exercise by emailing or texting
brian will summarize them so we can
discuss at the end of the exercise so
grab grab that number grab that email
and send us your feedback
good afternoon everybody my name is mark
boddy and i will be your moderator for
this exercise
we've developed training videos that
explain the incident planning process if
you've not seen these videos you might
feel a little lost but don't worry we
will do our best to explain things as we
go along to view the training after this
exercise visit the ics for ics website
you will receive a link to the website
after this exercise
hello my name is eric peterson i'm the
ics control analyst
uh as yes as the ics control analyst i
would i know i was notified at 4 8 on
april 18 2022 at 9 35 a.m that the
temperatures in the office building
began to rise
building maintenance was unable to
resolve the situation so i contacted the
hvac vendor hvac personnel arrived
on april 18 2022 at 10 a.m and
determined that we had been compromised
on our systems with some type of malware
the vendor has not been able to contain
or eradicate the malware so he has no
solution and able to and not been able
to restore hvac system at 10 15 a.m i
contacted the computer incident response
team to report that the malware is
detected in the hvac system supporting
the building the data center and the
other industrial control systems in the
building based on the escalation process
i've contacted the assert manager
who will who declared an incident and
assigned an incident commander
company executive leadership is
organized as crisis management team they
have designated specific people to fill
the incident commander or ic role and
empowered them with the authority to
declare an incident a secondary or
tertiary ic will take the role and
assume the authorities if the primary ic
is not available or as the incident goes
into multiple operational periods
the incident commander is responsible
for the overall management of the
incident they will determine the ics for
ics command and general staff positions
necessary to manage the incident
their primary goals are to ensure life
safety incident stabilization and
environmental preservation is maintained
during the team's incident response
after the incident commander identifies
who will be part of the ics for ics
command and general staff admin staff
will notify them and pass on response
and traveling information
so my name is mark bristow and i'm the
incident commander
my priority is to do an initial
assessment with the staff who are on
site at the scene and working with them
to understand where we are right now and
what resources i'm going to need to uh
to manage the incident so i speak with
eric who's the ics analyst in this
exercise to understand the current
situation and what options we might have
to be able to contain or eradicate the
malware that's impacting the hvac system
i get information from eric so i can
prepare what's called an ics 201
incident briefing form we'll get more on
that in a second
and this is going to help the ics for
ics team understand the situation
instruct the ics analyst to continue to
do the work that they were doing with
the hvac vendor to investigate and look
for other alternatives to restore
operations and i contact the executive
leadership team in the company
to let them know that you know if
they're part of the crisis management
team or cmt
what's going on keep them informed and
any escalations that i might need uh
with the cmt
so only certain uh company executives uh
and people designated as instant
commanders are uh given the authority in
this construct uh to actually declare an
incident so as the incident commander i
see i'm going to number one determine
which ics for ics positions i need um
and see if the executive leaders is part
of the crisis management team have
recommendations for people to fill those
positions they almost always do uh
activate the ics for ics positions
needed uh from my perspective for this
incident
and determine what messages uh um we
need to have and keep the uh crisis
management team up to date on the ics
for ics teams progress as we go through
the incident
the command staff are physicians who
report directly to the incident
commander and support the entire
organization these positions include the
public information officer who is
responsible for managing external and
internal communications the safety
officer who is responsible for ensuring
the safety of all staff including those
who may be impacted by the incident and
the ics for ics team
legal counsel helps develop contracts
that may be needed by the ics for ics
team reviews external communications and
any other legal functions and the
liaison officer would interface with
external parties like law enforcement
agencies
the general staff are section chiefs who
are who also report directly to the
incident commander each of them lead
staff in their sections and are
accountable for specific work products
the section chiefs fill any roles that
have not been staffed below them
the finance administration section chief
is responsible for managing all
financial aspects of an incident
logistics provides all incident support
needs such as medical food
transportation housing ordering
resources etc
the planning section chief is
responsible for managing all information
relevant to the incident response they
collect evaluate process and disseminate
information for use by responders at the
incident
and the operations section chief is
responsible for managing all tactical
operations of the incident
so as is commander as i mentioned it's
my job to determine which roles we need
right so i'm going to need an operations
section chief to actually manage the
cyber security and response team efforts
right which are all thinking of instant
response but that's not the whole
picture that's why ics for ics exists
right i'm going to need to staff some
other positions right away
but i may choose as the incident evolves
to to staff more positions as we go
right and so i'm going to see based on
what's going on so but for right now um
you know i'm going to need an admin
finance second chief right we have to
pay for all of this and do accounting
and that needs to start from day one so
that's a that's a priority for me in
addition to operations uh i'm clearly
going to need a planning section chief
it's going to help actually manage this
incident and make sure that we're doing
everything
and that's going to get data to the
operation section chief and help them
get what they need for the ir activities
um
really important one i need a public
information officer or pio uh to manage
public relations if you think you can
keep it quiet you went you can't so
always be planning for that right and
then of course i need a safety officer
it's control systems people to ensure
the safety of the staff uh in any of the
impacted offices and really importantly
of the ics for ics team members
themselves right first rule of instant
response is don't become a victim right
so each section chief is going to
request some resources for their
sections and they might create a
structure below them for some unileaders
to manage sub-teams to accomplish
specific tasks or something like that
so um you know as i mentioned as the ic
i'm going to answer to the the crisis
management team of the cmt right and
typically in a company context that's
going to be the executive leaders of the
company right the command and general
staff that i've activated though they
report to me right and only me
they might come from different parts of
the organization that's why on the
graphic hopefully you're seeing some
dashed lines that show the relationship
of their positions and their day jobs
right but for the purpose of this
incident they report to me right buck
stops here
so for example here the admin finance
section chief's day job is that might be
the cfo but for this incident they
report to me for all matters related to
this incident
so after consulting with the cmt i've
appointed the following people to to
these uh different positions that we
have right so the operations uh section
chief is going to be ghanda lambernick
uh the planning section teef is gonna be
neokay
uh the admin finance section chief is
gonna be like cheney uh the safety
officer is gonna be philip kosh the pio
is gonna be uh anne marie van der hoerk
and the industrial control system
analyst as we've already heard in adults
is eric peterson
once the incident commander has a handle
on the current situation she or he will
transfer their notes to the first page
of the 201 incident briefing form
they will provide this form to the
incoming team members so they can hit
the ground running if there is no time
or very limited resources the ics-201
will be hand-written in a sketch
free-handed
for this exercise we've created a formal
ics 201 form to make it easier for you
to read and follow along
you can also use your tablet or cell
phone camera to scan the qr code to
download the ics 201 incident briefing
and a copy
we had a long chat about this
in in real incidents we actually use
these to great effect
with those caveats so but you can do
this this goes to google drive mine
uh if you want to capture copy that
we'll have one for the incident action
plan later
so uh as insect commander if you've
chosen to click the qr code and you
should it's safe i promise
so i'm going to update the the 201
incident briefing form to create an
incident name put give it a number or
potentially use the number from the
ticketing system
if it came from the the computer
incident response team as this one did
um and you know put in the date and time
you know basic logistics that you might
overlook this is why forms are helpful
people yeah
good next slide
right so um i asked the uh industrial
control systems analyst to provide us a
visual that will help with the scope of
this incident right and so the visuals
is one thing that uh is an area where
there's a little bit of distinction from
uh traditional instant command system uh
in my view right so in this uh graphic
right it's gonna show the the different
things in the facility et cetera
normally in like a disaster management
you're gonna have like a physical map of
the area of the disaster right or or if
you're like a sector commander your
particular area right but uh for uh ics
for ics right the logical environment
may be just as important or more
important than the physical environment
it really kind of all depends uh what's
needed right so having some type of
picture though really helps everyone get
on the same page which is one of the key
elements of the ics 201 is to make sure
everyone has the same understanding so
yeah we might have a logical diagram if
it was impacting multiple buildings
perhaps we'd have a picture of the
different buildings it was impacting
multiple buildings over multiple just
geographic areas perhaps we'd have those
maps too right but you kind of have to
figure out what visual suits the
scenario and use that to help everyone
have that shared understanding so i'm
also going to update the situation
summary and health and safety briefing
section and this is to get the make sure
that we have any health and safety
hazards
that are documented and give the safety
officer
here a leg up on what they're going to
need to make sure that we're providing
ppe or whatever to our our personnel as
they they do the response right so
that's part of my job as we boot up the
incident
in a large incident it's possible that a
unified command will be necessary for
incident management
for example if a cyber security incident
causes a fire or spill representatives
from all agencies involved such as
company representatives responding fire
department epa or anybody else would
form a unified command making decisions
as a group and they would designate a
single public facing represented to be
the voice of the unified command in our
case a unified command is not needed
therefore this meeting will not occur
now that the initial response phase is
over we are entering the circular
planning cycle this phase is continuous
and ongoing for the duration of the
response the cycle of planning
activities will be repeated based on the
chosen operational period typically in a
very dynamic situation the planning p is
repeated every 12 hours so the teams can
get feedback from the operations folks
and still have time to do their work
before the next set of planning meetings
in a very low key incident an
operational period may be every 24 hours
a lap around the planning p is
considered one operational period
the current team staffing the ics for
ics team will have to be relieved after
some number of hours so they can get
some sleep the ic has determined the
operational period for this incident
will be 12 hours from 0 600 to 1800 and
1800 to 0-600 at 1800 the current team
will brief their replacements and be
backed by 0 600 in the morning to start
the next operational period
now we're into the racetrack of the
planning p and we start with the
incident command or unified command have
a meeting to develop or update
objectives this is also called a
strategy meeting the priorities and
objectives will first address life
safety needs based on the specific
incident we must ensure the safety of
our staff and the communities where we
operate
stabilizing the situation is the next
priority which enables the ics for ics
team to work the incident in a stable
environment and allows the business to
stabilize their operations while the ics
for ics team works to resolve the
incident
and the third priority is minimizing
adverse environmental impacts from the
incident the ics for ics team will work
together with a goal of managing the
immediate environmental impacts
potentially caused by the incident
at this meeting the objectives are
developed and are identified and the ic
determines the following what are the
response priorities is it life safety an
issue is it to get the industrial
control systems back online is it public
information
or is it something else or some things
else
limitations and constraints of the
response limitations might be will the
union object to longer hours
will the local community object to noise
after 11 pm
a limitation can be anything which can
limit response activities
constraints what is going to make the
response activities impossible a
hurricane is about to strike the city
heavy rain makes working on electrical
devices in the open dangerous
or severe cold working outside is out of
the question
the local mayor said no matter what no
response activities can take place until
the organization makes a fully disclosed
public statement about what is happening
critical incident requirements or cirs
are identified and delivered to the team
what type of information the incident
commander wants to know in the middle of
the night versus what type of
information can wait until the next
scheduled meeting
this is an example of a meeting or
briefing room layout visual aids are
placed on the front wall all meetings
will have a ground rules and agenda
visual the rest of the visuals are
dependent on the meeting or the needs of
the presenters
presenters will be lined up in order of
their presentation along the sides so
they can quickly move up to the front
when it is time for their presentation
a flip chart on an easel with markers at
the front of the room is helpful for
notes and ad-hoc items attendees
positions will be clearly marked in
their seats desk cards or by wearing
specific position vests
ground rules are typically the same
incident to incident these are some
common ground rules silence phones
radios and pagers unless it involves
life safety at which point take it
outside
and come back into the meeting when the
situation has been resolved no text
messages or emails again unless it
involves eye safety take it outside deal
with it then come back in
no sidebar conversations
stick to the agenda
presenters will be lined up off to the
side and order their
in order of their presentation so they
can quickly get to the front as in this
visual
the planning section chief usually runs
meetings and will call the chiefs by
name or position
when presenting the presenter needs to
be up front with visual aids facing the
audience and must speak loud and clearly
so that everyone in the meeting can hear
six hold all questions comments and
concerns until after the meeting the
only exception to this is the command
and general staff meeting questions and
concerns must be addressed in this
meeting
so every member of the team is on the
same page and finally number seven
maintain covet protocol if applicable
hello my name is neil gay and i'm the
planning section chief i facilitate this
meeting and typically present draft
objectives for the incident commander's
consideration the incident commander
will identify and or review response
priorities constraints and incident
objectives
so it's my job as the innocent commander
to establish incident objectives that
drive our incident operations right
these objectives are used to ensure that
everyone in the ics for ics organization
has clear understanding of what we are
trying to do and what needs to be
accomplished so for me for right now the
top three priorities for this incident
are going to be again life safety
incident stabilization and property
environmental preservation
establishing incident objectives is done
using management by objectives which
includes establishing smart objectives
as for specific a detailed explanation
of what we want to accomplish
m measurable what metrics are we going
to use to confirm we've met the
objective
a achievable the task at hand must be
possible
relevant the objective must help solve
the problem and t time bound we must set
up a realistic time frame to accomplish
the tasks necessary to meet our
objectives
so i developed these objectives for the
incident with input from others and
documented into that ics 201 incident
briefing form we talked about earlier
right we're going to review these
objectives at the next meeting and i'll
update the objectives based on as the
incident changes right things change
objectives change
the command and general staff meeting
may be the only time during this
operational period when all members of
the team are in the same room
this is the time for the ic command
staff and the general staff who are the
section chiefs to ask questions this
meeting is an open environment where
staff can near dirty laundry and ask
questions to clear the air
the ic defines the length of the
operational period that will determine
when this meeting will reoccur which
also determines the timing for the other
planning p meetings the planning section
chief will lead this meeting normally
this meeting will be repeated on the
established 12-hour cycle but the
planning section chief may schedule the
meetings more frequently or schedule
ad-hoc meetings as requested by the ic
the ic establishes the organization to
remind section chiefs that they are
responsible for performing actions
within their section for positions that
have not been staffed
as the planning section chief i'm
facilitating this command and general
staff meeting for our incident we'll
have at least one command and general
staff meeting every operational period
the ic mark decided on a 12-hour
operational period so i'll schedule
additional command and general staff
meetings if the ic requests them this is
the time for the command and general
staff to ask any questions the goal of
the meeting is to ensure that this team
agrees and can begin performing their
assigned functions there must be no
unanswered questions or ambiguity after
this meeting please review the ground
rules on the board which apply to all
meetings i'll start an ics 233 incident
open action tracker using a blank flip
chart on an easel up front mark as the
ic would you like to make any opening
statements or provide additional
information thanks neil and thanks
everyone for coming and responding to
this incident as neil mentioned it is
critical that we all leave this meeting
with shared understanding of what's
going on so if anyone has any questions
or concerns or you're not sure about
anything we talk about here voice them
now so that we're on the same page as we
go out for the next operational period
thanks i've posted a meeting scheduled
on the board using an informal ics 230
meeting schedule form you hear a lot of
forms today all of them are not
available by qr codes but if you go to
the fema website and look up any ics
form you're going to find it that's the
value of having all these forms already
pre-done for you
i've also posted multiple copies around
the incident command post to ensure the
command and general staff see it
when setting the meeting schedule the
timing between meetings must allow
enough time for the staff to complete
their work assignments and have their
products ready for the next upcoming
meeting
i've also started an ics-233 incident
open action tracker you see an example
on the board
i'm responsible for maintaining this
actions tracker and typically utilize a
documentation unit leader to assist me
in updating and or developing it i will
ensure all command and general staff are
prepared to discuss their assigned tasks
or actions during the command and
general staff and planning meetings when
it's completed i'll duplicate the form
and get copies to the command and
general staff it's also going to be
posted on the status board located at
the incident command post
so this is our initial ics for ics org
chart i didn't activate several
positions and we'll decide later if we
actually need them as the incident uh
progresses
please be prepared to recommend
positions you believe should uh should
be added to this chart
in the meantime the responsibility for
unstaffed positions are going to fall to
the section chief that those roll up to
so ganda you're gonna have to represent
all the positions in your operations
section until we fill people uh to fill
those positions
these are the objectives that uh we set
out to to drive our work right again
it's critical that we have clear
understanding of all these objectives so
if you have questions please ask them
right so number one is going to be the
safety of our people uh in our
facilities
and the people working in the ics for
ics team philip as the as a safety
officer this is going to be your primary
focus and the entire ics for ics team is
going to be there to support you to make
sure that we have a safe response effort
managing media and and public relations
is also incredibly critical right so ann
marie as the the public information
officer this is going to be your primary
focus um the entire team is going to
make themselves and the information that
they have available to help you form
that messaging strategy
um you know we need to make sure that we
we have that proper relationship with
our stakeholders right and so um i'm
going to be performing the role of the
liaison officer who's going to be going
out working with other stakeholders
stakeholders including the uh the crisis
management team to ensure they have all
the information that they need to know
not what they think they need to know uh
to quickly resolve the incident uh and
you know pass other information on to
other stakeholders like investor
relations um you know it's an important
objective to also determine you know how
we're gonna actually you know fix the
incidents right we need to contain
mitigate and eradicate this malware
that's causing incidents so ghana as the
operations section chief this will be
the the core of your effort
as the planing section chief i
facilitate the command and general staff
meeting for our incident we'll only have
one command and general staff meeting
per operational period but in a real
incident the ic incident commander may
request the planning section chiefs
schedule more of these meetings this may
be the only time during the current
operational period when all members of
the team are in the same room
this is the time to ask any questions
the ic might need to clarify there must
be no unanswered questions or ambiguity
after this meeting we also set the
meeting schedule for today and the
incident duration and i'll start an ics
233 incident open action tracker
my name is mike chaney and i am the
finance section chief mark i would like
to ask you as a commander
what is the spending limit for this
incident
thanks mike so as the ic i'm gonna set a
spending limit that matches the
delegation authority that i have which
is uh 500 000
so uh please make sure you work with the
other sector chiefs to develop a provost
budget for this incident and if we need
additional funding that exceeds my
delegation of authority
i'll go back to the cmt and get that
authorization my name is anne marie
vandenherk i am the public information
officer
i need to know if i have the ic
permission to prepare and release public
media messages and make statements
without clearing each media contact with
you first
i will work with corporate public
affairs on messaging and i will obtain
the appropriate approvals before issuing
any messages
i will share all communications with
this team at the next meeting
so thanks emory i approve you uh of
developing those communications without
getting additional approval from myself
as long as you get approval from
corporate public affairs
for those messages please though make
sure that you disseminate that
information as you mentioned to the
entire team so they can make use of that
information as well
so um at this meeting so i'm going to be
briefing uh everybody kind of on the
length the operational period the
objectives etc right and and the org
chart right so we already set it for 12
uh for uh 12 hours this can be the
operational period uh and then you know
we already talked about how the
organizations could be set up uh and
then how the resources are going to flow
right so for example
this would be the time when uh section
chiefs might propose to create sub teams
that kind of stuff we would have that
conversation at this meeting and
incorporated as appropriate
this is a block of time specifically for
the operations section chief to prepare
for the tactics meeting the operations
section chief creates a draft tactical
plan and orders any personnel and
equipment that are immediately necessary
for ongoing response
the ics-213 resource request form is
used to request those resources during
this time the operations section chief
will develop strategies to minimize the
impact and ultimately resolve the
incident
they will also define the structure of
the operations section into groups teams
and task forces
the operation section chief also
prepares the ics-215 operational
planning worksheet that defines a number
of available and required resources
during the next operational period they
will get help from the resources unit
leader or in the absence of one from the
planning section chief the safety
officer shadows the operations section
chief and prepares the ics-215a the
incident action plan safety analysis
form to identify and mitigate possible
safety concerns if any exist in
operations plan
my name is honda and i'm the operations
section chief i'm going to be preparing
for this tactics meeting
and i have a block of time to understand
what i need in terms of resources on top
of the existing team
and my name is philip
i'm the safety officer and among other
tasks i will be shadowing my
operation section chief and looking over
her shoulder
and
as she comes up with her tactics plan i
will come up with my
uh
with my counters to why certain actions
could be dangerous and i have to come up
with mitigative techniques for those
actions
and i will secure those mitigating
techniques on ics-215 alpha which is the
operational safety analysis form
this meeting is managed by the
operations section chief she will
present her draft tactical plan and
garner support from the safety officer
the purpose of this meeting is to sell
the plan and to secure support from the
planning section chief the logistics
section chief and the finance
administration's section chief the
safety officer is also present to review
any safety concerns along with ways to
mitigate those hazards
after seeing the draft tactical plan the
safety officer may submit ics-213
resource request forms for any
additional safety resources needed
the resource unit leader if staffed
represents a planning section at the
tactics meeting if there is no resource
unit leader the planning section chief
joins the meeting to fill the resource
unit leader role the meeting is
deliberately kept small to ensure it is
an effective tactics meeting because it
helps prevent major revisions from
occurring later in the process
a common understanding agreement and
situational awareness can avoid
disagreement during the later phases of
the planning cycle this is very
important
the liaison officer and the public
information officer may attend if
they've identified an issue that may
possibly affect the strategies and
tactics for example a government
representative communicates to the
logistics officer that they will no
longer participate in this incident
because they no longer see value in
participation but this organization was
part of operations draft tactical plan
other factors that might require the
public information officer to
participate might be that we become
aware of community concerns media
sensitivity or other issues that require
public relations efforts
the incident commander is never invited
to this meeting and may be performing
other work with the crisis management
team so as the operations section chief
i developed a draft tactical plan please
take a minute to review the plan if you
can
by the end of this meeting i will ask
the following people to confirm their
support for the plan those people
include the planning section chief the
logistics
section chief the finance or admin
section chief
and of course the safety officer
i want to ensure we have sufficient
resources for this incident so i begin
submitting
ics-214 resource requests
to obtain the resources i needed to
respond to this incident on top of this
team of one currently
since we don't have a resource unit
leader i'll present their resource
status operations has identified a need
for five resources we currently have two
and the operations section chief has
submitted the appropriate ics-213
resource request for the remaining three
safety officer
while shadowing the operations section
chief preparing for the tactics meeting
i've identified some hazards or risks
and provided some mitigations as shown
here on the ics-215a form we will
require all staff to work in pairs and
have security staff visit every 15
minutes
i've submitted this ics-213 general
message to the incident commander asking
if the company can provide security to
check on our responses or responders and
provide physical building perimeter
security we have brought a volunteer ems
truck to location
that is on standby
so michael as the admin and finance
section chief do you see any issues with
obtaining the funding for additional
resources that i will be requesting
the incident commander authorized 500
000 for this incident i will develop a
budget based on an approved expenses
and report any project changes in the
budget forecasts at future meetings uh
please give me your ics 213 resource
requests as soon as possible
the public around the impacted offices
don't appear to be aware of the
situation yet the media contacted our
public relations office and is seeking
information about the incident i'm
drafting a press release which will be
approved by the corporate public
relations and then distributed
the incident commander approved my plan
to issue public messages without
additional approval by him i've informed
the media person who inquired about our
plan to have a press release shortly
based on the current status of the
incident i've identified the need for
two additional teams also known as
divisions one will be the hvac
mitigation team where we have one person
on scene but need another person for the
next operational period
and the other division is the industrial
control system repair team there's
currently one person working so two more
are needed to provide relief for the
additional operational periods
i updated the
ics-215
form to identify where the units will
report and by what time they should be
working
i will submit an ics-213 resource
request form for these additional
resources
i want to confirm that all of you
support the draft tactical plan mike as
the finance admin section chief do you
support a tactical plan or do you have
any other questions or feedback for me
before you can approve i support the
draft tactical plan
neil as the planning section chief do
you support the draft plan and do you
have any feedback maybe i'd like to
understand if you believe sufficient
staff have been added to the operations
section for the next operational period
in the absence of a resource unit leader
i'll let you know of any resource
changes
obviously this is an evolving situation
so i've staffed the team based on what i
know now and immediate actions that i
believe need to be taken i will work
with my team to determine what
additional roles will need to be
developed and staffed and by when okay
uh support the draft tactical plan thank
you
and philip as the safety officer do you
support the draft tactical plan or do
you have any other questions as long as
my
suggestions about mitigation are implied
i support the draft technical plan
well now that everybody has signed off
or the planning section admin and
finance section chiefs and the safety
officers have agreed
to the tactical plan i will request
resources using this ics-214
resource request form and submit it to
the finance administration section chief
at the direction of the incident
commander
in the absence of the logistics section
chief the incident commander has
requested that i take the steps to
secure the resources you've ordered
in your ics-213 resource request
so now that concludes the tactical
meeting
and philip as a safety officer do you
know i do support
during this block of time the incident
commander may informally meet with team
members and stakeholders to make sure
everyone is on the same page the ic
makes sure the command and general staff
members exchange information about the
proposed plan to ensure that all members
are able to support the plan when
presented at the planning meeting
all conflicts must be resolved or
mitigated prior to the actual planning
meeting
during this time frame the operations
section chief will review the strategies
tactics and organization the ics-215
operational planning worksheet must be
finalized and the operations section
chief must coordinate and work with
other team members involved in or
affected by the plan
the safety officer must complete the
ics-215a the incident action plan safety
analysis and deliver to the planning
section in sufficient time for the
planning section chief to prepare a
display version for the planning meeting
the planning section chief ensures the
material intelligence resources displays
and anything else requested that will be
used or discussed in the planning
meeting are prepared displayed and ready
for presentation during this meeting
these preparations include posting the
agenda incident objectives an updated
map an ics-215 an ics-215a
and any other forms requested by the
command and general staff this meeting
brings together all ics for ics and
cooperating agency team members to
review the plan and obtain the support
for the plan the draft tactical plan was
presented at the tactics meeting and
support was garnered from those present
support for the plan at the planning
meeting should just be a confirmation
that everyone is working from the same
plan agency representatives are invited
to attend so they can see the team's
vision for handling the incident our
current situation is that the ics
analysts and the cert are working
together on isolating containing the
malware and determining the root cause
i'll review the incident objectives so
everyone's clear on what we're fighting
ensure the safety of the building
occupants ensure the safety of response
personnel maintain proper relationships
with the press and media and provide any
necessary updates that they request
maintain proper relationships with the
stakeholders and ensure adequate and
timely updates and proper addressing of
the stakeholders interests and finally
determine incident mitigation
eradication course of actions and status
i confirm that those objectives are
still valid
so based on the ics-215 operational
planning worksheet we still actually
need two additional divisions
the division bravo will be the hvac
mitigation and division
charlie sorry the additional division
the second additional division charlie
will be there for ics repair
and the division that we currently
already have working on the malware is
division alpha
as a safety officer i reviewed the
hazards or risks and provided some
mitigations on the ics-215 alpha form
we will require all staff to work in
pairs and have security staff visit
every 15 minutes we have brought a
volunteer ems tractor location that is
on standby
i prepared a budget for the upcoming
operational period based on the
submitted ics 213 resource requests and
we are still well within our fiscal
constraints
the proposed plan fits within our fiscal
working with corporate public affairs i
have released a media brief in attempt
to prevent rumors from spreading based
on feedback it seems to be working
i will now go around the room and ask
each member of the command and general
staff if they support the operational
plan as presented by the operations
section chief each member responds with
i support the plan as presented
operations and i worked with each of you
prior to this meeting so your support
should be just a formality
admin finance section chief do you
support the plan as presented i support
the plan as presented
safety officer phillip do you support
the plan as presented i support the plan
as presented
public information officer anne marie do
you support the plan as presented yes i
support the plan as presented
operations chief ganda as a formality do
you support the plan that you presented
yeah i still support my own plan as i
presented it
thank you please get me here ics-204s as
soon as possible
as the planning section chief i support
the plan as presented and now that the
command and general staff have responded
i ask the incident commander mark if he
approves the plan
i suppose i approve the plan is
presented
thank you
now that the plan has been approved by
the incident commander please submit all
documents and attachments for the
incident action plan to the planning
section chief within two hours please
get everything to me by the deadline so
that i can complete the incident action
plan and the incident commander can
review and approve it
thanks dean for all your great work and
this great plan uh as mentioned uh we'll
be working in 12-hour shifts uh so uh to
continue the work in the incident uh
around the clock so make sure they have
to continue working the incident until
your relief comes in the next
operational period please do let me know
immediately though if any of you or any
of your staff have to leave for health
or safety reasons i'd like to be
imported immediately if that occurs
now formally adjourn this meeting
command and general staff members and
appropriate unit leaders who have
deliverables needed to complete the
incident action plan finalize their
products and provide their completed
document or documents and products to
planning section chief before the
deadline given at the planning meeting
the planning section chief assembles the
incident action plan components and
personally checks for clarity and
completeness
the incident action plan covers every
aspect of the response for the duration
of the upcoming operational period
including medical plan communications
plan operations safety stakeholder
engagement public information
requirements etc
the ics-204 is the assignment list form
the meat and potatoes of this entire
planning process this form will be
prepared for each division or group
supervisor and it will list individual
assignments for their respective team
members the plan must be completed and
duplicated with enough time to hand out
copies of the iap at the operations
period briefing
this is the ics 204 assignment list
work assignments as shown on the ics-204
were based on the ics-215 operational
planning worksheet the ics-204
assignment list is a collective effort
with different blocks prepared by
different members of the ics for ics
team the operations section chief
prepares the main header and the work
assignment sections as shown here
since we do not have a resource unit
leader it falls on the planning section
chief to prepare the assigned resources
block
and the planning section chief asks the
ic and command staff if they had any
special instructions and they're
documented here
the public information officer provided
instructions about media contact and the
safety officer provides safety tips
since we do not have a logistics section
chief it falls on the incident commander
or their designee to complete this
section with contact information for key
people this section would normally be
completed by the communications unit
leader or the logistics section chief if
we had one of those roles staffed
the planning section chief will
facilitate this meeting this is where
the incident action plan is presented to
the team and responders the iap must be
completed approved and duplicated prior
to the start of this briefing
the operational period briefing
communicates the decisions planning and
preparation to the tactical supervisors
the briefing must be complete and
efficient so the responders feel they
are executing a logical safe and well
thought out plan
in a real incident the tactical
supervisors would be staff in the
operations section this briefing
highlights all important components of
the iap and should be focused relevant
and directed towards the operations
personnel who will be implementing the
incident action plan specific operations
section tactical supervisors attend this
operational period briefing so they can
give out assignments to their teams
hey
trust us this one's okay
again you can use your tablet you can
use your cell phone take a picture of
this you'll download a copy of the iep
which is one of the handouts that we
have provided for you there
i'm responsible for compiling the
incident information from the other team
members and creating the incident action
plan the planning process results in an
incident action plan or iap an iep is
created for each operational period
the iep communicates the incident
objectives and the tactics that will be
used to manage the incident during the
operational period the iep is generated
for the ics for ics team cooperating
agencies and the affected company our
incident small therefore we didn't need
or include every incident command system
form in our incident action plan the
forms are designed to be used for small
incidents as they scale all the way up
to large incidents so the form list may
change
as the incident expands or contracts the
incident action plan will also expand or
contract
here's the cover sheet which includes
the incident name the operational period
it covers a signature line for the
incident commander's approval and the
logo of the team the agency we are
working for as well as any cooperating
agency's logos
ics 202 incident objectives describes
the basic incident strategy incident
objectives commands emphasis or
priorities and safety considerations for
use during the next operational period
this primary audience audience for this
form is all supervisory personnel at the
section branch division group and unit
levels
ics-203 organization assignment list
which provides ics for ics personnel
with information on the units that are
currently activated and the names of
personnel staffing each position or unit
like the ics-202 the primary audience
for this form is all supervisory
personnel at the section branch division
group and or unit levels
the ics-204 assignment list informs
division and group supervisors of
incident assignments a separate ics-204
will need to be prepared for each
assignment captured on the ics-215 and
or the ics-215 alpha
division and group supervisors who will
pass on assignments to their
subordinates are the primary audience
for this form
ics-205 alpha communications list
records methods of contact for incident
personnel
this form could also have radio
frequencies or any methods email
addresses any way that you're going to
need to communicate during the
operational period
the audience for this form is the entire
ics for ics team and cooperating
agencies as this tells them how to
contact supervisors or anyone where you
may need assistance
ics 207 incident organization chart
provides a visual chart depicting the
organization position assignments for
the incident this form provides the
entire ics for ics team cooperating
agencies and the crisis management team
a visual overview of the response
organization that's put in play
ics 208 safety message or plan outline
safety messages priorities and key
command emphasis decisions or directions
safety hazards and or specific
precautions to be observed during this
operational period
the primary audience for this form are
all ics for ics team members and
responders from cooperating agencies
ics-214 activity logs records details of
notable activities at any incident
command system level including single
resources equipment task forces etc
these logs provide basic incident
activity documentation and a reference
for any after action report they're also
going to be really good to help
help you decide what happened if
something goes wrong along the way you
have good documentation of what went on
every team member is required to
initiate and maintain one for each
operational period or for the duration
of the incident it is to be turned into
the planning section chief before
demobilizing at the conclusion of the
operational period briefing and breakout
sessions resources travel to their
assigned work locations an important
step once they arrive at their work
locations is for each to meet face to
face with the individual being relieved
to receive a clear current detailed
briefing of conditions at their assigned
work location command and general staff
members check in with their staff to
check on progress review any any issues
or concerns with an emphasis on solving
those that arise and they also prepare
for their upcoming meetings
assessment is an ongoing continuing
process to help adjust current
operations as appropriate or required
and to help plan the future operations
needed to meet the incident objectives
resources begin their work assignments
as outlined in the incident action plan
strike team and task force leaders or
single resource bosses give assignments
to the people working for them progress
and recommended changes in actions or
resources such as kind type and quantity
are passed on to the next level of
supervision these recommendations are
then incorporated into the planning
process for the next operational period
so i want to assess how we're doing
during the last operational cycle so i
can make changes to improve our
performance i'm going to meet with
various people asking these kind of key
questions what's working or not working
i'm going to ask the operations section
chief to interview division and group
supervisors and get their feedback and
i'm going to also ask the general staff
to meet with their staff to assess their
operations
with the feedback from the command and
general staff i'm going to determine if
there's need to update or change our
incident objectives or strategies or
team compositions
so the incident hasn't been fixed so
we're going to start the planning p
again yay all right
the assessment started previously it was
carried over
and if there's any changes that we need
to make we're going to have another
command and general staff meeting
discuss those
changes or go on to prepare for the
tactics meeting at the end of the
exercise we will discuss your feedback
related to what were the strengths of
the exercise and suggestions to improve
the ics for ics processes and or future
exercises please share your thoughts
during the exercise by emailing or
texting brian will summarize them so we
can discuss at the end of the exercise
we will take a 10-minute break
okay
on day 11 at 11 15 a.m the fire alarm in
the building is triggered again
the fire department confirms there is no
fire and state that these types of
alarms are happening throughout the
community
on day 11 at 1 pm the fire alarm is
triggered again and readings are falsely
showing an increase in temperature
some staff refused to evacuate
on day 11 at 1 15 pm an email is
received demanding payment of bitcoin
equal to 10 percent of the company
annual profits
the email threatens additional loud and
disruptive events if the ransom is not
paid
on day 11 at 3 15 pm the sprinkler
system in the building lobby is
activated facility staff determined
significant damage water damage occurred
on day 11 at 5 pm
a local a local tv news reporter
contacts senior staff
they state they are investigating a rash
of these type of events in the community
and say that the fire departments are
being heavily taxed
the reports say staff have already
confirmed the incident
and the exercise continues
this is the start of the second
operational period in a real incident
the responders working in the first
operational period of the ics for ics
team have briefed their replacements
before leaving their post the first task
is to review the priorities and
objectives to determine if any updates
are needed some content will be repeated
because a new group of responders has
just arrived to take over managing the
ics for ics activities for this exercise
the players from the first operational
period will continue to play their roles
for the second operational period
i facilitate this meeting also known as
the strategy meeting and typically
present any proposed changes as draft
objectives for the incident commander's
consideration i didn't propose any
changes or additions to the initial
priorities and objectives the incident
commander is going to identify any
uh and or review response priorities
constraints and other incident
objectives
so as incident commander once again it's
my job to ensure that the objectives the
drive-ins and response operations are
clear to everyone in the ics for ics
organization and they know what needs to
be accomplished i agree with mr gay
who's playing the incident planning
second chief version two that the
priorities for the incident haven't
changed and the the emphasis is going to
be life safety incident stabilization
and property and environmental
preservation just like last time
the current plan objectives for the
incident are noted in an ics 202
incident briefing form from the first
operational period and they have not
changed right the discovery of
ransomware uh kind of falls under that
last objective that that's on the on the
list right so we're gonna review these
objectives at the command and general
staff meeting and i'll update the
objectives as needed based on these
changes but we're gonna move forward
with what we have so far on the thing
for the last operational period
this is the command and general staff
meeting for operational period two some
reminders this may be the only time the
command and general staff are in the
same room during this operational period
the goal is for everyone on the team to
work together and be on the same page
there must be no unanswered questions or
ambiguity after this meeting
i'll start an ics 233 incident open
action tracker for this operational
period mr bristow as the ic would you
like to make any opening statement or
provide any additional information
thank you and thanks everyone once again
for being here uh for this operational
period um recognize that there's some
confusion going on with the discovery of
ransomware so if there's any questions
anyone has please don't hesitate to ask
them we need to make sure that we are
all good as we leave this meeting and
all on the same page so do ask questions
thanks
mr bristow as the ic do i have your
permission to continue with the same
provisions
as my colleague in the first operational
period has specifically to prepare and
release
messages and make statements without
clearing each media contact with you
first i will continue to work with
corporate public affairs on messaging
and will obtain the appropriate
approvals before issuing
any yep you continue to have my approval
for that and uh working with corporate
as well as also please continue to
disseminate those uh messages to the
entire team when they're completed
the meeting schedule from the first
operational period works and does not
need to be changed it's prominently
posted around the incident command post
so make sure you familiarize yourself
with it
i'm updating the ics-233 incident open
action tracker from the first
operational period
so in a real incident the ics for ics
orchard would be updated with the names
of the people who just came in to
relieve the people from the first
incident operational period right so
we're not doing that for the purpose
that we don't want to switch everybody
out we should have gotten mustaches or
something i don't know
um
but for the purposes of this exercise
these same physical humans are going to
be playing these roles again just
version two of
themselves team has been working
extremely hard last hours uh with the
vendor attempting to find alternatives
to contain the malware but unfortunately
not identified any viable alternatives
so we just received an email that
demands ransomware payment
in bitcoin totaling 10 of company annual
profits by close of business
the email threatens that failure to
comply will result in a loud and very
disruptive continuation of the day
finance admin section chief mike i'm
submitting an ics-213 resource request
to add a malware expert to our team
based on on the recent malware payment
requests this external person will
require a fifty thousand dollar retainer
do you think we can cover this
uh mr lambert we can afford the retainer
but may only be able to keep this
resource for five days given our current
budget when you submit your ics-213
resource request please estimate the
number of operational periods you'll
need the resource so i can review this
with the incident commander in case he
needs to ask the crisis management team
for more money
the ransomware decision process is
defined before a cyber incident occurs
and looks like this
number one the incident commander meets
with the crisis management team about
the ransomware request legal counsel on
the ics for ics team pre-meets with the
chief legal counsel
number two the chief legal counsel
advises crisis management team on legal
implications and reporting requirements
number three incident commander asked
the operations section chief to advise
the crisis management team on the
current and likely future efforts to
contain the malware and or restore
systems
number four the crisis management team
decides if the company will pay the
ransomware if the ransomware request is
to be paid the company cfo will work the
work with the admin finance section
chief if no payment is to be made the
ics for ics team will continue to
contain malware or restore systems
a local television news reporter
contacts our media relations staff
seeking to investigate a rash of
computer eras that have incurred in the
community that have resulted in the fire
department
being taxed beyond its limits
the reporter claims several staff from
the company have confirmed the building
we are working in has been affected and
asks if you have any comment
mr briscoe i would like your approval to
develop a draft media message that i can
work with mrs lamberden ms lambert inc
about obtaining
to obtain facts that can be included in
the media message i will review with you
and the team before obtaining corporate
public affairs approval of the medium
message
so i preview developing this media
with the corporate team as well as the
ops section chief miss lamernick
to get the content correct in the
message and please do make sure that
they get available they get passed out
to the entire team for further review
as the safety officer i once again will
shadow operation section chief
and update or create a new ics-215a form
to mitigate possible safety concerns
imac in a draft tactical plan to take
one step out of the script as a safety
officer i heard the trigger word in one
of the previous slides i heard the word
loud and disruptive day as a safety
officer when i hear loud or else i'm
going to probably request law
enforcement to come in and sweep the
building for any possible ieds that's
just me out of the script back to the
script
makes a lot of sense
thank you for that
additional thought and um
i'll manage this meeting and present the
updated draft extra plan to garner
support from the safety officer the
planning section chief logistics section
chief and the admin or finance section
chief so after i review my updated plan
the safety officer reviews it
and updates the ics-215a
putting out any further safety concerns
or ways to mitigate those hazards
while shadowing the operations section
chief preparing for the tactics meeting
i've changed the ics-215a as the heat in
the room 315 could be a problem for the
incoming malware expert
based on this ics-213 general message
submitted during the first operational
period additional security has been
deployed for this operational period to
check on our responders and provide
physical building perimeter security we
continue to have a volunteer ems truck
to the location that is on standby with
crews rotated in and out
i want to share with you the status of
the different divisions so division
alpha if you remember is the ics system
analyst
and the company has been rotating them
on our 12 hour operational periods
then there's division bravo the hvac
mitigation
team and they have one person on scene
and another person has been identified
for the next operational period
then division charlie which is the
industrial control system repair team
they now have three people available
with two on the first shift and one
person on the second shift and lastly
division delta will actually be the
incoming malware expert for the
ransomware detected they will arrive at
10 o'clock this evening
i updated the ics-215 to identify where
the malware expert will report and by
what time they will be working i will
submit an ics-213 resource request for
the additional resources aka the malware
expert
so mr gay as the planning section chief
do you support the draft technical plan
i'll support the draft tactical plan
mr cheney as the financial admin section
chief do you support the draft technical
plan i support the draft technical plan
and mr cautiously safety officer do you
support the draft technical plan i do
support the drive tactical plan
well that that was easy uh now that i've
confirmed the planning section and admin
finance section chief and safety officer
support the technical plan i will
request resources using this 213 or
ics-213 resource request form and submit
it to the finance administration section
chief at the direction of the incident
commander
in the absence of the logistics section
chief the incident commander has
requested i take the steps to secure the
resources we've ordered on your ics-213
resource request perfect then that
concludes this tactical meeting
during this block of time the incident
commander may informally meet with team
members and stakeholders to make sure
everyone is on the same page the ic
makes sure the command and general staff
members exchange information about the
proposed plan to ensure all members are
able to support the plan when presented
at the planning meeting all conflicts
must be resolved prior to the actual
planning meeting
during the time frame the operations
section chief will review the strategies
tactics and organization the ics-215
operational planning worksheet must be
finalized and the operations section
chief must coordinate and work with
other team members involved in or
affected by the plan
the safety officer must complete the
ics-215a the incident action and safety
plan
incident action plan safety analysis and
deliver to the planning section in
sufficient time for the planning section
chief to prepare a display version for
the planning meeting the planning
session chief ensures the material
intelligence resources displays and
anything else requested that will be
used or discussed in the planning
meeting are prepared displayed and ready
for presentation during this meeting
these preparations include posting the
agenda incident objectives an updated
map the ics-215 the ics-215a and any
other forms requested by the command and
general staff
this meeting brings together all ics for
ics and cooperating agency team members
to review the plan and obtain the
support for the plan the draft tactical
plan was presented at the tactics
meeting and support was garnered for
those present support for the plan at
the planning meeting should just be a
confirmation that everyone is working on
the same plan
agency representatives are invited to
attend so once again they can see the
team's vision for handling the incident
the ics analysts and assert continued to
work together on isolating and
containing the malware and attempting to
determine the root cause they have been
unsuccessful so far but hopefully with
the malware expert coming in
they will make some progress
now i'm going to review the incident
objectives
ensure the safety of building occupants
ensure the safety of response personnel
maintain proper relationships with the
press and media and provide necessary
updates maintain proper relationships
with the stakeholders and ensure
adequate timely updates and proper
addressing of the stakeholders interest
if you don't they'll call you anyway
determine incident mitigation and
eradication course of actions and
finally address the ransomware that was
recently discovered i confirm those are
the objectives
based on the ics-215 operational
planning worksheet we still need the
malware expert
as a safety officer i reviewed the
hazards or risks and provided some
mitigations on ics-215 alpha form we
will require all staff to work in pairs
and have security staff visit every 15
minutes we have brought a volunteer ems
tractor location that is on standby
again
as the finest administration section
chief i have prepared a budget for the
upcoming operational period based on the
submitted ics-213 resource requests and
we are still well within our fiscal
constraints
with ic's prior approval i've worked
with corporate public affairs to draft
and release this media statement to the
public
and the rest of the team
now is the time i go around the room and
ask me each member of the command and
general staff if they support the
operations plan as presented by the
operations section chief
mr cheney is admin finance section chief
do you support the plan i support the
plan it's presented
mr kash has safety officer do you
support the plan i support the plan
ms vandenherk is public information
officer do you support the plan yes i
support the plan as presented
and ms lamberink as the operations
section chief can you support your plan
as presented yes i support my plan
as the planning section chief i support
the plan now that the command and
general staff have responded i asked mr
bristow the incident commander if he
approves the plan i approve the plan
now that the plan has been approved by
the incident commander i need all
documents and attachments for the
incident action plan to the planning
section no later than two hours from now
so i can produce the incident action
plan and the incident commander can
review and formally approve it
so thanks everyone for your continued
work on this incident uh you know i know
that things are changing but looks like
we've got a great plan to attack for
this new operational planning cycle
again if you have any questions please
let me know and once again if anyone has
to leave for any health or safety
reasons please let me know immediately
during this meeting
command and general staff members and
appropriate unit leaders who have
deliverables needed to complete the
incident action plan finalize their
products and provide their completed
documents and products to me within the
time schedule i gave at the planning
meeting with the help of the other
section chiefs i the incident action
plan components and personally check for
clarity and completeness the incident
action plan covers every aspect of the
response for the duration of the
upcoming operational period
ics 204 assignment list forms will be
prepared for each division group
supervisor and will list individual
assignments for the respective teams the
plan must be completed and duplicated
with enough time to hand out copies of
the incident action plan at the
operations period briefing
this is just a reminder that the ics-204
work assignment
requires input from multiple people in
the ics for ics organization they
include the incident commander
operation section chief resource unit
leader or the planning section chief
logistics section chief the 204
optionally contains information from the
safety officer the finance admin section
chief public information officer and or
the liaison officer
the changes to the incident action plan
include the updated date and time for
the upcoming operational period on all
incident command system forms in the iep
besides updating the date and time of
the upcoming operational period other
forms with changes and updates are
since ransomware has been discovered
we've changed the last objective from
operational period one and added a new
one the updated one is determined
malware mitigation and eradication
course of action the new objective is
develop ransomware response
the malware expert was added to the
ics-203 organization assignment list
ics-204 assignment list
contact information for the malware
expert was added to the ics-205 alpha
communications list
the malware expert was added to the ics
for ics organizational chart under the
operations section
and we're back to the operational period
briefing where the planning section
chief presents the incident action plan
to the team and the responders the
operational period briefing communicates
the decisions planning and preparation
to the tactical supervisors the briefing
must be complete and efficient so the
responders feel they are executing a
logical safe and well thought out plan
at the conclusion of the operational
period briefing and the breakout
sessions resources travel to their
assigned work locations an important
step once they arrive at their work
location is for each to meet face to
face with the individual being relieved
to receive a clear current and detailed
briefing of all conditions at their
assigned work location command and
general staff members check in with
their staff checking in on progress
addressing issues and concerns with an
emphasis on solving those that arise and
they also prepare for their upcoming
meetings
so once again in this part of the cycle
i want to assess how we're doing
compared to the last operational cycle
so we can make changes improve
performance and try and close out the
incident
i'm going to meet with a variety of
different people i'm going to talk to
them ask them again what's working
what's not working i'm going to talk a
lot with the operations section chief
and ask them to interview their
divisions and group leaders make sure
that they're getting that feedback and
then ultimately talk to the general
staff to see if there's anything that
they any comments they have to the
situation
so when we grab all that feedback
together determine if we need to update
the objectives like we did last cycle
strategies or uh add new resources team
compositions as we did in the last cycle
so once again the incident has not been
resolved so we start the planning cycle
again
the you know the assessment that we had
last time is carried over uh if there's
any changes in that from the the
feedback we get from from the staff we
can discuss those changes as a team and
then prepare to go into the the tactics
meeting
so the incident commander meets with the
crisis management team periodically to
provide incident status updates and may
ask the operations and finance
administration's section chiefs to
present the status and updates in their
sections
the incident commander may request the
operations section chief to present a
current status on containment and
restoration efforts
the finance administration section chief
may be asked to provide a financial
status or update on response finances
and budget
and after the presentations by the
operations and finance administration
section chiefs the incident commander
mentions the new legislation that may
have ramifications on the current
situation and seeks confirmation from
the crisis management team about the
current plan and or additional direction
from the cmt
this exercise has provided you a glimpse
into how a cyber response might be when
utilizing the incident command system
we've tried to condense about 18 hours
or more into the preceding 90 minutes
by doing so there are lots of little
things we've left out you've likely
noticed some redundancy and that was
intentional the planning cycle or
planning p is completed once for every
operational period so it's rinse and
repeat
implementing the incident command system
into a response requires practice don't
wait for the proverbial cyber hurricane
to hit before you try using the incident
command system for the first time
use it for the annual company picnic for
mary's retirement party and for a
tabletop exercise of a hypothetical
cyber incident
in real life an incident management team
who has spent some time training and
practicing will run an incident smoothly
just like clockwork
their meetings will be smooth and they
won't take as long as we have here
there are free fema courses online if
you do a search fema emi for emergency
management institute you'll see a list
of them there
the primary ones ics 100 200 700 800 are
all free they're all computer-based
self-paced a couple of other there are
other ones that are available that you
can access your city your county or your
state emergency management
group
and they will help you find classes and
partners
the first few times you implement the
incident command system things will be
bumpy which is why practice is essential
again contact your local emergency
management folks and ask to be invited
to an exercise
or an event that an incident management
team is running usually the liaison
officer or pio will be your guide in and
around the incident command post take
note of the collaboration and teamwork
check out the forms and documents posted
on the walls
ask to be invited to meetings to see how
they are run afterwards take what you've
learned and implement those into an
exercise with your team after the first
practice exerciser 2 you and your team
will see marked improvement and pretty
soon things will run like a well-oiled
machine
thank you all so much so at this point
um i'm looking for brian peterson but
we're actually going to go into the hot
wash brian you're all the way back there
and you're you're pointing towards the
screen
okay so these are the additional slides
mark would you like to read these since
you're a little bit closer sure okay
thank you and here here's the mic oh
i've got one
list the top three organizational
strengths
so this these are the
this is what we're asking you from
uh asking
yes
can we go back
while they're working on that uh in real
life if you do get a chance please go
out contact your local emergency
management fire department whoever and
asked to be invited to an incident uh as
part of a type three all hazards
incident management team we love to have
people come through we're always looking
for people to join our team it's very
enlightening it's very illuminating and
it helps us as well so please
um
okay so we'll start with this exercise
versus real world again we condensed at
least 18 hours we we said two
operational periods which 12 hours each
24 hours and we
butchered them into 90 minutes
we didn't scratch the surface
and it requires practice again don't
wait for that fire don't wait for that
cyber storm don't wait for the hurricane
the floods practice it now
when i learned it i learned it on the
tailgate of a pickup truck because we
filled out forms at two o'clock in the
morning after a rollover and we filled
out the entire ics-201 form and so it
does require practice
and it's easily done through tabletop it
doesn't have to be a real incident it
can be an event that's the beauty behind
the incident command system
it's used in marathons it's used at bike
races
county fairs state fairs all sorts of
different events
resources to learn the incident command
system fema emi online again that's free
and contacting your city county and
state emergency management group
the first few incidents would be bumpy
it's not going to go as planned we have
planned pre-planned incidents and
not a single one has ever fallen into
the plan that we wrote but we were able
to get through it because we practiced
talked to emergency management about
assisting youth exercises again ask a
tour in imt in action check out the
team's collaboration note the documents
on the wall normally we would have the
documents that you saw on the screens
that we had presented earlier those
would be up on a wall
and everybody would be presenting right
off of those wall charts once they got
those down after the meeting then they
would condense those into the forms that
you've got in the iap there
and sit in on any meetings
okay back to this ics for ics hot wash
form lists the top three organizational
strengths
list the top three items requiring
improvement
and any hot wash remarks comments so
what i would suggest is the file got
corrupted coming out of apple to windows
and so there's only about five comments
qr code
there's about six comments and maybe
what we should do is just ask the
audience to provide those comments again
i type about 100 words a minute i'll
capture all the notes and i'll combine
the emails that were sent to me but
there's only five or six comments if you
could ask the audience to do that i'll
capture okay great about that no
anybody
so y'all were pretty agreeable tonight
everybody supported your plan
that's not that's not real life
how does the incident uh command system
work when
when you can't have agreement on those
situations
i'll take that um
honestly in real life on an incident
management team nine times out of ten it
does go that way
it has to go that way if you have worked
with these folks before it will go that
way if i'm on an incident management
management team as a planning section
chief and i don't agree with something i
will sit down i will let operations know
that i will talk to everybody in there
if the rest of the team is on board then
guess what i'm on board they have
listened to my concerns they may have
addressed them they may not have i'm
part of a team that's how it really
works
do you have
weird things happen absolutely you do
but when you present a unified front to
the public it is just as we presented it
is agreeable a unified command is the
same way when you're talking you've got
epa you've got fema you've got company
representatives in there guess what as
unified command they may not all agree
but they're going to come out as a
united front and it has to be run that
way so all those involved do that yes
i'll grab that too yeah i'll
i i will kind of talk about the other
side of the coin which is when you just
can't get to the alignment and the
consensus that you need alignment is
probably the most difficult job that any
of us do in our day-to-day jobs
alignment is hard okay
and when alignment cannot be achieved in
an efficient manner that's exactly why
you have this person right here the
incident commander because it is their
job to call balls and strikes on the
hard problems and i i have worked in
emergency management and i have seen you
know
productive conflict i would call it
between ops or planning or logistics or
whatever right when things go sideways
and ultimately having that incident
commander where they're they've got to
make a decision and they will make a
decision
incident command system is not a
democracy
yet
uh positive conflict or whatever i want
to steal that it is it's positive
complex i'm going back to the video um
no but just to underscore that right if
you look at the process right there's
number of opportunities i have my uh so
the number of opportunities for that
conflict to get resolved before it has
to come to a decision but the incident
command system is pretty clear the
incident commander is in command and so
if it can't get resolved that's why you
have the adjudication right but there's
several kind of sub
activities the different like the
tactics meeting and the planning meeting
where that that can be used in order to
to resolve as much of that as possible
but conflict will happen that's okay
just one one more last thing if you
remember the diagram of planning p the
cycle
there are blue periods
those are the periods for conflict
resolution
so before you
present the finalized plan
all of those conflicts will be spoken
about they will be resolved one way or
another
maybe you'll change the tactic maybe
you'll change the entire plan but you
will solve that conflict however it fits
uh incident commander's agenda of uh
solving the incident and only after that
conflict is solved and you are out of
this blue
sorry
of this blue field you you're ready to
proceed to the next meeting so when it
comes to the meeting time
you are on the same page one way or
another no matter how you arrive to it
but when you are at the meeting time you
are already on the same page
anybody else
thank you
i noticed that your safety officer
seemed to conflate a couple of different
organizational roles there were times
when the safety officer was analyzing
safety concerns real hazards and there
were times that the safety officer was
doing physical security analysis
and i could imagine there would be times
when that person would also be looking
at environmental hazards nepa exposures
it wasn't clear in the documentation
that that conflation of responsibilities
was aligned in that one person is that
how this normally plays out or could the
forms be updated to reflect that
so
first of all anything can be updated to
reflect anything that's why ics is a
living organism it changes and it adapts
to however you needed to be adapted to
your organization and to your response
second artificiality of the exercise
here yes i was i was jumping
and bouncing around
in reality safety officer will not be
alone in reality one safety officer will
have
what is called assistant safety officers
and each one of those will be a subject
matter expert on one or another field
so like you he here today i jumped out
of the script and i mentioned i heard
loud bang i want uh
law enforcement to sweep well the only
reason i said it is because i'm prior
service law enforcement so i actually do
know what i would do in this situation
in any other situation safety officer's
job is to
take feedback from assistant safety
officers and from everybody else
and then come up with mitigative
techniques to whichever aspects of
danger or hazards have been identified
to me
you also notice too that the safety
officer is constantly working with
operations as well so you know the
question come up what if you have a
safety system malware right you've got a
trichonix yeah a crisis type type event
happening right as that's coming up from
operations the safety officer is going
to hear that early right and so they can
kind of bring that color to the
you know the cyber piece of the response
but yeah you know they're not going to
work as a single person right and
they're not going to have domain
expertise in all things and that's where
you know typing and qualification which
is something we did not get into at all
in this exercise but it's something
we've already worked on in a robust way
is really important because it says you
know you have this level of training
this level of experience and expertise
that means that you can be the safety
officer for this kind of incident right
and have that have that knowledge to
cover down in those areas and so that's
something we didn't get into in an
exercise but is an important component
of the overall incent command system if
you guys would like to stay for another
25 to 72 hours
i would be more than happy to walk you
through a full planning p workshop and
i promise you you will probably not
enjoy it
i i'll just add like for any of the
rules i guess more facets can be brought
to the table and in 12 hours or 24 hours
i was thinking to myself like after
having triaged malware
and
looking at the hvac system how is it
connecting to the network and you know
is is it in and of itself a c2 system or
is it
moving laterally through the network
what's happening in terms of control of
the system and other systems potentially
so probably you would have involved
whoever is in charge of network
segmentation quite
quickly as well just as another example
i i mean obviously it left the building
and went to the community so i mean that
was
you know something that would
involve a lot of i.t support not just in
uh our building or our organization but
we'd have to collaborate with anybody
else that might have been affected
because maybe you know
that collaboration
can help us resolve the incident because
they might have discovered something and
so
you know that would also be happening
with uh
in the operations group and that's where
i was i was just i'm the window dressing
so just so you guys know that's my whole
roll up here but uh did great job yeah i
think neil has a response too and i'm
i'm interested in what other feedback
you all have too so
mark you can
shuffle the mic around or i can get up
and do it too whatever's easiest
um
so one thing to keep in mind about this
whole system is the fire and ems and
other crews in the community or people
that are actually responding to a big
bang as he mentioned right they are
going to use this system that's what
they use so one of the primary reasons
that we're going through and showing you
all the components is that when you
interact with these components in fire
and ems you know maybe you have to go
pull um some forensics off a work
station in a could be a hot area or a
dangerous area right uh knowing all
these components and how they fit
together is pretty useful
anybody else
so the communications officer did a
wonderful job in getting the message out
to the media but i was kind of bummed
that i had to read about it in the media
first especially when the malware was
identified so is there was there
something you left out about information
about reporting or information sharing
to either cesa the fbi or i know we
don't know what sector this company was
in but we're going to presume that it
has a maybe a sector isaac or isil if
they're not critical infrastructure so
was there something about
in the plan there that you left out
about reporting reporting this prior to
the to the ransomware and then those
reporting requirements
but just when he's like hey something's
going on we identified some malware
and uh reporting that to cisa
so i think some of that would have
probably happened in the kind of
pre-incident phase and to be honest with
you
so uh when trying to scope the exercise
right we could have made this exercise
we did not get into a lot of places
because it was just going to run us down
rabbit holes that that really you know
we were trying to inform everyone of how
ics for ics would work and how the
instant command system works but there's
again a lot of details on a lot of other
things that that would that would happen
in real life that we just couldn't cover
in the time we had um especially when
not ever we had to spend some time
letting everyone know like what the
incident command system is broadly right
because uh you know
i won't ask you to show your hands
because i'm afraid to ask the question
but how many people actually knew what
the incident can system was at all
before they got to this did this thing
probably wasn't very high right and so
there was a lot of that that needed to
go on but yeah there's going to be legal
reporting requirements there's going to
be potentially public affairs things
there might be good reporting to do some
of that might happen before the incident
gets declared right at some point it
gets declared so there's a lot of kind
of fabric here that we kind of glossed
over as an exercise artifice but that's
where a lot of that i think would would
shake out
i absolutely agree with you by the way
though that those activities would
definitely be occurring yeah most likely
through the liaison officer capacity
that's a great observation
i had one more quick one um does any
tailoring guidance exist
for practicing ics in a very small
organization that may be responding to
an incident i'm thinking about the
co-ops or smaller utilities they would
probably love to have all of these
artifacts but they might need to
understand how to tailor it
thank you i didn't know if you were
taking that one as well so this was
built even though we went through
literally everything and we explained
the process of filling out you know 12
different forms today
um
this is for a type 1 incident
type three i'm sorry i always get those
i always split them so a type three is
the smallest type of incident which
normally involves one company a single
asset not multiple parties as you scale
up type two would be multiple companies
then your type one is like your biggest
and your baddest you've got every
government in the world involved and
it's it's a global response right
for type threes they are designed for a
single company so the material that
the isa gca has been sponsoring and
working on and taking the templates it
is specifically designed for a smaller
utility or company so they can pick
which forms to use and which they're
just like we don't need to borrow
bother with this for this operational
period so it is designed for type three
but future exercises and future content
and and there are more forums right but
it's your choice it's it's like burger
is it burger king have it your way like
you can you can pick which form you want
to use so um don't let the forms scare
you they're they're a tool for you they
should not be used um to slow you down
or to hinder you but once you get in the
rhythm of it these forms speed things up
and they're great artifacts during a
response one of the largest concerns i
have today is
it
many responses
i think in cyber tend to be kind of fast
and loose people are doing what they
need to do to get the job done but then
after the fact no one feels great about
the response they feel fatigued they
feel that things were left out and they
don't even have a way to go back and
look at the postmortem because hardly
anything was documented so what you do
want to document during an incident and
by the way your legal counsel will
counsel you on what should and should
not be documented in such a way
these forms help you they help you
figure out what happened who made the
decisions why the decision was made i
mean every the thing about
cybers that we're the only
nationally um understood or recognized
form of a disaster that does not follow
incident command system today we're the
only one everybody else does if you look
at natural and man-made disasters as the
federal government classifies them
we're the only space that hasn't adopted
it yet so um to ginger's question you
know hey can can i take this material
could a smaller company or a utility or
a
wastewater facility in a locality could
they use this yeah we've got the
material we want them to use it and and
it's free
yeah the other power of the the
structure and
yes it feels a little burdensome for
like a smaller but
there's a lot of value there and it
makes you think about things you
wouldn't otherwise consider right
the thing that drives me crazy is that
when people have incidents they don't
think about public affairs so like we're
gonna keep this quiet sure you are right
you know even if you manage to actually
do that it was not a bad it was not
wasted resources to come out with what
your holding statement would be at a
minimum for the incident right and so
with the structure it kind of makes you
think about you know if you're an
incident commander you gotta go okay
well what do i actually need to staff
right so like pio is one that always
gets staffed budget and finance right
people just kind of start spending money
they don't really they're not accounting
for time right this creates a structure
by which you can have good better
reporting and know actually what what
how it went
i think you had a question as well we
missed you then we can get to you in the
back if that's okay
thank you i also work in a lot of
incident responses that natural hazards
other side of things the delegation of
authority you said it but you went fast
and that is a critical part of this
could you speak to the delegation of
authority how you would see that going
yeah so uh hopefully uh
before the incident is part of your
planning right you're going to get as an
incident commander or or you're going to
get
your organization is going to pre-set up
like where your authority is right what
your left and right boundaries are what
your financial resources are for
whatever level the incident is right
that's where you have you know the type
three is the smallest right then you go
two one but you know you're going to set
up different boundaries as an
organization for what decisions can be
made and at what level what gates you
need to pass to go up so
the inside commander role in this in
this exercise was is kind of
i approve
sounds good right but in reality the
inside commander's running off and
talking to leadership talking to legal
talking to finance like making sure that
everything's good to go is happening in
that interstitial time when people are
off doing real work right the ins and
commander is generally off kind of
working some of those challenges and
like
often working with like finance like hey
we're getting close to to our line
right now do we need to get that
increased that's not usually an easy
thing like it was in the exercise but
again we didn't want to admire it in
details that weren't as fun so
great question though yes
i just um i worked with the co-ops for a
long time and
to get to your question ginger we ended
up using a program called decide which
was created by newari
hsip um and
with the smaller utilities so if you
imagine a staff of 20
you've got multiple hats on each one and
so you can't take something that's that
structured and fill all the roles so i
think you can take i'm really excited to
see this but i think if you want to work
with the smaller utilities with it you
really need to think about cutting it
into stepping stones and even taking it
a few steps back from this structure but
the overall structure they'll get but
you can't implement it with that many
roles and that much complication because
they just don't have the staff resources
at that size but we really like decide
we the first time we ran it we had 36
utilities and i think the second time
there were more than a hundred
i mean you can run an incident with two
people you can run you can run an
incident with an incident commander and
then i'd say the second position which
is quite frankly
i've always loved being a planning
section chief
so in theory you could run an incident
with an ic and a planning section chief
so again the the org chart um
the way it was presented to you today
and this is like a little bit of
background from almost two years ago
when we started this is mark bristow me
neil
i think chris systrunk was uh was in the
meeting too we said if we knew nothing
about an ics incident and someone said i
need you to send a fly away team
somewhere at a minimum
what would be the roles you would want
to have to go in there and so i really
we doubled down on the op section that's
where you see the specialty and the
incident command system to where if you
got to go in and figure out what
happened those were the roles that you
needed but to your point
most incidents if you're talking about
day-to-day activity or even
things coming in that you're reviewing
and you're trying to decide it it's very
small staff we're talking two three four
people but the the benefit of the
framework is not necessarily the roles i
don't want you to focus on the roles i
want you to focus on
the general framework and the concept of
unity of command separation of authority
everybody has one role and they're
allowed to play that role another large
problem i see today is that say a cyber
incident happens you're not recused from
your day job i've seen so many cyber
incidents where
it's out it's run out of a sock you've
got a sock director who
is commanding 20 people they're standing
up a call you've got one person running
the call taking notes on the call
telling somebody to do something else i
mean
it is so stressful and it creates such
horrible response fatigue the way that
we did this and i saw people suffering
and not having a common framework to use
or common terminology and it's all
different by company to company today
even the utilities like everything's
different
so
this at least gives us a common language
and a common framework that can be
adapted is it perfect no of course not
it's not meant to be but first
responders use it every single day
so who am i
in my vanity to imagine that i can
create a special cyber response system
not using this
and so that was the entire premise is
that we don't want to create something
new we want to use what every single
other first responder in the world is
using and it's good enough for me so
yeah and i think that goes back to two
two important pieces right so the first
thing was we declared an incident we
kind of glossed over that as well right
but most organizations will have a
threshold by which they would even
activate
this
right so
your day-to-day stuff may fall below the
threshold of activating and like
declaring a formal incident right and
then the second thing we did was
basically figure out what's going on and
then tailored the incident and tailored
the roles right so to megan's point it
can be even if you've gone into a
declared incident as previously divined
by your organization
you now may
still only manage it with two people
because that's all you have or that's
all the resources that you can you can
apply or it's all it's needed for the
thing
okay
so
with that um i just have two two quick
slides we're landing on and it's just
really to kind of give you all an update
and tell you all where we're landing the
plane on this and hopefully to solicit
and engage your support as well so we
will be conducting ics for ics exercises
globally based on the exercise performed
today we have several people who have
already volunteered to help host these
exercises please volunteer if you're
interested in helping to host an
exercise for your country or industry
sector we are finalizing the ics for ics
credentials process which everybody's
been asking when and how can i get
credentialed i think i could be a pio i
think i qualify for ops section chief
i've done it i just need to complete the
fema courses complete the courses
complete the courses we want to ramp up
again on credentialing so
all the credentials are running through
the fema one responder system thank you
fema thank you dhs for giving us an
access to that platform that's where
your unique qualifications as an
individual with all your training your
experience that's where all that is
stored that's your official credential
that says i am a type 1 incident
commander
this will allow people to obtain
credentials to help perform specific ics
for ics roles defined in the program
the ics for ics team will be working to
expand the program to include more
complex incidents this will include type
2 incidents that impact multiple assets
and sites for a single company
ics for ics will be expanded to include
mutual aid processes and other incident
command capabilities
we need further help we need your help
so first off anyone in this room thank
you like this this was just an idea it
was a dream and all of us got together
and said we think that this could
actually work and now we have over 1500
volunteers globally
i mean this is huge we never could have
anticipated this because we feel it's
the right thing to do
so please consider registering to
receive the ics for ics newsletter i
promise we won't resell your email or
anything like that so you can follow our
progress and provide input to shape the
program host an ics for ics exercise or
participate in one of the plan exercises
that may be one of the last steps many
of you all needed to get credentialed
was today so thank you
the newsletter will share information
about these exercises we are looking for
people to join the ics for ics team to
help expand the program
we are also seeking people to present at
various events to help others learning
about ics for ics
i don't i don't want to be the only one
talking about this and i'm not
thankfully mark ayala and others they've
been presenting at conferences i've seen
it get out there spread the word become
an official ambassador we need your help
and lastly if you want to get involved
contact brian peterson he's here
um
but i i did just want to just close out
and thank everyone
for for your help thank you for all the
work that has gone into this those of
you all again someone said like you put
all this together i didn't put any of
this together i didn't do the work it
was the folks up here on the stage that
did all the work and the books in the
background as well so thank them thank
them for taking the effort this far
and um talk with us meet with us we'll
be here um you know through thursday
like everyone else but
again thank you so much and um
i i can't forward the slide on so i
can't see it
okay then
then you go ahead brian because i can't
see that
thank you
so for two seconds i'll be megan
so megan would like to thank these
people in particular who did a lot of
work to create this program uh mark bode
who is our gracious moderator and uh
philip kosh our safety officer they
created a lot of the materials most of
the materials
that went into the training as well as
the program content itself all the stuff
you saw today so we greatly appreciate
their efforts catherine hutton leads our
awareness and outreach team which you're
welcome to join
we do a lot of awareness outreach
coordination planning as well as trying
to find exercises we've got about 20
exercises on a road map which is great
catherine is fabulous for that she
couldn't be here today
and then mike cheney is sitting at the
table and he leads the the training team
and contribute contributed to the
exercise eric's at the table as well and
he contributed to the exercise team and
anne marie is our pio and she has done
a great job of trying to get us a
certification process with fema which
will be available hopefully very very
very soon although i have been saying
that for probably a month or six weeks
since megan's probably sick of me from
saying it but we're getting there and
you can get certified very soon get your
credentials
thank you
real quick one disclaimer the phone
numbers on the incident action plan that
you have are bogus please don't call
them expecting to reach any of these
individuals
i don't know who you're going to reach
but please don't
okay so this concludes the s4 2022 ics
for ics exercise thank you all so much
[Applause]
you