hello everybody
and i see some of you filtering in and
out so keep going but we are going to
get started because i know we are the
only thing keeping you from your drinks
uh this afternoon so we are going to be
talking about a controller the new
state-sponsored threat to industrial
control systems my name is
nathan brubaker i am a director at
mandiant i manage the cyber physical
intel focus area as well as information
operations i'm joined today by keith
keith hi everyone i'm keith london i'm
the manager on mandiant's cyber physical
threat analysis team so i manage the
team that focuses on threat actors and
activity targeting ics and ot
so our plan for this presentation is to
first give you an overview of what in
controller is and some of our initial
observations next we're going to do a
deeper dive on the actual malware
families that comprise in controller
we developed a couple of high-level
attack scenarios that we're going to
walk you through to help put this in
context
after that we're going to highlight just
some initial observations on attribution
and we're going to close out with some
high-level considerations that we want
you to think about
all right so before we get started i
just wanted to you know give some shout
outs and thank yous a lot of folks here
get to work on similar types of stuff
like this but for those of you who don't
this takes an immense amount of time
it's like months and months of work and
very late nights so thank you to
everyone at mandiant up on the screen
and those who are not and a huge thank
you to all of our partners at us
government and certainly our industry
partners including schneider electric
who's here this year so thank you again
all right
so uh as background before we kind of
jump into things i wanted to give a bit
of well i get a lot of questions on
twitter from customers so on and so
forth about like well honestly from this
all the way back to triton uh you know
who's the victim where did this come
from all that kind of stuff and the
reality is you know we work for a global
intelligence organization that gets
information from a lot of different
places so in this case uh we can't tell
you explicitly where this came from but
i can give you some insight we routinely
collect information from you know our is
the response engagements from our
partnerships as well as from some of our
independent research so that's kind of
where this came from
so hopefully that's good enough but uh
to give you an idea we started working
on this analysis really early this year
on our own quickly realized that we were
uh that this the malware really impacts
a number of different uh vendors and so
we reached out and have been working
with many of them closely since
again early this year and so a huge
again shout out thank you to schneider
who's partnered with us uh for much of
our research
finally in controller for those who are
not aware directly relates to sisa alert
aa22103a as well as the schneider
bulletin and codesys advisory as well as
dragoos there's some overlap with
drago's pipedream reporting
so what is in controller at a high level
it is a piece of malware that targets
industrial automation machines that is
comprised of these kind of three
components so the first one which is tag
run targets opc ua servers and it is
built to do recon and can provide some
level of attack support keith's going to
go into a lot more detail after a couple
of slides and i give you kind of this
overview but it's helpful to kind of
have an understanding as we talk about
through some of the initial
observations we've had so that's tag run
code call is uh target schneider
electric controllers it communicates
over
modbus as well as code sys and it's
extensible so it's got an ability to
expand out its capabilities it has
functionality related to kind of lower
level disruption
all the way up to kind of targeted
destruction and
that kind of attack so i think kind of
like triton level of work
shell is a framework that targets omron
plcs and it's got similar capabilities
ranging from lower sophistication all
the way up to disruptive and targeted
kind of destructive attacks
so that's what falls under incontroller
for us we also track this uh as rock
driver exploit and what we call ice core
which is a
kind of i t focus command and control uh
slash recon tool that keith will go into
a bit more detail i think dragos tracks
this all together under their pipe dream
name we have reason to not do that and
so we kind of separate these out
to give you an idea about well for your
visual learners but also to kind of
understand how this all plays together
we juxtaposed it against the our version
of the purdue model so you can take a
look up at the top here uh tag run again
targets opc ua servers so it kind of
falls into three and four then if you
look at the exploit and ice core uh
pardon all my fancy graphics here but uh
those kind of could be used from level
two all the way up to level four uh we
do have reason to believe though that it
potentially could target primarily
intermediary systems so this would
probably be more likely to be used at
level two and level three
then down at the bottom here we have
code call and um shell targeting more
kind of hardcore traditional ics devices
all right so moving on to some
observations before keith really digs in
first there's quite a lot of code and
it's really complex the
malware is well written and this kind of
contrasts pretty significantly against
triton some of the other ics malware
that we've done analysis on it probably
would have taken a team of engineers and
subject matter experts
many months if not more to write
and they probably would have needed a
lab so that kind of gives you a sense
about the amount of of money and
resources that went into this
the attacker definitely if they're
looking to carry out some more targeted
cyber physical type attack similar to
triton or something of that consequence
would definitely need additional i.t
tooling to support earlier stages of the
attack life cycle so this that kind of
attack generally requires many months on
target to prepare for and also
eventually carry out so to to gain that
kind of dwell time you need either
custom or off-the-shelf tooling to
support that we don't have any of that
at the moment but it's something to keep
in mind
so the incontroller tooling is comprised
again of these three components
it's important to understand that
theoretically each of these components
could be delivered to any number of
target environments
independently and or we think equally
likely deployed to the same or a small
set of of targets under the incontroller
kind of
tool set
so i mentioned before the code is
extensible and modular at least parts of
it are and this provides the actor with
the ability to pretty easily increase
the number of targeted devices as well
as increase the capability
and functionality we actually have
reason to believe that the actor
intended or has already built additional
functionality to support their efforts
so devices that are targeted explicitly
in the code and also stuff that is kind
of impacted based on uh overlapping
technologies and things like that uh
are generally present in kind of
machines that are
in a
that are sold by a reseller or something
like that so an an asset owner may not
actually know that they have these
devices in their networks which is
something certainly to consider
that all said there is a very good
chance that based on our research that
this tool and
honestly we think probably it's meant to
be used together is meant for a a
specific target or
small number of targets
and finally
we as we mentioned in the title think
this is very likely state sponsored
keith's going to go into that in a
little bit more detail in a minute but
uh we also have some evidence not much
of it unfortunately we can share here uh
that links this to some russian nexus
and you know we usually don't go into
that level of detail but we thought it
was worthwhile for this considering the
current geopolitical environment and
kind of how this can then be actioned by
defenders
so
on to keith
thanks so i'm going to cover each of
these tools and also those two
supporting windows tools as well so
first to talk about tag run it's best to
describe this as basically an ics
reconnaissance tool and potentially an
attack support tool that's targeting opc
ua servers and data so if you're not
familiar with opc essentially its job is
to collect what might otherwise be
disparate ics data
coming from different plc devices that
might otherwise only speak
vendor proprietary protocols so opc
centralizes that data and gives you a
singular view into
the different ics devices on the network
and also the status of those devices and
the overall process
so it stores that information as tags
which is why we chose to call this piece
of malware tag run and keep in mind this
is opc ua not opc classic so it can run
on windows
linux systems and potentially embedded
systems as well
so to run through the malware's
execution basically first it has some
scanning functionality it does an icmp
ping sweep
to look for open ports and ip addresses
to scan them for the presence of opc ua
servers once it identifies them it'll
try to connect using credentials that
the attacker might have already
harvested
similarly but with authentication
certificates but it also has a brute
force mechanism as well to try to gain
access
once the attacker has access they can
read the depth of the server structure
but also read and write opc tags so
that's why we think it has a
reconnaissance component to read the
tags and get an understanding of the
process but also potentially in a tax
support
component as well by overwriting
specific opc tags they can
manipulate what the operator might be
looking at and how they're viewing the
process even though they're masking uh
some changes they might make in the
network
so the implications of this activity are
really similar to the opcda component
that's an in destroyer and there's a lot
of really great literature open source
literature on that topic so i encourage
you to read there further if you want
some more information
so next i'll cover code call so this is
a disruption and attack tool that is
targeting some schneider electric plcs i
think this piece of malware requires the
most nuance to to appropriately discuss
at its highest level it's actually a
framework for interacting with modbus
enabled devices but it's extensible with
additional plc specific device attack
modules so when we say that incontroller
is extensible we're primarily referring
to this tool
so first to cover the modbus component
it's pretty straightforward it can scan
and connect to modbus enabled devices
and then read and write specific device
registers
so if you overwrite a modbus register
that can impact how the plc is executing
ultimately resulting in some potential
change to the physical process that it's
controlling
more interestingly so there is a device
module that's targeting the schneider
electric tm-251 plc
so there's a similar kind of
identification component where it will
scan for schneider electric devices
then it'll try to connect to that device
using schneider electric's machine
expert or sew machine protocol which is
essentially their implementation of code
sys the programming
software so that's why we called this
code call
because that's a really widely used
programming language
so
it'll try to connect using a brute force
mechanism it has a hard-coded dictionary
list that it uses passwords from to try
to to try to log onto the device if it
successfully connects it essentially has
engineering workstation-like
capabilities so it can change the device
configuration it can change the control
logic
ultimately affecting how the physical
machines are operating
lastly it does have some additional
disruption capabilities
for instance there's a denial of service
capability there's a separate crash
function and there's some simpler
capabilities like file deletion
so next i want to distinguish between
the devices it's actually targeting
versus those that it's impacting
so aside from the modbus functionality
all of those other components are
implemented in the context of a device
attack module and the only module that
exists is the one for the
tm 251 plc which i'm showing here in the
center of the presentation
so this is a pretty versatile plc it can
be used for
a number of different applications
schneider describes it as supporting
modular machines in distributed
architectures
there's also some use cases for
substation automation so it's a pretty
versatile plc
and that is the only major attack module
that we've identified although we did
find a second reference to a second
a device module which is targeting the
tm 221 plc which here i have shown on
the left side of the screen
i'm showing some of the specs just so
you can compare amongst those two
devices but essentially it only has a
fraction of the ram and flash memory
capacity it's for much smaller use cases
and schneider electric describes this as
supporting simple repetitive machines
so lastly there's also a component that
targets
the tm 258 potentially in the hard-coded
list of usernames and passwords
it references that m258 username and it
tries to log on using that username so
that could be indicative of targeting
that device as well although we didn't
identify an attack module for that
device
so we didn't find again any evidence
that the malware is targeting any other
devices but there are a lot of other
impacted devices
so some other schneider electric
devices particularly those in that
modicon family
series of plc's are potentially
vulnerable to the entirety of code call
so when you look at some of the alerts
and they cover some additional devices
they're primarily talking about that
those devices are impacted but not
necessarily explicitly targeted by the
malware
there's a broader problem in that the
malware implements code sys because
that's a really widely deployed and
popular programming application for plcs
so given that it implements that library
it's potentially
compatible with a lot more devices and
vendors because a lot of
other systems utilize that
but i distinguish between this and the
prior point just because some pieces of
the malware are still targeted towards
schneider electric devices like
potentially the identification module
and some of those username and passwords
that i mentioned
and also i'll just mention that it does
have that modbus component that's
implemented outside of the device
specific modules so it can potentially
target any modbus enabled device
there's nothing too new here because we
know that modbus is very insecure
although now we can consider that the
risk is going up since risk is a
function of threat activity times
vulnerability times impact
so next we'll talk about omshell so
omshell is a similar framework this time
targeting omron devices and through a
very different
execution cycle
so it can also scan for omron devices
using three different mechanisms it'll
check the mac address of the device
it'll parse the http response and it'll
use the fins protocol fins being the
factory
interface network
service which is a proprietary
protocol from omron
so after it identifies omron devices it
primarily uses http to administer the
device
it will query for different types of
information it can essentially change
the configuration and again ultimately
impact how that plc is executing
and the physical processes that it's
responsible for
you can also read and write values of
connected devices so not just that plc
but other devices connected over
ethercat it can change and read and
write their values as well
it can also execute the telnet daemon to
initiate the telnet service on the
device and transfer over an arbitrary
payload uh potentially a shell that's
why we called this particular
malware family om shell
there are also some other disruption
capabilities they're not extensive as in
code call but it has some simple
capabilities like for example wiping the
memory
and lastly it also has a servo module so
that it can explicitly interact with
servo drives that are connected to the
plc
if you're not familiar with servo drives
they essentially convert
electrical power into precision motion
control so you can think of like robotic
applications that do pick and place
types operations or anything else
involving that type of precision motion
control
so it's a little bit less clear-cut
which devices armshell is explicitly
targeting versus those that had impact
but we found a couple of references to
specific plcs and an add-on module to
those plcs
so in a couple of places it references
this nx
1p2 and nj 501
series of plcs this is actually the cpu
unit of like more of a modular plc
solution
so these are both also involved in
advanced motion control applications
with one of them being
more for compact solutions and the other
being a bit more versatile for larger
faster solutions
there's also a specific reference to one
servo module servo drive and omron
actually offers 22 different omron servo
drives in this r88d
family of servo drives and we just see a
reference to one particular one so that
could be indicative of reconnaissance
and to some targeted victim or it could
just be a reflection of the attacker's
testbed environment
so i also mentioned that amchel does its
initial identification by doing some mac
address comparisons
and i wanted to list here some of the
different actually the omron specific
mac addresses it looks for so one is
related to their electronics division
but there are also two specifically
looking for the healthcare
division of omron so while that's a
little bit
lower fidelity in terms of explicit
targeting i think it's worth noting to
highlight the the range of potentially
impacted industries
so next to talk about other impacted
devices so again the primary protocol is
http that it does to administer the
device
so potentially any other plc's that
omron makes that are primarily
administered over
http could potentially be impacted and
or targeted by this malware
unfortunately omron doesn't have a lot
of documentation that talks about their
http protocol or api
availability for some of the plcs but we
know that there are others in the nj and
nx series of plcs and so again when you
see some of the public reporting listing
other omron devices i think they're
referring to impacted devices and again
not necessarily explicitly targeted by
the malware and i think that's a
distinction worth making
so we know some of those devices
potentially support it as well but there
could be others from omron and that's an
area of ongoing research
so lastly i'll cover those two windows
tooling
devices that we mentioned as well so one
is a pretty straightforward
implementation of an exploit targeting
the as rock
driver
again it's straightforward so we didn't
bother to classify this in a malware
family but potentially this could be
used in the it or ot network
with again potentially some
some types of systems in the ot network
actually leveraging this motherboard
the more interesting tool is ice core
that's a commanded control and itot
reconnaissance tool and here when i say
reconnaissance i'm talking about the
traditional
network intrusion level reconnaissance
where the attacker is looking for
different systems and assets on the
network to exploit them and gain further
access so again there's a command and
control tool it implements
cnc over ssl and it has a couple of
different capabilities related to
for example doing wmi and enumerating
directories
so next nathan will talk about some
high-level attack scenarios that we
developed to kind of elaborate on these
tools
yeah thanks keith
so you know we have limited information
on what the attacker's intent is related
to in controller so we thought it'd be
helpful to kind of mock up some
different scenarios to give you an idea
about what is theoretically possible
with the tech so in each of these cases
well first of all if you want more
information we're going to be pretty
high level on this check out our blog we
go into a bit more detail but for each
of these scenarios it kind of expands
from a lower sophistication scenario on
up to destruction in scenario three so
uh for all of these we kind of
made an assumption that tag run would
probably be used to enumerate and do
recon certainly uh for scenario three
and lesser extent as you move back down
to one
it's going to need a the attacker will
need a decent amount of information on
the physical process to actually plan
out an attack and be successful so let's
just jump into it scenario one this
would be something similar to in
destroyer one or two for that matter
and where the actor would leverage kind
of the lower level functionality to
cause some sort of disruption which
could shut down operations it'd be kind
of less severe but still would make a
point and statement scenario two is
similar to stuxnet for example where the
actor could
carry out some sort of industrial
sabotage and then leverage tag runs
functionality to potentially hide that
and let it carry on for a long period of
time something like that scenario three
would be akin to
triton for example where the actor could
leverage armshell to target specifically
omron
safety plcs
leverage that access to
allow for an unsafe state to persist and
then go back and leverage other accesses
and capabilities to actually make that
unsafe state occur which could then
spiral into some theoretical physical
destruction this is similar to what we
expected in triton from
from that kind of attack perspective so
let me pass it back over to keith for
attribution and then we're going to wrap
up with a couple of takeaways yep so
when we did our reverse engineer of in
controller we didn't identify any
obvious overlaps with any previously
tracked groups so right now we're
tracking this as a new cluster of threat
activity we think it's very likely that
this is state-sponsored for a few
different reasons
one it's a really complex tool two it
probably required a significant amount
of investment in terms of expertise and
resource costs and three there isn't
really a obvious utility that other
financially motivated threat actors
would
would be motivated to to use this tool
for so it's very likely state-sponsored
we found some initial circumstantial
evidence that this is a russian nexus
unfortunately we can't share too much
information about that publicly at the
moment but i think it's worth mentioning
giving the current geopolitical context
and the history of russia's
threat activity targeting ics uh so here
we're displaying kind of a high-level
history of a lot of what they've done
and
basically to cover it since 2014 we've
seen them target ics uh through a number
of different espionage campaigns cyber
physical attacks uh sometimes the
malware is leveraging specific ics
exploits so for instance piece pipe back
in 2014 this is some of what was covered
in the
department of justice indictments that
were released last month
in 2015 they leveraged black energy
to target different types of
internet exposed hdmis
there was multiple attacks targeting the
ukrainian power grid so there's a long
history of russia's attacks targeting
ics
more broadly a lot of the capabilities
that we found in controller are
consistent with some of those attacks so
for instance in the different ukrainian
power grid attacks they did some ics
manipulations followed by a lot of
discrete disruptive events
wiping windows systems wiping linux
systems
wiping embedded embedded assets bricking
serial to ethernet converters so the
overall strategy they've employed in
some of those attacks is really
consistent with the capabilities that
we're seeing in controller
so we wanted to end with some high level
considerations
basically open-ended questions that we
think are worth thinking about
so the first one would be is how should
we
consider the threat posed by in
controller
so for example is this targeted towards
some specific victim like certainly was
in the case of stuxnet but also
potentially in triton
so you might recall in the trident
incident that the actor got control of
the ics network and basically
immediately deployed triton which was
tailored to a specific make and model of
a safety controller
so i mentioned a couple of times
throughout this talk that there are some
very specific devices that this
malware currently seems weaponized
toward so that could be indicative of
some type of reconnaissance into some
particular victims environment
now alternatively we could view this as
a capability so rather than focusing on
the devices it's targeting think about
some of those protocols that it
implements like
codesys and opc ua and modbus so that
gives it really a broad use case across
a lot of different environments
and has potentially a repeatable
capability like we saw within destroyer
so i think another question that's worth
thinking about is
go back one slide
i've gotten this one
oh yeah what industries are most likely
to be targeted
so there were some initial analysis
reporting that it could be utilities as
a primary focus of this
utilities have been the focus of a lot
of prior activity but when we look at
some of the devices that are impacted by
this
like for instance those nano plc's that
have a lot of use cases in standalone
machinery
i think it's much more likely that we
see some sort of manufacturing like
target and a lot of different
environments use these plc's all flavors
of manufacturing like
automotive aerospace
even food and beverage and other types
of service industries like for example
shipping could use a lot of these
different types of machines so i think
there's a really broad applicability of
these and that's important to get the
messaging right so that all the
different affected
companies and organizations know to
potentially look out for this malware
and that it poses a risk to them yeah to
be clear on that point we don't have any
information to indicate a very specific
sector or we obviously would have told
you
instead as keith mentioned we really
want to expand the aperture here if you
have these devices on your network you
should definitely figure that out and
mitigate any risk to them so
if people are telling you otherwise you
should ask them why and look for
evidence
all right so that's the gist of our talk
i think we got four minutes so uh
just to highlight some of the things
that we can provide you if you have
customers or if you yourselves are
impacted our blog has a bunch of
different uh mitigations and hunting
rules and things like that we're hoping
to rule more stuff out over time so
check back there if you are interested
in any of that but that's it for us
thank you so much we appreciate your
time and we will see you at the cabana
session
thanks