[Music]
[Applause]
hello everyone
so in destroyers back
that's going to be the main subject of
uh my talk my talk today but it's not
going to be the only thing
we're going to focus on we'll also put
the attack into perspective and and
cover also the context that it's
happening and also look at the other
attacks
that we've been
seeing that we've detected
in ukraine since the beginning of the
russian invasion as well as in the past
eight years so i'm glad to be here uh as
a last-minute presentation so thank you
for thanks dale for for having me and
and
that we were able to set this up uh so
last minute uh it's my first time uh
here at s4 although i did speak
at dale's
conferences in stockholm
on the early
earlier cyber attacks in ukraine which
i'll mention uh very briefly as well so
this is the agenda that we have for
today
i'll begin with uh
a recap of the original in destroyer uh
the first version in 20s that we
detected in 2016.
uh i'm sure for you for this audience
this needs very little introduction
uh as uh you all read all the
publications about it and i guess some
of you maybe even worked analyzed it
yourselves or were somehow uh part of
that investigation uh for the but it's
been over five years so so i'll do a
little memory refresh so that we can
compare
uh the functionality and the changes uh
in the new version that we discovered uh
on the 8th of april um the malware
wasn't deployed by itself uh there was
other malware involved in that incident
so we'll briefly discuss that as well
and then we'll continue
as i mentioned putting all of this into
perspective and talking about talking
about some of the the attacks the most
notable attacks that the perpetrator uh
the san juan apd group has been up to
okay so uh
a few words about myself robert lepowski
i work for eset i've been doing
threat intelligence research for over 15
years now
i lead a team of researchers in
bratislava slovakia so what i'm going to
be presenting today is not my personal
discoveries but it's very much a team
effort and the main credit goes to my
colleague anton cherepanov
and our focus in our team it's not ics
centric instead our coverage is is
pretty broad so
we
we look at we investigate we track and
analyze
uh apts nation-state actors but also
e-crimes or regular cyber crime that's
financially motivated and we also do uh
some uh actual technical vulnerability
research as well so pretty broad
uh scope
for those of you who
uh don't know eset so we're a company
based in slovakia and we're actually the
biggest
uh
internet security provider in the
european union
um
the fact that allows us to have all of
this visibility and and and to
what it enables me to uh bring to you
the things i'm going to be talking about
today is that we're also
uh the most widely used security vendor
in ukraine
so we do we do endpoint security and edr
xdr all that stuff but we also provide
threat intelligence uh feeds to our
subscribers as well
so let's get on with it uh in industry
one in 2016.
so i'll first talk about the malware
itself uh its architecture uh so that we
can compare it to to the new version
and along the way i'll i'll
mention the impact and compare the
impact as well uh so the first version
of industry was uh as it's often called
it's it's a modular framework so so
there was a lot of components involved
in there there it begins with the main
backdoor uh it that establishes
persistence uh on the system and and it
uh makes sure that it stays persistent
so there's even additional back door in
case the first one uh gets uh gets
removed somehow uh they're accompanying
tools as i mentioned there's the port
scanner there's the denial of service
tool we'll get back to that in just a
second because that's really important
then the back door
launches a launcher component and that's
in charge of
executing the most important parts
which are these for payload at a
specific
time so that time is hard-coded in the
malware
and it was set to december 17th
uh sometime before midnight about an
hour and a half before midnight well
that was utc time so around midnight in
ukrainian local time
and
it
what makes the malware unique and and
when we discovered it it sort of uh blew
our minds because this i mean we
uh we detect new malware every single
day and we detect malware that's
probably worthy of mentioning and
speaking about
uh because it's unique in some way every
month i suppose but for us to
find this malware that's able to to
speak
with industrial uh hardware with
protection relays and remote terminal
units
in using using these industrial
communication protocols that's something
that we have never seen before
and industry basically joined this elite
league of malware that can be counted on
the on the fingers of just one hand
that's directly uh
affecting industrial
hardware uh the others being like
stuxnet and heavyx and and then triton
that came after it
okay so uh
again this is just a refresher so i'm
not going to go into all of the details
about uh all of these
communication protocols that's not
necessary
but i'll focus on this one just just a
little bit further and that's iec 104 so
it's a protocol based on tcp
it operates in one of these modes range
shift or sequence and its functionality
is very dependent on the configuration
that the malware is supplied
uh this is an important thing to note
and and that's also a differentiator
from the new version uh here with
indestroyer one uh the configurations
were separate any files and there was a
separate configuration for all of these
payloads these payloads themselves were
implemented as dlls that were basically
part of the framework so here's an
example of what such such a
configuration file for this payload
could look like it has the target ip the
ports pretty standard stuff asdu
it operates on
ios information object addresses
goes through
can go through a range of these and it
can also
operate in parallel so targeting
different uh different stations
uh simultaneously
um
the code
tells us basically what what it's doing
so so it's producing uh command line uh
output and also a log file so that kind
of gives us an idea
about its capability
um
from a high level perspective and just
to really simplify it its main
functionality is to change the state of
the circuit breakers uh between open and
closed
so it can either change those uh
discrete values or it can also
uh depending again on the configuration
it can do a strobing effect so switching
between uh open closed back and forth
okay so there were there were also these
these other ones and all of those were
executed and targeted different parts uh
different different different equipment
different remote terminal units at that
electricity uh electrical substation
but that was not the only thing so so
these were the components that were
there in place to to cause the impact of
de-energizing
uh the grid but that impact was
amplified by
by other modules that were there in
place and there was a wiper component uh
that's the one
again launched by the launcher
that you can see that you can see here
and its purpose
obviously it was to amplify the impact
by making
uh
making recovery efforts more difficult
so that the operators would have a
harder time
uh getting power back online it would
take them offline they basically denied
them visibility and control of what was
going on in that substation so this is
this is a significant part to the attack
it was it was going after specific uh
software's the specific machines running
scada software the examples that you can
see here so it was wiping the files uh
that are the configuration files for
some of these uh
scada applications
but also it will continue to
corrupt
the registry and reboot the machine and
effectively make it make it unbootable
but there was another component to the
attack and that was a denial of service
functionality implemented by as i
mentioned in the in the overview by the
denial of service uh
component and this abused a
vulnerability that was in siemens uh
cyprus devices this was not a zero day
so so
a patch for that uh vulnerability had
been made available uh by siemens
nevertheless
it was abused by the malware uh
technically it's it's not that special
it's but sen it's sending a specially
crafted uh packet to udp port 50 000. uh
this is an example this is this is
actually what it looks like and the
effect of sending this is that
or the way that it causes the denial of
service of these protection relays is
that it effectively uh sends them into a
firmware update mode and as you're all
very well aware when you update the the
operating system on your phones or on
your on your laptop uh you pretty much
can't use it right so that's the basic
idea here with this with this exploit
that uh these protection relays would
not be doing their job uh
and
why were they doing that why why were
the attackers trying to
uh
to do that so we have the
de-energization we have the wiper module
denying the operators visibility and
control and then then we have protection
relays
being taken offline so when the
attackers would uh go into manual mode
and try to restore power uh during the
incident then this could have the
potential of causing physical damage to
equipment all that being said this all
this capability is in stark contrast
with what was actually
actually achieved
by industry so
it did cause a blackout
the blackout lasted for about one hour
but i think we can all agree that that's
not the worst that they could have done
and
the intended impact the intended damage
that they were trying to cause which was
much much
much larger
so with that
let's move on to in destroyer 2.
this was a collaboration with with sir
eway
so so thanks to them we were able to
analyze
the malware and they also
released their report
on it so that's the screenshot that you
can see here
and
uh
really a hat tip to them for
being able to to thwart the attack and
and and to basically mitigate it and not
allow another another blackout to happen
they certainly learned a lot of their
lessons from the past
and
uh when i said that in destroyer the
first version didn't achieve its goals
well industry two didn't even achieve
that so that's a positive thing uh so in
terms of impact uh
some of those things have already been
published
i think we can all appreciate the
sensitive nature of all of this so for
example i'm not going to name the
affected uh company the it's a regional
regional
electricity
distributors so in ukraine they call
them obel energos or from oblast which
is which is a region
um but they decided not to not to name
this because of the situation that's
going on uh what has been uh published
is that this area
uh provides power uh or or that this
company provides power to uh power in an
area that serves uh over two million
people so had the attack been successful
uh that means that
potentially two million people would be
left in the dark in the situation that
ukraine is in
okay so uh here's a little bit of
timeline uh and and some time stamps of
what was going on
so all of the all of it was uh was uh
launched through scheduled tasks
uh we saw that at 1500 hours universal
time
uh the sandworm uh operator created this
scheduled task to launch in destroyer
and that industry itself executed at uh
16 16 10 universal time and i'll fill in
that
timeline later on and i'll add
additional context to that
um there are a lot of differences in
terms of architecture when we compare
industry two with with in destroyer one
uh and it looks like it's
from an architectural perspective it's a
lot simpler um it's implemented as a
single executable
uh
that executable
uh according to the compilation
timestamp unless it was uh it was
tampered with of course
but what we quite often see is that
these attackers don't really bother that
much so so i think we can believe in
this compilation timestamp and if valid
then that means that the malware was
compiled about two weeks before it was
actually deployed
an overview of of some of the main
differences between industry 2 and and
the original version so i said it's
simpler and and it only implements one
of those uh
ics communication protocols that the
original industry did specifically iec
104.
um i don't want to speculate why why
they only specifically chose this one i
guess
uh that's what they uh
established would would be most
effective for them i'm sure uh the the
ics experts here in the audience will be
able to provide even better explanations
uh than i can um i already mentioned the
simpler arctic architecture so deployed
as only as a single executable
but it's but it wasn't so so it wasn't a
framework with with dls and plugins uh
as as the earlier one but it
other pieces of malware other
executables were co-deployed and i'll
get to that in just a second
um i already mentioned the
configurations um so here the
configuration is embedded so it's not
standalone any files
everything is is there
which basically
allows us i mean with with the original
industry we basically were
doing guesswork because a lot of those
uh any files had not been recovered so
during the analysis we were
um
we were analyzing the capabilities of
malware what it what it what it could
have done and actually comparing that
with what it what was the uh what was
the outcome and and looking at the log
files but a lot of the configuration
files we did not have them uh here we
can actually analyze the configurations
and analyze uh the intentions a little
bit better
there are code similarities there is
code to reuse and i'll show that in just
a second
so here's uh here's the that embedded uh
configuration parts of it uh in the code
that i mentioned uh some of the
sensitive parts have been uh redacted
um
in terms of functionality it's trying to
accomplish very similar things to to the
original industry so um we we see
commands and and the um the parsing of
this config it's able to uh change the
states uh between open and close it also
has uh the the the capability of doing
the strobing effect as well
operates on on ios 2 so so from a high
level perspective very similar
functionality
and also the code looks like it's it's
been made from from a similar code based
like a refactored
source code
uh here you can see one example of the
similarities this you notice uh i want
to draw your attention to the similar
text strings being used in these two
functions
and then in this next one this this this
is a comparison of the piece of code
that actually constructs uh the
communication packets
uh
so yeah a lot of similarity there as
well
i deliberately
mentioned the
the log outputs of industry one so that
we can compare with what industry two
outputs and here as you can see here it
makes a lot less sense so so it is
providing something which looks a lot
like garbage not making our jobs uh
easier at all
uh so let's continue to talk about the
other malware that was deployed and as
you can probably guess
it's going to be something from from uh
the similar functionality that what
industry had
uh and it was a wiper it was wiping
wiping capability uh one of the
wiper malware that we detected being
co-deployed with in destroyer 2 was a
new version of caddy wiper i'm stressing
the part new because this was not the
first time caddy wiper that we uh
saw caddy wiper and i'll talk about the
other times uh later on
um otherwise caddy wiper pretty pretty
uh advanced uh wiper
um
not going to go into too much detail you
can read more in our publications uh
it's uh going over the see user uh
folders and and then the subsequent
drives from d onwards so wiping all
files with zeros and again corrupting
critical parts of the of of the hard
drive like the gpt the mbr and so on
making the machine uh unbootable
and here is how the deployment of caddy
wiper sort of fills into that timeline
that i showed you earlier
so a caddy wiper was actually executed
the first
on some of the machines there
running different operating systems
then it was uh the execution of industry
and then caddy wiper was scheduled to
execute again
on the same machine
that industry two was deployed
to
erase the traces of the of it being run
so that's this part on the left uh and
then there were uh the components
targeting the other uh operating systems
so it was not not wipe the wipers
uh not only featured for windows but
also for linux and for solaris uh
actually the launcher determines
uh as you can see here this sets up the
cron job and on the fly determines uh
the right wiper to execute depending on
the operating system
uh running there
what's
what's interesting here uh one more
thing to note is that uh with caddy
wiper uh not only was it was a refreshed
version but it also used a new execution
chain
and and the launcher for for caddy wiper
was actually
a modified a patched
uh
version of the ida pro remote debugger
and this is i think this is pretty
interesting because there's no real good
reason why i mean it's definitely not
there to to cover their tracks or make
it make it appear
uh innocuous uh ida pro is not used at
an electrical substation
we use it reverse engineers analysts to
to do this analysis so
uh it looks like they've been trolling
us
okay so
since we're don't have that much time
i'll quickly go over this part where
we're going to
put everything
into context
so
sandworm isn't the only apt group
targeting ukraine and even
the list here is not comprehensive so
this is just the tip of the iceberg some
of the most noteworthy in my opinion
groups that
were targeting ukraine and that were
tracking
but as i indicated earlier we attribute
indestroyer to sand worm
sandworm has been attributed to the
russian gru
in 2020 the usdoj
released this indictment of these six
nice fellows
in case anyone
doesn't remember is wondering where the
name san juan comes from it's coming
from uh these strings so these come from
one of the early black energy campaigns
uh that we analyzed
um
and apparently
the authors were
fans of frank herbert's classic novel
so
let's put all of that
into context of the geopolitical
situation
we have seen
sand worm attacks
even before these dates
like
in 2012 for example but they really
intensified
towards the end of 2013 and the
beginning of 2014.
um here's just one example uh and black
energy targeted a lot of different
sectors in ukraine government diplomatic
military
and critical infrastructure you name it
it was using mainly spearfishing
campaigns to disseminate the malware
i would in my opinion the most notable
campaign was this one because it was
using a zero day
within a microsoft powerpoint
so this was pretty significant on their
part uh so when the recipient would open
this attachment again with the
geopolitical context so this was
referring to the warren donbass that was
actually just starting
um
on the end even with the with the users
having the latest and greatest uh
operating systems and and office
everything up to date the malware would
be would be installed
um
then the most significant event uh was
uh was the power outage in december
2015.
this was facilitated i want to highlight
facilitated by blackout so black energy
opened the door for the attackers it
wasn't doing it programmatically as
indestroyer was doing uh
one year after that
then there was an evolution of of of
this group we actually track san
sandworm and different subgroups
belonging uh to these attackers so there
was black energy there was in destroyer
uh we tracked uh the subgroup that
carried out the infamous non-petty
outbreak uh what uh to a subgroup that
we what we're tracking as telebots
intellibus is pretty significant
um not ptr will skip through that we
doesn't need too much uh introduction
uh
but
here this attack
basically originated from a supply chain
attack of emidoc
uh a legitimate software vendor a vendor
of
the most popular accounting software in
ukraine
and
then we know what followed it spread
beyond the borders of the country and
caused uh huge uh huge damage
but
that allowed us to
put together pieces of the puzzle
because
uh when we discovered and analyzed and
and then even as we published our
findings on in destroyer uh at the time
we weren't actually attributing it to
sand worm uh it was the most possible
the most probable explanation i mean it
makes sense when when an apt group uh
targets uh
this the same types of targets as as the
incident in 2015 it's it makes sense i
mean you would kind of expect that
and uh there were some
low low confidence um
indicators uh
being around but there was no
high there was no concrete evidence to
actually confirm these claims and uh
that proof
was actually we we we found it in april
2018 with exterminal so exterminal was
uh a back door uh deployed by the
telebot subgroup which we were able to
attribute
to
to sandworm
and that
allowed us to link it with industry so
there was actual code similarity with
the industry main backdoor
okay so
then moving on to more more uh recent
events
as you can see a lot of these things
they they have a common theme of
disruption uh they were wiping
capabilities wiping wiper malware
in all sorts of flavors such as hermetic
wiper for example
which we discovered only a few hours
before
uh the russian invasion began so
uh we published about that this was this
was pretty uh pretty busy at the time
and of course when we were doing this
this analysis we had no idea what would
happen just a few hours on february 24th
um
this affected various different
organizations in ukraine and again the
topic compilation timestamp suggests
that the attackers had been planning
that attack for some time in advance
um the other thing i'll note with with
the hermetic campaign is that it
contained these components so there was
the wiper there was the wizard which was
a worm component by the way also this in
destroyer two campaign uh
the the
wipers aimed at uh linux and solaris uh
also contained worm functionality to be
able to spread it along the the local
network
um but back to hermetic um so there were
these different components and and it
kind of resembles the from a very high
level perspective the mo of what we've
seen with no patio so it was able to
spread the spread the malware um across
the network as a worm
and what initially didn't make that much
sense there was a wiper component and
then there was like a fall ransomware
component so
why but apparently fall ransomware is
kind of a thing that they they're
they're doing
um this is the ransom message these are
these are some easter eggs uh hidden in
the code
and then as i said there were a lot of
these there were
various different wiper malware that
we've seen and i already already talked
about caddy wiper which was
used in the incident uh within destroyer
2 but it was not the first time that it
was used so the first time we
saw caddywiper was on march 14th
and then it led us to the events that i
already talked about
so to wrap this all up um
the attackers
sand worm they're they're doing they're
trying to accomplish two main objectives
with with all of their attacks the first
category is espionage and data
collection and the other type is is the
destructive uh
capability for sabotage for signaling uh
these two are not mutually exclusive so
so in a lot of the cases we will see
that they are doing uh espionage trying
to collect uh data and then
pave the way for the most more visible
attack for the disruption
okay so
with that we're almost at the end
um what do we do about it well obviously
we detect the malware and we also
provide uh threat intelligence to our
sub subscribers
but we also since it's such an important
topic we also like to share um publicly
so so you can find a lot of
those publications here on our blog
we livesecurity.com and on our twitter
eset research
so with that i thank you and maybe we
have time for some questions
and i might have answers yeah sorry or
might not should i come here first um i
have a question you mentioned that the
attack actually well this time the
attempt of the attack was to stop before
it happened
uh
if possible to say do you know what
happened there like was it caught by any
detections did you find it in the
process maybe it failed or something do
you have any details on that
uh
i have some details uh we did uh detect
a lot of the malware and and then there
was active
uh
active thwarting so so from the
operators they they they were able to
get on it quickly and basically take
those machines offline um i don't have
all the details so i can't really um
provide much better explanation or
closer explanation to that um and also
because it's so sensitive so
both the affected utility and and search
uh
are not disclosing every detail
okay thank you
hey robert thanks for being here um
there's been some speculation about um
the supposed hastiness with which the
code was deployed or prepared
um can you talk a little bit about how
you see that whether it's
you your your team assesses that this
was rushed
and at all um you know uh coordinated
with what was going on on the ground in
ukraine uh kinetically thanks yeah i
mean um
it does appear as a step backwards right
i mean why why uh shrink the capability
and make make something you know slimmer
compared to the to the capabilities of
the original version
um
at this time we haven't identified any
errors coding errors per se uh there
have been errors made in the
uh in the original in destroyer version
uh i would say it's pretty early it's
too early to to actually judge the the
efficacy of of the malware and
the level as to which it was rushed so
hard to say
okay if there are any further questions
that popped your mind stop by or reach
out to me on twitter or anywhere thank
you
[Music]