please welcome your s4 program chair
dale peterson to the s4 main stage
it has been
27 long months
that i'm sure we're difficult for each
of us at times
but i'm so happy to be able to say
welcome back to s4 in miami south beach
[Applause]
welcome to the
797 attendees from 30 countries
welcome to the record
164 women
here at s4
[Applause]
yes this is progress but it's still only
represents about 20 percent of the
attendees
we have work to do
back at s 420 we had to limit the number
of tickets that were sold with access to
stage 2 technical deep dives because
the theater only held 200 people
and let's be honest stage three was kind
of more of a you know a bowling alley
than a theater
i'm pleased to say that this year we
have a 400 seat stage 2 and a 200 seat
stage 3 across the street at the elv so
your ticket gets you into all three
stages
after we did that we said well we
removed that limitation
what other limitations are we putting
on the event
so liz and i we looked at everything now
of course we kept what worked and what
you loved
but we looked at everything with a fresh
set eyes
from the program to the parties
from the stages to the swag
what do you think of the swag bag this
year
you know i
i did notice though that last night the
black hats
flew off the table there's none left and
we have a lot of white hats left and i
don't know what that says about you but
and as we looked at everything from the
focus of how do we improve the attendee
experience
and how do we help our create the future
mission
once we we did this we said we're going
to get even bolder we're going to make
the theme for s421 no limits
and we did this planning in february
and then the universe showed us some
limits
and
and it showed us some limits again in
december with omicron and quite frankly
we were tempted to go virtual and we
were even more tempted to just stop
doing s4
but i really believe that we need a
place where the leading edge of the ics
security community can get together to
accelerate progress
now i know most of you
and i have great faith and admiration in
you
i don't always agree with you
but i love the spirit and energy you
bring to the challenge
so our
s4 recipe to create the future is we try
to bring together a large group
of
the leaders in ics security the people
on the leading edge trying to drive
change
now all are welcome
but we really design the event for those
people
then we put you in a creative
environment something very different
than what you do day to day
and even different than you see at other
conferences
next we throw ideas at you new ideas
crazy ideas conflicting ideas
and then the last ingredient and i think
this one might be the most important
is we give you free time at social
events and other things for all these
ingredients to mix rise and bake
we have seen
at s4
some really great things happen
we saw for example at s420 there was a
session on ics for ics
and a session on plc secure coding
practices
those went from initial ideas over these
past two years
to actual projects that are in place and
making a difference today
companies themselves have been conceived
here at s4
and i would be remiss if i didn't note
that the beer isac
started very very late one night after
s4 around the surf comer pool
now the key to this
create the future thinking and
accelerated change
i believe is no limits thinking
yes the vast majority of people out
there still need ics security 101 they
need those knowledge and recommendations
and raised awareness
but that's only going to get us slow
linear progress
and quite frankly it's a slog
if you were one of those people in 2005
that said it's going to take decades
to secure ics
congratulations you were right
but you maybe should have said three or
four decades
now if you have to do that slog in your
day job that's understandable and i'm
sorry for you
but this is s4 damn it we have to do
different things here we're not going to
create the future by just working hard
the same way we've been working the last
two decades
it took us a long time to get back here
longer than i think any of us expected
we need to make this week worth it
so yes have fun
and yes
create and establish those personal
relationships that we've all missed so
much
but yes also come up with new ideas and
approaches to create the future
of ics security and ot
i have a few different ways for you to
do that
the first one and this is my favorite i
call the flip
basically you take
conventional wisdom some saying some
mantra
flip it over and look at the world as if
the opposite was true
so a great example of this is devops
we for decades people thought long
uptime long time between reboots was a
key metric for reliability
devops showed us that in fact
frequent tear down and rebuild actually
increased reliability
so here's one for you
all employees need to care and be
involved in security
we spend a lot of time and money and
handling how do i just get my employees
to care more
what if we flipped that
and said
employees should have little or no
security responsibility
now you don't need to believe that but
what would if the world were that way
what would you do
to make security effective in a world
where that were true
here's another one
you can't protect what you don't know
what if we flip that to say
don't even bother trying to create and
maintain an accurate asset inventory
now i know the acid inventory vendors
out there your blood pressure just went
up
take a deep breath
it's going to be okay
you don't again you don't have to
believe that but just imagine a world
where that were true
what would you do differently if that
were true
and the last one and this is quite
frankly my favorite
cyber assets need cyber hygiene
what if we flipped that and said we need
to live with dirty cyber assets
what would you do differently if that
were true
so technique one is the flip
technique two i call the literal
we have these mantras again
that we frequently say and mostly
believe
but we don't act as if they're true
now you guys probably all know the most
common one
ot
is different than i.t
have you heard that one before yeah
maybe said it once or twice yourselves
i find that what most people mean by
that is keep your i.t security good
practice crap out of my ot
but if we take that literally ot is
different than i.t
then shouldn't we be coming up with ot
security controls and other techniques
that are not used in i.t that are unique
to ot
and coming up with those so that we
reduce the chance of a cyber or a cyber
physical attack causing an unacceptable
consequence
so what are those if we take this
literally what are those ot techniques
so one the flip
two the literal
three
i don't have a third sorry
they always say in speeches you should
do things in threes and i only have two
but maybe i'll create it this week and
i'll tell you about it in the closing
panel
now
we are making progress in ics security
largely due to the hard work of a lot of
people in this audience
it's just
too slow
we're not going to get where we need to
go when you need radically new ideas and
approaches
now s4 is an environment where you can
create those new ideas
open your mind let yourself go take some
risks
i want to close with my second favorite
lord john maynard keynes quote
the difficulty lies not so much in
developing new ideas
as in escaping from old ones
so let's see if this week
we can use the the sun and the fun the
good sessions and great company to
escape those old ideas
now you might be wondering my favorite
keynes quote was what he said right
before he died i wish i would have drunk
more champagne
i look forward to seeing what you create
this week thanks