so we're going to spend the next 30
minutes having a nice discussion in here
i'm really happy with the turnout um
this is most people realize this kind of
what they would call the vendor stage as
you obviously realize i'm not a vendor
i'm a product i'm a solution specialist
in cyber security and industrial
automation and control and i'll be
sharing the stage of course with miss
mariam from phoenix contact who allowed
me the opportunity to share some insight
of what's been going on for probably
whoops
that was a good save probably what's
been going on since the world really
woke up to this in about 2010. so with
that we kind of are gonna use an
underlying theme about both recent
attacks as well as kind of a look back
on the past decade of attacks and
figuring out
why people are still succeeding
why are these attacks
still able to progress and now the big
buzz is
uh pipe dream and we'll obviously talk a
little bit about pipe dream because
there's a lot of hype being put against
something that there should be no real
reason to be afraid and to be
overly concerned assuming you've done
basic steps and we'll talk a little bit
about that so i'm glad that dale was
able to kind of shift things because
there was a lot of last minute changes
that were taking place so again slides
are available which is kind of a nice
new addition with s4 that dale was able
to do using that new whatever it's
called wowzawya
what is it
well hoover so that's a pretty slick app
so the presentations are there but
presentations for me for those and i'm
really happy to see a lot of my old
friends and colleagues and supporters
here as well as a lot of new people it
was good to be able to get a feel for
you all
by looking at the attendees coming in so
i want to set the stage and this
architecture for people that have known
me and work with me has been a staple
architecture for introducing teaching
and reinforcing cyber security for
industrial networks and the reason is is
that there's a lot that can be done with
this architecture and those that also
know me know i'm very outspoken on
people that oversimplify ics
architectures you know they'll show a
network with one hmi and one plc well
that's crap and we all know it and these
architectures really consist of dozens
or hundreds of controllers and dozens of
hmis redundancy across the bottom across
the top across the networks everywhere
so it's important to teach concepts
using some reference model that provides
some reality to how architectures are
built out and another thing about this
architecture it's actually be is is
presented based on fact when i've done
this in more of a closed environment
where we learn some of the hooks it
handles about it people say did you take
this from our architecture because what
i use this for is to teach a lot of
concepts around
not only the concept of cyber security
but resilience
so the buzzword of the day for me if you
looked at what was going on on the app
is resilience if you designed resilient
architectures last year all of this hype
is completely worthless you will ride
through it
easily another thing that's been going
on a lot in the app is all this issue
around vulnerability disclosure zero day
dropping vendor obligation to get their
patches done in 90 days if you saw my
responses i was a vendor for 20 years
that's never gonna happen i did a
massive project with emerson i've
discovered a vulnerability with their
dcs controller that impacted every
controller they ever sold every system
they ever sold over about a 10-year span
across the world hundreds of thousands
of controllers were impacted by it it's
not something that we could fix in three
months
because we had to test prove
reassure get the word out to the
community the internal community the
vendor or the
asset owners and fix it so what we're
going to go through today is kind of
this problem and why we're still seeing
a lot of panic around industrial
automation and control and that tends to
be people hanging on to the low hanging
fruit they tend to focus on the top side
and to this day it brings tears to my
eyes and it's the one thing that keeps
me up at night is people today still
believe the attack will always be
externally originated
so no matter what we say no matter how
much supply chain attacks have shown
their ugly face we are still seeing this
predominance to develop secure
architectures
under the sole premise that the threat
is always outside that door
and this architecture was built based on
all of the facts given to me from the
research team at mcafee as part of their
work on the night dragon campaign in
2010 it was an apt
attributed completely to china it made
its way into skate architectures it
never got press because stuxnet took
over the media waves
but what it showed was one very
important thing that happened if you
look down on the bottom right
the initial step was externally
originated there's no doubt about it it
was the chinese government we knew that
the attribution was hard firm but the
problem is is after the first step
the lateral pivot that occurred in step
one
made this person appear as a legitimate
trusted authenticated insider
so now all of a sudden what are you
doing to secure your architecture from
the insider
not the malicious employee but the
outsider that's able to masquerade and
appear as the insider
so that's what happens in this
architecture and as we start to pivot
through it and learn about it in both
offensive and defensive courses that
i've have is that you find it at the
very bottom of the architecture where
the real gold lies
the assets that are connected to the
physical world that cost far more than
the cyber infrastructure have far more
physical impact typically can result in
loss of life all of that is connected at
the bottom of this architecture which
tends to have little ability to be
defended using normal methods and means
and in this architecture for learning
purposes there are no vulnerabilities
down there
so all of a sudden you've used all of
the pivots and all of the chained
exploits at the top
to create a bag of loot that allows you
to compromise a system
in the presence of no vulnerabilities
so the way that we do that is through a
concept of understanding resilience and
learning how to secure architectures
from obvious things that should never
happen and move away from first
move away from designing for convenience
to designing for security so we'll take
this one slide we can go on and on i get
two slides i've got about 10 minutes to
keep this in
everybody knows about zones and conduits
okay so i'm going to give a huge
i i love what the isa 99 standards and
practices team i'm a voting member of it
the work there
initially led by eric cosman has been
revolutionary
but to be completely honest let's just
get a quick show of hands how many
people make the 62443 series the
foundation of their industrial cyber
security program
that's pretty good so i'm gonna say five
maybe ten percent
for me in an industrial world i don't
understand why it's not a hundred
percent
so a lot of people have a lot of reasons
and they're all well justified
isa 6243 doesn't have the global
acceptance that other standards like the
27 000 family does but the one thing
that's unique about 62443 is the
creation and establishment of zones and
conduits
and the reason that i always say this
nothing's changed nothing has changed
and
what's really interesting is that the
triton attack that occurred against
saudi
petrochemical algebale i actually was
the original architect on that system
in its first phase
so the system that got attacked was the
second phase attack second architectural
phase attack so i knew a lot about what
happened there and everything that
happened on that attack
would have been stopped dead in its
tracks if people had implemented the
model against the zones and conduits
concept
because the zones and conduits
concept allows you
to group items assets devices
that can't traditionally be secured
and to then secure the conduit that's
used for all communications that enter
and leave that particular zone
so what we see is going to go like this
there is no like that if you look in the
the diagram on that picture the problem
is is most people that haven't lived
this document
don't understand that we don't create
one big zone for our industrial control
system there is a big
macro zone but we really must start
creating micro zones
so i did a lot of
we'll just say anti-marketing against
the reference architecture that was
published by homeland security because
they still have not embraced the concept
that the security around active
directory
is very important
and very different than the security
around the engineering workstation and
the engineering environment
which is very different and equally
important to the security around the
operational environment right because
each one of those provides a different
service to the overall architecture
and the compromise of any one of those
could lead to the subsequent
consequences associated with any and all
others
so it becomes a real big challenge to
understand
why are we not creating subzones and
those sub zones should be based on
unique risk isa 62443 iec i should say
to be properly correct does a very good
job at making risk the cornerstone of
the establishment of zones that risk can
be through a lot of things like
implementing control on secure or
insecure by design controllers i hate
that word you guys know that hate that
word insecure by design because insecure
is relative to time
we thought windows nt was the greatest
thing in the world when we made the move
to windows in the 90s it was the most
secure operating system ever developed
today we laugh it's a joke so no matter
what we do and we got some people here
from bedrock automation that make the
most secure controller that's ever been
developed we hope that it will be that
way 20 years from now but who's to say
it will so i'm not a big fan of this
insecure by design
we need to learn how to secure things
with what we have today in a resilient
mindset so as i kind of move to this
last slide
in comes this concept
of what's being coined micro
segmentation
so what you see in here is the creation
of
subzones or micro zones
that allow you to implement granular
control that in every one of the common
and well-publicized breaches it would
stop them dead in their tracks
because it limits the ability of
services
based on the individual assets role
so for instance it's hard to see in here
um there's there's bigger i brought
bigger pictures of this reference
architecture if you take a look at
something like active directory
active directory should never
initiate
comms
with an asset
never
it's there to handle authentication type
services now i'm talking about the
domain services role within active
directory there's dozens of roles so
we'll focus on the key one domain
services
even a server that's running file
services file servers don't start
sessions with clients to start sending
things to them automatically
so you start to look at this the number
one gold mine in any hacker's playbook
is to go active after active directory
you do that so that once you have all
these credentials you can start to move
elsewhere well what if you can't move
elsewhere
that's where this starts to come into
play into this whole concept around
establishing these micro
segmented subzones
which you can then strictly enforce
communication
for instance engineering workstation
no comms should ever be allowed to start
outside of an engineering workstation
now you can never say never but in
almost all cases on an operational
system not a dev system but an op system
the engineering workstation is the
originator not the receiver
so when you start to look at this okay
you exploit an engineering workstation
but the ability to exfiltrate or
laterally move becomes
very difficult because of the micro
segmentation that's in place and the
enforcement that's placed on the
conduits associated with only a subset
of the authorized assets so what if an
engineering workstation allowed
no inbound access
you would start to say wow it kind of
makes that device appear
hidden to a lot of adversaries that
could jump on the network so with that
of course we're going to talk more about
this at the cabanas but now i get to sit
down and shut up that was my ten minutes
continuing with uh what joe was saying
is
we are focusing on micro segmentation
here and you know the base of zones and
conduits that he just talked about it's
great and we can see it on the image but
then we're not talking about flow of
communication right
do you know the flow of communication
that go that is going through your
operational site right do you know
exactly where the operator station is
talking to
is it supposed to talk to that is it
supposed to move uh vertically or is it
supposed to move laterally right so all
of that flow of communication is what
gives us uh pretty much the resiliency
or knowing that flow of information
would give us the resiliency within the
network if we secure those systems so
this is a slide where pretty much we're
used to this right we know that
north-south communications are supposed
to happen this is where ot cyber
security pretty much started we needed
or sea level suite people needed the
data that we were producing down right
at that bottom level how much are we
producing we need to figure it out
because we need to forecast how much
we're going to charge whatever that
process it is
so that connection needed to happen and
it just plugged pretty much in this is
where air gap got lost um
so this is the data flowing right we
know there is supposed to be production
data moving from the bottom
going up
because they need this information now
is there a reason is there a need from
communication flow
the other way back is there any reason
it or any other device up top of that
network on the office network on this
big graph
needs to flow down
i really don't think so right the data
that is on the bottom can still flow up
security data can still flow up to some
type of seam or some type of sock or
maybe host something at the middle but i
still need to cut you still need to
protect down at the bottom but now we're
focusing more
on the lateral east-west communication
flows right and this is where the
micro-segmentation starts happening
if you think about it i want you guys
all you all have an i.t department you
all have services
are they using firewalls
are they doing micro segmentations
within their own networks
of course they are that's still a thing
to protect networks
we need to be applying the same things
within operational sites they know the
flow of communication they know how to
micro segment their networks we need to
be applying the same concepts but the
way i like to do it or the way i like to
translate it to people is
there are some policies that they do but
we have to implement it the way we know
operations work right we cannot just
implement the firewall down there
because
it might interrupt that process
that's why information is really
important
so obviously we all know the concept of
a firewall it's like it's nothing more
than a police
traffic device that sits within a
network understands or
sits on the network reads the flow of
traffic and depending on the certain
rules that it's following it's like
you're allowed to go through you're not
allowed to go through that's as simple
as it goes um
there could be static or dynamically
configured they could be user configured
or they could be smart as well there are
now a days technology that the firewall
can actually save some steps for you to
be able to configure
that communication flow
now the traditional steps and if you
have not configured a file if you do not
have the it experience to be able to do
this um they're not really pretty
straightforward right
most of the time you need some type of
tap device or poor mirroring on a switch
to be able to gather the data traffic
right you have to gather the data the
second step is you have to analyze the
data it's understanding what's the ap
address coming from what's the ip
address going through and understanding
what ip address is it could be a plc a
user workstation it could be maybe the
theme or the sock log logs going through
the security room all of that is very
important to understand that's just the
ip address and that's how you start
mapping flow of data right we all know a
famous wireshark everybody probably
knows um here but that's a screenshot of
like a data packets uh that or permanent
image of a couple data flows that that i
gather
after that obviously you grab that data
analyze it as i just mentioned um
you can go obviously packet by packet
this is a lot of this is an exercise
that you're going to sit down and do you
can filter out or create firewall rules
that filter out mac address source and
destination mac address depending on the
network you can filter out the source
and destination port the source and
destination ip address and depending on
the type of firewall
you can even filter out
the the
application layer right so depending on
what you're doing you can even filter
out for example modbus
tcp connections these specific write
read
communication that that plc client
server are actually meant to be doing
and then obviously after you have
analyzed all these data then you have to
sit down in front of your file and
configure it sit down and say where's my
incoming traffic going through where is
that firewall sitting on the network and
where is the traffic flow
is that firewall rule that i read
incoming on the firewall or is it
outgoing some firewalls are stateful
which means they know the state of the
connection so you only have to configure
one way some firewalls are a little bit
less smart or connectionless what means
is you have to configure both ways
including the reply so it's one of those
things that allows you to kind of just
go through but overall that's how you do
it if you take a look at the screen you
go rule by rule this is from ip to ip
maybe the port numbers you're doing and
the actions specifically what do you
want to do with this do you want to
accept it
do you want to drop it maybe you can tie
it to an additional action because
depending on the firewall there's
advanced options
and one item here that is missing on the
screenshot is
do you want to log this and maybe send
it to a central log server which is very
important for
audits in the future right so think
about it if there is an incident and a
fire will cause something going through
that's the first thing they're going to
ask you where they are where are the
logs when you're gonna come and do an
audit
now i mentioned the difference between
uh
there are different types of firewalls
of course and we're gonna be focusing on
industrial firewalls a
stateful packet inspection means that
they can they know the connection states
so you just need one firewall rule that
will allow the reply to come through it
knows the state of the connection but at
that level you're also only filtering
mac addresses uh ip addresses imports as
basic as that
some industries some applications
majority honestly this is enough to do a
prop an appropriate micro segmentation
strategy within an operational network
some other industries they need a little
bit more and this is where you start
talking about the packet inspection
firewalls which as the name says it goes
all the way down to the packet layer and
filters for example a modbus tcp packet
function called pdu addresses and
think about the no two the level of
expertise it is not just from the it now
you need to have somebody that is an
expert
at the controller at the modbus who
configure that client server who really
knows what is the communication that has
to be that has to be happened between
maybe that scada room and that specific
controller right to be able to get to
this function code into the specific pdu
address probably that so you're not
going to have that unicorn it's really
tough to find somebody that can really
do firewalls that can really do modbus
tcp for example
now
this would not be a sponsored
presentation without a little bit of
information of the sponsor side of
course as you all know i
i work with phoenix contact i am the
senior product specialist for networking
and security or cyber security and we do
have available industrial firewalls but
i do want to
focus all of your guys attention i mean
you can see the pictures but i want to
focus on your guys attention on one
specific one
it is recently
it's pretty new i mean it's been
launched for a year but it's a really
nice firewall because
and it's that one right there on the
plastic casing actually the second from
the left
um
is the one in the plastic casing because
we actually added a very nice
functionality that you remember all the
steps that i mentioned to you before the
gathering the analytics and all of that
it's pretty much doing all of that for
you okay
so
and i had that of course
so we have a feature in there
i really really like it you don't it's a
really low cost firewall that you can go
ahead and get and test it out but
overall the only thing you have to do is
kind of put it on the network
start literally it's just a start button
the same way you see it on the screen
and as soon as you click that start
button for that specific functionality
within the firewall assistant that
firewall system is just kind of sitting
there you can leave it running for a
couple of hours or an hour depending on
how big your system is or how much flow
of data is going to go through
but think about it as on the operational
side
is there maybe logs that are sent every
month you don't want to leave that
running a whole month right but there
are that is another functionality that
will help you there we're focusing on
this one you click on that start button
you can go to launch and come back when
you come back and you click that stop
button
that firewall assistant will give you
the log traffic and it's not just just
going to give you the locked traffic
it's already giving it to you either if
it's incoming so if it started from the
external network into the internal
network or you will place it already on
the firewall rule
if it started from the incoming network
out so you already have that flow of
course it's not as smart as telling you
well 1.23 plc
and 1.4 is your hmi
but then that's what you are the owner
right you would kind of start mapping
out okay this should be the right there
is you know the type of poor 443 should
be https connection if you if you see
tcp 80 it's http or if you see standard
2 2 2 we already know rockwell or modbus
tcp is 502. this is how you start and
save some of the steps uh within the
specific firewall so it's not you know
there's still one more step that you
need to do as a user you want to come in
here and actually do the action right so
after you have analyzed a little bit
more you save some steps you what do you
want to do with the traffic
no traffic should be going out of the
operation going to an internet ip
address for example right so you want to
make sure that it's actually fully
blocked you can block that just change
the action that would be the only thing
and all that time that that little
firewall device is actually helping you
save within the configuration side
so of course we have additional features
within the different family of the
mguards we have a lot more advanced
features but i do want to leave
time for questions and
we any questions that you might have or
we will have um obviously a demo
within the cabana uh at four o'clock so
find the things contact cabana and i'll
show you guys this specific
functionality and obviously
any of the other additional features
within the m guards but
this is pretty much what i you know the
end of the slide or the last slide this
slide or this image joel put it at the
beginning and it was so easy for me to
say listen micro segmentation to zones
and conduits could easily be split out
everything where you say there is a
firewall there that's exactly what
they're trying a firewall will allow you
to do the micro segmentation will allow
you to separate those zones and pretty
much create the conduit that is gonna
secure the sounds
so that's kind of like the message i
appreciate everybody's time and we have
a couple of minutes for questions
we have uh we have the mic on the back
um there is different ranges of prices
and i'll be more than happy to get it to
you on the of the cabana but the little
eleven hundred doesn't go over seven
hundred dollars
see so you know i was saying how we stop
project or stop these these campaigns
dead in their tracks this particular
solution so i was one of the researchers
on dragonfly havocs and watching how
that thing initiated provoked and
started moving around all i did was
deploy this right away boom done another
thing for the security assessors that go
out in the field and actually do a lot
of this these devices i always have had
one in my bag whenever i deploy i have
it in my tool kit because when you're in
a bind and you're under pressure to
develop firewall rules you don't need to
do all these multiple steps i take this
device put it in line it's completely
passive let it run for a while and boom
you've got your firewall rules this
really paid off at
idaho national labs for the red team
blue team exercise well that's kind of
the whole key is initially getting a
handle on your network security we have
a question on the back
hi i think this question is for joel um
hey i'm right here i don't know
so um i agree with you know the premise
of micro segmentation and really
leveraging the principles within iec
62443 i think my question is before you
even get to that point i think there's a
lot of assumptions or things that you
need to do to prepare yourself in order
to do that micro segmentation especially
at level one level two and networked or
unnetworked assets so can you talk a
little bit about how you prepare to even
do that micro segmentation to save time
and to not have to do it continuously
and maybe manually well no this is
actually that's an awesome question and
you all got to hear it tonight's repeat
because probably the biggest step in
doing this is to understand the asset
exposure of each of the assets so of
course and no matter what document you
read outside of 6443 you're not because
the first step is is your asset
inventory once you have your asset
inventory and having done this for years
the biggest step is the prioritization
of assets
so you have to be able to look at your
assets and in the real world the
engineers that actually run these
systems know that all controllers aren't
equal there are controllers that are
more high priority in terms of loss risk
of loss potential impact should they be
compromised so you start to group your
assets and create a risk profile
then you see if your infrastructure can
handle it and i get really frustrated
when the first thing we have to do on a
project in order to deploy security is
to create this new network
infrastructure with all new managed
switches for instance there are ways to
do the segmentation through grouping
physically through what you have
and again it's still taking what could
be a flat level one network but creating
physical segmentation through the
establishment of independent switching
infrastructure so not converging
everything on a 48 port switch but
busting that 48 port switch possibly
into groups of eight where you can then
do that segmentation on the outbound the
connection or the uplink associated with
the eight port switch rather than trying
to manage that beast around a stack of
one two three four 48 port switches does
that help
thank you
so our time's up obviously with 30
minutes you can't do a lot but we sure
encourage you to come over to the
cabanas in a couple hours
and lots of pictures lots of discussion
demonstrations and lots of talk points
so again i really appreciate it thank
you guys thank you for coming
you