please welcome director easterly and
dale to the s4 main stage
[Applause]
[Music]
so welcome to s4 jen thank you we are so
happy to have you here i know you have a
very wide swath of things you have to do
and ics is just one of them but
we've got a lot of ground to cover so
i'm just going to jump in let's go let's
do it let's start broad
and then maybe we can
you know go down to the current events
if you look at 2022
2023 what are
two of the top two or three goals you
might have or objectives and and very
interesting on those i'd like to know
what kind of metrics how do you know if
you're succeeding yeah
well first of all i'm thrilled to be
here
thank you for having me
um just to step back a sec i think most
of this audience understands sysa
because i know my predecessor has spent
time here
but we were really set up three plus
years ago to be america's cyber defense
agency right to help reduce risk to the
cyber and physical infrastructure that
americans rely on every hour
of every day and unlike other
places where i've worked in my career
whether that's the army or the national
security agency or in counterterrorism
where the government arguably has
monopoly power
in cyber security we're just a partner
with private industry and our state and
local colleagues and so
you know particularly because the vast
majority of infrastructure is owned by
the private sector and so those
partnerships are so incredibly important
and among
you know one of my top priorities is the
security of industrial control systems
and operational technology and that's
why i was really excited uh to come down
here to be with this community
because this really has to be about
collective cyber defense and so when we
talk about the the goals dale
um i'll let me lay out three of them
okay um i'll try and use a little
alliteration with uh people process and
partnerships
uh people to me is always the most
important thing but in this case i'm
gonna start with process
uh process is not sexy uh but it is
super important and one of the things we
were asked to do by the white house in
july of last year based on what's called
a national security memorandum we were
directed to come up with
baseline goals
we call them cyber security performance
goals cpgs because you need an acronym
for everything in the us government as
you know
um and so we were asked to work with
nist
and to lay out the cyber security
performance goals and we did it across
about 11 categories from risk management
to vulnerability management to incident
response to data access to configuration
management all of that
laying out what the top line goal is
what the rationale for that goal is a
series of objectives and then to your
point about metrics
essentially sample
samples of evidence how can you show
that you've actually met those goals now
we were asked to publish the first
series of
ot goals by september of last year we
went out to the community the ics
working group and asked for their
feedback
they came back with some great feedback
we published an update that included
both ot and it in january since then
we've we've received about a thousand
comments
and so we're adjudicating one of the
uh the most popular comments was about
how do i think about this with respect
to the nist cyber security framework
that the private sector now has
thankfully gotten gotten very used to
well those of
us who are familiar with the csf it's
very very broad very um extensive
what the uh cybersecurity performance
goals are supposed to be they're going
to map to the framework but they're
going to lay out measurable actionable
and attestable and prioritized goals
baseline goals that that any
infrastructure owner or operator can
look to
and i can't stress enough how important
it is if you all have not seen these
goals please come to our website
check them out we are all about feedback
and improving and making sure that we
are working closely with community
particularly you know i know this is a
very sophisticated crowd of experts so
we can absolutely
use input and guidance and feedback so
please look at that we're adjudicating
guidance right now
we hope to get the baseline goals out
by fall of this year and then we're
going to do sector specific goals so
these range these are designed to range
across sectors and then we'll we'll work
with each of the critical infrastructure
sectors but again designed to be
measurable and actionable uh by
providing sample evidence so that's sort
of the process pieces before we move to
people let's let's talk a little bit
about that
so one of the questions i actually had
later down in my list here was
uh sis has put out a lot of yeah a lot
of information you know which is great
um and actually some of the things that
you've done i think have been excellent
from a marketing perspective the bad
practices guy or the bad practices list
the graphic novel i think really
engaging the community with different
types of messaging is good but one of
the things i've been confused on is
there's been a lot of guidance documents
like every time there's a new
in control or pipe dream or whatever any
any time
you put out these recommendations
they're
similar there's overlap but they're
different so if someone was to say what
is the one document i should look at
is it this document you just talked
about is that kind of the north star
that say they should say this is what we
should do and everything else is just
supporting material yeah that's the goal
that we're trying to get to right we're
trying to drive this common baseline and
then the sector specific goals
across the community look i just spent
four and a half years in the financial
services sector i know
how crazy it is to have the government
coming at you with all these different
signals saying we need this we need that
and none of it's harmonized they ask for
slightly different things and and
frankly dale it's one of my concerns
because
what i don't want is to drive our
private sector partners in a direction
where
it's all about compliance box checking
that was something that i worried about
doing
cyber security at morgan stanley but
rather actual risk reduction and and
that's a really important goal with this
latest legislation the cyber incident
reporting
act as we work with all of our partners
some regulators uh some not but to try
and harmonize all of this so again
uh we are not burdening the private
sector in what we are asking them to do
or asking them to give us and we're not
burdening us with a bunch of noise what
we want to do is get signal and so i
would say that these cpgs are the common
baseline and then we'll build off the
sector specific that we hope to do over
the next two years and then just one
other quick question on that in terms of
metrics so the documents do have a
metric
are you going to gather information from
the sectors so are you going to come up
with like an oil and gas
rating and an electric rating and is
that going to be voluntary or how are
you going to get that information from
these entities well i mean certainly we
would love to do that right you and i
know this is not a trivial endeavor
right the elusive measures of
effectiveness and measures of
performance you know one of the things
that i did when
i came to cisa i actually changed the
mission statement slightly we used to be
uh to understand and manage risk
so i changed it to understand manage and
reduce risk right making my job and my
team's job a little harder but if we're
just managing risk i don't think we're
doing what we need to do as america's
cyber defense agency so we need to be
able to work with a community to reduce
risk so i am in your headspace in terms
of getting actual things that we can
measure to say that we are reducing risk
these
sample evidence is sort of the start of
that but i'm really interested in
working with the community because i
know in my time in the private sector
there's a lot of work being done on this
and i think it's being done in a good
way because boards are now starting to
ask these questions in a really
important way right five six years ago
or when you started s4
boards probably had no idea cyber was
like this i.t thing yeah right and now
boards are asking these questions and
they're the ones who want to understand
all my investment how am i reducing risk
and so the baseline again is working off
these evidence which i then hope can uh
actually feed into measures of effect
effectiveness to reduce risk okay so how
about people yeah it's going to say
different people
it is my favorite um so one of the
things that's why i'm so psyched to come
down here because this is the community
that we need we need help from is we are
going to expand considerably our
ics technical team we just put out 20
job vacancies
i've got a great team here of folks
people like jay gasly and lindsey
tvornick and mj emanuel a whole team of
folks out there
and so if people are interested in
coming and working in the government
whether it's for a couple years or for a
long period of time
understanding what we do uh defending
the nation so we've got those new roles
coming in the other thing is we just got
these new authorities
it's called the cyber talent management
system ctms the congress set it up about
seven years ago and it took seven years
to implement so welcome to bureaucracy
uh but i get to benefit from it and so
what it is it allows us to hire people
much more flexibly so not the 20 plus
steps that you have to go through to
come into government which drives me up
the wall
and we can also pay closer to market
um you know not a huge amount but in
some cases you know upwards of three
hundred thousand dollars which is a lot
for the government now as we know nobody
comes into government to make money
right they come into government to serve
your country to get the experience of
defending the american people but we do
realize that we need to be more
competitive and so we are hiring for a
senior ics
technical expert who's going to be part
of our office of technology to really
help drive our vision and our strategy
as you probably know when
chris set up
cisa we went through something called
cisa 2020 and all those acronyms that
people had become slightly familiar with
from the n-kick uh of course we're still
u.s cert we're still ics cert but all of
that became our cyber division
and so we have that expertise but we
want to bring in somebody really senior
who again can help drive the vision the
strategy
and a lot of the outreach that we're
doing with community so look for that
posting as well
we're excited about that uh and uh look
for the other 20 job postings that we
have going on and then can i talk
partnership or do you have something you
want to ask no i was just thinking i
should have tried to sell you a sponsor
booth here you know like a cabana or
something you could you could have done
recruiting there why didn't you
you know i just i wasn't looking for an
angle do you want to apply it i think i
think it's going to be very competitive
to try to get these people i think a lot
of these vendors are trying to hire
people you know we offer remote work you
could do it from melbourne oh there you
go i keep trying to get dale to host
this thing in maui next year and it
starts with an m ends with an eye
exactly
okay let's go to partnerships okay you
know as i said at the outset
this is not something the government can
do right we are just a partner with uh
with industry and so we set up this
thing called the jcdc uh joint cyber
defense collaborative about eight months
ago i launched it when i when i spoke at
black hat
uh and the theory the case is we want to
be able to work closely uh with our
industry partners to be able to
understand the threat you know just as
we saw in solar winds it's not the
government that's going to detect
malicious activity on critical
infrastructure it's very likely going to
be a company like fireeye like mandiant
like
a big technology company because
technology underpins the backbone of all
of our critical infrastructure and so
working together with
our private industry partners we've
actually had some pretty good early
success it's early days but working on
log4j the vulnerability from december
working on uh ukraine all of the
tensions and the potential threats
around i know we're going to talk a
little bit about shields up
but as we're growing this i'm super
excited to announce uh we're actually
tapping into the expertise of the ics
community and so we just put out an
announcement
we are working initially with uh about
10 or so companies from bechtel and
clarity and dragos and ge and honeywell
and nozomi networks and schneider
electric and schweitzer engineering labs
and siemens and
xylem uh all together uh as part of jcdc
ics or jcdc ice i like to call it but
um so the idea is we're gonna tap into
yeah we're gonna tap into
the ingenuity the innovation the
expertise of this particular community
the icsot community
to enable us to work with critical
infrastructure we're going to start with
an exercise with our pipeline friends
and then we're also working with water
and chemical and really tap into that
industry expertise so i am super excited
about that and you know we've been
working i think rob was up here before
and maybe megan mentioned this we put
out this product
about
some tools around ics scada pipe dream
and controller whatever you want to call
it um but we work with our federal
partners on that both fbi nsa doe but
also got fabulous input from mandiant
from dragos from schneider electric
and so really and from palo i think as
well and so working with industry
and having them enrich and make these
products better i'm really excited about
jcdc ics for that and so you know those
are the initial companies we welcome
anyone who wants to work with us and
we're excited about building that
partnership i think it's incredibly
important um to get this collective
defense right
i think that's a good move i know there
was rumbling in in the community when
the first list
came out and we're like where are we
yeah you know so there was some rumbling
so i think that's a really good addition
to
is it like a sub group or something are
you going to create these subjects yeah
let me just let me let me address that
because i want folks to understand so
the first group were the technology
companies the backbone infrastructure
isp csps cyber security vendors
and the theory of the case on that was
everything's underpinned by technology
and so we wanted to be able to
really see the dots together connect the
dots and drive down risk to the nation
at scale
when the ukraine
war happened we actually brought in
some finance companies so jcdc finance
jcdc energy and then jcdc ics is really
this group that is going to help us
specifically focus on industrial control
systems and operational technology that
of course has been a priority for the
administration you know really since
colonial pipeline as you recall
um which gave us a lot of lessons
learned
about how we can work better as a
community and so what we're trying to do
is really expand this platform because i
think i think the other point to make
that's unique and important for this
community and rob lee might have
mentioned this look
you know we were built to be america's
cyber defense agency but there's a whole
federal cyber ecosystem of everybody
that has a really important role in this
uh fbi nsa us cybercom people like
energy the department of energy the tr
the tsa and so what jcdc does is
it's a platform but cis is just one
federal partner it brings together all
of those partners so that you can
actually go to one place and be able to
work with all of the federal partners
and with the private sector and you
don't have to have a phd in government
to figure out who to interact with
that's what congress recognized and you
know frankly it was one of the
motivating factors why i came back from
morgan stanley
to the government because i just felt
the government was kind of incoherent
you know you were getting signals from
all these different places and it's why
we have worked really hard to make sure
that we are joint sealing everything so
you saw doe you saw nsa you saw fbi
we're working very closely with industry
partners
later today we're going to release a new
product
with our fbi our nsa our five five eyes
partners
that was enriched with a lot of
information from our industry uh
industry folks uh that is really a
detailed overview of uh russian
state-sponsored cyber actors and
russia-aligned cyber criminal groups
so we have learned a lot over the past
several months and we're putting this
out along with the mitigation guidance
and so everybody should see that around
today
which we're excited about but the joint
seals are really important because one
coherent cohesive
u.s government as opposed to coming at
you in various different ways i think
it's incredibly important to make sure
that we're doing this as a community
okay well let's pivot to talk a little
bit about shields up which i think
probably most of the audience has heard
about and you
you and rob are on 60 minutes talking a
little bit about it
the shields go up we're in a heightened
security posture yeah
what
or when will the shields come down and
what will it take for the shields to
come down yeah
yeah i know right um
so
a couple of things first of all
we wanted to make sure
that we were
[Music]
instilling a real sense of urgency you
know everybody in this room has a sense
of urgency every day
i don't need to tell this community
shields up and i don't need to tell
most cisos or most network defenders
shields up or shields up all the time
that signaling had a lot to do with
uh business leaders
small
large critical infrastructure owners and
operators to make sure that they
understood that there was a real sense
of urgency to this threat
and so it's been a campaign that i think
has gotten a lot of good traction we've
been able to use the shields up web page
as a one-stop shop again i like the
simplicity of being able to go to one
place to find all the information about
the threat advisory is to find the
mitigation guidance whether it's large
small businesses ransomware individuals
and then guidance to ceos and the most
important thing we're telling ceos is
empower your cisos
right and we want to continue to do that
but what is so the question is you know
what is shields i'm not going to say
shields down none of us should ever be
shields down in this threat environment
we'll go to what i'll call shields
normal
and
you know we have to realize that many of
the things on that website that you know
are really things that we should be
doing all the time that frankly
we're not if we were doing it all the
time we wouldn't have this these attacks
uh very often and we've seen the scourge
of ransomware
but one of the things a couple of things
that we in particular in this
environment we've asked people to lower
the thresholds for reporting right
because we want to make sure that if
there is leading-edge information about
attacks that we're actually
bringing that in and we've had to put
extra people on from our team on that
we have talked about being you know on
the ready for crisis response
um we have talked about
preparing for the worst and being being
ready to disconnect systems if we need
to i think those are things that
specifically are in this environment
that are not necessarily in an
environment where where shield's normal
but i think at the end of the day if
people are doing the things on that
website
it will stand us better as a nation
frankly and so i hope
that even when we go back to shields
normal that the basic things that we
need to be doing around
hygiene
which if we were doing them we'd be in a
lot better shape right
um we have instilled this sort of sense
of urgency you know for me i'm a little
bit on this campaign about
you know what do we do personally um to
keep ourselves safe online and this
again this this group are all experts
and very sophisticated but all of us
can be evangelists for not just the ics
and the ot community but what we need to
be doing um just day to day or on the
i.t side since really that's likely
where most things are going to start and
so things like multi-factor
authentication uh things like updated
software passwords all that type things
i would ask for you know this
community's help in getting that word
out across the country yeah i think a
lot of people are security support for
their families and their parents
but i i guess
i think a number of us in the security
community i think the messaging has been
very effective for the executives and
the business leaders and and i think
sometimes i i know sometimes i
underestimate the importance of that
just because when you live it day to day
you kind of
forget how many people don't
think about these things but on that
list they were things that everyone
should do
and then lowered thresholds or increased
monitoring
um
but you know probably from your morgan
stanley days and and even before that
you can't be at this higher threshold
all the time 100
and
i would even say there's
things that we could do more than what
was on that list and i think you and i
corresponded a little bit about that is
there going to be like a shields really
up or super up and
and
and i worry that if we don't go
if we don't go to shields normal in a
week or so
you can't keep people at at a heightened
state for very long look man i agree
with you where the we're the network
defenders so so i've got folks out here
and folks back at cissa
that are you know and i worry a lot
about this i am a huge advocate for
mental health we've made 2022 the year
of mental health and and well-being
um you know i have personal experience
with this and i lost my brother to
suicide and so i want to make sure that
we are taking care of all of our folks
and frankly i worry a lot about burnout
and i worry a lot about vigilance
fatigue and so i will be the first one
who's excited to say shield's normal
because
my folks and many of the folks in this
room probably need a freaking break
right and so um we're not there yet
though i mean we're putting out a
product today you saw the product we put
out um but i am very very mindful of
vigilance fatigue and i want to make
sure that we are giving the right signal
to the community and so
um we're very focused on when we can go
back to a posture
that people can get a little bit more
breathing room yeah okay
let's shift again and you kind of
mentioned it early on but
i want to talk a little bit about
regulation in this space
so chris inglis
uh said i think in front of congress
enlightened self-interest that's
apparently not working market forces
that's apparently not working and then
i think you about the same day at the
same hearing or as such you said it
seems to me that voluntary standards are
probably not getting the job done and
that there's probably some sort of role
for making some of these standards
mandatory now
that's a congressional
issue but they they look to cisa and the
administration as to what they should be
doing
what's your view on regulation for some
of the various sectors here that don't
have it yeah i think there is a place
for regulation but i should say cisa is
not a regulator right right and
and i don't want to be a regulator i've
been very clear with the congress on
that because i think the magic of cisa
and why we were built is all about
voluntary partnerships
and
to be a successful partner you have to
be able to build trust right trust is
the key to any relationship whether it's
a business deal or a marriage you have
to trust that partner and i am keenly
aware that it's hard to build trust and
it's easy to lose it
and if you think that
somebody is going to hammer you or
there's some sort of penalty
that's not the type of relationship that
i want or nor do i think is going to be
productive with respect to our mission
which is as america's cyber defense
agency you know that said i have seen
regulation be effective where financial
sector is highly regulated as you know
but i've also seen it as i mentioned
earlier dale where you have so many
different uh regulators coming at you
trying to figure out um how to
differentiate what you what you owe them
that timeline um on which you owe it and
then the resources that you're going to
allocate to do that i worry gets you
away from operational risk management
and gets you stuck in this compliance
box checking bucket so i think it's the
there is a role for for cyber security
regulations but i think it's really
important that the government figures
out how to harmonize what we're asking
for and so we're dealing with this now
with this new
cyber incident reporting legislation
which i actually think can also if we do
it right get your point about
understanding metrics right right now we
probably get 30
of the incidents that occur once this
regulation goes in place we can actually
have i think a much better baseline to
show whether in fact we're reducing
incidents or not but
we have this with other agencies the fcc
the sec
that are looking at uh asking for
reporting requirements and again i i
don't want to create this burden on the
private sector i don't think it's fair
and i don't think it's productive
so while there's a place for regulation
our focus is on working collaboratively
with the private sector and then
ensuring that as much as possible we can
help to harmonize requirements and i
would draw you back to
the cyber security performance goals
because if you have these worked with a
community consultatively if you have
this common baseline again mapped to the
nist cyber security framework if you
have these sector specific goals that we
worked collaboratively with the sector
and we all agree on that those can be
the driving force for what we're saying
or those minimum standards that
we expect because critical
infrastructure is all about national
security economic prosperity but
importantly what for public companies
anyway for what shareholders should
expect for what board members should
expect and so i think you create an
ecosystem that is more about uh
collective cyber defense as opposed to
just compliance
but then do you see for example water
the water isac
and it's funny the water isac suggested
that they might follow the nerc sip
model
and
whenever i tell that to someone an
electric they roll their eyes and say oh
they they shouldn't do that that would
be a big big mistake
it's it's funny to see their faces
but are you going to leave it then up to
like epa to decide what
you know to work with congress for what
should be water regulations and and
tsa for pipelines and and that you're
just advising them
in that sense so so
the congress set up set us up with a
couple important roles and one of them
was to be the national coordinator for
critical infrastructure cyber security
and resilience
because you have these sectors they have
different regulators right 16 sectors
you have these things called sector risk
management agencies so finance has
treasury electricity has energy
pipelines has tsa as you said water is
epa
but we work closely with each of them to
make sure
that and this is what goes back to the
common common baseline for the cyber
security performance goals to make sure
that uh we are asking
uh from a again a common perspective the
same things across all sectors and then
what those
uh what those sector risk management
agencies do or focus on sort of the
technical aspects of why water ics may
be different
from electricity ics or pipeline ics and
so but we're the national coordinator
because we you can't look at sectors in
a in a silo we know that right and
finance
it didn't matter if we spent billions of
dollars as we did on our cyber security
if the power went down if the telcos
went down right so everything is
connected
everything is ostensibly vulnerable made
even more exacerbated by the fact that
you have these supply chains
underpinning everything
and so we have to work with epa we have
to work with tsa they're the regulator
and so they they regulate um and they
develop those regulations but we're
there to provide technical assistance
and support um and to help make sure
that uh there are
harmonized uh standards across each at
the common level across each of those
sectors
okay
well we're almost out of time here i
have one thing i i wanted to tell you
and then i'll give you a chance to
tell the audience anything we didn't ask
about because i'm sure they're so
thrilled you're here but you know on the
in controller pipe dream thing
um there was a key sentence in in the
sizzle alert or bulletin the tools
enable them to scan for compromise and
control affected devices once they have
established initial access to the ot
network which is
essentially 10 years ago we did
something called project basecamp which
just showed all these plcs and things
were insecure by design that once you
got through the perimeter
you could turn things on and off you
could reprogram the logic
sizza and even before that dhs has never
said that those things should be secured
so i think that's that's a really big
hole right now is that it's just kind of
like yeah this is really bad stuff and
we're going to live with it for another
10 years so i hope i hope that you and
your team
sometime in the next year or two can get
on that big megaphone and say see these
things that are completely insecure and
really important
we need to put a little effort on that
so that's that's my pitch to you but now
let me let me let you make your pitch to
the audience what else would you like
them to know hey first of all i i love
feedback i treat feedback as a gift and
i have
a tremendous respect
for the network defenders who are doing
this in the world of ics and ot and
across the board and so
we love that feedback i look at this as
collective cyber defense we depend on
this community and so i think it's a
great point and i'd love to work with
you and the rest of this community to
make sure that we get our messaging
right because you know we're the
youngest agency in the federal
government right we're growing we're
building we do want to have that
megaphone
but we can't do it without the community
and so i'm just excited to be here um
i'm excited about the opportunity to
continue to strengthen and deepen our
partnerships with this community to work
together i'm excited about the jcdc ice
effort the people that we're hiring uh
you gave me a hard time on the website
the old website so just for you dale we
updated our website today the ics cert
page yeah oh all right this is my gift
to you
check it out yeah it'll make my friday
news and notes you go to sissa.gov for
ics okay great for you call it dale's
special page no but seriously um
it it this was a great motivator to
actually get a bunch of really important
stuff done between jcdc and all the
hiring and um and that web page to be
the place to go to that's updated and
has valuable information but again
please continue to provide feedback we
are here with
um gratitude and humility and we want to
be great partners
so let's work together okay well great
thank you very much thank you thanks
thanks john appreciate it
[Music]
you