[Music]
my name is food as Mike just said I come
from from Norway I work at Telenor which
is sort of the belle of Norway I've been
there for three years and I am helping
build a global search sock service for
talent in Asia Central Europe and new
Nordiques and before that I did seven
years at the national cert basically
hunting apt and I'm I used to be a
techie once when I was young and
beautiful I promise I was young and
beautiful I'm not really that anymore so
I and I'm not a developer even though I
I come from a developer background so I
cannot do stuff like assembly line and
I'm not going to be the cool guy you
know I reverse this cool malware what I
do most of my time is to think about how
we should work to become more effective
and that is was that's what's this talk
is about this is a bunch of models that
I think is useful for an incident
response team when you want to try to
become more effective at combating
advanced threats and taking the red pill
of attacker eviction that's like that's
the sexy title but this is the boring
title how to structure your thinking
when countering espionage and sabotage
from apt so little too long to be have
as my title but that's what this talk is
about and we're going to look
specifically at sort of how you are
going to attempt to evict mission-driven
you know and well-organized adversaries
which of course translates into your own
coz welcome the NSA you know the
Russians the Chinese the Israelis the
Iranians you know the the nation-states
and contractors of the world that is
task weed getting into your networks and
do stuff that you don't want them to do
there
so we're talking incident response
rights and this is the very can you see
this yeah I think should be particular
so this by the way this is how this is
how much lives are going to look I
cannot be bothered spending three months
making you know cool word art or
graphics in PowerPoint so I just draw
them and I import the pictures I hope
you're okay with that so this is this is
a simplified incident right
you're breached then you detect it you
analyze it for a while and then you try
to kick the attacker out and everyone is
happy and of course it's not even
remotely as simple as that and I'm
you're not supposed to read all this
it's just there to tell you no it's more
complicated because there's a whole lot
of planning going into an operation that
ends up being an apt attack in your
infrastructure but at some point you're
breached and then you don't know
anything for I don't know weeks months
years sometimes and then you discover
and that's what other people call dwell
time you know between compromise and you
detecting it and then you you you follow
all kinds of best practices and you
don't do anything until you've analyzed
and scoped the incident and then you
think oh I'm really clever and I'm going
to kick them out but somewhere in the
middle of that one of your analysts
uploaded a sample virustotal and the
attackers got wind of your you know that
you know about it so they spent their
the rest of the time planning how to
resist your eviction right and then you
think okay I'm good to kick them out and
you try and you think oh now the
attackers lost access but did you
succeed did you really kick them out and
what about when I try to re-enter the
point is there is a lot of uncertainty
here when dealing with quote-unquote apt
and advanced attacks targeted attacks
where everyone call it when you're
responding that there's just a lot of
uncertainty it's actually surprisingly
hard to know whether or not you're ready
to try to kick out such an attacker and
I guess this is
there's a sort of the problem statement
of this talk in a way or the problem and
that these models I'm going to present
is going to try to help you tackle that
is to deal with this uncertainty to have
a better foundation to make good
judgments all of you of course know
Department of Homeland Security I'm sure
a lot of you especially your coz guys
even know Chris Patera personally they
have an excellent presentation out about
best practices and communists missteps
when you're dealing with well they call
it major incidents the point is that one
of the within the missteps section there
is a lot about not acting too soon like
you know be careful before you act
because you don't want to tip off your
attacker until you are ready to you know
effectively kick them out so unlike will
are unlike whether for instance our
Terrier bleeding which there is no too
soon when you're trying to stopping a
bleeding when it comes to countering apt
there is actually a too soon right but
how do you know when the right time is
this comes back to the uncertainty and
yeah you want to try to reduce the
uncertainty before you act
not because it's like you whether it's
the to soon thing or something else you
want to make sure that you don't have
too much uncertainty when you decide to
act and that means you have to
understand the attacker you need to
understand what's going on anyway
infrastructure right so I will start off
by looking at somebody I call it apt
patterns so coming from a developer
background at least it's like everything
is patterns you know so let's look at
some apt patterns to better understand
what's going on and of course I was
telling a friend about this before and
she was going you know half the room is
going to be CSE right you don't have to
tell them up they tell them about apt
but
so bear with me and if you think I'm
wrong you let me know but yeah let's
start off so the first pattern of sorts
is that when it comes to intrusions into
your network I tend to think of them as
you know one of two either it's a sting
operation
you know sometimes called smash-and-grab
you just go in very targeted you steal
something and you're out and the other
one is where you sort of go in and you
actually infiltrate the infrastructure
with the intention of staying there for
a while and the reason I have like
fourth examples up here is because you
can have like a really simple
smash-and-grab where sort of you fish a
specific person you get onto that
person's computer and you let you know
you're expected to find some emails and
some documents on his servers user
profile and then you grab that and
you're done and the other one is like
you go in and you're sort of spread out
a little bit but you're very specific
goal with while you were you there and
once you get it you go out as opposed to
if you gonna you know go sort of a
persistent infiltration but then again
you have like the small footprint
persistent infiltration and you have the
the kind where you hear about sometimes
you know full compromised like
everything is compromised so that's sort
of that's how I think of intrusion
patterns when it comes to targeted
attacks and this I guess is something
that I don't need to explain to you guys
but it's here anyway like this is the
typical quote-unquote apt operation they
have some foothold in your
infrastructure here with three nodes
three compromised nodes talking to a
situ and they're gonna that's gonna be
the bridgehead that they're gonna use
most of the time so if you detect it
these guys here you're gonna see that
most of the the work they're doing
they're doing through these three
breach ads but if you sort of come if
you find this command and control
channel you find these three clients and
you go oh wow I got apt you gotta clean
this up fast and you clean this up and
then you dodged that bullet you sort of
missed the point right because these
kinds of operations they're gonna have
one or two you know backup small backup
clusters
compromise clients with different
malware different SI toos different IPS
they're gonna have they're gonna have a
web shell on a web server somewhere to
get back in if you kick them out they
have probably you know if you don't have
to factor authentication they will have
harvested some VPN credentials to get
back in through VPN and something really
cool that we've seen is installing
what's on Windows Exchange is called a
transport agent which is where you can
you can you can create a DLL that will
you can use it to filter email like so
spam filters for instance will be
implemented as a transport agent so
these guys they had made a transport
agent that would just look for some
magic header and if that magic had had
her appeared in an email they would read
the body of the email and execute code
that was in there right so even if we
did all the other things and we left
that one out I still had code execution
opportunities in our infrastructure so
onto the next one and this is actually I
realized actually last night that this
slide alone should probably be its own
presentation but this is something that
at least for me over the last couple of
years or sort of been like aha moment
that is when you're working at these
kinds of intrusions you need to realize
that there are several layers of them
and there is the access layer and I
learned recently that CSE's see any
group is called the same as an SAS tau
which is kind of funny because this
picture here just they basically took
their way of operating and they made it
their name because the a is acts
tailored access operations right and you
know the a that's access there you go
access layer that's the that's when they
penetrate your infrastructure and they
get a foothold and I'm and sort of
maintain persistency and backup weighs
in and everything and then it's sort of
the business layer
that is the tailored part I mean they're
in there to give access to something
right so they have tailored their access
so that they can get access to database
a B and C and I work at a telco and
turns out the big intelligence agencies
are really interested in what in the
public debates with NSA in the u.s. is
called communication metadata but
basically who called who one for how
long and from where so part of the the
tailoring on the access layer will be to
make it easy to extract that kind of
information from us as a telco right and
then it's the I call the mission layer
but I should have called the operations
layer because then it would have
actually been tau operation because
that's like why what are you doing you
cannot observe this directly you have to
sort of deduce what that is but we
analyze it so let's skip ahead here so
again don't try to read this I'll put
the slide deck online this is for your
reviewing afterwards but what's
important to understand you need to make
sure that you are able to distinguish
between what is basically what I've
started calling evil sysadmin like that
it's just the attackers sysadmin just
admitting their access you know so a lot
of the activity that you will actually
observe when you are analyzing an apt
intrusion it's just gonna be sis
saddening of the access that they have
based on sort of land of origin and sort
of how their play books look they will
come in in the morning just to make sure
everything is up pinging all the systems
they're supposed to access to you know
try to query a database just to see that
this still can sort of query it okay
okay so good and then they don't do
anything for the rest of the day maybe
and tell us sometimes they come back in
and oh I've got a task I'm gonna extract
this data and then they go in and they
just query in the extracted data so you
need to distinguish these two types of
activities because when you're going to
plan your response it isn't so on the
technical side it's important of course
they're full but when people say scope
during
incident like this basically what they
often mean is is scoping the access now
right the compromised assets and
identities but I think we should focus a
lot more on figuring out not just what
the access looks like but what are they
actually going after like try to
identify as assess down to the right
there and you can't probably cannot see
like try to identify the attackers
critical pathways to their
mission-critical data which in the green
thing is the green layer there is the
databases right try to identify why they
built this access you know and at least
make sure that whatever you do you try
to secure those because that's what
they're after
who cares which laptops and servers
they're wrong it's it's the data sources
that you need to protect first and
foremost so let's move on as I said this
could probably be its own presentation
so we don't have time for that okay so
why why are you being attacked in the
first place that is also something that
can I don't know baffle people having
worked with this kind of incident
response for almost a decade I've had a
lot of conversation with people who just
have one why why are they attacking me I
don't get it I don't have anything
interesting which of course is never
true and what I'm sort of where I always
circle back to is that if you're being
hit by targeted attacks like this there
is there exists an adverse adversarial
adversarial relationship somewhere that
you are relevant to that is the only
reason you're seeing capabilities like
this deployed against you if there is no
adversarial relationship between two
parties or more somewhere you don't see
this you don't get this in your network
if that doesn't exist and we we tend in
a security community to say oh you have
an adversary problem and then basically
what people are talking about is the CNE
teams you know the Taos of the world
they mean like the hand key on keyboard
operators doing the collection
of course that's that's not your
adversary at least not the one that has
an adversarial relationship with you the
adversary is someone else like for since
we're in Canada I guess Nortel is a good
example right it wasn't three PLA that
was nor Charles adversary it was I'm
just gonna go out and say it Huawei
right and they they pillaged Nortel for
what a decade and if you thought that
the 3p Li guys was if that was creepy
libel it was at least the Chinese was
the adversary you sort of missed the
point right because the adversary was
actually one of the competitors who
benefited from this so this I think so
so a lot of people of course all you
guys who work in the intelligence
community you get this but surprising
amount of people working in the security
industry doesn't really get this and of
course if you go to your managers in IT
in IT operations they absolutely do not
have this perspective and I think this
isn't a perspective that is important to
bring in during incident response and
yeah sometimes this is you sometimes
it's actually you who have the
adversarial relationship that is
relevant for this attack on you but
other times you're just a random little
random but other times you're you are
targeted because you can give access to
the final targets and again coming from
a telco the reason that all the major
intelligence services of the world are
super interested in telcos isn't because
they really want to target us but but
because we give them access to something
that they really really like who calls
to positioning data on people yeah so a
so telco we for the really really target
that there are really sort of the scary
threats out there like the really
capable organisations attacking us
this is the case they are not really
after us but they're after our customers
and being able to distinguish this
during incident response is are you a
direct target or you're sort of an
indirect target is also important for
how you think when you plan your
response like what is the best way to
respond
so and okay I'm sorry very crowded or
unclear slide but let me try to explain
it as best I can so you see the
Intelligence Agency up there in yellow
and you have the CNE attack group you
know the attack team or what everyone
call it some kind of a projects
operation in town right running an ops
against let's say Telenor a lot of the
time when we respond to this we are only
sort of responding to basically the
access the access layer right we are
responding to compromised assets in IT
that's what we respond to only the most
mature of companies and I haven't to be
honest Matt a lot of companies who
really are doing this responds to what
is actually the biggest risk here and
that is the business side of things so
at least where let's say let's use
corporate espionage as an example like
and Nortel right it's it's the it's not
hell's competitor that is the big issue
here right it's the impact on business
that is the big issue it's not the
compromised assets but I'm gonna yeah
I'm gonna go out on a limb here and say
I think that most insurance response
team of the world or are just doing the
the the sort of the response to the
access layer you know the attack on IT
operations and not the other side and I
think that should change if we want to
if we want to be more effective at
countering that the risks that these
threats supposed to us okay so that was
the apt patterns anyone fall asleep not
yet not too much gorilla so we're going
to have a very short intermission sort
of no more slides with the
with diagrams on them for a little while
just gonna make some I'm gonna assert
something here because now we've been
talking about apt intrusions and sort of
started talking about how to respond to
it
and a lot of the time we are when we
talk about this in the security
community we're talking about kicking
them out their master attacker you know
kicking them out and I think we need to
start talking about keeping them out
right and this I actually believe that
this is an important mindset changed
that that needs to happen that become
because kicking something out that is
like oh there's a leaky pipe on my
kitchen I'm gonna wipe the floor that is
kicking out right there keeping out is
oh wait I have a leaky I have a leaky
plumbing thing here let's fix that and
then we're gonna clean the floor but
once I clean it they're not gonna come
right it's not gonna start leaking again
immediately right so I think we need a
mindset change where we are saying we're
going to keep them out how we're gonna
keep these guys out so that you do all
the things you need to keep them out
then you kick them out instead of just
identify what's there and there and
there and there kick and you haven't
done anything to resist reentry and this
actually goes back to this kind of
cluttered IT ops versus business
response because the first one sort of
just responding to the access into your
network and helping IT ops clean up the
network I hope we at some point can say
that was the old way that we did
Incident Response and that we are and
everyone is talking about mitigating
risk but I haven't really seen a lot of
companies actually do it it's easy to
talk about but bringing in a bringing in
business and trying to figure out what
the business risk actually is from these
incidents I don't know but we need to so
we should yeah we should keep talking
about it but we should also try to
figure out a way how to actually do it
sorry and then all this talking about
cleaning up I think miss is a very
important point when it comes to
incident response toward in these
situations and that is that sometimes
letting them operate might be the best
way to mitigate the big risks you're
facing and I've talked about this with a
lot of incident responders and way more
than half goes like are you crazy we
would never be allowed to do that how
could you be allowed to do that this is
insane and maybe it is but sometimes if
you want to if you want if you want to
counter the business risk you cannot act
immediately on the IT operations risk
because if you do that if you act
immediately on the IT operations side
the access side of things you're not
even gonna come close to figure out the
other stuff so when I hear people say
that yeah you know let it run for a
while most of the time it's because we
need to scope the access layer the blue
layer you know the IT ops side of things
so that we can identify everything that
it come is compromised so that when we
clean up we clean up everything a lot
more seldom do I hear people say let it
run for a while so we figure out what
they're doing because most of the time
when people start extra trading
sensitive data it's like stop but if you
don't let that happen you're not going
to be able to figure out what the
business risk is but I see why this is
scary
my position on this is that it doesn't
matter if you let them keep at it for a
while or not because even if you kick
them out they're going to be back in and
there's gonna be a new dwell time so and
during that time they're gonna do this
anyway so you might as well just let
them do it while you're looking at it
because then you can figure out what the
big thing is and maybe actually change
something on the tactical or strategic
level that will mitigate
bigger risk so be bold so how can we
even come close to making decisions like
that we started out by talking about
well okay I was doing the talking but we
were all together right
I was talking about the uncertainty in
these kinds of situations and how do you
make these decisions with so much
uncertainty well the answer is of course
to try to reduce the uncertainty so now
we're going to go back to a lot of these
hand-drawn diagrams because the way I
think we should do this is to apply a
lot more analytical models to our work
you know structured analytical thinking
that's a thing so there are a couple of
really good books out there on
intelligence analysis but not that much
on sort of how do you how do you apply
those thoughts for our kind our kind of
work so let's see how I am doing on time
actually not quite bad that's good
because now comes a lot of I guess what
was here now was sort of I was up until
now this I guess wasn't surprising like
it wasn't yeah I've read that before
I've thought that before yeah of course
it's like that I hope we can continue
like that but but the what comes now is
just imaginations that this comes from
my imagination I have to be quite honest
I have no idea if this is actually going
to work because I'm still creating this
basically and sort of this is a work in
progress we are going to implement this
and try to do this where I work in
Telenor search but we haven't come that
far yet so your basic this is hot off
the press it's just so if it's rubbish
you can blame me if it's good you can
say our telemetry so first thing this is
the super simple stuff like I mean you
need to make sure that when you respond
to this you figure out the dwell time
I'd say short well time like also
between intrusion and detection that's
like hours to days medium let's say days
to weeks and longest months to years and
if you can catch something and you
figure out very
clear that yeah I think you know I think
we actually caught this pretty fast yeah
go for it you know just go after them
and try to clean up as fast as you can
because they haven't been able to you
know infiltrate you properly yet they
haven't been able to damage you yet so
you might as well you know try to kick
them out and prevent them from gaining
insight and foothold and providing or
giving you now crossing your damage if
it's days two weeks yeah well then it
depends a lot on your team your area is
response team and the kind of
capabilities that they have if you're
able to have a high operational tempo
you know you have a lot of you have a
lot of data a lot of telemetry and you
have good orchestration you can probably
catch up with these guys and maybe you
know go for a clean up but if you find
something and they have been in there
for years and you hear these stories all
the time I have in my career heard of
this or seen this many many times that
when you start looking into an intuition
like this it turns out that there are
traces of the attacker for as far back
as you're able to go in your log sources
so you know yeah they were in there in
2013 at least because that's as far back
yes we have data and then it's like okay
no matter what you do you're probably
not going to be able to get them out
because they and a by now probably know
your infrastructure better than your IT
operations you know they're gonna have
every password from every system there
yeah they're just gonna know you so well
that even if you kick them out they're
just gonna they're gonna have 17 ways
back in so then then you got it then you
may then you may need to you know shut
down and you hear you hear about this
from time to time you know you have
maybe any have to shut down the entire
network and just reinstall everything
reset everything or even worse you hear
this sometimes to just build a new data
center and migrate right of course it
depends on the threat but this is a
function of the dwell time as well so
getting an idea of the dwell
time is important then back to intrusion
patterns based on what you're seeing if
you if you think you're more on the
sting operation side of things well then
it's easier to clean up because the
complexity of the infiltration is less
right or if you see traces of them being
everywhere it's like okay now I know now
that this is going to be very hard so if
you have a long dwell time and you see
you see indicators that this is like you
know a really heavy persistent
infiltration then you know okay just by
these two factors you know that this is
gonna be super hard at that point you
don't really have to rush in my opinion
it's like okay
these two things alone and this you
should actually be able to get an idea
of just within hours and days of your
investigation if you say okay we in this
data source we see them back to three
years and yeah we see them on like so
many systems it's not even funny already
now you know that you can take a step
back in just like okay you know what if
I spend a month investigating this isn't
what's gonna make a difference they're
been in for so long even if we try to
kick them up now they're gonna have so
many ways back in we might as well take
our time and this is how we can just
these two very simple concepts you can
use to make decisions on how you want to
respond and even better hopefully you
can you can use these concepts to get
management approval for doing it because
that is going to be the big issue right
yeah we are totally compromised and we
don't want to do anything because that's
what's going to sound like we don't want
to do anything what do you mean you want
don't want to do anything no okay so I
didn't really not do anything but I mean
we're going to kick them out you're
gonna do a lot of stuff we're gonna
analyze we're gonna try to figure out
what's going on but sort of having that
conversation with upper management is
super hard but I think just these two
simple counts concepts these two simple
models can actually help you start that
conversation and maybe even
okay I guess I understand you explained
it to me so yeah okay I'll give you a
month or two or three so on to something
a little bit more elaborate kind of
random name
I like 3x3 matrix is so this was called
the thread type matrix and that is you
want to try to figure out what kind of
threat actor you're up against
what kind of motivations they have for
being in your infrastructure this ties
back to for instance the difference
between being a direct target and being
an indirect target like are you are you
attacked because you can provide access
to the real target or are you the real
targets like for the Taos of the world
attacking telcos like Telenor we are an
indirect target but all the times when
other threat actors attack it's
industrial espionage and so we are the
target and that sort of that so that is
a different kind of threat type sort of
different profile and I decided to
divide this into strategic tactical
operational and strategic that means now
and let's start at the bottom actually
operational means they are attacking you
because of operational needs in the snow
so so nice to be in Canada because I
have so many examples to give in the
snow mix there is actually something
about sorry CSE guys there is actually
something about how CSE is doing this
and at the time which is probably many
years ago they had like a surge two
times a year where they were just used
SIGINT find runner bro
you know internet exposed services and
exploit them and sort of you know pull
them into what we in the old days called
the botnet kind of thing you know
actually about that just get access to
it right put web shops on a fella know
and create what they call in the sort of
military speak orbs operational relay
boxes and then we just sort of gather
you know thousands and thousands of
these as a resource you know just to use
as proxy networks and see to service and
whatever so if if you are compromised
and you think that this is what's going
on based on based on everything that you
see around the compromised you think
that ok so I've actually just been
attacked because they want they want to
use my service as their infrastructure
well then I'd say you're up against sort
of an operational threat or they're not
operational threat but the threat actors
motive is operational that means that if
you just clean that up right now there
is no need to that there is no and you
patched your vulnerabilities there is
actually no reason to believe that that
threat actor is going to come back in
even though it's an apt there is no
there is no motivation for them to try
to be persistent on your web server it
was just an opportunistic target right
so then is the tactical motivation that
is more so a lot of espionage is done
corporate espionage is done because of
contract negotiations and stuff like
that and one of the more interesting
concrete examples I've talked to people
about is someone who lost north of 120
million Canadian dollars in a contract
negotiation because of an apt one breach
where they would you know steal
everything really regarding the the
contract negotiations and the when that
company piece together what had happened
and they made sort of an estimated how
much money they lost because of that
there was 120 million Canadian dollars
no not million yeah
yeah 100 and 120,000 Canadian no I'm
trying to do conversion in my head I
should have done this before I should
have the number down here sorry eight
hundred thousand eight hundred million
kroners and it's six point five whatever
I'm sorry a big number that's the point
yeah why did I even try to do this I'm
sorry you know I want to get it right
no one cares so that's the kind of a
tactical motivation where there is a
there is a specific objective and there
is a time frame most of the time and the
attacker they date they attack that they
infiltrate you to try to support some
kind of young tactical objective and
then it's a strategic one and for
instance go back to you know the big
intelligence services and telcos they
have a strategic motivate motivation for
attacking telcos like Telenor because
they they want access sort of our the
access that we can provide them to
metadata phone calls and positioning
it's just it's sort of a strategic
resource I guess for them so looking at
an intrusion you should try to figure
out what kind of motivation is behind
this what kind of threat are you up
against like are they is strategically
motivated are you tactically motivated
already operationally motivated as I
said if they're if you think they're
operationally motivated just kick them
out and that should be it
if they're if you think they're
tactically motivated well now you know
they're on they're on the clock like I
said if you have it's a full deep
compromise that has lasted for years
there's no rush well if you think that
your attacker is tactically motivated
the rest of the Risso rush because they
are on the clock so if you can slow them
down they might not be able to hurt you
right well if they're if their
motivation is strategic like for
instance they're so the Chinese
espionage on
the US and the rest of the world with
the apt one guys that was more
strategical strategically motivated
right just get everyone's secrets and
see if we can use some sort of
motivation at least part of it was that
it seems so if you're doing reso so I
mean like the different defense industry
right they're gonna have a lot of
strategically motivated attackers going
at them because everyone wants to know
you're the newest weapons technology
right and then of course you should use
the right to figure out what kind of how
capable is this attacker so low medium
high yeah basically the examples that I
I gave so if you have a highly capable
and strategically motivated adversary
attacking you or sorry I shouldn't say
adversary intelligence capability
infiltrating you that really puts the
eight that the P an apt those are going
to be the guys who are going to be
really really persistent well if you
have someone that is in the sort of low
capability spectrum and you think
they're operationally motivated there's
not going to be a P in there at all
right I mean so the whole term apt
doesn't really apply to this I've just
been using it because now everyone just
uses apts you know espionage but the P
an apt belongs up in the upper right
corner and and sort of figuring this out
getting an idea of the attacker based on
these just to simple access it's gonna
is going to inform your decision making
an instant response right because when I
said you can take a step back yeah well
if you think they're strategically
motivated and they're highly capable
there is nothing you and they have been
there for a long time that well time and
then they've gone for a sort of a deep
full infiltration you you don't need to
hurry because you're not gonna be able
to really you're not gonna be able to
get them out and there is no rush well
if it's tactical again well if it's calm
negotiation you think they're well fight
them as hard as you can until the
contract negotiations are done and then
they're probably just leave
so risk type matrix next next thing so
now it's time to turn the perspective
from the attacker to to assess the
target
so again operational tactical strategic
but this time it means what kind of risk
is this posing to us is it an
operational risk and by that I mean like
having malware on your servers is it
gonna make them unstable isn't gonna eat
resources or your service is gonna go
down because of this tactical well now
it actually matches pretty well to the
attacker like contract negotiations you
know is this project gonna fail because
of this are we gonna is this is this
procurement process going to be twice as
expensive because of this you know that
kind of thing a strategic is more like
oh that we lose all our R&D oh wow that
wasn't good and then just low medium and
high that's in the risk so we're not
going to read all this I basically just
sat down said this but you can find this
again in the slides when I put them
online the important thing here in this
in the diagram now is is what's on the
right side because on the operational
risk you're going to talk to IT
operations because I mean that's very
nice right I mean this is all malware
driven and you know it it's I access to
your IT systems so operational risk you
don't talk to IT if it's a tactical
business risk well you have to talk to
business you know that's going to be a
difficult conversation because they've
never heard of apt before and then if
it's a strategic risk well you have to
talk to upper management because then
those are the guys through whose job it
is you know to to make the strategies
and manage the risk to these strategies
and I'm gonna assert that as a community
we are doing all
locked her work down there just you know
on the operational side of things even
even if we know all this other stuff
exists we still mostly just talked to IT
right I wish someone would you know get
up and say you know you know seriously
no no no we're doing all of this but I
can honestly say that even though I have
created this slide deck I haven't been
doing this a lot more aspiring to
because as incident responders most of
us are technical so we go and talk to IT
and we talk technical you need different
kinds of skills different kinds of
people to go and talk risk to business
and then if you're gonna bridge the the
people who understand the technical side
of the risk with the people who can sort
of actually make sense of the business
risks you know there is a there is a gap
to be bridged and I'm not sure a lot of
t-shirts around the world or set up to
actually bridge that gap themselves at
least so next one and this this is
actually the title of the talk so what I
sorry Mike what I did after I submitted
this talk was that I just totally
changed it into not so in the original
talk was going to be just about this but
the more I worked on it the more I
realized no I need more models this is
just one out of several that we need you
know to do what I want to achieve with
this model so this is the fat pie or
seat him or whatever the cyber threat
intelligence matrix which is a name that
doesn't really mean anything but as you
can see fat pie is the first letters of
the two axis and how many of you have
heard about Ryan's dillion's detection
maturity level to retire after all the
curry or you haven't heard about it not
sure okay
then I I need to I need to
sort of ask one more question to figure
out whether or not you're just sleeping
or if you haven't heard about it how
many of you work with incident response
that was the usual five hands okay I
should have asked that before I started
and told you all this is only for
incidence response although this entire
talk is for incident response anyway
detection maturity level that is
basically you know what if you're
interested the slides are going to come
online and then you can find the link to
the presentation call yeah the
presentation there and it's going to
have links to the detection maturity
maturity levels but basically this is
depth of knowledge when you're analyzing
a threat what - what's depth of
knowledge can you can you you know how
far can you go like footprint that is
the easy stuff that's IP hashes domain
names whatever you know like concrete
stuff that you can sometimes well what I
guess you in threat Intel sharing
platforms which called observables
Arsenal that's more like okay so you
found a specific plug example so you
know that they're using projects so
using plug X as part of our Arsenal and
maybe you can even say yeah they're
using the early 2016 builder of this
strain of projects and then tradecraft
that is well I guess that is what makes
most immediate sense here that's their
processes their routines and stuff how
did in their training how do they work
how do they think how are you how do you
structure the work and then the other
axis is stages of attack so that is sort
of loosely based on the cyber kale chane
but that is that paper by the way is so
awesome and the way that Lockheed Martin
used and I guess still uses the kill
chain concept is awesome but now
everyone seems to think that every
attack in the world goes according to
the cyber kill chain which it doesn't
because that is a very malware oriented
you know
penetrating your system with Mallory
kind of attack so I've simplified it and
just try to make it more generic and say
that if someone is going to attack you
they're gonna first they're going to
prepare for it then there's gonna be an
intrusion face and I don't have just
mean exploitation you know getting code
running Orion system I mean the whole
access layer that we talked about
earlier right getting building
access into your network and then the
execution stage which is sort of okay
using that access to to delivering on
their mission and their objectives so
what are we gonna use this for okay so I
just told you this let's get beyond that
yeah so the purpose of this is to help
you identify knowledge gaps because if
you have knowledge gaps that means there
is going to be uncertainty and we
started out by you know saying we need
to reduce uncertainty if we want to make
better decision as interim Incident
Response so this is specifically put
together to help you reduce uncertainty
by identifying knowledge gaps so how
okay I if you read about what not to do
and do during public speaking one of the
things that's on top of the knot not to
do list is apologize
do not apologize just whatever it is
just go I feel I have to apologize for
this this is a bit too crowded for you
guys to make any sense of unless you
have like 15 minutes later today
after this is put online but I'm going
to try to work you through it so don't
try to read everything so if you have if
you observe that you have a hacked web
server and someone placed a see knife
web shell there
well that is I'm at right corner by the
way for those of you who want to sort of
see where I'm talking that is an
observation that you would put in into
you know for
print in the intrusion phase and if
someone sends you in a phishing email to
a specific user from a specific IP that
is also in a footprint in the intrusion
phase and so forth to pick some of the
other cells here like use mimikatz to
harvest credentials from memory well
that is an arsenal thing in the
execution phase okay maybe it should
actually based on what I just said maybe
that should actually have been an
intrusion face because that is basically
and I can access an access thing so
tradecraft
uses ping - and one an IP to check if a
host this up and then before all thing
to the IP C share right that is a
tradecraft thingy for the execution
phase point is if you if you take all
your findings and you map them according
to this it will become immediate to you
very quickly if it turns out that you
have zero clue what is going on in the
preparation phase like that would mean
friends so so in the footprint for
preparation upper left corner is like
register evil calm with enum thank you
some of the apt one guys they just loved
enum their like every every domain they
register was an enum right if you know
nothing about how they prepare their
attacks against you you know you have
knowledge gaps knowledge gaps that might
be critical because when we are talking
about preventing re-entry knowing how
they setting how they set up their
infrastructure for the next way is
actually very important and if you when
when you map all you know you see you
know I have nothing nothing in the
yellow column you can you can sit down
with your managers and say you know what
we have big knowledge gaps there's too
much uncertainty here for us to actually
kick these guys out now unless it's
really urgent that we do so
and you know so this the big bubble
there that is one of the the
observations from the last slide you can
also use this to take your observations
and just okay so this is what we absurd
use projects on host set set set to
query database server
why for data type a okay projects which
builder which train which group uses
this you know you can spawn a lot of
other questions host said said said okay
how did they get onto that system why
did I get to go to that system DB server
why whether they get the creds can you
use these credentials on other servers
have they used this these credentials on
these servers you know for every for
every finding that you have you can sort
of you can you can you can create a
whole list in your questions that you
possibly could answer and these will
again you know map into different parts
of the matrix and some of it will not
even map into this but in map into some
of the other models the point is you can
use this to figure out if there are if
there is a lot of stuff that you really
should know before you try to kick these
guys out that is the whole purpose of
this is in the yellow box at the bottom
there the fat pie is sort of its purpose
is to sort of be able to soon canary for
your response if you figure out you have
too many knowledge gaps you probably
shouldn't try to act until you fill
those knowledge gaps and this is equally
important if you figure out you have a
lot of knowledge gaps that you're unable
to close you need to figure out why
maybe you actually have to rebuild some
of the infrastructure before you act
because before you do that you don't
really have a defendable infrastructure
so if you kick them out you're just
gonna come straight back in
this is just all of them combined the
fat by the c-team that addresses your
uncertainty the risk type matrix that
sort of says something about your
urgency you know do we have to act now
or can we wait a bit and so this is sort
of this is gonna be you're gonna get
you're gonna maybe the urgency says we
actually do need to act now and then the
fat pie is kind of said we cannot really
do now but what you can get if you if
you try to organize your thinking this
way I'm not I mean you kind of use this
directly this is just you know concepts
to use when organizing your analysis but
if you do this you can actually start
you know saying this suggests that we
should wait this suggests that we should
act now this suggests it's going to be
super complicated you know so you can
sort of piece together an argument and
be able to present it to people and say
you know I I this is what I think we
should do this is why I think we should
do it this way and I hear you want to do
it like this but you know based on based
on what you know I presented to you here
if we do that
that is going to hurt us here so you can
get a lot more granular discussion
around the decision on what to do and
that is the whole point of all these
models so I think I have like four
minutes left is that true yeah so good
thing I only have four slides left or
something like that so we're going to go
to response patterns because now we've
been talking about the apt patterns
talking about analytical methods and now
okay
we I'm talking about instrument response
let's talk about some incident response
patterns and this is sort of an
sarcastic slide I'd say that's a very
normal response pattern is just
ignorance so you can't really call it a
response pattern but you know you just
ignore the problem completely Sony is I
don't know if they're ignorant or denial
but like no no it's okay we know we know
but we accept this risk and yeah well
turn out that that Cesar was wrong then
you have denial you know someone tell
you about the problem you just
you just go no I don't I've literally
had someone tell me that their CTO
quote/unquote didn't believe in a PT so
it was a question of faith apparently
and not then is what I like to
call the maqam old response pattern and
that is like alert reimage alert to
reimage you know you just
and then it's the clean purge and score
earth which basically is you know I
don't scope and identify and clean up
that's the clean purge is okay close
down the network we image everything
reset every password and scorched earth
is you know build a new data center and
migrate and in the middle there is
engaged and that means playing chess
with the attackers that means you don't
just Scopes sit back and do nothing
scope and then clean but you start you
know you start poking them a bit you
know I'm gonna I'm gonna close up this
access I'm gonna make it look like you
this was just totally random that we did
this but actually we did it to keep you
away from date the source X and the
reason this is an arc the response arc
is that on the left side you know very
little effect the stuff that you do
there has very little effect on the
right side you don't really want to do
that either I mean you do not want to
build a new data center and migrate that
is insanely costly right and I believe
that in the middle there you strike a
good balance between being effective and
being cost effective the problem is that
the engage response pattern requires a
really excellent response team if you
want to do that if you want to have it
effective but you don't want to build
new data centers from around you know
how we know in them you need to have
really really good people in your
response team like highly specialized
team of experts basically which cost a
lot which is going to you know make a
lot of companies gonna we can't do that
but I think that strikes a good balance
and now is for the wrap-up so why did I
call this the red pill of attacker
eviction well based
these models that I presented I'm gonna
I'm gonna say that responding to these
kinds of things is actually a lot more
complex than most responders really
realize and appreciate and you're up
against something I chose to were Volant
because I mean it's easy to think
knowledge you know viruses and computers
yeah yeah I know the whole adversary
thing but you know we're cleaning it up
but on the business side of things it's
actually someone coming at you know with
a knife you know they don't play fair
you know
they're gonna break every rule in the
book to win the competition against you
it's like in a soccer field it's like
you know hurting someone's need
deliberately to have them off the field
right is that kind of thing going on and
that is the red pill here to sort of
realize how complex it is and how how
bad it really is but the key takeaway
from the whole thing is that if you
really work at understanding what is
going on to you know use it for instance
using these models there is a lot we can
do to improve how we do this then you
can actually choose the right response
pattern to the identified intrusion
patterns and the trap and risk types and
hopefully land on a better a better
response plan than you would if you
didn't and I'm gonna end this talk now
with sort of my favorite well actually
it is a prodigy album but it's sort of a
motto because everyone is going like oh
the attackers have all the advantages
and I'm like nope if you use your
home-field advantage you are at a very
good place that's fighting back so even
though you are always outnumbered you
should never be outgunned and this stack
of models is just one more gun you know
in your stack to be able to fight back
and I hope at least some of you will be
able to use this for the good fight and
now I'm gonna
and not give Mike a heart attack so
thank you for your attention and yeah
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]