I'd like to introduce the EFF
panel. This is the ask the EFF
panel. You get to ask some of
the premier legal minds devoted
to making your sure your ass
doesn't end up in jail,
questions. So I'm going to hand
it off to Kurt Opsahl. And let
him introduce his panelists.
>> Welcome everybody. So great
to see so many people here
today. How many of you are
already familiar. With EFF? All
right. I have a good number of
hands. Thank you for following
our issues. So I'll make only
the briefest descriptions for
those who haven't. Electronic
Frontier Foundation. We are a
nonprofit civil liberties
organization, dedicated to
defending your rights online.
For fair use, for privacy, for
innovation. And we want to make
sure the future is one we want
to live in. One of the things
that we do a lot here is we
provide free legal advice to
speakers and security
researchers, who need that. And
we're here today to answer your
questions. We'll start out by
giving brief introductions to my
co-panelists here. So you can
see what sort of work we do.
Give you some ideas about
questions to ask. One ground
rule very important as we do
provide legal advice, and we
often have had members of this
community become our clients,
but this is not the place to ask
legal advice. You want to have a
attorney client privilege
conversation which is
confidential. When you're
explaining the things that you
might have done and you're
worried about. When you're doing
it in front of several hundred
people, that is not the right
place for it. So if you have
those sorts of questions, save
them for later. Come find us
after. Write to info@EFF.org.
Our intake coordinator can help
you get in touch with the right
people. But, umm, for these
questions, any other topics
about what we do? We'd love to
hear them. So let's start out
and have our panel introduce
themselves. >> Hi there. My name
is Eva Galperin. I'm a global
policy analyst with the
Electronic Frontier Foundation.
I work on EFF's international
team. Meaning that while we have
many employees of EFF who's job
it is to worry about U.S. law
and U.S. surveillance and sort
of U.S. persons, my team worries
about the rest of the world.
We're a little busy and we don't
sleep much. Primarily, I work on
-- my work is focused on
vulnerable populations. Which
means usually journalists and
dissidents and activists. I work
on privacy surveillance security
and free speech issues. You can
ask me about sort of the
security and privacy advice that
EFF is giving, the kind of
training that we're doing with
people in Ethiopia and Vietnam.
I'm also particularly interested
in the post Soviet states.
There's a lot of really
interesting stuff going on with
surveillance right now in the
U.K. and Australia. I am also
available to answer various
questions about sort of how EFF
views security research because
I have published a great deal of
security research with EFF and
also in cooperation with citizen
lab. So having said that, here's
Yan. >> Hay, I'm YAN, I'm a
staff technologist at EFF which
is a really vague title. But I
maintain a browser extension
called HTTPS everywhere with the
tore project. Wow, thank you.
[Applause] Cool. Yeah. Making a
new release when I get back on
Monday, I also make a browser
extension called privacy badger.
That's an ad -- You guys really
like browser extensions. Ok I'm
not done yet. We'll get this.
And what else do I do? We have a
new mail encryption project
called star TLS everywhere which
I've spoken about here for a
little bit. In general my work
is on -- focus on how do we
protect people's privacy from
advertisers and governments and
so forth. And also how do we get
people who run servers to turn
on encryption as much as they
can. So you can ask me anything.
>> Hey guys, I'm Mark Jaycox.
I'm a legislative analyst with
EFF where I hope to get our
message to congress and talk to
lawmakers and work -- depending
on the congressmen or
congresswoman, argue what their
staffers about what they're
doing. What they're trying to
do. And how their legislation
will impact tech. My main
issues, issues I work on deal a
lot with national security
issues, surveillance law, the
CFAA the Computer Fraud and
Abuse Act. And kind of a lot of
the surveillance privacy laws.
>> I'm Nate Cardozo, I'm a staff
attorney with the Electronic
Frontier Foundation. I'm on the
civil liberties team. I do free
speech and privacy and I work
with Curt on the coders writes
project. We represent hackers
and security researchers and
academics to try to keep them
out of trouble and get them out
of trouble. We do in fact
counsel people who present at
conferences just like this to
make sure they don't say
anything that they will regret
in front of a room full of Feds.
I work on, I don't really work
on the national security cases
that we do. Right now I'm suing
the government of Ethiopia for
wiretapping an American citizen
on American soil using a
targeted malware program called
FinFisher. If the FinFisher guys
are here, tell them I say hi. I
work on some automotive privacy
issues because I like cars. I do
freedom of information act
litigation as well and right now
along with our legal fellow
Andrew Crocker, who is not here,
I am suing the NSA and the
office of the director of
national intelligence to get
them to court over documents
about the so called
vulnerabilities equities
process. This is the balancing
test the government uses to
decide whether or not to sit on
zero days. And we want to know
what that process is because
they haven't told anybody. And
so we foyed it and of course
they didn't respond so we sued.
That's what I do. [Applause]
>> As I said, I'm Kurt Opsahl
another one of the attorneys at
EFF. Let me tell you about a
couple other pieces of
litigation that we work on that
you guys might have questions
about. We have a couple of
active suits against the
National Security Agency for the
war against wiretapping program
trying to put a halt to the
unconstitutional legal telephone
records program and the upstream
wiretapping program. I also am
working on the case against
national security letters. These
are letters that the FBI can
issue to serve providers without
a court, without any process. To
obtain information about their
customers and if they get one,
the service providers aren't
allowed to tell anybody, even
the fact that they have received
one, we got a court to declare
it was unconstitutional last
year. Thank you. [Applause] The
government has appealed. We are
defending that appeal so
argument will be in early
October and we will go explain
to the appeals court, why that's
not right and shouldn't be
allowed. We also work on some
intellectual property issues.
Probably answer some of your
copyright questions if they come
up. And I guess with that, let's
start this up with the
questions. Sir. >> Thank you.
Can you hear me okay? >> Yes >>
My name is Don Nindell. I'm CEO
of a Nevada corporation. I have
two patents on security. They
deal with encryption. Because of
that, about three years ago, I
got a card from one of the ACLU
panelists. And I want to ask, do
you compliment? Do you work with
ACLU? What I'm thinking about
is, maybe I need a card from one
of you also because if I'm in
encryption, you know exactly
who's looking at it and why I'm
a person of interest. Is it
possible to be able to edit --
to get a card like this after --
in a private session? Because I
think some day they're going to
be right here standing besides
me and yanking me off. Do you
understand my question? >> I
think the question is -- how do
we work together with our
friends at the ACLU. >> Yeah,
you complement each other? Do
you coordinate? Do you work side
by side. And which one of you
would be the best one for me to
consult with in the event that
no such agency -- I'm not
supposed to mention it. >> The
second part of the question was
how do you get assistance from
EFF when you find yourself in
legal hot water. >> Something
like that yeah. >> Let me
address, I guess, the first
question, the first and we work
together very closely with the
ACLU. For example, one case that
we're working on about the 215
records program. We are
co-counseling with the ACLU. So
that's a pretty tight
relationship. We have been
Amicus which is -- in court
cases, in addition to the
parties, you can come in as an
Amicus like a friend of the
court to provide some additional
views to the court from your
community. So we've often done
this in ACLU cases. They've
often done that in our cases. So
I think we have actually a very
good relationship with them. And
do complement each other. And I
think the second part of the
question was how to, how to get
assistance from EFF. So actually
on this panel, we have two
former intake coordinators. They
have now gone onto other jobs
with EFF. One of you guys want
to talk about that process a
little bit? >> I can do it. So
if you would like EFF to help
you in some way, if you are
looking for legal assistance,
the thing to do is to e-mail
info@EFF.org. At the other end
of that e-mail address, is a
very nice man named Amule whose
job it is to patiently talk to
everybody who wants EFF's help.
Figure out whether or not this
is the sort of case that that
EFF would like to take on. And
if that's the case, put them in
touch with an EFF attorney. If
it is not an EFF case, his job
does not end there. The next
step is to put this person
either in touch with other
resources, especially if this is
sort of not an EFF like issue.
Or to put them in touch with our
list of cooperating attorneys we
maintain a list of several
hundred attorneys across the
country all of whom are
interested in doing pro bono
cases and sometimes you know,
sort of semipro bono discount
cases that come EFF's way. And
who can also provide you with
legal assistance. What we do is
send an e-mail out to that list.
And if somebody responds, we go
ahead and put you in touch with
them. >> So YAN, I was wondering
if you could describe HTTP
Nowhere for the folks in the
room and where the implications
of billing that entails and
stuff like that. And another
question is, could you guys talk
about the Riley case and
implications for hackers in the
room and how things might have
changes. >> The implications
from which case? >> Riley.
>> Hacking -- Cell phone
searches. >> Absolutely yeah.
>> Okay. I guess since you asked
the first part of the question
to me, I should answer it. How
many people here use HTTPS
everywhere? So real quickly what
it is, it's a browser extension
that will automatically make the
HTTPS connection to a website
when you visit it if we know
that that server supports HTTPS
and things are unlikely to break
if we switch you over to SSL. So
this prevents SSL strip attacks
which Moxi has presented on in
the past, and also, sometimes
Redit for instance, doesn't
really, until recently, you had
to go to pay.redit.com to get
the SSL version. So we would
have that automatically in a
browser extension so -- it's
pretty good. We have like 10,000
sites or so in the development
version right now. Maybe 4,000
stable. So lately a lot of
people have been saying with all
these NSA attacks and privacy
concerns, HTTPS Everywhere is
not good enough. What you want
is a harden Browser mode where
you don't have any clear text
traffic. So what if you could
just only use HTTP -- sorry,
only use HTTPS, never go to
HTTP. So it's actually pretty
easy to do from HTTPS
Everywhere. So now if you use
the development version of HTTPS
Everywhere, you could experiment
with this mode called HTTP
Nowhere mode where it blocks all
HTTP traffic. I have to do some
weird things like turns off OCSP
for a little bit, otherwise,
you'll get SSL errors all the
time. I love feedback on that
and stuff like that. >> All
right. And a second part of the
question was asking about the
Riley case, which is a recent
decision by the United States
Supreme Court dealing with the
search of a smart phone. And of
course found nine-zero that you
needed to have a warrant to get
this information. This is a
really good decision. Not only
is it a good decision because
this means that the government
needs to get a warrant on a cell
phone if you're arrested. That's
good enough in itself, but it
helps establish precedent for
other cases. The discussion in
that case has a lot of really
good language that is going to
end up in briefs. For years to
come where the court was saying
your whole life is in your
phone. It matters to protect
this information and that they
-- the governments argument that
well, you know, basically as
technology made things easier to
have on your person. We should
sort of treat this like -- just
whatever happened to be in your
pockets -- ordinarily they can
look in your pockets and search
to arrest. So they wanted to
have the effect of new
technology be an expansion of
police power to search. So they
would be able to get anything
that happened to be in your
pocket, all the way into the
phone and potentially into any
server side information that was
accessible to the phone. And the
supreme court rejected that
theory. Rejected their theory
that because these phones were
connected to servers elsewhere,
that the, you had given up your
privacy rights to them because
you had communicated that
information to a third party.
The government said therefore
you didn't care about this
information -- should be free
rain. No warrant needed. The
court rejected that. The
government said, well we put
forth some regulations and rules
that will make sure this happens
in a very orderly and nice
manner And the courts said our
founders didn't fight a
revolution to have government
regulations and rules. This is
9-0. Right? [Applause] So if you
guys read in our briefs and the
years to come, I think you're
going to see a lot of quotes
from the Riley decision and
we're going to try to make that
precedent stick all over on
fourth amendment issues.
[Applause] >> Hi, I'm Andrew
Conway. I'm a researcher for
Cloud Mark. I'd actually be
interested in a a comment from
each member of the panel on this
one. What do you think the best
and worst things that have
happened in the past year from
the point of view of your
particular work for the year
ahead? >> Awesome question. >>
Great question. >> All right
well, we're hitting the whole
panel. Let's keep it very brief.
I think I'll start out with some
of the best and the worst
things. It's the same thing
which is the revelations that we
have learned about -- the
additional information we have
learned about NSA surveillance.
The best thing because we now
have much more information about
it, it helps us fight our law
suits against the NSA and it
helps make people aware of
what's going on and the need to
stop it. It's the worst thing
because oh my God, they're doing
an amazing amount of
surveillance on us in
contravention of our
constitutional rights. >> I'm
going to take a very similar
approach which is the, I'm going
to talk about a different leak
which happened just last week
and earlier this week. There was
a hacker who goes by the name of
Finius Fisher who broke into
Gamma. >> Huh? >> So the hacker
who broke into Gamma, which is a
company which makes a product
called Vinture and Vinspy. They
went ahead and pulled a bunch of
their brochures and also a whole
lot of other documentation. And
some of their source code. And
put it all online. One of the
most interesting revelations
that have come about as a result
of this particular hack is
conformation of a lot of the
work that Citizen Lab has been
doing over the last couple of
years about the fact that this
company which is based in the UK
and Germany is selling its
surveillance equipment to
governments that are using it
for very shady purposes. Using
it to spy on activists and
journalists and possibly
committing human rights abuses.
So it's really great to get sort
of conformation about this stuff
that we have been suspecting for
several years. Umm, the bad
news, I think the worst thing
that I've really seen this year
is a lot of security and privacy
burn out. I talk to journalists
and activists all over the world
and I watch them sub come to the
privacy anihilism. They read
things like the FinFisher hack
or they look at the NSA
documents and they say well the
government knows how to get to
everything all the time anyway.
So why should I bother
protecting my privacy and
security at all. And this is
really one of those -- one of
the most important fights that
we need to fight on the world
stage, which is getting people
the technical information they
need to understand that when you
simply give up on protecting
your privacy and security, you
are letting the bad guys win.
Governments want you to think
that they are all powerful and
that they see everything all the
time. Because if you don't do
anything, you make that work
trivial. And there are a couple
things that you can do that will
make their job hard. [Applause]
>> That is a difficult answer to
follow up. So I'm just going to
say something really boring
which is that SSL usage is
actually up quite significantly.
So there's a report that stated
in some parts of the world, like
Latin America, peak traffic
percentage of that that's
encrypted has gone from about
one or two percent to about ten
percent. It's amazing. And it's
largely because major service
providers have been turning on
SSL. And there's more about to
come. So Cloud Core has said if
we SSL for all customers -- but
very soon -- and word process
said, we're turning on SSL for
everyone in the next year.
That's a lot of sites. So we're
doing okay on that front. The
bad things that happened this
year was Heart Bleed. And it was
really demoralizing to other
people and we -- as a maintainer
of HTTPS Everywhere I actually
noticed some sites starting to
break after Heart Bleed because
their operators said we're just
not going to use SSL now. We're
going to turn it off. And that's
really sad. >> So you know what?
It is very rough out there but
you know what's a little comfort
to everybody? A little bit of
tradition. But what we could all
use right now is something that
we all know and love. Which is
welcoming new speakers. I know
not everybody that's up here is
new. Some of you have spoken
before. Please raise your hand
if you are a new speaker at Def
Con. >> Alright! [Applause] >>
I'll also take a drink cheers.
Congratulations. [Applause] >>
That's good too. >> I'm awake
now. >> Now back to your
regularly scheduled mayhem.
Thanks guys. >> Thanks guys. I
will have to take a similar
approach to Curt I think the
worse things are -- is really
the information we've had from
Snowden, from the leakers. I
think the best thing though I
will take is part of the
educational aspects. The public,
larger public non-tech people
are becoming a lot more aware of
what they share -- who they
share with. Their behavior's
changing. They're learning what
a third party is. And where
their information is potentially
going. To data brokers and other
third parties. And at least in
-- particularly in my area,
especially working on the
legislative side and with
congress, members of congress
actually are getting educated on
these things. We've seen members
of congress outraged that they
were not properly briefed on
this stuff. And completely
outraged that they have a right
to know, they should have been
informed and they weren't in
some instances. So that has a
huge impact on where congress is
moving with this stuff, gaining
a base understanding of the
complexity of these systems.
Complexity of what the NSA and
government and intelligence
agencies are collecting. So
those are really the two most
important aspects on my book.
You have a clear response which
was, increase education from the
public and from members of
congress. And that provides a
base level, right, it provides a
foundation to understanding the
systems and it provides the
foundation to reorienting your
actions towards more privacy
friendly, towards a more tech
friendly environment and in
particular when it comes to
lawmakers, legislation, and
smart legislation. And actually
thoughtful legislation. >> So,
one of the projects that I work
on at EFF is our, who has your
back report. This is the report
where we give gold stars to
companies that have good
practices in protecting user
data. Companies are little
children and they respond very
well to being offered gold
stars. This year was our fourth
year, fourth? Fourth year of who
has your back. And the best
thing that we saw this year, far
and away, is companies almost
down the line with the big
Internet Service Providers.
Google, Microsoft, Facebook,
Apple, are promising to give
notice to users when the
government comes seeking their
data unless they're gagged. That
is just extraordinarily
important if a company gives
notice to the user when the
government comes seeking their
data, that means the user can
fight back they can contact
info@EFF.org. We can move to
quash the process. And if the
company doesn't give notice, no
one can fight because the
company's not going to do it.
We've seen in the last year that
column on our who has your back
report just filled with stars
and it's awesome. That frankly
is a direct result of the
Snowden leaks. The companies had
egg on their face with that
beautiful prison slide that we
saw on August 6th of last year.
So they needed to do something
-- or June 6th -- they needed to
do something. And they are. And
that's great. I think the worst
thing that I've seen this year
is CFAA reform is stalled in
congress. It's not moving and it
needs to move. After our friend
Aaron Schwartz's tragic death,
there was some momentum behind
it, and now it's not moving. And
that sucks and it needs to
change. >> Alright. So when I
receive an email with a GPG
signature, it's really
reassuring that I know that the
e-mail comes from the person I
want it from. Is a GPG signature
generally considered evidence in
court that an email came from a
place, and ultimately a lack of
a GPG signature can that be used
as evidence that an e-mail
didn't come from someone --
asking for a friend. >> As to
the second part of the question,
I don't think anyone's ever
tried that. As to the first part
of the question, you would need
an expert testimony to support
that. Umm, but sure. I mean it
helps establish train of
custody. It helps establish
authentication. It's not forged.
My GPG fingerprint is on my
business card and I encourage
all of you to do the same thing.
So I know it's actually your GPG
signature. Anyway, yeah. >> Can
I ask a quick follow up which is
weird because I'm on the panel.
But that was a great question.
Conversely. >> Get in line.
>> What's that? >> Get in line.
[Laughing] >> So conversely,
people say OPR's great. Because
that's plausible deniability. Do
you think that will hold up in
court as evidence that someone
didn't say something if the
other party turns over their
chat logs. >> Maybe. >> I don't
know. Okay. >> I'm a lawyer. The
answer is it depends. >> Well
it's complicated. [Laughing]
>> Well plausible deniability
and non-repudiation are two
different things. So, sorry, did
that make sense >> Thank you
guys for what you do. What kind
of expectation of privacy do
employees have from next
generation firewalls that are
doing HTTPS inspection. And as
an administer. >> Could you
speak up? >> Could you please?
>> And slow down a little bit.
>> Sorry, what kind of
expectation of privacy do
employees have from next
generation firewalls that are
doing HTTPS inspection in their
workplace. And as an
administrator of one of those
firewalls, is there anything
legal that an admin would need
to know about running one of
those? >> I'll take the first
part of his question. Most of
you when you come to work for a
company, among the very large
piles of documents that you
sign, one of them essentially
says that anything they do to
you on their net work is nice
and legal and you say it's okay.
And that includes intercepting
your encrypted chats on their
network. Man in the middling
them and reading them. Networks
such as apple have been doing
this for years on the theory
that this will help them catch
leakers. If you have given up
your rights you have given up
your rights. That answers the
first part of the question.
Whether or not there is any
culpability on the part of the
network of administrators, I'm
not a lawyer, and this is not
legal advice. But again, if the
employee has already signed a
document saying that anything
you do to me on the net work is
nice and legal, I don't think
that you have any culpability.
>> I would add a little bit to
that as a lawyer. I would add it
depends. There are circumstance
sometimes where they don't put
the things in the employee
manual -- what it says in the
manual and how detailed it is.
There are cases from time to
time in which somebody has been
able to say what they have done
with actually not part of what I
gave consent to in the employee
manual. And under some
circumstances where government
employers if you're trying to --
you may have some additional
rights. So under particular
circumstances, it could happen.
So if there's something where
it's a concrete example and
there's a real question. That
would be the sort of thing to
get specific advice about that
particular situation. >> With
your encrypted e-mail
initiative, what is your
technical goals and are you
working with anyone else's also
working on the same sort of
problem like dark mail? >> What
was the last word you said?
>> Are you working with other
people who are also trying to
solve encrypted e-mail like dark
mail or anything like that.
>> So the question was, what's
our encrypted e-mail initiative.
Which makes me -- the way you
ask that makes me think that I
was kind of misleading in my
introduction. Oh so, our
encrypted e-mail project is for
server to server transit
encryption, not end to end like
you encrypting an e-mail to
another person. Which is what a
lot of people use PGP for. So
our encrypted e-mail project
Start TLS Everywhere, is to make
TLS connections between SMTP
servers more robust. I'm not
sure if that's actually what you
wanted to hear about. So I'm
going to stop talking. But if
you do, then ask someone else
will ask me that question. Yeah.
>> Hi, my name's Ethan, I'm a 3L
at UCLA. I really appreciate
your work. Historically when you
look at lot of the civil rights
battles they've been done very
strategically. An organization
will have a very clearly defined
goal, be it gay marriage or
desegregation and they go about
achieving that goal very
strategically through test cases
and being very selective. Do you
have any macro goal like that
with corresponding strategy or
are you a more of an attack
everywhere mentality. >> We
absolutely cannot attack
everywhere. We have about 50
people in the organization. And
that -- our band width is
constantly filled with being
able to work on -- a small
percentage of the cases. We
definitely try to be strategic
about it. One of the things that
happens with our intake
coordinator -- we're talking
about that process before -- is
try to determine whether to take
the case to see if it can be
done within our band width and
also accomplish the goal. Try to
set precedent, try to do
something which is going to have
a greater effect then just on
the parties involved and try to
push things forward. I know
there are things which are over
arching our goals. We want to
support fair use. So we take
some cases which will help
solidify the fair use doctrine.
We want to determine that a --
third party doctrine is book.
Third party doctrine is this
notion that you lose your fourth
amendment rights if you store
information with a third party
and then this was brought about
in the late seventies, nowadays
with more and more information
going online. It's very
dangerous doctrine. We're trying
to find the right cases to
undermine that. To come up with
a better doctrine for dealing
with information in the digital
age. So yeah, we do operate very
strategically. >> I'll also add
that we also have annual
meetings where we think about
hard and seriously what we have
done in the past year. At least
-- I'm speaking for the legal
team now, precedence wise -- and
each team does this. But
thinking about, for the year,
what have we done in the past
and what really do we want to do
in the next few years? You know,
three, five, seven years. So
there's a lot of long-term
thinking. There's a lot of you
know, figuring out where our
resources are best served. And
that long-term thinking, I
think, you know, is very
important to figuring out where
we spend our resources. What we
want to do, what we need to do.
And a lot of it, you know, we
get from talking to you guys.
>> I'll give a concrete example,
the Ethiopia case that I'm
working on that I actually
should be writing an opposition
to a motion to dismiss right now
but instead I'm talking to you.
We took that case so -- our
client is an Ethiopian American.
He's a US citizen, he lives in
Silver Spring Maryland, charming
man. We took that case not just
because what the Ethiopian
government did to him sucks, we
took the case because we want to
establish the precedent that
governments can't just spy on
people willy nilly without going
through the legal process. Which
is exactly what the Ethiopian
government did to our guy. And
if we can get an American court
to say illegal spying is illegal
and you can't do it, that's
valuable. Not just for our
client, but for everybody. So I
mean, that's a window into the
type of thinking that we do
before we take a case. >> So my
question's more about turning to
the offensive. I'm a malware
researcher. And I've come across
many times where a botnet or a
ransomeware coming out of a
control server, is vulnerable
itself. If I was to say attack
that server with the end goal to
shut down the botnet or disable
the malware network, what legal
ramifications are there and is
it even an option? I don't want
to take it, I want to dish some
back. >> It depends. [Laughing]
>> For a question about your
particular situation, that's
probably one in which we should
be taking offline and having a
-- >> Ill advised! >> I'll spin
on that question a little bit.
Microsoft did something
interesting a couple of weeks
ago. They discovered a botnet
that they didn't like at all.
That was using noIP.org. The
dynamic DNS services. For its
command and control structure.
Which I think is a pretty clever
idea. But that's neither here
nor there. And they decided they
wanted to take it out, and they
were going to take it out by
suing noIP. And they did, and
they got the registries to turn
over control of the name servers
to Microsoft. And as a result,
they put five million innocent
dynamic DNS subscribers out of
service for like four days.
That's not the way to do it
buddy. So thank you. [Applause]
>> My name's Shawn. With the
Supreme Court of the United
States weighing in a lot of
these issues where we have crash
course in technology for the
justices. Obviously there's
different ways that they can get
things wrong depending on your
perspective with regard to legal
and philosophical matters. But
it seems to me that'll be really
bad if they get things wrong
because of technical matters. It
seems to me that their lack of
technological savvy represents a
threat to them getting it right.
I'd like to know if you guys
agree. If so, to what magnitude
do you think that risk is. And
do you think there is any way to
mitigate that risk. >> This is
actually something that has been
involved with EFF for many
years. Which is explaining to
judges about technology. In
order to be a judge, you have to
practice law for 20 or 30 years.
So you tend to be of the
generation or two beyond what
the current technologies are.
And this has been one of the
challenges. And we try to do
this by explaining it well. We
have our staff technologists who
will help us out. We're writing
our briefs, trying to explain it
in clear plain English terms,
what these technology -- use
metaphors so the judges will
understand and try to improve
it. Now you may have seen for
some of the decisions the last
couple years by the Supreme
Court where they ask some
questions which indicated that
perhaps they weren't fully
understanding the technology.
Things like, if a pager got two
pages at the same time would
they get a busy signal and this
is about pager technology which
is already a generation behind.
They had -- and in a recent
decision, they talked a lot
about the cloud. Some of them
seemed to understand what that
meant. Some of them maybe not,
not so much. But, nevertheless,
this is something which is very
important. And one -- a very
important sort of, saving grace
which I think that's help come
up with some good decisions out
of judges in recent eras, is
they all worked with clerks. And
the clerks are recent law school
grads who are much more familiar
with modern technology than the
judges they work for and can
help explain it to the judges
and understand the briefs about
it. >> Thank you. >> I have
another Riley question. I'm a
graduate student. I deal with
human subjects data. I also have
to go travel internationally a
lot. Does Riley just protect my
cell phone, or does it also
protect my laptop and tablet and
does it protect me at the
border. >> Let me hit that, the
first question is does Riley
protect you beyond cell phone?
Just a little digression about
how sort of the the precedent
system works. So when you have a
case decided, what it means is
just specific to the facts that
are there. The case is about
cell phones. But when you later
have a case about a tablet or
laptop, you can say to the
court, look this is similar to a
cell phone. This is something
that is so similar to a cell
phone because it operates,
because like a smart phone, it
can do these functions, it can
-- communicate just like cell
phone can. That you should come
to the same conclusions for this
new technology as you did with
the old technology. And so the
cell phone decision forms a
precedent. And that we were to
be using that precedent case by
case to expand its scope so it
hits these other areas. And then
as far as international borders,
your rights are much lessened at
international borders. Coming
in, they are able to do --
instead of needing a warrant
based on probable cause, they
need reasonable suspicions which
is a lower standard -- >> Your
suspicious. >> What? >> I just
said your suspicious. >> Very
suspicious. >> Thank you we're
all suspicious. >> Umm does that
answer your question? >> Yes.
Thanks. >> One more thing. EFF
has written a white paper about
your rights at the border. This
is referred to as our border
search white paper. It was
written by my colleagues Seth
Showen and Marsha Hofmann who's
now in private practice. So if
you would like more details
about your rights at the border
just go ahead and take a look at
them. >> Thank you. >> There's
recently a technological
innovation that IC is expanding
the scope of what can be
accomplished through speech.
It's called bit coin. And it
allows a person to memorize a
phrase and there by travel, go
here go there, and keep secret
with an arbitrarily large amount
of money. To communicate that
phrase to another person through
speech alone. And that person
can then, if they were to so
choose, go use a computer to get
access to that money and give it
to somebody else in the same
way. So now that transmitting
money and storing money is a
form of speech, that wasn't true
until four or five years ago
really. The EFF has done cases
where people have encrypted tax
records and things like that.
There -- haven't there been some
EFF cases already that look at
the intersection between a
person's right to privacy and
free speech and finance. But now
that the scope of that
relationship is just being blown
wide open, why is EFF just
staying out of that fight and
why is it -- you know. Why do
they refuse bit coin donations.
Why are they -- >> We take bit
coin donations. >> Where does
that play out? Like the current
regulatory guidance's from the
IRS and Bensin, and New York
department of financial
services. Does EFF even do
regulatory law? Are they going
to start doing regulatory law
because of this intersection?
>> Let me clear up a little bit
of confusion. There was a brief
period of time during which EFF
stopped taking bit coin
donations. And the reason why we
did that was because we were not
sure that it was legal for us to
do so. And we needed the time to
consult. >> Modification on
that. It's that there was some
question about the legality and
what we'd like to do is be
counsel for people, and not be
the defendants of such. So we
provide legal services to others
who are in situations and so,
this sometimes means that we are
not the first actor on things
because we want to be in a
position to defend it. We didn't
want to have a situation in
which we're representing
somebody who is using bit coin
and the other side to say, well
you use bit coin yourself.
You're not a serious player
here. You're just trying to
defend your donation stream. And
then after it came to what --
I'll let you finish the rest of
the story. But I wanted to
interject there. >> All right.
We consulted with some trained
legal professionals that spent a
lot of looking at the law of
banking regulation. And once we
felt the chances of us ending up
being the defendant in a lawsuit
rather than somebody's lawyer,
we made another public
announcement saying yes we would
in fact take bit coin. I
actually think that bit coin is
a very important technology.
Primarily because it is a very
powerful tool in the fight
against sort of limiting free
speech by attacking its weakest
link. Which you definitely saw
in the sort of U.S. attacks
against papal payments to wiki
leaks. So this is one of the
reasons why we're excited about
bit coin technology and EFF.
>> Thank you for answering the
question. >> No problem. >> My
question is kind of threefold.
And it all pertains to the blimp
campaign at the Utah data
center. >> Well, try to limit it
to two, sort of twofold
questions. >> Ok, alright. >>
Fold folds two and three
together. [Laughter] >> All
right. How about one and two? Do
you believe that you achieved
your goals with add campaign and
what sort of backlash or
repercussions have you had or
challenges in launching that
campaign? >> Which campaign?
>> The Blimp campaign above the
Utah Davis center. >> Oh the
blimp campaign. >> The weather
was a challenge. [Laughing] >> I
think I -- I think I can speak
on that for a little bit and
anyone can jump in to. One of
the major goals of that campaign
-- well actually gets back to
the Beth Schwartz question. A
big aspect of that came was
increasing education around
that. We know that a lot of you
guys know about the NSA, it's
really reaching out to the next
step and reaching out to the
general public. To the people
who sometimes don't know what
HTTPS is. So that campaign was a
pretty huge educational campaign
around that issue. We saw
massive hits around it, we saw
massive sharing around it. That
is one of the main campaigns to
increase education awareness
about NSA spying and especially
around the bills in congress
too. We released a score card.
Score card is -- methodology
around where senators and
congressman and congresswomen
lawmakers rank. And that stopped
the spying.org. And so that
blimp campaign was part of that
larger roll out to make sure
that we pass strong reform that
we fix at the minimum one of
these programs in the
short-term. And making sure that
things get done. We've seen just
crazy things over the past year.
And we need to fix a lot of
them. So it's pushing that
envelope further and getting
people to act. Getting congress
to act. And increasing awareness
around that. >> Thank you.
>> You guys are great. Thank you
for your courage. >> Thanks. >>
The question I have is we've
seen a lot of mob enthusiasm for
net neutrality. And while I
think that's great, I have a
concern when congress makes
bills about the internet. And I
wanted to run a couple of lines
from these bills by you. In the
most recent bill, it says that
fixed broadband providers may
not block lawful content.
Application services or
non-harmful devices. And then in
the unreasonable discrimination,
it also says fixed broad band
providers may not unreasonably
discriminate in transmitting
lawful network traffic. It seems
like by making those statements,
they're also implying that they
will have someone at these broad
band providers watching to make
sure everything is lawful in
order to block unlawful content.
I was just curious, what is your
opinion on some of the recent
net neutrality bills? And do you
guys have a congressmen or two
that maybe has a little more
technical chops than some of the
people in there that can have a
voice in amending some of these
bills and all of this? >> Yeah
sure, I guess the kind of my
initial response is it's very
hard to do a spot on legislative
analysis right up on stage. I do
do that at some times but it's
probably a little bit hard. That
language sounds actually more
like from some of the computer
security and cyber security
bills than an actual net
neutrality bill. For the second
part of your question, I'd like
to take a step back a little bit
because right now, we hear a lot
of rumblings that congress is
going to do something on net
neutrality -- or not even do
something, but there are bills
in congress about net
neutrality. And that does not
equate to congress doing
something on net neutrality. We
have a lot of PR bills released.
We have a lot of bills that are
there for press release splash
and to make news. Right now net
neutrality is really in the
regulatory phase and they're
trying to figure that out. We
had over a million comments
filed on the net neutrality and
where it's going on -- net
neutrality reclassification and
where the public is at and where
the FCC is at. Congress right
now I think is watching. But
congress is -- I don't really
think congress is going to be
passing anything straight up on
net neutrality. I think the
important aspect -- especially
what you seen the EFF focus on
and our resources is, around the
FCC, the comment system and
community wi-fi and getting
those things out there. We'll
see, congress, as there want to
sometimes they react quickly and
will throw something on the
floor and try and move
something. But right now net
neutrality is really in the
regulatory aspect and we're
trying to hammer it down there
and get our opinions and our
thoughts out there. >> All right
umm, what is the -- I guess
current state of case law around
IMSI catchers or stingrays. And
what can we do to change that
case law so that it's not as god
awfully scary as it was last I
looked? >> I'm actually not sure
of the answer of that question.
>> One of the things we're doing
around IMSI catchers is we're
filing a bunch of FOIA law suits
to try and get municipalities
and agencies to fork over the
records of when they use IMSI
catchers. We think they use them
a whole lot more than they admit
to. So we are trying to do that.
Hanee Facurey our criminal law
attorney is not on the panel.
>> In general on IMSI catchers I
guess, some of the question is
how can you safely do research
on IMSI catchers? I guess point
back to when Christian Pagent
demoed a IMSI catcher at Def Con
a couple years ago. We were able
to get to a circumstance where
it could be researched within a
comfortable -- within the bounds
of the law. There are many laws
about using these kinds of
devices. So if you're doing
research on them, it is
definitely a good time to get
some legal advice to make sure
you're doing it in a safe way.
>> I would also add that the
current state is unknown. The
stuff that's actively being
litigated, I think just in the
past couple months. Our point
criminal defense guy has filed
amicus briefs on this. There's a
large question as to the breadth
of information and the breadth
of call detail records and
information that they're
collecting on innocent people or
on non-suspects. So I think the
current state is cloudy. That's
why we're here. We're here to
file those amicus briefs and to
make it less cloudy and clear
for the judges. >> I'll spin on
that a little bit. This is going
to get legal geeky for just a
sec. In the American legal
justice system, when law
enforcement come seeking a
warrant, they usually go to
magistrate judges, which are the
lowest level of federal judges
in the United States. They are
not appointed for life. They are
not full article three judges.
But they sign warrant
applications. We've seen in the
last year what's being referred
to as a magistrate revolution.
We've seen magistrates rejecting
search warrant applications a
lot. And it's great and they are
actively seeking amicus
participation from groups like
EFF and ACLU. And I think we
need to see a lot more of that.
>> Okay. I've got a pair of
questions. One on the
international side and one on
the judicial side. So I'm both a
U.S. and UK citizen. Does that
make me more or less protected
from U.S. and EU surveillance?
So maybe I am -- [Laughing] >>
So yeah, it's serious. Maybe one
can say awe he's EU. Nah we can
just take his stuff anyways.
What happens there? And then
secondly on the judicial side --
so for Riley, just as an example
whenever we see the government
pushing very strange
interpretations of what
constituted reasonable searches,
is that consistent across the
entire judicial department or
are there any particular
instances where they say no,
that's entirely reasonable were
going to abandon trying to push
some strange interpretation of
what is a legal search. Thanks.
>> Should I take the first half?
>> Response to that. The first
question is who do you trust
more? The NSA or DCHQ?
[Laughing] >> But Eva has a
proper answer I asume.
>> Meanwhile back in proper
answer land. [Laughing] >> So
very often when you hear
activism around opposing illegal
NSA surveillance, you hear very
sort of American centric
language. Which is the NSA is
spying on Americans. On American
citizens on, you know, blue
blooded whatever the hell. And
this is not okay. And the
implication is, that if you are
not an American citizen -- if
you are not an American you have
no rights. You're left out in
the cold. Screw you. The NSA can
spy on you all you want. This is
not true. This is not even
remotely true. One of the
reasons why you hear so much
rhetoric around how terrible it
is that the NSA is spying on
Americans is because Americans
are specifically outside of the
NSA's remit. So it is the most
clear cut case of the NSA
breaking the law. But, just
because you are a non U.S.
person, does not mean that you
don't have rights. And there are
a couple of points, a very
important points that EFF has
been making in this area. One of
them is in fact our Ethiopia
lawsuit. Where we are making the
point that if you are a
government and you want to spy
on somebody in another country,
you are still subject to the
laws of that country. And this
applies in the United States and
it applies when the U.S.
government wants to spy in other
countries as well. So we're
trying to set that precedent.
EFF was also instrumental in
putting together a set of
principles. The 13 principles on
the application of human rights
to mass surveillance. And
hundreds of organizations all
over the world have signed on to
the principles. Which you can
find at
www.necessaryandproportionate.or
g. Which is a very long and
awkward URL. >> And I can't
spell it. >> And one of the
points that we make there is
essentially that you are still
protected by international law
if you are a non U.S. person.
You still have privacy rights.
And the governments should only
be using mass surveillance in a
way that is necessary and
proportionate to the task at
hand. And what the NSA is doing
right now we're arguing is well
outside of these guidelines.
>> Thank you. >> Hello again.
How does the privacy law scale
to space and other worlds? >>
That's a great question.
>> There is a an international
treaty on space. It has some
rules about weaponization of
space and so on. But I have not
really examined it for how the
privacy laws -- but I would sure
hope that if we are going to
other worlds -- to going to
outside of this one, that we
maintain a society of the future
that respects civil liberties
wherever we go. [Applause]
>> Hi, in the last five years,
there's been a proliferation of
on officer video systems
throughout the country -- >> On
one what? >> On off surveillance
video systems. Cameras the
police officers wear on their
person. So then when they go
into somebody's home or into a
business, by contrast let's say
a dash cam that's limited to the
field of view in front of a
vehicle, or a CCTV on the inside
or outside of a business, now
law enforcement has the capacity
to enter into a private
residence or at least some sort
of a private domicile. Does the
EFF have a stance on law
enforcement wearing on officer
video. And also what are kind of
the restrictions about chain of
custody. And now we have storage
medias or mediums that can
basically store evidence
indefinitely, are there any
concerns applied to that as
well? >> I'll hit on the first
question. No matter what
technology the government is
using, they need to use it
within the bounds of the
constitution. So if they have a
camera on them inside of your
house, they still need to have a
warrant to go inside the house.
And where this is actually come
up most in the law has been
places like using heat imagers
to look through walls. Getting
that difference between
something that you're doing
outside of a house and being
able to see information that's
inside that protected place. We
want to make sure all of these
technologies are being used
within the bounds of the
constitution and where they are
seeing into a protected area, in
a place where you have a
reasonable expectation of
privacy that you are able to
protect that reasonable
expectation. And the, sort of
the other, I guess tension that
comes in there a lot as new
technologies are being used,
where previously there were
things that were very difficult
for the police to do by just a
sheer like challenge of having
the number of officers necessary
to do it. So this has come up in
the cases of GPS location vs.
--well we could have an officer
drive around and follow after
somebody but now we have this
new technology that enables us
to do that. In that case, the
Supreme Court said that the fact
that you might be able to do it
by having somebody go around.
You couldn't practically do
that. So this doesn't mean it's
always okay to use the
technology to replicate that. So
likewise they might say that the
difference you see the camera on
and off service. They couldn't
remember everything that they
saw. But now we have the camera
to be sure. But on the whole,
the real question is whether
they can go into a place that
require a warrant if they come
to your door, come back with a
warrant, whether they have a
camera or not. >> Thank you.
>> Hi. I've got a two parter on
the practical implications of a
technology lawsuit. So, when you
work with tech all day, a lot of
things could seem common sense
there's just simple facts of how
the system works. But to a
laymen and the court, it seems
like complete -- like
impenetrable to them. And I
wondered if there was any way to
think about when expert
testimony would be required in a
lawsuit. >> Expert testimony is
almost never required in a
lawsuit. There are some very
obscure areas where it is. It is
required that -- those are rare.
And especially in criminal law,
expert testimony is almost never
required. That said, it's often
extremely helpful. And the more
the better. If you are a
technical expert and you're
willing to testify for free in
EFF cases, e-mail us.
Info@EFF.org. >> So then is it
just a matter of having a lawyer
that's willing to understand the
technology deep enough to make
the argument? >> Yup. >> And
then my second part was what are
the implications on winning a
case if you do need a technical
expert? And also on bankrupting
a person that has to hire the
technical expert? >> What was
that last part? Bankruptcy?
>> So like, yeah, if you --
would it just be an incredibly
expensive ordeal that not an
average person could hope to do.
>> That's one of the things that
we try to resolve. By providing
free legal services to people
who otherwise could not afford
to do a defense. If you have to
pay for high quality lawyers who
understand these technologies,
there are a number of them out
there. They'll charge five or
$600 an hour. They're great. But
most people can't afford them.
And there are a number of
circumstances where it's been
really satisfying to get into a
case where the other side really
thought they could come in there
and brow beat somebody, just
blow them away because they have
so much money and resources and
then be on their side and we're
working for free and we get
experts to come in to work for
free and are able to match them
toe to toe where they are trying
to drive somebody under the
ground with the sheer weight of
money. It's very satisfying when
that doesn't work. [Applause]
>> Again, concrete example from
the Ethiopia case, we have a
whole stable of computer science
Ph.D.s from citizen lab, from
the University of California at
Berkeley, the University of
Toronto Monk school who are
doing top notch computer
forensics for us for free.
Thanks guys. >> First of all,
I'd like to thank the EFF for
all the good work that you guys
do. And secondly, I have a big
question for you, in regards to
Lavabit, and the talks that have
occurred here at Def Con, from
the founder of Lavabit. Has EFF
done anything, or do you plan to
do anything to try to address
the legal issues that
constitutional issues, really
that the founder of Lavabit face
where he wasn't able to tell
people his ordeal except the
attorney that he was engaging.
And the fact that the government
was aware of the fact he was
engaging certain people for
legal advice and all the issues
surrounding it? >> So we of
course have been following the
Lavabit case very closely. We
helped refer Ladar to a former
EFFer Marsha Hofmann who was
able to help him out. Umm, on
the broader issues, one of the
things we have been trying to do
with our national security
letter case is to try and
establish that silence enforced
by these lawyers where you can't
tell somebody that you received
a national security letter is a
violation of the first
amendment. We're trying to get
it so people can talk about the
process that they received and
can be able to fight back
against it more effectively. We
umm, we're very concerned about
the case. We ended up filing an
Amicus brief because of the
implications that were coming
out from the notion that they
could get the key to everybody.
That, you know, in order to go
after a particular target, you
get the key that decrypts
everybody's e-mail, and that's
far too raw. It is not targeted
and you have to trust the
government that they're not
going to misuse that key.
Unfortunately that case did not
go the way that I thought it
should have. Or the way I would
have hoped. Or you know, we're
there for the next fight as
well. >> Thank you. >> Hello. So
a while ago Europe decided that
we had a right to be forgotten.
And I think it was recently
declared technically infeasible.
I was just wondering if the EFF
was involved in that and what's
your opinions, if you can
disclose them? >> Oh yeah. So
recently the European court of
justice made a terrible ruling
regarding a gentleman in Spain
who wanted to have some
information about his previous
legal dealings. I think the sale
of the home of his in a
bankruptcy case removed from
Google search as part of an
implementation of the right to
be forgotten. And the European
court of justice moved this. Not
only could they require Google
to do so, but that they would
start requiring Google to comply
with a variety of requests. From
people all over the European
union to simply have things
removed from search if they
simply didn't want them there
anymore. Google is actually not
a big fan of this ruling.
Because as you can imagine,
having to hire a whole bunch of
people to process all of these
requests is an enormous pain in
the ass. It may seem easier to
simply, grant them all, but then
you're engaged in this sort of
mass censorship, which we think
is extremely problematic. So one
of the things that we've been
working with Google and other
search engines on, is we've been
talking about -- talking with
them about what they can say
about the things that they have
removed from their search
engines in response to the right
to be forgotten. And we're going
to see if we can do some sort of
analysis about what is being
taken down, how it's being taken
down. And why it is being taken
down. Because we have a theory
that when you grant people the
right to censor content about
themselves, you're really only
creating a tool for the powerful
to groom their own image. But
this is not really an argument
that we can make without facts.
And the European court of
justice is actually struggling
very hard to keep the search
engines from being able to
publish anything about what
they're taking down, not just
how many things they're taking
down, but who they are taking
down -- them down in response to
and why. Because they feel that
this will simply create a
Streisand effect. Where you have
essentially done everything but
tell them, hey, here's where you
find the information. So there's
that sort of struggle between
these two forces right now. It
is my hope that the European
court of justice will come to
understand that this is simply
not a feasible ruling that it
doesn't really protect anyone.
But people who are already
powerful. And I hope that they
backtrack on it entirely. And
this is something that the EFF
has really been working on in
its international activism.
>> One of the important things
to remember about the right to
be forgotten ruling, is that the
Spanish gentleman at issue sued
both Google and the publisher of
the newspaper to get the article
itself taken down. And the
newspaper won. So the article
still exists but Google lost and
it was de-indexed. So it's not
as bad as it could be. >> I'm
not sure that I would
characterize it as not as bad as
it could be. I think one of the
-- >> It's aweful. >> One of the
lines from the ruling is
essentially we could not get the
paper to take this down because
that would clearly be illegal,
and so we're going after the
search engine because we think
it would be easier to implement
censorship in this way. And I
think creating a new centralized
form of censorship that is
entirely up to very large search
engines is a terrible idea.
>> Yes. >> Just in case my
thoughts were not clear on this
subject. >> One of the best
benefits of the ideal of
electronic freedom that I can
imagine as an American citizen
would be to be able to go online
on some government web site and
authenticate my
self-appropriately and see every
database the government has that
has my name in it. Not the
contents in particular, because
that would -- my understanding
would be more likely -- freedom
of information act where you can
request the contents of a
document once you know that the
document exists. But there are
situations where you don't even
know that the government is
tracking you, for instance, like
on the no fly lists. Which my
understanding is, you don't have
the right to even know that
you're on it until you get the
hand in your face at the airport
saying you can't get on the
plane. And more recently, the
secret lists that the veteran's
administration had about,
cooking the books on how soon
they were actually getting to
patients and stuff like that. Is
there anything like that being
tracked as a form of electronic
freedom and do you know of any
other secret lists that the
government has that the average,
you know, that are being tracked
as an issue that the average
conscientious citizen might not
have furloughed? >> I guess --
no. [Laughing] >> I could answer
a little bit about the list of
lists. Actually a while back, we
did a freedom of information act
request to get from the FBI at
least more information about
some of their databases. We were
looking at the investigative
data warehouse. Which was there
attempt to combine a bunch of
these lists together in one
place. But, it probably is going
to be very difficult to get the
full list of lists because they
will often in the freedom of
information act litigation say
that this information is secret.
And therefore cannot be
revealed. You can go and foray
yourself and try to get the
records that the government has
about you. But the most
interesting ones probably will
-- they will not give you or
even indicate that they have.
>> Yeah just expand a little bit
on that. And then Nate if you
want to talk -- I think when
we're talking about lists and
lists of lists, it depends on
who you're asking. The domestic
non-intelligent side, they at
least published, they being DHS
-- and this is not for criminal
investigations. We know about
the no fly list because they
have to publish the list they
keep when they're keeping a
system of records. They have to
put out this notice. The notice
does not go into precise detail.
It does tell you the data they
aim to collect, often retention
periods, who they're going to
share it with. And more
information like that. So kind
of the crazy list at the DHS we
know about. It's really just the
intelligence list. Because it
goes beyond the privacy act,
which mandates DHS do those
lists. It goes beyond the FOIA,
the freedom of information act
to request where they have a lot
of the -- the information we
found out right from Snowden and
from the leaks. So that's kind
of my answer. You have to
separate it out. We are going to
know probably a lot of these
civilian agency lists. We will
probably not know a lot about
the intelligence agency lists
unless courage becomes
contagious and there are more
lists of lists out there. Umm,
and the criminal investigatory
list. We may know some of them,
but there is always going to be
some hidden lists. And I think
that sums up the nuance of how
we approach these things and how
we approach what information the
government is collecting. >> My
question dove tails on what you
were just saying. Given what is
apparently an increasing trend
of aggressively prosecuting
federal leakers is the process
of protecting federal whistle
blowers broken, can it be fixed
and what are the implications
for all of our -- for the next
potential Snowden. >> It is
totally broken. >> It is totally
broken. >> Agreed. >> And it's
broken in particular -- I'll
answer what I can and you guys
can jump in. It is particularly
broken on the intelligence side.
You know, we have seen all of
the leakers, to be honest with
you Rick, Thomas Drake. You
can't go -- you are forced to go
up through a system that at
least from the history and the
evidence we have, is intended to
and does neglect warnings from
lower individuals. People have
warned their managers. You know,
we have Thomas Drake saying and
Snowden saying we warned these
manager and what happens is they
don't listen. That is a huge
problem. Then on the other side
of that, you have the
congressional intelligence
committees, who are supposed to
be over seeing these things and
who are supposed to be insuring
that whistle blowers and leakers
can go to them. But again, we
see that not happening and that
doesn't happen because the
system is broken. There are few,
if any, protections. I believe
there are even no protections.
>> There are protections for
whistle blowers on the books.
They're just not strong enough.
That they are basically designed
to allow people to speak to the
government inspector general
about problems that they are
seeing or to a make a complaint
to the government. And sometimes
there's a concern that those
complaints will not be acted
upon and so sometimes the
whistle blowers are not
satisfied with internally
whistle blowing. There is a
really great site,
whistleblowers.org that actually
discusses what protections are
out there. So there are some,
but it's just not enough to give
a real assurance to somebody
that wants to blow the whistle
that they will be able to do so
both with protections and
effectively. >> Unfortunately, a
lot of the protections to
whistle blowers apply only to
federal government employees and
do not extend to contractors.
Snowden obviously was a
contractor. Not a federal
government employee. So a lot of
the whistle blower protections
that are on the books for
employees didn't even apply to
him. >> And last of all, if you
think things look grim for
whistle blowing and reporting on
whistle blowing in the United
States, try Australia, our
partner in the five Is which is
currently considering
legislation that would
essentially make it illegal to
report on documents which have
come to light on the subject of
national security in Australia
if they are made public by
leakers. And that's an attack
not just on leakers but on
journalism itself. >> Is there
anything we can do to fix it?
>> Certainly there are things to
try. One of the things is, there
is one on -- the journalism
front here in the United States,
there's a really good case
called Bartnickey which is
addressing a circumstance in
which a radio station got some
information that was unlawfully
obtained. They published it on
the radio, peole went after them
and that -- for publishing that
and went up to the Supreme Court
and the Supreme Court said
because that information came to
them through no fault of their
own, they had a first amendment
right to put that news out
there. So we haven't seen a lot
of cases in which after the
information has been received by
a -- newspapers or reporters
where they brought cases against
the newspapers and reporters. So
that's been helpful. And then
for some of the suggestions that
have been made, the espionage
act could be used against
whistle blowers. I think that if
that actually was brought before
a court, it would be a hard case
for the government to win. The
threat of it out there may
discourage people. But this is a
1918 law that was passed during
World War I. It's fairly a
draconian. And it hasn't really
been used. But it's threat is
there. I'm hopeful if it ever
does get through, they'll pull
the trigger on that. And that
ourselves or someone else whose
fighting on that case, can
establish that that is above the
law and take that threat away.
>> Thank you. >> The other -- so
there's another side to this of
course which is there are
technical protection measures
that whistle blowers can use to
protect themselves. The one that
I'm going to plug is secure
drop. Secure drop is maintained
by the freedom of the press
foundation which is a friend and
client of the Electronic
Frontier Foundation. And allows
what we think is probably a
secure way for whistle blowers
to talk to journalists in a way
that they will not be able to be
identify later. So yay, secure
drop. >> So I actually work on
secure drop and have since the
last major re-release of it. So
secure drop is based on a Tor
Browser window currently. So all
the caveats of browser attack
surface, all the caveats of
attacks against Tor -- services
and so forth, apply to secure
drop. So make of that what you
will. But there are people who
are, there are more people now
thinking about how to protect
whistle blowers internalists
because they realize this is a
really important problem. We
heard of this thing called
invisible.IM that some people
just came up with. So yeah,
there is more technology out
there. But, you know, like given
an adversary like the NSA, you
have to be really careful about
the claims you make about
security. >> You mentioned
earlier about community wi-fi.
My question in regards to that
is how does community wi-fi and
municipal fiber affect net
neutrality. And how can one like
myself combat the vast amounts
of misinformation surrounding
those subjects. >> Little hard
for me to hear you. You're
asking about municipal wi-fi.
>> Yeah community wi-fi and
municipal fiber and how do they
effect net neutrality and what
can I do to combat the
misinformation or any of us do?
>> So on municipal wi-fi, we
have an open wireless project
that we are promoting. Part of
it is actually, here we have
recently released some software
for router based on open WRT.
We're trying to make it both
more secure and also have it
easier to have a segregated
guest network, so people could
open their wireless and help --
basically be a good neighbor and
allow people to get on the
internet through their
connection while not
compromising ourselves. Another
aspect of this is -- in order --
municipalities are either making
unity wi-fi where they're
harboring free wi-fi for all the
citizens of their community, or
in some cases they'll have
municipal fiber which they will
make available to people who
want to use it. So it's like,
let a thousand flowers bloom
using this municipal wi-fi. And
this means that people will have
alternative ways of getting on
to the internet where they can
just go through their city or
through a neighbor who's running
open wireless. Then this can
help bring them out -- you don't
have to go through a major
provider who have been talking a
lot about being un-neutral and
throttling different types of --
or making a fast lane depending
on how you look at it for
various types of access to web
sites. So by providing an
alternative path for people to
get on the web, that maybe
helpful in making sure that
folks can get to the stuff they
want to see without having to go
through a major ISP. >> Thanks.
>> I know we briefly talked
about gag orders, I was curious
to get your opinion on warrent
Canaries. That being a canary
that dies in the mine to say
that it's now unsafe to be
there. Along the lines of, you
know, Google or someone hosting
a page that they update manually
every week or so saying no we
haven't received a warrant or a
gag order. And then you know,
can the government actually tell
them to not take this down and
to lie to -- with hold this gag
order. >> So warrant canaries
are fascinating. And I actually
wrote a FAQ about warrant
canaries so you can look at that
on our blog for a really deep
drill down. Sort of go over
briefly, that this has not been
litigated, we don't have a court
that has said one way or the
other about how it would work
with warrant canaries -- and you
were exactly right about what
the issues and things
--compelled speech. Courts have
dealt with compelled speech
before. And in a few instances,
you can compel someone to speak,
like warning labels are a form
of compelled speech. So that's
why they, the cigarette
companies don't want to have
warnings on their packs. But
nevertheless, they're compelled
to do so. Most compelled speech
circumstances have been in
commercial speech. And a warrant
canary would be a circumstance
where it is put there for
political reasons. And by and
large when it is compelled
political speech, courts have
not been friendly to us. I think
there's some pretty good
argument that the government
shouldn't be able to compel you
to lie. Never the less, these
haven't been tested. And one of
the things that we'll see if one
of these cases come up, please
do get in touch with us. Because
we'll be very interested in that
type of case. Ideally it would
be a circumstance in which the
canary, the event will not occur
for some time so that we can
have a full briefing schedule
with the court. And the court
can look at it in a calm and
measured manner which is sort of
-- courts if they're going to do
something bold and radical, they
need to do it in a calm and
measured way. So if you know
this is going to go live
tomorrow and the government is
saying there'll be blood on your
hands, we have a giant emergency
here, most likely the court is
going to say okay, I'm not -- I
don't understand this well
enough to do something bold and
to disagree with the government
who's telling me the world will
end. But if we're able to go
through it and explain these --
write a good brief that explains
the compelled speech law and how
it applies here, we're hopful
for the best. >> Hi, thank you
for your work first of all. My
question is regarding the topic
of privacy and identities. And I
wanted to get -- >> Privacy and?
>> Identity, online identities.
>> Online events. >> Identities.
Just want to get your opinion on
government programs that deal
with these issues such as the
national strategy for trust
identities in cyber space nstic?
>> Can you repeat the last half
of the question? >> Which -- is
this better? >> Yes. Much
better. >> Sorry. First time on
a mic. Your opinion on programs
that deal with trusted
identities in cyber space such
as nstic, which I just use the
acronym. >> It suggests what?
>> nstic national strategy for
trusted identities in cyber
space. I just wanted to get your
opinion on programs like that.
>> I know that some of my
colleagues have been looking
into that. But I don't know if
anyone is on this panel. Lee was
looking into that. >> Lee Chin
will be able to answer your
question another time. >> He's
really great. So he's probably
doing wonderful things about it,
but I just don't happen to know
what they are. >> Hi, so, it's
been an interesting year already
for supreme court cases. You've
already talked about a couple of
them. There was also the one
having to do with retransmission
of over the air television
broadcasts. >> Aereo. >> Aereo,
yeah. >> Yeah, I was wondering
if you could comment on that and
if you could comment on any
upcoming Supreme Court cases
that you're involved with or
tracking. >> I'll answer the
Aereo question. So Aereo, as
many of you may know was a
company that was selling a
service where you could
basically have an antenna --
individual antenna, so they have
thousands of these dimed sized
antenna. Each customer would
have one. It would get broadcast
from initially New York and
eventually some other areas. And
for residents of those areas,
they could watch over the
internet, a stream that was
generated from that antenna. And
we looked at that case, and
looked at the law, and it really
seemed like that was a
circumstance in which they were
not doing a public performance
of the copyright act. They were
doing something that was
basically an extended antenna,
it was an innovative way of
doing something. That was not
prohibited by the copyright act
under the language of the act as
drafted. And so we wrote an
Amicus brief in that case and
tried to explain to the court
that some people were saying
basically, this is taking
advantage of a loophole, this is
not what we want to have here
and then it's not the court's
place to make these sorts of
decisions. So in order to
preserve innovation, people have
to innovate within the law that
exists. As I look at the law
that exists, they find that
there is an area where the
copyright act is not prohibiting
it they should be able to do
that unless congress comes in
and changes the law to make
those changes. But nevertheless,
unfortunately, the Supreme Court
that did come out against
Aereo's business model, they
said they were kind of more or
less like a cable company and so
therefore they should be treated
like a cable company and well,
Aereo ended up losing on that
argument. >> Do you think that
has any other implications for
other companies outside of that
decision? >> So the court in
writing this decision took some
pains to say we are not doing
anything that's going to be bad
for the cloud. They were very
worried about the effect of this
case on the cloud. The word
cloud came up a lot. In our
argument there. And so I hope
that when other judges are
looking at this decision and
they have the content industry
saying this decision means that
something else that is
innovative is also bad. That
those courts will look at that
language that limiting language
and say okay, we should limit
this really to these specific
facts. But certainly the
reporting industry is going to
try and expand it as best they
can. And so, we're going to try
to limit it as best we can.
>> Thank you very much. >> If
you want a little piece of legal
decree, our colleague Parker
Higgens did a cut of all of the
uses of the word cloud in that
oral argument. And he put it on
sound cloud. So if you Google
Parker Higgens supreme court
cloud, it's masterful. >> Have
you or any of your associates
suffered any of the theoretical
consequences of your
affiliations be it increased
surveillance, selective
prosecution or anything that
would be considered heat. And if
not, do you at least feel like
you're walking on egg shells.
Harvey Silverglate's book talks
about the average American
breaking three federal laws a
day. Umm, I guess that wouldn't
really be an option for you guys
I would think. And also, I'm not
limiting the scope to just
governmental type heat, but any
organizations that would
consider you adversarial? >> So
-- to add to this, I feel like
we are within three hops of
people that they're interested
in. So under the terms of the
program that probably means they
are looking at our phone records
and such. But we're all under
surveillance under the program.
Whether it has been directed
heat. I don't think any of us
have been selectively
prosecuted. And you know, I
would hope that even if they are
looking deeply at us, that's --
I would think that if they
actually decided to do something
discriminatory, that they
realize that'd be a bit of news
and that they wouldn't want to
create martyrs. But I guess
we'll find out if they do.
>> For the U.S. government
detaining employees of the
electronic frontier foundation
is incredibly media pathic. That
provides us with a tiny bit of
protection. My threat model on
the other hand, because I do
international work and I spend a
lot of time working with
journalists and activists who
are under threat in other
countries, my threat model is
mostly non U.S. government. And
probably the funniest sort of
heat that I have ever seen come
my way was the time that the
Vietnamese government sent me
malware. [Laughing] >> I do all
of EFF's malware analysis
reports. [Laughing] >> Free
advertisement. >> So they
couldn't have sent it to a more
appropriate person. If it had
come to somewhere else, our
intake coordinator would have
just wound up sending it to me.
So I got together with Morgan
Marquis-Boire from citizen lab
and we wrote up the contents of
the malware, but what was
particularly interesting about
this malware, besides the fact
that it would not have worked on
my machine in the first place,
was the targeting. The malware
was made to look like an e-mail
from a gentleman at oxfam
offering me an invitation to a
conference in Asia. This showed
a tremendous understanding of
what interests activists. Which
is free conferences. [Laughing]
>> If they had really wanted me
to open the document, they
should have offered free flights
and hotels. [Laughing] >>
Business class travel would have
done it I think. >> Oh man, I
would have been owned. >> I
wanted to add to what Curt said
about canaries and say that the
courts are much more liberal
when it comes to restraining
action. >> Can you get closer to
the mic. >> Sorry, I was going
to add to what you were saying
about canaries. That the courts
tend to be much more liberal
about restraining action then
compelling it. So if the canary
is automated or already up, they
can restrain you from modifying
it much more willing to do that
than it would be to compel you
to continue to take a manual
action. But my question really
goes to what you said earlier
about infrared cameras peeking
inside home using heat
sensitivity. And it goes to
technology and the reasonable
expectation of privacy. And the
question is, does encryption
create a reasonable expectation
of privacy? Particularly
vis-a-vis Smith V Maryland?
>> So talking about Smith V
Maryland. For those who are not
familiar with it. That is the
origin case of the third party
doctrine this notion, that if
you put your information online
that you are no longer having an
expectation of privacy in it. So
it's open season on that
information which is one of the
things that we're trying to
undercut that doctorate and make
it make sense in a modern age.
On encryption, one of the areas
where this has come up has been
on forced decryption. There's a
little bit of a different
question. Because if your
encryption is good. Then the
question of whether you have a
reasonable expectation of
privacy isn't going to come up
so much as, can they get at it.
And they'll need to get a
password and the question is can
they require you to give up that
password? So it usually comes up
in a 5th amendment context.
>> Or a key. >> Or a key. >> So
umm, while you do have a fifth
amendment right, to not give up
your password. Sometimes this
could be undercut by the
inevitable disclosure doctrine.
So what this means is that if
they are able to convince the
court that that information
would have come up any way
because they know what's in
there, then they could require
you to decrypt it. They can't
tell you to give up your
password. They will require you
to decrypt the information,
which is the same. But if
decrypting the information would
show that this is your
information, it would be a
testimonial act, it would give
them new data that you actually
had control over this, then that
starts to be more strongly
protected by the fifth
amendment. There have only been
a handful of cases on this so
while we're going to continue to
work on those fights and push
against forced decryption. And
we really have not had one which
has put decryption or encryption
into, directly in the third
party doctrine. So we'll look
forward for when that case comes
up before the courts. >> I think
an important -- another
important point here though is
-- I would argue very strongly
and I have, that you have a
reasonable expectation of
privacy in your communications
even if they're not encrypted.
>> Absolutely the fact that's a
case that we were successful
with in the sixth circuit where
the court found that there was a
reasonable expectation of
privacy in e-mail, even if it
wasn't encrypted regardless of
whether it was encrypted and
required a warrant to get that
e-mail. And one of the things we
did with the who has your back
report, that they were talking
about earlier, is we asked all
these service providers, do they
insist upon a warrant before
they give up content. And you
can look at that report and see
where the gold stars are. We're
basically asking them to say
that they agreed with that six
circuit decision and would apply
it regardless of what circuit
they were in. >> I was concerned
that my question may have
actually just been pulled out
from under me by the previous
questioner. But it looks like it
veered in a different direction.
So, my question was, can you
speak to third party doctrine in
the context of data that is
encrypted before leaving your
system and being stored in
cloud. In other words, true
crypt file stored on drop box.
That sort of thing. Without
veering into the fifth amendment
side of it which I know is a
separate discussion. By doing
those two actions together, are
you automatically going to fall
under third party doctrine, even
though the data was encrypted
before it left your system? >> I
guess you echo a little bit of
what Nate was just saying. What
we've been pushing for is to
require warrants before you get
that information regardless of
whether it's encrypted. That
this notion that you've given up
your privacy rights by taking
advantage of online services
where you're storing your
information elsewhere is an
antiquated and out dated notion.
You should be able to take full
advantage of modern technologies
without giving up your civil
liberties. So. [Applause] >> Now
you can add to that by giving
yourself some technical
protection. By using encryption
both in the communication and
storing it there. And this can
be helpful to add an extra layer
of technical protection against
that principle. And to -- what
gives me a lot of hope on this
front is the Riley decision. The
Riley decision we talked about
earlier, this was the cell phone
decision. And one of the things
they talked about was why you
needed a warrant there was in
part because if you got onto
somebody's phone you might be
able to access information they
held elsewhere. And if you think
about that, if they believed
that the third party doctrine
made all of that pointless, you
didn't a warrant, once you put
it on the server, it doesn't
matter there's no need to say
that in the opinion. It's
suggested that when they were
looking at the phone, looking at
the capabilities of the phone to
be able to get that information
off of a drop box or wherever,
that this was something that
brought a warrant to their mind.
So hopefully we will get a good
case on this. More good cases to
establish that a warrant is
needed for any of this
information whether it's
encrypted or not. But sure, you
might as well also add that
extra layer of protection by
putting encryption on any
materials your storing
elsewhere. >> Thanks for
everything. >> The files that
allowed for the 3D printing of
firearms were taken down, can
you discuss the law around that.
>> The question was about the 3D
printer and the firearms. I
don't know if anybody on this
panel has worked on that. >>
That case is in progress. That's
the best answer I can give. >>
I'm curious about if in your
international work you've run
into situations where a foreign
government is using the U.S.
court to suppress free speech
from bloggers and online
newspapers from dissidents from
their government. There's a
recent pattern recently, the
Haitian government has been
using defamation laws in the
U.S. to silence, by opening
multiple lawsuits against
bloggers and online newspapers.
I'm wondering if you've
encountered that strategy from
other governments or -- and is
that something that you guys
would be interested in looking
into? >> Well it turns out that
there's an incredible variety of
tactics that governments use to
silence speech all over the
world. Especially speech which
is taking part on platforms that
they do not directly control. So
third party platforms like
Facebook and Twitter and Tumbler
and Blogger are tremendously
dangerous to governments that
want to maintain strict control
over their media. And frequently
these platforms become one place
where you can get independent
media in certain countries.
Probably the best example of
that that I can think of off the
top of my head is Ethiopia.
Because I spent a lot of time
working with Ethiopian
activists. We've seen a couple
of different tactics for
shutting down speech. Probably
the most common one that
involves the U.S. law is to
simply file DMCA takedowns
against speech the government
doesn't like. And this is a very
common abuse of the DMCA. This
is sort of the basis of one of
our main protests against the
DMCA. Because the way the DMCA
works is that a person who is
complaining can actually get
content taken down merely by
alleging that the content is
theirs. And that it is an abuse
of their copyright. And it is up
to the person who has put the
content up in the first place to
file a counter notice if they
want the content to be put back
up. And in doing so, they both
have to reveal information about
themselves and also open
themselves up to the possibility
of a lawsuit. And so often they
are -- even if they know they
can do this, they're scared to
do so. Sometimes the content is
also time sensitive. So by the
time they have filed the counter
notice and put the content back
up, it's already too late. We've
seen this approach. We have also
seen the abuses of the abuse
reporting system. For example, I
worked with activists at Viet
Tan which is sort of
prodemocracy opposition group
mostly located in Vietnam that
was having a bunch of their
Facebook sites taken down. So
many members of the Viet Tan
were losing access to their
Facebook accounts. And this is
where they were doing most of
their activism. And it turned
out that supporters of the
Vietnamese government had
figured out that one way you can
shut down somebody's Facebook
account very quickly is simply
by reporting that the user is
underage. This is another abuse
of the abuse system rather than
abuse of the court system. And
one of the things that EFF finds
extremely worrying is that these
third party platforms like
Facebook and Tumbler and Twitter
have become sort of the
semipublic comments. And umm,
often you don't have to go
through the courts anymore and
you don't have to go through any
kind of legal rig ma role if you
want to suppress speech. All you
need to do is gain the system
that these platforms put up in
order to decide what content
stays up and what stays down.
And in order to sort of fight
this, EFF has just received a
grant from the night foundation
to run a site that we're calling
onlinesensorship.org. I think
the first version of it is
already up. It's a place where
people can report things that
have been taken down from -- on
these sites usually for TOS
violations and this gives us
some insight into how these
services are taking content down
and whether or not there is bias
in the kind of content their
taking down and whether or not
there are campaigns to get
certain kinds of content taken
down. Which is something that we
really don't know anything about
right now. >> Thank you. >> We
only have a couple minutes left
for questions. Only about two
minutes left for questions.
>> Two minutes? We'll take these
last two questions. >> Jump into
it. As we use technology more in
our civilization and I assume
technology related questions
like the DMCA and -- maybe a
keylogger in Divorce or
something, those are all
penetrating the courts across
the country and just boring non-
precedence setting cases. And I
wondered if you guys had any
insight into how much or how
often these technology issues
are coming up just in random
cases that don't make the news
and if you think our courts and
the random lawyers across the
country are up to it. What's the
situation with all that? >> We
get a little bit of insight into
that because our intake system
receives a lot of requests where
they may not be precedence
setting that we end up referring
them to other people. But at
least it gives us a sense of
what's out there, we try to
refer people to qualified
council so they can fight those
issues. There's probably a lot
more people out there who don't
know about the EFF who might be
in the situation that don't know
to contact us. So, if you hear
about people who are in a
situation where they should
contact us. Pass down the good
word. But yeah, I think the
technology is coming into many
many cases. A number of years
ago it was -- it would go to the
courts for the subpoena to try
to identify an online speaker.
And we were called to a lot of
litigation around that to try to
establish what the test is for
revealing the identity of an
online speaker. Now we will
occasionally get involved in
those cases where it's going to
be a chance to approve that test
or find that test in a new
jurisdiction. But in many many
cases all across the country,
people are using that and
applying those tests to either
identify or not identify
somebody. >> Cool, alright, last
question. >> So if people want
to use software, they have to
click something that says yes I
have read this document and I
have agree to the all the terms
so although people technically
have agreed to it, they probably
aren't aware that every single
thing they type into the address
bar of chrome is going back to
Google and they probably haven't
begun to think about how nest is
going to affect what Google now
knows about them. You guys have
the who has your back report for
encryption. Are any plans to put
up a similar report for who
isn't asking you to give out
copious amounts of your privacy
or calling out the ones who do?
>> That's a good question. We
don't have any plans to do that
right now. We are pretty slammed
bandwidth wise. But it's great.
You should do it. [Laughing]
[Applause] >> Alright, thanks.
>> Thank you. Thank you all for
coming and thank you so much.
The support from this community
has always been very important
to us, we love you all. It's so
great to be here once again to
answer your questions. So thank
you guys. [Applause]