>> I am Chris Littlebury, and
this is all about automating
home defense. A little about me,
I am a senior penetration tester
with knowledge information
group. We are hiring, if you
have skills, let us know, and I
like building stuff. Couple of
pictures there, it's an Xbox
Live Controller that ummm did a
randomization thing on it, so
you can do rapid fire and it
won't be detected on Xbox
Live cause it had a randomizing
cadence to it, yea it's
cheating, I used it once and it
just sat on the shelf, but  ‑ ‑
one of my first really your own
‑ ‑ and the other picture is
swapping out the 5th gear on my
car to get better mileage,
anything I can do with my hands,
on stuff, so  ‑ ‑ >> A quick
disclaimer. During this talk,
providing ideas, codes that
worked for me, things that
haven't worked, pretty much just
a trial and error thing,
afterwards, definitely open to
questions, suggestions. I like
to hear what other folks have to
say. >> I am not getting paid to
endorse anything, there's a
bunch of products I will be
talking about, they work well,
some have strength and
weaknesses, we will go over
that. Nobody is paying me to be
here. And I definitely not
promising an end to burglaries
especially if you live in
high‑risk areas, sorry you're
screwed ‑ ‑ but you can try to
stack the odds in your favor.
Definitely not advocating
setting up booby traps in your
house. This is a big federal no‑
no. A lot of people approached
me, yeah, I want to build a
moat and have a spike pit ‑ ‑
and shit come flying down with
spikes when you open the door
when I am home alone  ‑ ‑ you
will go to prison. So please  ‑
‑ I am not advocating that.
Please don't do it. Don't do
anything that can result in
hurting other people or property
damage. It's something  ‑ ‑
doing something to somebody's
car that's on your property or
something, just use your head,
don't break shit. >> Lastly, a
live example from my place,
stuff I have done, please don't
come and test my home, again, I
would love to talk with folks
afterwards and have you thought
about this and wow  ‑ ‑ I
haven't thought about this,
thank you for  ‑ ‑ let's open up
a cool discussion about it
instead of showing up at my
place at 1:00 in the morning,
standing over my bed freaking me
out. Which somebody of yall
deviant bastards would do such a
thing. >> So, store starts out
once upon a time in South Texas.
I was living in San Antonio,
below the poverty line and they
like to have a great tourism,
Riverwalk, nice place to visit,
family affair and everything,
and  ‑ ‑ completely talking
trash. Anybody here from San
Antonio? >> Thank you. Yes. So
anybody else from San Antonio? I
will talk shit so I apologize, I
spent 10 years there, I feel
adequately qualified to do so.
The crime map in San Antonio is
just terrible. Their local
pastimes are DUIs and home
invasions, just what they are
known for. It's bad. So they
ranked number 3, I forget what
year this was, but they were
like the third least safe city
in America. So  ‑ ‑ at the time
I had this little Honda Civic,
and again  ‑ ‑ anybody have a
Honda Civic, or had a Honda
Civic  ‑ ‑ keep your hands up if
it was stolen. You are my
people. Okay. At the time it was
the most‑ stolen car in America
and I happened to have it. Air
conditioning, good mileage,
worth about $1500, that's all I
needed, right? I came out one
morning and the doors were
unlocked, people had gone
through my stuff but the car was
still there and I was like yeah,
this sucks, I would like to be
able to do something. I should
be able to out‑smart them. I
like to soldering stuff  ‑ ‑ I
should be able to out‑smart
them. I had an idea. >> They
have a main fuel relay up near
the kick panel. You unbolt it,
it's like a 12-pin connector  ‑
‑ you take this with you and the
car completely is immobilized.
Sure, there's a chance somebody
breaking in like oh gee, I
happen to have one of those and
I will look there, but I roll
the dice. Pretty safe bet. >> I
also got cheap alarms that pages
you, so I hooked it up without
sirens, lights, anything, I
removed the relays in it to
trigger the lights and turn
signals, so I removed
everything. All it does is page
you. >> It's a car, sure, but my
car, I wanted to drive it to
work. I kept it that way three
months and sure enough, it
worked. Early one morning the
alarm goes off and I go running
down stairs and there's two
respectable gentleman going to
work on my steering column. I
persuade them to exit the
vehicle, one of them runs, the
other tries to establish a kind
dialogue with me. I was able to,
through power of persuasion,
maybe you should lay down on the
ground and wait until the cops
come. I was effective in doing
so, they came out, arrested him
and  ‑ ‑ I was like you know
what? I think it's time to move
away from the shithole, because
‑ ‑ other neighbors, tons of
anecdotal evidence that it was
just a bad place. Case in point,
I found this on Reddit a year or
so ago, I said that looks like a
lot my old apartment complex and
sure as shit, it was my old
apartment complex. So somebody
got upset, set their ex's car on
fire, burned down a few other
things, it was terrible. So I
moved up to a nicer area.
Actually this picture is one of
the three times in the history
of mankind it snowed in San
Antonio and I mean it just
dusted a tiny bit, people were
trying to sled on it. >> Anyway,
it was a nicer place. I moved up
to the third floor, tried to get
as high off the ground as
possible, okay, that  ‑ ‑ you
make it more difficult to get
into, lock exterior doors, even
sliding doors, third floor on
the balcony, that kind of thing,
stacking the odds in your favor.
You won't keep everybody out
but, everywhere I looked, there
were all these tips from cops,
and the number one thing that
kept popping up was "make your
home look occupied." If people
come by, knock on your door,
make it look like somebody is
home. Lights on timers, leave
TVs on, just stuff that makes it
look occupied. You see the other
stuff, lock your doors, basic
stuff. >> That got me thinking.
Everybody has seen the movie
Home Alone, right? Yeah. So I
steal off of that during this
talk a little bit, so  ‑‑ I
thought okay, I work a weird
schedule, at night, ‑‑ during
the day sometimes, all over the
place, but I wanted something
that would make the place look
normal all the time. At the time
the cheapest automation stuff
was the Extent hardware. I am
waiting to hear groans. Anybody
done that before? It's terrible,
yeah. It's been around since the
late 70s, and really cheap
hardware, works off of sending
data over your home power line.
What it does, included on 120‑
hertz carrier, transmits during
the zero crossing, and it sucks
so much that it sends the
command three times every time
it  ‑ ‑ it knows it's not
reliable, but if you are in a
small apartment complex or older
house where the wiring is not
that complex, it worked. >> They
had this God‑awful GUI you can
program, macros, certain things,
none of it worked really well
but some of the timers had a
cool feature, security feature
you can time, say, you want
everything to turn on at 5:00,
every day. They had a security
feature where it would turn on
anywhere between like 4:50 and
‑‑ and it would be raining every
day. It's a cheapy company, the
tech is terrible, but it's doing
what I want it to do. So
eventually I moved to a house.
Excuse me. >> I moved to a
house, started doing it with
exterior lighting  ‑ ‑ So I had
lights would come on at
different times, some would use
photovoltaic centers, some using
the Extend, but it wasn't
anything special, but ‑‑ is this
wooden? So knock on wood, I
never had issues. It seemed to
be occupied all the time. The
neighbors got broken into but
mine  ‑ ‑ I didn't have issues.
>> But, eventually, I moved
away. So I moved back to
Colorado after a 10‑ year
hiatus, crime is a lot better
there, I will do it right this
time. So, I will do it right. >>
Of course I have to advocate, do
not set up booby traps in your
house. It would be cool as shit,
but, what are they going to do?
My wish list was I wanted
efficient lighting. Most of the
stuff out there for doing wall
switch and lighting and things
are all incandescents, 60, 80,
100 watt bolts per can, the
equivalent of a microwave or
something. That just wasn't
cool. I wanted efficient
lighting, granular control over
it, do individual zones, turn
things on and off whenever I
choose, have some sort of
centralized way to control it  ‑
‑ adaptive timing, not always
the same schedule, randomization
and things. Again, I wanted it
to look like it was lived in as
much as possible. Do some
geofencing, anybody done the
if-then stuff? No? Okay. >>
There's some if‑then geo
fencing, I have read it's a 20%
success rate. You establish a
geo fence on your phone and
leave, once you leave certain
actions happen. Arms your
security system or turns lights
off, people leave their house
and lights are just on until
10:00 at night. >> I wanted to
do my own that I had control
over and, yes. I wanted to be
able to do defenses against
wireless home automation
attacks. Everybody all around
for last year's DEF CON? The Z
wave enabled door locks are
encrypted. Instead of breaking
the encryption you just did a
replay attack  ‑ ‑ replay the
exact same thing over RF and the
door was like "welcome home,
buddy." Everybody was just ‑ ‑
holy shit. Funny anecdotes, a
week after that I had a dude
come to my door, trying to sell
that, Comcast, other places,
building out home security
system and have that sort of
thing where it's on your smart
phone, gee, I can look at
cameras, know when my kid's
coming home ‑ ‑ I can spy on my
baby at night with infrared
cameras, straight up Skynet
shit, but they love it. I can
open my garage, unlock my front
door. That seemed like a
terrible thing to me. I wanted
to be able to defend it. >> Not
only that, if somebody really
wants to get in it's just smash
and grab. If you have a great
alarm system you have a big
giant ADP sign, prominently
displayed, it's like please,
please, don't screw with this
house. If they really want to,
they will do if anyway. I am
sure everybody in the room has
friends that during the day
people kick in the front door,
alarm goes off, they grab stuff
and take off. That's how it is.
I wanted to be able to do
something that would immediately
react to that and try to
mitigate what they can carry. If
they kick in the door, alarm
goes off, they are freaking out
and something that they have
never seen before happens inside
the house that might be like,
you know what maybe we should
GTF out. >> That was my wish
list. One of the first things I
did was Wi‑Fi enable lightbulbs
‑ ‑ did anybody get in on the
LiFX kickstarter? No? Awesome.
So they did, started a while
back, took a while to ship the
bulbs, had a bunch of regulator
‑ ‑ regulation things to do, but
in the grand scheme of things
their Wi‑ Fi enabled LED bulbs,
big claim to fame is they will
do 1000 lumens ‑ ‑ they are
bright as shit. They will always
do full color, their full color
representation is fantastic if
you are into that, the picture
with the blue is my living room,
two of them in the ceiling,
it's, yeah, cool. Side note to
that, I will talk about later,
if the alarm goes off one thing
it can do is the whole house can
start flashing red. So  ‑ ‑
[laughter] upstairs, down
stairs, entry way, chandelier,
everything, the whole damn house
will just light straight out of
aliens sort of thing.
Everything  ‑ ‑ if I can rig up
a fog machine too  ‑ ‑ leave her
alone, you bitch. So they are
great bulbs, at full power draw
17 watts, fits into their  ‑ ‑
i'm not drawing a ton of power.
And you can dim them down, do it
all through software. They
recently released an API, so any
Ruby fans out here? Good. Good.
>> No. Anybody from Python? You
are my people. All right. And I
will get to that with the open
source, but several different
libraries to work with. The
official API is in Ruby, not
that bad to work with, you can
port over to python, but yeah.
The down side to these bulbs is
they are large. They have some
heft to them. You can't put them
in normal fixtures that sit
sideways. They will start
sagging down when they come in
contact with the globe  ‑ ‑ look
terrible and heat up a bit. You
can't enclose them. >> The other
option is the Philips Hues ‑ ‑
really easy to work with, great
API, has python, so  ‑ ‑ python
people. Even lower power
consumption 8.5 watts at full
brightness, a little cheaper.
Their power output is not the
same. You put three in a
fixture, it will be like three
60‑ watt light bulbs, but it's a
good option. The color
representation isn't as good,
but if you are looking at
lighting up a side room, dining
room, if you want to be able to
control that remotely, still
have the thing flash red, freak
the hell out of people, it's a
fantastic choice. >> Couple
pictures. Fourth of July at my
place, the camera didn't do it
justice. The purple are actually
blue and red ones are red, that
was LiFx and Hue bulbs. My
living room just, messing around
and  ‑ ‑ during my perfect  ‑ ‑
>> Audience question/comment.
[Laughter] >> We're hiring. >>
So yeah. Other devices out
there, WeMo devices, they had
vulnerabilities last year that
are really not good. Fair
enough? They had them come out
last year where there was a
vulnerability where if they
rapidly cycled them there's a
hack where you can recycle, hook
up for a load, like motor or
something like that, initially a
really large amperage and then
settles down. >> Are we
distracting you? >> No just
concerning me ‑ >> To our first
time speaker ‑ [applause] >>
Thank you. >> We have been doing
this four days. Three talks,
every hour, I have lost track.
>> I really want to get me one
of those little rascals. So, the
WeMo devices, you can rapidly
cycle and depending on where the
device is hooked up, they can
catch fire and burn the place
down. It's bad. So they have
since pushed out a firmware
update for them, but still not
that secure  ‑ ‑ what I have
read, lock down IPv6 on the
routers, don't have anything
else and just lock down
everything you have. With that
said, they are extremely useful
for if you have exterior
lighting where you have CFL
bulbs, like all around your
house, hook up one of these,
talking about 20 watts worth of
draw all night, then you can
switch it with one of these
switches. The problem being they
have timers built in, their own
app and own timers built in,
both of which completely suck.
Their app is not reliable and
their timers, well they work,
sometimes, if you have, like say
your external lights you want to
turn on at 8:00 at night and
keep them on until 6:00 in the
morning, when it comes up on
midnight they will shut off a
few seconds, midnight five
seconds later they will come
back on and there's no rhyme or
reason for it so if somebody is
casing your house or whatever,
it's a pretty good indicator  ‑‑
and again, yes, terrible
security. There's a link to that
exploit on there too  ‑ ‑ and
the slides will be available and
everything. >> So, creating a
home defense server, available
24/7, low power consumption,
hook up to an UPS, integrate
with sensors, be able to pull
your own sensor network, and
integrate with your existing
home security system. It would
be more of a supplement. Can you
build one on your own, and have
it respond, do stuff, but I am
of the mindset I like someone
monitoring. If they call the
cops, the cops come out. Whereas
if I see something in a text
message, hi, I am Chris, I built
this Rube Goldberg system at my
house, can you go check it out.
Sir, this is 911, don't ever
call back. If it supplements
your home security system you at
least have a little bit of
clout. >> Couple of slides
integrated in, but the raspberry
pi is a good choice. And again,
how many people mess with
raspberry pi? they're fantastic,
they're wonderful. >> I had a
little experience with pis
before. I built a Wi‑Fi enabled
barbecue smoker just because,
shit, I didn't know if I could.
I got some meat probes, a probe
for a GE oven that I found, all
the other therma probes I could
find were worthless after 240
degrees. I found one good to
400, put a rail server on there
‑ ‑ what's that? Sorry, ADD. I
put a rail server on the front
end, I had rails experience at
the time and just didn't know
any better. Any rails coders
here? >> Good. But it worked and
it was one of those proof of
concepts where I could build not
only the sensor portion, but
have a front‑ end riding on the
same hardware, all self‑
contained, on wireless and do
fun stuff with it. >> So,
creating a home defense server,
anybody familiar with wiring in
just regular home systems where
you have a long line of sensors
and everything has to be  ‑ ‑
for it to be okay  ‑ ‑ yeah.
There's two different ways of
doing it. You can have a closed
loop or open, and either way
most of the newer ones you can
program them through  ‑ ‑ to do
either way. Stick the pi online
with that and put it in the mix
and put relay  ‑ ‑ the power you
want to wire in and have it
connected to its own network,
say you have your own PIR
sensor, or your own what‑ have‑
you. You can then send a signal
to that pi, it can trip it and
fire off the security system.
Another thing you can do, they
have a panic button, wireless
panic buttons, take one of those
apart and solder on, run
transistor over that, something
happens you hit that, when it
goes to the alarm company it
will go in as silent alarm
instead of oh a motion or door
alarm. Straight across. Silent
alarm, old Betsy fell down or
old Betsy is being robbed by
hoodlums, whatever. >> A lot of
ways to graft it in and I highly
recommend grafting it into the
alarm system. There are a lot of
different open source out there
for  ‑ ‑ Magic Monkey did the
original version  ‑ ‑ the big
giant LED bulbs, and great,
great tool, only thing is it
wouldn't do multiple bulbs, if
you want to flash your entire
down stairs red it would be one
bulb, one bulb, kind of sucked.
>> And then  ‑ ‑ sorry, he was
the job scripter on that and
Sharp did the LiFX Python which
was built off of that, later on,
LiFX came out with the official
API, written in Ruby, we have
all been over this. You can make
it work. It's a good API, I just
have this thing against, and
there is  ‑ ‑ I can't pronounce
this guy's name or project name,
but they have an API for the
WeMo devices and it works
fantastic. Code support and
command line support. It's great
stuff. You can control all these
things just from command line or
different scripts. So from there
I created a front‑end service
where I wanted something like
weights to control the stuff,
front end. You can do rails,
rails sucks. It's heavy. Python
has flask ‑‑ Ruby has Sinatra ‑‑
back end services for each of
the tech screen readers, their
own services and on their own
ports. So if one of them fails,
then just that service fails, so
I don't lose everything in my
house sort of thing. >> Also, I
wanted to have a database keep
track of it all ‑ I ended up put
up on separate pi, really light
weight, fast, and not that
complicated. I wasn't looking
for giant enterprise‑ level
stuff, just wanted something
quick. On a separate pi,
separate room. If you go that
route I highly recommend you put
external swap on, get a powered
USB hub, hard drive on it and
set up swab, even if you have a
great SD card, you look at the
log, just swapping out all the
time and all those read/writes,
are hell on those cards, so  ‑ ‑
finally creating a monitoring
service with alerts and one of
the services go down, be nice to
know about it. >> Again, all the
code we are talking about here
will be available on a GetHub
after the conference. I am going
to do a disclaimer right now
that my code is terrible. I am
not a developer. I am a pen
tester, so my code works, not
pretty, for the ones that are
professional Devs, like nice
polished code, it may be
offensive to you. So just ‑ ‑
but it works. >> Moving on. I
wanted to be able to determine
if I am walking into a room and
things happen. I want my place
to know if I am there or not.
Originally I wanted to do
Bluetooth, pair to my phone and
know if I am walking into a
room, it will see my phone,
okay, he's here, and then
whatever else happens, update it
in the database I am there,
certain other things. So I
played around with it, it was
kind of a pain in the ass. You
have to create a connection,
open the device after it's been
paired ‑ ‑ while being pulled,
you have to do the request for
the RS  ‑ ‑ the signal strength
identifier. You do that, pull
it, while being pulled say oh by
the way what's the signal
strength, come back with a
number and from there you say oh
the phone is within this amount
of distance. You put a couple of
those in different rooms and you
can determine where something is
but if you get to aggressive
with that it will break your
wireless interface on your
phone. Not just Bluetooth but
regular 802.11 as well. That was
a fun one to find out when I  ‑
‑ but it worked, for a bit. >>
From there I went to do it with
802.11, your phones will  ‑ ‑
beacon every 60 seconds if you
are not doing anything but as
soon as you turn them on, start
doing stuff your MAC address
will be all over the place. >>
There's a command line utility
where you can go through and
parse out what MAC is being seen
and what signal strength it is.
If you have neighbors and stuff
that you don't care about, I
will be lower signal strength
and you can grit that out. But
if you have a certain set you
want to keep track of,
significant other, kids,
whatever, a list of things that
it will look for. >> If you are
really curious about it, the
Tshark command on the very
bottom will bust out just way
more information than you will
ever want to know about wireless
packets and you can do all sorts
of magic with it. I did a python
way with scapy and it's ugly,
it's very, very ugly, but it
works and so what I have been
doing, I have a flat file of MAC
I want to keep track of. It
fires up, starts looking for
those, when it sees it, it
updates the database that okay,
it's been seen, what time it's
been seen and a separate process
goes through the database to
look at time stamps, outside of
certain time, okay, it hasn't
been seen in this amount of time
so I am not there, other rules
now apply. Lights will be
turning off, at pre‑determined
times, still random, that way it
knows if I am home so I am not
sitting watching TV and the
whole living room goes dark. >>
Again, proximity monitoring
looks for a  ‑ ‑ signal strength
actually, I just went over all
that. Adaptive scheduling. I
created a SmartCron system ‑ ‑
everybody familiar with weather
integral  ‑ ‑ they have a
fantastic API free for
developers. Every day at 1:00
my  ‑ ‑ will pull down the
source schedule for the day,
sunrise, sunset, that sort of
thing and from there block off
randomized times of, okay, I
want to turn off my outside
lights sometimes around sunrise,
turn them on somewhere around
sunset, bunch of other stuff. It
shifts every day, and things are
built in, cloud cover, UV index,
moves interior lights if  ‑ ‑
again  ‑ ‑ >> So, for the fun
stuff. Defenses against wireless
based attack. You saw this last
year. Does anybody go to the fox
hunting thing on Thursday?
Really early on Thursday, I went
to the Wrapping 7 party before
and was not able to get there.
No? So the fox hunting is RF
direction finding, really cool
stuff. The only way I can think
of to defend against these sort
of Z wave attacks, a replay
attack or somebody trying to jam
345 Meg sensor data  ‑ ‑ newer
alarm systems that use those,
should be able to determine if
somebody is transmitting on the
band and where from. Anybody
familiar with the Doppler
effect? >> For the ones that
aren't, ambulance goes by, high‑
pitched coming and regular pitch
as it goes by, lower pitch as
it  ‑ ‑ same with RF. You have
the signal, switch through it
fast enough you can get a good
idea of where it's coming from.
I have a setup that works
against 345 and 900 mess  ‑ ‑ so
if anything does key up, outside
of a certain parameter for where
it's located, I haven't actually
stepped past my front door but
anything outside my house will
pick up  ‑‑ it uses the Agrello
DF message format, whereas it's
signal quality, the system I use
called the picodopp  ‑‑ fixed at
7 for signal quality but I don't
care, I just want to know where
it is. The text there you see is
an actual output from a test I
was doing ‑ ‑ and the numbers
327, 316, 312, 319, those are
all numerical bearings off the
antenna array of where the
signal is coming from. I was
able to sit outside with one of
the sensors, one of the 345
sensors, and key it off, the
system says hey, there's
something coming from outside
and  ‑ ‑ you can pipe that into
a database as well, have that do
time stamps, if it's a bunch you
know somebody is jamming, it's
from outside, up know somebody
is trying to do a Z wave attack.
The possibilities are endless.
If you put two together,
correlate the two and have real‑
time triangulation. It's fun. >>
Lastly, again, a lot of folks
want to just kick in the front
door. Alarm goes off, they don't
care. They want to steal things.
The best thing you can do is try
to make it an inhospitable
environment for them. They want
to be quiet, anonymous, just get
in and out and nothing happen,
right? So I talked about earlier
on the whole house will flash
red, that's a good way to do it,
especially if it's at night, the
whole suburban house is
horrible, you can flash exterior
lights as well. Do something
that is going to be
electronically activated and do
something in a safe way. Again,
safe way, nobody wants to be
sued. One thing you can do is
hook up a 12-volt solenoid or  ‑
‑ for door lock, people who  ‑ ‑
car handles, these real high‑
powered solenoids you can
push/pull with. Have it set up
somewhere to knock over
something. Alarm goes off,
people come in, all of a sudden
they  ‑ ‑ something upstairs.
What the hell was that? It will
buy you a few seconds, and don't
create anything that can do
harm. >> With that said, so this
is purely theoretical. I don't
want anybody to ever do anything
like this, especially with
doors  ‑ ‑ everybody knows,
don't do this. Don't build your
own fireworks either. You can go
buy firecrackers, around the
fourth of July they are very
cheap. Do not break these open
or combine them into something,
again, this is Chris Littlebury
at DEF CON 2014 saying do not
create your own fireworks. >> So
they make these things for model
rockets, I have a good friend,
figuring out a way to light
these, dude, they are rocket
igniters. I said dude, tell me
more about this. This is the
middle thing with the black  ‑ ‑
wires that come in, really thin
wire at the end and spark plug
material on top of it. What
happens, you put power in,
shorts out, ignites the spark
plug and it creates fire. >> If
you have it taped up to a bunch
of firecrackers like that, it
will go boom. For the sake of
argument, if I were going to do
something like this I would do
them one‑ on‑ one, separate
channel for each one, fire one
off individually, it would be
like a bang, bang bang, bang,
not something that sounds like
the kid from home alone put
something in the the thing and
lit it all on fire have it sound
something realistic. But inside
a closed space it will be super
loud. Your mileage may vary, may
be completely illegal, do it
somewhere nothing will catch on
fire. These things fly off in
the air. I have found them on
the roof of my car testing them
out. It's a lot of shit. To give
you an idea  ‑ ‑ [firecracker
sounds] >> That was just
12‑volts with just that one
strand that you saw before.
Again, you can do that with pi,
just drive a relay and apply
four volt and boom it goes. So
from here, I don't have any Z
wave integration yet, it's not
open‑source, shit's expensive. I
would like to be able to do
that. I would like to integrate
SDR scanning into the 345 band
for the wireless sensors, that
sort of thing, to be able to
read those on the fly, not just
the hard line. If there's any
SDR guy that's know how to pull
information out of 345 meg AM ‑
‑ signal, and actually use it,
talk to me afterwards. That
would be awesome. >> There's the
345 900 Meg receiver,
transmitter that  ‑ ‑ wanted to
spend time in the hacking
village, see how that works out.
That came out a day before I got
on the plane to come here. I
want to hear ideas from you
guys. If you have awesome
stories that don't include giant
pits with spikes at the bottom
‑ ‑ no, no. Question? >>
[indiscernible] >> Shut the door
after the  ‑ ‑ no, that may be a
good idea but that also could be
some sort of booby trap, that
theoretic firework thing if
somebody implemented such a
thing, not that I would, but if
it did and the door was shut,
they were not able to have a
timely egress outside the
establishment, were to be maybe
burned alive, that would be bad.
>> Anyway, I am running out of
time, I apologize, any
questions, there's my Twitter,
e‑ mail, all that. Come find me
afterwards. Yes. [Applause]