All right. Say hello to KRBTGT.
Say hello to KRBTGT. Come on
this is DEFCON people! >> [Cheering] >>
Since the beginning since your domain
was formed. KRBTGT has been
there. It's been there through
the early years in 2000, 2004
>> [laughter] >>
when everyone thought
they were special and
deserved admin
rights. You remember the time?
KRBTGT was there protesting with
everyone else that everyone
should be an admin and then
there was these things called
domains an active directory and
everyone wanted to be a domain
admin. Windows 2000 was
revolutionary but so was D con.
So in 2003, all those domains
that were sitting on the
internet very likely could have
been owned by D com or
any of the worms that were
going around at that time.
Things got better, right? Everyone
remembers KRBTGT was there when
you finally installed a fire wall.
So all those remote attacks and
those worms that were destroying
your domain for years finally
stopped. It was the answer to
all of our security problems,
right? Yes. Then there was
Windows XP probably Microsoft's
greatest product. Except there
was MSO8067 and once again pen
testers and hackers rejoiced
because they were easily able to
knock over every enterprise.
Then there was the great
administrative layoff of 2007 as
much when you realized your
domain admin's group ballooned
to over 400 people and over a
hundred of them no longer worked
at your company anymore. Why
would you say you have admin
rights? So then it really got
better. 2009 the security
industry blossomed and everyone
was selling windows server 2008
and KERBEROS was the answer to
your pass the hash problems. You
didn't have to worry about pass
to hash anymore. KERBEROS it's
awesome. To manage your local
admin accounts you decide to
deploy this policy group policy
preferences, right? Yeah.
Everybody did that. Including
Microsoft. So in case you didn't
know group policy preferences
are terrible, you should never
use them. Microsoft even came
out with a patch to keep you
from being able to use a feature
that they swear was never
security vulnerability. If
you're using group policy
preferences that's terrible.
That means anyone on your
network can get local admin
rights or any of the passwords
that are in those group policy
preference files. So, let's talk
about the last two years. So,
you decided to move on, the
domain moves on, the server 2012
and KRBTGT is loving life
because you finally gotten rid
of MTLM you've gone to Kerberos.
You got rid of MTLM and then
there was heart bleed. And it
knocked over all your VPN
servers and you got owned again.
And there was this thing the
golden ticket which no one seems
to know anything about that you
find all over your network as
well. Account number two. Thanks
to Mr. Benjamin Delpe in the
front row. So, do you know how
old your KRBTGT hash is?
Anybody. When you created a
domain or when you upgraded from
2003 functional to 2008, anybody
created their current domain in
2001? Nobody? 2002? 2003? 2004?
Five? Six? Seven? So anything
that happens to this domain was
2004 so I guess the question is
do you know where your KRBTGT
hash is because this domain's
hashes are on P span.
(Laughter).
>>> That's not good. But the
bottom line, the whole point of
this talk is this. If you've
ever been owned, if your domain
has ever been compromised your
hashes dumped you may still be
compromised because that KRBTGT
hash is what's used to sign all
of the tickets so with that and
only that tickets can be created
to take any user and add them to
any group or a lot more. Did
anybody go up to the Kerberos
black hat talk besides the two
speakers in the front row who
gave the talk? Awesome. They're
only here to heckle me and they
have been heckling me the last
half hour while I had to sit
next to them the previous talk
but now I'm on stage and you're
not. So maybe you could be like
this guy. Does anyone know who
this guy is? Nobody? Cool. So he
testified before senate that as
long as you scan you're secure.
He testified against Dave
Kennedy or countered Dave
Kennedy earlier this year and he
said that with a straight face.
As long as you're scanning
you're secure. You have not been
compromised. So ‑‑ (Laughter).
>> Now that I have an audience
other than twitter, I would like
to say good luck with that.
Let's talk about Kerberos. Does
nobody get the name? No one gets
meme. I swear. All right. I'm
not going to bore you with how
Kerberos works. That was Skip
and Ben's talk at BlackHat, but
this is the basics of it in a
really crude diagram I drew
several years ago. If you would
like to go over that. But what I
want to focus on is the Spoofed
PAC attack which is the
privileged account certificate
(PAC) which is a portion of the
Kerberos ticket. The previous
diagram and this diagram are
taken from skip and my white
paper for black hat 2012 and if
you see what we're doing here,
we're basically just adding
groups to the pack and then
we're using the KRBTGT hash to
sign it and make it valid so you
can take any user and add them
to any group temporarily and
they're not actually going to
show up on the domain network in
that group so there's almost no
log of this unless you actually
use the privileges Who has heard
of the golden ticket attack?
Awesome. So, golden ticket which
is a great branding by one
Benjamin Delpe sitting in the
front row heckling me right now.
He added to the wonderful tool
Mimikatz Who has used Mimikatz
before? Awesome. So, the golden
ticket attack is not just the
spoof pack that skip and I
theorized several years ago. It
goes beyond that. It's not only
that but in addition Ben was
like man, you guys are idiots,
you could make this ticket last
forever. We were like wow, why
didn't we think of that? True
story. So there's a great
tutorial by Rafael Mudge who is
awesome and not talking this
year, which I'm disappointed
about but did he a great
tutorial, that's the link to it
if you want to check that out.
So now it's demo time. So, I
prerecorded because this is DEF
CON and I knew everything was
going to go wrong. I'm just
going to pause it, cause it's
going to go real fast I'm doing
who am I. I'm limited user, I'm
nobody. In this scenario the
attackers already compromised in
one of those hundred ways that
we kind of talked about earlier,
compromise the enterprise way
back when in 2004 with D con or
MSO8O67 or MSO90S in server
2008. So, the question a lot of
people ask is if you knocked
over the domain then you've
already got everything. The
point to all of this is that you
can leave and come back whenever
you want. You're not going to
leave anything beaconing, you're
not going to leave anything to
find. So, this is one way of
coming back in this limited user
is going to check the group
membership or domain admin and
it's just administrator like it
should be. No one else. All
right. Phishing E‑mail really
important. Got to open that up.
From the boss. It's too legit so
we got to ‑‑ that was not enough
hammer time. Hold on.
You got to get that.
All we need to do is enable
macros. So we've got
to do that. I'm going to put
this on youtube and that's
mostly for when I put this on
youtube but what this macro is
doing is it's using PowerShell
and then PowerShell is going to
pull down invoke-Mimikatz. Has
anyone used invoke-Mimikatz and
power-- It was released last
year at DEF CON. A couple
people. It's awesome. Basically
we get a fully staged Mimikatz
without having to worry about
A/V or touching disk at all. So
what we're doing is we're using
a macro to call PowerShell to
pull Mimikatz down reflectively
in memory and then in addition I
added a few things so now I'm
going to use the Krbtgt hash
I've already stolen to create a
ticket and add myself to the
domain admin group. It's not
just a Kerberos ticket for
domain admins we'll take this
limited user and add them to
domain admins without them
realizing what's going on.
It's kind of a silly example not
really what you would want to
do. How you would want to do
that. All right so now the user
has enabled macros and they
shouldn't feel remorseful
but in this case shouldn't
have done that.
We see PowerShell firing up. And then
you'll see limited user is in
the domain admin's group.
So thanks to Kerberos if you've
ever been compromised, it's
trivial to come back in. A
single phishing E‑mail and all
privilege escalation is done.
Let's talk mitigation. As I gave this
talk to a couple people, experts
beforehand ‑‑ what's that? >>
>> [Applause] >> Yay!
Both I and Windows 8
suck. All right let's talk
about mitigation. So, this side
had to be reworked multiple
times because everything I had
on it was wrong originally. So,
the easiest thing and if you
read this a couple places on the
internet, MSDN maybe one place,
if you really want to reset the
password hash to the Krbtgt
account you got to do it twice
but be warned it might literally
break everything. Shear point,
exchange, you name it, it will
not automatically fix itself. It
may be multiple reboots. Someone
who has actually gone through
it, caution that it is not worth
doing and even Microsoft hasn't
done it. So, the only reliable
way is if you happen to have ‑‑
if your domain functional level
is 2003 and you've raised it to
2008, this really shouldn't be a
reason to do it because if
you're doing this because you
know you've been compromised,
you probably should start
completely over so I guess the
biggest take away from this is
if you've gone through and
changed all of your passwords
and thought that you were good,
you're not. Or if you're an
incident handler and you cannot
figure out why a threat group
keeps coming right back in and
you can't figure out how the
privilege is escalating this
very well could be the way. So,
it's all in Mimikatz. I put
business practice DC with all
available futures don't get
owned again. Detection is worse
than mitigation. It is
completely a needle in the
haystack. Harder to detect than
pass the hash. >> Pass the hash
you're actually doing something.
In this case you're generating a
ticket on a single box. Until
you actually use it it would be
very difficult to detect. As
well as whether or not your
Krbtgt hash has been stolen.
Unless you know you have been
compromised like you find PW
dump sitting on your PC I don't
know a way for you to know that
that has already been taken. You
can look for strange account
activity. I thought it was
really sneaky, and I was like Im
going to look for ten year old
tickets and Benjamin is going to
go ahead and change that is
feature to allow the tickets to
be an arbitrary length. Even
that detection mechanism is not
going to work for Mimikatz. One
thing you could do is look for
low privileged accounts
performing privileged actions.
That might be the only way to
detect this particular attack. I
do want to give some thanks to
Skip. Stand up, Skip and
Benjamin, can you come up here.
Is Joe here? Joe. He wrote
Invoke-Mimikatz which is the
awesome PowerShell script and
added. Will and a bunch of other
people. This is Vince. Vince has
never been to America. He came
all the way here for DEF CON and
black hat. He seldomly ventures
out of France and it took a lot
of negotiating I think and I
just really want him to feel
appreciated for his tool
Mimikatz and the number of
people that use it so let's give
them a hand. (Applause).
>>> And I think for his long
trip, he deserves this speaker
badge more than I do. So I'm
going go ahead and give him
that. (Applause).
>>> One more time for Ben and
everybody else on the golden
ticket stub. Other than that,
that's all I got. I will see you
guys around and partying
tonight. (Applause).