>> It's time for our next talk,
and it sure looks like we are
picking on every little thing
that you can buy at Best Buy and
plug into your network today,
and that's awesome, that's
awesome. So we're going to hear
from the guys from Duo right
now. We've got Mark and Zach,
and let's give them a big party
track welcome. In fact, one of
these guys is a new speaker. So
that will be fun. [Applause] >>
I think he was expecting his
shot. Anyway, so welcome to the
Internet of fails. Where IoT has
gone wrong and how we're making
it right. I'm Zach Lanier,
Senior Security Researcher with
Duo Security. >> And I'm Mark
Stanislav with Duo Security as
well. >> Thank you. Thank you.
So IoT, you know, if you have
been in the space for a while,
you probably know similar things
as M2M, so machine-to-machine.
If you've been doing embedded
security research, you're
probably much more friendly with
that term. I think cloud
computing is a good example of
how we all bitched about
semantics for the first five
years, and now everyone is just,
like, yeah, cloud computing,
cool. But everyone was, like,
oh, that is not a thing, this is
bullshit no one will do this. So
I think IoT is the same way, you
know, probably get passed the
definitions and the semantics of
a lot of this stuff, and kind of
look at it for what it is, which
is a huge sector for research. A
lot of the talks I think will be
seen at DEF CON for many years
to come we'll be around these
kinds of devices. There is a lot
to talk about today. So let's
get onto it. In terms of what we
have going, you know,
pervasiveness really is kind of
where it comes down to. You
think about like home router,
right? You have the home router
hacking lab, all that going on.
The number of devices that we
have in IoT where you have
firmware going, right? We can
barely update one router. What
makes us think we're going to
update like hundreds of devices
in our households in five years?
There is a lot going on there,
the service, whether it is a
business or whether it's your
personal life, right? You're
going to bring the stuff in IoT
into your offices and if you do
penetration testing, I'm
guessing you're hoping people
are going to bring these random
things off the shelf of Best Buy
that reverse proxy out into the
office. In terms of the overall
environment, there is a lot
going on in terms of how diverse
the technologies are. So the
ecosystem are really messed up
right now. You see companies big
and small trying to standardize
and make sense of it all, but
really we don't see that quite
yet and I don't think we will
for a while. Part of the cool
thing about IoT right now and
where we're at with a lot of
technologies we'll talk about
today is you can innovate really
easily. You have a lot of
agility and IoT is really taking
advantage of that right now. So
how do you patch a bunch of
firmware on the devices? Do you
auto update? Do you have people
manually do it? What's that
going to look like, again, when
you're on that scale? And the
problem we've always had with
embedded hardware is you get
random, you know, ODMs. You have
firmware that no one has
actually done. Security audits
of kernels that are like 15
years old. And, you know, this
is the kind of stuff that we're
putting in our networks right
now. So even though the device
is new, the actual technology
underlined is probably not.
Ecosystem overall, if you buy an
IoT device, guess what? That IoT
device probably has like three
or four services behind it from
three or four other vendors. So
you're not just buying a piece
of hardware and on you're
putting it on your network.
You're buying a piece of
hardware, putting it on your
network, and then it's calling
out to three other services that
then have data that you have for
your device to function or
service accounts to make it tie
into something else you're
doing. So where does your data
go when it goes to the IoT? It's
the same problem as CloudRight.
Where is my data at? Um, with
IoT you definitely don't know
where it's going. At least with
Cloud Services you at least know
who, like, what provider might
have it. With IoT you're kind of
just blindly trusting that the
person that created the hardware
has a good service provider on
the back end. And like I
mentioned, the proxy
connections, if you haven't done
this kind of research yet,
you'll see a lot of devices
traversing through all of your
security, going out to the
Internet and then exposing web
interfaces on a public port
through one of the search
providers. So again for
attackers this is kind of a big
deal. Internet things. A lot of
insanity is trademarked by me,
unofficially. So if you think
about IoT and you think about
attack surface, right? IT
cameras seem crazy because they
are cameras in your home
recording you, audio and video
whatever. But really, that's
kind of the purpose of this
technology world. It is
convenience, yes, there is some
risk, but at the same time, if
I'm in Las Vegas I can see my
home right now, and that's
pretty cool. But if you go down
the line though, an egg tray
that is connected, it tells you
how soon your eggs are going to
expire. That really kind of
solidifies the insanity part of
this for me because imagine what
company wants to be the company
that gets breached by an egg
trainer office. We get really,
really scared when fridges start
sending spam. How about you
actually have someone running
code execution from your egg
tray or running Wireshark from
an egg tray, that should scare
you. >> So one of the things
that we have noticed is, so
there is IoT, you're probably
familiar with a lot of big
commercial vendors who have kind
of occupy the IoT space. But,
lately, there has been this,
this explosion in terms of just
anyone can buy, any one of these
things like an electric end,
they don't really have to
understand hardware or software.
They buy this thing and they
Sauder some stuff maybe or they
get their friends to do it, and
they go to this web based IDE
and they plug in some code, and
then they get $800,000 on kick
starter. So hardware is really,
really cheap and very
accessible. And the
possibilities are endless here,
and it's great because anyone
can do this, but at the same
time, any one of these pieces of
hardware might have its own
security-related idiosyncrasies,
the people developing the
software, the people running the
services that back some of these
pieces of hardware might not
actually have any security
experience or actually apply any
controls whatsoever. So, you
know, the low barrier to entry
is $25 to become a new IoT
vendor. I don't know if any of
you are familiar with some of
the WiFi enabled lightbulbs but
is one of the things that we
started to thinking about. We
actually have some WiFi enabled
lightbulbs back in one of our
offices. And you see something
like Philips, which is a $60
WiFi enabled lightbulb which you
would assume all things being
equal. Philips probably took
into account some security
measures, maybe, but then you
have, you know, the $23 kind of
Alibaba special that comes from
who knows where, made by who
knows who. And probably not as
robust from a security
standpoint. So if you're going
to be deploying these lightbulbs
across your office so that you
can maybe, you know, cut down on
your electricity bill and
automate some of the lighting,
what are you going to pay for?
Are you going to pay the $60 or
go as low price point as you
possibly can? So this is kind
of, I think, really represents
Mark's point about the IoT
ecosystem. It basically stacks
all of the way down, right? Just
like with mobile, we've built on
top of existing services and
added a whole new device of
software with its own
vulnerabilities and hardware
issues. So have we done with IoT
as well because now we have
mobile apps that control these
devices and they talk to web
services. So it's just a
spaghetti of security to
connect. >> So the to point out,
you know, if this and that,
we're not talking about phones
and their service and everything
else. But we want to kind of
talk about the principle that
when you have all of these
embedded devices on your
network, the next thing you want
to do is connect them all,
clearly. You want them to do
cool things, and some that are
practical, right? Like my
example here, you have a CO2
monitor, if all of a sudden CO2
goes up, aside from of course,
like alarms, maybe the lightbulb
turns red, or some other way
that can actually, you know,
permeate your household or your
office space to add value to
what you already have deployed
for technology. However, if you
have 110 platforms and if this
and that, what happens when, you
know, they have tens of
thousands of users and they get
compromised? What does that mean
for infrastructure, for
businesses, for personal homes?
What could you do if you had
access to APIs, maybe you found
a venerability in one of the
APIs that they are using for
customers. What could that mean
to people actually leveraging
these platforms? So government,
of course, at DEF CON is always
a tricky topic. I think, though,
if you paid attention, FTC is
ideally there at all times to
help consumers protect their
interests. Whether that is
companies lying to you, that
company is saying that, Oh yeah,
we secure your stuff, don't
worry about this. It turns out
they don't use encryption or
whatever else. So FTC is
actually been pretty forward on
this, you know, they've had
panels and they have meetings
and talking to different people
in this space, but TRENDnet,
which we'll talk about an
example here in a second. That
was actually a case where they
came down pretty hard on
TRENDnet because they had a
vulnerable IP camera with a
pathetic vulnerability that
should never get out the door
from any respectable business,
and that put a lot of people in
danger. So for better or for
worse, there is government
oversight in this space and so
the people in this room, you
don't want to be left behind. If
the government is ahead of you
in technology we've got a
problem. So think about what
you're working on that, that
would definitely set a
precedent. >> So just to kind of
give an overview of some of the
challenges that small vendors in
particular face and large
vendors as well, when it comes
to IoT. We'll just kind of run
though some of these. The talk
that preceded ours and many of
the talks that will probably
happen throughout this entire
conference, and I'm sure that
none of you are strangers to
this, but hardware security can
be a death nail for a lot of
these devices. And as we showed
with the $25 to the $130 devices
that are out there, a lot of
these devices that are out in
production use just sort of
generic development, you know,
system on chips, or development
boards and they're designed
basically facilitate rapid
prototype and quick development.
They don't really have a lot of
security features for a variety
of reasons. They want to make it
as agile as possible, they want
to make it as quick as possible,
they want to have a lower power
consumption. Any number of
things and another thing that
can be overlooked is the
prevalence of the same
components if they're using the
same SoC or if they're using the
same micro code or any number of
things. Finding one issue in one
of those things could affect a
whole swath of devices that
might have been not even by the
same vendor. Like we said,
there's almost no expertise
required to really a common IoT
vendor at this point. So the
least common denominator any of
this is, I'm not really a great
hardware hacker, but this has
cropped up time and time again,
it is literally, like, these
devices getting shipped out in
production with things as simple
as UR headers, so exposed and,
you know, you just drop right to
a root shell on one of these
devices and you start stealing
the whole thing. And then you go
and repeat that on every one of
those devices. Software security
is still a big issue here as
well. Because of a lot of the
environments, in particular, an
example, you are kind of
restricted as to what language
you can actually develop in. So
people might not necessarily, if
it is something like a really
low end, or really like, great
embedded device, you might have
to learn C and people continue
to fuck up and not learn C
correctly. So they use functions
that they are not supposed to,
right? There are is dangerous
behavior repeating itself
because we write C pretty one
day. So it's just sort of
history repeating. And then
because you might be picking a
platform that restricts your
language, you might be also
restricted to what operating
system you can run as well. And
if it's, you know, if the OS is
already loaded there or you're
using a vendor-provided OS, they
might not have taken into
account simple things like
exploit mitigation. They might
not have even done things like
DPA Solar or XN. They might not
be doing any sort of mitigation,
nothing. So just an example over
here from an embedded device
which actually runs a web server
that talks to a bunch of other
things that are really
important. There is zero, pretty
much zero memory address
randomization. So the dependency
on other libraries, if you think
about things like heart bleed,
for instance, relying on these
other opaque, or open source
libraries you basically get this
bug inheritance as well. And
this applies to mobile
applications that run these
things as well. So
communications and network
security for a lot of the
devices. There might be some
really weird goofiness. I know
someone in the audience is going
to recognize this example, but
when the device actually acts as
an access point or it connects
to a remote control that they
are acting on either mode, when
they don't necessarily enable
things like WEP, or WAP or WAP2
or they just have some other
exploitable behavior. There are
cases where they will transmit
things like software updates
over plaintext or if they do
transmit them securely or over
SSL/TLS they don't sign the
firmware update blogs or
anything like that. Numerous
services that are exposed on a
lot of these devices that don't
necessarily enhance
functionality in any way, so
just remote administration
services. Shared accounts are a
problem as well when the vendor
might provide a support account
for updates or remote support.
And maybe there's a static SSH
key shared across all of these
devices or the same hardcoded
password, things of that nature.
And these are complicated even
furthermore by use of other
technologies like 6LoPAN,
ZigBee, et cetera. And then the
simple example where you can
spend I think $50 and plug a GSM
modem on to your device. There
are talks here to we'll discuss
yet again how ridiculous GSM is.
So COM security is still a
really hard thing to solve if
you're a small IT guy. >> Kind
of getting back to the fact that
the IoT device you have really
is not just an IoT device, it's
really just kind of a hub for a
bunch of services that are then
going to connect to from like
four or five or third-party
vendors. So if you think of
things like APIs, APIs rarely
are actually APIs. They're just
like, oh, I did a get against a
web server, therefore API. What
we're not seeing, A,
authentication against these
devices is really there. It will
just say, oh, well, this
embedded hardware, clearly you
can't see what these calls are
over the network and have no
protection on them because they
think that no one is going to
look at this kind of stuff, or
signing request to ensure
integrity to what API calls are
made in the first place. So
OWASP mobile, you know, web top
ten. This is all alive and well
in the world of IoT. The same
problems that we all, you know,
attack online and the Internet,
guess what, they're all on these
IoT devices as well. So if
you're looking to get a shell on
one of these devices, maybe it
has a sequel server, because why
not add a sequel server to
everything, and maybe it has a
web app with poor code handling.
Well, guess what, now you write
your PHP shell or suburb, CGIF
and you drop it on the IoT
device, and you have, you know,
CNC over this entire network of
IoT devices in that home. So
just kind of conflating all of
these different technologies
that we already screwed up
really badly all the time. Now
it's just like this magical box
of terribleness, and that's what
you're buying for $150. So the
third party provider thing, you
know, I have seen those go
really badly. We will talk about
that today, but not too much. If
you think about cloud
infrastructure and the services
that people stand up, whether it
is a pass or they are doing
infrastructure, like, EC2 or
something. A lot of these cases
they might understand how to get
the software out, which is
probably isn't true, but they at
least know how to get a nice
piece of hardware out. And then
they're saying oh, we need all
this infrastructure now to
support this, well, they're
going to have infrastructure
vulnerabilities, they're going
to have, you know, OS updated
packs, and default credentials
to web app services and
everything else that people do
wrong already. Now you're going
to have that across four or five
vendors. Kind of getting back to
what I started on which is this
idea where, you know, it is hard
enough to get people to update
their routers, but at the level
of coverage in IoT that I think
we will see in the next few
years. That's going to be a
really big problem for most
consumers out there. This
audience is exempt, you guys
will upgrade your firmware
hopefully, but if you have all
these different examples across
your life in technology, you
know, some things you bootstrap
by and opening a mobile app and
saying, like, oh, new firmware
version, hit, you know, update.
And then some of them you hold
the button on the back of the
thing to call home, and you
know, bootstrap to that process.
And some of them you go to the
web interface on the device. You
know, the web interface that was
mentioned once in the
instruction booklet that you
threw promptly away. So there's
all these different ways to do
firmware, and one thing we're
not seeing very commonly is
auto-updating firmware. Now you
can make pros and cons to
whether you should update
firmware. Certainly for the
vendor, it is a harder process
to get right and have a recovery
mode and all that, but again,
how many of these you're going
to have, and what's that gonna
look like if one bug comes out,
if another heart bleed happens
in five years, what would that
mean to all these devices that
have SSL snaps that are
compromised now. So let's jump
into some failures. So a lot of
this section at the top is
really an anti-pattern talk. You
know, what happened, why it's
wrong, how you should be doing
it right, because I think that's
a pretty good methodology to
help people understand what is
going on. So the TRENDnet that I
mentioned earlier, basically
they had a CGI app on this thing
where it was viewing video --
and don't let this /anony part
fool you. That's not supposed to
be typed anonymous endpoint for
this thing. They actually just
failed -- I think it was a code
regression, some of the firmware
that was across dozens of their
cameras and in this case, the
first time the bug came out,
someone actually indexed 700
cameras almost immediately, put
them online, they actually
created a Twitter account to
say, like, oh, look, a new
camera that is vulnerable to
this. And you could just watch
the video stream by going to
this URL on any IP you could
find off Shodan or Google. So
it's kind of a big risk for
people that bought this camera
thinking, like, yeah, TRENDnet
company, they have been around
for a while. In this case, this
is all that you do. You go to
Google into your URL and find
some cameras, and that's of
course if you don't just go to
one of the many aggregation
sites for big creepers, but
don't be a big creeper. And
really what frustrates me, this
isn't a security thing, right?
This is like basic QA101, does
your admin have access to admin
pages, do your guests have
access to guest pages, and can
your guests get to admin pages?
The answer should be no. And
they didn't take the time to run
a curl script on a loop or
Selenium tasks or anything else.
That would have very quickly
caught that this was a problem.
So second one, you know,
IOActive has done amazing
research. One section they did a
little while back was on some of
the Belkin WeMo stuff. And, you
know, in this case, you have
Belkin which is actually doing
some of the best practices out
there. They're actually signing
firmware. Unfortunately, and you
know, anyone who has ever got a
key burn knows how this feels.
They had the key, and then the
pass phrase is actually
hardcoded in the firmware. So
the firmware got dumped, they
extracted the signing key and
pass phrase and now they're at a
point as an attacker where you
can actually sign valid
firmware. So if you can amend
the middle of the update request
or you can somehow otherwise
interface into the update
mechanism, at that point you
would actually be able to push
valid firmware on to that
device. So you know, QLDR on
this one, and we're going to
touch this one or two more times
while we're standing up here.
Don't hide stuff in firmware.
It's not hidden, like, whether
someone gets the firmware today
or tomorrow, whether you think
that you obfuscated a key in
there, you didn't, it's not
hidden. The same thing applies
to mobile apps. Just because
it's encrypted when it goes up
to the app store, it doesn't
mean that someone can't just
dump the memory and get all of
the ASCII out of that binder and
go through. >> So contact
security was looking at these
LIFX devices and what they
discovered was that -- so
6LoWPAN and other low-powered,
you know, IPV6 over this low
power -- inside of the device,
once again, hardcoded symmetric
key for encrypting all sorts of
data, including credentials, and
WiFi pass phrases and such for
the other side of this device.
So the hypothetical exploit, you
give this to someone as a gift,
you creep up on their house
pretty usual, and one they add
the bulb to their network, you
just capture traffic decrypted
with symmetric key and then you
get all their WiFi credentials.
And then you just jump on to
their WiFi network and you creep
on them there as well. So,
again, repeating the same exact
thing from before. Don't
hardcode things if you don't
want them to be found. They will
be found. So that's why --
Dubbie and Dolan are over there.
So another example here. This is
a whole automation gateway that
was built by a large utility
group. Well, provided by a large
utility provider. What they did
was they actually outsourced all
of this to another service
provider who gets these
basically like white label
devices that connect to their
infrastructure so that you can
on there and, you know, have
your lights flip on and off, and
have your pool pump flip on and
off, and it has this beautiful
web interface. It's really ugly,
it wasn't that beautiful. It can
be controlled though a mobile
app as well, so, you know, you
talk to this magical cloud site
and then over this verse
connection to this gateway will
push down directives from the
users of scheduling and things
of that nature. So this kind of
represents sort of the whole
swathe of things that, you know,
the web interface itself was
vulnerable to all sorts of OWASP
top 10 101 things. And then the
gateway itself had unfettered
console access, there were the
UR headers exposed that dumped
you right into the root shell.
There was no privileges
separation for any services on
the device. The same support
credentials are used to manage
all of the devices. And then on
the other side, on the ZigBee
side of it, where it talked to
the controllers there was
vulnerable, like, things
extraction, replay, injection,
et cetera. So this is sort of an
example of we start to kind of
encroach upon utility and more
ICS-type stuff. >> Cool, so that
is pretty cool stuff that other
people have squared away in this
space. So this next topic
someone actually did last year,
does anyone have an IZON IP
camera? There's plenty of
people. There's got to be one or
two in here. Yeah! Did you get
rid of it? It's not surprising.
So a couple examples. So IP
camera, I bought it, I had the
best of intentions. I happened
to scan my network one day as
you do, and there was Telnet
listening, and whenever Telnet
is listening in 2013 of this
time, you should just stop what
you are doing, and figure out
why Telnet is on your network
and stop it immediately. So in
trying to break into this device
and do bad things to it, one
thing I did getting back to my
don't hardcode stuff anywhere
is, okay. All right. No, setup.
So the mobile app in this case,
again, people assume mobile apps
are safe and they're encrypted.
Well, when you have them in your
phone and you start them, guess
what? They decrypt. So you dump
the memory and you get the
decrypted version of this. In
this case, you know, in this IDA
screen shot, this was actually
shell scripting that connected
over Telnet to do the firmware
upgrade kickoff. So you have
hardcoded root credentials over
Telnet firmware upgrade. This is
what we're talking about in IoT
and the Internet of fails. This
is like a collapsing of
terribleness. So in this case,
run strings, get some details.
Drop your admin credentials and
log-in. And now, you've guess
what? You have access to root on
every single camera because this
isn't a mobile app. This isn't
one off thing, this is every
single one. >> All right. Let's
congratulate our first time
speaker to DEF CON. [Applause]
>> Thank you. >> There you go.
>> Oh, I feel so much better
now. >> All right. I just want
to point out, I love that
Internet of fail comment about
the Internet of things. >> Is
there anything different? It's
not just a synonym? >> Well,
that is true. That's where we've
been for ages. >> So if you are
ever in charge of this scenario,
do not use Telnet, if you do,
you're not a DEF CON, so let's
face it, you guys are fine. And
don't hardcode passwords.
Another example, this gets to
the service layer. So Amazon web
services was being used to
actually store the video
recording. So if you had a
motion alert, or sound alert, it
recorded, drop it to S3, your
mobile up would then go, hey, I
need to see that alert, and then
it would pull it up. So in this
case, there was no
authentication required to hit
the endpoints for S3. So they
weren't using the IAM or any of
the other very smart ways you
should do things. The times were
protected with MD5 strings for
the actual file digest, and
there's no SSL. So A, if you're
in a coffee shop and someone is
on the network, guess what?
They're going to see the same
video you are watching on your
own. B, if you have a shit load
of time, and a cluster and want
to piss off AWS, you could
probably get through a little
bit of key space and maybe find
a video or two. But it's one of
those things, you take something
as simple as upload a video and
store it, they don't encrypt it
in transit, they don't encrypt
it as rest, and they don't
actually protect it with
anything more than just a file
name stream. So if you thought
your video of you getting out of
shower and walking by was going
to be deleted off of the
Internet securely, I wouldn't
hold hope out. So yes, simple
things like AWS has identity
access management. It's very
easy. You can give credentials
per users. Block things off, put
it in a mobile app, and make it
connect out and actually do API
calls the right way, and segment
data. Also, hey, Amazon, you can
just encrypt before you upload,
simple as that. Yes, good cat
video is cat videoing. So you
guys enjoy that for a second.
Getting back to my tirade
against APIs. Is it the poorly
implement or is it the low sack?
Okay. So API calls in this case,
the API calls that were actually
going out, again, without SSL,
because why would you encrypt
anything? And the secret token
in the API call, this is how you
can tell that this is always
true. The secret token was just
the user's password that was
MD5. So if you didn't already
have their password, and you
were on the network with them,
you sniff the terrible password,
anyway, and now you can just
login as that person and look at
their video realtime and see
them when they're getting out of
the shower. One thing that
happened here which really
pissed me off, and I made that
very clear to the vendor is they
actually took my password that I
signed up with for their
service, and transmitted the MD5
sum to their vendor, and they
thought that was like okay to
do. So when we do things like
use, you know, one password or
last password or whatever, and
we're like, yeah, we have one
password per site. Guess what? I
didn't know that this was a
vendor. So if they get breached
I'm not changing my password
because I don't think I'm
impacted, but I am because
they've passed my password on to
someone else without telling me
about it. So I think one thing
that helps is looking at kind of
the big picture of what is
happening in IoT. Remember, this
is one device. All of those
things that you're seeing on the
screen are a direct
vulnerability I found, just a
terrible failure of best
practices or just a total
compromises of security for all
customers to the point where
they actually had hardcoded
Amazon S3 credentials in the
mobile app. Remember how I was
just saying that Amazon S3 was
the place they stored everyone's
videos without any kind of
segmentation? So we're supposed
to say this vendor is redacted,
but -- yeah, whatever. So these
are real, real issues that we
identified maybe six, or seven
months ago. Well, even longer.
So basically just to give you an
idea, this device is basically a
little embedded device, there's
a mobile app that goes with it.
You can pretty much control
everything through this mobile
app and it talks to AWS and
pushes messages back and forth
and down. And it uses the
electric input. So the session
IDs to talk to their service to
actually manage and push
messages down to this device
were just based on UNIX epoch,
period. Just the UNIX epoch as
timestamp for when you logged
into that service. So that's a
very small space in which to
actually root write. So with all
of the recent timestamps, just,
you know, brute force through
them. So then you become a user
simply with this little browser
header. So clearly the fix is,
use real session management,
right? This is all back to ten
10 OWASP 101 basic web security
stuff. The impact here is pretty
bad because it has to do with
kids. So they also have a system
where you can buy credits to
then send messages to these
various devices. So you purchase
these, these credits via an app
purchasing inside of the mobile
application. Now, it turns out
that -- the, it was the client's
side enforcement. The client
would tell the server how many
credits it wanted. The server is
like cool, whatever you say. You
can pick a number, any number, a
signed integer, add and remove
credits as you felt fit. So you
get that many of whatever
things, whatever credit things
this gives you. So obviously do
not let the client be the
authority for this because you
must assume that it is in the
bad creeper's control. Excuse
me. So there was also this sort
of -- I don't really want to
confuse deputy problem, but just
basically a major fuck up where
-- if you, the analogy here, is
if you are using something like
Facebook, I send you a friend
request, you have to then accept
or reject that friend request
before we see each other's
stuff, right? Technically, like,
that's generally how it works.
Here, however, you could ask the
user or whoever, you know,
whoever your target is to be
your friend and immediately
access their stuff. So you could
start sending messages to this
device. So, you know, ask a user
to be your friend, you get some
stuff back about the user and
then you can just start sending
messages to their device. So,
obviously, have, you know,
authorization process for all of
these things. I don't actually
transmit anything about target
back that the attacker can then
use. You know, actually have
control be on the target's side.
And then, of course, there is
the heart bleed discussion that
doesn't seem to want to die. So
you've got MoLEP speaking to
embedded devices, you've got
embedded devices speaking to
remote services and back and
forth. You know, there's been
these stats, I think it's been
something like 300,000 services
that have been identified out,
live out on the Internet that
are vulnerable to heart bleed
and probably other things as
well. But you have to ask
yourself, what about these
devices that are employed
internally or the services that
they are talking to or even the
clients, are the clients
actually vulnerable to heart
bleed, obviously, that's been
demonstrated as well. So you
really think that the $25 Ali
Baba special lightbulb that you
bought. If that happens to be
vulnerable to something like
this, do you really think that
you're going actually get that
addressed that the vendor
actually cares? They might even
be a fly by night operation or
may not have the expertise to
actually deal with this. >> So
one problem that we're seeing
and why we're so interested in
this space in trying to make it
suck less is the vendors that
you're going to see in this
space are not, you know, the
Belkins. You know, obviously
they have some stuff, Cisco has
some stuff, but they're not the
people that you're going to get
most of your devices from. A lot
of the stuff -- if you look at
the kick starter, and you go-go
dragging innovation, you know,
there's a lot of IoT right now,
and if you think of like
$80,000, you have to do R&D,
prototyping, software
development, hardware
management, Cloud Services,
hiring marketing and
salespeople. To build devices,
ship them and then have like
legal, right? $80,000 is going
to go very, very, very quickly.
They're not going to have money
to spend on protecting your
device. Again, everyone has the
best of intentions, right? And
that's why this road is paved,
you know, to hell with IoT
devices all along the way. We're
going to be in a really bad
place, much worse than we are
now, which is pretty bad. And if
you look at postscapes.com or
devices that are from alpha.com,
go see how many companies you've
ever heard of because they're
probably brand new
entrepreneurs, brand new
bootstrap startups, or someone
that crowdfunded a device. And
this is the kind of stuff all of
us are going to want to buy, but
at what cost, right? One other
main point to this is a security
researcher to Belkin, or Cisco
or Samsung at least mean
something, right? Security
researcher, these vendors with
two people on staff that are
both like maybe one product
designer and one guy that is
okay at mobile apps they don't
know what security research is,
they probably don't come to DEF
CON, and they are going to be
the people that are trying to
triage bugs in thinking that
you're breaking in to their
company and trying to extort
them. And we've been told on a
call by a lawyer that we hacked
their systems, and that we were
doing like terrible things to
their company when all we were
doing was testing the device
locally in our home. So
crowdfunding, again, a lot of
this is coming out of
crowdfunding. It's not just,
like, speaking of platitudes,
like, literally some of these
devices are that you might be
using right now actually or
probably crowdfunded. And it's a
great way to innovate, for sure,
but again, the margins on these
things are nil and the amount of
extra capital they have to
invest is also nil. So it
doesn't really turn out too
well. >> So kind of back to what
Mark was just saying a minute
ago. A lot of these small
vendors, and we've had this
experience time and time again,
as I'm sure many of you probably
have as well, the small vendors,
even some large ones to this
day, right? That's why we still
have CFA reform and shit like
that. They just don't quite get
why you're coming to them and
telling them that their baby is
ugly. Why would anyone want to
hack my device? What are you
selling? Why would you want to
talk about this publicly? They
don't have the resources or the
experience to necessarily deal
with this. Like Mark said, Mark
said they might be strapped for
cash or they're just trying to
get the product out the door. So
the need for this space as well
means that certain researchers
even if you're like bad ass, you
know, super mega cool exploit,
but haven't really ever
interacted with an IoT vendor
before, especially one of the
smaller ones, you might not know
how to approach them. So we kind
of like to bridge that gap
between, like other initiatives
have done before for the
traditional space. We kind of
like to make sure that stuff is
fixed and that you-all stay out
of jail when it comes to IoT. So
born out of some of that
redacted slides you saw, and
just general frustration talking
to vendors in this space and
realizing that they're not going
to get it. We started an
initiative called build it
securely. So primarily we're
focused on the small company.
The vendor that is kick starter
or it's bootstrapped because
more often than not, they're
going to have no money. Even
some of the big vendors don't
actually have as many security
resources on staff as you would
like to know or like to think.
Ad so primarily we're trying to
bridge that gap for them and
help them get better devices in
your hands so we're going to
still do research. You're going
to get devices you don't have to
throw away after two days. We're
also trying to create resources
on the site. So if you want to
know, hey, I'm an engineer, what
is the one document I should
look at for IOS security, what's
the one API presentation I
should look at, and we'll try to
create some of those on the site
and just give resources that we
think are pretty legit, and
hopefully they actually read
them and go through them. And
then of course, presenting
conferences like this to talk
about this and, you know,
getting people involved. Okay.
It has been a long road. We will
look at a timeline in a second.
But where we're at now is the
drop cam was just acquired by
NASA for $550 million, unrelated
to our impact on them, I assure
you. And Belkin just came on. So
obviously we talked earlier
about IOActive and Belkin's
research. Brian over at Belkin
actually has a good security
pedigree, and he really does
want to make things better. So
we're going to be working with
his team as well to give them
extra resources and make things
more secure for all of the cool
stuff they have coming out. Dip
Jar is actually an incubator
startup out of Boston, and they
are doing some cool stuff with
basically a tip jar, GSM
enabled, that you can just dip
your card in and that's how you
tip people if you don't have
cash and you kind of want to go
and like say, here's two bucks.
And who else do we have?
Pinoccio which is actually a
system on ship vendor, you might
have saw them in earlier slides.
Zendo is a stealth startup right
now in the IoT space. They're
going to have a pretty large
product line coming out here.
Fun fact, the CEO of Zendo is
actually the former CEO of
Steminnovation who made the eyes
on camera. He saw my research
previously, and that this new
company he doesn't want to do it
the wrong way. So, you know, we
get really cynical about
companies not giving a shit, but
I had a cold call from a CEO of
someone I burned in the news.
And he reached out to me to have
me come in and give security
lectures to his engineering
staff. So it's not all doom and
gloom as much as we might
pretend. There are companies
that are trying to work hard on
security, and we should try to
support them. Amazing
researchers, IOActive, Steven
Routley, Stephan Chenette, Don
Bailey, did we forget anyone?
Zack, and then Bugcrowd is
providing their entire platform
pro bono to us. So that
researchers can triage bugs to
vendors through a private
communication between them. And
the best part about all of this
is, all of the researchers are
basically doing this, one,
because they want to help some
people, two, because they're
going to get research done and
not be sued for it. They already
have opt in from these vendors.
So, these are some pretty
awesome companies. Some
companies you might not have
heard of up here, but these are
really interesting companies
doing some pretty impressive
product lines coming out in the
space. And we're going to have
researchers looking at
preproduction hardware, doing
assessments against them,
getting them bugs and actually
making this device better before
they go in people's hands rather
than after. But, again, they'll
be at DEF CON hopefully next
year talking about some of the
stuff they brought because
that's part of the deal. In
terms of timeline, we just
started this up in February,
besides San Francisco, you know,
we've really been kind of
spinning things up pretty
slowly. We don't want to have a
situation where we say every
researcher on Earth get involved
in this. We're not trying to
have the largest list of people.
We're trying to have the most
output and the most production.
And sometimes you have to kind
of do the walk before you run.
So far so good. We actually just
in July shipped hardware from
Pinoccio to two of our
researchers. So that's kind of
our first line in the sand that
hey we accomplished something
that we were trying to
accomplish. And we have a lot
more coming out for the next few
months, and we'll be bringing
for researchers on. We have
contact details at the end if
you want to look at some of
that. Pinoccio has got the
hardware. Bugcrowd is setup for
our vendors at this point. We're
still kind of doing some of the
stuff that we all deal with
already which is like timelines,
triage, when the bugs have to
get fixed, when we going to drop
bugs and is the kind of stuff
that any kind of coordinator
goes through when you do this
sort of process. And we're
growing. It's not about having
the most people on our website,
but it's about having the most
people getting shit done and
associated with us, which is
something that our vendors have
taken kindly to. They don't want
to have you throwing 300 people
at them because it's hard for
vendors that don't have security
in-house to understand how to
work with vendors. So we're
actually doing a lot of
knowledge transfer and teaching
vendors in this space, what kind
of research it is, how it works,
why people do it, and why we're
at DEF CON in the first place.
>> So what does it all mean?
What's the conclusion? So
basically what we've learned is
that people can actually be
altruistic occasionally. There
is a lot of cynicism, but
sometimes people can suspend
that or actually erase it
entirely and, and don't be
afraid to actually reach out to
people, and vice-versa. Don't be
afraid -- we would encourage
like collaboration. We want
people to want to do this. We
want this to be a community
effort so we can have an impact.
That's why we've partnered with
like I Am The Cavalry, for
instance, because this kind of
falls in line with some of the
stuff that they're doing. It
gives us visibility and gets
them resources. Of course, we
did have some aggressive goals
initially, but we've stepped
back and kind of made it a
little more comfortable. Doubled
the timeline, basically. Since a
lot of the researchers are doing
this, you know, pro bono, they
are doing this, they get the
benefit of business, they are
doing it for us. Pro bono,
they're pretty busy, they have
day jobs, so do we. So this is
also us kind of taking spare
cycles and working on this
project. And, again, like Mark
said we want quality, not
quantity. We want more people to
be involved, but we want to make
sure that everyone is kind of on
the same page and everyone is
going to be able to relax into
this. And measured successes and
milestones. So far we have done
pretty well in hitting some
pretty significant milestones.
They might not be significant to
a lot of people in the grand
scheme of things, but it's
definitely accelerating to where
we want to be. So IoT is still
malleable enough. This is still
enough space that we can
actually have an impact versus
like some other spaces like --
web security has been solved or
some shit, but you know, we're
not going to have there is some
shit, but we don't have to shoe
horn this into everything else.
IoT we can make a difference now
before it comes catastrophic.
This could also help consumers
make better decisions as well.
If they see not so much an
underwriters laboratory-type of
thing but something similar, it
would give consumers a, sort of
a yardstick to say, oh, this is
been vetted, this vendor cares
and people can decide with their
wallet, right? So if nothing
else, if this goes haywire. We
helped vendors and got
researchers to do doing cool
stuff. At the end of the day,
that's not bad. So the site is
BuildItSecure.ly. You can also
reach -- there's a mailing list.
I think we actually did mention,
the mailing list, the thing
about that we have our vendors,
our partners and the researchers
on the same mailing list. So
there is no silo, and talk bad
about this vendor over here.
That created a nice open
communication, if there is a
question, someone says I'm going
to be deploying firmware XYZ do
you want to help me. So there is
no silanization. So with that I
think we have a couple of
minutes left if there are any
questions. Otherwise you can
meet us in the chill out lounge
afterwards. [Applause] >> And,
and thanks.