>>We have another short talk and
then one more long one and
Andrew here is clearly going to
do another live demo so wave the
rubber chicken in the air and
say the incantations so that
nothing breaks and he'll talk to
us about this rad little Verizon
unit he has here. Give him a big
Party Track welcome. (Applause)
>> Thank you very much, My name
is Andrew Hunt and I'm currently
a graduate student at George
Mason University and also work
at Pac. Tel. So shout out to my
peeps here. Thank you. Standard
disclosure, what I'm doing here
is my own personal work, not
necessarily the views of my
employer. But, it's fun stuff so
let's talk more about it. 	So
the moCA alliance was formed by
a bunch of large companies that
got together and said we have
all this great copper in
people's houses that we have
installed about 30 years of
cable, and they wanted to find a
way to use this as they were
moving into the age of the
triple play, being able to
deliver video, voice, and data
over this network. Copper
carries electrons a long way
because it's shielded and it's
got to a pretty nice insulation
there. 	They developed a PHY and
max specifications so that they
would be able to do that, so
that they would be able to
process package to basically
turn your coaxial bus in your
house into a network. The key
point of this is they wanted to
deliver guaranteed bandwidth
because this is what video
requires. So that's pretty much
what MoCA looks like, it's in
your house, it's coaxial cable,
everyone knows what it is. This
is what it looks like a little
bit. They use, at the PHY level
they are using signaling
division -- frequency,
divisional multiplexing. I found
this graphic on Wikipedia but it
actually works really well, for
what they are doing with MoCA
and dividing it into two
channels. There's a WAN channel
and a LAN channel, two operate
at two different frequencies but
standard. 	They use this to be
able to talk with the router and
also to have the router talk to
other devices on the coax. On
top of that, they overlay a,
well, thank you! -- (Laughter)
So. 	>> Woo-hoo! (Cheers and
applause) 	>> Somebody has done
the research, this is pretty
good shit. 	 The Mac layer
basically over these channels
are dividing it up by time so
they can create variable length
frames which means that they can
encapsulate things in them and
that could be video which has
very big frames and also
Ethernet packets, Ethernet
frames, they will encapsulate as
well. Running at the standard
100 megabits per second PHY they
can guarantee a sustained rate
of 54.6 5 megabits per second.
Consider what your typical
Ethernet looks like and
collisions are going that's
actually very good for 100
megabit rate. They're
everywhere. Everywhere you see a
DVR setup box, everywhere you
see these routers here, they are
using MoCA. Which means that it
is a great exposure. It's
everywhere. 	You'll typically
see these enter the home through
something call wall works on the
outside of your house. This is
the one outside of my house
that's opened up but there are
different ones. You might have a
smaller one if you have a cable
provider that's bringing it in.
It won't have this big optical
network terminator but basically
just a splitter that splits off
to the rest of your house.
That's a good point of entry.
On the inside you have this
router so every cable company
gives you some kind of a router
to parse up these streams and
packetize them. Read the packets
they are sending to you and push
it out over the network. They
typically have a SBI firewall to
divide the inside from the
outside as is standard network
security practice. 	They also
have on the left side of this
little picture -- uh-oh -- on
the left side of this little
picture they've got the coax
binder there, the plug but it
actually carries two MoCA nodes,
called network connected --
we'll talk about that later.
They also provide a
MoCA-Ethernet bridge on both of
those nodes that basically
allows them to encapsulate the
frames onto the coax. So, they
now turned your nice coax bus in
your house into a large Ethernet
system. 	This supports your
digital Video recorder so your
DVR requires time, you have to
be able to schedule shows and
find out when everything is.
That's the prime function of
having Ethernet on that, to be
able to tell when to record your
functions. 	So, yes, sir?
(Laughter) 	>> May I borrow
podium for a second. 	>> All
right. 	>> If you are a new
speaker, raise your hand.
Awesome! [Cheers and applause]
Are you familiar with this
tradition? 	>> No, I'm not. 	>>
Really? Do you drink? 	>> Yes, I
do. 	>> He brought his own. 	>>
You just -- you provide it for
me. 	>> Every new speaker at DEF
CON, see, they know this, how do
you not know this, every new
speaker does a shot onstage. 	>>
Okay. 	>> How about love for our
new speaker? (Applause) 	>>
Great. Congratulations, quick
shoutout from the guys at
Whiskey Pirates that gave me
this. Pretty awesome. I see we
have a pirate in the audience.
>> Tell him how you got it. 	>>
He chained him to a radiator and
had their way with him.
(Laughter) 	>> Some kind of
pirate. (Laughter) 	>> Thank
you. 	>> Okay, so what just
happened here, let's go back one
slide. What this is doing, this
is action tech is bridging your
Ethernet and coaxial bus which
means if you have a coaxial
splitter as most of you do
somewhere around the house that
splitter is carrying not only
the WAN traffic that is supposed
to be going out to the biosfeed
but also carrying your LAN
traffic on a different channel.
If you notice on the left you
have a MoCA LAN, Ethernet LAN
and wireless LAN. The action
tech router bridges those
together and most of the do.
That just makes it easier to
manage the notes on the device
so you can see everything, nice
big happy broadcast network.
Same domain. 	It's great!
Except, oops. You can take over
all three networks by plugging
into that splitter. If that
splitters happens to be outside
your house, as this gadget
diagram depicts, but is also
similar to the Cox, Comcast and
Verizon default installation
guides for field technicians,
they want it on the outside of
the house because it's easy to
maintain and install. 	So now
that we know the LAN is exposed,
just walk in and plug in. All we
need are a couple items, things
we usually locate here at the
utility point of presence so all
I have to do is walk around some
houses and look for the utility
pole, on the outside of your
house look for the electrics
box. Yes. 	>> Drink! 	>> Yay!
(Pause) (Applause) 	>> All
right. So you'll need a couple
items and you'll be able to go
on this fishing adventure. A
MoCA Ethernet bridge. Mine is
net gear MCAB 1001 and then
you'll need some RG6 coax cable
and a greater than one GHz
splitter line, line splitter.
Plug that in, I had to color
invert this picture because it
was almost impossible to see if
you were just taking a picture.
I had to invert it to see that
x-ray image. It's hard to see
when it has cover. Which is
great for us! 	The action tech
LAN does not also engage any of
the encryption features provided
by the MoCA protocol. It does
have a -- I believe it's 40-bit
key DEZ that is a pre-shared key
but you can code into it. It is
used on the WAN side of the
connection that has the key that
Verizon knows but it's not on
the LAN side. It's open, clear,
hey, works with everything
because it's consumer-friendly.
So basically what happens you
had a MoCA device on the outside
of the house, it connects to
your action tech router, your
action tech router says hey and
lets you on the Ethernet. Pretty
awesome. 	So as y'all have seen
this since 2001, typical
Ethernet line of attack, this is
your normal traffic flow but I
really don't want you to go that
way, I want you to come to me
first and I'm going to do unholy
things to your traffic. 	So I
think we have belabored this
point. What could possibly go
wrong? We all know what can go
wrong. We have known about it
for a decade. 	Yeah, whatever.
Take the device, take it over
and get the more persistent
presence. One of my co-workers
actually brought up to me and
says but I'm protected. I have
this MoCA filter. So MoCA
filters are great, they
physically block the MoCA ranges
in the bandwidth. What they are
designed for is blocking these
signals between one house and
another. So you can't block it
within your own house otherwise
your DVR won't work. So it has
to be located on the egress of
the splitter that they are using
to provide the cable signal to
your house. That's usually on
the outside of the house. But
even if it's not it's usually
not in a place where you could
divide the inside of the house
from the outside of your house
because if there's any cable
exposed that is carrying your
internal connection all you have
to do is splice it and you're
done. 	So, great idea but it's
not going to work for this
particular purpose. 	So, the
idea here is to be able to build
a disposable attack unit. So
yeah, we can walk up but yeah,
someone is going to find that
lap top. So we built a
disposable attack unit that is
small, that can hide under a
bush and lasts forever, and
allow you to walk away and go do
your evil. To illustrate this,
you have some requirements. You
have to have some point of --
some way of providing power. You
have to be able to physically
insert or demonstrate with that
is and you have to have some
type of compute device to
execute these attacks. Once it's
installed you have to be able to
access it and then commit some
type of attack, redirection and
manipulation. 	The objectives of
this is do no harm so first of
all, I'm really just here to
demonstrate the problem, but you
know I'm sure people out there
could take it to the enth
degree. Want to use some
standard tools. We do not want
to expose ourselves by showing
everyone our latest and greatest
coating techniques and be
profiled and arrested. We want
to use common stuff that
everybody has. Needs to be
updateable so we can a few
change things, or add new tools.
Needs to be disposable, so we
don't care if we lose it. That
basically means it has to be
cheap and has to be small and
not too powerful, because if it
is too powerful it will burn up
all our battery before we have
even gotten home. So, some
ingredients I just recently
purchased these gorilla 16 800
milla amp batteries, got two of
them on woot. Thank you woot.
Smaller than a paperback book, I
used two of these because I have
two because I have two different
draws on my units. MoCA draws
one amp and the raspberry unit
draws half an amp and that's a
little more than this can put
out on one battery so I need two
batteries. 	I also used the
raspberry pie, Model B. Has an
ARM 11 processor. It's a little
bit slow but doesn't consume too
much power, can last 18 hours on
this battery and it's cheap, so
if somebody finds it go buy
another one, buy 10. 	So Kali
Linux has a distribution that
works amazingly well with
raspberry pie and the ARM
distribution, thank you, guys,
for that contribution to this
field. It's awesome. Has all the
necessary tools you need pearl
python and also squid Apache and
mini PUMP. Let's talk about that
later. 	It also supports the
universal plug and play IGDE
protocol which is available on
the action tech firewall and
then you'll also need the
Ethernet bridge. I bring this
picture up, I don't know if you
can see it down there but the
original MCAB mockup that I did
before I modified it had a -plug
that you had to plug into an AC
adapter in order to provide
power. Looking at the back it
was 5 volt, one amp which means
that it is within the USB
specification for power draw.
So, a little hardware hacking
later and soldering up and you
have a USB power cable for the
MCAB. I recommend it because
then you can provide it direct
off battery. I was originally
trying to do this work with the
APCUPS. Only lasted about six
hours and it beeped a lot. I
didn't think that would be very
good for hiding it from
attackers, outside of someone's
home if they were looking for
the freaky beeping. Also this
nasty habit of shutting things
down before I was done with it,
I'd get about halfway through
the battery and say oh my God
I'm out of power and shut it
off. These batteries are a real
God send. They came out in the
last couple years, they are
really great. There is no loss
of conversion from DC to AC to
DC, there is just direct power
which means they lasts longer.
So on each of these devices
MCAD adapter I've got about 14
hours of up time so that's about
how long you've got to commit
whatever you are going to do.
For those who can't see it on
stage, this is what it looks
like, a bunch of rubber bands
and duct tape. But, it's dark,
you can spray paint it and hide
it under a bush and no one will
see it. Word about universal
plug-and-play, I know this is
kind of beleaguered by GRC and
other sources but it enables,
it's a PMP protocol that enables
Gateway manipulation, the action
tech supports this. Basically it
allows, everything talks to
everything and says hey I'm an
iPhone, hey I'm a printer, let's
talk, right. Downside is also
hey I'm a router, you want a
firewall port opened, let me do
that for you. 	So I borrowed an
idea from Joshua Wright, his
scripts for doing image high
jinks with the I Love My
Neighbors distribution. I
borrowed those from him, did
modification and some batch
scripting and now we have a nice
little device that will go and
punch holes in firewalls from
the inside. 	Mini PMP is
basically what we use here,
PMPCA, tell it to forward 22 to
myself and send a nice little
report to my e-mail address and
tell me what my internal and
external IP and port are. This
might be a little hard to read
for you guys but basically you
will turn on your engine. You
are going redirect web streams
and then to you'll manipulate
that stream. So, let's see if it
actually works. (Pause) All
right. Nope. (Pause) All right.
There is my MoCA device there.
63... Aww, it doesn't like my
key. (Pause) (Laughter) 	>> You
want me to get through this demo
or you want me to drink? 	>>
Drink! 	(Laughter) 	>> While
this is loading up, I'll take a
drink. Okay, that's on and now
we have to do one more thing.
What that's doing is going
through its sequence. I owe you
a drink. (Cheers and applause)
The sequence it was doing, it's
just going through and doing the
normal networking stuff, it's
also engaging over the MoCA
network which is then going to
poison the action tech router.
If you want to play along, get
laptops out and want to connect.
The access point password is
testing 123 testing 123 SSID is
testing. So, go ahead and play
with me. I don't see any takers!
{{(Pause) We are getting to the
end here. It's going through the
set up sequences. It's going to
engage the squid engine and web
server, it basically provides
the redirects and squid proxy is
going to redirect to pearl which
is going to do the re-writing of
the sequence to provide the
re-directs. Okay. So let's get
through. While that's going on I
can go ahead and show you this.
So you enumerate the redirects,
it's not there yet, that one has
failed. Oh, there it is. So you
can see there are all kinds of
redirects from things like
Microsoft, they've got all kinds
of protocol in there that they
contracted to get on the action
tech. But you can see here this
is my PP and C this is my port
forward for my SSH to my router.
So that can be reached through
the Internet and then want to go
for it, give it a go! All right.
There we go, somebody is on here
and they are getting redirected
around and if we try it, so we
can stop them... (Pause) Look at
that! It went somewhere else.
Can't see it. There we go. So
anyway, not too exciting but the
entire point of this
demonstration is to show the
MoCA network is exposed to the
outside of your house, anyone
can walk up with no keys, can
walk up and take over your
network and do whatever unholy
thing they want to do with you.
So I just have a couple wrap-up
slides and then we're out.
(Applause) So basically some
results from this research, the
arm 11 is single core, low power
drive, but it's also kind of
pokey. If you actually do use
this, don't try to do any image
processing it will show itself
very quickly but it's great for
injects, redirects, and things
like display. So tested it with
my network at home, it has about
a dozen devices on it, works
just fine. So it's cheap. It's
disposable. It's quick delivery.
Walk up to a house and install
this in less than 2 minutes walk
back to your car and drive away
and you have all afternoon to do
what you're going to do. Allows
you to find a more permanent
back door. So what do we need to
do about this? You need to talk
to your ISP, tell them you want
them to allow their devices to
support better encryption, since
the DVR tends to break when you
turn on encryption on that local
LAN. The ID do not want IGD, you
want disable turned off whatever
because you can't turn it off.
It's a Daemon and you can't
disable it. You want them to
stop bridging all your networks
together on the same domain and
actually have it route so you
can do something with it instead
of having it just lave
everywhere. 	Customer should
demand this, you guys should
demand this. Ongoing work on
this, we want detect these MoCA
injections, people installing
these devices, we want to be
able to alert on insertion, but
something better, you could it
and see the poisoning that's
going on here but you can't see
the MoCA side of it. You want to
be able to see that. We're
currently working with a
gentleman named Steven Barani,
he is a fellow grad student of
mine and we're working on a
product called Slim and then
integrating that into another
raspberry unit that will face
off with this one called counter
pie and hopefully able we'll be
able to demonstrate that soon.
Thank you. (Applause)