>>I'm here to talk about
Dropping Docs on Darknets. How
people got caught and talk about
some things about the history,
various people who have been
using tour or sometimes
itemizing systems and have
gotten busted still, in all of
these cases, none of it was tour
directly, all bad  ‑ ‑ all, I'll
cover what they screwed up. To
save a little time, how many of
you have been to my website?
Okay, fair enough. My name is
Adrian Crenshaw, I am likely to
get something wrong, like if you
ask me about the newest relay
that people are talking about
with tour I'm only this much up
on it, so I probably contact get
it for you but I'm interested in
learning on it. I'm also senior
information security consultant,
and they were kind enough to fly
me out here and also a cofounder
of derby con. Executive general
warning I'm taking this from two
perspectives how to keep people
anonymous and how to be
anonymous people, I want
anonymized, I think all secrets
should be known if would
probably be a better place but
people with more power are
better at keeping secrets than
others. But I'm interested in
like I chest game, how to keep
it, it's just an intellectual
interest for me. I am not a
lawyer, some of the things I'm
going to talk about is legal
stuff, any legal advice I give
is not legal invoice in the
definition of legal advice. If
something has the word I
understand in it several times
it means that they know that
they're lying but they don't
want to be called on it. I don't
like lawyers, if there was such
a thing, I believe I have one,
so I won't say I never need one.
Anyway, be careful what you say,
most of the people out there I
think are techno meanies like me
to just like encryption bull
some people are university
administrators, but groups do
exist that are bad, so be
careful where you web certain,
if you do E certain, I highly
recommend automatically
downloading. Let's just say I
have a friend of mine who is in
research, I this is his flame is
Bob who actually to give a talk
at DEF CON on dark notes and he
was looking through this and
there was a picture of himself
right next to a bunch of child
porn, because there are some
disturbed people out there, so
be careful where you surf, but
most of the stuff I think is
fairly innocent. We're going to
talk about how it works. Tour'
is sometimes referred to as a
dark net and it uses proxies and
multiple levels in description.
I like the term cyberspace, I
think it sounds cool and dark
net means something different.
That's a piece of IT space to
say that anybody who is touching
it, we know it has to be
illegitimate, so we shun them,
it has two meanings, that's why
like dark net better. This is
the onion router, the most
popular one out there. It
doesn't have as big a base as
tour does. This started off as a
Navy research project back in
the day, eventually, the EFF
took over and then it became
it's own 5013 C. This is for
privacy, this is so you can surf
the web and not have you know
who you are than host something
and not be able to shut it down.
They can cost it via a hidden
service, hidden services don't
have a website, they can be
other hidden service, anything
old thing cull do over TCP. But
mostly with the anonymous sites,
we are talking about Human
Services in this talk but how
you access it, you have a proxy
in your local machine and you
can put in web browsers to it
and it just generally functions
all the time, hopefully. It's
hard to get that configured
right if you do it from your own
browser, which is why extremely
recommend that you use the tour
browser bundle that has all of
this for you. But yeah like I
said before it's layers of
encryption. The data you send
out is the same way, I say that
here because some other dark
nets are different, you're out
tunnels and in tunnels can be
different, but tour is basically
bidirectional. It has directory
service which can be a simple
point of failure, but it used
distributed hash tables for some
of the hidden service stuff, I
need to look at the tech manual
more to understand where they
use which one for what. A few
years back, the serves kept a
lot of people from accessing
tour directly, so they need to
use some sort of tour bridge
node, but it is generally come
posed of multiple levels of
encryption. What they do is they
have three levels of encryption,
one first of the first who that
gets stripped off, there's
another one inside of that which
is the second who then another
one for the third hop, at that
point, the exit point which is
that last node decrypts and send
it is on. It's still going to be
encrypted but the people in that
exit point can see the traffic
they're sniffing about using
HTTL, they can see that stuff.
This is different, say you want
to the host something, I want to
start up a site, Polyester Road
because I'm going to sell zoot
suits, from like the '70s for
like lounge lizards, so I wanted
to go ahead. I'm Bob, I want to
stat Polyester Road, I can send
that to the DB and have it known
what my points are and that's
advertising for my onion
address, usually it's semi
random, it's mostly random, you
can brute force and make it kind
of an especially signed name if
you want. Have you ever been
Slick Road's website, the first
few characters, there is a way
to brute force and assign a name
that you want close to but you
can't do the entire thing
because it's a little bit too
long for you to do it. The GPU
systems are coming out with
those names. Alice finds out
about the it, she finds out the
introduction point, and she sets
the boundary point so that Bob
can talk back to her, sends that
information to introduction
points and they can start
talking about how they're going
to communicate and eventually
set up a channel and start
moving data back and forth. I
know I'm going through this all
of fast, but really it's better
to read the website on how to
works, but we both agree who
we're going to anonymously, and
hosting it and people don't know
who is hosting it and that's a
good idea. There is node ideas
in tour, they're just general
clients that use tour, these
relays and these are people who
hand traffic on to the next
person but they're not
necessarily exit point where is
it sometimes get tricky, in the
United States, it's legal to
have an exit point, Austria had
some problems because contraband
was going across, but you can
get exit points meaning bad
stuff is going through the
system? You generally are not at
fault for it. There's always
bridges, remember I mentioned
those directory services before
that shut down, bridges are
basically core nodes that are
not advertised in the directory,
so the only reason you can get
them is think of the pathway or
the website and they would email
you certain bridges they could
use. The idea is none of the
bridges are listed in one place
so you can get on if you can't
get on the directly, that was
the idea of the berms and
they're slightly more trusted
nodes for the first hop. It
might be your first hop and your
last hop and if I'm watching
traffic I can kind of figure out
who you are. And this is a guy
not giving a talk now, they were
doing a type of  ‑ ‑ if I
understand what I read about it,
they were adding some tags to
the data. But the guard node, I
don't know how the process for
that worked but they could
become more than one
[indiscernible] if you can
control multiple nodes in the
networks you can [indiscernible]
there are also introduction
points which I mentioned other
points, you get a web browser,
you get tour up and run, you use
the tour browser bundle, you
download it, unzip it and just
use it, set up your own tour
service, it's more complex, I
have links in slides, I have a
three‑ hour class I did, and it
covers the same thing in ITP.
Okay. Applications, there's tons
of stuff out there, I wasn't to
give a quick shout out to tails,
tails is essentially a live CD,
you can also do it
[indiscernible] that there's a
lost things add‑ ons to tour
that make it more secure, and
since the plug‑ ins are not
going to be there, other
authorizations, generally, every
time you sit down to start, that
kind of thing, it's what you do
as long as you get the memory
fast enough, you are generally
okay. Do you know what a code
rude attack, if they can hit you
hard enough and past enough,
they can pull memory out, they
pull it out and mount it and
suck off all the data, if they
do that fast enough, they can
[indiscernible] so the amount of
time it takes is probably  ‑ ‑
it would probably be okay. And
we're talking anti‑ forensics,
also. You don't want to look it
up, trust me. This other tool
that is out there scallion, if
you look at the silk roads one,
I think I have this up, they
brute forced the part of it, oh,
crud, I don't have  ‑ ‑ let me
bring this up real  ‑ ‑ yeah.
Notice how they brute forced the
first part of it because they
actually have Silk Road as one
of the characters but the rest
is random. I have to mention the
security concern because it
lessens the [indiscernible] but
will be able to tell you better,
but let's get back to the
slides. But there are always
tools out there, if you want to
know more about hidden services,
go visit the public Internet
site on onions where you will
find various ones lited. There
are pros and cons, a big pro is
anything you can do here you can
make it work, like this over
tour perfectly feasible and
three levels of proxy, it gives
you a lot of anonymity, the
downside it it's slow, a lot
footer than it used toking but
yet never going to be as fast as
just using the public Internet,
it can't be. Because you have
all of these extra hops you are
going into. You have to trust
your exit node, they didn't want
the country they were in to spy
and you want to get out of the
country, without the French
people spying on you, you might
use tour but using the top 3
without encryption, whatever
your exit point is it's going to
be sniffing your traveling and
people did things like that and
I mentioned the great fire wall
of China blocking 80% of the
relays a while back and so those
were all issues but it is the
biggest point [indiscernible].
Before all right. What does the
traffic look like? Ports for
your proxies and you're using
manual rapport, using your tour
browser bundle, this is a hidden
service, use the tour browser
bundle or tail. Usually, there
are some 80, I'm not sure if
that's still current, there's a
lot more detail on my website
and there are ways you can
detect it also, saying is this
IP address part of tour, part of
tour directory, you can query
them and find out. There's a
little onion icon in the top
left‑ hand corner instead of the
normal one. Oh quick shout out
to ITP I don't know if anybody
got busted on it, not because
it's more secure but it's used
less, and having different
people doing different kinds of
research in this kind of
community is important I think
and that's another big player
out there, tour pretty much is
the 800‑ pound grill gorilla
when it comes to dark net. There
is a Goon named Bob and he gives
a great talk, Bob Rice on bit
point, so I recorded it once, go
check that one out but
essentially, by the coin is a
quick currency that is used for
proof of work, this is not bit
coin work, but this is proof of
work to you. It really came up
as a way of stopping spam, let's
say the idea is if you want to
send me a message, you've got to
do some work before you can
extend to me, this way if you're
a spammer it's going to
discourage you, I'm not
discouraged from sending emails
but if it takes more than a
second for spam to calculate it
slows them down massively from
being able to use spam
campaigns, so an example is this
one for most security people.
This is really fast to take a
password and patch it to of to
the hash value, however taking a
hash value and turning it back
into the password is much more
difficult, so a proof of work
example might be you can only
send an email to me if you boat
force my password it's a 4
character password and here's my
hash and a four character
password you should be able to
do that fast but it's still a
little time and it's not a
nuisance, but it might be to
others, by the coin uses a
similar kind of system of proof
of work, also in big blocks that
they communicate through passing
on bit coins to say I now
assigned these bit coins I own
to this particular address. But
watch Bob's talk on it, it's a
innate, if you want to send
stuff anonymously, it's the way
to go. There are alternate stuff
out there, like doggy coin and I
don't know how many others. But
check out Bob Rice's talk
sometime. I burned through that
in 12 minutes because want to
get to the good stuff.
Basically, we're talking about
how people got deanonymized, and
the first thing I want to talk
about is the Harvard bomb
threat. Here's what he said,
there is a bomb placed in the
science center, 204, be quick or
they'll go off seen. He sent
this on December  16th. Well,
they had to figure out who this
guy was. Apparently, he used his
gorilla mail. I sent my own
message using gorilla mail and
one thing it does is it uses
your originating IP address,
that's not mine, I modified it
some, but it can originate
[indiscernible], so Let's say
you did it from home, your IP
address would be in that mail
and you can look in the header
this guy did use tour, it had a
server IP address, that was a
step in the right direction, of
course. However, all nodes are
public and it's easy to figure
out is this machine tour or not,
you just look it up, and you
justifying out if it was a node
a lot of times they have tour in
the name of them, so it's easy
to correlate who was attacking.
Well, what they did is they
looked to see who was using tour
during the time that the email
was sent. And they found this
one particular individual, now
this guy had been using a
bridge, but [indiscernible] it
would have been advertising
directly he probably would have
got away with it but if he just
walked to the local coffee shop
and used tour he probably would
have gotten away with it
however, he used it through the
university network. He was one
of the few people on tour at the
time, I don't know what Harvard
does with anonymity, but he was
using tour but when he found out
he was one of them, he admitted
to everything and apparently he
put to the in to get out of a
final, and so he sent that in
just to get out of a final. Oh
well, more details, there's
great write ups, also, court
documents out, these slides by
the wear are very close to the
exact version should be on your
DEF CON and I have them online.
>> [Off mic]. >> And he did it
from  ‑ ‑ well, the Harvard
network, I think maybe his dorm
room, I don't remember the exact
location. >> [Off mic]. >> Yes.
>> [Off mic]. >> So lesson
learned from this, don't be the
only person using tour at a
given time, use the bridge, if
you had used the bridge,
probably wouldn't have been
caught. Don't admit anything.
That would have gone a long way.
And correlation attack or bitch
and we'll talk more about a
correlation attack here in a
second. Essentially what a
correlation attack is you watch
the traffic and see what's going
on. Everything is encrypted but
if you see a 5 Meg request,
which would be a big request but
still and then go out and you
watch this node and this node,
you can tell these two are evil,
especially are the goatee, Ralph
looks like my evil computer, but
anyway, these guys were sniffing
it, so this one and this one,
this was a similar attack,
someone controls both of those
nodes and he says I saw 5 meg
come in this way and out that
way and I saw a 8 meg come back,
see go out that way, come back
this way and you can see them
both. Now, grant, the encryption
there, the message don't look
the same because they have extra
crypto keys in the middle, I'm
pointing here, why am I doing
that? Yeah, like this guy right
here. So I mean, the traffic
doesn't look the same, it's
different feeds but this was
actually the size and the timing
of it they have a good idea that
this might be who it is. Now, in
this case, the correlation
attack was who was using tour at
that particular time. Timing
correlation might be similar.
Pain in my buttocks! All right.
Let's see if this crash again or
not I'll get myself together
here. Shift F 5. Macintosh.
Okay. So that was the attack I
was mentioning before just
looking at traffic. There is
also the timing attacks that can
be possibly done based on when
the traffic is coming through
and there's been some work on
people trying to DDOS part of
the network to know I've DOS'd
that and I can put  ‑ ‑ well, if
I can force certain patterns in
the traffic, you might be able
to recognize that. (Lost audio).
Company, let's see. No, history
buff, no. >> [Off mic]. >> They
had this party called Molanear,
and it's a document that is a
little bit like this, called an
expert tracker along the way so
you can kind of modify and put a
pattern to the data, I could be
misreading it. Somebody from
NSA, if they want to talk it me
about it, I would love to hear.
>> [Off mic]. >> Just saying the
little hat here. All right.
Another thing, this is not
[indiscernible] remember how I
mentioned how sometimes you can
really screw it up if you set up
the browser itself, if you set
up tour in Firefox itself not
using the browser bundle, there
is a setting that says use it
over the proxy, when you query
polyester road.onion, they want
see the traffic but they will
see that you are trying to go to
that particular site, that's why
if are you going to set up
yourself, you have to do
something like proxy relay DNS
but the tour browser by default
does that. They can see who
you're trying to visit based on
the DNS queries. Okay. Next
case. You remember this from a
couple of years ago, right?
Hector Xavier Monsignor, I'm
going to call him Boo because
that is easier to remember. He
got lazy one time and he got
himself caught and started to
collaborate with people so he
wouldn't go to job. Last I
heard, he got off exactly now, I
think he's home free at that
point, but anyway, he didn't use
tour consistently, eventually,
they found him, and I don't
understand some of these people
that do this, why don't you use
ITP, and you can do it all over
anonymous networks, because even
if you use a cloaking, a cloak
that hides your IP address from
other people doing things, it
still is a problem because the
person who owns the service
might look into your IP address
and figure out who you are.
There is actually a guy to lives
in great Britain who was part of
the anonymous movement at one
time and he got pissed off at
other people and he was on one
of the IRC servers so he started
dumping the IP addresses. So if
you are using ITP and IRC, he
probably wouldn't have got
caught. He was speaking with
such G, ends up it's Jeremy
Hammond, but they didn't know
that at the time. And Jeremy had
been arrested or detained
before, and various political
groups he was involved with and
they got a general idea for
where in the world he lived and
this narrowed down the suspect
pool a whole lot and they
finally got enough evidence to
be able to get  ‑ ‑ well, the
marker was in the access.
Because I was doing things like
I was involved with the people,
doing some of the things that he
said made it very clear that he
lived in the Midwest and there
are only so many people that fit
those kinds of qualities and
already have a record, so they
were able to narrow it down.
Now, he did use tour
consistently, from the records I
read and he was never busted but
this were able to use
essentially time and sequential
time and correlation attacks to
figure out he was always online
at the same time Hammond was and
talking when [indiscernible] was
talking to [indiscernible] he
was in his residence. They were
able to figure out well, seems
likely that it is indeed him. A
lot more details and technical
articles, but there's a few
lessons from this one. Lessons
learned: Use tour consistently,
if you use it part of the time
that's going to cause a problem.
Back in the day when you had to
configure it for yourself, one
thing that was really cool to do
is get the cookies in tour, when
you disconnect tour you go back
and visit the site against
without tour, you see that
cookie and you know who that
was. I have a future on my
website that does that. If you
are using tour browser, it's
going to clear out that history
every time you shut it down. But
yeah, if you use tour
consistently, don't give out a
lot of personal information,
don't release a bunch of stuff
about these are the people I'm
languaging out with, these are
the people I'm involved in.
Also, correlation tactic is
still a bitch, because when he
was online versus when he was
talking to Boo, they figured out
who he was. Case No.  2, by the
way, the cases that kind of
stick out, I'm following the
program standard of 0. So Case
No.  2, freedom hosting. Now,
freedom hosting is a company
that basically allowed people
to  ‑ ‑ hosting services inside
of tour so they didn't have to
set their own boxes for hidden
services and they would
basically use these people but
they hosted a lot of different
things amongst them some child
porn related services, not the
only thing they were about but
some of the stuff they had, they
also had length mat stuff like
tour mail, but that's as to you
have the stuff that particular
group ran. Because of the whole
posting the child porn anonymous
had an opp document where they
were attacking them and trying
to hack the websites and I think
at one point they dumped a bunch
of information about who was
using them. Just because
anonymous doesn't mean the web
application isn't vulnerable,
and that's how they dumped a
bunch of accounts from them.
What is that? >> Oh. >> Oh, on
July  13th, the FBI found the
hosting boxes and decided to
insert some malicious Java
script. And it existed in
Firefox, version 17, extended
service release, and a recent
version of tour browser win
doughs happened to be using that
particular version of Firefox so
it was vulnerable, now tour had
only updated the panel, if all
of the people had updated by
that time they wouldn't have
gotten caught because they
weren't involved in this but
some people don't if you date in
a timely fashion, so they had
this vulnerability, and they
installed this malware, they
installed Magnito, and it was a
service in Virginia, and it
would host the public IP
address, some of the content you
see, Mac addresses they were
pointed that can narrow it down
to your machine, the windows
host name and in the site visit.
This one is kind of similar to
[indiscernible] Snowden
documents, coming across the
egotistical direct project, this
is a beautiful name, I don't
think it's exactly the same
exploit though. They exploit but
not entirely the same project
with the FBI, because I don't
think the United States
collaborated that much. There's
a lot of cases in the past of
law enforcement doing something
similar like getting malware
getting installed on machines
and track them and see what
they're up to. There was a NSA
project, GB 8, what is great
Britain equivalent's to the NSA?
I may get this wrong so just
pointing it out and if I get it
wrong let me know after the
talk. And CPAB is another
example, Joe gave a talk that
was really good, unfortunately,
it was not recorded, so if you
ever get to talk with him go
check that out. He might even be
here at DEF CON. The first time
I met him was at DEF CON 2009.
Anyway, freedom hosting, the box
you will be able to take malware
off the machines, and you can
Figure out who is hosting or who
the head guy is in charge of
hosting and it ended up being
this Marquez. They always traced
him down because of the way he
made the payment. Once they
compromised the box and realized
this is the IP address, they
found out who was actually
leasing the box and this tied
him to it pretty quick. Now,
when they busted him he is said
to have diced for his laptop to
shut it down. If the machine was
shut down, it has full hub drive
in description, you don't beat
it mathematically, you beat it
through limitation or rubber
host cryptography, he apparently
though didn't get to it fast
enough. A lot more details in an
article on it. Lessons learns
from this one: Don't host
[indiscernible] that's one
thing. You're not
[indiscernible] in culture are
you Beshear is jail bit, captain
card, CP, child porn, actually,
I gave a talk a few years back,
at a security forum, it was some
ISA appoint and I gave a talk on
anonymous, they are one cohesive
group, for home to want to go
and do a particular thing and I
used a bunch of in culture
terminology, things that are
offensive, people who do it for
the lulls and control people, so
I was using in term  ‑ ‑ in
culture terminology and in think
what he said about me not
getting invited about is I
wonder if [indiscernible] talk
was well researched and it was
wholly inappropriate, if you get
to know the guy, okay, maybe it
was some what true. The next
thing you can learn, patch patch
patch. If these people had have
kept up their patches, they
would have been fine and dandy.
I don't think they put the
warning at the time, now if you
have an outdated version, you
will see a warning next to the
onion that says, there's a newer
version out you should really
update, I don't think they were
doing that at the time. Is
anybody here from tour project
here? I guess they can't answer
that question now. I don't I
think they were doing that at
the time. Also, my standing is
they tied the server to him via
how he paid for them. and
leaving encrypted laptops
powered down when not in reviews
would have helped a lot. This is
some kind of web vulnerability,
let's say they had an injection,
if you can connect to it, send
your exploit to it, even if it's
encrypted getting there, you can
make it contact you outside of
the tour network, depending on
what fire walls are in place and
so forth. This would be harder
on tails because they have rules
in place to keep you from doing
that but it's just like my old
box I set up to use tour for and
I happened to have a command
injection vulnerability, they
can ping themselves or do a
trace and have a good idea of
who it actually is with the IP
address. That brings us to case
3, the silk road, who else knows
about these guy, okay. Silk road
is something that is ran by an
gay named dread pirate Roberts
and it allowed buyers and
sellers to exchange less than
legal goods, there is all sorts
of things that they would sell
on there. Here is some stuff in
the court couples, Ectasy,
opiate, all sorts of really,
really fun stuff. This is Tommy
C's stuff in here. So but it
also said other things like
various services, people would
hire someone to attack a system
for you, you could find
counterfeit bills, and other
things that you could have
currencies, I'm a little
confused about some of that.
Also, they had a fellow that
forged diplomas. >> [Off mic].
>> I'm not sure what the deal is
with that but anyway they were
making some big bucks. $1.2
million  ‑ ‑ billion, the FBI
got a little interested in these
guys, so they started looking
around for the silk road on the
public Internet it you can use
Google operators to say give me
everything from this time period
to this time mered and you can
find the earliest reference to
the Silk Road and they found it
on [indiscernible] a little
druggy website, and this guy had
posted on it a guy going by the
handle Altoid on 1/27/2011  and
here's  ‑ ‑ well, I don't think
I should have up what he said
but essentially, he was
advertising the Silk Road and he
had these very flavorful word, I
came across this website called
silk road, it acclaims to allow
you to buy and sell anything
online anonymously, I wanted to
see if anyone here had heard of
it or could recommend and it
gave information on how to visit
it. And the way he wrote it, it
sounds more likely
advertisement, but that was the
very first reference they could
find to the silk road on the
Internet. Then on bit coin,
there was someone posting, and
asking about it as well. And
pointing out that Silk Road
exists and seeing if anybody's
actually used it. Then also, bit
coin talk later on he is strike
again, using the name, Altoid,
once again it sounds very much
like an advertisement. Then
later on Altoid on bit coin talk
starting looking for an IP pro
in the bit coin community and
here's what happened, he said
contact me at
Rothubric@gmail.com. So yeah,
that's the first mention of silk
road of they could find in
handling Altoid and to an email
address Ross. So that was pretty
bat. Also, a few other things to
point out, he put his economic
philosophy on sic road and they
had interest in an institute and
Austrian school of economics, so
they had similar interests, sort
of like Jeremy Hammond's
personal life, well, same thing,
and as I said, he was using the
same things that Ross mentions,
so that kind of narrowed it down
to him possibly, that's not
necessarily a firm thing but you
get enough little pieces of
evidence together and you can
get a court order. Also, another
thing he did that is kind of
screwy, the Ross Albrich was
asking for help on HTP code and
he quickly changed his user name
but the first one he used was
Ross Albrich, I don't know why
but that's what he did. So guess
what is the main subject of this
point? That's about the
[indiscernible] if I was
[indiscernible]. [ Laughter ] >>
What is it, $1.2  billion. And
the FBI takes notice. Somebody
who is connecting to a website
and they found a hidden login
from gmail, it becomes a death
by a thousand paper cuts
essentially, he had the IP of
silk road was attached to a VPN
server that was connected to an
Internet cafe in San Francisco
where he had connected it to his
Gmail account before. There was
a site that was some sort of
experimental IP address. This is
kind of fairly common on so web
applications and you type in the
right things and it brings up
the standard optimization and
the IP address belonged to the
VPN. Eventually though, the FBI
was able to find some servers
and start getting hard drive
images of him. How they caught
him initially I'm not sure, I
don't knew if they used a bug or
exploited the box there's a
story read about someone
contacting Ross about wanting to
tell a whole bunch of cocaine I
believe it was and Ross
[indiscernible] former admin.s
and employees and the employee
was going to buy it but he
bought it at his own house and
the FBI was able to land him on
his own house so now they have
someone who works for the silk
road, they may have just
followed where the drugs went,
oh, you work for Silk Road and
you work for us now and they got
hard drive images and were able
to start monitoring, and another
big problem, let me see if I
have it on here. I didn't update
this slide, I don't think.
Another problem they ended up
having is he had order a bunch
of fake IDs, and these got
intercepted coming across the
border, they all had his picture
objecting it. Homeland security
found these and they went to go
talk that him and he denied
having order them, I see a lot
of documentaries on people
escaping prosecution and
generally denying anything is a
good call, the next thing he did
I don't understand though, that
denying thing was okay, but he
was said that hypothetically
anyone could go on to a website
named silk road on tour and
purchase any drugs or fake
identity documents the person
wanted. Why in the hell wouldn't
you say that? But that the that
the brought him back to him and
the roommates when the people
showed up, the home security
folks, knew him as Josh and not
his real name, and also fake IDs
with your face on them, what
reason would other people have
to buy those? Also, one of the
servers this they ended up
getting control over it had
frosty, and he's used frosty
before as a handle, and
eventually, they took down the
site and landed a library and
they got his password on his lap
tap. In these particular Anson
did a great write‑ up, and they
did a lot of best courtroom
document stuff I've read.
Lessons learned keep online
identities separate, if he had
kept his interests to himself
that would have helped and if he
hadn't used tour in the same
location he logged into his
gmail that would help also, and
not using the same handle in
multiple places don't have
information, I have no idea why
he said you could buy this on
Silk Road. I have a little bit
of time for some demo, let me
illustrate some of the things I
was mentioning about possible
ways of deanonomizing people.
Let's say you are using tour and
in try to convince you hey, go
to this one particular website
and download this Word document.
It's after safe and good, go
ahead and do that. Well,
depending on how you're browser
is he tell up, it may not
respect the proxy settings. Now,
I'm trying to connect to tour
right here and hopefully it
comes up within a reasonable
amount of time, I should have
had that up earlier already.
Okay. That's up, let's say I
visited this particular site.
Tracking doc and this is a
little Word doc, I've embed an
image in it. John is trying to
show me a better way to do this.
I'm dining all of the tour
browser, I've got the Word
document I'm going to open it.
And it's a trap, yes, it's a
trap. And hi there, image, yes,
I need to register, I know I'm
sorry Microsoft. Hi there, and
now I send you to a certain page
I have set up for tracking, let
me see if I can find real quick.
Yeah, let that password real
quick. I notice I now have the
IP address, the real IP address
of whoever is accessing, I
think. I hope it's one of their
IP addresses. Anyway, that's
hopefully what I got right there
and I can do a correlation pack,
over tour versus this. Another
option that way, more
professional than my little
ghetto doc file is something
called  ‑ ‑ I'll get to it in a
second. Honey docs and my
friend, Kerry runs it, and I
made a bunch of fake documents,
I'm calling this one credit
card.zip and if it downloads it
gives you Excel files and Word
docs, so I'm going to switch
over screen where it is, and I
can go in and see who opened it
with their real world IP address
except it's probably logging out
by now. Everybody close your
eyes. Let's see. Not that long a
password, you all can guess it.
And remember it. I feel bold! Do
your thing. Okay. And there are
various people who have accessed
it. I asked people to access it
over tour, that should probably
IP address. How much time have I
got now? 5 minutes. Okay. If I
were to open this up and look at
the documents in it, I would
basically get more of the same
thing, so you see OT like open
the document and a few other
formats but you get the idea,
basically I'm marketing this
tool as a much more professional
way of doing it than what I had
before. But I can also do those
things like where I showed with
the log, I can go down  ‑ ‑
another thing that you can do to
mess around with people, I have
an IP service set up, at this
location, so this could be a
condition to see how can hack my
site first. Right here, this is
Tilde it's a vulnerable script
and in find it very very easy to
write deliberately vulnerable
PHP code, currently it's taken
over by Jeremy Brewer, a better
coder than me, but if the
website has vulnerable, there
are attacks you can do. I'll
show you a few of them right
now. I'm going to describe this
one because of time. I'm doing
this one in command injection
attack and trying to get the IP
address, I could sit there
through my connection and see
who is actually pinging me to
figure out who they are. Another
option might be  ‑ ‑ yeah, tour
is acting way, way slow in here
right now. Lets me see. Open.
I'm looking for direct object
references and I'm opening that
one, too. So this demo may not
work, I have videos of this
online, essentially what I'm
doing is using a vulnerability
injection, I can have it trace
the route to me and see the IP
addresses along the path and
hopefully figure out who someone
is. However, tour on this
network is running pathetically
slow. Believe it or not, I did
it earlier, but the idea is you
do a command injection, you can
get that remote box to contact
you back and if anybody really
wants to see it, I've got about
3 minutes, don't I? 2 minutes.
Oh, questions, yes? >> [Off
mic]. >> This is a VPN server,
it's not like a VPN turn them, I
would get the IP or the VNP, it
might get me close but it
wouldn't be instantaneous. Yes?
>> [Off mic]. >> Shhhhh maybe,
but I haven't really looked into
it. In VIPS maybe, I know
there's some control you can do
over which nodes you hop
through, yeah, it looks like my
tour connection is not doing
that well. If anybody wants to
see this, I have videos on the
website about how to did this,
but you're injecting this and
making the control box contact
you back. You can also have it
suck up files from another Word
site you control and have it
delivered that way as well. And
I have had videos in the past
working. Unfortunately, I am out
of time and tour is going very
slow for me. I thank you for
your time and if you have any
questions, I am around.
[Applause] >> Thank you. Yeah, I
tested all of those demos before
and they were working earlier
but something is happening right
now.