Thank you so much for being here
this early in the morning. A lot
of people think there are no
mornings in Vegas. We're proving
them wrong consistently. And
anyway we're going to talk about
measuring the IQ of your threat
intelligence feeds. If you are
from the internet and you do the
Twitters we have, like, a
hashtag so you can hash tag the
talk and making fun of us.
Please do because I want to
laugh at everything later
because I can't check Twitter
here. It's kind of lame but
that's the way it is. I don't
like talking about myself. I
just brought here a very special
guest. This is Wendy Nader. She
going to do the introductions
for us. >> You didn't bring my
fez and my cup of rum. All
right. Good morning again
everybody. I want to introduce
these awesome guys. I am a
little annoyed with them because
in my analyst role I cover
threat intelligence and in this
talk is just something that I
wanted to do. But they probably
did it a lot better anyway. We
have Alex Pinto otherwise known
as the brain from Brazil. Is
that right? He's been giving
talks in all three conferences
this week. And people just can't
get enough of him. And his
hacker spirit animal is
decaffeinated Kathy Barra. Kyle
Maxwell, on the other hand, is a
math smuggler. His spirit animal
is the axiomatic armadillo. I'm
here to tell you he is a
fugitive time traveling Karl
Marxs and there's a reason why
his initials are KM. Sorry. I
had to out you like that. So
enjoy the talk. (Applause) >>
Thank you so much. Anyway, we're
going to cover a bunch of stuff.
We're just going to give a brief
introduction about threat intel
and really go into what is the
crazy idea about measuring
threat intelligence. Anyway I'll
just ask Kyle to do his magic.
>> Good morning everybody. So
we're going to talk real quick
about threat intel. We didn't
want to do threat Intel 101 for
those who have thought about it
before. Honestly the stuff we
talked about today, talk about
that what that really means.
When we talk about threat intel,
or intel in general there's two
things we really actually care
about. It's not IP addresses.
Its capability and intent,
right? What can your foes, I
hate the word "adversaries" and
all of that. So I'm going to
bring it back Viking style. What
are your foes able to do and
what do want to do? That's what
you really want to know so you
can prepare on your end for
whatever it is that you need to
do. So that's the core idea that
what we're trying to measure,
honestly most of the time what
we look at threat intel is
capability. What are they doing?
What are they able to do? We
don't spend enough time looking
at what they can do or rather
what they're planning to do. So
we'll talk about that a little
bit. There are a couple of key
concepts that I want you to be
able to take away where there
are some dichotomies within this
field. So we're going to talk
about kind of these cage match
between things that oppose each
other. One of them signatures
versus indicators. So Dave Vital
for example has made the point
very correctly that a lot of
times the way people use
indicators or indicators of
compromise sounds like
signatures, right. But that
shouldn't be. If you are using
them that way, you are doing it
wrong. 	The idea is that
indicators rather a signature
says this is definitely
something that happened here.
It's, like, a fingerprint,
right. You have a very, very
high degree of confidence that
this means X. Whereas an
indicator says look over there,
there's something fishy going
on. And you may have different
levels of confidence. You may
even have a pretty dang high
level. But the reality is that
it's not supposed to be used for
blocking. It's not to be used
for complete confidence. It's
supposed to indicate something
that you need to go look at. The
other thing I'm going kind of
deflate a little bit here is the
difference between threat data
and threat intelligence and data
and intelligence in general. Now
we talk about threat intel feeds
here because that's what vendors
typically label them as. But
they're generally speaking
they're doing it wrong. It's not
threat intel because it's data.
Data without context is UGH. If
you want Intel you need to do a
lot of things, right. You need
to be able to establish some
context around it. You need to
be able to add some of that
intent and capability understand
and we talked about it a minute
ago. And as we're going to see
you kind of escalate up the
abstraction of what you are
looking for. But since this is
what vendors sell it as we want
to make sure people know at
least what we're coming to talk
about. There's also a difference
between tactical and strategic
intel. Tactical you can think of
as the how and the what. Like
what they're attacks, how
they're going about it. Whereas
strategic intel and this is a
continuum not a binary either
or, towards the strategic end,
you have the who and why. Who
are my foes? Why do they care?
And why do I care about them?
This continuum is important to
understand what type of Intel
you are getting. And then very
briefly we talk about atomic
indicators versus composite.
Atomic indicators are an IP
address. A packet stream you are
looking for. A hash And
composite is when you pull these
things together and now you
start to get some value out of
them because I really don't give
a SHIT about the IP address but
I do if I see it combined with
other things. 	A colleague of
mine has a concept he calls the
pyramid of pain! And I always
use it because I like to say it
like that. The pyramid of pain!
And the pyramid is basically
this idea. At the bottom of the
pyramid and you can quibble and
Alex and I do, about what is
easier and what's more trivial,
IPs or domain. The honest truth
is it really depends on content
if you are talking about domain
generation algorithms versus
phishing. or what have you, but
the idea is Either way they're
kind of at the bottom. It's
pretty easy to get a lot of IP
addresses. Right? It's also easy
for foes to change their IP
address. As you move up this
pyramid of pain you get network
artifacts that are a little
harder for you to analyze and
figure out what to look for. And
a little bit harder for the
attack to be able to change on
his end. Whereas now when you
start to get to specific tools
of TTP whic are tactics,
techniques and procedures, how
these guys go about what they're
doing, that's much harder. It's
much harder to change your
process than it is to flip a bit
and have the hash come out
completely differently. Now,
that said, we talked about
simple, easy.and trivial We're
going to see it's not always
they're simple and easy. But
relative to these other things,
right. With that said, I'll hand
back over to my brother here to
go into his analysis. >> So, I
mean, just a side note. I think
if you did like do the pyramid
of pain in a falsetto voice it
would be much more funnier. But
that's just me. >> That would
hurt my throat. >> Okay it's
your throat. I guess the point
here is like Kyle was talking
about, I mean, should we care
more about the IP addresses and
domain names if that's all you
got? Ideally all of our
intelligence would be a bunch of
contacts in it. We'd all have
animal names attached to all of
them and it would be awesome. We
would really understand what
we're up against. I really want
to work with IP addresses here.
They have a bunch of interesting
stuff we can look for. And the
thing that is interesting for
me, it's finite resource people
are always bitching about iPv6
stuff like that. The fact is
there is an intrinsic cost of
getting and changing an IP
address. Some places it's easier
or less easy for you to get an
IP address to do that stuff.
Right. So people are quite on to
it. Some data centers, some
providers, if you try to do
something a little weird they'll
shut you down almost
immediately. Others you like to
have to talk to them we've been
here for three months while
they're ignoring you and stuff
stay there's forever. Maybe
there is some structure, some
patent there. I'm actually
proposing that if we're getting
a bunch of these IP addresses
why don't we try some
experiments in them to see if we
can learn a little bit more
about what thus threat
intelligence landscape is, I
don't say that in the threat
intelligence landscape like all
capital letters like what the
world is doing against the world
in cyber war. But who is
actually trying to get to you.
That's the thing you should be
most concerned about. 	Anyway
let's try to do some science
here. Can we measure how much a
specific feed is going to help?
How it's going to help us in our
strategic defense of practice
we're trying to do in our
organization. Can we actually
get something out of them. Are
they just a bunch of numbers
with DOTS in them? How can we
actually measure? I have some
ideas and I wanted to share
those ideas with you. 	 So
actually I put together all of
this is GPL3, a bunch of
statistical tests and data
visualization that you can do,
You do have to use R. I almost
did it on purpose so you guys
start to get to know some
statistical languages. Get with
the times. In five years it's
all going to be data. I'm sorry
but that's pretty much it.
There's some phyton dude beside
me who is just going to be
bothering me the rest of the
talk. All the code is there. The
sample data that i used for the
talk is there. So you can rerun
everything and say there is a
bug here youre such a stupid
guy, and stuff like that. But
look how I know how to use this
library much better than you.
You can do all this awesome
stuff. Also, all the graphs and
all the data that I show here is
in the mark down file. So it's
pretty much here is blah, blah,
blah. Here is the code, the
results. you can actually follow
thru if you like It's all in the
repository. There's a link to
everything. Let's get started. I
think. 	Just for you to have a
general idea how did I structure
this data, how did I try to,
like, create a sample database
or something like that? First of
all, I was trying to extract
what I am calling the raw
information from this feed,
right. And I extract both IP
addresses and host names. Just a
side note, all of this data is
publicly available, right. So
all this stuff that I've
gathered, and I'm going to show
here, you might as well just
gather. And we actually have a
treat for you by the end of the
talk that we might just need to
help you a little bit with that.
But the point here is, okay, you
got your iPv4s you git your
FQDNs I did this weird thing. It
may sound weird at first when I
am calling stuff inbound or
outbound. And it's pretty much
I'm just trying to differentiate
very broadly between the types
of threats, let's say, that
these IP addresses and domain
names provide me. not so much
domain names for inbounds but
uuhhh So think about the way the
data flows from your
organization or your IP or your
dingly tingly internety thingy
think about all the direction as
things go in and go out, right.
So, if it's someone that is
spamming you I am calling that
an inbound feed. If you have to
access this website to download
this malware or it's a dropper
or CNC I am calling that
outbound. and thats pretty much
the list of the feeds that i am
harvesting, There is a mistake
in this slide so you are free to
call me out on the internet if
you figure it out. But the point
is, and all of this is
documented which feed is which
but if you guys have been
playing around with this you
should recognize most of them
almost immediately. How did we
prepare this data for the
experiments we're going to talk
about? First of all, we I only
wanted to work with IP
addresses. First because there's
more interesting topological
stuff that you can work with as
opposed to domain names. I do
plan to do something similar to
this using who is data in a
future installment of this
specifically for host names. But
I was only willing to work and
frankly only had time to work
with IP addresses. So I just ran
all the domain names through the
passive DNS database.
Particularly the far sight. For
that day that I got this
indicator, what were the IP
addresses active that day,
right. Assuming you had the data
and were taking some measure of
that data, that would be the IP
addresses you have been flagged
as weird, malicious or
suspicious or however you take
this threat intelligence. So we
also removed non-public IPs we
dont care if the IP address
results to local hosts that's
obviously a parking technique
but it wasn't really conductive
to what we were trying to do
here. Anyway, we got this domain
names and IP addresses and we
made them a bunch of IP
addresses. After we do that we
went to do some enriching on
these guys. So we want to make
sure we were able to identify
what were the ASs that was
associated with the IP addresses
on that specific day. So there's
a period of time that we have
the data for and that's when we
did those, we did those
enrichments right. Also country
from geo occasion databases. We
also resolved the remote host
also using passive DNS at that
time. And I had some plans for
it but we didn't wasn't really
interesting. The data was too
sparse. There was not a lot of
cool stuff to be shown. Just a
side note as well. Although we
are doing geolocation there will
be no maps at this presentation.
Maps are not a good way to look
at data. Please, stop doing
that. (Applause) I mean, if the
country is big you think they're
more of a threat. That's how the
brain works. They look at stuff
that's bigger and more
important. Stop using maps. Okay
let's move on So, yeah, this is
a sample, right. And you can see
exactly how easy or not it is to
actually use the code that I put
together to actually okay I'm
going to load in from my
database and I want to see it
and see what data is in it, et
cetera, et cetera. You can see
there some examples of things
that people thought to be bad in
a specific moment and time. All
right we got our data. So what
are we going to do with it? I
propose three different
experiments here, right. I'm
calling them novelty. It is a
pun because it has both
meanings. You can use it because
that's how much this feed is
refreshing itself as time goes
by. Or maybe it's just like I am
going to add a bunch of stuff
and take a bunch of stuff off.
and make it look really active
But anyway you got to know how
your feeds are updating
themselves. You want to make
sure that whomever you are
getting them from be them open
source or commercial, the guys
actually putting some work into
it. Because, I mean, things move
around. There's an overlap test
which is one that I mean, it's
the most simplest thing ever.
Just, like, let's compare
everyone against everyone and
see how much they have the same
indicators, right. This is
specifically useful if you are
trying to buy something, right.
Just get all the open source
feed that you can handle,
compare them against the
commercial feed, and how much am
I actually getting for X. I
completely lost it. But like
this ridiculously amount of
money I am paying for this. The
one that is much more
exploratory there a little bit
more math than the other ones
which I'm calling the population
test. Which is can the data
we're getting actually teach us
something about our adversaries?
Can we actually learn something
from them? Sorry. Sorry. Foes.
Foes. Can we actually learn
something from this? Can we
actually find some patterns on
this attacks? Anyway, population
is tricky. I'm doing some
examples here where I'm
comparing against the whole
population of IP addresses where
they should be at least. And
also should ideally mean your
data. So get your data and
compare how are the IP addresses
that your companies accesses or
accessed by your company against
actual threat intel feeds.
Anyway, we'll get there. I was
looking for an IQ. I wanted a
grade. No we're not going to get
there. Specifically, I want to
make sure that you guys
understand that the idea here is
to make sure that you guys are
able to reach your own
conclusion, right. Whatever I
think is right for my company as
far as the specific mix of
threat intelligence or i should
be focusing on this or that is
going to be very, very different
from whatever you are doing at
yours. I just want to make sure
that you understand, feel free
to publish your own Metrics.
Feel free to tell X Y X sucks.
I'll try not do this because I
kind of like data and I don't
want to piss of everyone at the
same time. I try to get on their
good side. if you wanna meet and
do this work for you i can help
you out >> youre so nice. >>
Well I don't know. Anyway, I do
intend to--I will do more
private research on this because
there is all of this comes from
the other researching that I do.
So I actually had to go through
all of this. I'm explaining
which were the threat intel
pieces I would use in my models.
Just thought it would be
interesting to share. Anyway,
novelty test. So we're measuring
pretty much added and drop
indicators, right. So how much
stuff is being added day by day
and how much stuff is being
removed day by day, right? And
if you run this kind of thing
you will get something like
this. This is specific for
inbound. So alienvault is
actually divided because they
got both stuff in there. It's
majorly inbound. There's a lot
of inbound stuff. And it's
because it's fairly easy to get
like you just run a couple of
honey pods and suddely you are
like threat intelligence all the
way to the bank. That sounded
worse than I meant it to sound.
But anyway. The point here is
you want to make sure that the
stuff that you are doing is
actually refreshing itself with
something. So you can see there
just like a 20 percent refresh
in one of them. Sometimes 50
percent. You definitely do not
want the guy on the lower right.
I mean, they're not dropping any
IP addresses, right. The red
line is how much it's being
dropped. So it's an upside down
and the blue graph is how much
is being added. This guy is
adding a minimal ratio of stuff.
this is only percentage, this is
not an absolute values And it's
not removing anything else. I'm
not sure the guy is doing the
work. It looks abandoned to me.
So it might not be a good one to
actually keep using as you go
forward. But not updating every
time does not mean it's bad,
right. So this is an example
from outbound. Also you got
stuff moving up and down. You
got something adding or not. And
as a rule of thumb if something
is being updated hourly or being
updated daily there's a lot of
out related stuff going on there
and it's potentially getting
information from other sources
as well. And it's being
presented to you with little or
no human interaction. If it's
something that's more like
weekly or something like that,
maybe there's some people
actually doing the work and
computing and everything. Of
course when I say all of this I
mean specifically about open
source, right. If people are
getting paid to actually deliver
this to you, they might as well
give me hourly. humanly created
feeds all the time otherwise i
should not be paying for them at
least thats my opinion It's cool
because it can see patches. How
malware domain list. and malware
domains they actually have a
huge spike in a specific day, If
you guys are wondering that's
was right about the time we had
that no IP thing with Microsoft
and people got to know, like, a
bunch of new domains and
everyone started sharing it. So
you can actually see when stuff
happened in a way. It's kind of
cool. Anyway, do this test. Run
this and see how much your feeds
are updating and see if yeah
does it sound right for the
sizes of the company or for the
kind of data that your reading
that they are actually looking
at it It is a lead indicator of
quality. It's not the last one.
We can talk about overlap,
right. More data is better but
there's so much you can give
your hadoop vendor to actually
store all the data. So let's try
to keep it only add data that is
not the same or it's useful. I
mean, it's easy for me to say
that because I don't really
care. I do lot of summarization
for people the way that i
consume threat intelligence some
people use the fact that
something appeared in multiple
feeds as a quality issue. A
bunch of people read it. They
might not have all done the
research. Or just want to leave
it out there. But I don't know.
I honestly don't know. It's just
that you have to make sure what
you are looking for. So when you
look at inbound you get stuff
like this. So the brighter the
square there's more overlap
between those specific feeds.
And this was a specific day in
time. And you can rerun this
test for all the 30 days that I
have on the data set. And you
can take your conclusions about,
I mean, who is potentially
drawing this information from
the same kind of honey pod or
some kind of research, right? I
have no idea what's going on in
the sense that this guy did
that. And honestly I don't
really care. I just want to make
sure that if you are ingesting
this and if you are working with
this you are not just, like, oh
yeah I got two minute indicators
here. All the IP addresses in
the world. But it's, like, yeah
a bunch of duplicates and that's
not really helping your bottom
line. Something that was
actually I found was very
interesting and it actually
relates to information I heard
privately. Is that when you look
at outbound, there's much,
significantly less overlap,
right. So it seems that peoples
aren't doing their research or
work on some specific issues.
And specifically some people
they will specialize in specific
threat. Oh yeah I'm specific
whatever hunter. And but okay.
Sorry. And what we get here is a
little bit of the domain only
you do get a little bit of
overlap. I just wanted to point
out that specific day that we
had that spike. On that day
there was actually a 25 percent
of overlap of potential
indicators between malware
domains and malware domain
lists. Because they all updated
quickly to add all that
information. Which is very good,
very positive. Then you see that
result also represented here,
right. Because you can measure
the overlap those feeds have.
And also you can also from this
graph you can very easily see
that a lot of the stuff that the
WCH guys put on their Zeus feed
is also being used by alienvault
as well. Which also I think is
good. I know a lot of people who
use it and a lot of people who
use WCH stuff. Anyway let's get
to something which is a little
more interesting I think which
is the population test. And I
guess it's interesting and this
is kind of a cornerstone of the
research that I started doing a
couple of years ago. Which is,
you know, maybe, maybe stuff
isn't random, right. Maybe it's
not like maybe we can actually
track. There's some sort of
likelihood that some specific
corners of the internet are more
likely to be targeting you or
not. And all the different
information that you get are
from the providers, they will
give you different information.
And there is some sort of
alignment that I believe that
you should be trying to reach
when you are talking about here
is my data, right. These are all
the IPs address that im
communicating to. Potentially
the threats that I have, the
people who are targeting me or
the people who maybe have
already reached me, that are
exfiltrating data they are
probably from that pool. It's
not going to be like an IP
teleporting thing. I am not talk
about which type of animal web
or from the from the zoo you
come from. I am talking about at
the end of the day does it
really matter. But there has to
be a way that the data is being
exfiltrated the IP address is
there. The guy who is out to get
you, who is potentially messing
around with your data is on that
list. So why don't you try to
tailor the threat intelligence
and the research you are doing
through the specific countries
ans ASNs that actually make more
sense to your data, right. So
then we start doing some
comparisons and doing some
tests, right. And we've come up
with some interesting things. I
specifically separated the
domain, the outbound and inbound
stuff here. Of course on the
inbound China all the way,
right. And I can see some people
smiling here. Yeah. And at least
in my perspective the actual
penetration of those kind of
things are people who are doing
SSH scans or they have, like,
this three year old joomla or
exploits they're running against
the whole internet. I don't
think those guys are really
going to get in. I mean, if they
do you shouldn't be in this talk
you should be in, like, 101 or
something. But the point I am
trying to make is when you start
looking at the outbound data
it's not that different from it
is different from some but the
fact that China wasn't the first
one and the first one was the
U.S. actually made me chuckle.
Actually, if you squint you can
see that the actual proportion
and I'll get there. The actual
proportion of Chinese IP
addresses which are actually
distributing malware is less
than the actual Chinese
proportion of IP addresses on
the internet. So, I mean, maybe
they're less likely to be
posting malware than other
countries which I think is kind
of funny. Anyway, you can play
the same game with ASN, right.
And the prevalence of Google
there obviously startled me. At
first I was looking at that and
was, like, okay this is a bunch
of punk domains. Everybody knows
that. When this stuff, domain
names they are they're not being
active and used, like, they're
changing their infrastructure.
Someone just took the BOTnet
down and put something else
together. just spark it all like
8.8.8.8 or 1.1.1.1.1 or
something like that and those
are all owned by Google. So at
any moment in time like a very
high percentage of your domain
names from these open threat
intelligence feeds will be
pointing at Google. Be aware of
that. But, even so, I don't
know. dont be evil and all that,
im with them The thing is I
guess the point I'm trying to
make here is this kind of
population test, they can also
help you to key weigh your
feeds. Right. I'll get to the
specific of that. I just wanted
to show you the graphs and now
I'm going to get to the math.
I'm sorry about this. But the
point is I don't like to squint,
right. So let's do some
statistical entrance testing.
Let's compare the proportion,
right. So, if I know the exact
proportion of IP addresses on
the US, right, just get any geo
IP database and make sure you
are, like, keeping with it, make
sure it doesn't enrich in one
database and use another one we
can do an exact binomial test
which would be okay assuming
that the I can just choose
randomly the IP addresses that
are going to attack me, is that
consistent with how the IP
addresses are distributed? Even
if I don't have the full
population, right, and I'm only
like comparing my sample of my
data against the sample of the
threat intelligence feeds, I can
use something that's the
chi-squared proportion test
which is similar to the
independence test. Which pretty
much ask the questions these are
two different samples of stuff.
Do they look like they came from
the same population, right. And
it's a little bit more fuzzy and
fidgety than the other one.
That's why the other one is
called exact, right. But it's a
statistical tool that you may
have. So I really wanted to get
an idea of our error measures. I
wanted to get confidence
intervals and say it's something
along this line. But at least I
can tell you I'm messing it up
here in this calculation but
this is pretty much how much I
am messing up. I can also use
p-values. I personally apologize
to Alex Hutton for using P
values and not like doing some
bayesian evil shit. But he said
it was okay. So I'm allowed to
do this. Some people have to
clear it with their lawyers I
have to clear it with Alex. 	So
the point is, if we're doing
p-values we're being very
conservative. So for the number
of tests we do, so what does
that look like? we're assuming
95 percent because it's pretty
much what everybody does. If
we're doing multiple tests we're
actually dividing our critical
value or the value that we use
to oh there's something
interesting here by the number
of tests that we do. So what
does that look like? It looks
like something like this. So I
have this I'm using this
functionally extracts the
population from a threat intel
feed. It's all there. And I'm
comparing it to my known MMGU
database. And lo and behold, it
seems that Thailand is a winner
right now. Which maybe the
proportion is five percent more
than the number than their
actual proportions on the IP
addresses there, right. Followed
closely by the US. Russia is
there. I'll give you guys that.
But you should go to China.
China is the second least likely
to be hosting something.in
comparison to the random
proportion, I don't know maybe
it was not these feeds. Maybe
these feeds were not tracking
specific addresses for there.
But that's not the point. The
point is if that's the data that
you have and the data we should
be comparing, that's what you
should be analyzing. You want to
add something? You were just
gasping. Did I say something
wrong? >> No you are good. You
are good. just keep presenting
knowledge bombs >> Co-presenting
is hard. The guy is judging me
right beside me. I can't really
see you because of the lights.
Like, why did I get into this?
If the feed value is higher than
critical value which is the last
one here it's pretty much we
can't really say anything. It
looks like it's on par with the
randomness that we would get. A
challenge we got when we reached
this conclusion is that hold on,
I don't know what to call these
countries yet, right. Come on. I
mean, we do not have, like, ugly
animal names for all of them. So
we propose a guide. So as you
are trying to create your own
and you are creating your own
threat intelligence with those
statistical techniques you can
actually call people and
actually view people to what you
are doing. Just clarification.
Capybara. is like south south of
brazil and toucan is more like
the amazon part, its very very
different hacker spirit animal
just be consious about that.
Where are my Texas people?
(Applause) >> This is not an
exhaustive list. So feel free to
tweet your own suggestions at
the hash tag of the talk. We got
to catch them all. Anyway, then
we get to the not exact test.
And this is just a little thing
that I did trying to compare how
this feed evolved and changed
from the 11th of July to the
12th of July. Those are the same
feeds. What did change from the
one day to the next? You see a
bunch are pretty much the time
on the bottom side. Thailand
again, there's actually a trend
from this information you are
getting from your threat
intelligence feeds. That
Thailand is getting more likely
to attack. Based only on the
data and geo location. So, if
you got I can see some of you
guys have got, like, the brain
thing going on and that's
exactly what I'm hoping for.
There's a lot of interesting
stuff and a lot of interesting
conclusions you can get from
your own data. Not so much the
threat intelligence feeds also
trying to do something like
this. While you are at it at the
animal thing, we do need some
for Thailand. Because they're
everywhere on this presentation.
theyre obviously up to something
bad Tweet it. Tweet it. We can't
really hear you. So then I
wanted I was bothered by this
Google thing right and I wanted
to make sure that I could
understand if this is all
(inaudible) or something
different. So I ran the same
test, the same exact proportion
test on the AS information as
well as the population
information. And yeah Google's
like ten percent proportion
increase. That's crazy. That's
too much. That's way, way too
much. And then, what? >>
(Inaudible). >> Okay. Where is
he? What we get there is if you
actually look into the data you
will find that maybe not so
much, maybe it's not just park
data, there's some cleaning that
needs to be done. I am not the
biggest fan of chrome but I'm
pretty sure it's not malware so
probably we shouldn't have
chrome.google.chrome in our list
but Its alright, it happens
sometimes. You just got to be
sure if you are consuming this
you need to look out for
information like this. And maybe
they can help you do a little
bit of triage because no one is
going to look through the whole
thing all the time. I am talking
about a bunch of stuff and I
talked about my data. What about
your data? How can you get your
data to use those? For that I'd
like to invite back my good
friend Kyle Maxwell. (Applause)
>> Oh my God thank you Alex. So
as you are pulling in these
feeds you want to be able to do
this yourself. You want on going
data in addition to be able to
run these analyses for
yourselves you may have other
uses for the data. In this case
we did a lot of the work for
you. But ongoing we need
something to help you with that.
So what we did is we are
releasing this week a tool
called combine. You can get it
right now. its a TPO ver. 3 And
what it is, it is a tool for
harvesting and processing these
types of feeds. >> I just want
to point out at the ML sec
project we're very serious about
our needle in a haystack joke.
so this is why this is a
combined harvester I am not
implying, well maybe I am,
that's all hay. >> So there's a
few different components to it.
reaper pulls it in We really,
really like this metaphor here.
so we reap it in that just pulls
in the data directly, We'll
normalize it to a very simple
data model. we do a little bit
of validation We throw out all
the RFC 19, 18 shit stuff like
that. Do the AS numbers, the DNS
look up. We transform the data
into CSV or J song. We haven't
released the SY box or sim for
splunk As this is an open source
project, help us help you. Feel
free to submit full requests for
it. That's another output form
that you want. We're constantly
trying to feed more data into
it. This can be your own data
sources. There's a number of
tools to bring in. CSV,XML,
parsing HTML, what have you. We
have a number of feed sources
bundled in in terms of the URLs.
We're not saying clearly based
on the last half hour that any
of these feeds are good or bad
these are just the ones that we
have and we'll add more as time
goes on. When we do the
enrichment, if you are not
familiar with the term think
metadata and metadata
accessories. So we're pulling
the autonomous system and geo
location only down to country
level from the maxline database.
We do DNS resolution from the
far site passive DNS database.
That requires an AP IP. If you
have one fantastic. Plug it
right in. If you don't. Ask them
for one. Tell them Alex Pinto
sent you and he'll get you
hooked up. >> Alex, really good
folks at far sight can help you
out with that. Again, all of
this is open source software.
This is not commercial. This is
not us trying to make a buck off
these tools. This is, you know,
us trying to make thing as
little better and help you pull
in these feeds and pull in your
own data as well. >> And,
honestly, I don't think that's
where the cool stuff really is.
And I we had to build a lot of
this as we were building out the
research we were doing for MLSec
project. We just figured out
yeah but this is very
commoditized stuff. or at least
it should be very commoditized
stuff, So we want to make sure
that we are replacing our stuff
our internal stuff is being
replaced by open source versions
and we will continue to support
them as we actually need to use
them in dot coding and all of
that. Talk to us about the
project if you are interested.
If you like the specific
TIQ-test you want to test your
data against it. oh but i dont
wanna publish my feed We can
totally help you out. Either you
setting up your own stuff to do
that or we can help you out and
do the test for you, right. And
I just want to very quick
takeaways before we are kicked
out. Look at your data. That's
all I'm asking, right. That's
all you should be doing right
now. And I will try and as much
as I can to keep banging this
point forward and actually
providing helpful tool that
people can use for that, right.
i Also feel very strongly about
the asymmetry of information.
So, if people tell you something
is good, don't take their word
for it. Just try it, right. Just
test it. And make sure that it's
appropriate for what you are
doing. Anyway, if you just got
data lying around, you know, we
can pick it up for some
exercise. We can play some
games. >> Think about, like,
data sitting like with dot
sitting. We can totally do some
data sitting for you guys.
Anyway, thank you very much.
(Applause)