>> Good morning. I'd like to say
it is nice to see all of you
bright and early, but I can't
see anybody at all right now so
I've got bright lights in my
face. We're going to be talking
about Oracle data redaction and
how it failed to protect data at
the moment. Or actually not at
the moment because it has to be
patched so I won’t be dropped an
0day at the moment. But before
we get there who am I? I'm David
Lichtfield. I'm been a security
researcher for 12, 14 years now
or so. I work for some companies
work with really cool people. At
stake back in the day NCC, we
were acquired by NCC back in
2008 and since then they Accu-
vant. I'm working for a company
in Australia called DataCom TSS
well, TSS is a nice company.
It's more for the sharks and
Australian waters. Buffer
exploitation was my forte. I
enjoyed the bits and bytes but
commercially I was driven
towards database security. No
one seemed to be doing it or
doing it very well, and so
basically I took a decision that
I would get out of the bits and
bytes; well to be fair, I still
do a lot of bits and bytes
because database obviously have
data overflows. >> Probably the
best bit of work I did was in
2003. I've not really done
anything great since then or
what I feel is good. When I
wrote the first paper on
defeating the MicroSoft stack
protection and SafeSEH. Ever
since then, I have not really
been writing exploits (inaudible)
To be fair I gave this presentation
at BlackHat a few days ago and
the person said the exploit you're
doing now and I was like whoa
whoa these are not exploits
this is straight SQL so I just
want to be fair about this.
Obviously it might bypass security
and everything but by todays
standards I would not call these
exploits. I've written a couple of
books. The Oracle Hackers Handbook,
The Database Hackers Handbook
and some of the Windows exploit
stuff in the Shellcoders Handbook.
If you're interested in security or
sharks, you can follow me at D
Lichtfield on twitter or if you
wander to have a session longer
conversation not necessarily in
public I can be contacted.
So I want to put a framework
or a foundation for this talk.
At the beginning of this year
Larry E said To the best of our
knowledge an Oracle database
hasn't been broken into in a
couple of decades by anybody.
(inaudible) I know, exactly. What?
Who remembers Sony PlayStation
Network breach in 2011?
That was the biggest breach
of it's kind to date. That was
an Oracle based server. That
senior Oracle management didn't
know it was their database. It
was criminal. He should spend
less time on his boat and more
time concentrating on his
software. His CSO whom I'm
actually quite friendly with,
she's actually a nice person we
just don't necessarily see
eye to eye at a professional
level. She said Customers
should hold their vendors to
a high standard. The only way
to do that is through your
checkbook. Pocketbook. Checkbook
is UK. So essentially what she
said is we need to be getting
on our vendors cases. If they're
not delivering a secure product
we need to be voting with money.
We should be buying
other products. So standing by
those words I would like to then
continue this talk. I want to
give you some background before
we get to how we bypass Oracle
Data Redaction, stuff like
that I want to cut to the more
interesting stuff.
Let's do it from the beginning.
So, the guy a few years ago
about 12, 14 years ago called
RFP, still around but he was one
of the greatest researchers of
our time and he did a lot of
research into SQL injection.
It wasn't called SQL
injection at the time.
In fact the term SQL injection
was invented by Chip Andrews
who manages SQLsecurity.com
People were talking about things like
sequence session at the time.
RFP had written a couple papers
and we had a conversation about
it. I was like I've never really
looked at database service.
So it was actually RFP who
got me into database server
security and one of my
colleagues, Chris H and I were
doing a pentest on one of our
customers back in servers
and they had a Microsoft SQL
server, this was back in the
days when SQL was trivial to
exploit and own and we
discovered some new
techniques that allowed us
to workout what the backend
was doing, come across the
data structures and so I
put together a paper called web
application disassembly. This
was my first venture into the
database world essentially. And
then we were kicking the hell
out of Microsoft server. I wrote
a paper called threat profiling
SQL Server and then I covered
a couple of buffer overflows
Who remembers what happened
on January 25th 2003? Slammer
exactly. So there's a worm
basically that came out and
exploited a buffer overflow in
Microsoft SQL server. It
happened over UDP port
1434. And that was a bug I had
discovered and spoken about
at BlackHat and said listen
if you don't patch this it will
be the next big worm. The
reason I'm including Microsoft
is because I don't want to look
like I'm just bashing Oracle.
I'm bashing database servers
in general because they should
be secure but they're not.
Well, they're much better
these days. Anyway.
Then Larry E. turned around
announced his product was
unbreakable and you know
when everyone heard that
JFK was assassinated they
remember exactly what they
were doing at that time. I
remember exactly what I was
doing when he said his
product was unbreakable.
I looked up from my keyboard
and said what? >> [laughter] >>
So my brother and I spent
some time, 24 hours, and
we sent Oracle 35-40
critical flaws, many of them
not requiring user ID and
password to gain full control
so much for an unbreakable
Anyway that led to this ongoing
love hate relationship with Oracle.
Some more interesting patching
stories we've had with Oracle, I
want to, the reason I'm
bringing this up is because as I
said it's sort of setting the
scene for where we are today and
why we are called data re‑‑
the Oracle data redaction stuff
is as bad as it is. It's not so
much that it can be bypass. It's
more representative of what's
going on in the Oracle security
world or their approach to
security. Any way I want to give
background. One of the reports I
reported to them was essentially
you could without user ID and
password cause the database
server to load an arbitrary
library, execute an arbitrary
function. Now the way this
operates is through (inaudible) what
happens when you have a PR
package that sort of like PR
sequel is the stuff that extends
an Oracle database server,
the, if you want to load
the library and call a function
or something like that what
happens is the IBBMS, sorry,
sorry, the IBBMS connects to the
T nest listener the great way to
all Oracle communications
essentially so the database
connects to the listener. When
you execute this function it
says no no I won't do that but
I know a program that will. It
launches a program and passes
Oracle back, the handle sort of
redirects it to a port basically
and the Oracle connects to X
pock loads the library and
executes the function. There's
no authentication going on
there. IBBMS from the other side
of the network and say to the
listener will you load the
library for me. It goes no way
will I do that but I know a
program that will. Lo and behold
Xbox loads the library in this
case in the case of windows
executes the system function and
executes an operating system
without using any password and
of course the network so that's
pretty bad so I report this to
Oracle of course because I'm one
of these people who wander to
find a bug and report it
straight to the vendor, I'm
quite happy nowadays but let's
be honest about it, you know,
computer security is a fine
distinction am I report my bugs
to the vendors when I find them
and so Oracle said yeah, okay,
we're going to fix this and what
they do now or did at the time
was basically turned around and
said if someone attempts to do
this we'll block it but we'll
log it which is good because we
want to see if someone is
attempting to attack us. The
problem is they (inaudible)
and I was like, aw crumbs.
>> [laughter] >> I can hear people
laughing already. The C programmers
know exactly what's going on
There's a stack box for the
overflow. So I was like Oracle
we can still exploit this
without using (Inaudible). And
then we were like oh yeah we'll
fix that. So what we'll do this
is Oracle speaking here, I'm
paraphrasing of course, we'll
put a link check in before we
call S print out. Why they
didn't say SSM print I don't
know. They expanded environment
variables. That's in between you
remember so if I said don't sign
par that is expanded off to a
line check so that's five
characters and that expands. So
suddenly we have a (Inaudible).
They should have just done SFM
print F260 bites max but they
didn't do that. This went over a
period of years backwards and
forward until eventually they
fixed all supported versions.
Unsupported versions are still
vulnerable to this. There are
still people out there using
Oracle seven. So, this was the
kind of, you know, approach to
patching that Oracle would take.
You would wait two years for a
patch and it would be
insufficient and I'll give you
another good example of this.
So, way back when, Oracle
application seven, originally
called the Oracle web listener
had something called PL SQL
it's a cool function especially
if you want to hack into it,
essentially what it does is the
PR sequel gateway allows you to
program your web application in
PISQUELL and have it execute in
the database and the results are
broadcast back to the browser.
Essentially what happens is the
web server takes the user's web
request, get flash PLSv package
dot procedure, basically the web
server turns around and takes
that request, strips out the
package dot feature, turns
around to database server and
says execute that for me and
pass me back the results. This
is going to be riddled with
security bugs because nothing is
being validated and it's just
being executed by the database
server. If you knew of a
vulnerable package or procedure,
that allows you to execute
arbitrary SQL for example
How many actual Oracle
people do we have in here?
Show of hands? Who
remembers dry load.
It was a package that
basically had a procedure
validate statement and
what it did was
basically and remember it
was a DBA at the time. You
passed SQL query would execute it.
Executes would deviate
privileges and so you could say
grant BBA to public and suddenly
the public was a DDB
essentially. We could execute
this through the server. We
could just go get slash dolt
validate statement question mark
C buffer equals select star from
whatever or create user or
load, create library,
whatever we wanted to do we
would deviate privileges
essentially. So that's pretty
bad. Oracle introduced the PL SQL
exclusion list and on that list
are things in the sys schema,
sys is like root basically. It's
the most powerful account
on an Oracle system. So
anything in the sys schema
would be rejected. Anything that
starts with DBMS underscore
would be rejected because most
of the sys stuff has a synonym so we
can access it without specifying
a schemer and they will be given
that uh most of the
packages start with DBM
underscore schemer. They decide
to reject that. Anything that
started with the OWA underscore
because the Oracle web
application toolkit basically
had things like, there was a
package called OWM underscore
and one of the features was
sells print and it presented the
results back to you so this was
banned. So, it became incumbent
upon you if you wanted to break
into an Oracle database
server to execute things like CTX
were not in the band from the
get go so you could still
exploit things like the dry load
validate. And assuming we wanted
to execute scheme load we had to
bypass the PR SQL exclusion. So
having reported this and them
introducing the exclusion list
it was now important to bypass
the list. And so certainly the
first way of doing it was put up
imprint assist 'cause it's a
space and a space does not match
of course SIS. They're two
different things. Or you could
go zero wave new line, zero
defer line feed and all of these
things would bypass the
exclusion list so we could gain
access to everything for
example. So I reported this to
Oracle, Oracle fixed it so on
and so on. All good. We came
across another Oracle
application and they all
patched. We have to bypass the
exclusion list again so this way
next time was basically using
angle brackets. If you do double
angle bracket, double angle
bracket that's like a go to
label. You would request get
slash PL slash angle bracket
angle bracket, bar angle bracket
angle bracket and that would
break the matching. Oracle fixed
it. This is now about year three
and another time they, uh I'd
found a few bugs in the schemer
and they were like they're not
going to fix them because the
only risk is through the
application server. What if we
find another bypass. They're we
fixed all the bypasses. You're
not going to get around it this
time. And I was like well I'll
stop you guys. And it's silly, I
should have thought of it from
the get go. Double quotes
bypasses their exclusion list.
So they go ahead and fix that
and eventually, you know, we're
now sort of like ping pong or
tennis they fix it, I bypass
it, they fix it, I bypass.
Eventually and this is a real
funny one. Who knows what the
character with the value hex FX
looks like? Anyone many like a Y
with a numeral on top of it.
Looks like a letter Y and guess
what the database server thinks
it is? So, anyway the web
application server would look at
it you go SFS, you know, for SIS
essentially, the web server
would go well that is not SYS
because that FF character, that's
not a Y, that's some weird
thing, I've never seen that,
pass it through. The database
searcher depending upon the
language eventually says what
the hell is this double doing on
there. I don't think you mean
it. Convert it to a Y. >> [laughter] >>
So then you would get access to
the SYS schemer. >> Eventually
Oracle decides that they can't
rely on the web developers to do
the validation so here's a
really smart idea. Let's get the
guys to do the validation. So
I'm sorry I was expecting a
laugh. You're getting the
database server to do its own
validation. So guess what? That
first attempt is vulnerable
SQL injection. We're now
six years into this. So, you
send this stuff and you wait six
months or eight months for them
to come back with a suitable
patch and it's just not
sufficient enough. You've paid
it lip service. We'll come back
to Oracle patch in a minute.
Spend some time looking
at DB2 I'm not just pulling
at Oracle here. Sent IBM is
bunch of bugs I think about 50
in all. We'll talk about common
criteria in a minute and a
problem Oracle had with it but
info Mex had a buffer flow way
long user name. The
authentication procedure
I said we'll come back to that.
As time progresses you start
looking for these wonderful
things, you know, and coming up
with new classes of attacks such
or new classes of flaws. Lateral
SQL injection but here's the
thing. Nine times out of ten you
go and do an assessment of
someone and they still got like
weak password management in
place so they don't care about
things like lateral SQL
injection and stuff like that.
They've not even got the
password stuff right. It's a bit
of a disappointment. And so yeah
long story short I went by
eventually and came back to it:
Most of the time they used to
fix the flaw. They didn't fix
the flaw they would fix the
exploit. If my exploit had a
space in it because you like
select start from SYS user
dollar or whatever it happens to
be they would say well if the
parameter being supplied by the
user has a space in it, reject
it. Well, hold on, we don't need
a space. We could replace the
space with forward slash star,
star forward slash. And
or you know double pipe. There's
a whole number of things. It was
still vulnerable. They hadn't
fixed the actual flaw itself but
just the exploit. So that was
typically the kind of response
you would get. Or they would use
a super secret that no one is
supposed to ever know but of
course that's what hackers do,
researchers do that, they
reverse engine. As long as you
knew what that secret was you
would pass that as a parameter
and you would still be able to
execute the flaw. You would
typically report an issue and
often you would find the same
vulnerability in the probe two
lines later that they had
neglected to fix but they fixed
the one you had reported so
again I just wanted to stress it
that this is, Oracle
often takes a long time to
patch. Two years you used to
wait for a patch to come out and
it would be broken severely
broken. I do want to point out
though that who
remembers the hacker group, they
found this is the flaw
that slammer, uh Blaster
ended up exploiting. Anyone
remember that? It was very nice.
Any way, just, you know, showing
that even people like Microsoft
basically after the whole SDL
stuff they fell vulnerable to
this. There was a heap of
overflow they forgot to overfix.
Two lines of code later they
fixed the base overflow. So,
it's not that this is just
Oracle doing this, it's the
other vendors, too. So, I want
to do some comparisons between
Oracle and Microsoft in terms of
just the database side of
things. So, we can see that
they're actually getting better.
Back in 2004 days, you know,
they would patch you 28
issues, sorry, each one of these
blue blocks represents a flaw
that they have caught in their
advisories basically and so
before 2004 they patched things
on an ad hoc basis. Now, this
was at time when Microsoft was
turning towards patch Tuesday.
And Microsoft was saying we have
to patch so many things we need
to really get on top of this so
our customers can have a
recognizable date when they know
they're going to have to look
for patches. Excuse me. Oracle
at the time slagged them off.
Oracle was like that's leaving
your customers exposed for a
month, you know. Says the
company that waits two years to
patch things crappily. Oracle
has three months, a quarterly
patch update. So, after slagging
off Microsoft for doing a
monthly patch cycle, Oracle will
do a three month, you know. So,
I think one of the things that
Oracle doesn't like to do is be
like schooled by Microsoft but
they really should and one of
the things we'll talk about is
SDR, the security development
life cycle and really if,
I know Oracle says they've got
one but I see no evidence of it
at this stage of the game and
this what we'll talk about
towards the end of the talk. So,
here is for all Microsoft SDL
server products is the
comparison. So, this is Oracle
remember eventually that
died out. So, all the way to
Oracle 12C, so this is all
Oracle's products. This is all
Microsoft SQL server products.
That's a pretty good record so
it sorter of those SDL is
probably working. On the
left hand side of the graph is
the days when people who like
myself were weekly kicking the
crap out of it basically. And at
that point Microsoft turned
around and said you know what,
enough is enough. In fact, bill
gates trustworthy memo was at
this time, they were
hemorrhaging customers and
what's important here is that
they took everyone off, this is
unheard of in, you know,
at the time was unheard of, they
took everyone off the
development review con and said
you know what, let's get back to
sequel server 2000 do thorough code
review and the results have paid
off as far as I'm concerned.
That's a fantastic graph compared
to that one. Even SQL 2005 it was a
number of years before some
decent bugs were found in it. I
think it was a bit more from
security assessment found a
couple overflows or something
and again there's been so
many ‑‑ so few flaws. I
don't want to talk about IE
because IE doesn't follow this
track record so well, but when
was the last time you saw a bug
in internet information server.
Everyone's scratching their
heads. When was the last
time you saw a decent
overflow in exchange server?
It was a long time ago.
They got the service side
down and it is due
to the script. I don't know
what's going on with internet
Explorer. I think they're trying
to compete with fire fox and
Chrome or something but those
guys are doing really well. You
know, the other people,
yeah, it's just like IE what is
going on? I'm confused. So they
actually work for the same
company, they read the same
documentation. Where are we?
Yeah. So, this is the
background. This is the back
drop to Oracle. And when I
retired from the industry in
2010ish I went shark diving and
decided I'm never coming back.
I'm back unfortunately. I
actually gave them a B plus am I
was like, you know, they've sold
they oversold the PL
sequel injection problem so
that's pretty good. Their
processes are looking much
healthier and so on. When they're
releasing products, like when
release 2 came out not bad Oracle,
B plus and I go away diving for
a couple years and I come back
and I'm like what the hell.
What's going on? They revert
back and they're back to an F.
We are going to be looking a the
something very, very simple.
Oracle data redaction. At any
stage this is, these are points
from the Microsoft SDL by
the way. If Oracle had an SDL in
place, a decent one, any one of
these stages would have found
and stopped the bugs that I'm
about to speak about in their
tracks. They would not have
reached the public. So,
establish security and privacy
requirements, attack service
analysis, skipping through to
the end, conduct a final
security review, okay. That
means pen test the product
before it goes out the door.
Anyone with a modicum of SQL
would have found these bugs as
far as I'm concerned. And I
think you'll agree with me by
the time you get to the end of
this talk. So you're going to be
really disappointed so what is
Oracle data redaction? It's a
simple but it's a great idea.
So, if you have a web, a
database application there has
some kind of potentially
confidential information in one
of the columns, for example,
Email addresses, passwords,
credit cards, whatever it
happens to be, you can redact it
so what is presented to the
user, if they select from that
table, is a list of X's or
whatever you want to redact it
with essentially. It's not a bad
idea. We don't have to change
any redaction code. We change
the policy on a particular table
and if our web application is
vulnerable and someone tries to
do a union collect stop in
customer kind of situation, you
know, and snap all the juicy
stuff out there they're not
going to get the secret stuff
because we redacted it. The no
change necessary to the
application code which is I
think really cool. The problem
is at the door, this is in
Oracle 12C, the back port to
Oracle 11 release, it's trivial
bypass. It failed within the
first five minutes of simple
assessment so it's real,
it really speaks to Oracle not
pen testing their products
before they, you know, in their
flagship product before they go
out the door. So, let's look at
some demos. So, before we do
anything I'm going set up a
table called redaction tests and
insert a fake credit card number
into it and then we'll commit
it. Okay. And now so if we
select it. Can everyone see or
do I need to increase the font
size? Increase. Come closer.
(Laughter).
>>> Let me see. All right. I'm
just going to modify the size of
the window now. Layout, width.
All right. And zero. Okay. No, I
said zero. Okay, perfect. Okay,
so if we select from select CC,
that's the name of the column
we're going to redact and ID
from redaction test see if we
get the credit card. We don't want
the world seeing that credit card
We're going to create a policy.
and now if we grant select
and update to David, then
connect as David, we
do a select from the redaction
test table, we can see we get a
list of X's essentially so we
can't see that date today. The
data has not been changed. The
data is still there, it's just
the way it's been presented to
us has been modified. If I had
bypassed policy and stuff like,
that redaction policy wouldn't
patch me and I would get to see
the stuff. If I was like a DBA
for example I can see the data
but I'm not a DBA so I can't see
the data. All there is is the
redacted data. Let's get the
data out. There are a couple of
X and L inquiries that allow you
to run X inquiry. One of those
XML query functions is
called XML query and it
allows you to query using
X query. This stuff in the middle
(inaudible)
this is x query stuff and
we're using SQL and XML
query
function. Now, those of you who
do penetrate testing and get
involved in exploiting sequence
injection rule understand the
importance of functions. We can
execute this XML inquiry to
get the unredacted data back. We
are going through a path that
they've forgot about. A simple
pen test anyone with an idea of
how the Oracle data server works
and everything like that would
have said they should probably
check XML inquiry to see if
they can bypass redaction and of
course you can. If you're going
to, if you're looking for
information like, you know,
monitor and everything like that
the XML table function is
also vulnerable so it's not just
sufficient to protect against XML
inquiry. Table needs to be
do as well. These are trivial.
This is SQL. One of the DML
operations update, we'll
concentrate on update has a
returning into sub codes and
what returning into basically
says once I get this table if
there's an auto column for
example a sequence that's
incremented or whatever return
that value to me so I can
include it later on in a further
application code. This returning
into feature, guess what? We
don't, it doesn't have to
be incremented or whatever. You
can just basically specify
return the credit card column
information into this buffer and
print it to the screen so there
we go. So, we can see what's
going on there. We've updated
the redaction test column set
the ID to itself so it doesn't
modify data but it returns the
credit card column into the
buffer and then printed the
buffer to the screen. So, again,
trivial way. Anyone who has done
will know the returning into
clause. So anyone at Oracle who
I assume they know SQL because
they work in Oracle would have
said well, do a pen test on this
project and we got to check this
because without it you'll be
able to bypass redaction, you
know. The predicate is
not is not protected
either so I would like to take
credit for this one but turns
out Al Cornbusker had already
done this. He noticed that the
web predicate was not protected
either so you could pass it to
UTL underscore HTTP, you know,
dot request and send it tout
some server somewhere and
there's a couple other functions
that can be used that generate
an error or alternatively what
you can do is simply force it.
So we'll create a, sorry, create
a little procedure here
and let's talk about what it
does. We select from the
redaction test table the where,
the credit card column sub
string so we get the first
character of the proper credit
card column and convert it to a
letter and check if that letter
is a zero, one, a two, a three,
a four up to nine. Once we find
out what the answer is we then
go to the second character and
the third character and the
fourth character. Essentially we
guess it as we go along. Now we
created that procedure where we
sorry. So, if we execute that
little procedure now, it
basically, you know, returns the
information. So, given that the
information once we can't get
that information back from the
where inquiry unless of course
you're shelling out using UPI
it's not protected its another
thing to be aware of. They can't
fix it in the where clause. The
other stuff has been patched
apparently but this they can't
fix because they need to be able
to inquiry in the predicate. So
just be aware of that if you are
using that redaction. If you
If you have the privileges to
execute DDMS underscore redact
you have the privileges to create
redaction policies in other
peoples schemas. You have the
privileges to remove redaction
qualities from other people
schemers. Again that's another
thing you need to be aware of.
If you've got privileges on DDMS
redact you have control over
everyone basically. There is a
thing called a lateral sequence
injection in most database sis
and what it essentially does is
where there's information coming
from, say, environment variables
or stuff like that, that's
considered obviously trusted,
you know, by database server and
often the developers will like,
you know, do simple straight
encapsulation and that may
become vulnerable to sequence
injection. For example,
in, um, a couple years ago
people used to think if it was a
number, you could not exploit a
number, a numeric sequel
injection. You can because you
can specify the number format in
a certain way that the comma or
the decimal sign is actually a
letter. So, essentially we can
provided we can create a
synonym, we can create a
function that eventually
is concantonated as a
number and would be translate it
into a, P01. If we have a P01
that gets executed. So, because
of developers thinking you
can't, if it's a number how are
you going get arbitrary SQL
into a number there is a way but
they forgot about that. So
remember I spoke about PL sequel
injection almost being gone and
Oracle doing a good job in that
regard. They have left all of
the numeric sequel injection
flaws so typically this stuff
I'm sending them these days is a
numeric sequel injection flaw.
or a (inaudible) which is
a whole other ballgame.
But anyway, we have to
I've got five more minutes for
questions and stuff like that.
So I'll wrap up. Just last
point. As I said this is basic
stuff. A pen test of the product
before it was shipped should
have found this stuff and this
really speaks to the Oracle
security processes so going back
to what Mary Anne Davidson said,
the beginning, you know, that I
spoke about, holding the vendors
to a higher standard, well, this
is what we need to do. If you
don't, if you're running Oracle
database servers and you
don't like the way they're
treating you as far as security
is concerned get on the phone to
them and tell them I'm going to
start buying something else
instead because we really need
to get this improved. So thank
you for listening. Are there any
questions? >> (Inaudible). >>
Sure. Oracle, which features? >>
(Inaudible). >> Database vault. No,
I haven't. But I know other
people have done sorry.
Oracle database, I have played
with Oracle database vault yet. I
know some other people have done
great research in that area and
I can't think of who it was off
the top of my head but if you
Google it, you know, you'll find
it but it's on my list to do
because they've patched a lot of
stuff. The same with audit volt
as well. I suspect it's going to
be like the rest of Oracle
product. Sure. Any other
questions. Sure. In the front
here. >> (Inaudible). >> I'm
sorry? >> (Inaudible). >> It
should be, yeah. You just need
to. yeah. Right. I think
we'll wrap up. I thank you
everybody for attending.
Hopefully it was useful.