why are what
[Music]
and are correct
that's the problem tempering usually you
would want to make this in a demo
lighting because it's easier to see the
colors and they go fast
it goes like straw brown blue colorless
and that's it
you're already over the limit let's see
if I yeah I cut it correctly you can see
there straw it's already there Brown
blue light blue and the dark ray what
we're after that what still most in the
end it was a light blue and we are close
enough we're now 52 roughly at the rock
wall so now it should be filed
[Music]
yeah filed by it so it's under 55 so
that's our tool it should be now quite
bendy possibly yeah there's a lot of
give to it so I call that the success
it's now spring 3 so that's a harness
that I would be happy with you know tall