[Music]
hi everyone
we are back for another talk we are
coming to
the last of the last talks of the day
this is the second to last talk
unfortunately i hope you're enjoying the
conference
we certainly are enjoying the conference
ourselves
we have some amazing lineup
such cool speakers and this talk is not
an
exception in this talk we're going to
talk about uh
buzzing but not me but the speaker is
going to talk about buzzing
which is something that i'm quite sure
most people in the audience have
has had at some point in time some
experience with
it's a great way a practical way to find
a
buggy code or flaws in your code and
our next speaker is going to tell us how
can we
how we can integrate this uh different
fussing strategies into our testing
strategies
in the best efficient way so
uh let me introduce to you melissa venua
hello everybody i'm excited to be here
and talk to you today about
fuzz testing so fuzz testing is one of
probably the favorite
things i've done over the course of my
career
and so i started many many years ago
as an s den at microsoft now i am a
director of engineering at imparticle
i've done a little bit of everything but
like i said being when i was in estet
and then a developer working on
networking on bing was one of my
very favorite things because i had so
much freedom to explore
and one of the very first things that i
ever explored
was this thing called the forking
service
so i'm going to be very careful here
throughout this talk while i talk about
the forking service because it was known
by
a lot of uh a lot of different names as
you might guess
sometimes it was known as that forking
service
when it annoyed dabs and brought down
traffic sometimes it was also called
that service that forked all my test
environments
um but you get the idea about
my forking service and so what it does
was
something that's also known as traffic
teeing um the basics of it is that it
would send
actual copies of sanitized production
traffic
um from production uh make a copy of it
and then federate it out across a couple
of different parallel production
environments in order to validate
um to validate that the services were
operating correctly
under prod light conditions with prod
like traffic
i know what you're thinking of course
there was anonymization in place we were
always very careful not to be
leaking customer data from production
into um into our test environments also
this was many
many many years ago they have moved on
beyond this
um but anyway so when i joined bing you
know i didn't invent this
forking service when i joined it was
already considered a pretty critical
part of the whole release process if a
release candidate could go
24 to 48 hours without any crashes or
any memory leaks or any weird metrics
then the code was probably able to be
considered stable enough for production
but obviously there were still issues
that were missed um and i wanted to know
how could i take this data
you know this very good production-like
data and how could i use it to drive out
any more issues
so at the time we had an internal
security team who was publishing you
know internal microsoft who published a
set of fuzzing libraries uh especially
with attacks
um and this library was pretty cool it
was a you know i was able to access the
source code to it it was in c
plus and i worked on.net not a big deal
but i thought well if they've already
got you know put together this expertise
to create this library of attacks i
wonder how i could apply these
libraries on top of the pretty good data
that we already have
and then combine that also with the
model of our domain-specific http
traffic
and create a thing called the fuzzing
service
and so the fuzzing service was just the
forking service but
with the layer fuzzing applied on top
and able to run at scale as well
so basically it would just take our
existing good traffic and inject
you know inject an excess attack into it
um anything that he could think of it
had some security specific attacks and
non-security specific attacks we'll talk
more about what those look like in a
minute
um but it would just transform our
traffic into something exciting
um and so let me tell you so the first
time i turned it on
i you know went i was sitting at my desk
and i was typing type of typing and i
sent everybody email and said hey
the release for you know the next
release that's coming up just know
if you see anything weird on the test
beds that i've turned on the small
fuzzing addition to your fork traffic
i don't think it should cause anything
any problems i'm not concerned about it
with the release but
just let me know if there's an issue um
then i locked my he locked my desk got
up and went and grabbed
a t and as i was walking back down the
hallways
i could hear
what this forking service what the heck
happened with the forking service the
beds are down
um i could hear complaints popping up
all up and down the hallways
and so by the time i got back to my desk
i had a bunch of red bang emails saying
what did you do why are all the beds
down can you make it stop
uh so i scrambled and turned you know
turned the traffic off
and lo and behold we started triaging
there were something like eight
different crashing bugs encode that had
been running stably under production
like traffic for
days to weeks there were these eight
different bugs that were brand new
crashes
and so the devs of course scrambled to
fix them in order to save the release
fix them got them out again and then i
came the request came in hey can you
melissa please put that fuzz traffic
back on we want to validate our fixes
so i said sure okay i turned the traffic
back on
and within 10 minutes all the beds were
down again
and so i turned it back off and after
those eight crashing issues have been
fixed there were there were a few more
to be driven out they had been uh
um less frequent than the earlier
crashes but they were still crashes
and a lot of these were crashes that
were in production already they weren't
even in that new code
um so there's more scrambling and more
fixing um
we turned it turned turned it back on
again and this time the beds didn't
crash
for a while uh until they ran out of
memory
because we turned out we had driven out
some memory leaks as well and so once
the machines were stable enough to run
for
seven eight nine ten hours we could see
their memory ramp was doing that
and that they had memory leaks in them
so again there was more
frantic frantic fixes going out
um i don't even i don't remember exactly
how long it took for us to stabilize the
beds again but there were
more than a dozen bugs in code that had
been living in production some of it for
years some of them were very old weird
ghost crashes that would happen you know
1 in 100
million requests we had no idea nobody's
going to chase down that nobody's got
time
um that we were able to reproduce very
quickly with the fuzzer
we had issues all over the place we had
issues in our c-plus plus web service we
had javascript vulnerabilities rendering
on the page we had memory leaks we had
crashes we had deadlocks
we had actual vulnerabilities and we
found all of these things just by making
our traffic look
really really weird um
we had at least one pretty nasty bug in
there there was one buffer overflow that
was causing cross
cross process memory contamination that
took hours to track down and fix
um and who knows what would have
happened if that bug had actually made
it live into production
there were all kinds of really serious
interesting issues that we found
with fuzzing that we wouldn't have never
never found no human would have ever
come
up with the combinations doesn't matter
how many you know doesn't matter how
many teams we put on it we never would
have found it
so let's back up a step here
and let's lay down some definitions so
what
exactly is fuzzing
so the definition of fuzzing is just
generating random inputs to explore the
bounds of a system under test
and these are my definitions that i'm
going to work with here i'm sure if
you're looking online you may see
slightly different definitions but they
should be pretty pretty standard here
so the fuzz testing is just to explore
the boundaries of our system that's
under test so that we can understand
what it's doing
um and and figure out
all kinds of interesting test cases we
wouldn't have come up with on our own
um so what is an attack so can we talk
about an attack an attack is a
as a specific type of data meant to
drive out a very specific class of bugs
so you may have an xss
attack you may have a
xsrf attack you may have a sql injection
attack
you may just have a buffer overflow
attack right is it designed to cause
some specific type of vulnerability or
bug
the manipulation which we'll talk about
is going to be the combination of an
input
with an attack so taking your known good
input or known bad input and then
layering an attack upon it
and then there's three specific types of
manipulations we're going to talk about
the first
is a creation manipulation which is just
a de novo
generated input inserted in place of
your text
so imagine if you have the value of a
header and it goes from you know
your accept header being application
json to
semicolon drop tables
meanwhile an insertion manipulation
would be modifying a known input to
include an attack so
in an example of our header we might
have application slash
j semicolon drop tables son
and finally genetic manipulation is
successively modifying an input based on
system behavior we're not going to talk
about that
too much today because that's kind of a
solved problem
so if you have the ability
to monitor coverage right to monitor
branch coverage of your application
then you can do genetic manipulation to
continue to explore all of the branches
and that's what things like fuzzy lock
do
as they allow you to they have insight
into what they're accessing and they can
intelligently modify the inputs for
successive attacks to try to drive all
the way through your code
so what are the keys to a successful
fuzzing
run so we've got to have a model
right where we'll look at what models
look like you have to have the attack
set which is some of what we just talked
about
you have to have a plan and so
your model is what you care about right
if you are on the http level your model
is the http model if your application
has some json
your model is whatever you're defined in
json
the attack set is all of the bad things
you're going to do to yourself
and your plan is how you're going to
apply that attack set intelligently to
your model to get the best bang for your
buck
so the first thing we're going to want
to do here is define our data model
because again if we're talking about if
you're talking about a simple input
output program
if you're talking about something that's
command line based there's tools for you
you're not going to need to define or
invent anything here you can just go
grab afl hook it up
it'll just walk you walk through you
walk through your application
and you're solved you're good to go um
but if you're talking a service
if you're talking something with a with
a highly structured input model
if you're stuck in something that can't
be easily watched for coverage which not
every language and application
lends itself to do so you're going to
want to be very crisp about defining
your data model so that you can
customize what you're going to do next
to your specific input case
and every day every piece of data is
going to have a model where we don't
just have unstructured data nobody
nobody runs a service that way so for
talking http for example there's a data
model here
right http always contains these pieces
http right has a method it has a uri and
that uri has a specific format
and in that form is for example query
parameters query parameters also have a
separate format which is separate from
the format of the overall uri
likewise headers right are key value
pairs they have a format
some headers are comma separated but if
you get down into the cookie header for
example it's actually a totally
different format right it's
semicolon and ampersand separated
and so the important thing about
defining our model is we need to know
what's important to us
right if i'm interested and i'm running
an application at the http layer that
has
you know say it's reading data off of
query parameters i'm not particularly
interested in fuzzing my web server
not because there couldn't be
vulnerabilities in my web server of
course there could
uh but that's not my job right if i work
for
company x i'm supposed to be testing and
validating company x's application
it's not as much of interest to me to
make sure that that if i'm running on
apache that apache has done their due
diligence
in in um making sure their service is
secure
and i'm not saying we shouldn't nobody
should be testing apache i'm saying it
may not be your primary job to ensure
that apache works right
your primary job is validating that your
application
is behaving as it's supposed to
it's not a good use of my time to be
dealing with apache at the tcp level if
my application is js
is json layered over http
and so the first part is understanding
the fundamentals of your data model and
then understanding what your application
is going to do with that
data model and the specifics of it so
for example if we actually are reading
json post bodies on top of http then
that's going to define what's actually
of interest to us
more specifically it's going to define
what is not of interest to us
because if i'm on json on http then i
don't really care about xml
vulnerabilities
if i'm a purely nosql shop i'm not going
to be all that worried about
about oracle db vulnerabilities injected
in either because
it's not likely to be relevant to me so
understanding
your data model and understanding your
risk layer is going to be
a big deal in helping you figure out
what's going to be really important
right json also has a format all its own
json has
you know specific layering of
parentheses and quotes and then your
application is probably going to have a
specific type of
data model layered on top of that again
right it's going to have required fields
optional fields it's going to have
structures of those fields this one's an
int this one is a string this one is an
array of objects
um you're going to have your own
specific things that you're going to
want to
test for
and so with that in mind we're going to
want to be very
cognizant of our tax election
and so attack selection is is a fun
thing
and it's it's sort of a solved problem
when i say a solved problem i don't mean
that new attacks aren't being invented
all the time because they are
i just mean that if you find that you
are having to invent
attacks you should stop and look around
for example i'm going to show you all
some sample code later that uses fuzzdb
which is an open source solution to
generate attacks out of
my full-time job is not investigating
and
exploiting vulnerabilities that some
people's full-time jobs and that's an
awesome job but those are the people who
should be then
helping to craft attacks my job is
helping to take those attacks and apply
them at scale to ensure that my services
are behaving
as well as can be expected
so lots of things can be attacks
right of course sql injection
everybody's everybody wants to drop
tables that's the old
that's the old best standby um but
control characters
are also an interesting attack just this
um
just this uh this piece here you don't
want to know that i basically crashed
powerpoint twice
trying to put it in right i fuzzed
powerpoint for them they're welcome
um xss obviously it's a set of attacks
more useful if you're going to be
rendering in javascript in some way or
the other but
it can be a useful set of attacks
integer overflows redirect attacks
but don't neglect the benefit of trying
to do buffer overflows with just some
random strings you'll see a little bit
later
that the most mileage out of any attack
i've ever gotten has just been a lot of
a's
and i don't mean you know the seven or
eight a's that are on the screen which
is this is fine
um but you know 20 000 a's
50 000 a's 128 000 a's
lots and lots of a's
we'll start to tell you very interesting
things about where you may have buffer
overflows where you're not cleaning up
buffers where you may
or you may get very interesting emergent
behaviors where things are you know if
you're in a managed language where you
may be
pushing something into garbage
collection you're going to be vulnerable
to being ddosed
or just dost for that matter um
you can get a lot of mileage out of some
very very simple
attack test cases
so we've got our attacks we've got our
data model
um and so great let's generate a fuzz
request and so this
this one to some random website is
fuzzed
and it is you know it's it's very fuzzed
but it's not going to be very useful for
testing and why is that
uh for a number of reasons it's so
fuzzed that it's unlikely to go anywhere
useful
it's unlikely to even leave the machine
upon which you're trying to generate
traffic from much less go to the machine
that you care about much less trigger
the application upon that machine that
you care about
right for one part the verb is the verb
is messed up
for another uri also these not correct
so you're not going to go to the
endpoint you even wanted to get to to
begin with and even if you did
we've injected an attack into uh into
our path
so if we're testing a specific feature
under our application we're just going
to get four or four
if you're testing the 404 that's great
but if you're not testing the 404 then
that's not going to be all that useful
to you um
likewise you know we're missing headers
all together our cookie header is gone
so if we care about the data in the
cookie header well that's not going to
go anywhere useful again
we're still um we've basic is basically
a wasted test case
so without a plan your fuzzing is going
to be extremely scatter shot
it's not likely to get anywhere useful
you're gonna have to spend
a ton of requests trying to get you know
a small fraction of them even to be
acceptable enough to hit the application
under test never mind actually do
anything interesting to it
if you fuzz too many things it's going
to be difficult to find a repro you're
going to have a lot of things that are
just summarily rejected because they
don't even get to the application that
you're interested in
meanwhile if you don't fuzz enough
things right if you fuzz
you know one teeny tiny thing at a time
it may take too long to get a repro for
anything
right one crash out of a hundred million
is unlikely to be something that gets
investigated
and so what you need to do is you need
to make
a plan so the plan can be pretty simple
um here we have a very simple example of
a plan
for fuzzing uh fuzzing an http request
so it says you know the basics here we
want no more than three attacks we want
to use a specific attack set
um we want to fails our method very
infrequently um
remember i'm not saying you should never
fuzz your web server but it shouldn't be
the primary goal of your
of your um if your of your operation
here
so we want to fuzz the method but very
rarely um we never want to fuzz the host
header because if we fuzz the host
header then we're just not
we're not going to get any routing it's
not going to go where it needs to go um
in this specific case
obviously there's ways there's ways
around that um
we don't really want to fuzz our path
that much either because we're trying to
test a specific sub path
uh we want to fuzz our query line like
crazy let's say we know our application
we know that
the path you know the path is not an
interesting host another they're
interesting but
the things on the quarry line are
extremely interesting
so we want to fuzz those like crazy um
likewise we'll take a look at our
headers right we don't want to fuzz
necessarily
the name of the header because we fuzz
the name of the header as we all know
that's just a key value per dictionary
again it's not going to be that
interesting but fuzzing the values of
that headers could be very interesting
especially your authorization header if
you need to be logged in and you
you know we never want to get rid of the
authorization header altogether but
sometimes we may want to fuzz it we
don't want to buzz it as frequently as
the other things because
we're fuzzing you know our authorization
system
and so if we know for a fact that if we
don't off then we can't access the rest
of our request then we don't want to do
it that often
right it's not the most important thing
we could be checking we know it's going
to be an artificial limiter on the
amount of traffic that gets to somewhere
interesting
okay and so
if we take a well-crafted plan and we
apply it here
all of a sudden an interesting request
emerges
so take this one this is very likely to
get where it needs to go
it's on the right it's got the right
method it's got the right
ghost name it's got the right path um
and we've injected you know pretend
there's more a's there
because my screen is only so big we've
injected some a's into potentially an
interesting field on the query line
um likewise we've fuzzed one of the
cookies you fuzz it in a very
interesting way
especially if you have awareness of how
your application is using cookies you
may know that
oh this part of the application has this
you know this
cookie layout and this cookie for
example i know is always used
um as a user identifier and sometimes it
shows up right sometimes it shows up on
javascript page
that's interesting right using your
knowledge of your system to help guide
the fuzzer
so that it can generate attacks well
beyond what your knowledge and
creativity could come up
is the key to crashing your application
12 times in an hour
right this is also a very good fuzz
request it's respecting uh first and
foremost that we have to authorize or
nothing's going to happen you're just
going to be testing your testing your
authorization handler
it's going again to the right url with
the right method
um and it's most important it's json
aware
and if you notice we're not we don't
want to fuzz our json parser
which you know could be interesting
sometimes but that's not
usually the most interesting thing we
could do
and so this is a json aware fuzz output
that says ah this is a number great i've
inserted integer.max
or you know this is a string great i've
injected some
extra xss into the string
and so this request is also very likely
to cause some
very interesting behavior if interesting
behave you know
if there's interesting code to be
explored much more interesting than if
you're trying to fuzz you know
newton's soft jsof json parser
and so let's say you've got your attack
set
you've got your plan um you've got your
data model
now the next and most important thing is
knowing that you've actually found
something
this is actually a pretty hard problem
and if it's you know something beyond
just a straight-up crash and a bunch of
core dumps it can be quite tricky to
know that you've found something
interesting with your fuzzer
um there's a little bit of an art so
first of all it involves knowing
um knowing what your baseline metrics
look like right what do your metrics
look like
in production what does the deviation
from those metrics look like
um especially memory usage that's a big
one
and then being able to isolate and
reproduce down to see
you know do we have an actual memory
leak or is it just that we've allocated
more buffers and so we're using more
memory
right because those are both are both
are potentially valid and both
may look the same in your metrics to an
untrained eye
likewise being able to scan through your
logs look for look for anomalous log
readouts especially if you've got
um really good logger logging or
observability wired in
you can also look for side effects
that's especially good when you're
trying to do
if you've got a bunch of sql injections
or you've got a bunch of xss
xss is unlikely to crash your box
sql injection may or may not right can
be hard
but you can craft your fuzzer with side
effects so that you know
um you know if
uh you know if a certain table gets
written to well then there was a
successful
a successful sql injection um or if you
log a specific message
only if you manage to trigger an xss an
xss exploit
so you can craft side effects or hooks
and once you've got those you could also
use an oracle to help you figure out
what was good and what was bad
um an oracle is just an automated way of
making judgment calls about the things
you found in case you don't want to
spend the rest of your life staring at a
dashboard of
graph go up graph go down um and
entailing log lines like you're in the
matrix
so the oracle will help you set
thresholds on alerts that says ah
this is bad right memory ramp like this
this is okay
remember ramp like this this is not okay
uh somebody a human needs to go look
so we talked a little bit about how you
can find it and here's you know some of
the things you can find
and these are things that i have in the
over the over the many
uh the many many years of my career
these are things i have actually found
i found lots of crashes uh whether it's
buffer overflow or just you know top
level exceptions
uh depending on your language set i
found crashes du jour
so many crashes also a lot of memory
problems because both because you're
doing large allocations and also because
um you're doing strange allocations you
can find leaks
um you can also find thread
contaminations right buffer overflows
um you can find actual exploits right
you can find sql injection xss code
injection
redirect you can find all kinds of
exploits with some well-crafted fuzz
attacks
so there is if you are interested there
is an open source rebound that's at this
github link and i'll post about it as
well
in the chat it's a it's net core based
it's extremely lightweight
it's a library that's meant to be used
to make it very easy to define your data
model we use it actually as a part of
unit testing because it has
it has reusable seeds so you can
generate the same seed and have
reusable test case runs um but there's a
simple fuzzing library that you can use
it's open source you're welcome to
contribute play around with it
no problems
and we are going actually to take a look
at what that looks like
so here let's see here there we go
here is our fuzzer so you can see here
um i've got a very simple program that's
using the fuzzing library to define
a data model and i apologize maybe it's
maybe a little small
there we go so you can see here that we
have a very simple default strategy
which is the plan we're going to use to
fuzz this http
um this this very simple http method
uh a simple http message we're not
fuzzing the method
we're gonna set some very simple
probabilities define our model
we're gonna send some requests here so
let's actually take a look at that
so here we go we've generated some very
simple requests
just a random website on the internet
just you know whatever
you can see they're extremely simple
they've got a count on them we've got a
quarry line they got some
got some headers got a cookie but it's a
really simple cookie
so great now we're gonna fuzz them
so we generated some a's and this is a
random seed
so every run is different never know
what you're going to get
but it looks like it did a pretty good
job here we can see we fuzzed within the
accept encoding header so it's still a
valid header it just has
this uh this
i'm not sure what attack it is but it's
definitely a fuzz db attack injected in
here
um we can also see that there's so many
a's and it's got oh look there's a
exercise vulnerability in here looks
like uh
so this is one request here and we can
see the query line
uh is massive with some additional
injections in there see if we can find
anything else interesting in here
so many a's it's full of a's ah here we
can see that it looks like there's a sql
vulnerability in here
um access alert in here
but for the most part the requests are
actually pretty well formed they're just
uh they're just full of a's so if we
were to actually send these requests
i want you all the way down
where did you go here if we're gonna
actually send these requests now
here we go two of them had bad paths one
of them
interesting right uri too long that's an
interesting test case
and then two of them 503
so if we want to change our seed
you can see something else happen
here we go we're going to fuzz some new
requests maybe we'll see less a's yeah
see
less a's here so let's see let's see
what happened here
let's see this one
[Music]
might not have had anything bad happen
to it this one did right we got a very
modest amount of a's injected in here
interesting things happen so if we send
these requests
totally different thing right probably
one of them had their path found and the
other ones were accepted
the other ones were okay and so imagine
this reproduce not over you know five
requests at a time
five requests per second right five
requests per second
is 300 requests per minute um
i'm not going to keep doing math here
but you can see how this can add up very
quickly
when you're fuzzing at scale so no now
imagine not five requests per second but
50 requests per second that's 300
or 30 000 test cases per minute
that's a lot of that's a lot of room for
ace that's a lot of room for
vulnerabilities uh but more importantly
you have the scale in order to drive out
interesting behavior
because oftentimes bugs are not just
dependent upon a bad code path but
they're a bad
driving them out can be a combination of
a bad code path at scale right
especially when you've got
multi-threading going on
and you've got interactions of you know
thread deadlocks you've got interactions
with different threads one against the
other you've got
memory cross contamination all of those
things are much much more
interesting when you're operating at
some sort of scale
memory pressure cpu pressure etc
so that's that's a very simple fuzzer
does very simple things
yeah so if you want to explore a little
more
of course you're welcome to go grab that
repo
but likewise
there are some other further readings
reading hints here for you
um the fuzzy book is actually a really
great entry level
um entry to introduction to fuzzing uses
a lot of python uses a lot of actual
code examples
um in python uh walks you through sort
of setting up fuzzing from beginning to
end
uh you heard me mention afl before
american fuzzy lop
i believe google puts took it over yeah
google's got it um
uses code coverage for genetic
algorithms really great if you've got
input output based application or a
single box application
especially one in a language that it can
parse mostly c
fantastic solve your problem you don't
need you don't need me for that
you can just go grab the tool and
install it and run with it
uh fuzz db is actually where my
dictionary of useful attacks
came from and i will show you a little
bit about what that looks like
here and so fuzz db
is an open source
set of things so
for example it's just a list of proven
um proven vulnerabilities so for example
here's a stat of things that have been
proven to drive the cause problems in
mongodb likewise here is some
db2 sql injection my sequel local file
read vulnerabilities
here's some
good old xss
look pretty familiar to anybody who's
ever played with xss even once
this is yeah this is standard
um but yeah so that's fuzz tv
free for anybody to go and look up uh
use attacks that have been proven to be
useful
um likewise on blackguard there's a list
of fuss testing and of course if you use
kali
um kali has lots and lots of built-in
security cools one uh several of which
are to enable you to do fuzzing on your
own
whether that's via a proxy or a couple
other tools there's a bunch of stuff on
there that's useful
so let's see here
that's about it thank you all so much
i'm excited to answer questions
we can deep dive through plenty through
some code i've got no problems showing
code or showing some more test cases
we can run some more fuzzing paths we
are back here
i i told you this was going to be a very
interesting talk
and now is the time for q a so let me
welcome
hi thank you hey everybody
enjoy yes we already have some questions
like is your sample code in c sharp
yes the sample code is in c sharp the
library itself is in dot net standard
2-1 so it's compatible with.net core or
net framework i loved your talk we were
talking backstage that it's so
interesting uh so technical and you are
very
uh you explain very well what you're
doing so it was amazing so
i want to thank you uh publicly again
once more
for everything that you're doing for us
and for for participating enough uh
now pink on um for the audience if you
have any questions
again you know you can post them in here
on twitch or
using our discord channel uh so i'm
gonna be
waiting for those questions in case you
you wanna ask melissa something so um
yeah
yeah thank you you know first for having
me i was really excited to
to speak today i love talking about
buzzing um
i don't get to do nearly as much as i
used to once upon a time when i wrote
a lot of code in my day job uh-huh
yeah so it's it's so interesting and i
think it it's
so uh interesting talk about i'm sorry
it's it's very interesting to talk about
security
when it comes to development because uh
there there's so much
improvement that we have to apply yet
uh for many companies and developers
that don't take security into account
so it's good to create awareness and
public events like this one um
about how you can secure your code and
find different uh flaws
using uh very uh i think intuitive
uh tools uh other that's uh
up for discussion so i'm not
sure that the audience thinks the same
but uh they are very easy to to use and
following your methodology you can
integrate this
testing tools to the the testing
strategy that you have already
implemented so
it's a it's a public service that you're
doing
here to secure apps everywhere
yes i'm a huge fan of integrating
uh develop integrating testing and
security
as part of the first like first party
process of getting code out with the
rest of the development pipeline
um like like in the cicd talk earlier
right everything that i do and that my
teams do
has to happen as a part of the cicd
pipeline is to happen as early as
possible so
security right happens built into the
cicd pipeline happens
certainly no later than code building
but um
earlier the better the same with all
testing right
security is is a type of testing
exactly totally um we have a question
here how did you get started in buzzing
you are truly a queen of code as your
twitter
handle says so you have so much
experience uh perhaps you can tell
something about your journey
towards buzzing yeah so i
started with fuzzing um by actually
going to a talk
through it was an internal company talk
presenting what fuzzing was
um and presenting you know the the types
of things that you could find with
fuzzing very
you know very similar to my talk but
given you 10 years ago
um and so from there i found some
resources and i explored with it i
made a proposal to my manager at the
time that i
was responsible for this system and i
wanted to do an experiment to see what
would happen and that's
that's you know the basis for the tool
that we talked about that i talked about
first
today so i just started with learning a
little bit and then experimenting and
that's pretty much how i started with
everything which is learn a little bit
and then experiment and then you learn a
little more
that's a great advice um someone here is
asking for the link and github um
for the sample code so oh
someone shared it afterwards but if you
have any other resources that you want
to share
you cannot do it later on on the discord
channel via text we have some people
that's right
are writing questions right now so let
me
paste the uh uh or they already got it
never mind
yes uh you're fast
if you come next year to nothing con we
will gift you a t-shirt full of aaa's
i would be delighted to come next year
to not think
we'd be delighted to have you back yes
those of you
i'm sure nobody knows my family is from
buenos aires so
i'm always happy to come to you
please don't make me give my buzzing
talk in spanish you won't like it it's
better than my english that's for sure
no no i'm doing my best
you're doing much better than i would be
doing in spanish i promise
okay um we have another question what is
your opinion on cis certifications
um that is a good question i am not a
good person to give
an answer i don't tend to evaluate
people based on their certifications
um i tend to get more practical tests
when i'm hiring so
i cannot give you an opinion either way
i know lots of people
feel very strongly about certifications
yeah i know and it's kind of like a
trend i see people are obsessed with
certifications security certifications
but
uh there are other types of um courses
and certifications that are so much
more interesting perhaps than um
security ones but
i'm talking about myself
right when i was coming up and starting
in the industry certifications were not
it was different than it is now so
it was it wasn't a thing for me so i'm
just not as fluent with than you know
the needs of a certification yes
totally i get it um some people are kind
of obsessed
with them there are other ways to prove
knowledge
yeah there's lots of ways to prove
knowledge you can do certain the
certification route you can do
the open source repo route you can do
just proving it in an interview group
there's lots of different ways
totally i agree uh we have a another
question here
are there any online platforms for
learning uh
that you recommend
um online platforms for learning so it
sort of depends on how you like to learn
so
um i will say my friend tanya janka has
a
she hacks purple is her twitter account
she has um
a website i think is called we
hackpurple.dev that she's putting
together a learning
a learning platform specifically for
people who want to get into infosec
so i i definitely approve of that and
not just because i was on her podcast
the other day
um and she that's a pretty good place to
start she's got a lot of good resources
for people who want to start
um in infosec um otherwise i just
tend to float around and see you know
see who see who
see what talks are being recommended out
of my network because
it changes so quickly as a field that
the platform that was the best platform
last year is not the best platform this
year oh totally
target a year ago
yes totally i totally agree the
technology changes
so fast um
if you feel free you feel free to
share those links uh afterwards on our
discord channel because i'm sure many of
these people in the audience are really
very interesting
in checking them out yeah so i will put
those in the discord
since well um does anybody else have a
question
yes someone says so yes please
exactly everybody's asking foolings
so yes we will share them with you yeah
i will share them i promise
okay melissa it has been so good to have
you here
uh thank you again we are so grateful
for your talk you have made this event
even better
uh you and all the speakers who are so
we are so thankful
um so uh if you have anything else to
say
if you want to comment on uh fuzzing
something else
feel free to do it otherwise uh we just
want to thank you for your participation
and i think that'll be all
yeah thanks a lot if you're interested
of course to learn more there's the the
github repos open source feel free to
open issues or make pull requests or
just make commentary um and i'll see you
all see you on the discord
great we will so i'll leave you
uh i'll leave the audience and uh
and uh every one of you with uh sheila
next
because we have the last talk coming on
unfortunately this event is coming to an
[Music]
end
so
[Music]
[Applause]
you