[Music]
hi
everyone welcome back from our
small break let's say technical issues
we had some technical issues i'm gonna
admit it but
we are back that's the important part as
you may notice i'm speaking english so
the next talk it's in english
be aware that you can use our live
translation channels on
the discord server um i'm so excited
again about this talk
because it's really interesting it's a
topic that you may not see
everywhere when it comes to information
security and i think it's very good that
we got the speaker to
to participate in nothing for you guys
just for you
so um she is has a very interesting bio
actually um she's a computer uh
engineer actually a software engineer
senior software engineer
but she also has a master in degree in
mechanical and
aerospace engineering and it has many
published research and papers when it
comes to machine learning and also
robotics
and now she's going to talk about how
you can secure
your own web application pipeline when
it comes to
continuous integration and continuous
delivery
so she's going to talk about how can an
attacker
compromise these pipelines and also how
can you what can you do
to to secure this i think it's a very
interesting topic
and without further to say i'm just
gonna present to you
malicious mcgregor
hey everybody my name is melisha
mcgregor
and i'm a developer advocate at conducto
but today i'll be talking to you about
securing your web application pipeline
from intruders
if you're interested in more things like
this you can follow me
on twitter at flippedcoding and i post
about cool tech stuff all the time
so to jump right into it i'll give you a
brief
overview of what we'll be talking about
today
first we'll go over some common best
practices
in devops and just ci cd pipeline
creation
then we'll talk about some of the
reasons why cicd security gets
overlooked and why that's such a problem
we'll get into how intruders work which
is probably
the most interesting part because you
get to see
just how attackers think and learn about
some of the tools that they use
then we'll go over some of the things
you can do to prevent your pipeline from
getting attacked
and we'll go over a few real examples
in circle ci conducto and travis ci
personally it always helps me when i see
a tool
in action so when it's actually being
used in another tool that's commonly
used
on a work process that helps me out a
lot so i'm hoping it'll help you guys
out too
nope i said you guys wow that's so
ingrained
i mean you all we're not all guys here
but then we'll get into the key
takeaways
of what you should learn from this talk
and just some of the things you can do
to take security going forward forward
so some of the best practices for just
general cicd pipelines include
keeping your build size small because
you don't want your build
to run for a really long time when
you're trying to deploy
different feature changes and bug fixes
to production possibly multiple times a
day
you want to make sure that these builds
run really fast
and you also want to make sure
that the pipeline is the only way to
deploy
changes to pride so part of the devops
philosophy
is having this automated
process that any developer or user can
come through
and deploy a code change to production
for customers to see
you don't want any hidden processes or
secret scripts that only one person
knows how to use
so just make it a good practice to only
deploy changes through the pipeline
and something else you really want to
make sure you do just for testing
purposes
is keep all of your environments in
parity
with production so if that means you
have to
update databases overnight or
you need to include different services
in your app as it goes through different
environments
just try to keep it as close to
production as possible
because this is how you'll get the most
value out of all of the testing
and security checks that you do in your
ci cd pipeline
and something else this is one that a
lot of devs are guilty of myself
included is that we don't always run
tests locally first
i'm sure a lot of you have typed that
dash dash
no verify on a get push but
try to make sure you run your test
locally first
not only does that save you a lot of
time
you know going through the build process
and spinning up a new node or a new
server
it just helps you find those bugs
a lot earlier so that nobody else has to
know about them
and you can fix them and look like the
hero
and then documentation so
this is something that a lot of
developers don't really
enjoy but it's so crucial
to keeping a pipeline that's
maintainable because there's it's not
very often you'll go
into your pipeline config and make
updates
so you might want to make sure that even
if it's just comments
in the pipeline config itself you want
to make sure
that the process is well documented so
that other developers or other devops
engineers can come in
and figure out where to make changes and
why
certain variables are set a certain way
just
make some good documentation it doesn't
have to be really long
it just has to be there
but now we'll switch gears a little bit
and talk about why
cicd security is overlooked so
often so one of the big reasons is that
there's just time restrictions
remember we kind of talked about how a
good cicd
pipeline should have a small build and
be really fast
well when you're trying to get all of
those things done in a sprint or
as a hot fix it's really
hard to justify including extra steps
so that's why security gets left out a
lot
is because it's just seen as this big
time constraint
if we go through security testing it
means that the app gets delayed
for deployment by who knows maybe hours
if they find bugs it could get deployed
by days or even weeks depending on how
long
it takes to address those security
concerns
so a big reason security gets overlooked
in ci cd
just has to do with time restrictions
and then something else that's kind of
an interesting problem
is that it can be really hard to find
answers
so when your pipeline breaks or there's
some kind of
bug it's detected it can stop
at any point in that process and if
you've tried to trace through
circle ci like their visual
visualization of all of your notes it
can get a little bit confusing if you're
working with something really
complex like deploying a lot of micro
services
so you run into these cases where you're
trying to debug
the pipeline and when you finally get it
working
most people have done hours of just
googling so when you feel like
building the pipeline itself is just
that
difficult adding more tools to it
makes it even harder to find answers
when things break or when things don't
run or deploy like you expect
something else is that most of the cicd
configs are written in yaml and that's
fine
it's a really structured language but
it's not something
that developers or even devops engineers
just
use all the time so it might be a little
bit harder to
remember what the syntax is or to even
remember which questions to google
you really get this situation where
people know what they want to do but
finding
the right syntax in the language
just makes it a little bit trickier and
that
extra layer of trickiness
is just one of the reasons security can
get overlooked
another thing is that how often do you
actually update a cicd pipeline
most of the time that doesn't get
touched until there's some kind of
new service added or there's a huge
feature update and you need to update
where certain artifacts are getting
deployed
those type of changes don't happen
super often so when you're just not
looking at the pipeline all the time you
tend to forget about it
and when you forget about it all of
those updates and all of those
fancy little widgets you were gonna add
well you forget
about those two and usually security is
lumped into those nice little widgets
and that's also how security falls along
the wayside
and something else which is a little bit
more subtle
is that now there has been more of a
push
for developers to own the pipeline
and to get more involved in the devops
area
but the problem with that is not all
developers
are familiar with pipeline flows some of
us haven't touched a pipeline we just
worry about the bug fixes
the feature requests and making sure
that our unit tests pass
but as far as going in and updating a
circle ci config
is just not something that developers do
often or really at all
a lot of companies have dedicated devops
engineers
and shout out to you all because
that is just something so different from
what we do
every day that it's a little bit
overwhelming
so if you task a developer with adding
security to your pipeline
you'll get something but it might not be
as optimized as it should be for a good
ci
cd pipeline
now the fun part so we get to talk about
how
intruders work basically what they do
is really simple they use attacker tools
yup there's no guy just sitting in some
dark room
trying to hack into the mainframe there
are
tools that are sophisticated and very
user friendly now
if you guys ah i did it again if you all
are familiar with kali linux then
you've probably seen a lot of the tools
that just come installed there are tools
to scan ports
there are tools to automatically run sql
injection attacks
there's tools to run cross scripting
texts
really easily like i'll show you a few
of them because we're going to use the
same tools they do
to try and keep them out of our pipeline
but they aren't doing anything that you
probably don't already know how to do
if you know how to set up any new
project
on the computer on any operating system
then you probably know how to use
attacker tools or it wouldn't be
too big of a jump for you to get up and
running with them
something else that they do that we
typically don't do is
check for misconfigurations so
when is the last time you check to see
if new developers automatically have
admin permissions
or when's the last time you actually
deleted
those user permissions for employees
that don't work at the company anymore
they just
poke around and try to find these little
holes
in your application in your pipeline
just throughout your entire process
and they're looking for
misconfigurations like maybe
an environment variable isn't encrypted
or
maybe you left some kind of secret
in your version control but they're
looking for things like
that you things that you might normally
just overlook
in a rush to get it deployed
so kind of like i mentioned you'd be
surprised
how many repos just have secrets
in their version control and of course
you can go in and delete it
but it's in version control so anybody
that wants to take the time to dig
around through your code
can and they will find those secrets
if they're in there that's something
that you really
want to keep an eye out for
so when you're about to commit changes
and i know that we do this for testing
sometimes
try to make sure that you aren't leaving
any production
level secrets in your code
it it's not really okay to do it with
the development environment
especially if you are keeping parity
with production
but before you commit any changes
ever make sure that you did that double
check
and that there aren't any secrets in
your version control
because if there are somebody will
eventually find them
this is also another tricky one
sometimes
we leave ports open that we forget about
so maybe you moved a service from port
3400 to port 7500 but you still left
all of the 3400s open
the that's a way that they can just get
access to your server
and you potentially not even know about
it because you aren't listening for
anything on that port
and because that port is just open there
is a chance you don't have
any type of security around it like
maybe you don't even need
a user login to access whatever is
running on that port
this is just one of the ways that they
can start poking holes into your
application
and find ways in
so make sure that you don't have any
extra open ports
when you deploy your app to the server
you've provisioned
and this is a big favorite for
developers you know those github
messages where they're like hey this
package you're using
has these vulnerabilities or when you do
an mpm or a yarn install
you'll see those hey you need to fix
some of these because they have
really bad security problems but they're
patched
so something that hackers and other
attackers count on
is that you don't keep all of those
packages up to date
they know what the weaknesses are so
they'll just check
all of your code to see if that package
is included
and if it's not the right version number
they already know how to attack you
so they can just go in to
that specific library and have
some form of access into your code that
you don't want them to
so make sure that when you're going
through all of your security auditing
you do take the time to look at
the third party packages you're
importing
into your application or else they will
find it
so now i want to share with you some of
the tools you can use
at different phases in your devops
process
to get some of that security coverage
that'll keep your application
safe and less hackable
so there are four phases four main
phases
in the devops process you have the build
phase the test phase
delivery and deployment so with the
build phase
this is when you get your application
code it's been committed with all of the
nice shiny changes
and it's ready to build an artifact
that you'll send to the production
server
so before you get that artifact that
you're going to ship to production
these are a few tools that you can use
to
do some security checks
owasp zed is a really great tool
if you're trying to do just some general
attacks
just to see if like there's any
cross-site scripting allowed or
if there's any sql injection
that can happen in your app this is a
pretty comprehensive tool
and you should definitely check out
their website
so let me show you guys
show you all this
you know even recording this before
the conference it's always just a little
bit
tricky so
sorry don't have that tool open
apparently so i'll just jump back into
the presentation
hopefully you guys didn't see too much
but
you can google any of these and just go
to the home page and check them out
sql map is perfect if you're
specifically worried about sql injection
attacks
so it'll go through your app and find
any places
it thinks it could possibly
do a sql injection attack on and it'll
just try it
and if it finds anything it'll give you
a little report of what happened
next is arachne and it's probably my
personal favorite
just because it does the vulnerability
the vulnerability checks
for your packages it does some
automatic s cross site scripting checks
on i think all of your input fields
and it just does a lot of
brute force attacking that also
a hacker would do so this is a tool that
a hacker would use
to just test your website and see if
they could get access to
anything on it
and then next is burp which is probably
one of the more popular tools
and it's another one of those tools
where you can pretty much
check for everything in the build phase
if you haven't
noticed you want to check for everything
that you can possibly find
that way you don't get an artifact you
can't use
you can send this report list back to
the developers
and they can work on security patches
for whatever issues you find
and another tool that helps to automate
all of this
is called gauntlet and it actually
lets you use multiple
tools to do security checks in this
phase of it and in other phases of the
devops
process but with
gauntlet you can use any of the tools
you see
and automate them in your
pipeline so now that you know about some
of the stuff you can use in the build
phase let's
go ahead and add one more because this
is the one i'm going to show you in the
demo
so sneak is another one that i really
like
especially for javascript projects
because
it does pretty much the same thing as
arachne
but with a javascript focus
so we'll see what that looks like in a
real
pipeline configuration a little bit
later but now let's talk about some of
the
testing phase tools
so the owasp dependency check is a
really good one
because it's going to go through
and just recheck everything so
this is particularly looking for things
like
packages that have been identified in
the owasp10 and stuff like that
retire.js is another one that's just
gonna go through
and look at packages that are known to
be
either vulnerable or they've been
deprecated
things like that and it's specific for
just
javascript applications
then if you want to get into more
enterprise level tools
sonotype nexus and varicode are
also really good tools for checking in
this test phase
so if you have a large application
that multiple developer teams are
working on
with different deploy and release cycles
one of the enterprise level tools might
be a better choice
just because they give you more fine
control over how and when
tests are executed and they let you
check for specific security things
regardless of
what program and language your
application is in
then in the delivery phase this one is a
lot smaller
and a lot of people just lump it in into
the deploy
phase that's why you just see cicd
because the d in cd
stands for delivery and deploy
but not all organizations follow that
process
even though most of them really do so
the delivery phase is when you're
taking the artifact you've built after
it's gone through all of those unit
tests
and you deploy it to other environments
that aren't production
so this is when you're deploying to
staging
or to a qa environment it
should deploy to environments that are
close to pride and maybe you have
specific things that you test for
in each environment but either way
you can add a few different things to
this phase
that'll help you get through some
security testing
faster so the first
tool is actually not a tool
it's a pdf that walks you through some
of the steps
you can take to make sure your
application is ready for an audit
so if you have an app that's
in medicine or you take
customer billing information you might
have to comply with
hipaa or pci or if you're running
ads you might need to deal with the gdpr
compliance these are some tools that
help you
figure out the process for doing that as
you get closer to production
so chef has a really really good tool
for this too
and it's called inspec and the way that
they describe it it's like security as
code or compliance as code and it lets
you
it basically lets you reassure
yourself your team and the company that
when
this application goes to production
you don't have any worries about
compliance
to whatever regulations your app is
governed by
and then lastly we get to the deploy
phase so this is when you've gone
through all of the build
checks this is when you've tested
everything
because we all love unit tests so much
this is when you've done the soft deploy
to staging
and qa where you can check for things
like you can run your integration test
to see how your third-party services
are working with your tool
this is where you check for those
last minute things in the deploy phase
you are testing directly against
production
so you're trying to make sure that your
production application is as secure as
it can possibly be
so this is when a lot of companies bring
in pin
testers and try to have hackathons to
see
if there are any um security holes
but a few services that
one of you all could even go sign up for
right now would be
hacker one and bug crowd these are just
communities where companies put bounties
out for anybody that can find some kind
of security flaw
so if you're interested in trying to
hack
i don't know i've seen some from
microsoft i saw
one really big one from apple but
if you're not interested in the big name
companies
you'll find a lot of other companies
that will give you exposure to how
hackers
really work or you can use one of these
services to get somebody to try to hack
your app
and see if you've made all of the
security fixes you needed to
and something else you can use is called
signal sciences
and it's a different service so
what this one does is kind of more of a
monitoring thing
it makes sure that nothing
you're not getting any weird hacky
activity
and then threat stack is pretty similar
to signal sciences
it just makes sure that if there are any
threats
which it's actively checking for it will
send notifications to
your development team to your devops
team to anybody that needs to know
hey there's something that needs to be
fixed because this is a security hole
but now we'll talk about some of the
other things you can do
since you've seen the tools
keep your user permissions up to date
please
there have been a few old clients that i
won't name
that even though i haven't worked for
them for three or four years
i still have admin permissions
to pretty much everything i did when i
worked there
i'm not sure if they've deleted it since
because i'm a little bit scared to go
try and log in
but if you have new people come on the
team
make sure you give them the permissions
they need as soon as they start
and when you have people leaving the
team make sure you delete those
permissions
as soon as you know they don't need them
anymore
and try to pay attention to the security
patches from the services you use
because those are third-party services
you don't control their code you can
only
do what they let you do so when they
push
a security fix in a new version you want
to make sure that you
update to that version even if it causes
some breaking changes to your code
because you rather have to deal with
a few broken i don't know a few broken
components or maybe some api responses
don't return like you expected but it's
much
better to deal with that than to deal
with being a headline on the news
because
all of your customers data is leaked to
who knows who
again make sure you don't have
unnecessary ports open
there are so many port scanning tools
available that are just free
and hackers really do use those to get
access to your servers
don't don't make it that easy for them
because you probably aren't
watching an open port that you don't
know about
another thing is that whatever cicd
tool or pipeline thing you choose to
build in
check out their security features like
do they have tools that are built in
that help you run some of these things
automatically
so that you don't have to add them or do
they have
different packages or different
plans that include security audits
so be mindful of what you're using to
build your pipeline in because it might
have everything that you need
then you can also use an iast
securities tool to push any
type of security issues it finds to a
tracking system
so maybe during your testing phase
it finds out that you have this really
really deeply hidden input field
that does allow for cross-site scripting
as soon as it finds that it's gonna take
that issue
and push it into jira or
it'll make a github issue or it'll send
a text message
whatever it does use something that
actually lets you know there's a problem
it's fine if you have to skip the
security test
like if you don't want to stop the
deploy to production because of a
security issue
but you should have a way in place to
get
all of this information to your
developers or the respective team that
handles them
then make sure everything is encrypted
so
at this point i'm pretty sure everyone's
using https
and that helps a lot but behind the
scenes
if you do have any secrets or
environmental variables
make sure that they're being encrypted
there
have been so many stories about
just different databases getting hacked
because
all of the passwords were stored in just
plain text you want to at least
make sure that that sensitive data is
encrypted
in a place that is not easily accessible
then if you want to stay on top of the
really really big security issues
just follow the oasp top 10 list
i think the last time i saw it
i want to say cross-site scripting was
still one of those
top 10 issues that and sequel injection
which is kind of wild because we've
known about those
issues for so long but they're just hard
to guard against
so make sure that at the bare minimum
your pipeline tries to address
all of those top 10 issues if they apply
to your application
and then use the same tools that the
hackers are using
there's no better way to figure out how
secure your application is than to use
the exact same thing that hackers are
going to use
to try to get in so when you run across
a tool
or you have a hacker friend that tells
you about this cool thing they found
go use it see if it's something that you
can integrate into your ci cd pipeline
somehow
because regardless of whether you do or
you don't
it's good to know about them so that you
can try and prepare your code
and your infrastructure for any attacks
that could come
and now we're going to get into the real
world application of this
so i'm gonna show you a little code and
i will go ahead and say this
is like just some skeleton code
because i can't show you the super
sensitive information
that does go into a config file but
basically in this case we're just going
to pretend we're deploying
some kind of javascript app to
production and we're using
sneak as our security check
but basically the way that this works in
circle ci
is you get this sneak orb and
you use it right before
you get into all of the build
phase things so in this case
we're checking for any
high severity vulnerabilities
so this is going through and checking
all of our packages
to make sure that none of them have this
super high severity threshold and
if they do then we're not
going to stop the build because it
doesn't fail whenever it finds an
issue but we will know
that if they find if it finds a package
that has a high security threat
it will let us know like in the console
it'll output some stuff for us
and once it's gone through this scan you
just continue through
if you want to include more tests a good
place would be after the build
or even up here before you run more
tests
just to see if there's any changes you
need to make in the code
before it gets further into the deploy
process
and it starts triggering other nodes to
execute
so that was circle now we're going to
look at an example in conductor
this one is a little bit different from
the others because
it doesn't use yaml you can actually
write your pipeline in
python which honestly is really awesome
because you can run unit tests
on your pipeline like there's no other
tool where you can do that
so on top of making sure that your
application is secure you can make sure
that your deploy pipeline is
still up to the standards you expect it
still has all of the pieces you need
and you can write your unit test with
python like you would for any other
piece of code
but in here you see where we install
like we set up our container then we go
in here and we make our different nodes
where we run our install phase
and we go ahead and do our sneak test
and that's gonna return whether there's
any vulnerabilities or not
but after that we go ahead and run our
regular
unit tests then we go through the build
again
you can do more tests here or you can do
more tests before
just as long as you test before the
artifacts are deployed
but the cool thing about conducto is
that you can just see everything
just how everything is working you can
define what goes
into your node and you can see the
different steps in your pipeline really
easily
but that's how you would include
security testing
in conductor so now the last one we'll
look at
is travis ci which is really similar to
circle but slightly different in this
case
we're still deploying some kind of crazy
node.js app and we're going to go ahead
and do
whatever install stuff needs to happen
but then we get here to the sneak
test and we've added a different
sneak command here and basically what
this
does is if there are any vulnerabilities
found
it tries to fix them
basically but this
is how you would include sneak testing
in a travis ci pipeline
so i know that those were really short
simple examples
but i wanted to show you that including
these
tests in your pipeline doesn't have to
be super complicated
it is often as easy as adding an
extra command into one of the nodes
so the main thing that happens is when
you
add these commands is it changes the run
time
for the builds because you have extra
tests to run
so you have to find that balance of
adding security tests
versus how long it should take a bill to
run
so the common metric
for how long a bill should be is the
coffee test
can your pipeline finish running in the
time it takes you to go make a fresh cup
of coffee
if it does then it's probably fine if it
takes longer than that
that's where that balance really comes
in because you'll have to figure out
whether it's worth the extra time to run
those tests
or not because that's going to slow down
your time to
production so i'm going to go ahead and
wrap
up with some key takeaways
keep your secret safe is just like those
secrets you're hiding from childhood you
would never tell your parents
you don't want those things in version
control
where people can just come through and
do a quick search and find it
keep those secrets encrypted in maybe
an environment file or
hopefully inside of the cicd
tool you're using so like in conducto or
in circle ci just go in there
and define your environment variables
and they should be
good to go as long as nobody hacks into
those accounts
and then whenever you do some kind of
major update to a project whether it's
adding another feature
or you're adding another service
go through your pipelines and just do a
quick audit of the configs
do you see any nodes that
aren't being used anymore that happens
a lot when you're switching to different
services or you're updating your code
and then again check that your
application tools have been patched for
any known vulnerabilities they're going
to check for this low hanging fruit
first so make sure that you're covered
and lastly don't be afraid to try new
tools
sometimes the ones you pick when you
initially start a project
just don't grow with you in the way that
you thought it would
and that's okay there are no really
right answers for the tools you should
use or the devops process
you should go through just do what works
the best
for your application and your company
but
always try to include some kind of
security check
in your pipeline and i hope that those
examples really helped explain some
stuff
and maybe clear up where you add those
tests in your pipeline
and i really hope this was a good talk
for you all
if you have any questions for me you can
always
get in contact with me on twitter at
flippedcoding
or on twitter at conductotech either one
of those
i'm available and yeah
security and pipelines is important
because you can just
automate it who doesn't like more
automation
well i promised you an interesting talk
and in fact this
was such an interesting talk and now i
have for a live q a with
me uh militia welcome to nothing con
hey i hope you guys like the talk do you
have any questions for me
well we have over 200 people in the
audience
so if you have any questions feel free
to ask them
same as we did before using this uh
twitch
chat or you can also do it uh using the
discord server i see some people are
actually writing on discord
while we wait for these questions to to
pop up um
i was wondering and this is kind of a
personal questions
but do you really have a master's degree
in mechanical and
aerospace engineering i mean that is so
interesting we didn't talk about this
on our previous meetings but i mean wow
tell us more
more about it it's so interesting so
yeah i have
my master's in mechanical and aerospace
engineering
and i did my thesis project on an
autonomous
golf cart and teaching it how to
interpret
like pedestrian and passenger intent
and based on how people were moving in
like the algorithms we used we were able
to get the golf cart to like
move around people in non-threatening
ways
it was fun wow oh my god i mean that
was like my dream job when i was a kid
so i kind of
envy you where did you get it
to oklahoma state university and
we just had some really cool projects at
the time
like we got the veladan the lidar that
google uses on their like autonomous
vehicles
so working with that was really cool
my god i really want to research that
i'm going to start
and i may start a new career from now on
okay we got some questions here
what resources do you recommend to learn
more on
circle circle ci and conducto
um honestly for both of them just
to get started with anyways the
documentation
they have pretty straightforward
examples to make
basic pipelines and then you can just
add different nodes and
whatever processes you need from there
that's great um we got another one for
the cicd sect talk
how would you integrate sonarqueen into
it does it compare it with sneak
that it kind of is
like sonar cube is kind of like sneak
it goes through and checks for the
vulnerabilities but
i haven't personally used it before
so i'm assuming it would be really
similar
like there's just a certain maybe an orb
in
circle ci or there's some package you
can download for conducto
to get sonar cube
like set up in it
i have a lilly lily you
are writing a question that's so long
that's taking so long
i've seen her writing soon it's like 10
minutes it's so funny
we got another people writing as well um
while we wait for these questions oh
okay here
uh for people who are university
students uh can you give us tips
to venture into cicd oh
um honestly the best advice is just
to go try to build the pipeline even if
you don't have a super fancy
web app or data science project
just try to put something together and
see if you can
push your local code to github
and trigger a pipeline build and i don't
know maybe try to deploy like
a react app to netlify with conducto
or with circle ci or something
just try to do some kind of real project
it doesn't have to be big as usual
just get practical with it hands-on
do you also have recommendations for
understanding bug bounties for nuis
um honestly the hacker one little
tutorial course
is really good because that's why i
learned a lot about hacking
like they break down some of the
concepts really easy
so if you aren't quite sure of what
approach to take
that's that's a really good place to
start
that's great yes i i totally agree
um we got another one coming in uh any
tips for integrating snake
with container registries how fast is it
for this type of task that is a really
good question
congratulations
yes i guess if you put the i guess if
you integrated sneak
in maybe like a docker file
you could put it in a container registry
but it kind of depends on
what checks you're doing like sneak has
it where it can do some surface level
scans or it can go a little bit deeper
if you need the test to run really fast
in your pipeline you might just want to
do
like the surface level check for
vulnerabilities instead of the deeper
dive for
like cross-site scripting checks or sql
injection checks
i get it um how effective is the use
of containerized servers
you guys have some really good questions
honestly they are super effective just
because you can
deploy the same code that you've been
working on locally
to production without worrying about any
weird os
changes or any packages that you don't
know about
getting included into it but
that's that's the biggest thing with
containerized servers is they just give
you that consistency the whole way
through
that's great um we got i think one more
question coming in
i'm not sure i'm waiting for it because
i see him typing
louise if you want another chance to
to ask another question this is your
chance i'm giving you the chance right
now
um well if not i think we have finished
the q a but
still you can linger on on the channel
and
answer these questions via text melissa
is going to stay with us for the rest of
the conference i guess
if you want to of course i want to i
don't want to pressure you um
but thank you so much for joining
nothing con
and thank you so much for joining to
this live q a which is so important to
clarify all these questions that we all
have when it comes to
like uh so such important topics and hot
topics
like this one so thank you so much for
your research truly
thanks for having me it's an honor
likewise let's go to a
short break and we'll be back with
another talk
[Music]
[Applause]
you