maria who will be speaking about the
generalized montgomery coordinate a new
computational tool for isogeny-based
cryptography
thank you for introducing me
okay first i explain
the main results of our study
first we propose a new concept that
generates mongodb konate that unifies
some special coordinates of fd curve
used for isogen based cryptography
for example uh exco nato mongolian cub
an x coordinate of mongolian minus cub w
coinage of elvis cup every coin and half
cup
and omega coordinate or twisted jacobi
intersection cups
and next we constructed general
quantitative formula formulas using the
general memory coordinate
and
finally as application we construct new
formulas and coordinates
okay here contents and why first i
introduced one coding type formulas
first i define the ft curve
we call a pair of smooth algebraic curve
e of genus one and it's point o oe and
fd curve
and here are some examples of fd cards
a montgomery cub is a cult defined by
this equation and oe equals zero one
zero
and this is among the minus curve
and it was called this curve different
by this equation
and only is equal to zero one and half
curve is the difference with this
equation
and always as zero
and uh an important property of epic
card is uh etikov has a commutative
group structure and its identity point
is oem and this image represent uh
this group operation or the uh case of
mongolia
and this point p and q and we can set
the point this point as p plus q
and then
set this point as a doubling p and this
operation becomes a commutative group
operation
and next i i define as sargonii
and i saw generator subject to morphism
between fd cars that is of group
morphism and this is astogeny and uh
this is a very important concept for
isogen physical cryptography
and
in isogen-based cryptography
there is a very important formula for
computing isogenes
there is formula is the formulas uh
it's computed from the subgroup g of e
and it outputs an empty curve e over g
and an i sergey
phi from e to e or g with this kernel
equals to g
and in isogen-based cryptography we use
these formulas and compute london many
exogenous
and here so important for computations
for isogen-based cryptography
and first one is addition
and second one is
doubling
and we can use we can construct a scalar
multiplication by using these two
formulas and third one is a complete for
image points
and last one is the complete4 for the
wing curve e over g
so uh these last two one is a very
fullness
and any isogen based graph system use
these four computations so uh it is
important task to
make these computation efficiently
and in isagen-based cryptography we use
one cornea type formulas
and there are some one corner type
formulas are known the most basic one is
a formula using x-coordinate of
monomials
and this is
and this is called and the first uh
formula is the suit addition
by using this uh formula uh equation we
can compute the x coordinate of p plus q
from uh x coordinate of p and x
coordinate q and x coordinate of p minus
q
and second one is the sub doubling
and we can compute the x coordinate of
the p from x coordinate p
and alpha alpha is a
coefficient of
and we call this question one recursion
and by using these two formulas we can
compute the scalar
multiplication
and next this is a
formula for computing isogenes
and the first one is a form s4 image
point and we can compute the
x-coordinate of phi p
from the
exponent p and x-coordinate of points in
the
and kernel
second one is a formula for domain card
the uh the target of this formula is the
boundary coefficient of e over g
and we can compute uh the moment
coefficient of a or g from the amount of
equation of e
and
x coordinates of points in the kernels
so we can compute
all four formulas by using x coordinate
of monomial curves
and second basic one is a w coordinate
of edwards called and edward's curve is
this
curve
and the double coordinate is defined by
d
x squared y squared here it is a
quotient of edwards call and we call
this quotient elves coefficient
and similarly uh
by using uh the recognition we can
compute the solution so we can compute
every coordinate of p plus q from a w
coordinate of p and w coordinate of q
and double cognate to p minus q
and similarly we can compute uh the
recording determine p from the root pe
and algorithm coefficient d
and here also the uh formulas for uh
computing isogenetics
then we can compute uh
w coordinate of yp from the wp and
uh
the double coordinate of uh points in
the kernels
and we we can also compute the uh
formula column in curve and the target
of this formula is uh
edwards coefficient of a or g
so uh you may know uh these two uh
cases are very they these have the very
similar formulas
the last one uh the performance for
clean cut is a totally different but
addition the suit that ring and image
points are
looks very similar
and this is not only for the mongrel
cards and foreign it also uh occurs for
the
w coordinates of the house card
and i didn't write it but uh
omega coined it uh twisted the aqua
intersection cups also similar coins
uh so there is one question i lies uh is
there any way to unify these formulas
and in classical uh
there's a famous theory that's a
recumbent line this is a
sorry for one conan type formula
and in this theory uh by using uh data
functions we can construct some one
coordinate type formula
and by using this theory uh for the
scalar multiplication we can construct
explicit formulas so by using data
functions we can unify the two of four
formulas
uh in the previous right
and for isogen computation uh there are
some studies
and there's some algorithm but these
algorithms are a little bit complicated
and these algorithms are target for not
optical these are targets turret in uh
uh
three uh available varieties
of io genius
so uh
it it seems hard to adapt uh use
unifying
the
all four formulas
so we think uh
we need another approach to unify
these four formulas
we are going to the generous memory
coordinate
uh before defining one recognite uh i i
explained about the diversion of the
function
for function f4 we call c we go the
following divisor a device of a function
then here is a very important
property for different function for
function e and g
if these devices are equals
then
there's a constant value c and f equals
c times g
and now uh we have the
definition of generals among memory
connect
for
e and its subgroup g and the point are
in this set
and define the function hd also as uh
satisfying this uh property
and we call this function a general's
mongolia coordinate of e
next i explain
some important properties of this
function
first
these 7
holds if we compute the h g r 0
e plus r 0
it is equal to the g over
h g other p for a
longer constant c
we can prove this very easily
by uh considering the divisor of the
left hand side of this equation and
consider the light the divisor of the
right hand of this equation and we know
that these uh devices are same
so there is a constant value c uh
satisfying this equation
then by using this sum we can define the
normalized transmog recognition
if the constant values equals one we
call this general coordinate and
homogeneous monomial coordinate
then here are some examples of normal
genes among recognition
for among recurves x coordinate is a
normal generally coordinate
0 equals 0 the set of 0 and g is the
trivial group
and for mongolian minus curve no margin
mongrel kuni is a
the square root minus one x is a normal
origin smaller coordinate
and
what it was called uh the inverse of its
mean the one over w
it's the numerator and small recognition
are there is a point at infinity and g
is a cyclic group of all the four
and four half card adobe coin8 is the
normal general coordinate
and r0 is a set of a point at infinity
and g is
the trivial group
so uh
[Music]
later i explained the uh generalized
formula from the uh gentlemanly chronic
so this is the reason why these cognate
have the similar one coordinator
formulas
it is because they are corresponding to
the numerators memory coordinate
then next i explained another aspect of
the normalization recognite
a normal generator coordinate h igr cell
can be represented by the composition of
x coordinate of mongolia called e over g
and an isogeny by e to e over g
okay and these are the some properties
of adjacence
and next i explain the uh general
formulas
of the general monogamy coordinate
and the first formula is the
pseudo-addition and for any inverse
genome we call it it holds that this
equation
and and it is also kind of easy uh
proved
by the comparing the the red file
divisor and the right size of divisor
and these devices are equals so uh there
is a uh
known constant value c and by
substituting some good points to e b and
q and we find their constant value is
equal one
and next uh
there's a
formula for the doubling
and here are i you know the new concept
alpha h
g l0 and this is the constant value i
usually computed from the general
coordinate hdr0
and we call this alpha ah general memory
coefficient
so uh also uh subducting also hold for
any normal genes among read coordinate
and third one the formulas for image
point
and we uh
pour on isogeny by satisfying the
uh this property
and it and then there is a normal
smaller generator coordinate h5g file 0
and it holds that this equation and this
is the formula for image point
then here is the
last formula and formulas for computing
column curves
the target of this formula is a
generally generalized monomial
coefficient of h by g and pi i zero
and we can compute easily compute this
coefficient because this is either
computed by the
general mongol coordinate h phi g fire
zero
so uh we can uh construct the formulas
focus on emc curve and actually uh this
formula can be represented as a lesson
function of alpha and of hp earp is a
point in the columns
but this is one problem
this formula is not a function of p
so we cannot use in the discussion of
divisor and
these formulas are not unique
in fact the formula for
x-coordinate among recall and the
formulas on the double recognition cards
are totally different
so there is another question like
how do we constant construct the other
formulas
the key is a division polynomial
and here's one proportion and n is a
possible number and then the polynomial
of psi p and phi p
with the integer coefficient
and satisfying these
three properties
and we call the polynomial uh
sine m as the uh
ms division polynomial of generous
montgomery coordinate
and by defining this uh
concept we have the next seven
and if there is a two different formula
for computing cooling cards the
difference of these formula uh can be
represented by the
psi l
times some rational function
so uh we can theoretically construct any
formulas by using this 7.
okay and then finally i explain the
application
uh first application at
the construct new formulas
uh the from the theory of generalizable
coordinates are formulas of x coordinate
memory cards and the dozen double coins
edwards called are two three same
and so we can uh transplant an efficient
formula as fd cards
to uh
uh tractable among recall and this is a
new formula so among recurve
the formulas for computing uh following
cup
and here's the expensive result
and we use the svc library
and
the
the in image of the horizontal is a
degree of
isogeny and vertically the layer of the
previous formula the cost of previous
formula and the new hormones
and under this red line is the
part of the
our new formulas are more efficient than
the previous one
so uh the
at most add about the five percent
more efficient than the previous one
and there's a final application
we construct a new coordinate among my
mars curve and it is a generalized
boundary coordinate
and by using uh this coinage we can
use efficient formulas for the
generation formulas of genetic molecular
kinade
so uh some item-based schemes using
montgomery mine's carb for example csof
are
expected more efficient
okay my presentation is over thank you
for racing
[Applause]
all right thank you for the nice talk
are there questions for the speaker
uh so it it seems like
like a problem with um
like
one coordinate representations is that
you can't distinguish a point and it's
inverse
are there any like it seems like you've
showed that all of those representations
would have that problem right
are there any like one coordinate
representations where
you can distinguish a point from its
inverse
uh sorry oh uh
you mean that is there any
uh one contact formulas that we can the
uh exp experiment
more connect
sorry i i i answer i know i i can't i
didn't catch your question
uh like uh so if you if you're only
taking
the x coordinate on a say on on the
montgomery curve right you can't
distinguish
now you don't know whether you have like
p or minus p
right so are there any are there any
like
one coordinate representations where you
could do that or
have you proved that is impossible or
like yeah i guess that's my question
your question is is there any other
representation for one corner type
congress
you mean yeah where you don't have that
problem uh
the answer is we don't know but
this is one of the future work uh for is
there that research research uh any
other uh representation for one contact
formulas okay
thank you
right do we have some other questions
okay let me ask if there's any questions
coming from zoom
so i have one question actually um can
you go to the slide with the graph
yeah i'm curious um
uh i mean it seems like there's a sort
of
infinite search space of possible
possible formulas that you're like you
start with one formula and you can
modify it right so how did you how did
you search through this space
uh okay and uh i searched by that this
is a previous my work and then it is
already known that using edward's car we
can compute uh efficiently but edward's
car is not so tractable so
but by using this theorem we can use the
adwords curve and the formulas over the
curve
to that of the monomial cup because
these formulas are
same
so uh
the so the how do we search for the more
efficient one is the
i sorry i don't know but uh how to
refine this formula is that
the answer is uh it is already known for
the editable that's everywhere it was
called
but then on the on the next slide where
you have the graph how did you find do
you know that those blue points are like
the best that you can do
uh this is uh
this is a parameter for the hivc library
and we can check this many primes at
the many degree primes and uh
and
we can compute the cost by using sfvc
library so
[Music]
it is a prime of the sibc library
all right thank you any other questions
okay let's thank the speaker again
[Applause]