talks cannot be delivered in person so
the next two talks
are going to be given remotely
they have to change last minute and
these are this is the only set of talks
that are going to be
given remotely in this
event
so i understand
laxmi is there
hello yeah
yes perfect so can you please share your
screen
yeah
okay perfect is it fine yeah yeah it's
it's playing fine and um hold on let me
make sure we can see you yeah it's
playing fine right
yeah it's playing and we can see you
okay
excellent so
the next talk um is on cmc ml inference
secure against the malicious clients at
semianas cost
laxmi is going to give the talk and
that's going to work with nishan
shantran divya gupta and akash shah
thank you so much
yeah
thank you
um
good morning everyone
i am uber from microsoft research india
and in this talk i will discuss high
level ideas of our result constancy
and this work is published at u62
so the problem of inference is as
follows here are two entities a client
who holds his sensitive medical data and
an insurance company that owns a
well-trained machine learning model
which could classify clients as high low
risk or high risk based on the client's
medical data both the parties want to
learn this classification and my way to
do this would be for the client to send
his data to the server who then learns
the inference and shares the result with
client
but the problem with this knife solution
is that it does not preserve privacy of
the parties as the server loves the
sensitive data of the client in clear
secure inference tries to solve the
problem of inference in a privacy
preserving manner
two threat models considered implied
literature for the problem of secure
inference are the semi honest model
where both the parties the server and
client are honestly participate in the
protocol execution
and because of this weaker threat model
in this model we have super efficient
protocols due to results like
gasoline and kryptonites delphi secure
ml siren crypto2
and the other stronger threat model is
the malicious model where one of the
parties can arbitrarily can
choose to arbitrarily deviate from the
protocol because of this richard the
security guarantee the protocols in this
setting turn out to be highly expensive
bridging this gap another interesting
model
that was introduced for secure inference
is the client malicious model but the
server is semi honest but
the client could behave maliciously
this is a reasonable model as there are
scenarios where the server is reputed
and may not have any vested interest in
cheating the client whereas usually
thousands of clients interact with the
server and it's unreasonable to believe
that all the clients would be semi
honest
this model was introduced in the result
called muse
which was authored by lei mukul mishra
srinivasan adapa which was published at
u6 2021
in this result they also give explicit
model extraction attacks against
existing semi honest secure inference
protocols
which are much efficient when compared
to just black box access attacks when
the client
behaves maliciously
and this paper also builds secure
inference protocols in schleich
malicious model but this protocol
though it provides this intermediate
secure
intermediate
protocol that secured again in this
intermediate threat model
this is much less performant than the
state-of-the-art semi-honest protocols
so this made us wonder if we could build
secure inference protocols in the client
malicious model that are as efficient as
semi-honest protocols and with our work
simsy we could positively answer this
question
and simsy stands for secure inference
against malicious clients
heading into technical details the
building blocks that we use are as
follows
we use authenticated shares which are in
the client malicious setting which are
defined as follows
so two parties the server and client are
said to hold shares of a field element x
if the server
and the client hold x 0 and x 1 such
that
x 0 and x 1 sum to x and authentication
of an element x is defined as
alpha into x where alpha is a uniform
mac key that is chosen by the server
and the parties are set to hold
authenticated shares of x if they hold
shares of both x and alpha x
the security guarantee here is that
given authenticated shares annex the
client cannot forge authenticated shares
of any x prime not equal to x by locally
manipulating his shares by cannot i mean
that this is only possible with
negligible probability
the next building block is a garbling
scheme
so at a very abstract level a garbling
scheme can be viewed as a functionality
that allows two parties a garbler and
evaluator to evaluate any boolean
circuit c on their private inputs a and
b respectively for simplicity assume
that the circuit
just outputs one bit then the
gargler inputs his input a to the scheme
and the evaluator inputs b to the scheme
and then as the output from the scheme
the gargler learns
a pair of uniform labels denoted as k0
and k1 and the evaluator learns
the label kc where c denotes the output
of the circuit evaluation on a and b
the output of the scheme which are these
uniform keys can be later used by the
parties to learn the circuit output we
call this procedure as the garbling but
the gargler sends two surface attacks
encrypting with zero or zero
and one using labels k zero and k one
respectively and the evaluator can
decrypt the ciphertext corresponding to
kc
to recover c due to time constraints i
haven't told you how the evaluator can
locate which of the two ciphertext to
decrypt and this can be done securely
using the point and permute optimization
but for this talk we will not get into
those resets
the security guarantee provided by the
garbling scheme is that
each party learns uh nothing other than
its own input and the output
of the circuit evaluation which is
denoted by c here
and garbling schemes can also be easily
generalized for circuits with multi-bit
outputs too
now
um i'll go on to summarize our protocol
framework
so
typically a neural network is a sequence
of alternating linear and non-linear
layers where linear layer consists of
operations like matrix multiplication
convolutions etc and non-linear layers
consists of operations like relu max
pool etc
so
the protocol framework is as follows
first the clients
the client's input x
is
authenticated and these authenticated
shares are fed as input to the linear
layer first linear layer and
at the end of the linear layer
evaluation our protocol outputs
authenticated shares of m1 into x where
m1 denotes the matrix to be multiplied
in this linear layer
these authenticated shares are further
fed as input to the next non-linear
layer which outputs
authenticated shares of f1 of m1 of x
where f1 is the non-linear function that
needs to be evaluated in this non-linear
layer and this pattern follows
we use additive homomorphic encryption
to perform linear layer evaluation and
more or less the ideas are same
how on how to evaluate linear layers of
the prior work and major contribution of
our work lies in the non-linear layer
evaluation and that will be the focus of
the remaining talk
so
let y denote the output of the linear
layer evaluation the previous linear
layer evaluation so
therefore the protocol invariant by the
protocol invariant parties start the
non-linear layer evaluation with
authenticated shares of y
now in this non-linear layer evaluation
we need to
be careful about three issues
firstly we need to ensure that the
malicious client inputs the correct
share of y into the non-linear layer
evaluation
secondly we need to correctly compute
the shares of f of y given the shares of
y
and then finally we need to ensure that
the client feeds in the right share of f
of y into the next linear layer
evaluation
these input consistency checks that we
need to do in steps one and three are
crucial and are responsible for major
cost
in use
let's see how we tackle this how to
tackle these input consistency checks
so let's see since since the linear
layer outputs authenticated shares of y
a naive solution could be to input the
authenticated shares into the carbon
circuit and reconstruct both y and alpha
y
inside the kerbal circuit and track that
indeed the authentication is correct
but this would involve representing the
field multiplication as a boolean
circuit whose secure evaluation turns
out to be expensive using garbling
schemes
we provide a super lightweight solution
for this issue in simsie on a high level
what we do is to reauthenticate why with
the help of a garbling scheme with the
help of a simple garbling scheme that is
we recompute we compute another fresh
sharing of alpha into y using a garbling
scheme that just reconstructs y which is
just a simple addition circuit
before going into how we exactly do this
reauthentication let's see how does this
reauthentication help
now suppose that we
somehow have this reauthentication we
need now note that we end up with two
different sharings of authentication of
y
one from the output of the linear layer
evaluation and another is the
re-authenticated that we just computed
now with these two instances of the
sharing of the same value we can
publicly reconstruct the difference of
the sharings and the server can check if
the difference reconstructs um if the
difference equals 0 or not if it equals
0 it means that the same sharing of y
was used by the client in the non-linear
layer evaluation if the difference is
not equal to 0 then we detect that the
client is cheating and we abort so this
is possible by the randomness of the
mackie that was chosen by the server
so here um this is how the
reauthentication helps and
thankfully we need not do this
consistency check once for every
non-linear layer
and in our paper we show how to club all
these consistency checks for all the
non-linear layers together into one
single consistency check that can be
done at the end of the protocol before
revealing the output
okay now
let's see how do we actually uh do this
re-authentication using a simple
garbling scheme
we first garble a circuit that takes in
shares of y from both the garbler and
the evaluator so here the server is the
grappler and the client is evaluated so
this k scheme just takes in both the
shares and it reconstruct the shares of
y using a
boolean circuit and then it output share
software
note that uh here
we will just talk about the output of
the garbling scheme and not the output
itself so instead of the evaluator
receiving by the output y itself it
would receive
the output is as follows as the result
of this garbling scheme for every eighth
bit of the output y the server who acts
as the garbler learns a pair of labels
ki0 and ki 1
and the client who acts as the evaluator
learns the label k y i where y i is the
ith bit in y
now for each bit of y i will slightly
tweak the
d garbling procedure to obtain shares of
alpha into y i
the server chooses its share of alpha y
i uniformly and encrypts
0 minus alpha y i 0 using the 0th label
and
alpha minus alpha by i zero using the
one label
and he sends across these two ciphertext
to the client
and then the client using his key kyi he
recovers
um alpha by i one
now that by the definition of the
ciphertext it's easy to see that the
reconstruction of the shares that the
client and server hold are in in
indeed reconstructs to alpha by i
now that we have shares of alpha and y i
for each bit of y i for each bit of y
shares of alpha into y can be obtained
by taking local linear combination of
the shares with appropriate powers of
two
summarizing
[Music]
our solution ensures consistency between
the output of the linear layer and the
input of the next non-linear layer by
re-authenticating y with the help of a
garbling scheme
and then we have seen how the how this
re authentication helps and we have also
seen how the
the
authentication actually happens
then we can use the same techniques to
ensure consistency between the output of
a non-linear layer and the input of the
next linear layer
that is we can actually use the above
garbling scheme itself
to
to also compute share uh to also compute
and output shares of f of y and then we
could compute shares of alpha into y in
the same manner as reauthentication
and then we have also noted that we only
need one single amortized consistency
check at the end of the protocol
so just to give an example of analytical
comparison of course
um we take the
relief circuit as the non-linear
function and then sim c requires just
sim c requires a communication of just
18 l lambda bits whereas news requires
communication of 293 l lambda bits where
l stands for the log of the field size
that the computation goes in and lambda
stands for the computational security
parameter
in our result we also show how to push
majority of course to an input
independent preprocessing phase
now um finally concluding with the
experiments we do experiments on sinc c
news on benchmarks uh
um
mnistensifat10 and
simsc is 23 to 29 times more
communication efficient than news and it
outperforms views by 4 to 8x in a high
bandwidth setting and it outperforms
news by 6 to 11 x in a low bandwidth
setting
and um
surprisingly simsy also communicates 21
percent to 41 percent less than the
state of the art semi honest protocol
delphi
implementation of simsie is available at
this link so
yeah
thank you any
questions thank you so much thank the
speaker
i'm not sure you can hear the ovation
but
there are these people applauding yeah
yeah yeah i could hear the clamping yeah
perfect thank you no so
you finished on time we do have a time
for a question if the audience or people
in soon have a question
so we have a question maybe you can say
yeah as i mentioned
i don't think she's hearing you so i
maybe you can come here or say it again
and i will be
so you said by this technique you uh get
around the field multiplication problem
but uh you would still need the field
addition to be done in order to
reconstruct the share right yeah yeah
field addition is quite cheap right if l
is the size of the
um
if l is the bit length of the element
field multiplication would need l square
and gates whereas field addition will
only need l and gates right
so
it's much cheaper than field
multiplication and
yeah
okay yeah that's quite bearable cost
okay thank you so let's thank the
speaker again
yeah
thanks everyone bye
thank you