of the day
and
we have
abdel
excellent so he shared his lies already
can you can you speak of that to make
sure we can hear you
so we can see the slides
yes uh sorry yeah i i made that more
okay no problem
so for the last stock of the day
abdel is going to be giving this talk
through the looking glass benchmark and
secure multi-party computation
comparisons for rallies
and this is joint work with kashif navas
eugenio salazar and victor zukaz
yeah hi everybody thank you dani and
thank you for being there
i know this is the last talk of the
session and i am the only thing
separating you from the coffee breaks
i'm gonna try to be as fast as i can and
thank you to the organizers to allow us
to do this online
uh i our wish was to be there and to be
able to give this presentation live but
because of certain circumstances outside
or control this was not possible uh
hence i recommend you to also attending
daniel scudero talk at the wrong session
it's gonna be interesting
as well so as danny mentioned uh we are
gonna talk a little bit about release
today uh it's a it's a word that you
have heard many times already in this uh
in this session and release typically
need two things they need a
a fixed point representation a
flattening point representation some
a way to
to process rational numbers and
comparisons so we're going to talk a
little bit about how you can
do that for release what is the state of
the art and how you can combine the
state of the art to obtain the best
results when you implement results okay
so i'm gonna go
wait let me see yes i'm gonna go to our
first slide uh it's like that you
probably are gonna see like 20 times
during crypto so i'm gonna talk a little
bit what mpc is so you can imagine any
set of parties they want to compute a
function together
and they want this function to be
computed in a way that the inputs of the
parties remain secret and you have some
correctness guarantee on the output okay
the typical way to solve this problem is
to
outsource it to a trusted third party so
like you give the information to an
entity that you trust it performs the
computation and gives the results back
okay the magic of npc is that it allows
you to get rid of this
of this trusted entity
okay
so you can imagine that you have a magic
box and in this box
it's not controlled by anybody this box
can perform the operations that i just
described it can calculate the function
it can give you a privacy guarantees and
it can give you correctness so npc does
this in the real
world are you moving your slides by the
way
uh
yeah can you see it no unfortunately
it's stuck on the on the first line
oh man
let's see no
now it's moving yeah please continue
okay yes so sorry guys like i think i'm
not gonna maximize it because if not
it's gonna be
like that again so
uh just to recap
mpc lets you do this in the in the
in the real world using mathematical
protocols okay mathematical products yes
so now let's talk a little bit about
values
relus are rectified linear units
they are a quite popular activation
function you can find them anywhere
nowadays in
not only in the ppml domain but also in
other applications that doesn't require
security why is that is because they are
fast they are good representing data
that you
yeah that you would typically do using
sigmoids and they don't require as much
of
a computational power as you would do
for the sigmoids which is also quite
good on the encrypted domain right
because non-linearities are quite
expensive and as long as you can do the
comparison fast and you have a way to
represent the fixed point arimatic you
are on the other side and you can get
rid of the
of the
sigmoids so how fixed point arithmetic
typically works for npc for an unbounded
number of parties
well the most typical construction was
introduced by saxena and katrina and
this was many many many years ago and
it's the question that you see on the
screen okay where you have some mantissa
that i'm gonna call v that lives from
zero to some power two to the k
and these are integers of course and the
precision is given by that p that you
see there the two to the minus p in
reality this v
leaves on some
on some ring or
on some field this being npc for the
matter of the stock i'm gonna assume
this uh q that you see at the end it's a
prime hence this is a finite field
and i'm not gonna tell you what is that
the space in between 2 to the k to 2 to
the k plus kappa
it's gonna be abducted for the time
being okay
so every everything works well and fine
until you come to multiplications when
you multiply multiply two numbers using
this representation
you quickly run into a big problem like
that is that the
space needed for representing the b
expands
so this is where this space that i was
mentioning
comes into play
this space is typically called slack and
it allows us to use probabilistic
masking
to bring statistical security
once you use this kind of masking so the
authors of katrina the elders katrina
saxena they propose a fixed point
truncation protocol that allow us to
reduce this space that because of time i
cannot explain this into detail but it
requires the use of a slack
they also propose a comparison protocol
that also uses slacks reuses the same
concept to be able to compare two
numbers in this case
you can subtract these two numbers and
compare them to zero
and the protocol is based on extracting
the most significative bit
so imagine that your number lives in
between 0 and 2 to the k again if your
the most significant bit is 0 it means
that it's negative if your most
significant bit is 1 it means it's
positive
so the trick here is how you produce the
masking the masking is produced as you
see on top
where
you have to
where is composed by these by these are
prime and these are double prime the r
prime is the randomness up to 2 to the k
and sample bitwise
okay so we use the random masking again
that uses a slack and these allow us to
have this complex equation
somehow that
it's capable to determine what is the
most significant bit
and the most important thing here is to
notice that there is a comparison inside
this equation but the interesting thing
is that that comparison is against the r
prime and the r prime was sampled
bitwise so this allows us to use a
bitwise comparison
that can be taken for a by that can be
17 implemented using any binary circuit
and it's not quite efficient but you can
obtain it that way and that is how
katrina and the hog in this case decided
it would be a good way to use this by
the way these two protocols are
extremely commonly used you can find
them in scale mamba in mps speeds
they are everywhere
and this was 10 years ago
i think one two years ago rabbit
appeared rabbit is a little bit
different the comparison here is in
absolute terms so there is no concept of
positive and negative and
the comparison is done against some r
and this r is a public constant
in the domain in this case for the
authors the domain was bounded by some n
that's why you have an m in the end and
an important detail is that the r is
sampled b twice okay
the method explodes the
commutative properties of addition
so
it produces a couple of equations using
the following elements first the x mask
with the randomness
that is called a
then the b that is basically the a plus
this capital v that you see there and
then dc
together when they are mixed up uh
for some process that i'm gonna also
adopt from this presentation because
there is no time to explain
you come up with these three basic
comparisons that when are added in the
way that is stated there
gives you the x
is smaller than r okay
one of these is public the other two
contain sacred data but the secret data
is r and as i said to you the r is being
sampled bitwise
using ella bits
hence this can also be performed using a
boolean circuit okay
if the m as i said at the beginning is a
prime number then the sampling on r
bitwise has some trouble right
so
in this paper what we try to do is to
take all the stuff that you saw try to
mix it up so that we produce the fastest
comparison possible and we also use
state-of-the-art elements to evaluate
the bitwise comparisons that you saw
there for that we used something called
zaphod it's an mpc mix protocol
contribution of a couple of years ago it
allowed us to mix hsl 17 which is a
something akin to bmr to evaluate
garbage circuits in a distributed
fashion
and
full threshold implementations of
arithmetic circuits like speeds
like overdrive speeds or whatever
variation of speeds you
want and it allows us to do that in
constant rounds so it's amazing so
the first thing that we did is to try to
use support with rabbit as i said to you
there there is a problem with the
sampling the problem with the sampling
is that it's done bit wise so hence we
use two techniques that the authors
succinctly mention in their paper a
rejection list
and using a prime that is close to a
power of two and we use
the subhot techniques and dabbits to
instead of elevates for the sampling
then we incorporated also a slug into
rabbit and we change fundamentally
rabbit we use the random sampling for
from katrina and we use subhead for the
evaluation
and finally
we
come up with something that we call
beyond katrina
it's a unique protocol in the sense that
it uses the fastest the less than
implementation from rabbit that we have
to also adapt
the flow and the random sampling from
katrina
and the evaluation from zapcod and
[Music]
for sampling
the circuits were also compiled using
vhdl and then transformed to crystal
fashion
so that it can be used by the the
framework later on so our testbed is
quite simple by machines they see each
other
we use a scale number 1.14 and then we
did extra modifications on a scale mamba
so that we can
use something that we call offline
gardening so sad foot is reactive which
means that garbling also happens online
we modify it so that we can break a
spray garble the circuits in the in a
preprocessing phase and then
do the evaluation of aurelius as well
we also
compile the circuits as i said using the
hdl the original circuit and then we
used a hardware synthesizer to try to
accelerate
the circuit execution as well and this
is the takeaway so this is a
time map
the orange box there is the time that it
takes using
to execute a relu using mps pits with
the typical comparison that is
implemented there that is katrina uh
as you may see it's quite significant
when you compare it with the fastest
version of private that we have that is
rapid slack that is actually much is uh
faster than than
than katrina and if you use a beyond
katrina you can even reduce the times
further and if you use the offline
garbling uh that is eighty percent
faster than the young katrina the the
improved was quite astounding when when
when when we finally implemented this
but to be fair these are the timings for
all the methods so typical rabbit
using a rejection list and with a power
of two they were the slowest ones but
you have to also bear in mind that
ravi's rabbit implemented with a
rejection list has perfect security
so that's a super nice characteristic to
have this is the
chart that you saw above as you can see
the difference with the original katrina
is quite significant but if you take
only rabbit slug and beyond you can see
that when we use the hardware
accelerated version
the results are much better so these
were tests
that we perform in
one two machines we introduced in the
chart that you see on the right we even
introduced some delay instead of just
having the two machines talking to each
other we have some artificial
delay so thank you so much for your time
the paper is available we also have a
repo with all our resources so you can
use it if you want and that's it thank
you again for all your time and again
please go and see danny's talk at the at
the rome session and enjoy your coffee
break thank you
thank you so much
you did receive innovation as well of
course
uh so
one quick question from the audience if
there's any
so just a quick question of that like is
there any difference between fields and
rings in your protocol
well uh not really like not really you
can use uh anything
that you want but in this case it was
simple to explain it using it feels more
evident yeah okay no that's great to
hear so let's thank the speaker again
and