hi i'm linka this talk will cover
material from a paper studying the
messaging protocol of telegram which was
joined work with martin albrecht kenny
patterson and igor stepanov
given the focus of this workshop i will
narrow it down and mainly talk about the
attacks in the paper
so briefly i will first motivate why we
did this work and introduce the protocol
in a less formal way
i will explain the attacks both on the
protocol and the implementation level
and to conclude i will briefly mention
what we learned from the proof side of
the project
telegram has grown in popularity in
recent years claiming to have reached
550 million users last year but that's
only a part of the picture
the thing that makes it especially
interesting is that it gained a
reputation for being a protest app
around the world
it was used for coordinating protests in
hong kong and belarus just to give two
examples
in these protests it was always
described as an encrypted messenger on
power with signal or whatsapp even
though they give very different security
guarantees in practice
the cryptographic protocol securing
telegram is custom-made and does not
follow standard practice
yet it has not received much detailed
study to date
three attacks were described in previous
versions one theoretical and cca attack
and two attacks on
implementations there is also a recent
paper that proved telegram to be secure
in a symbolic setting however it
abstracted away most of the details of
the building blocks of the protocol
further most of the focus on telegram
has been on so-called secret chats which
are supposed to provide end-to-end
encryption
however they have very limited
functionality and seem to not be used
much in practice
so most users are actually using cloud
chats which only secure the client
server links and these are the focus of
our work
so empty proto version 2.0 runs directly
over the transport which is normally tcp
or http
now at a very high level the key
exchange uses a variant of the jp helmet
key exchange
the output of which is a 2048 b value
which is called an auth key
the symmetric channel could be described
as a stateful encrypt and mac
construction
using aes in ige mode which i will get
to later and the heavy use of shatter56
the scheme has a few quirks the most
important one being that the client and
server use different but related keys
and so the direction matters for how a
message is encrypted
and this symmetric channel was the main
focus of our work
i will now go through this in more
detail
we start with the auth key and a plain
text payload
the entire out key is first run through
sha 1 and truncated to compute something
called an auth key id
which just serves as an identifier for
the connection
next a portion of the out key is run
through shutter 56 together with the
payload
in the middle 128 bits form a so-called
message key
which will also serve as a mac
then a different portion of the out key
is used with the message key in two more
shutter 56 calls
and then interleaved to produce a
symmetric encryption key and iv
finally this key and ib are used to
encrypt the payload using aes 256 and
ige mode
and so what is actually sent on the wire
consists of the authkey id message key
and the ciphertext
there's a few things you can notice at
this point
first you see that this is an encrypted
mac construction because the message key
is sent along with the ciphertext and
the receiver must decrypt first before
checking the mac
the second thing is that the derived
encryption key is message specific
because as you see it depends on the
payload through the inclusion of the
message key in the kdf
one thing i didn't show in detail the
first diagram was how the various slices
are taken from the auth key and you can
see it here
so when the client encrypts a message it
uses keys that are mostly overlapping
with the keys that the server uses but
not fully
this is what the actual plain text
payload
looks like
it has a header that is composed of
64-bit or 32-bit fields
and here the first two fields
server sold and session id
are normally unchanged for the duration
of a single session
where the server sold is generated by
the server and the session id is chosen
by the client
the message id here serves as an
identifier for the particular plain text
and it implicitly also includes a
timestamp
the message sequence number is
essentially just a counter of sent
messages and message length stores the
byte length of message data
so here message data contains the actual
request or response which also has a
specific format but we do not model this
and consider message data as our input
message
and finally this is followed by between
12 to 1024 bytes of random padding
to say a bit more about the ig mode
it stands for infinite garble extension
and it was first described by campbell
in 1978.
as you can see from the diagram it's
basically like cbc mode with the
addition of also chaining the plain text
blocks
it was supposed to have infinite error
propagation and therefore provide
integrity but this claim is actually not
true because one can modify a ciphertext
in such a way that it will differ from
the original only in two blocks
however mt proto does not rely on this
property
and because it has message dependent
keys it is essentially only used as a
one-time sag
before going over the attacks i will
quickly set the stage for what we
actually looked at and what the
implications of this are
first to re-emphasize we looked mainly
at the symmetric channel part of the
protocol for encrypting cloud chat
implementation-wise
we looked at three official clients and
that is for android ios and desktop
telegram also provides a cross-platform
library that implements empty project
however the official clients don't make
use of it
further the protocol protocol
implemented across these clients is
roughly similar but not entirely the
same
especially when it comes to details of
how the plain text format is processed
and this also has implications for our
attacks
further there is no clear separation
between the code of the protocol and
application code
but we had to make this cut for our
analysis somewhere so there is
possibility we missed some problematic
interactions
we also looked at the official
documentation for md proto
which was in some cases outdated or
incomplete so it also cannot serve as a
definitive reference for the protocol
finally we invert server behavior from
practical experiments
since telegram has expressed multiple
times that they do not have any plans
for publishing server code
all in all this means that at least at
the time of our study it was not
possible to have a single specification
of this protocol
which had implications mainly for our
modeling part of the work
i will now speak about the two simpler
attacks that exploit payload validation
the first one is message reordering
and the client to server direction
which is due to insufficient checks on
the message id and message sequence
number
which are determined by the sending
order of the messages
this is because the server decides the
final order of messages not based on
these values but based on when it
receives the messages
we confirmed this in practice on the
android client
and it's worth noting that despite what
telegram claims this kind of reordering
is easily preventable
and it's either on the empty proto level
or the application level
the second attack is enabled by the
re-encryption of unacknowledged messages
what this means is that most messages in
telegram require a special
acknowledgement message to be sent back
if they don't get this acknowledgement
within a given time
the messages are re-encrypted using the
same message id and fresh writing
in practice this means that the stateful
scheme is no longer stateful
because all of the plaintext headers are
the same
so we describe an ncpa attack in the
setting where the adversary controls the
randomness which is a strong assumption
but our proofs are also in this setting
and if the stateful scheme works
properly then the randomness should not
be needed
however if you don't give the adversary
this power then this attack requires
around two to the 64 queries because you
will need a mac collision to produce a
message key that will be the same for
two ciphertexts so then it's just a
theoretical attack
now our tags on the implementation
explore timing side channels
first we found an issue during the
processing of a received ciphertext in
various official clients
this was in the message length field
which had certain constraints on it and
these were checked before the mac in the
message key was checked
in both cases telegram returned the same
error but if the message length check
failed it would return early
the actual timing difference was quite
small about three microseconds which was
tested with the endpoint implementation
depending on the client this lets us
recover between age to 32 bits of
128 plaintext block
this attacks is similar to existing
plaintext recovery attacks on ssh
in that the idea is to move a target
ciphertext block to a position where the
underlying plaintext will be interpreted
as a length field
and then use the resulting behavior to
learn something about the target blank
block
what's complicated slightly is ige so we
need to construct valid ciphertext with
our target somehow in the second block
which i will illustrate shortly
and for this to work you also need to
know two other plain text blocks
suppose we have a plain text made up of
four blocks that look like this
so the first two have the header and the
next two have some message that we are
interested in recovering
they are encrypted with ige using a key
and iv derived as shown earlier
the last plain text block is our target
and we further assume that m1 and m3 are
known
for the preceding message block this is
perhaps reasonable
but the header block lies so because the
server result and session id are
effectively secret random values
however these values are the same for
many ciphertexts in the same session
for now assume we have both of these
blocks
what the attacker can deliver to a
client is then the following ciphertext
made up of the first ciphertext block
unchanged
followed by a new block which is the
exor of the target ciphertext block with
the two known plaintext blocks
the claim that decrypts this will
compute the following
we're substituting c star we get this
which recovers
the underlying equation on the left
and so the client will get the target
plaintext block exert with two known
ciphertext blocks
and if the attacker can now leak some
information from the message length
field
they can directly compute bits of the
target plaintext block
the previous attack requires knowledge
of the first two header fields so this
attack attempts to recover one of them
the server sold
the server salt is normally generated by
the server and periodically sent to the
client
but in the connection immediately after
a key exchange this is different
so initially the server sold as derived
from a secret knowledge that is sent by
the client during the key exchange
more precisely the server sort is an
example of a portion of the so-called
new nouns and the server nodes where the
letter is actually sent in plain text
the new nonce is however encrypted using
rsa on a custom padding format that
looks like this
it starts with the sha-1 of the data and
the actual data and finally padding
where the data can be of variable length
and notice that the padding is not
included in the checksum so the server
must parse this before checking and
there is a potential for several timing
side channels depending on what is
checked first
telegram doesn't publish their server
code and we were only able to test what
checks are made not their order
however the developers acknowledged the
attack but did not offer any details on
the server implementation
but first let me walk through the first
three steps of the key exchange in more
detail
assume that the server has an rsa public
key with modulus and prime and exponent
e
the client knows this because it is
shipped with the app
the client generates a random nuns
and sends it over in the clear
the server does the same
but it also generates a number n that is
64 bits
and actually a product of two primes
which is intended as some kind of
proof-of-work mechanism
it sends this over in the clear
alongside other information that is not
relevant to this
exposition the client has to factor n
and then it generates a new nonce which
is supposed to stay secret
and encapsulates it in a string of this
form
where ink
represents just a deterministic encoding
function for variable length integers
and header is a fixed 32-bit value
and so this data is encapsulated in the
custom format i have already shown
earlier
which includes a sha-1 of the data
without the pattern
it does textbook rsa encryption over
this
and sends the ciphertext over
at this point there are many options
depending on what happens on the server
side
knowing that the server has to parse
data before checking the hash
we confirmed that the server did check
the header value
some bounds on the encoding as well as
the values of p and q
we also confirmed that it did not check
the provided value of n for example
and however we could not determine the
order in which these checks were
performed
for this attack we will assume that the
leakage is from the header check but the
paper also discusses other potential
leakage patterns
and you can notice here that in the
plain text format
the attacker already knows all parts of
the message m except for the new nouns
the hash and the random padding
for this exposition suppose the header
check returns earth
if the attacker submits the chosen value
c prime and put in place of the target
it can learn if the 32 bits in the
header position of the decryption of c
prime match the header value which
provides our oracle
and we can use this oracle in a similar
way to black and white as a tag by
choosing c prime to be s i
to e times our target whereas the s i
values are chosen randomly
and the probability of a correct match
here is then
1 over 2 to the 32.
we can rephrase our goal as recovering h
and n prime from a message m of this
form
where h is the unknown hash of data
gamma encompasses all known information
such as the values of p and q
and prime is the new nouns that we want
to recover
and p is the unknown padding
and here we need to recover the value of
h first because it is necessary for
recovering and prime our actual target
and written another way the plain text m
is of this form
where the values l l prime and gamma are
known to the attack
to recover the hash
we first have to find random s i values
such that
m prime the decryption of our chosen
ciphertext as a header match as
explained earlier
but also that sr is sufficiently small
so that the parts of m prime determined
by the new nouns n prime and padding p
don't contribute to the header bits of m
prime
and they can essentially be ignored in
some sense
with this you can construct the lattice
for inequalities of the form shown on
the slide where sigma i is unknown and
ti is derived from known values
and so finding a shortest vector in this
lattice recovers the target hash when
the parameter mu is six
so we need to find six si values that
fit our criteria
next to recover the new nouns the
process is similar
we first have to find random si primes
values such that
again m prime has a header match
and si prime
is small enough to let us ignore the
padding but large enough that the part
of m prime determined by the new nouns
does contribute to the header bits of n
prime because this is the value we want
to recover
and so with this you can construct a
lattice of a similar form where sigma i
prime is unknown and t i prime is
derived from known values but this time
also include the recovered hash h
and finding a shortest vector in this
lattice recovers all but around 4 bits
of n prime
when the parameter mu prime is set to 9.
recovering the rest is simple however
because we can use exhaustive search by
just recomputing the hash and comparing
it with age
overall this attack requires around six
plus six plus nine times two to the 32
queries and a small amount of offline
computation
now i will show the remaining steps in
the key exchange but in less detail only
to see that recovering this new nums
value also actually gives you a man in
the middle on the key exchange
both the client and the server use these
nodes to derive a key and iv for
symmetric encryption
which is
for our purposes just some function that
uses sha-1
this key and iv are used by the server
with ige mode
to encrypt data of this form
which includes a diffie-hellman value g
to the a
the server sends this over
and similarly the client computes its
secret and encrypted in the same format
with ige
with this data and sends it over
both computed the auth key
and additionally another hash value
using xiaomi that depends on both the
neuns and the computed out key
and send it over
so here you can see easily that if we
can recover the new nodes we can
manipulate these ciphertexts as well
however there is only a short time
window of 10 minutes to execute the
attack
because otherwise
afterwards the server forgets the
in exchange of disclosure we disclosed
the results of our analysis to the
telegram developers in april of last
year
which they acknowledged in june and we
agreed to a public disclosure date in
july 90 days after the initial
disclosure
they also awarded a bug bounty for the
timing side channel and for the overall
analysis
during this process we were informed
that they do not do security or bug fix
releases except for immediate
post-release crash fixes
so the vulnerabilities we reported were
supposedly addressed as part of regular
updates
and the versions that include these
fixes are shown on the slides
before i conclude i will briefly mention
some points that came up during the
proof side of this work
first some attacks that we thought were
obvious are not actually possible
against telegram
for example like length extension
attacks on chat 56
these are prevented in multiple ways
either through fixed length inputs and
truncated outputs but also by the
uniqueness of plaintext headers
second although we prove security of the
empty proto channel
our results require assumptions on
checkout 2 the block cipher underlying
chat 56
which are in some cases highly known
standard and not studied before
for example they must behave as a prf
with partial key leakage or unfixed
inputs
thank you for listening if you want to
read more you can check out the full
paper at the link on the slide