there's and I find that
it's helpful to take what I learned from
my regular day-to-day consulting clients
and try to distill it and make it easier
for people coming up to learn from their
mistakes and go out and make new ones
and this has been inspired by
essentially a lot of my work now is
taking small shops that are maybe one or
two funding rounds past a good idea a
garage or a dorm room to they're making
money they've they've you know I'm
thinking of a shop one of my shops is
they're doing something really intimate
with Salesforce that makes it better and
then my eyes glaze over because they're
talking about sales but their problem is
from my point of view as a security
strategist as a I used to be a pen
tester and now I don't call myself one
anymore cuz pen testing is boring
write me dead for saying that but a lot
of my a lot of my challenges now are how
do you take that small shop and that
small shop up until now has been nailing
small businesses you know we have we
have two accounting firms of 30 people
in the Atlanta suburbs we've got we've
got a NZ window company with sales all
across the Northeast and all of a sudden
the sales rep calls up Bank of America
and says holy I got a demo next
week and it goes from you were selling
to shops of 20 30 50 employees and you
go and you just you you are gonna get to
pitch you are something as a service to
Bank of America what's the difference
anyone run into this problem yet this
sales rep what are they what's the next
thing they're doing after they're gonna
pitch Bank of America what's their next
great concern
their concern is do I get a 35-foot boat
or a 40-foot though right they're like
holy I get 20% Commission on that
sale and it's all gonna go smooth until
there's oh we just have one question
about this you fill out this little
security questionnaire about how you are
going to secure our valuable data
and at some point you hear the you know
you hear the music skip what are you
trying to turn the lights off okay
I've been a professor long enough I'm
happy to do that so this is you're
tasked with that job how do we make this
security questionnaire just think of
every shop I've worked at before I do
this work who filled out that vendor
questionnaire
Wow sales rep right guy who wants to
make the sale again should we do that
thing
what's DLP
okay that is the voice of reason
yeah I just said yes for all this
[Music]
I didn't know what what are these words
meant but we can do all this in a week
actually my favorite one doing one of
these I'm helping a client pitch a large
state agency and I hear a sales rep say
we can pass FedRAMP in two weeks and
like you don't have policies but you
don't have any like true no and I just
kick him out of the chair and
unfortunately the problem is is that
there is a woman who's like in charge of
like something in sales like after sales
support so she's probably wondering why
am i trying to like play footsie with
her oh my god I'm trying to kick him can
you kick him stop the sales rep from
speaking instead she's like why are you
doing that and I actually just kind of
nudged her chair into him I stopped and
I do apologize after like look I had to
make him stop saying things and it was
that I was gonna fake a seizure like
that was the next move I had that's the
sort of commitment I have for clients
like I will stop you from doing
something you can't walk back so Who am
I why am i justified to be here ranting
about this I am I think that's my title
risk advisory services for Leviathan
security group out of Seattle
I of course you know they don't let me
go to Seattle that often because my
Philadelphia accent and my sense of time
doesn't really work well there
I'm a lawyer as well just not your
lawyer
my day job is against a concerted
security consultant but not your
security consultant that can be fixed I
have business cards and I sign retainers
I do the stuff I'm gonna rant about
how to rapidly mature your shop how to
spend as little money as possible and
get as much bang for your security buck
and I used to grade the stuff I'm gonna
talk about my gig before this was being
an Assessor not an auditor because an
auditor implies a third party can
benefit from it no I was contracted by a
Blue Cross Blue Shield to go and torture
their subcontractors and go so you say
you do this thing prove it or not maybe
you maybe you lose the contract maybe we
give it to the other shop that does what
you do because they don't suck as badly
so who are you and why are you here you
work for an adequately staffed and
funded security program want to know how
the other half lives right I'm assuming
not you know I'm assuming if you are
working for losing
oh no we've got it we've got four fully
staffed all our recs are closed I have I
have a fairly unlimited budget and like
then you wake up and go oh you're right
I have nine open wrecks for a team of a
team of twelve
I'm current I'm currently 18 18 - duze
behind
so yeah no one is adequately funded no
one has the staff they need
you just got promoted into security
management hey remembering you were like
senior nerd and then your boss left and
you're like and the other senior nerd
was like one two three not it hey
congratulations your manager what no I'm
fantastic too late
or maybe you got suckered into it it's
gonna be me you are gonna get them
you're gonna get the appreciation that
you've always wanted from vendors who
want to sell you things all right this
is bill from rapid7
you know what we do do you know what I
do no please stop calling
so the old managers walked away and you
got promoted that's actually one of my
clients they're their security manager
literally like I said I can't do this
not like jump to another shop just like
I think he's delivering pizza or uber
just like saw the writing on the walls
like I know I've signed too many I've
I've let too much slide I gotta go
Harr anyone ever been this guy or gal
you're the first security hire
so who's the see so me says in this
vendor it says in this this this org
sheet
I'm the see so and the firewall manager
and I are response ah oh boy it's good
it's it's yeah and you look at the
policy and it's like the instant
response team shall be headed by the sea
so and the instant response team shall
be the sea so and anyone else who the
sea so can contain strong-armed into
help right so you're the first security
hire at that shop so you
you have to rapidly mature your IT
operations and your other operations
really really quickly to be able to
maintain existing client relationships
and get new ones
this is sales driven which some may
scare some of you if you're if you think
about it though the right way what's the
advantage of a sales driven model for
security
you've got allies I'm thinking of a
traditional company where you have sales
people these are people who say nice
things in order to in order to convince
other people to do what they want so if
you can get sales reps people whose job
it is to manipulate sorry um convinced
in a favorable manner and you get a
sales rep who recognizes that the one
obstacle between him and that 35-foot
Chris Kraft is a thing called I PS I di
I I pee urine I don't know do we need
one of these things I will sit outside
this the the CFO's office and get that
thing you that blinky box thing you want
because I want to sell Bank of America
all of a sudden you don't have to do it
you can go and make those people your
house so you go and find compliance or
somebody else there's because it's just
you you have no power if you are there's
there only security hire you haven't
back you have a portfolio and nothing
but if you can go and make some allies
you can you might be able to win some of
these so why do we care about security
because the law makes us right
these are just letters and numbers and
right HIPAA requires that we
gdpr requires that we 23 NYC are ours
the new New York cybersecurity law mg/l
93 inches the Massachusetts one I could
go into these but that's off in a driver
right the law requires that we do
something about security because these
breaches are getting crazy yeah that
drives a lot because your customers
require it what's a scarier phone call
at 4:54 on a Friday
your biggest customer complaining that
you are a regulator
our customer are of course why do we
care about security because your
organization cares about security I have
heard that line so many times and my
answer is usually uh-huh yeah yeah I
still love the Equifax CEO when he says
the guy whose job it was to make sure
those systems were patched didn't do it
and oh well I'm like you know what you
probably have more quality control over
the press release right if someone used
the wrong Pantone color there was
someone else to QC that thing right you
used the wrong font whoa you got to stop
and pull that back yet did you QC
because I'm imagining the person whose
job was to make sure that apache struts
is updated I wasn't like oh I'm just a
complete moron it's like yeah I've
here's my to-do list this you know 9000
line spreadsheet Apache struts was 2300
deep in there I was going to get to that
but I was still trying to clear February
right so so if we you know this is this
is a this is open the few shops
that actually care about security maybe
there are some maybe you even work for
what maybe you still believe it but
really there's a legal there's a legal
fight over it our customers require
these are the two that might actually
show up and make you do a thing
so this is a great question I use this
to stump consultants who try to work for
our shop when I interview them what's
the appropriate what's the appropriate
expenditure for security
that asks for that in one bullet point
what would you say
whatever it takes up to and including
the budget we already have
I've often liked the 10% of your IP
spent where'd you pull that one from I
could show you but it would be rude
right usually the answer is
what do our customers demand what are
our peers doing but really we know that
what the actual question is what's the
least we can get away with what's the
least I can spend and still have an
appropriate and I should put that in the
air quotes appropriate level of security
what's the least we can get away with
and hopefully by the end of this we can
figure out what we can do in the least
amount that still is good enough it
still meets your actual requirements you
use this this phrase actual requirements
not what the law requires or your
customers ask for because there's a
difference between anchor Americo quests
that you do this thing versus Bank of
America pull the business if you don't
what is it one's a request yeah there's
a hard demand filter out the things you
actually have to do and concentrate on
those debt wins where you can outside of
that thick or hard kernel of your
security program should be what can I do
that actually is a hard requirement or I
lose business
No
let's start the finding terms because
I'm speaking of securing this ad morphus
you know the gray goo oh I'll have to
securities please
case you're unfamiliar controls or
individual measures to detect prevent or
mitigate security risks pentesting is a
control a firewall is a control a
request that your employees show up to
work sober is a control some of these
are enforceable but we've got you know
physical you have an 8 foot high fence
with concertina wire around your around
your secure facility that procedural how
often do you do a vulnerability scan
with clawless once every I feel like it
right some kind of some kind of
procedure that you task with somebody to
say you got to go do the thing access
rights review
technical you actually have a blinky box
to do a thing
and many of you are familiar but just
see we're talking about things
compliance these are the it's written on
policy that you do these things if you
don't we may fire you are we may dock
you pay our we may make you sing I'm a
little teapot in the break room some
kind of punishment to take you do the
things you're supposed to do
don't give your passwords to everybody
don't put your passwords on post-it
notes don't have a shared login for
everyone in the HR department
those controls frameworks are big
collections of controls that we all
agree to such as ISO mist 853 COBIT I
mean NIST is already kind of for
masochists unless you actually have to
usually want to think what should we
pick I'm like ISO is the easiest to fake
because you've got scope you can scope
down ISO to almost nothing like PCI
where you know PCI certified
this box but nothing in it and therefore
right my sack D is compliant you know
you can play games with scope you can
play games with these things but you got
basically your collection of control
dude stuff you you promised to do then
an outsider will assume if you say we
have an iso certified or iso aligned
policy kit it means that you're probably
doing a bunch of these things
now those are the two terms I'll use
again so so many controls so little time
including my proofreading the my doc so
implementing controls requires money
effort and Burdick using this is to
three different things money
I gotta go spend money to go buy the
thing I got to buy the blinky box I got
to buy the antivirus subscription I've
got to buy the something as a service I
got to go pay Splunk some money or more
money
effort I actually have to have someone
who either works for me or I've hired at
a high rate go do the thing turn the
crank
right design configure maintaining use
that control to do the thing
and pen tests well that's that's that's
that's money and then effort to go and
we'll mediate those findings track them
down and make sure they happen so and
then there's burden
policy that says we have a five minute
lockout on all PC screens does that cost
money no you can set that with GPO in a
couple minutes
is it effort minimal will result in
complaints yes will you get yelled at
when you have things like when you get
those really stringent things like we're
going to air that next thing you know
people on the people on the Bank of
America team have two pcs on mister Bank
America business only the rest is for
other because you put up some burdensome
control to satisfy a need I'm gonna use
that burden as that's often what gets
you the most kickback because I spend
money that gets spent and the only
person is really worried is accounting
but you spent it it's done no longer it
no longer rears its ugly face effort the
only person is really complaining about
that is the poor you know the the the
man or woman you said go validate that
thing that's what you're doing today
go check the firewall rules make sure
they're compliant with this standard
once a month yes it's that time of the
month go do it
burden burdens the one that keeps coming
back and regular people your end-users
your customers going to go I don't have
to do this I have to change my password
the Bank of America
so
how do you select the controls right
just ISO or our covet our NIST is going
to have a set of controls that you
should plunk in
HIPAA and GLBA and those may also
suggest controls you have to take all of
them
Oh
you pick the ones you've got to do do
the things that are mandatory and here's
this is the biggest way to save money
and do this on a budget is figure out
what controls you actually have to do
the problem is is that this is this
control set this actual real hard
controls you've got to do is specific to
your organization in a in a period of
time that same organization
two years later may have a different
control set as you sign contracts with
new clients who made you do things
because you changed business because
regulations change you got into this
business you exited this business so you
are figuring this out as you go if you
are new to this or your company is new
to this you're figuring this out and
here's the fun trick
basic rule of consulting is I don't have
to know everything I just have to be
half an hour ahead of my clients you as
head of security or you as a new
security manager do not know have to do
everything don't have to know everything
you just have to know how to be ahead of
your customers and your end users before
they ask it will come across as a genius
there is nothing wrong with pulling up
the Wikipedia page about the thing
during a con call
however one point if you've got like if
you're a fetishist about keyboards
sherry Reds or cherry Browns are really
really noisy so if when you hear the so
Alex can we do that thing yes yes we can
so I have been asked to get a quieter
keyboard for for con calls and I have
wind this in such a way that I've made
my clients happy it's okay to wing it as
long as you validate that you did it
right later when you're not under would
not under crunch time so
how do you select the controls how
extensive should they be so how we can
do the old-fashioned way
cost-benefit risk based right jet engine
Plus peanut butter equals risk I think
is what my old boss used to say and I
never listen to him because he's
Canadian
thanks James ideas this right the the
probability of an event times the impact
of that event with with without controls
if the cost of that is greater than the
cost of the control plus the probability
of the event still happening in the
impact of the event with that control
you put the control in place if they're
equal to wash if the cost of the control
plus the probability of the plus the
potential impact of the control width
with it is higher than the then the
control than the probability without the
control you don't do it you accept the
risk that's great right but you know
remember when you took calc 1 and Cal
tune you learned how to optimize and you
know wow I can solve problems until you
realize a problem with this
right implement the control if the
benefits if the benefit is great you
know you the cost is cost control is
less than the unmitigated probability
really hard to quantify what's the
probability that you're gonna get
breached this year 100% what's the
probability how much does that
probability go down if you buy something
really new and shiny from Palo Alto this
year
yes depends are you if you are Palo Alto
sales rep you'll say our research shows
that oh nice actually better yet knowing
knowing if they're proper enterprise
sales rep seventy-three point that added
that added little alcohol
but oh yeah so the only thing you can
actually guarantee you have a good idea
to guess is the cost right like this
would be great if you could quantify all
this rest so you can make some guesses
but you're at the end of the day you're
like I I don't know I think I feel
better knowing that there's a for you
hundred thousand dollar box from Palo
Alto that does next-gen threat hunting
threat centric something I don't know
it's awesome
here that thing when it fires up it's
noisier than the freaking Sun efore 20
that's that's underneath of it I don't
know what that does but it's still there
so it's a great idea it only really
works when you absolutely have a I know
that the risk is dramatically reduced
and the impact is dramatically reduced
and the cost ain't that high the rest is
your wing so as nice as this model is it
doesn't actually work
second model is I don't want that to
happen right how many times you get a
regular line manager and non-technical
manager
waving around one of those magazines
often times it's the award-winning air
airline magazine outside this issue this
issue is about cybersecurity you're like
oh god what the hell is this guy gonna
be on a badly we need up flame wall
ah what is incredibly there calling you
like while waiting for their luggage
like we have a flame all right
firewall no no Flint I do we have one of
those yeah yeah sure because that breach
thing that sounds horrible like yeah
yeah it is that's why I'm here why am I
taking your call no you don't want that
thing to happen and I want you to
guarantee that thing won't have no I
sure yeah
I don't want that thing to happen again
ring hi who authorized to put the entire
customer list on piece pin
my favorite is who authorized to put all
of our prospectus ease on scribed like
ah you're in trouble cuz you're right
they all are on scribe what are they
doing there so I don't want that happen
again
I want you to guarantee that that
horrible thing that made us all a
scramble won't happen again
right do your Lord Shane God knows we do
Airlines airport security like that oh
oh
people might people's shoes may explode
so you have to take off your shoes and
I'm waiting for some entrepreneurial
Isis or al-qaeda member to go like the
suppository bomb just like yep yep gonna
make you all do some extra special time
in line right you want to prevent that
horrible thing from happening
yes and I call this the senior
management protection program I told the
security guy to do that thing now you're
in this well did you give me the budget
to do that thing let me take it out your
existing budget like yeah about that so
this is the I told you to fix that you
didn't on you
so more ways of controlling selection
controls some controls are soon because
they're low cost and high estimated
right
we use encryption you know I often have
this one full disk encryption of laptops
that may hold sensitive data it's a
no-brainer now right because pretty much
every OS you can get unless you're that
poor bastard is still running some kind
of like plan 9 running on on brain-fuck
if you've got some relatively modern OS
that you're supporting full disk
encryption it's an easy thing to do is
click the box done one of the many check
boxes I've got fixed right expensive you
know highly well we're low impact high
expense you like I'm not doing up it
like kind of knee-jerk of course we do
that thing hit those controls or what we
call the laughs test if I heard that
another shop wasn't doing this thing I'd
freak I'd laugh
problem is that I no longer laugh
because many of my clients don't do like
the primitive things like that was like
why is CalNet still open oh it's a
useful way to administer your next box
like
dude I like the 90s too but they're over
now
ssh has been scape like i don't know
about that so i know under laughs I cry
so I should replace this with like does
it make me drink more
but right so you've got some controls
because they just you do them you do
them why you've already got a budget for
it why are we replacing the firewalls
because we have money in the budget and
we used to have firewalls so it's easy
to say I am replacing the old ones with
the new ones
is that low-cost highest made an impact
no but it's easy
regulation requires it this is a great
way to cut through some except
I know way too many beardy sucide means
who will why my favorite is a friend of
mine who literally stood up in front of
a manager and said
I think you're violating HIPAA because
you are sending protected health
information in clear-text and that
violates HIPAA
now of course I'm going to ask two
questions one
was HIPAA relevant he was doing a pen
test and he was sending a pen test
report to the client I was asked to send
a pen test report to the client
how many pen test reports have Phin
unless you've really screwed something
up should be not right you may allege
like here is data and you exit out but
he was convinced that the pen test
report included pH I the second one was
he said
HIPAA requires encryption anyone and
anyone want to argue that that you have
to encrypt pH I under HIPAA
good you don't pressable so maybe it
doesn't
maybe the regulation doesn't require but
the number of times people want to get
into a regulatory fight over over this
is rare I do it because well lawyer but
that's kind of neither here nor there
right your customers tell you what they
want you to do you've got your base
controls cuz you've already had them or
you want to just not be laughed at by
your compatriots but then your customers
will tell you what they want and that's
a half-decent way of figuring out what
is considered normal for your industry
how can you tell vendor requirements and
contracts and vendor assessments
you know the number of contracts have
said that have you've got these controls
the ones that scare me are the ones that
have a blank there right you will you
provide the following contracts like
like don't let the sales rep write that
don't cuz they'll add things because
they want to make the sale happen like
now you just agreed to do all those
things that a week ago you didn't know
what they were we got one of those DLP
things right no don't
would you like to try to install one
today so here is a body of knowledge
that you can steal from if you are new
to the industry you can go get them make
some friends in your industry there is a
meet-up for people in for for
informational security people in
healthcare or financial service or
whatnot
yeah no these people on a social basis
if they like you are and and this is one
of those reciprocal things what you do
is you take the ones that you're getting
hit with I'll off the serial numbers so
you have a body of knowledge about what
everyone's expecting it's a really quick
way doesn't violate in NBA if you're
just taking the information out of it
right these are the controls I'm not
naming the client I'm naming you're the
ones I see that all the ones asked for
you want the common ones you want to
want you want the ones that all your
customers are demanding that body of
knowledge is valuable share don't be a
dick
share that information right because it
it also an away from from the
perspective of the vendor the vendor
would like to not have to fight you
tooth-and-nail to put in some controls
they would like you to have a pretty
good idea of what controls they're
expecting
so use that as your first body knowledge
so talk about that so you've got this
big pile of controls right I so plus you
read the last eight vendor assessments
and you went through and asked legal to
dump all the appendices from the
contracts and now you've got this whole
selection got a hundred and twenty-five
different controls to select from
how do you pare that down right because
now like holy I have a hundred and
twenty two controls my own kind of
seat-of-the-pants risk assessment says
we might have twenty in place partially
in places
how do I go from that big body to a
smaller one how do I cut it out how do
we cut out ones that I don't think I
need until you make me and so so I'm
gonna give you a couple guidelines and a
dirty trick so if you have three
requirements that you think you need
first one only gets checked after an
incident right it's checked didn't you
have that in place and the only time
we're gonna ask is post breach number
one number two we ask that you prior to
the contract do it but you can self
certify like say PCI sac D I say I do
these things
parmitt 3 gets checked by people who can
cost you money which requirement do you
bill
great
this
in this like the chances that you get
breached no it's it's less than a
hundred percent and then again even if
it's like hey you should have had this
in place
sometimes you're then arguing would that
have stopped it right
you know the number of times they have
had arguments about blp would have
prevented that the opie would have
prevented that except they walked out
with a hard drive
I've not seen DLP stop physical theft
you know and I really want some like
some sales rep from Symantec to go ours
would like okay awesome
well you sign that new contract I would
love to see that so you you actually go
and say this is the requirement that I
care about which are the ones they're
actually that the vendors going to check
on I want to make the vendor Assessor
happy
not saying you don't do the other two
other two are slightly lower importance
so easily cheaply verified things get
checked even if they're lower value a
tell a story and I love telling a story
because it's it it's one of those
something that CI I have a rule that
says many times I will see something it
seems just asinine and stupid but I'll
ask why because sometimes you find out
there's a really good reason for the
story I'm going to tell that a rock band
called Van Halen
um Van Alen had a rule that said if you
had brown M&Ms in a bowl in the dressing
room they could walk from the show and
you would have to pay the reason why was
theirs there they were one of the first
they've kind of built the idea of a
giant arena show had massive loads power
weight on the theatrics and essentially
people would just sign the contract
riders and these look an engineering
degree you know engineering diagrams in
these contract writers saying we're
gonna show up and we need all the power
all the mounts and if the last thing you
had here is a folk show no we need like
real infrastructure and we don't want we
want to make sure that you read the
goddamn contract you read these
requirements said yes we checked we have
the power we can support the weight we
can we can move things in or out however
to validate that you've got power every
18 inches 60 feet off the stage is hard
you can however force them to identify
something that you can check so there is
a bias towards things you can easily
show to say we are doing that thing here
is proof as you show if you if there's
something you can validate and you
aren't doing and you say you're doing it
it means you lied about something that
was easy to check that makes me believe
you less when you say the hard to check
thing we're doing
so what are they easily so like a sock -
I hate them because I've gotten people
through them and I have well because
they always send like second-year
accountants who don't know what any of
the words mean and I've had I've
actually during a sock - someone said
you don't have a policy on Incident
Response I'm like have you read my
document called incident response policy
and like well that doesn't discuss IR
like you know what IR is right
well IR is different than instant
response like so like find/replace
there's a whole IR section that was
copied and pasted from the instant
response like see I've and the fact that
I that bet you know what what security
tool do you use the most Microsoft Word
finder in place not a client of sock to
sock to is easy like vomit up and go
there we do those things does it make
you more secure no because it's a bundle
lies at at a point in time was not
obvious to an accountant who's had two
years experience
but that's easy to check right I asked
for you know if I'm an outside vendor
and I say I want your last three years
of pen tests how many of you who are
doing those pen tests will go I'm not
showing that honored
and why am I asking if I'm asking for
the last three years what do I want to
say
that's one but
you
thank you are they the same report
because as a pen tester the most sat the
saddest moment of my time was writing it
was was realizing reviewing the last pen
test report that I could save the 12
hours I normally book to write a pen
test report with change date
it was
for Vaughan unfixed Mike so extra brode
in the bottom like why am I doing this
juicy didn't catch it and I'm like and
during the readout like I would like to
skip to Section four point five why am I
here
look I've identified a new finding that
says you are not remediating the
problems and this bothers me like Alex
you're doing pen testing why are you
lecturing them like cuz why why are we
here now I'm in strategy where I get to
go and say that's the more valuable
findings you didn't fix it last time the
pen test is useless why spend run time
for someone to pound your systems if
you're not gonna do anything about it
and I get when you have like the
informational ones because there's
nothing like I can determine the version
of the OS
Wow that would be a big guest it's got
you know it doesn't have any of the
microsoft services but has ssh i'm gonna
guess it may be a UNIX box just say it
that's okay that doesn't bother me but
like I can get RCE and you didn't fix
that problem three years running
that shows that trend that's the easily
verified thing I want to show you know
if I'm worried about about a vendor I
want to see that you fix the problems
so I'm gonna say some crazier things you
all say this right compliance bang
equals security usually that's from
people who are so well funded that they
can actually have like a threat hunting
P I get called about that like would you
like to be on our threat hunting team
like I don't know what that really is
that sounds like it should have a
trademark by SecureWorks on it you know
like that's great but really I want it
you know most of my shops like could you
patch the from last year that's the
I'm the bone hunting team did patch
it can hit are there systems that have
been out of compliance from 90 days and
then some are like we've had systems out
of patch out of patch for 900 days Mike
like how are you allowed to do that but
oh they support our core infrastructure
like your stop please stop talking when
you like you're just making this worse
so yes compliance bangle security but
one's easier to show
from vendor sessom point of view from a
your client has
four hours to figure out
whether or not to jump in front of the
freight train that is the business deal
right because if you're a shop big
enough think of it from the vendor
assess or one of you right your job is
to is to write up a spreadsheet that
asks a bunch of questions and all you do
is read lies all day
your job is to throw up a hand and say I
really think this is a bad idea and you
have limited political capital you can't
stop that many deals
so what you want to do is show enough
that means if you are not the biggest
asshole way from that that week that's
all you have to do to make the sale
right
someone else has openly lied that we can
like I'm gonna go put a hurting on them
you you're just a garden-variety schmuck
I will let you pass I might put a
requirement or two in but you're gonna
make the sale so but proving it
oftentimes proving compliance as far as
improving security because every time I
see I get a client's like they demanding
a right to audit like a right to pen
test like I have never seen one Xers
ever I've been doing this for way too
many
but don't ask to show all you see all
your paper because that's a lot easier
so compliance isn't security but from a
vendor point a vendor perspective it's
the same it's better it is possible to
over control it is possible to overspend
on a control cuz that Palo Alto sales
guy was really nice and we went to a
steak dinner I think the bill was like
$8.00 and you're like oh sure and they
you know like you wake up the next
morning and there's a thank you note
from the pallet hill sales rep like what
did I sign
that's really that's beautiful and
blinky box you're like that just blew
half my security budget i overspent I
over controlled and the problem is is
that checking a box really hard doesn't
check the surrounding boxes I know
check security is bad yeah but if
you first you check all the boxes right
and then when you're done with that you
can now go back to the castle cuz yeah I
think if the check box Security's you go
walk around the castle and go there's a
wall here Rick the stones are fine and
you're looking for like gates open it's
missing gates on fire right and when you
jog around and come back you're like now
we can talk about higher end stuff and
my check boxes all the check boxes are
filled I can now really think about moat
design or power
you know tower configuration and stuff
like that but odds are you're scuttling
around checking boxes cuz that's all you
have time to do you've got open wrecks
for five people to help you with that
but guess what
checking the boxes is probably the best
bang for your buck until you can do them
the other stuff is no I'm thinking of
like every big breach falls back to one
of those
you did something you failed to do
something that is relatively
programmatically easy to do
target got alerts that you didn't do
anything about
Equifax you didn't patch a known
vulnerable
was enough to have it all happen but
while yes compliances and security check
all your boxes first it's a part of this
nutritious balanced breakfast
so good controls the ones that people
are actually asking this is customer
based but it's you're looking for them
to go and say this is what we really
care about other stuff is stuff that you
have to be independently convinced you
have no allies for that other control
that you want but ain't no one asking
for and maybe you can justify it maybe
you think no this blinky box or this
this policy or this thing will pay off
but you're the only person in the room
advocating for that it's really easy to
say 60% of our customers require this
control means that I can go to six
percent of the sales reps and say back
me up on this make that sale easier and
at that point that sales rep will now
pay attention you because you just said
something to them you said I want to
help you buy a boat
all of a sudden you went from the weird
twitchy guy in the break room to the guy
who can help me get a bow like all of a
sudden you were now relevant to me hey
you will stop doing the other sales rep
e things and now pay attention to you
for a minute
don't freak him out explain in small
words you've got three bullet points and
two of them are oxygen is necessary for
life I like money you've got a third
bullet point where you can explain why
you need that control
so proving your assertions if you say
you're doing a thing how do you prove it
people ask for more than a
self-certification any of my clients run
into this problem like hey we can
promise everything this we self-certify
we have somehow found that a sack be a
line that says we have an ISO 27001 -
aligned security program but we have not
yet certified
we have an internal pentesting so we
don't use an external vendor
we do our own vulnerability scanning we
don't use we have not used a qsa because
we're under the size something like that
so sometimes you'll get a vendor who
will demand prove it show me that you do
the thing
so this makes you have a fallback
position when you know that the vendor
is gonna ask for more dirt the things
you should have you should be doing then
you are and you can prove that you're
doing
this is where I talk about policy and
and and and standards and artifacts of
compliance and most people's eyes glaze
over except that this can be a magical
thing where you can shut up a vendor
Assessor Traxxas vomit documentation on
them it go away
ain't no longer bother because they
figure anyone who's willing to drop a
bunch of documentation that shows
they're doing that they're actually
looking they're going and checking the
box and make sure the castle hasn't
fallen over odds are just going back to
looking looking at the worldview of the
vendor Assessor
your job is to make sure that they don't
get fired what can get them fired a
breach for a vendor that they said was
okay
are you blue all your political capital
trying to stop at the old from happen
those are the two extremes of their
lives so if you can give them enough
warm fuzzy feelings that they're not
worried about you you get a pass from
them you don't have to be perfect you
just have to be good enough and showing
documentation it's a good way to do that
so artifacts be able to drop a risk
register of all the issues these are all
the things that bugged me from a
security perspective
big ugly Excel spreadsheet lists are so
big that using Archer are our Sam and
then if you're that big on I feel for
you I've tried to fight with Archer and
our Sam and risk fabric and I think that
really they're all basically an Excel
spreadsheet with ugly your front but all
the stuff you're worried about that you
have to fix goes in it goes in one ugly
spreadsheet or a database are something
that says I am worried about those
things
I will check them off when I can so at
any given time I can say here's what's
still on my plate that I have to worry
about
because it shows that even if I have a
horrible pen cast all the things are
broken but I have a remediation plan and
you can show better that the last time
you had a horrible pen test and you
remediated the things it means that your
promises that say I will fix that before
your company's data flows through me
all of a sudden a little bit of process
here buys you a lot of credibility for
your security program this is cheap
this is some effort on your behalf it's
not a lot of burden on your end-users
you can suffer through this there may be
times where you're sucking this into if
you have internal audit or accounting or
regulatory groups they may want you may
want to merge the risk registers to say
that way you can compare and contrast
their risks the stuff they're afraid of
but you should be able to vomit out in
one document here's all the stuff that
I'm worried about
I haven't yet remediated but I'm
planning to these are the ones that we
decided we're not remediating we're
accepting the risk it show it builds
good faith it shows that you're doing
the things you say you're doing
there's nothing like dropping a really
nice policy kit that's perfectly
compliant with iso 27001 and - and then
when you ask so do you do any of this
that's that awkward silence
because you're not I can have you know
asking when I did that when I did
assessments he'll be something like
so when was the last time you actually
tested your IR plan like oh we've never
done that but your policy says you
tested annually like oh it does doesn't
it so if you show had an incident this
is what we did even if the incident is
Bob at the loading dock got a piece of
malware on the Maui on me on the
combination malware collector inch and
FedEx box
did you do the thing you do this proves
that you do the thing
what did you do random Malwarebytes next
shows you do the thing shows that the
things that you can show easily you're
doing so therefore the hard things are
probably doing too
tract exceptions right there's nothing
like when you get the answer it says are
all your systems is all are all your are
all your systems running supported
operating systems and people check yes
and invariably there's a kiosk in the
reception area that's running XP like
but you said you were this annex you
know the XP extended they're like no
like shouldn't leave the proof that
you're not doing the thing in front of
the auditor it's okay to have that XP
box because you say I do have an XP box
that runs the incredibly important task
of telling you what office any
individual works in
we do have systems that don't meet our
policy but there's a we accepted the
risk XP box in a kiosk in st. Louis
and isn't plugged into anything else but
it shows that I'm not lying to you
because I'm point that pointed that out
that doesn't mean I'm were that means
that I'm less worried about by a cluster
of wind mm boxes that haven't been
patched since the since like the George
Bush administration running something
core as you called out the thing said
there are places where I'm not compliant
but I think it's okay you're showing
that you're working what you say you're
working the cheap control
you
no substitution
so a lot of times you have a technical
control that's really really hard trying
to think there was one I tried to get a
client through this and they wanted to
show that you could not access the jump
box from an outside country and we said
we can whitelist and blacklist IPs and
like what if they use a proxy like what
you want us to like did catch something
and figured help and like fine you know
what
the only people coming into the jump box
are the remote support P half of which
are in Canada
so technically half of our staff is
violating your requested policy of only
us-based people can can login to our
boxes though I couldn't put in a
technical control I instead just put a
policy control and it says you know you
must click I hate curling and socialized
medicine to login
Trump is better looking than Justin
Trudeau yes and therefore by policy I
bar the Canadians from logging in and
it's a stupid controls a stupid request
but it was a vendor I was a client that
had a lot of money and we're willing to
pay what the what are my client wanted
for this service so I'm like well put in
it we'll put in a compliance control
that's a hundredth the cost it's slight
burden but I can't come up with a
technical control to rewrite your
application to make this happen
so also I can replace controls by SOAs
right I have say say you get someone
who's got very very rigorous physical
security controls quickest way to do
that I'm not building out a data center
for your nitpicky performance that you
know physical security I'm gonna shove
it in AWS hey
that's those controls are an SLA that
say Amazon has these physical controls
in space Don I don't have to build a
secure Kiriko low I don't have to do all
that like Amazon's doing that thing
well you're not gonna trust Amazon at
the usin physical security
I haven't seen any Amazon racks at 401
North Broad and Philly so I'm assuming
they at least go to decent colors
I like playing the homeless vagrant our
sis admit on a two-day rollout at 401
North Broad and and we figured out that
the it depends on what boxes the person
sleeping on
I've done that I've actually didn't hug
someone like dude you can't sleep in
front of my rack and they muttered
something I'm like let's see they smell
bad ill-kept
yes
okay but nonetheless like right I can I
can replace it you requested control
that I can't meet maybe I can I can
handle this with an SLA somewhere
as I'm doing this it four-bit I'm not
doing this for all of my services I'm
doing this for you one vendor or one
client because it's cheaper stovepiping
this is more advanced I'm doing stuff
just for one control they have a stupid
overburden thing because they want to do
something perverse with your with your
service
you've got essentially like a box
knockoff and all of a sudden a large
health insurer wants to use your thing
you know like ah our tool is not built
for this we're not we don't have all the
compliance controls in I would like to
put them in but that would piss off all
my other customers well maybe I can
cheat
and just create a second segregated
system for them
I use the same software you should same
Cole are you I mean not the cold same
sim configs and all that but there's a
different landing page that you guys go
to that I can put all the controls you
want in
you
say they say they had these this list of
unreasonable demands you know like wait
this is just for you something you have
two choices when you get a large client
that once something this otherwise
they're like that's gonna be expensive
that's right you're gonna cost money and
you have to now go from a technical
decision to a business decision
I kind of went through this analysis
with one of my clients they wanted
essentially we had to rebuild their app
well and we like the cost to remediate
all these requirements that no other
clients ask for comes out to about
$60,000
how much are we going to be making from
that client and the sales reps like a
hundred so like so $40,000 is a revenue
just to put in implement these controls
odds are it may not be worth it
however just say during the call when
you're talking to security people we can
do that but for you those additional
controls we're gonna offer you a special
deal instead of $100,000 to 140,000
we're gonna charge you more at those
controls you actually asked for
and sometimes you'll get a we're fine
with that we'll sit we'll pay you more
money are you may decide how many other
people will also want these controls we
lay that off but you turned a technical
set of technical issues into a business
decision you as a company decide to
shoulder these new costs you spread do
you spread the cost back to the customer
he open and obvious about like you
you've got all nitpicky and want all
these controls this is what it's gonna
cost
odds are by this point you've gotten
deep in by the time you're doing the
vendor assessment all the other shops
that were pitching or have fallen out
so you might be able to get away with
that I've we've negotiated that or you
may actually have to decline the work
like one was essentially a software
testing app that a large hospital chain
wanted to use doing live testing on live
data like so you're all HIPAA compliant
here like no there's literally like we
crowdsource
testing so anyone can log in so that
means like 110,000 people can and Det
thi from the system's they're testing no
we cannot make that HIPPA compliant
because HIPAA requiring the you limit
data to the people who need to see it a
bunch of a bunch of basically click farm
level QA testers in Chandigarh aren't
going to do that that's not limited to
the people we need to see it we cannot
become HIPAA compliant for your needs
it's gonna be too expensive to modify
your service just for you he can't take
the work because we don't ask we don't
think we're gonna get any more work from
similarly situated customers now of
course this isn't your decision this is
the decision you help the business
people make but you go and very honestly
say it's gonna cost more to do this
thing
so if you fail to convince a customer
take it a lesson cause we didn't do that
thing it cost us this
add the requirement to the next sprinter
quarter if you think you can was one of
those we could do it if we knew we had
to had time
oh that's how that's how you can kind of
build a body of knowledge for the
controls you need and get some support
to build it
questions
Oh
you
as in
okay I think that's here we've got
usually the self-certification with
something that's out by an open body
like like PCI allows you to if you're
below a certain size number of
transactions you can describe your
controls and say and without having an
outsider test them you say we do all
these things that's a self-certification
right I have seen you know there are
open certifications that don't require
third party to validate what you've done
like I can validate I can say I meet
HIPAA recline I can I I as a is their
virtual C so say a me older quirements
have hit them and if you trust me that's
great that's a self-certification a
third-party certification B where a
third-party comes in and says we who
have no skin in the game other than we
would like to not we would like to not
have a bad commercial name have reviewed
this stuff and we think it meets those
requirements like I trust is an example
PC PCI after qsa if you're if you're a
tier one provider where you say third
party came in and looked at this and did
this I don't think you're gonna have a
questions of illegality I think I'll
have a questions of do I buy yourself
self certification or do I make you on
the vent if I'm the the prospective
client do I if I don't trust you do I go
make you get a certification do I make
you get a third party to say I believe
that their certification is valid
you
oh okay
so I create I I create a a certification
test
my own software and
so like ISC
you
to get ahead
um until you make it a requirement like
I'm thinking sis peas required for some
there's some if you are in DoD are yeah
it's you can make a requirement there
would be a question of is it unfair is
it some kind of unfair competition I
haven't seen anything that's I haven't
seen the case yet because I'm thinking
if you do if was a if it was specific to
a vendor say for example I required
you've got a vendor specific
certification to work on device then you
get into hazing where that is there's
there's sort of like right to repair in
the light but I I don't know where you
would get a
i'm sheree a legal claim against a
certifying body for creating certain
but
I don't I don't I don't know my answer
my long-term my TLDR answers I'm not
sure
okay
you
Belt certification
yes
there's a better rant about this by
Duncan minutes at gherkin this is his
talk two or three years ago about
certifications and it's a great rant
about ISC bangla sis P is a marketing
exercise like this I don't know I have
somehow managed to stumble through my
career with getting only two
certifications in my life none of which
are like I have the CCS k because my
boss made me get it I have an old Apple
laptop certification to do repairs under
Apple care and somehow that's been okay
like I'm a would yes there's that
certification
yes I oh yeah their bar dues and cles
and all that but it's rare that my like
my day job is being a security
consultant so the number of times the
fact that a lawyer comes into play isn't
that often because I'm not giving legal
advice giving technical and procedural
advice and really marketing advising how
to you take your tiny little shop and go
huh go and be able to hunt
big clients and a lot of times I do the
I play that I play the role of ice-t I
walk you're the vendor Assessor around
the room a few times and basically
convince them like I will give you the I
will give you good enough answers so you
can go back and not get beat up for not
asking the right question and I'm not
gonna lie to you I will give very
crafted answers that make that explain
why our security while it may look
woefully bad
because we don't have you know we're 16
people we don't have a separate group
that does this but this is why it's not
certifications is an interesting
I don't I think they have a value I
realized some this is the own way off
point but
I talked to people coming up right how
how did you get where you're at I'm like
that's not the right question to ever
ask me like I took the wrong path to get
where I'm at it's a meandering path
clearly to do security I think you need
to break into it
certifications don't sell a person's
gotta sis P is at least gonna get
listened all person without assists be
it's like who are you
unless you've otherwise built in me
I mean generally this at this point in
my career it's like oh you're the your
you know you're the the loudmouth guy
with the ponytail who yells a lot and
that's you know that's more valuable
than this appeal but coming up clearly
you don't even get a phone call from a
recruiter if you don't have something so
it Elise establishes that you could pass
a test you could sit still for long
enough and answer questions about the
appropriate height of a fence
is that enough
Oh cuz I remember doing comm 1.0 and
meeting people had all the Microsoft
certifications and couldn't explain what
a domain controller
I remember the one was couldn't
understand how to troubleshoot a simple
IP connectivity problem
was this machine is looking for a DHCP
server that thousand things it's like
well I have an MC se I'm like I can
troubleshoot move the PC from here to
here the old Network had a DHCP server
the other one doesn't
hey MCSE again I'm going to you I'm
going to take your mouse is he just like
you like and it was so I don't want to
be the knee jerk certs or but I
we are for every story we have someone
who's certified is smart there are three
stories about the person's got a lot of
certs and has no common sense about how
to do the thing
whether it's why is this not working why
does the why does this not these
requirements
why does Qualis keep crashing why does
koalas keep showing all these
vulnerabilities why can't I patch this
right and some kind of context I think
certs that would get in the door and
then after that its its reputation and
quality
Oh
[Applause]