not really I don't care
okay cool we're on the Internet
apparently good morning everybody
welcome to besides Delaware my name is
Claire tills and today I'm gonna be
talking about advanced soft skills how
you guys can use efficacy to actually
get things done in security so a little
bit about me maybe
there we go a little bit about me I'm a
communication researcher my background
is in public relations don't hold that
against me and I started studying cyber
security when I was studying for my
master's I was researching crisis
communication and before I went to
graduate school I worked for a PR firm
that focused on high tech mostly
security in that time it was 2014 there
were a lot of breaches going on so we
had a lot to talk about in our PR firm
involved in crisis communication and
cyber security and what I realized is
people are doing this really badly
cybersecurity communication as a whole
isn't really a field it's not a thing
that exists in research in particular
and it's still brand new in terms of
practice I have a couple of friends who
do cybersecurity communication but
there's maybe a couple of handfuls of us
so I started researching it I started
looking into crises and from there I
kind of expanded to be four broad
communication about information security
issues last April or this April I was in
Rochester giving a presentation about
crisis communication and they had these
lightning talks and a couple of the
Lightning talks talked about how can we
be more proactive in information
security how can we get people to
actually take our recommendations and do
stuff and I was like hey I can help with
that so that's sort of how I put
together this talk I also came from a
lot of the common complaints I heard
from my friends and information security
of ok no one listens to us we have
recommendations we tell them to do
things to be more secure then they get
breached and they come back to us and
say why didn't you stop this so
hopefully you can learn some things here
today that will preempt that cycle of
stuck and I also want to move InfoSec
communication away from crisis
communication most of what you see when
people are talking about InfoSec is
something is on fire something has gone
terribly wrong that's not the best time
to be talking about this you want to be
talking about it all the time and
here are some reasons so when you only
talk about something during crisis
you're creating the perception in
people's minds that only crises happen
here so if you're only talking to people
about information security when
something scary and bad is happening
they're only going to have scary bad
associations with information security
they're not going to want to think about
it people don't like thinking about
things that make them afraid we don't do
things we don't plan properly for our
wills or our end of life because we
don't like talking about it we are in
denial that it will ever happen because
it's scary so by moving more proactive
with communication about information
security we're building those better
connections or building better mental
associations and trying to make people
feel good about talking about
information security so then they'll
feel good about doing something to be
more secure and also only talking about
and permission or information security
during a crisis create silos in an
organization your PR team if you're in a
firm is probably never talking to your
security team
they're completely siloed and then
during a crisis that's the only time
they're getting in touch and so they see
it as okay well I only need to talk to
my security team when something goes
wrong no you want them talking all of
the time so and then what if the bad
thing never happens so this is something
that I've heard about a little bit where
you know there's a lot of chicken little
potential for some information security
we keep saying if you don't do this
something bad will happen you if you
don't do this something bad will happen
but we've seen so many organizations
fall victim to these huge mega breaches
that should totally end their company
but we haven't seen any companies
actually go out of business because of
these mega breaches that might change it
might not so what if the bad thing never
happens if you keep telling people
something Bad's going to happen and it
never does they stop listening to you so
being more proactive it's just a better
way to get people to listen to you into
action so that's why I
here hopefully to help you so I call
this advanced soft skills because it
takes a step beyond just learning how to
talk to people building relationships
it's the direct application of empathy
if you read any piece on how to use soft
skills or improving soft skills for
information security there are a lot of
them out there they're all fantastic
most of them are going to mention
empathy and so empathy is the idea of
putting yourself in someone else's shoes
and you really need to do that in order
to apply efficacy you need to envision a
lot about the other person in order to
use it so that's why it's called
advanced soft skills just a quick little
bit on that so why should you guys care
have you ever had and I told you so
moment at work where you gave a
recommendation and it was totally
ignored and then something bad happened
couple of nods hand up thank you did it
feel good to say I told you so
in that instance no it doesn't feel good
sometimes it feels really good to say I
told you so sometimes it feels awful so
hopefully you can apply some of these
skills and tactics to avoid the
i-told-you-so moment and just tell them
and then they do the thing so the
premise here is that there's some risk
or threat that requires action to
mitigate it and you're gonna use
efficacy to convince them to do some
behavior you need to know what behavior
they need to do to fix the problem and
efficacy is how you're gonna get them to
do it so I've used this word a lot
already efficacy anybody familiar with
the term
they heard it before a couple of nods I
think you were my talk already you so
count you read ahead
so efficacy is the power or ability to
produce an effect its effectiveness I
use it because it comes from scholarship
it's one of those words that they've
decided to stick their hat on and so I'm
gonna stick my hat on there as well no
where does it come from it's got a
medical background I'm not gonna say
farm nope yep I did it in DC and I
didn't have tried to do it again so in
the medical field it is defined as the
capacity for beneficial change so what's
the therapeutic effect of a drug device
or procedure know if something will cure
a disease it has high medical efficacy I
think it might I've seen it a couple of
times used in terms of technology you
know the technology has some sort of
efficacy to solve a problem the cop this
concept eventually traveled across
campus to the social sciences through
health communication so that makes sense
the doctors were using it in their
research than the people who needed to
talk about the doctors research used it
in their communication and that's where
sort of how it transitioned a crust
across campus so what are some issues do
you think health communication is using
efficacy for
any ideas just shout it out
you
yeah so medical advertising might use
efficacy you'll see it in campaign so if
you think of public health campaigns so
your Public Health Authority wants you
to do something they want you to get a
flu shot they want you to use condoms
they want you to avoid smoking all of
those sort of pro health communications
you see those public service
announcements those are using efficacy
so this is looking at how doctors and
public health organizations convince
people to do healthy things the one
example that I want to show is a
commercial that ran several years ago
I'm not sure if anyone's familiar with
it but I've got a video at the end and I
really like this because it's a good
example of efficacy it's a commercial
that's trying to tell you how to
determine if you have pre-diabetes and
then get you to talk to your doctor
about it and so the way it works is this
man in a lab coat comes up and has you
answer a bunch of questions and with
each question you put up a set of
fingers so if someone in your family
already has diabetes put up one finger
if someone if your body shape looks like
this and he has a chart put up the
associated number of fingers and then at
the end he says okay if you have more
than seven fingers up right now you
should talk to your doctor and this is a
really good example of how efficacy
works because it's about reducing the
barrier to action and making things seem
simple and meeting the audience where
they are so we're going to look into
these tactics a little more but I want
to cover one last area where
efficacy comes into play and that's
emergency preparedness and so that's
sort of where I see information security
coming into play as well as emergency
preparedness is about doing things to
prevent damage when something bad
happens so do you live in an area that
is subject to a lot of hurricanes or
flooding here's how you prepare your
house preparedness
I think overlaps really well with
information security so that's why I
wanted to throw this in all right so
principles of usage so we're finally
gonna get into what we're actually doing
here I'm gonna stop kind of parsing it
among different disciplines and just
talk about it generally so we're not
going to say this is from help calm or
whatever this is just a kind of grab bag
of all different ideas from efficacy so
there are a couple of types of efficacy
and I'm going to talk about -
self-efficacy and response efficacy
self-efficacy is the belief that you can
actually perform the recommended action
so whatever you're being told to do if
you don't think you can actually do that
you have low self-efficacy and then
response efficacy is will this thing
actually solve my problem so if someone
tells you to do something to solve your
problem and you don't think it's gonna
work you have low response efficacy so
in order to actually use this you need
to know a little bit about your audience
and this is where empathy comes in
because in a lot of cases you won't be
able to ask your audience this but you
need to know whether or not they
actually recognize there's a problem and
that's something that I think we
struggle with in information security a
lot of our audiences either don't know
there's a problem don't know how serious
the problem is or don't think the
problem is airs so you have to kind of
argue with them and convince them this
is your problem you own it you have to
do something not just you can do
something and then constraint
recognition what are some thing
is that your audience sees as barriers
so what are some barriers that people
might throw at you when you tell them to
do something about InfoSec budget yes
our favorite one what else though time
budget time
I'm sorry I didn't hear that one history
yeah we don't do it that way or we've
always done it this way or we've never
been breached before so we're totally
fine right those are all barriers and so
what you do with efficacy is think about
okay why do they see that as a barrier
and how can I get them around it over it
through it or show them that it doesn't
actually exist so what you want to know
is where are they now what barriers do
they perceive do they see an actual
problem in existence and where do they
need to be to act what is that sort of
minimum level of interest or constraints
or what-have-you that will actually get
them to do something and that's
something that we're gonna need a little
more empirical research on I hope to do
that eventually but you get the idea
that you know you have to move them
somewhere you don't have to get them to
being InfoSec evangelists you just have
to get them far enough along the tikar
to actually take the action you want so
now you know where they are and now you
know where they need to be so how do you
get them from point A to B what we've
been using a lot in InfoSec has been
fear and I've mentioned before that
hasn't worked super well and I think a
lot of that stems from the sort of
history of how InfoSec has been treated
as a field and a discipline it's been
treated like dark sorcery and hidden in
a corner and no one really wants to talk
about it so the information security
people had to be louder they had to
shout to get attention and now people
are actually paying attention but
InfoSec is still kind of in that place
where we think we need to be loud and
shouty and scary to be heard because
that's how it has been but I think we
can move in a more positive direction
focus less on fear because people are
listening and if you move in a more
positive direction people will feel
better talking to you if they feel
better talking to you they'll want to do
it more and you'll build those
relationships
so I haven't said this yet but we're
talking a little bit about manipulation
you're trying to manipulate their
perceptions you're trying to persuade
and influence them and her PR and
communication likes to avoid the terms
manipulation but that is what you're
doing the thing here though is you're
supposed to be using this for making
people more secure you're trying to kind
of hack their risk perception show them
that they are at risk they can do
something about it and make them more
secure using efficacy so I can trust you
guys to use these powers for good great
promise right exactly that's totally the
audience that I should be asking to use
this power for good anyway this is how
you actually do it
so self-efficacy you can do something
and you have to do something so first
they have to realize there's a problem
that requires action
I mentioned that and you have to remove
perceived constraints so this is where
you think about what are their
constraints unfamiliar behavior trust
money those are all constraints that I
think really apply to information
security unfamiliar behavior these
people have probably never done the
things you're asking them to do they
have no idea what two-factor
authentication is they don't know any of
the controls you're talking about you
guys don't necessarily speak the same
language that creates a lot of anxiety
in people and makes them uncomfortable
and that's a constraint they stopped
listening when they feel bad so trying
to take a step back reduce the language
reduce the things you're asking them to
do into very small understandable steps
it's important and that really does
depend on your audience
if you're talking to executives they're
gonna have a different level of
understanding then if you're talking to
a CEO or if you're talking to your mom
at home they'll find out what language
your audience is familiar with and stick
to that so they don't have to ask you to
define words you're doing it beforehand
you're pre-empting their questions and
anticipating their needs so that you
show that you're empathetic and you're
listening and you're caring so now that
you have convinced them that the
constraints are gone actually I want to
go back so what are some other ways that
you might reduce constraints for your
audience
so say that the constraint is trust
they don't trust security procedures
they don't necessarily trust you cuz
you're a brand new face what might you
do to build trust or a different
constraint if you want to pick that
become their friends no show that you
know stuff about them and we'll get into
this with response efficacy as well but
if you're consulting with an
organization and they say okay well
that's not gonna work for us your
response should be okay well based on
this this and this in your organization
I know that this will work so showing
that you've done your research and you
know them and you've taken the time to
tailor your responses to them as an
individual
they will feel special and they will
trust you more what about unfamiliar
behavior I gave a couple of general
ideas but what are some other ways you
can reduce that constraint
training go start early if you're trying
to do employee awareness it should be an
ongoing process it shouldn't be one and
done ongoing exposure to these sorts of
terms this terminology these sorts of
behaviors is the way to make people more
comfortable that gets rid of unfamiliar
because they're seeing it all the time
it is now familiar all right so now
response efficacy so you want to prove
that this is the best action for them
why are you telling them to do this
particular thing there are a lot of
different solutions and information
security the thing that I always point
out in this for sort of my friends and
people who aren't as technical is I
asked them okay how do you make a good
password what what is a good password
and they can't answer because to them
there's no solid agreement on what a
good password is that's the perception
we're dealing with is that we don't have
our ducks in a row we can't agree what
the best response is so why should I
trust what you're telling me to do now
that's the thing you're trying to come
and get across you're trying to say no
this is the right response for you
here's why so again you're going to be
tailoring it to their specific pace
saying I know this much about your
organization and that's why I know that
this is the right thing because of XYZ
if you have statistics that's fantastic
anecdotes are also really good tell
people a story to get them to change
their behavior if you have it make one
up tell a hypothetical story and use
that to get them through and show that
this is the best action so I want to
circle back to fear one last time and
talk about why we don't respond to those
so if someone says to you you have 20%
risk of this thing happening you're
probably going to think you're part of
the 80% if they say there's a 99% chance
of this happening to you
you're gonna think you're part of the 1%
that it won't happen - we love its
human nature to think that we are
special that's not a bad thing that's
just how everyone works
you're gonna think you're part of the
percentage that is safe you're going to
come up with lists of reasons why you
are not at risk and so that comes in
with response efficacy you're trying to
convince your audience unfortunately you
are not special you are going to be at
risk for this you are probably part of
that 20% or 50% or 80% that is
susceptible and here's why so walking
them through your rationale is really
important it's like in school when you
were told to show your work and you were
like I got the right answer why does it
matter here it does matter because
you're trying to lead your audience
through your decision process so that
they can see okay well I would have made
a different decision here
so I can negate everything else they say
if you're walking them through your
decision process and you're convincing
they're following you and they will come
to the same conclusion it's almost about
tricking them into thinking they made
the decision themselves so show your
work yeah
you
I'm really glad you asked that question
because I'm currently working on
updating this talk based on research
I've been doing right now into gain/loss
framing and that's exactly what I'm
arguing is that you should focus on the
positive so you should focus on gaining
instead of avoiding to move even farther
away from fear so instead of saying you
have a 20% chance of being a victim say
this this solution will improve your
security like focus on being more
positive focus on the benefits that
they're gonna gain and so that's
something that I've been working on and
I'll kind of plug my blog later so you
can look at it but that's a really good
question
moving away from saying here are your
risks here's how dangerous this is for
you try focusing on here's how good
you'll feel after you do this thing
you'll be able to step up and pass your
competitors you'll be able to brag to
your friends or you know when I tell my
friends and family to start doing
different security things I'll say ok
well I'm gonna teach you and then you go
to work and teach your friends and
they're gonna think you're really smart
and cool and you're gonna be a badass in
your office and so focusing on the
positive side of things is sort of the
next step of this oh thank you for that
question it's like I planted that but I
didn't so
No
you
yeah
yes
you
absolutely ya know and so that brings it
to a good point as well is knowing your
audience is knowing where your audience
is and what will persuade them the story
I tell a lot in when I taught public
speaking and we were preparing for
persuasive speeches is whenever I was
trying to convince my dad of something
he is an engineer so he needs to know
the math and the science and whatever
sort of hard facts behind your decision
so in it whenever I was trying to
persuade him I would do calculations I
would come up with at one point I
actually used net profit in a
conversation with my father to convince
him
whereas with my mom she is not as hard
science she wants just to focus on the
more qualitative benefits so I'll say
it'll make me really happy if this thing
happens and so knowing your audience and
what will persuade them is the
foundation to all of persuasion is
knowing what is actually going to be
persuasive to these people so if you're
talking to money people you're talking
about return on investment so you need
to figure out how to calculate the
actual return on investment because they
need to hear dollar amounts and so that
is a really key point as well is you do
want to be more positive but some people
you will have to scare and you are gonna
have to make that decision on your own
or hopefully you know talk to the
communication people because their whole
sort of background we've spent years in
PR trying to figure out how to quantify
what we do because what we do isn't easy
to quantify its seen as fluffy it's seen
as a lot of waste in a lot of
organizations that's taken a turn now
but we do have a history of trying to
figure out how to show hard statistics
in ROI for something that is avoiding
bad so you can't quantify okay well
because you you applied this you didn't
experience a breach and you didn't
here's the money you didn't lose like
that's not the best way no figuring out
how to quantify this is something that
communication and PR can also help with
and there are other fields who have done
it as well but yeah it's all about
picking your audience and knowing
they need to change their behavior so
and I think the balance is the key part
is not only focusing on one or the other
use I think the way the way that I would
recommend is developing a narrative
through what you're saying
go start off scary start off with these
statistics start off with their actual
risk and the difficult potential and all
of that and as you're progressing move
in a more positive direction that's
another principle of persuasion you
start off with negative emotions and as
you're communicating you're
transitioning into more positive you're
talking about the benefits they'll gain
in addition to the risks that they're
going to avoid so really taking that
balance and creating a narrative with it
so you're telling them a story and
they're the heroes of that story so I'm
gonna skip the exercise for now and talk
a little bit about some of these
specifics for emphasis I've hit them a
little bit but I want to kind of circle
back before an incident you got to make
the risks real so show them similar
organizations to them show how those
organizations are similar so if you're
trying to use Equifax as a case why is
your company similar to Equifax what are
the similar cases are they in a similar
field are they going to be targeted
because of the data that they have so
really tying together your carry
statistics with why it applies to them
getting them over that hump of it'll
never happen to me because I'm special
why are they not special linking
security behaviors to ones that they
already do this is one that I think is
especially particular if you're talking
to end users if you're talking to an end
user they're not going to be familiar
with the language they're not going to
be familiar with the behaviors if you're
able to link the security behavior to
something that they're doing in their
life already
so maybe using or doing a drill so I
hear likening it to fire drills all of
the time it's not a bad idea if you're
talking about having them do security
audits or penetration testing maybe
liken that to
quarterly performance reviews things
that they're doing on a regular basis so
that's gonna be a little bit on you to
think about okay I've got this security
thing that I want them to do what is
that like in their everyday life so
think about it use that empathy that
sort of putting yourself in their shoes
even just think about what you do in
your everyday life that's similar
and then overcoming fatalism this is one
that we see a lot in information
security as well it's not if you get
breached it's when companies are
starting to get why set and they're like
okay if I'm gonna get breached anyway
I bother why yet why even do this and so
trying to get them over that I think the
positivity might help showing the
different benefits you're not just gonna
avoid a breach this is you're going to
be a leader in your field you're going
to step ahead of your competitors
whatever other benefits that they can
get beyond just avoiding a breach
because it is there's a good chance it's
still gonna happen
alright so during an incident you can
still use efficacy you can still use
these communication principles you're
highlighting the protective powers of
whatever behavior you're doing so
instead of avoiding risks you're telling
them doing this thing will protect you
so when people are talking about doing
credit freezes after Equifax this is how
it's going to protect you that sort of
example so instead of saying it will
avoid a breach saying how it's going to
defend you once a breach has happened
using statistics and anecdotes to prove
your response efficacy is also important
here and then finally you want to break
it all down into small digestible
actions so you guys probably do this
already in terms of not just plopping a
whole security plan in front of your
personal contact or anyone you're going
to take it into little bites did we do
this first and it's really easy and it's
like doing this in your everyday life
and then you do this and making it small
and digestible so they're not
overwhelmed
all right and then embracing uncertainty
there is a lot of uncertainty and
information security and you're better
off actually fessing up to this
uncertainty in your conversations with
people then trying to deny it if there
is uncertainty if you can't make
guarantees don't do it okay okay well
this is your best case scenario because
I'm an expert I know what I'm talking
about here's why I think this is the
best case scenario if you try and tell
them that this will save them and it
doesn't you're breaking down trust
you're trying to build trust and
actually coming forward to someone and
saying this is your best-case scenario
this is the best I can do it's not 100%
but it will be better can help build
trust because people are initially
reactive when they hear over-promising
or think that people are overcome over
compensating for potential drawbacks so
if you come forward and point out the
drawbacks proactively you're gonna build
that trust they're gonna say okay
they're not hiding things from me
they're pointing out that drawback
they're not hiding anything else you're
gonna tell me straight up so a way to
build trust with that alright so times
of crisis I want to skip this a little
bit and so today we've talked about
moving information security
communication beyond crisis we're saying
how fear isn't the best motivator
you don't want to have risk statistics
but you also want to balance that out
with more positive messaging simple
explanations like my end users are
stupid or they don't care aren't
sufficient because they don't actually
get anything done and yes a lot of end
users make mistakes and do the wrong
thing a lot of executives don't listen
to you when they should and it's
horribly frustrating I can't even
imagine but tapping there doesn't solve
the problem of people being insecure
using efficacy and understanding okay
why don't they care enough why aren't
they paying attention to their their
risk
thinking about the whys behind these
simple explanations can help you get
around them hopefully and then finally
efficacy is direct application of that
empathy to try and get across so what we
still need to know here through
empirical studies I want to find out
what are people's levels of efficacy do
they think they actually have the
capability of being more secure and
that's all audience based few executives
think this I've seen a lot of studies
recently of usually the statistic is
executives thinks executives think that
they are prepared to respond to an
incident despite the fact that in the
last year 65 percent of them failed to
do so so that's where you see it is they
think they are capable of doing things
when the statistics show that they are
not but I want to get some some more
statistics on that and then levels of
problem recognition do people actually
think that these problems are theirs and
that they need to be solved so this is a
little bit more about end users the
general public how concerned are they
really with their security and do they
think it's a problem that they need to
solve constraints we talked about that a
little but also thinking more about the
psychology behind it so why do people
ignore security recommendations on a
psychological basis why are they giving
the excuse of money is it because money
is really a case because when you really
think about it an investment in security
shouldn't be that big of a deal it
should be important enough to get over
most budgetary constraints so what's the
psychology behind them saying we don't
have the money for it it might be
legitimately we don't have the money but
there might be something else it might
be we don't see value in security so how
do you twist that how do you get them to
actually see value and then finally
what's the threshold for action what
movement do you need in there constraint
and problem recognition in their self
efficacy and their response efficacy how
far do you need to get them to move
because if you only need to get them to
move a little bit
that's really different than if you need
to them to move a marathon so figuring
out how much distance is required how
much persuasion is required is really
important and then figuring out and this
is more of a project for me it's
figuring out increased consensus on
recommendations everyone's going to have
their own solutions but trying to figure
out how to communicate what the best
practices really are so that's what I
have to cover and further reading here
where to find me
I am on Twitter all of the time I have a
blog that I write about every other week
and so you'll see that updated post on
gain and loss framing and so with that I
argue about moving in that more positive
direction focusing on the benefits that
your audience can gain from being more
secure and how to develop a
communication program around that so
that's my information I also include
some scholarly sources I really
recommend you look them up if you're
interested you can only you can read
just the abstract if you want cuz
they're probably about 20 pages each if
you're not a nerd like me so let's go
back to the overview and I'll take some
questions
you
yeah so I kind of see two answers to
your question and so the question was
about sort of the stereo I'm doing this
for the the web folks and the people in
the other room the question is is there
a place for the stereotypical antisocial
InfoSec person in this sort of model and
that one the answer is definitely yes I
see this as it's kind of a formula so if
you don't do well with people I'm an
introvert despite all of this I'm
uncomfortable talking to people I don't
know and so having a formula like this
okay I can brainstorm and think about
their constraints what are their
constraints how do I break down those
constraints and get them around it
it can give you a little bit more of a
script and a formula to be more
comfortable and more personable if
that's not your jam so you can kind of
script out what you're going to say more
so you're not necessarily talking off of
the cuff and be more prepared so you
don't have to necessarily be charismatic
or extroverted you can plan ahead have a
script have an outline have you know
brainstorm questions and treat it a
little more like an engineering or math
problem rather than something softer and
so that's part one and part two is if
you are an InfoSec person who is more
personable who doesn't fall into that
stereotype you can then kind of step
forward on your team and say I got this
like I will be the external face of our
team I will use these skills so sort of
double answer to that of if you're the
stereotypical person you can take this a
little bit of a step back make it a
little less fluffy and make it more
about a math or science problem of okay
I have this constraint and here are the
ways that they can get around it and
make it a little more low charty and
less storytelling but if you do like
storytelling if you like talking to
people and you're in InfoSec this can be
a really good way to kind of flex those
skills and get that into your wheelhouse
a little bit more
did I answer your question okay great
yes
you
yes yeah that would be my dream for
security teams and communication teams
inside of an organization working
together to develop communication and we
see that in a couple of organizations
you know maybe a handful of
organizations are actually teaming up
communication and security to develop
communication programs and messaging and
campaigns and all of that so it is
happening and if you have relationships
with your communication team you can go
to them and say hey I need to do this
presentation to get more budget can you
help me out they'll probably have the
tools to help you out they might have
just general speaker training guides
they might have actual like budgetary
presentations that they've given that
worked so make friends with your
communication people and I don't just
say that because I'm a communication
purple person and I like having InfoSec
friends but make you know take them out
to coffee meet them at just an all-hands
meeting get to know them because
hopefully what I want to see is
organizations talking openly about
security when isn't on fire so
eventually my idea is that the security
team is going to be working with
communication because they're going to
be talking about communication console
are they're gonna be talking about
security all the time so they're gonna
need that relationship but that's just
pie in the sky dream for me any other
questions
you
yes no I definitely good question so the
question is how do you get someone to
change when you're telling them that
they're wrong and making them feel bad
about being wrong and that's a big
question and I think a lot of it has to
do with giving them an excuse for being
wrong letting it be okay that they've
been wrong and maybe it isn't actually
okay maybe you went to them two years
ago when the problem actually started
and they didn't listen to you then and
you had to come back now and say hey
look I was right you were wrong that's
not the approach you want to take so
giving them an excuse to be wrong making
it safe so potentially you're showing
them brand-new technology or a new
problem trying to find a way to make it
okay that they were wrong and kind of
protect themselves save face in their
wrongness or depending on which
direction you're going try and get just
present them like hey I've got this
problem how do you think we should solve
it so let them come up with the
solutions start at that conversation of
just here's a problem that means a
solution don't attribute it to anyone
just say here's a problem that exists
can we work together to fix it so they
they don't have to be wrong they're
fixing a problem or you know giving them
that safe that safety of like you were
wrong but here are all of the reasons
that it's okay you were wrong so many
other people were wrong or here's a
brand new technology that proved that
you were wrong and you didn't know all
of those things yeah
you
yeah no that's I think that's a really
good plug so I'm going to repeat it for
the internet public speaking isn't easy
for the majority of people I was and
sort of am still technically a
professional public speaker and I
couldn't have coffee this morning
because I was going to just like vibrate
at a frequency that made me invisible I
was so stressed out and like I'm fine
now I've given this talk before I'm very
comfortable with it but I still have
anxiety when I speak publicly he
mentioned a couple of people web Reacher
gave a really great talk at besides DC
that's online that you can see about
impostor syndrome and I think that
extends here as well but getting
experience with public speaking or just
speaking to small groups I think is
really important or anyone and
particularly if you're naturally
introverted the way that I kind of
solved this problem was when I joined
grad school I had to teach I taught
three 50-minute sections three days a
week that's a lot of public speaking in
front of freshmen in a required public
speaking course so it wasn't a really
excited audience no finding I don't
recommend doing that for anyone but
finding something like Nova hackers or a
different local small organization that
does these sorts of things if there's
something like Toastmasters or anything
like that that you can be a part of
there's a program called nerd night as
well that's not InfoSec you can talk
about security issues but anything where
you're getting up practicing and talking
to people is a really good sort of
practice to get into pushing yourself
out of that comfort zone will really add
these skills kind of to your tool belt
and when you're just a decent public
speaker no one really notices there
they're like oh he was good he was good
they don't you know they don't notice
your mistakes
they don't really point anything out
you're fine but when you're a good
public speaker when you really hit your
mark people remember and they notice and
they remember you know that's that's one
way to get these across as well as to be
memorable
it's just sing your public speaking I
think is a great plug as well any other
questions
you
yeah so becoming friends I think with
legal in particular is great because
when organizations are making decisions
about security they're thinking is this
gonna get us sued so they're gonna talk
to their legal team so if their legal
team then can say oh wait no I know the
person you should be talking to about
this and that person is you that's great
so even maybe before you talk to your
communication people which breaks my
heart
talk to your legal team make friends
with the legal team make friends with
the people who write the budget
understand why they write the budget in
a particular way and try and slide in in
that direction all right any other
questions
all right so I'm going to wrap up now
with that thank you guys so much for
your attention I'll be around the rest
of the weekend if you want to keep
talking
you