hi everybody in the room and you at home
my name is Joe Klein I am a yes hacker
and we're gonna talk about this because
um people are getting confused about
really what this means I've got lots of
certifications I'm actually a fellow for
the ipv6 forum have been for six years
and have been a a into the ipv6
community now for 16 I think 16 years
may be doing security research in this
domain helping write standards
designing products designing defenses
and attacks just primarily looking at
this from many different views this
presentation oh yes I'm also CTO of
disrupt six which would create ipv6
specific products and services security
researcher and a trainer I have a new
set of training coming up in February
which is a four day I only know
networking to here's how to hack or do
to defend ipv6 only environments which
is pretty fun it's only taken an
additional year for me to write it
because I have a lot of laughs as
someone to write and then there's my
contact if you want to add me to your
Twitter stream there's my Twitter by the
way so I spoke at Bogota
when ipv6 security a month ago and I
became this was I consider now my blue
period and they informed me that I was
definitely a hacker so with that I like
the 1960 version of hacker okay I
explore the details of programmable
systems and how to stretch their
capabilities okay
and then this was also good I eat EF
standards body you know intimate
intimate understanding it's kind of
interesting of internal workings of
systems computers networks
okay it was until 1985 where that
definition of hacker changed from
somebody that would be considered an
inventor just someone's considered a
criminal so I just want to mention that
I usually preface this particular talk
on that so sorry this is the high level
stuff community computing has driven
prices down for every generation we've
actually brought on new protocols new
systems new applications new concepts we
have this growth curve that doesn't look
like it's gonna stop at least maybe 2030
2040 based on that least current physics
current understanding current other
things so this is gonna continue for a
while which means if you're in the
information security domain woohoo we're
gonna still have jobs okay and yes there
are now more devices then there are
people okay how many devices do you have
on you I have I have five okay at my
home I have herds and herds of little
things okay maybe I'm abnormal you know
maybe I should be worrying about you
know Arnold visit but this is an
understanding that we still have a
population increase but we're also
seeing new systems they're actually
supporting individuals in healthcare in
building controls things that actually
improve hopefully our lives so this is
the whole plethora of Internet of Things
ok what we've been focusing on for
information security kissed or eclis has
only been the pink area okay we've kind
of not done any of this and a lot of
these are systems matter of fact I just
in an assessment against a logistics
company
not patched for 12 years running out of
date this no passwords RF was open
blah-blah-blah-blah-blah
okay is a company actually designs and
builds this replicates this every month
someplace in the country so crazy so
there's an opportunity from a security
standpoint to look at all this
okay Internet the historic internet
growth you notice 1970 there was
actually a day where everybody had to go
from the old protocol turn their
computers off reboot them with the new
software and go to IP v4 guess what we
couldn't do that with ipv6 something
about six billion computers we just
can't upload and patch them all at the
same time if they anybody would actually
allow us to patch okay so we saw a
growth but during that growth because we
started seeing extreme growth we had to
find a whole bunch of new protocols and
changes we had to add NAT NAT is bad it
really is not a security product
we'd have RFC 1918 to support NAT we had
to have classless classless classful
classless yes center blocks DHCP and
then we had to actually add and I it was
funny at one point web servers only ran
on a single IP address and after the
study and from IETF internet Engineering
Task Force who writes the protocols for
the internet once they made their
announcement and 2019 93 we started
redesigning Apache which by the way you
know how to patchy stood for it was a
patch II configuration of the NCSA
open-source code so that's where patchy
came from
you didn't know that which i think is
funny so we helped design it to create
virtual servers because at one point one
server per IP address now with web
services we have many devices using
other techniques on one IP address which
by the way adds confusion and makes it
harder for us for security and that I
actually have an hour presentation on
that don't have the time to talk about
that so this is today's security
environment okay these are like let's
see Nats
yeah okay and bridges and gateways and
you know this is the Commons because
it's all dirty and everything so
security wasn't built into ipv4 and by
the way helmet the addresses the address
assignment based on Vint Cerf father of
the Internet he said well you know we're
gonna use a 32-bit number and the
world's only gonna need because there's
less than 200 countries let's say we're
gonna have to in our countries and each
country is going to have a network for
their governments and a network for the
commercial side awesome now we know how
big of an address space we had and
that's how the ipv4 infrastructure was
actually scoped okay and because of that
a lot of changes had to take place that
that at one point caused routers to have
problems and things like that so we've
been working since 94 to extend the life
of ipv4 until we can come up with some
kind of replacement sadly a lot of the
aging infrastructure still sits out
there I found a router that's 15 years
old last week when I was looking at it
that had a very very very old version of
an operating system on it very bad we've
also lost our end-to-end trust because
we have Nats and CD ends and we have all
these other middle box technologies each
of those middle boxes actually take us
one one level away from being able to
trust a specific machine or specific
individual
in your early IP before we had a book
which you basically open up ago I need
to go find this here's the data that's
here and here's the IP address and
here's the administrator awesome ok it
was a text file that we would print but
you know the other problem we have is
negative externalities people are
unwilling to fix their infrastructures
if it doesn't help them directly they
directly will not provide a certificate
on their system unless they can see
personal benefit not benefit to their
customers they won't support DNS SEC
because well it's gonna cost them time
and effort therefore if anybody gets you
know redirected to somebody else's
system servers VPNs not a big deal same
thing with proxy same thing with a lot
of Technology so basically we have this
mess on our hands with ipv4 we have a
chance to change things ok this is the
war we're in yeah they're coming from
all directions and we're all standing in
line we have to be close because there's
so few ipv4 addresses so let's talk
about how fast we can scan six minutes
the whole internet do you feel
comfortable now ok so if you put a
system on the Internet in the next six
minutes somebody will scan you actually
multiple peoples can you which means
it's yet speed for discovery yeah
microseconds compromises on systems that
have been detected for a specific thing
or about two minutes this is a study I
did four years ago makes me feel really
comfortable and warm and fuzzy plugging
anything into the ipv4 infrastructure
the impact of cyber crime on the
industry on the world today is 2017 was
about 450 billion dollars and the a
single attack and I was talking to the
group yesterday was that businesses here
either
hobbled sold or died within 10 years
after a major compromise we discussed
specific companies that in the last five
years have been found to be compromised
and then we're sold off for pennies on
the dollar okay
or going out of business or close
three-quarters of their stores or
whatever governments if the government
is hacked we lose their data that
reduces our trust right and lastly we
have lifelong burdens when our
identities are stolen so that's a real
problem so yes you are here yeah that
right there
so FRA pv6 everybody saying nobody uses
ipv6 okay in the world and this date
right here is interesting the 2012 is
world internet day this is when we
actually turned it on before this is
when crazy people like me spend our time
watching packets move back and forth and
doing both fun and evil things to it
okay starting June 6 a 26-6 I anyway
2012 we started seeing growth if you
noticed the world is already at almost
21% as of today and everybody says but
what about the US what do you think
could we call that 40% that's pretty
significant so how many you're securing
your ipv6 infrastructures 100% of your
technology supports ipv6 at least your
host based systems and your servers but
not so much your security products and
we will go into detail about that but
it's a little bit disconcerting
so you have one or two choices by the
way I love this picture
this just makes me laugh so comparison
deployed in 1970 where we actually
turned all the stuff off and a return to
back on it was experimental for ipv6
since 96 and actually gave a
presentation in 96 about ipv6 which is
pretty funny
maximum devices are 2.4 time times tend
to be well I didn't put that up there
that's funny
the term is 240 undecillion so for your
interest you can look that up
it was commercialized and 1990 ipv6 win
world on 2012 you may not be aware of
this but last year the internet
Engineering Task Force has made a
commitment not to make any changes to
any protocol that runs across ipv4 only
that's a risk to anybody running only
ipv4 okay so if a change if they find a
major fall in something they can patch
it but they it won't become a standard
to ensure that we have consistency of
communications that's that's an
interesting thing the other thing is
there's already an end-of-life chosen
this is the initial 20 22 Wow we're
gonna be really busy upgrading stuff are
we and yes this makes me laugh
one year at major conference I security
conference I put together a bunch of
these and printed them and I tested
almost 200 companies yeah supposedly
supported ipv6 and everyone except for
for receive my sticker of support which
is fun the other ones received that one
a current estimated life shelf-life of
ipv6 an underlying protocol is 2062
20100 so an asshole depending on a bunch
of other things there's technology for
the galactic internet and planetary
internet right now there's protocols for
that it's it's pretty interesting stuff
so you need a unique addresses for to
connect devices you really do sir yes
uh yeah I you can go to the NIST
standard there's a NIST standard for
testing ipv6 products I when I rent went
around made sure the interfaces worked I
made sure the administration worked and
I made sure that if I gave it a few
packets it could detect it and within 10
minutes I could find a product actually
failed so it was it was pretty
interesting so anyway so this came out
from Ken gear if you haven't seen him
he's a great presenter he I'm very
impressed with the man as far as
presentation skills someday I'll be that
good he basically did while he was at in
a research position he did an analysis
against how do we fix cyber crime and
cyber threats so he approached it from
the technical he approached it from the
military the political military which we
keep on hearing people talk about it and
the political technical things like you
know let's create cyber deterrence we
keep on hearing that we have a cyber
arms race we use art of war for us on
sue please go out and pull this paper
and read it
it's fascinating based on both game
theory and his particular process to
show what's gonna work what's not gonna
work and some of these things are gonna
work or that aren't gonna work are gonna
actually end up making the internet and
operations using the Internet even worse
so just want to mention that but he
actually had a call-out based on two
years worth of studying on this dad ipv6
with good crypto provides end-to-end
trust therefore there's a better way of
providing a more trusted infrastructure
so you guys have heard of the kill chain
no Kay no kill chains here this is the
survivability model for resilience
I wouldn't mention this because I'm
spending a lot of time if you see other
presentations I've given over the last
year I'm working on a survivability
model called anti fragile but I'm trying
to put this in context to the discussion
we're gonna have on ipv6 the closer to
this side that we can catch an attacker
the least expensive it is on the
organization the further we get to here
this is where the boom starts this is
where the big money starts for a lot of
people and that's why a lot of people a
lot of organizations are focused on
trying to fix this but if you can get
ahead of the game it's very good the
other side is that we're win Swart al
who wrote a book called time-based
security discuss is from an analogue
standpoint that we have to basically
have protection has to be greater than
the ability for us to detect and respond
today most of our technologies assume
that we can detect and respond think
about your your device that's gathering
your logs how fast does it go from the
sensor to the sim and somebody either
automatically or gets in the way to do a
response to be able to fix that problem
that could be seconds minutes or hours
or days or weeks or months right maybe
years depending on the company you're at
so the faster we can respond here the
more secure we have there is a new book
coming out analog security which will
discuss this including a whole set of
mathematical formulas to actually start
defining or creating a start to defining
a mathematical model of what security
and assurance looks like and I'm really
excited I've been part of that project
so if we're moving to ipv6
the first thing we have to do is we
really have to move we'd love to save
move to ipv6-only right away
you really can't every organisation it
has things went bad real quickly mostly
because you have a lot of hidden ipv4
Mis installed both in your architecture
your applications the way we design our
database our management systems our
security systems our sock or NOC our
management infrastructure funding
everything else is is focused on it so
we typically have a first step to go to
dual-stack so the first thing you have
to think about is the mindset okay
these are only a couple if you're
interested you can go to a website
called ipv6 bingo and it will generate a
bingo card for denial and then it then
if you click on the link it'll actually
give you the science and all references
to all the current issues one is that it
won't have any impact on batteries there
was a study from Nokia that we can
reduce our battery or we can increase
our battery life anywhere between six
and 20-some percent by going to ipv6
only and getting away from ipv4 because
for every application I have to make a
connection I have to create a NAT open a
firewall someplace I have to open on my
side and I happen to have to open on
their side and then for every CDN and
everything else along the way I have to
maintain state on all of that for every
application I run so your phone is
running how many applications has to
make so many connections it actually
maintains state so that you can actually
communicate so v6
data's sent there's no NAT there's no
state required it comes back like is
good okay because we're trying to take
state away from the network
infrastructure and put it on the hosts
they're a little bit better for dealing
with state but yeah this these are fun
no business value want to mention this
there's anybody in datacenters by do
data centers I'll mention this LinkedIn
and Facebook have said that they once
they move to an ipv6 only environment
they say anywhere from nine to twenty
plus percent operational and staffing
and now they've created new models
they've actually reduced programming
costs and lots of other things so this
is a big deal
so that's just one example so I just
want to mention that there's some
interesting things the other thing is if
you're gonna get people trained don't
just train your network engineers make
sure your helpdesk how are they gonna
answer you know if they type you know
NAT stat or whatever how are they gonna
represent to the customer what that
means and how to troubleshoot that stuff
the defenders if you're doing defense
you should actually have a real good
handle in ipv6 because there's some
really cool features I'm going to talk
about a couple of them and your
programmers have to know how to write it
because programmers we have today some
of them are using old libraries that
don't support ipv6 and have flaws in
them one of the challenges that we have
today is that because of that long
build-up because we didn't want to
restart the internet the we had four
generations of ipv6 protocols and
standards depending on the company that
you've worked with to buy products and
services even today you could have any
of those generational issues in it
the newest one actually has a lot of
fixes for security and operational
issues the older ones don't
so you'll find code and products that
have made your falls in it so I want to
mention that because this is this is
what I've been trying to crusade for to
get fixed for the last umpteen years the
other thing is problems exist when you
migrate at layer 2 through layer 7 we
found Ethernet cards that don't support
ipv6 so therefore if it runs data real
fast and they offload it to the ethernet
card it sees ipv6 it uses a seat for you
there for now processing and everything
else slows down and those are the kind
of little tidbits that we found also the
management layer because the management
layer needs to know that you're trying
to do something that's good for the
business procurement I mentioned this
yesterday something called the S dock
basically a procurement document
requiring organizations to buy products
that have security and specific sets of
compliance if you go to nist ipv6 s dock
you'll get all the definitions and
references back to the ansi documents
without paying for the ansi documents so
that you can learn how to use this in
your procurement policy interesting
organizations that have used this
process have improved security because
every new procurement that says i have a
processor in it and i have a network
interface must follow this standard
whether it's a there has to be a patch i
have to be a to do real authentication
there has to be encryption whatever it
is that your standard requires has
actually saved money over time for
companies have done that and i'm going
to mention that because the ipv6
community started that four years ago
when we've had some real successes on
not only ipv6 compatibility and but also
security of improvement of devices over
time ok
if we're running dual-stack we had this
crazy problem it's early in the
deployment of ipv6 we thought about wow
we're gonna have a oceans of ipv6 and
islands of IP v of ipv4 and islands of
ipv6 and we had to create all these
protocols so everything talked so we
started creating lots of protocols I
didn't include them all because it would
go off and it would be too small and you
would be to read it and not really
useful on the other side now we have
protocols to deal with islands of ipv4
across ipv6 oceans ok so these things
cause real havoc one specific item I
want to mention so when do you say thank
the first published vulnerability and
attack using ipv6 was actually the first
published because they had logging on
was 2001 ok that's a long time ago ok if
you go to some of my previous
presentations over the last 12 years or
whatever 15 years I keep a timeline of
all those compromises and what caused
what caused them what was the root cause
what was could they detect it could they
not detect it things like that so these
are a real headache for us when we're in
an ipv4 ipv6 environment the other thing
these layers can be deep we have found
we found GRE with ipv4 the ipv6 embedded
in it as ways of getting around IDS's
intrusion detection systems okay so this
impacts us from a security standpoint we
have to be able to detect us
and I've running dual-stack is expensive
so the surface areas increase its
doubled yes it the tunnels are a real
headache to deal with a lot of
applications and security controls are
inconsistent and a bunch of products for
about eight years I spent a lot of time
trying to make sure that the firewalls
worked and in some cases the firewalls
for ipv4 would be turned on and it would
turn off the ipv6 firewall hi Charlie
I've gave you six five the ipv4 firewall
and some of those who are commercial
products some of those were consumer
products so you have to look at the
secure the application security for
anything that comes across your network
also the increasing complexity of DNS
because now if I'm doing passive DNS
monitoring I can have a DNS go through
TCP or UDP across ipv4 or ipv6 looking
for a or quad a records C in complexity
or concern here how are you going to
monitor that and associate it with each
request to see if it's a C and C or not
a tunnel okay this this makes it rather
complex also budget which is really the
largest risk ipv6 when you're running
ipv4 and ipv6 together operationally and
it increases it some people say it
increases the operational cost by third
a lot of organizations are trying to
move to ipv6 very quickly anybody heard
of LinkedIn they're completely
internally 99% ipv6 only in their data
centers and internally same thing with
Facebook they love it it's it's reduced
a lot of complexity they have which is
pretty neat and the organizations that
are using internal we'll talk about that
our finally I PU six is pretty cold ok
security analysis I still find
applications
don't log the address right you have 128
bits and a lot of applications go I only
do 32 bits so I'm gonna whack out off
the front or I'm gonna whack off the
back and this is what goes to your sim
there are certain addresses that then
look at like and map to specific nation
states that aren't really attacking us
via ipv6 so that's a concern the other
thing is a lot of storage and analytics
engines haven't upgraded their back-end
so they're representing the ipv6 address
as a string how fast is it how fast is a
binary compared to a string very fast a
lot of products haven't upgraded that
therefore if you're doing threat
intelligence you're doing sock work
you're trying to look for some address
that matches something or close to it
this has become a real problem in socks
also mapping ipv4 to ipv6 if I'm being
attacked by a p4 person and an ipv6
person are they the same are they
different should you know that that's
again that's some of the complexity that
we have today in a dual stack
environment so ENGO yes ipv6 and
increase the pain make them cry make
them painful make them have to work
harder okay so I mentioned five items
that we can use to make it painful I
don't have the time to go into everyone
because the complexity of it and the
time would would basically be until
tomorrow the next day depending on how
much detail you want so I'm just going
to go over five very quickly and I'm
going to tell you why these are
important okay first denied apology
enumeration when somebody does a
traceroute and depending on the
traceroute tool I can only define the
routers but I can check for firewalls I
can check for IPS is low
balancers and other hidden networks
depending on which version of of
traceroute I use so that gives them
context on which networks to go after
what's available on the network in some
cases somebody will have a firewall
which is which they can trace route to
and trace route through so the actions
say oh this is the firewall okay I know
where that is and oh by the way now that
I do a reverse look-up on it I know it's
a Cisco or I know it's a Juniper or I
know it's a whatever box it is so this
basically bleeds so much information
excuse me for information and yes I
think that's a funny picture with the
kid here and the ones hiding in the
stack so how do we implement that in
ipv6 we have a separate set of addresses
it's called a linked scoped address it
means that if I'm on the same segment I
have a unique address you'll see this
when you pull up your computer's you'll
see an fe80
and some additional bits here some
additional characters here hexadecimal
by having this we can take this
interface when we're routing from point
to point and say we're gonna use this is
just an example you wouldn't use one or
two you would use a random number a
large random number I'm gonna I'm gonna
route from here to here this guy would
actually have that address as a default
route this guy would have that addresses
default route now women attacker using
trace route I would see this this
disappears it's at layer two it's now
not from a network standpoint it looks
like it's at layer two so I can't get a
decrement and then I would hit that if I
do the same thing here I can again
manage it so when I do a trace route to
here all I get is that interface
and that interface pretty neat huh
here's the other thing the best choice
of managing these systems would be to be
out of band okay the second choice is we
have another special set of addresses
called a unique local address unique
local address allows you to assign some
random set of bits here and it's part of
the RFC and you can look this up and
they actually educate you on how to use
this so your internal administrators so
I'm walking around a lot
your internal administrators can have
access from internal to each of the
interfaces on an address that they can
still connect to and do traces with okay
and they can apply control here to make
sure that there's no X fill of the EFI
the unique local addresses external okay
so essentially this allows you to hide
Recology and still provide management
for each of these systems which is
pretty cool okay and these are not
global addresses so that's nice
see next fun thing so make sense okay
second thing let me tell you a story
about attackers attackers will choose
passive especially free services first
and then paid for services and some of
these paid for services are extremely
expensive but you have to know they
exist
we identified over 100 so far that we
can classify on v4 that are doing scans
and then selling that information
there's interesting they can do active
but then they have a cut out which means
they have their own VPNs they have their
own proxies they're using tours so they
basically have a cut out network they
can do it for free or there's paid
service that have
low medium and high anonymity okay
pervy four so that's interesting and
then the last thing they'll always
choose is the direct connection that's
we don't want to do that so based on a
study that we performed we were able to
classify these into the type of attacks
and then we were able to figure out
where that knowledge came from
we found that inbound connections the
DNS queries because we were running our
own authority of DNS we're identifying
that some of these people got this
information from the DNS server which is
inbound services HTTP HTTP SSH SQL we
said we had telnet we didn't we said we
had a bunch of other things but we
started seeing them show up over here we
also have outbound
this is an interesting one if you make a
connection at one point last year to NTP
another company that sells these
products would have scanned your
networks because you made a request to
the public NTP creepy huh same thing
with patched servers we're seeing
patched servers actually scan you back
after you make a connection within a few
minutes we also have DNS servers
depending on whose DNS servers pop and
IMAP servers do the same thing we found
we have a whole list of these it would
be little tiny characters also
management servers if you're on the
cloud how do you know if somebody's not
trying to hack the management server
which actually impacts you okay or are
you using SSH when you're calling in or
telnet to manage the server okay it's on
the same addresses these day now the
attacker can get contacts for for free
or for pay we also have search engines
search engines are running things all
the time
are they claimed to be search engines
these guys are providing information out
so I'm an attacker I have this choice
and oh yeah and monitoring how do you
monitor your system do you ping it you
do a query against the system remotely
do you log into the system and have you
send logs I mean those are all things
you have to ask a question
these also provide indication we we put
up a server one place and we kept on
transmitting data and these two except
for regular scanning this other system
wasn't known and we only allowed a
certain type of connection we provided
some false information we found that the
connection between here and here
somebody was listening on a tap and then
started scanning our monitoring system -
okay that's the reality of today so they
can choose to do this the process is I
scan this small address space in six
minutes I can do a DNS lookup for it
which then provides that IP and I can
scan for it or it can take this address
do a reverse lookup get this information
get other information and go through
this loop a couple times to find
everything for a company okay do you
feel safe now so FRA pv6 let's talk
about the address space that large
enough 19 + 19 19 zeros it's a pretty
large address space when you have more
bits to work with in the address space
there's ingeniously fun things you can
do okay to brute force at address when
I'm across the router years or tens of
years or hundreds of years depending on
how you talk - okay that's good there
are several techniques that I teach is
actually several others there's a smart
one which is which is pretty funny
because people put people put web
servers on on an address
and they call it a : 80 and it doesn't
like hide anything right or they call it
dead beef or they call it something that
they can remember easily because they
don't want to put something in the DNS
server that they have access to or their
internal DNS server so that's pretty fun
the other thing is we're seeing brute
force of DNS do you run your own DNS you
know somebody's not doing a DNS brute
force against you you get reports from
your DNS provider authoritative DNS
server provider anybody anybody Bueller
and also reverse DNS your address space
your your the address space that your
internet service provider or cloud
provider or service provider provides
you is that being enumerated okay before
these are all done and everybody ignores
them for v6
these are strong indicators that
somebody's interested in either
something on your network or they're
going after your domain okay
the more interesting part is they have
to scan from here to here in this large
field and I have one nugget of gold in
several different locations let me show
you where they are
okay this confuses the heck out of
people because to get service from these
things I would have to tell you where
they are and again that's what we do
through DNS let's talk about how we
recommend mitigating it for ipv6 has
anybody heard of a privacy address for
ipv6 okay that's an address that will
change the actual address the last 64
bits of the address on a regular basis
and you can schedule that on a regular
basis so is an example say that you're
going out and doing an NTP once an hour
what if you were to change it so that
the address changes
every half-hour that looks like two
addresses are coming to them right so
from a signaling standpoint when you
change the address space you've changed
your address what happens if they come
at you you're no longer at that address
for scanning awesome that's a signal
that somebody's actually looking at your
site
same thing with DNS pop IMAP patching
anything that's actually outbound
service monitoring and performance guess
what
ipv6 allows us to take a single system
and put depending on the operating
system up to a thousand 24 dresses
that's have fun with that
why because the attacker today assumes
that all services are on the same
address so if I have 65 535 ports times
that defined a single active device on
that network how probable is it highly
improbable yeah this actually changes
the game so as an example I can change
the IP address from the llao llao
temporary address exists and throttle
through I can take change a create a
static address just for monitoring so I
can check for up to updates I can have
another one for managing ssh isn't that
what people do is a scan something they
see a web server and they scan for ssh
to see if they can prove for sit haha
now you don't have to ever put SSH on a
high port Wow search engines with DNS we
could direct it to a specific IP address
to see if it truly is the search engine
from Google or whatever interesting albe
out HTTP we have a load balancer read
balancing it to that how about HTTP we
can have it on a different address
how about my SQL Server that we don't
want anybody to enumerate and if we see
somebody in numerating that's a high
indication that something either was
leaked or somebody's after your
organization pretty cool by the way this
works real well
I have servers that have been up for
four years and except for the outbound
initiation on the privacy address which
I get pained all the time just letting
it do patches and things like that I get
no scanning on this okay so from the
attackers view they're looking for the
little gold they're in the wrong place
it's pretty cool so because we have the
non allocation space we can actually
detect once we track that we can detect
when I made that connection outbound and
associate it with the IP address to
figure out who I was communicating with
to identify who's actually scanning me I
mean does that make sense it's it's
really simple we now have new options
because of it and by the way we do see
bots from time to time trying to find
something in here but again that gives
us early indication that there's a bot
running around we have different options
that we can then make we can block the
IP Blake block the cider block for them
we can block the packet based on how the
packets form oh we can entice them into
a honeypot okay so again we have new new
strategies to identify bad actors and
BOTS yeah
yes that's why we're using a special set
of packet identifier x' and cider blocks
and a combination of two were allowing
us to identify specific actors and
that's been really fun
thank you guys you're making it
interesting okay something else
everybody like malware you like it C and
C's aren't they fun okay well so it's
been a while since I moved a specific
well-known client to an ipv6 only
environment that was getting attacked
all the time by different nation states
some of the things that we learned is
that one an ipv6 only ipv4 is an
indication of a C&C or bad application
implemented or a plug-in that's flawed
or or or or actually a web RTC socket
that's miss configured but that's
another issue this is a really strong
indicator very quickly how fast can I
see this well as soon as I see it go to
my black hole my DNS black hole and I
see a DNS and I'm walking at those logs
I can make a determination based on the
IP address of internally oh my god it
doesn't like me anymore
I just so I'll tell you the stories this
way so very quickly if you're you're
monitoring the DNS service from a
logging standpoint if you see a quality
or if you see a a record query or any
type of ipv4 query very quickly can
determine that somebody uses put now
we're on there they're doing C&C they're
trying to do lateral movement or
whatever this is sobbed the whole class
a problem for most of the people trying
to mitigate heavy attack oh and why is
this
what do the attackers in bed they
primarily embed an ipv4 address or they
do a DNS query across ipv4 to find the
C&C that makes sense this has been very
very successful with a bunch of my
clients that we've moved for certain
areas specifically to ipv4 oh by the way
those have actually had p6 we turn we
turn it off what we do is we go through
and we do an assessment against that
that particular air that particular
group of networks we turn all the
services off we identify anything that's
ipv4 or we turn it off we update it
there's several other things we can do
we can do code audits and stuff like
that for it there's some tools for that
that are quick so we can actually have
it fixed if it's an internal if it's an
external we can make recommendations for
updating but once you have that it's a
v6 clean environment any v4 shows
tarnishment
as an example say that they're being
fished there they're pulling ipv6-only
traffic from the mail server so if
they're being fished we're gonna see
only an ipv4 connection okay that's
typical they'll bill turn on the ipv6 oh
by the way we do leave ipv4 on on
purpose just to detect us we don't turn
it off on the interface and the reason
we do that is because people use some of
those ipv4 to ipv6 transition techniques
like Tara dough
some of them will embed that code in
their malware and that also gives us a
strong indication so these are all just
indicator which we've been able to find
very successful and very quickly
detection is a few milliseconds for the
log to process and for it to be shoved
into something to detect it which is
pretty fun pretty cool okay black cat
find the black catch when you're setting
up a new device on the Internet today
how many people set up a new device and
you get hammered and then all of a
sudden you five it's you find that the
system is compromised I'm so tired of
that so what you do is is anybody heard
of DNS or pcs think about it like it
shares information based on the IP
addresses that you allow to share with
so if your internal addresses are a and
the rest of the world is B through Z and
lots of other characters you can create
a firewall then only allows when a
source address within your organization
makes a request this could even be just
the engineering group makes a request
they can only oh they're the only ones
that can do the DNS query okay that's
pretty cool what that does that provides
logging with the sources the destination
and it also gives you indicators that if
you see that any of this information has
been leaked
besides from these sources dresses you
very quickly can identify some kind of
compromise or some kind of leak okay
that's pretty cool so basically you base
it on the source of who's making the dns
query so you can block certain countries
certain organizations things like that
v6 we had the ability to block whole
continents okay pretty cool because
there's a specific network block
assigned to so different continents
so if I have internal but not external
all that stuff we talked about
enumeration discovery gets kicked in
play again this this works really well
again I have servers that have been up
for years for years I have really good
time to see if anybody looks at them
nobody scanning them it's awesome would
you agree that these all call it
increase the cost to the attacker okay
yeah pretty quantifiably so yes this is
this is what pace from my hotel room
this is what we do basically a threat
intelligence indicators compromised
custom IDs and other weird things if
you're interested and then we do a bunch
of services for readiness assessment
testing security testing sock
integration and attack of Defense and
that's all I mentioned about that slide
ok you have any questions did that did
that make sense
I try to make it as simple as possible
to roll the different features like I
said there's lots of other features that
are a little bit more complex require
some coding things like that things like
moving networks for DDoS protection
where we can integrate a signal that all
the addresses on all your servers change
addresses to a different address block
so they're basically ddossing you here
but now you're here
it's a DNS lookup it's a DNS lookup all
the yeah all the bots don't do DNS
lookups they use IP addresses the ones
do DNS they usually pull it back once or
you can actually identify the duck the
bots doing that type of DNS query so but
that's that's one of the fun things so
any questions comments did you get
enough swag okay have a great day