all right well I'm gonna get started
thank you everybody for coming
this talk is on windows management
instrumentation if you're not here for
this talk then I won't be offended if
you get up and go but I hope you are
here for this talk so thanks for coming
so if you're gonna take a picture one
slide actually take a picture of this
one cuz this is actually where the link
to the slides so if you want these
slides for later I'll let you guys take
a picture of that real quick these
slides are gonna be posted with the
video I hope as well so if you find this
on YouTube you'll be able to get to the
slides
I'll keep it up it has a couple videos
in it embedded for the demos but I'll be
trying to do some of those demos live
and I'll be showing some of them
so our agenda for this talk how quick
hello world about WMI using it for evil
and then using it for good
so hello world hi I'm Jamie or root
hopefully with that with a prompt like
that
I am jgeiger I'm on Twitter I tweet
about things follow me if you like
one boat I n as my website I blog about
computer stuff security things to said
men cool tricks I haven't found anywhere
else that I had to dig through I'm an IT
manager for my company and I also do
some security work and development as
well I love teaching and that's why I
love speaking at these kinds of things
there's gonna be only spongebob gifts in
this by the way
so who are you guys so I'm gonna do a
couple raise your hands in this how many
people do we have that a herd of WMI
before know what it is have you have you
used it in an engagement in a red team
engagement okay
have used it in a blue team sense or in
defense okay cool
I need power shell programmers
couple alright so there's gonna be a lot
of PowerShell stuff we're gonna go
through that I'll step through it if you
have questions or I'm talking too fast
please tell me because that's we're all
here to learn if you have a question I
guarantee you someone else in the room
has that question please ask or find me
afterwards if you don't feel comfortable
that's totally fine
what is this WMI thing well stands for
windows management instrumentation like
you saw in the first slide and it's
based on this web-based enterprise
management standard it's a big standard
that was put out by a group for IT
management for data collection which is
awesome so we'll learn more about that
it's based on this common information
model which is an object-oriented model
how many uh you know have any program
object-oriented programmers in here do
any Java programmers or anybody like
that C++ okay so I'll go through what
object-oriented means those of you who
are not programmers in the next couple
slides but will learn about this CI M
thing what is WI basically it's an
interface to interact with objects on
Windows and the really important bullet
at the bottom there is it's available on
every version of Windows since Windows
2000 so it makes it a very powerful tool
to go all the way up from Windows 2000
which you should not be running to
current Windows Server 2016 or Windows
10 and it's remotely accessible which is
really awesome when you learn some of
the things you can do with it you'll
learn that it being remotely accessible
it might not necessarily be the best
thing or it's great if you're on the red
team
so what is this common information model
it's basically a model it's a standard
the document is very long I've read some
of it it's very dry but it breaks down
into defining how to represent anything
within a computer system and so WMI is
like Microsoft's implementation of this
web-based standard in the common
information model we're gonna go through
so the components you have which I'm
going to go through each one of them our
namespaces classes instances properties
methods events and event consumers so I
have a slide for each one of these so
we'll go through them now
a namespace is a collection of classes
and you can have sub namespaces and all
these things I'm gonna show this
visually at the end of the kind of
explanation of this so don't worry about
visualizing it in your head right now
they all exist under this thing called
root so there's the default namespace
which is roots in v2 common information
model too and then we have another one
that we're gonna worry about which is
root subscription so keep that in the
back of your head
like I said these namespaces are
collection of classes and classes are
basically the definitions of some type
of object a perfect example is a user
account on the machine so you'll have a
user account class it'll have properties
which are key value pairs so it'll have
a account name or a user ID or an S ID
and then a value to that the values
actually are put into instances so you
say here I have these properties that I
can fill out I'll create an instance of
this class and that is administrator
with the S ID whatever and their home
directory or whatever kind of attributes
that class has it can have methods which
is also cool so the one that I'm going
to be talking about a lot is win32
process which is a class that represents
every process on the system but I can
query this WMI interface for processes
on the system so as process ID process
name who it's running as and it also has
methods like create or terminate and
create as a great method for attackers
we'll get it out later many of these
properties can be strings integers
how do we talk to this thing it's
basically a database of information that
we have and then we can act on so if you
guys how many sequel how many people
have done sequel before eco queries okay
so for those familiar with it this will
look familiar if you're not it's fairly
easy to follow so you're selecting from
the table or the object to type the
class win32 user account we're disabled
equals false so you're looking for all
of the enabled user accounts this query
is going to return you a bunch of
objects that are all the enabled user
accounts on the system
what can we use to interface with this
well a couple different things there's a
command-line tool called wmic that can
be used I think it exists on Windows
2000 and we can correct me if I'm wrong
on that one but this one is is the most
reliable tool because it's on most
platforms WMI Explorer which is a front
end which I have a demo of the next
slide so you guys can kind of see how
our shell which would be focusing on to
create and access classes later in the
presentation you can access it from the
windows API programming c-sharp C++ C
and then there's tons of other interface
to this like I said this has been around
for so long but it's adapt been adapted
to so many different languages those are
just three that I looked up there's tons
more that actually has
this WMI explorer demo that'll talk
through real quick I'll explain what
what it's actually showing so you don't
have to squint so you're going you go
under the root namespace this is roots
in b2 and you can see there's all of
these different classes so win32 account
when 32s ID win32 process win32 binary
all this stuff so all this is each one
of these is a class that you can query
so current time it has information on
number of fans that are connected this
is an AWS machine so there's no fans
connected directly to this virtual
machine but the user groups this is a
specific example the one that kind of is
more understandable this is user groups
this is the administrator group and you
can see all of the information that this
offers so like I said this says domain
name description s ID so yeah zoomed in
here for you
so you can see that the group is the
name is administrator ASID the local
account or whether it's local account or
not so it has a ton of information so
this is just one of those many things
and you saw how long that list was huge
so there's tons information career from
this
and like I said these are inheritable so
this inherits from the win32 account
group else uh-oh I will skip over that
the rest of that one but like I said
this is what the interface looks like
and this allows you to run through and
query everything you have your
namespaces in this panel you can
enumerate these are your classes and
then you'll actually be able to go and
view instances of classes inside here
and you can check out what properties
they have like I said I don't expect you
guys to be able to squint and see this
but you can see all the properties they
have and what types they are and you can
also see all the methods they have I
believe the demo lays out the process
class so you can see the methods create
and terminate of the process class
okay
and so far what this thing is yes
I know it's just when 32
pretty sure there's historical reasons
for that it's like probably one of their
last worries or I just changing the date
like the database names but yeah that is
true yep
that okay so yes sir
you
you can look at the parent process ID
but on Windows that's not really
reliable that our functions to actually
change the parent process ID look into
that if you haven't it's really cool
you can absolutely based on what the
system gives you for information you can
you can do your best whatever the system
gives you like that's if you open task
manager it'll have the same list it's
the same information so these are this
is like an alternative is a great
alternative API the query stuff with
that's common throughout all windows
bill to Windows 2000
sure about that one you might have to
hook something for that
there are tools to do that and this is
internal sweet so I'm gonna do a quick
overview of the kind of what this how to
interact with this in PowerShell some
one of these things doesn't work on the
most recent version of PowerShell I
tried but just just a heads up for that
so your best friend at for examining
this is gonna be get WMI object you can
specify the namespace which is default
routes in V to the class and then the
filter to get objects these quick -
query and - filter will not work for
some reason it's broken in PowerShell
it's documented online but you can use
PowerShell filters which you'll see
later to filter stuff out you can use a
you can use the list command to list the
classes in a namespace I want to see all
of them in routes in B - and watch it
scrolled all the way down the screen I'm
gonna get the same result as this window
where I have classes here
invoke WMI method so those those methods
we talked about earlier where you can
maybe create or terminate a process you
can do remotely or locally you need
credentials you need administrator
credentials so it's not just wide open
to the world
but that's something you can you can
play with and if you're not familiar
with PowerShell to get help with these
commands you just have help and in the
command so it's really really nice so
set WMI instance you can create new
instances of classes for certain things
one and such we'll talk about creating
classes and actually do some of that
later
remove WMI object be careful with this
one you can actually remove whole
classes and then mess up anything that's
querying it so if you remove the win32
process class it's probably not good
because anything looking for processes
will be that yeah was it
I
I'm not a hundred percent sure about
that and that would be good to look into
I don't I would hope that it wouldn't
delete them off file but
Ranger things have happened on Windows
registered WMI event you can actually
register local events to monitor for in
a local PowerShell console there's a way
to do that persistently what we'll talk
about later and you can actually also
interface with these common information
model objects directly this is how you
would interface with them remotely
you'll have to start up a sim session
you can do these this command get
command - now and sim star and that will
eat you all the commands for sim I'm not
gonna be talking about those those
series of commands we're only going to
need the ones up here
a basic powershell demo
this says get command - noun WMI star
and then you can see get to be my object
invoked of a method you can see that
these commands exist so we're gonna try
to query for a class win32 process and
then we're going to say question mark
property process name - EQ PowerShell
that you see so we're gonna I'm running
PowerShell I know that process is
running so I'm just querying for
PowerShell that exe I'm sorry if this is
hard to see the lighting sort of weird
so you can see that this Scott returned
this object got returned and it has a
process name PowerShell - exe and we can
interact with that object by setting it
to a variable
this becomes a PowerShell object so
we're set it to the process - I we can
just check out the process name it's got
the attribute process name and then we
can also check out all the properties
that has to offer by just querying the
PowerShell object and see all this data
you have from this interface
like I said these slides will be up and
the videos are embedded so you can check
them out look closer
okay so
kind of had an interruption to talk
about PowerShell and interacting with
this thing in PowerShell I haven't
covered the rest of the parts of the
common information model that are
defined that I'm talking about in this
slide set so where it gets really
interesting is you can have events
filters consumers and then binders so
essentially you have these classes that
can fire events there there's win32
process start trace so that'll fire an
event whenever a process starts and so
you can query for that and then do
actions based on that so these filters
you have to write a filter to query for
these things and they're in wql that
language we talked about before that SQL
familiar thing so if we want to know if
we want an event to fire whenever an
instance does command prompt pops up
maybe this is just a contrived example
but you can say select star from win32
process start trace within 5 so every
five seconds check for this thing where
process name equals cmd.exe and then it
will fire in it your event filter will
fire and you can query for that and do
something based on that and we'll talk
about what more can what actions we can
actually do these consumers in a couple
slides
Zoomers basically act on these events
when you bind them together with a
filter to consumer binder and you can
run commands you can send emails you can
write to logs so you can see where that
can kind of a useful
and all of these like I said you can
have subclasses you can have a parent
class and then a child clashers inherits
all that's its attributes and you can
extend it so just an example of that all
event consumers that we're going to talk
about in this presentation are subs or
parent or child's of children of the
event consumer class
go into like actually using an example
of these in a sec here so this is just
the overview and now using WMI for evil
so we're here to attack stuff if you're
here to attack stuff this is great these
methods have actually been used out in
the wild right so apt 29 the Russians
anybody here that dnc hack recently
right
Yeah right this guy gets it so the guys
some of the some of the breaches
actually use this back door so this is
being used out in the wild by real
adversaries so there's this root
subscription namespace that allows you
to create special event consumers so if
you can if you can read these you see
that they might be very useful command
line event consumer allows you to
actually run things on a command line so
execute arbitrary code as a system user
active script event consumer will iater
on VB script or JavaScript also useful a
log file event consumer allows you to
write to a log file when that happens so
useful for blue teamers if you're I'm
using this method NT event log consumer
right to the event log or then SMTP
event consumer which allow you to send
an email you can do mix-and-match these
you can use them together so the apt 29
file lists backdoor essentially what it
did was it registered an event filter
that queried win32 local time and it
said every Monday Tuesday Thursday
Friday and Saturday at 11:30 3 a.m.
local time run this thing and it
essentially would it registered a
command LED event consumer to run this
crazy encoded PowerShell script that
would go and get ducey to exfiltrate
data get commands grab arbitrary
executables whatever the operators
wanted so this will run
on a schedule which is great great for
attackers
interval back doors if you want a
persistent call back that calls back you
know every 15 seconds you can do this
thing called an interval timer
instruction class and then you can
create this and it'll fire a what's
called a timer event every however many
milliseconds you would like
but then in your event filter you say
select star from timer event within 15
where timer ID equals whatever your
timer name is and what that will do is
will allow you to run an event consumer
you bind a consumer to this you
basically have a scheduled task that
runs every X milliseconds you can
execute commands you can use power you
can use the full power of PowerShell and
you can grab things from the internet
and execute them you can upload files
you can I don't know nuke the whole
system if you like every 15 seconds I
guess I'd only if you only do that once
or something like nuking the system you
probably wanna use an absolute timer
instruction which will execute at a
specific point in time only once so fire
at a specific time
that's pretty cool I have a demo of that
it works these were all failing to like
start last night so I'm happy that it
actually works so what's up on the
screen right now it's the command is set
- w mi instance - name space root
subscription so like I said we have to
act in that space to create that
specific consumer we're gonna create
ourselves a class a sub an instance of
the interval timer instruction class
with the parameters timer ID equals I
timer and then the interval between
events is 15 thousand which is 15
seconds 30 15 seconds we're gonna fire
this event
there we go that's the resolution is
better on that now alright so we're
gonna do that it created successfully
the next thing we have to do is register
an event filter and I am copying and
pasting these we have to register an
event filter I know that's hard to see I
apologize which basically does what I
said on the slide here the last slide
which was select star from timer event
within 15 so query every 15 seconds for
this event where the timer ID equals I
timer so this event filter is going to
essentially rabb that event that every
15-second event
so we'll register that real quick and in
the final the the next thing you have to
do is register a consumer so this is the
part you haven't seen yet the consumer
is actually a simple command line script
so you set the command line template for
this command line event consumer to
message star hello world
I am WM I and so I paste that in just to
show you what that's actually gonna do
when this thing runs so it's gonna pop
up a message box on the screen very very
non functional example for somebody
that's gonna be attacking but you're
definitely gonna be able to put whatever
you want there you can write like I said
run PowerShell commands then bind them
together with this filter to consumer
binding that gets created and then
within a couple seconds here we'll see
it pop up it'll be checking for it will
see the message pop up and it's actually
run from an elevated elevated context
and so if you go into the WMI Explorer
you can see that the event consumer was
created as a command line event consumer
with the command message star hello
the event filter was created with our
query
it's still it's still up coming up
closer to consumer binding was created
with the two names of our filter and
consumer and then the interval timer
instruction that fires every 15 seconds
was created as well I have a scripture
above that you can schedule things from
this and you know I know people will
check scheduled tasks I know people will
check their run keys and things like
that and typical persistence locations
but this is something that people don't
really think about how many how many
people in here like run security for
their infrastructures all right do you
guys check for WMI stuff you guys
specifically check in your so
yes
autoruns does catch this yes so if
you're running but that's on a host
BioSpace if you're running a massive a
massive infrastructure you know you're
not gonna notice one host that gets
infected with this most likely it's it's
definitely tough so it's interesting
there's that another evil thing I saw
this when I put this talk together I saw
this tweet and I couldn't help but
include it but Matt graver is a
PowerShell wizard
he's a Windows Wizard he's a good dude
and he's he is there's this tool sim
sweep that's on the good end but you can
actually recover BitLocker keys from WMI
which is terrifying like this is your
drive encryption key like so that's
that's the impact of this right you can
schedule tasks you can query for
information it's great for recon and you
can also recover things like the
BitLocker key password the BitLocker
password which is for those of you who
aren't familiar with BitLocker it's
Drive Encryption or Windows that's huge
like I said you need local admin to get
this information but
remise this happen
so usually WMI for good I think that's
my favorite gift in the entire world I
don't know some stuff I couldn't just
give you guys the evil without the good
hello
you
all the all this stuff has to be created
from a straighter context but it can be
done so remotely if you have port 135
open which is
that's like support that people usually
leave alone on Windows networks
so I've been able to do this you have to
have I think RPC has to be unfiltered
inbound and then also the windows that
manages that automatically in this
you're running some other sort of other
firewall on a Windows network you're
gonna allow those ports because that's
what I eat like the main domain
controller we used to talk via RPC and
point map and stuff
so it's the same kinds of ports that
Active Directory uses so if they
compromised and I'm pretty sure you can
log into this with a domain admin
account if you get it so
or certain groups certain Commission's
all right so I've looked I've spent a
lot of time in this tool just looking
for things that are cool to go through
and and one of the things that I found
was actually Windows Defender has a WMI
interface so you can use this for good
things so it's at the namespace root
Microsoft Security client there's a
malware class so I don't know if you
guys can see you will be able to see
this but security client and then
malware we can actually pull up
just as here
our instances of
oh there we go this is every time it
detects a threat it'll actually register
in WMI so you can query
so these are all and you can tell how
many times I tested this demo because
that's the number of times that tested
the SEM
so you can get notified when malware SEC
did I mean like I said that's kind of a
not so useful example but think about
whenever Windows Defender to text
something which Windows Defender is
actually fairly decent these days better
than like old Windows security
protection used to be which was nothing
if you fire if you fire an event you can
run a quarantine script you can run a
data collection script they think of the
possibilities there was like as soon as
when you defend Windows Defender catches
something you can get the state system
state they can't so you have it at that
that snapshot at that state of time
that's pretty neat so you can get
notified you can use that same event
filter consumer trick
actually query for this and then do
something based on it
you can so you can you can do whatever
you like whatever a PowerShell script
can do or whatever a VB script can do
you can fire in response to this so
collect data or whatever so essentially
what this is doing is I wish the
resolution would up
HD there we go alright so essentially
here we're creating its how can possible
to see I'll read it off to you so
essentially we're creating a an event
filter that queries the root Microsoft
security client namespace and says
alright whenever an instance creation
event fire select star from instance
creation event which is an event that
fires whenever an instance of any class
in that namespace is created and the
target instance is a malware is the
class type malware we're gonna fire
we're gonna we're gonna meet this filter
so we'll register it under the root
subscription namespace
we'll register a consumer for this which
in this example like I said we're just
going to do something simple which we're
going to pop up a little message that
says hey you have malware at this
directory and it's this user launched it
and the severe area is this the Windows
Defender severity ID is blank
I'll register that as a command line
event consumer like we did before with
the malicious part
and then finally you bind them both
together with a filter to consumer
binding that was created successfully
as an attacker will go and will unzip
mini cats so we know that's going to get
caught that's Windows defenders in that
as that it's a tool to dump passwords
out of memory and other things
credentials out of memory so we can see
that Windows Defender did find it
and then in a couple seconds here there
will be a notification that will run
showing that our filter worked you can
see pops up a message that says malware
@c users and ministers desktop me me
cats win32 me me dirt sis which is the
driver for mini cats that uses don't
memory and then from administrator
severity for you can take the
information from that class and feed it
into whatever scripts you're running on
the command line in response to this you
can say you know hey we have this
malware this information collection
script that we're supposed to run when
the system detects malware perfect feed
the information to it tell it where the
malware is and then you can you know set
fire off an alert to you can also do
event event logs to so you can fire up
an alert I'm sure collecting central
logs and monitoring you can fire that
off as well I'm fairly certain that
called Windows Defender already writes
in an event log but just to the kind of
possibilities of what you can do you can
send an email as well at the description
you know exactly which user is trying to
infect your machines
when Windows Defender catches it and
anybody can develop and make interfaces
for WMI so another nd I'm not sure which
if there are any antivirus providers
that are doing this but they can provide
an interface to this if they would like
you can see go through and it's any WMI
explorer you can see you know all the
information the path and all all the
stuff that gives you category ID gives
you the threat ID it gives you the
threat name the domain it was on the
time it was executed you know the action
that was taken against it
it gives you all this information that
you can use and siphon off somewhere
else
there's a tool called sim sweep
which essentially it's an open-source
PowerShell project that was mentioned
earlier to grab the BitLocker keys but
if you're a blue team or if you have
running an environment you have this
open why why would you not use it for a
fur collection on your host to see if
anything's wrong there's a wealth of
information there you can go and like I
said you can correct collect this stuff
remotely so sim suite will allow you is
it's designed to you be used at a large
scale enterprise in a large scale
enterprise with many many Windows
machines so you can use this to collect
forensics data if you know something's
wrong you can use this to just generally
query stuff if you're curious to collect
it's it's on github contribute if you
can you know PowerShell it's a great
tool for threat hunting Incident
Response because you know gathering that
much information off hundreds and
hundreds of machines is a tough task but
if you can do it all remotely with a
click of button
how do you find and stop this register a
consumer filter to tell you if there are
any new consumers created so if someone
malicious is trying to persist using
this method you can use that instance
creation event thing we did before with
the malware class you can say hey if
anybody registers one of these tell me
about it or delete it probably tell you
about it so you know where the there's a
leak in your infrastructure or if
somebody's trying to do something nasty
just delete them all and make sure there
are none there there are legitimate uses
for this I will tell you that the Amazon
machine that I spun up for this demo for
the the recorded demos for this they all
have at least one registered event
consumer filter and binder so this is a
real thing that people use sometimes
make sure you're not deleting anything
important off your system I don't
remember what it was for but it was
something
I have the command in the slide show
notes I forget what it is I didn't feel
like pasting it in here because it's
kind of like if you're curious go check
out the slides but there is a way to
turn on verbose login for this it's off
by default which house getting to so the
logging the verbose logging I think the
the log file that I after doing all the
demos I looked at the log file and it
was like 20 lines long didn't have a
single command that I ran in it you'll
see the access for it especially if you
run it remotely you'll see successful
login ID 46 24 which is the successful
login ID for Windows event logs but type
3 network I'm pretty sure other things
are gonna fire that but for
administrator accounts that shouldn't be
firing all that often unless you're
doing a lot of remote activity normally
or standard infrastructure I don't think
that's
always audit your admin accounts I don't
have that's something that's huge I mean
you're normally your your admins should
be performing I've been tasks with their
admin account and then have a separate
account to check their email I know I
like below it recently I think someone
was running one as an admin and checking
their email like they got popped that
happens so make sure you audit your
inmate accounts who has access I know
your CEO wants domain admin but receipt
partly doesn't need domain admin
yeah so checking for stuff with
sysinternals tools that autoruns will
catch this and if if you try to run
PowerShell you explicitly try to run
PowerShell just PowerShell and then of
commands in Auto runs will come up red
which is a big big alert so definitely
check that out
Auto runs is a great tool finds things
that run automatically on your system or
pretty much any place registry
directories WMI all that stuff
I'm a bit under but that's okay regular
references check out this presentation
itself I can go back to the first slide
to give you the link to it if you'd like
to grab it the bitly link to it if you
want to grab that and check out the
slides they're open to view all the
demos are on there
with the direct link and also embedded
they said they weren't working at all
last night embedded so I'm some for some
reason things started working better
when I gave my presentation definitely
check out all these resources this is
how I learned about this these were
great great helps the apt 29 stuff has
there's a great write-up on that I I did
this I skip I practice scheduling these
things in C++ there's a way to do that
and some sample code on my on my blog 1
by n if you want to go there and then
the monitor malware script which is on
github it's on the gist so you can grab
it and in the sims sweep repository
check that out grab it
I said I'm a bit under but that's okay I
recorded my demos less when I gave this
I did these the demos all live but I was
paranoid this time so show me
so questions from anybody
pretty good hello
what
I think I'm not 100% sure which version
the WMI commands were added in I want to
say anything beyond PowerShell 3 you're
perfectly safe but that's the case for
most stuff I'd have to look into that
more closely when in doubt you can use
wmic and wmic will allow you to do all
the same things and it's on it should be
on everything since 2000 Windows 2000 so
our shells nice it allows you to work
with objects very nicely but it's
definitely uh you can do it with wmic or
in c++ with the windows api
that's a that's a good point so I had my
demos have like select blank within our
select star from blank within 5 within
15 don't do that if you're gonna run
this if you're gonna run these normally
do them don't do them anything under 30
because that's querying this thing over
and over and over again that's
definitely not something you want to do
on a regular regular basis
and he said there's some some versions
that will cause a few spikes just
regardless right
particular okay Oh watch out for that
test this if you're gonna deploy it
that's with anything get a question and
do your question
you
I don't I don't think
wmic has that capability I think it just
specified computer name and then you can
specify user name and password and allow
you to execute stuff
I know PowerShell will allow you to do
it but I'm almost 100% sure that you can
do it with wmic
so as I covered before I think I skipped
over that part actually you can run this
via normal PowerShell remoting either
the non-encrypted or the encrypted
version you can also run it over port
135 I have a challenge that I'm running
for my company that one of the problems
you literally have to connect to it's
just for 135 open and then RPC that's
the only port open and you can
compromise the host completely
regal
with credit secret but that is somewhere
else
hopefully nobody that's on that
challenge what yeah okay anyone else
have you questions
yes I can do that yeah please
you're gonna take a picture one slide is
to be the one
because this has the link we'll try to
put the link up on the YouTube video as
well
the slides
check that out follow me on Twitter
you
I'm not sure if there's a way to do
specific like disabling specific methods
if you disable WMI as a whole your
system will not function so I think it's
kind of an all-or-none kind of thing if
you have that admin access you have
access to that port like kind of game
over if somebody wants to use it and you
don't have a good egress filtering
but if you someone has your admin
password you've got bigger issues than
that one host I think
alright anybody else
I think you get so much for coming I
really appreciate it hopefully it was
informative for you and you can use it
in some way in your jobs and tell people
about it
Thanks
[Applause]