yeah everyone's so excited and over on
the other side of the room hi all right
there we go make sure you make it really
awkward when people walk in the door
just everyone stare right at them
because it's really awkward to walk in
during the talk in the front of a room
so let's make it extra awkward for
anyone else that walks in I'll stop and
look with you I gave a talk a few years
ago where I mean I normally get kind of
weird in the middle and people get up
and leave and I manage to Rivet most
people's attention for a really long
time about 40 minutes in some do got up
and left and I call them out on it it's
like 2,000 people there when I called
the guy out and it turned around it was
a client of mine I was like oh hey bad
time to be an asshole like this that's
cool so appreciate y'all joining me on a
talk that abstence ibly doesn't have a
lot to do with security but I think
it'll be interesting and I'll get you to
a place where we talk about security
first for those that don't know me I
talked I started all my talks exactly
the same way telling you not to believe
anything that I'm about to tell you I am
an autodidact Didac dieback I had that
and I saw somebody called a lot of
people on Twitter call themselves this I
didn't know what I meant
I eventually wouldn't looked it up and
then I put it on some slides and I
spelled it wrong for like a good six
months so it was an autodidact which is
not a word and I felt so cool because
like I know what other Didac means but I
didn't know how to spell it which really
was altima tyranny of being a
self-taught person was not having
knowing how to spell self-taught so I
I'm self-taught in the sense that I went
to school for a while I spent four years
going to school in Fairbanks Alaska I
dropped out never graduated really
wasn't even close to graduating pulled
cable and never declared a major I was
literally just going to school and
around for four years it was a
lot of fun I met my wife there so it
worked out but everything else was kind
of a cluster so ended up working pulling
cable and coal mines and doing work
above the Arctic Circle ended up running
system and network operations for the
largest isp and alaska eventually got
into security did a lot of software
security work for private industry and
apps tech space and work for Segel for a
while ended up at Booz Allen ran some
Intel labs for them around Wireless and
high assurance
work started my own shop we did a lot of
DARPA and IR / research as well as
private sector work during that time I
hacked planes I hacked trains I hacked
cars we did work for the largest hedge
funds in the world I work for state and
local had a lot of opportunity to do a
lot of things and I think I've learned a
lot along the way and I think I've
learned things incorrectly along the way
as well so when I speak it's kind of
story time with Bruce I'm giving you my
view of the world you're welcome to
disagree with me if you don't believe
what I'm telling you raise your hand the
one thing we've learned from Xiuquan and
arming people with squishy foam rubber
balls to throw at us is when one person
throws the ball a bunch of people will
throw balls right because you always had
that thing like I can't be the only one
thinking this is and it turns
out you're not right like the entire
room is agreeing with you but no one's
saying it so if you disagree with what
I'm saying today please throw whatever
is convenient at you what okay all right
if anyone here fly-fish okay call me out
I'm really a terrible fly fisherman I'm
also self-taught in that space as well
I've been doing it for much less time
I've been doing security for 20 years
and fly fishing for like four so yeah
yes well there's kind of I mean there's
the it's more around conservation than
fly-fishing but there's a lot of there's
there's people like your grandfather
taught you how to fly fish I broke my
grandfather's fly rod after he died
because I didn't know how to use it so
that's a very sad story as I tried to
teach myself fly-fishing I broke my
grandfather's hand-built bamboo rod
which in hindsight was really bad and no
one should have let me get away with it
so it was like cathartic it never told
anyone about that congratulations it's
like you know therapy with Bruce time
lookout me thinking about doing this
talk is last year I I've had a lot of
really ridiculous opportunities given my
background people taking chances with me
that they probably shouldn't have
last year I served as a senior technical
advisor for the Presidential Commission
on cybersecurity and I traveled around
the country with the Commission
interviewing public and private sector
organizations organizing all the
Commission events talking with the
commissioners and their staff and
Congress critters and people from the
White House and whatever and I learned a
ton through the process it was
fascinating but I was traveling a lot
like between being a commercial
consultant and then a CTO of a publicly
traded company at the time and being the
adviser of the presidential commission I
was on the road all the time in order to
stay sane I used to bring a bike with me
when I traveled and I would like take a
bike and go bike around because you get
to see the community you get out of the
hotel you get out of that rut of like
I'm in a Hampton but I don't know what
Hampton like I don't know what time zone
right so with my fly gear it was an
excuse to get out into the wilderness
right it was because biking in places
like Dallas like I just stay in a hotel
in downtown Dallas and think I like to
go for a bike ride it's like I'd like to
go get run over by a car they're
functionally equivalent it's the same
concept so I'm like they've never seen a
cyclist in Dallas before I was the first
one there was like a referendum to allow
no more cyclists they're like no we
can't have any more so instead I went
out and I go fly-fishing and I find
local bodies of water and sometimes once
it was in Dayton on Memorial Day weekend
and it turns out every body of water is
filled with drunk Ohioans and they're
just tubing and the fish do not eat when
there's drunk Ohioans in the waters that
sucked but other times it was in
Minnesota I get to go fly-fishing and
then a soda in Wisconsin it would be
great
and as I'm standing there not catching
fish and thinking is there a tie between
what I'm doing here and my day job doing
security and extensively the answer was
no and so I pushed a rock uphill and I
eventually came up with this talk so
we're gonna try this out and see see how
it works out
so fly-fishing in a nutshell is actually
a pitched battle I was just describing
this to someone if you're doing like
normal Lake fishing you're going after
like a bass or something something far
away that you can't see you're trolling
in the ocean you don't see the fish
right you were just like real in the den
waiting is anything there I have no idea
with trout fishing you'll be like
there's a trout your odds of catching
you're almost zero right that fish is
smarter than you it's basically like
you buddy like I was fishing in
like a legendary trout stream in Arizona
I'm standing from like here to the
middle of a table away from a whole
school of brown trout all about yay big
I spent an hour nope nope you don't know
you don't eat that one okay change it
out nope not that nope give him a break
try it again you when I walked away
like I just sat there and had this fight
it was one-sided
right like I was having a battle and
they were just like hanging out like hey
what's up buddy so this is fly-fishing
in a nutshell is you have a human who's
doing
I'm standing in cold water it's usually
actually quite relaxing I had a client
where they their headquarters were on a
protected trout stream and the morning I
would get dressed for work I would drive
to client site I got out of the car I
put on my waders grab my gear walk into
the stream right like in front of where
I was working fish for two hours get out
take all my wet stuff off throw it in
the trunk of my car going and work at
the end of the day get dressed again and
fish until I got hungry and go go it was
great well I was best client ever like
as far as I was concerned no one else
did that by the way like when you're
working for a hedge fund and you come
walk it out like stripping off all your
waders and all the people working the
hedge fund or like who's this guy
trespassing and I pulled my badge out
there like that's weird you know we
should investigate the contractors
better so what's the secret to
fly-fishing anyone could put a hook in
the water I proved that empirically with
those brown trout that day there's
what's the secret to that there's
there's an awful lot of opinions on how
to catch trout right and I mean trout
very specifically like fly-fishing is
kind of a an asshole sport in the sense
that almost exclusively we're fishing
for trout you can fish for all kinds of
things you can catch other fish but for
the most part like trout's the thing
that you're going after this is a
picture of Heidi having caught her first
trout in Estes Park at Wright middle of
downtown Estes Park and I had nothing to
do with our guide that game was that day
was great walked her through all the
mechanics of how to fish and everything
if I had done it
we'd probably not be talking to each
other right now so it worked out very
well she caught her first fish but how
did she do it so there's lots of parts
to fishing and one of the things that
people focus on when they think of
fly-fishing is the cast right like
there's this process that you thinking
of getting the line out there it'll
looks beautiful you know we were talking
earlier like what's the difference
between fishing with a lure and
fly-fishing well a fly-fishing you're
casting the line right with the lure
you're casting the lure you've got this
monofilament this heavy thing at the end
and you throw it out there and it goes
out if you're fly-fishing it's actually
the weight of the line that you use in
to your advantage to get the fly to
where you want it to be and that's why
you have this weird mechanic of when
you're casting arms are going everywhere
as it turns out when you start doing
this you're just overwhelmed right it's
for like anyone who's tried to learn how
to golf like there's a million things
at once and the whole time the ball is
just there like yeah you know every arms
are going everywhere knees are bent back
straight bend that elbow not the other
one and fly-fish casting is the same
same concept it's very easy to wave your
hand next to your head usually you just
kind of make a knot this was from a
guy's website that teaches fly casting
as part of his guide tours this is the
single hand rod cast I teach are
outlined below these are all the
different things he teaches which
apparently is not a comprehensive list
which is a little frightening right
there there's casting that isn't that
like the double and Annie's pretzel not
one you know I don't really I don't know
this is me and one of my sons when I got
back into fly-fishing after I broke my
grandfather's rod I took a 35-year
hiatus and my family was kind enough a
few years ago I biked cross-country and
they followed me and make sure I didn't
die so Heidi drove our RV and our three
sons across the u.s. very slowly at 60
mile increments while I didn't die
biking across the country and we got to
Colorado and once you get out of the
wasteland at is Kansas I'm no offense to
anyone from Kansas but you're just a big
ramp that goes to Colorado right like
you gain 1500 foot of elevation in a
smooth plane that ends in Pueblo so they
have a cool Space Museum and there's
like a big underground salt mine and
corn you know I this is fascinating
industrial industrial farming is
fascinating especially if you've like
ridden through a state that does nothing
but industrial farming and you think to
yourself how does corn grow how many
ears of corn are on one corn stalk one
one Eirik or do you think it's like the
pilgrim is just like laden with corn no
and it's all exactly at this height if
you go past an industrial corn farm
every year according is right here and
there's only one because that's what the
machine is designed to do
pop-pop-pop-pop isn't the most efficient
way to get corn nope but it's the
cheapest that's how we grow corn so
Kansas is passing in this sense like we
do dry passed a Chicken McNugget factory
that is a Purdue slaughterhouse for
chickens you have to explain to your
kids like huh what's in there you're
like that's where they grow chicken
nuggets you learn a lot about industrial
farming but we get to Colorado and
they'd like oh there's
trees in the wilderness and it's very
engaging so I decided like we're gonna
start fly-fishing so we're in this town
and and we buy a couple fly outfits and
I act like I know what I'm doing and a
business like watching YouTube videos
I'm like how to fly-fish and so we go to
the stream and within a few minutes I've
caught a 40-foot pine I'm measuring it
to see if it's the length if I can keep
it my son is a little skeptical the
situation is you can you can see I I've
taught myself almost exclusively through
this is not not kidding YouTube videos
right watching YouTube videos reading
some books that's how I learned how to
fly cast and it's the few guides I've
met with then if they correct the
idiotic things that I'm doing it helped
me kind of kind of adjust you can be
mentored by someone it helps a lot when
you're starting right it helps a lot to
be with someone that knows what they're
doing to prevent you from building up
bad habits like any other sport like any
other you know profession if you build
that habits early you're gonna carry
those bad habits for the rest of your
life right so is I'm busy watching
YouTube and focusing I like my forearm
is doing or not paying attention to my
wrist a building bad habits with my
wrists and therefore my cast is going to
hell and it takes some like 22-year old
guy from Colorado to correct me so you
can learn it off the internet but it's
not like the ideal way to learn it what
else yeah one of the the styles I don't
know like this guy I think he's trolling
by the middle of this right like the
curving line it you know bending around
corners like I'll come on like this
isn't well so roll cast is actually when
you think of fly casting you think of
this big movement where the fly goes
really far behind you and comes back out
if you're an environment like this where
you've got a bunch of brush behind you
you can't bring your rod tip back so
rule cast is a way to basically do it
all in front of you so you start the
line coming up toward you and then you
roll it back out so the jump roll must
involve some extra like flourish in
there for some god-awful reason but a
roll cast keeps everything in front of
you so you're not getting tied up with
the trees behind you
so this this concept of presentation of
the fly right so you say no no the cast
is okay it's really how you present it
to the fish right this is another secret
you got to worry about so you can think
about
fish will hide behind barriers right cuz
there are like birds and that want
to eat them so they're like kind of was
my hawk by the way I'd be practicing
that it was that that was good yeah okay
good feedback thank you I appreciate
that so if you win oh it's these really
small talks that I like if I did this in
front of a big audience that would've
landed but that really that was good
when you land a fly here in some slow
water what you really were trying to do
with the fly is it get it to imitate
what it would do in real life and for
the most part any of the things that
you're casting in water are just getting
taken by the water downstream right you
think of flies as things that live on
top of the water and scoot around very
little of what you're presenting to
official is on top of the water it's
actually just under the surface and
you're trying to get it to move in a
natural way as if the current we're
dragging it along because unlike bass
which are pretty stupid they'll eat
anything that looks like it might be
food trout the minute it doesn't look
natural to then they give up they're
like oh that's not real I'm not going to
eat that thing so in this case the fly
lands here but they have all this line
resting in water that's moving faster
and so that line starts to go downstream
and it drags that fly down with it at an
artificially fast speed right so in
order to correct that what we do is calm
ending the line so you tend to take the
line and you loop the line that's closer
to you up into the fast-moving water and
let it come down and let it come down
let it come down
well that fly which is on a big piece of
monofilament so it's not affected by you
doing all this will slowly work its
way down the current to try to trick
that fish so that's called the
presentation right and so the
presentation is important because
sometimes you'll be on a you know on a
curb sometimes you're going downstream
sometimes you're going upstream a lot of
this is because you're in a freaking
river right and it was like rocks and
trees and you can't necessarily control
the best place to catch like the best
place for you to cast might be filled
with a giant down oak tree and you can't
stand there so you got to be downstream
or upstream so understanding how to
present the fly effectively to the fish
that you're trying to catch is very
important okay some of the people say no
it's actually the fly itself right the
fly is the most important thing there's
all kinds of different flies what we did
today about four or five people in this
room came in tied fly
yeah she's got her fly so we tied some
flies today and what we tied were called
attractors these are flies that aren't
designed to look like anything they're
just designed to be kind of exciting you
know they're like the club scene of
flies there's some spoons and the bass
and the pan fish and the kind of more
predatory things that will just
basically eat anything or like yeah
that's cool but trout and other fish
that are can be more selective and
typically live in shallower water are
going to go there they need something
that looks more like what they're trying
to eat what happens in a fly's life
cycle most aquatic flies when we go in
for trout were going for gun to
basically imitate three three things a
caddisfly may flyers don't fly the vast
majority of things that trout eat are
those three three different types of
flies and those three flies go through
the same three stages of life there's a
nymph stage which is like a larval stage
living under a rock just kind of
chilling down low in the water sometimes
they break loose and they tumble through
the water until they land on another
rock so what you're doing with these
nymphs is just kind of imitating this
little thing that's broken loose from
iraq and this tumbling around anna
merger is that after it's transformed
from its larval stage into an insect it
comes up off the bottom and it'll slowly
rise to the surface of the water sit
just below the surface of the water and
it's trying sky like a wing sac and its
back and it's trying to get its wings
out of its wing sac break the surface
tension and eventually fly away right
and so this is just fresh meat for a
trout because it's a totally defenseless
big juicy bug it's got all the nutrients
of a fly that's already made it but it
can't fly yet so when these things are
you know in the water they'll eat them
and a dry fly is what you would think of
it's like the fly that sits on top of
the water we're thinking of like
conventional kind of kind of fly fishing
and so tying the flies getting the flies
to imitate flies is it's a it's a
lifetime skill actually this weekend at
Sunday I'm going up to the fly Tyne
symposium in Lancaster Pennsylvania
anyone else planning on going even my
family I think it's decided actually no
we're not gonna go this doesn't sound
like an hour long seminar watching
someone tie a fly and then go to another
hour-long seminar like somebody else tie
a fly
go yourself so
this is actually even if you're not a
fly for sure person you're not into this
the history fly-fishing in 50 flies is a
very interesting book that goes through
from back in in Western Europe when
people started the sport and it kind of
advancing through materials through the
different types of fish that they were
catching the different technologies they
had if you want to learn about fly
fishing it's actually I think it's
fascinating and not just because I'm
into the sport it's actually a kind of a
neat deconstruction of sport based
around the Flies it does have lots of
pictures it's my hand draw and lots of
hand-drawn pictures it's really I love
that I love that book okay so then
you're like no no flies whatever you can
buy the flies present them correctly
don't have to be perfect and iatest like
you do not have to have a perfect
looking fly they can be pretty raggedy
but he's presented correctly maybe it's
not it but you're in the wilderness
there's gear right so here's me and my
sons having just purchased this fly rod
you all know there's like line
everywhere like we have no idea what
we're doing with a in this kit when you
go fly-fishing and you're off in the
woods somewhere there's a non-trivial
amount of crap that you need to go
fly-fishing right you clearly need the
rod and the reel but then you need
waders right because I'm gonna stand in
the water and if the water is below like
50 degrees or 60 even 60 degrees you're
gonna be freezing your ass off of you're
in there in a pair of sandals and shorts
right so you need waders to stay dry
it's slippery and you need to be able to
stand on these rocks so like the
Birkenstocks wherever you were wearing
as a hippie they weren't working out so
you need these big boots and sometimes
they have like tungsten cleats in the
bottom to help you hold onto the rocks
and that kind of thing and then you need
a net on the off chance that you catch
something you need a net right like I
have a nice gently used net if anybody
wants it like it sits on my back and
every once in a while I put it in my car
and then put it back on the back and
that's about always you can get really
expensive all this stuff can get
exotically expensive I've seen net sort
of like $700 nets right because these
are all I can made hand bent exotic
woods and whatever clearly designed for
the fisherman who doesn't cut right
like if you're if your net is like a
piece of art to you it's because you're
not using it as far as I'm concerned so
I have a $700 net I really I don't I
don't know just
sorry clear
that was just for the theatrics of the
situation yeah sorry yeah actually it
tells you is he kidding like I'm not
really I think we're good yeah the one
you know yeah have a storage unit full
of other stuff is you need you need a
vest because again you're carrying all
this crap you got a whole bunch of
different you know cuz you have no idea
what the fish are gonna eat so you
brought every fly you own because you
have no idea what's about to happen and
you'll be damned if you're gonna miss
out so you have like all kinds of flies
tucked in there you've got nippers these
are basically really expensive
fingernail clippers like you can spend
these are like 40 dollar nippers you can
spell like $300 on nippers it's just a
piece of machine frickin titanium or
something so I don't know these bespoke
nippers just for you I don't know they
have a little thing to kind of like ream
out the hole and the in the hook cuz a
lot of times you get glue and crap in
there you get tip it this is extra line
so if you need to tie more leader on and
of course you're tying you maybe have a
couple rods a couple reels they all
different weight line so you carry a lot
of different weights of tip it you gotta
carry a bunch of frickin forceps again
on the off chance you catch a damn fish
and then it swallows the hook you got to
get the hook out from like way inside
its anus apparently because they will
swallow it like all the way through
their body right like well then you take
your like oh it's it's into another fish
like oh my god like I don't understand
you have high float something that will
make the dry fly actually float if you
tied it correctly it floats in its own
I don't tie it correctly so you have to
give it a little Viagra to get it to sit
on top of the water then you have the
boxes to keep all your flies in small
large waterproof floaty floaty
everything should float right because
you're gonna drop this at least once
right and be chasing after it running
downstream scaring the hell out of every
fish around you right that's also a
predicate that you've scared everything
around you so they don't come got
another bag because your vest doesn't
hold all the that you needed in the
first place and then you've got to have
the Hat so you're not a poser okay so
like this is the gear like that's the
baseline you're like what do I need to
go fly-fishing it's like I don't know a
grand worth of crap just to get started
to go stand in the water not catch
anything so if you want to not catch
fish you just give me $1000 we'll call
it even
right like you
have to you don't have to do anything
else all right so that's the gear people
say the gear is important the Gary is
important but like any you know racecar
there's only as good as a pilot you
still need the humans involved so then
the next thing the human has to do is
read the water right so this is out of
Estes Park when how do you and I were up
there fishing the fish are not uniformly
distribute it's not like raisin bread
right like the water doesn't just have
like a reasonable amount of fish
everywhere the fish are all concentrated
in the coastlines are all the liberal
fish and then the more right-wing fish
are kind of in the center of the water
so why I like that way that was pretty
good oh yes oh yeah got it got oh yeah
so if we look at this section of water
like the first thing that you do when
you get to a body of water is first kind
of assess like what am i dealing with
like is this even a reasonable spot to
fish and so yeah we like on this side
there's a road so this is actually all
I've been flooded out what four years
ago in the big Colorado floods and
they've reconstructed all this but
they've redone a lot of the banks with
these huge boulders to prevent erosion
because there's a road up here I didn't
want to have to deal with it again so
these are gonna climb down through all
this crap on this side is those all
brush right so it's really a pain in the
ass to cast because you have to like you
have to be doing the roll cast and
everything else so we actually spent
most of our time fishing over on this
side you got this is fast water that was
coming down off of a fall you got a pool
over here open water fish don't like
open water it's warm trout don't like
warm water they want it cold I mean they
want pretty damn chilly in Maryland as
an example everywhere except for Garrett
County which is all the way in Western
Maryland they mean they stocked trout
all over the state and every River
except for the rivers in Garrett County
all the trout by July are even usually
June are dead they expect a hundred
percent fish mortality for the trout
that they stock in Maryland that aren't
in Garrett County because lar gets too
hot 70 degree water trout are dead
they don't live so they Maryland's
stocking trout in streams that is not
natural for them to be in just for
fishermen to catch them so I I mean I
still fish the Patapsco and some of the
other local rivers but doesn't really
feel right like I'm like yeah these fish
don't even want to be here and they're
gonna die if a freaking hawk doesn't get
him at some point so
so the war like you know on a cold day
they like to warn the Sun and I've got a
warm day they'll stay away from it
plus they're out in the middle get
caught by predators so in general
they're not going to be in shallow water
right in the middle of an open space and
then this all starts again the falls are
something to consider because what will
happen is the Falls where that where the
water's coming down makes this very
turbulent motion and you get a lot of
food churned up so any kind of nymph or
anything that was attached to rocking it
area has relatively short lifespans
they'll get turned over so at the tail
end of the Falls as things fall on out
of the water and go to the bottom you'll
often find trout they're eaten there so
you gotta get to a place read the water
okay what else this is a big one
matching the hatch so once you get an
idea at the read of the area you'll
actually walk into the water pick up a
rock and you'll look at it and what
you're looking for are the insects that
are living on the bottom of the rock all
the larval states of all these different
types of flies and things that are
native to that area how big are they how
much sure are they are they hatching
right now what colors are they and you
try to find a fly the pattern that you
have that matches something that you
find on that rock if you go in and at 9
o'clock in the morning start throwing in
some kind of caddisfly emergere right
this thing that's hatched and is coming
up to the surface trots probably not
gonna eat it because the they those will
emerge in later afternoon like 2 3 4
o'clock as the water gets warmer and
there's more sunlight so if I take a
caddis fly merger and cast it in the
water at 9:00 a.m. I probably won't
catch anything I come into the same spot
4 o'clock the afternoon I'd be hauling
out trout as fast as I can hook them
right and so in the morning I'm gonna be
looking for more you know things that
more apt to be in the water than imps
the scuds the worms things like that
that the fish won't find unnatural for
that that kind of day so the idea of
matching the hatch is like super
important and then there's like blind
ass luck so sometimes you're at the
right place the right time this is me
drinking champagne while fishing as one
would do with a big asshole sport like
this not catching any fish and that's
this park I'm it was a snowy March day
or April day in Estes Park
I catch a thing so noise and Heidi
handed me champagne and I'm still to
this day a little confused as to why but
it was nice it was good okay so then the
big question right as this guy walks out
the room he says what the hell does this
have to do with security he's like I
don't I don't get it like a straight man
there nailed it for me that was good I
was perfect so what does this have to do
with security well on the face of it
phishing is complicated I just went
through like there's a whole shitload of
stuff that has to happen in order to
catch a fish it's an industry filled
with hobbyists and pros filled with
people who are self-taught if you're
mentored early on it stops you from
making mistakes your gear matters but we
still matter more it's dangerous you're
not paying attention it's predominantly
white and male like that's the reality
of fly-fishing like it's a white male
sport and it's a lot of fun as it turns
out that's the same thing information
security has the same traits as
fly-fishing right all these things still
hold true so let's kind of kind of walk
through that information security is
complicated right like no right
this is this is a big no done 2017 the
thing on the left right is the the nice
framework so NIST has put together the
nice framework in the last few years
they've given it a little more structure
and made it a little more reachable I
mean there's a whole document now around
the the framework and how they broken
down and effectively it's the big book
of every cybersecurity related job ever
at any point in history of mankind and
it's a big tree because NIST will make
things that look like trees because they
want the hierarchy in the structure at
the top level the tree all jobs that we
would do in this industry fall into one
of these buckets and then they split and
they split and they split until there's
hundreds of different jobs with hundreds
of different levels of skill associated
with it then this defined as every
cybersecurity job ever in the history of
mankind right you go back 20 years ago
there weren't that many types of jobs
right like you had some network security
admins you had somebody that did risk
management we didn't really understand
cyber risk all that well you had some
penetration testing type people maybe
for lucky a couple people around
investigations but we didn't
broken into all that much unless you
were the government like he most people
didn't know that they were hacked
pre-google arora most organizations
didn't believe that they were the
victims of being hacked right google
aurora was like the big watershed event
like hey we got owned another people
like oh we got owned too and we've now
been living in this age of breaches
because people have better eyes on the
system and they're doing a better job of
analyzing the data in front of them so
you know when you think about again the
number of books that i showed earlier
with about four thousand books on
fly-fishing computer securities
twenty-four thousand books that's just
an arbitrary metric and arbitrary search
term but it got that actually got more
than cyber security which i thought was
good right computer security got 24,000
cyber security only got like 12,000 it
was like haha hasn't totally taken us
all over yet just closed so while we're
talking about over the cyber scape from
from momentum so momentum like is a
track investments and M&A material in
our industry and the cybersecurity
industry and they break broken apart the
the landscape of everything that has to
do with cybersecurity into a bunch of
buckets and then categorize every
company that they can find that's active
in this space into those buckets right
so we talk about the complexity of the
industry we have things like excuse me
we have let's say network security
endpoint security we have application
security there's messaging security web
security managed security this is
actually at some point my locum
company's logo being there we have risk
and compliance industrial fraud security
operations Incident Response
transactions security specialized right
now threat intelligence data security
identity access management cloud and
mobile security right that's uh that's
it right and the every little dot here's
like a pixel because this is so small
like they've had to jam all these
companies logos because there's so many
companies and wedged them all together
to fit on one frickin page it's mine by
the way yeah sure
mm-hmm that's their whole shtick is is
secure messaging on mobile platforms so
as much as they have a desktop thing
it's very much like designing around the
ability of communications and
communicating the way that you want it
and whatever I look man so it's I
actually talked with the Wicker CEO the
other day and got like his pitch about
what are you trying to do and it wasn't
what I expected like I was thinking it
was more like secure messaging kind of
thing but when you put a point on what
they are trying to do it's land in this
space I don't and and and he will freely
admit they're not doing a good job of
communicating that message because
people have that reaction right they're
actually like oh you're a messaging
company like no no no no stop it's the
same way like you know tenable is that
neccessity right haha drives them nuts
like because people will call them like
I had to call meses and get some support
but you had a call tenable they get
support so I mean there are companies
that struggle with their identity in
this space but they I mean in their
universe they think they're mobile
hobbyists and pros right so you can get
degrees this is a new thing right the
ability to get a cyber security degree
if you're over the age of 32 you do not
have an undergraduate degree in cyber
security you may have a master's degree
at some graduate degree in cyber
security but as of what we require now
14 years ago there were really not
general access to programs at the
undergraduate level that would
constitute a cyber security information
security computer security degree right
we started having what what oh but it
was this is a ditch slide from a
different talk and I gutted it and now
I'm getting for it so okay man yeah
thank you that yeah it was actually as I
was fishing while I stepped in a bear
trap is what it turned out so the un--
this is a relatively new thing at the
undergrad degree but it's ramping up
really
right and it's amazing the diversity
that's happening at the collegiate level
so I do a lot of college recruiting at
different universities and I used RIT
and Penn State RIT Rochester Institute
of Technology in New York and Penn State
obviously in in State College and I
recruit from both of those organizations
very aggressively they could not be any
different more different when it comes
to what they're teaching their kids from
the security space RIT is a Technical
Institute
it's very applied it's a good school
right it's four-year school they have
all the resources you can imagine like I
mean the amount of computing power they
have the access to the industry that
they have you get people who are very
applied very up to speed on state of the
art and what's possible but they don't
necessarily have the grounding and kind
of core research methods they don't have
the broader humanities background that
you would get somewhere else you got a
Penn State get a lot of big thinking
right people that understand the
foundations the practice they understand
you know a lot of the policy issues I
could get a an analyst on depends out of
Penn State any any day the week I can
get a consultant out of Penn State if I
need somebody actually go do something
to a system that's not Penn State right
I have one person I've ever hired from
Penn State that would consider kind of
in that doer category there was a cop's
I major who coincidentally kind of likes
security so I pulled him through the
security not hole right but everybody
else they've hired them to be policy
people and do like seto work and that
kind of thing so and I'm not slagging on
Penn State I mean that's clearly that
both those kinds of disciplines are
important they're an industry but when
you think of like hey I want to go get a
degree in cybersecurity I'm looking at
Penn State and RIT that's like hey I'm
thinking of something that will get me
from point A to point B so I'm looking
at a lamborghini and leftover space
shuttle right like there wow those are
two radically different things like you
have need very different skills to
operate both of them but they will get
you from point A to point B like
congratulations and divining that so and
then you get local schools like I
advised Penn College of Technology in
Williamsport Pennsylvania as a two-year
school that's now a four-year school
very much vocational their cybersecurity
program is in the same College as the
their welding degree right you can get a
four-year degree in welding and the Dean
of that College has a master's in
welding right and he oversees the
cybersecurity program
thankfully he freely admits like I don't
know a goddamn thing about this right
like that's my assistant dean knows
cyber and he's putting together the
program in the curriculum but they're
really like you know what do we do and
so they've gotten industry people and
academic folks together to try to help
them build a degree that's targeted for
for the kids that are there so and the
same things even happening here and in
Delaware as you putting together the
program here so there's not unlike
mechanical engineering like psychotic
psychology things like that
there's no agreed upon what the
disciplines here look like we can we can
hem and haw about certs and the efficacy
of them in our industry all we like my
struggle with for those of us that don't
have these that exist at a time where it
wasn't even possible to get those what
is the other metric in which to gauge
competency if it's not a cert right the
other metric is smart person interviews
right someone smarter than me
interviewing me to see if I know what
I'm talking about in my domain they've
heard a lot of organizations that's hard
they don't have people smarter that's
why they're requiring the ceh and the
SIS P and whatever because they're just
gonna rely upon that as like a surrogate
for a smart person doing the interview
so I mean I struggle a lot with this
because of the mandatory nature and then
the fact that it's a printing press of
money for the organizations that run
these systems and you know that's a
that's a bigger issue but I come to the
come to grips a little bit that this is
a necessary evil and again you can't age
discriminate but part of it and still we
have two or three generations of
programs that the undergrad we're not
going to be able to kind of start to
push these aside because this is for
people like me if you need I don't have
any certs right I've taught cert
programs for asserts that I didn't have
it's weird like I don't know how I was
able to do that but I've never had a
single cert in my life abstence ibly
most contracts that I worked on on the
federal government
I didn't qualify for most of the labor
categories I had special labor
territories constructed for me because
of my college dropout with 20 years
experience and no certs they're like
well that doesn't fit anywhere like
we'll just right Bruce's labor category
and they're there would be there were
several contracts with different
government agencies I was the only
person in a labor category cuz they were
wired so I could get in the door and
then we go to conferences and we learned
from our
peers and that's four again people that
in this space before their degrees that
was how you learn right like you go to
events like this and you listen to
people you're talking you network and
you get to know who's doing what and
what else is interesting and it's still
the case right I mean we def cons huge
then we have all these b-sides events we
have all these other things we can go to
places and talk to people that are
like-minded and get interesting the same
thing in fly-fishing right like there
are people that I mean they probably
degree in wildlife conservation
environmental whatever but their focus
was on freshwater aquatic wildlife right
there are focused on fish they know
everything about the the streams in
central New York right there are
agriculture universities in New York
State that you can go to and learn all
about New York agriculture and wildlife
and become an expert in that space in a
way that I can't even envision I grew up
as a fourth-generation lumbermen my my
father his father and his father all
were lumbermen my brothers work for them
they still all are lumbermen I got out
of that business that was not my thing
but I have an appreciation for my
brothers degrees in forestry like the
fact that I do like some casual
woodworking and I cut down trees in my
backyard with a chainsaw does not make
me a forester it just means I'm kind of
reasonably confident with a chainsaw and
if the zombies show up like I'll
probably not die in the first wave but
you know that there's a real discipline
around wildlife management right and
part of what we do as fishermen is is a
respect for the outdoors and whatever so
these are pros in this space you can get
certified as professional cast
instructors you can get certified as
professional guides there's all these
different bodies that will certify
people and say hey trout Fisher person
who's giving guided tours you probably
know what you're talking about
which is about the level of thumbs up
NIST that some of these certs give us in
the cybersecurity space and as I stated
earlier I'm going to international
flight and symposium on Sunday I'm super
excited about it I mean I'll be honest I
am excited to be a bee size Delaware I
think I'm actually more excited to go
talk to guys about flying just so you
all know where where I stand anyway door
yeah
if filled with people who are
self-taught
I love this photo that's it's not a
self-portrait but it could have been
like is this how are you really sure
hacker what I I'm a mixed mind of the
bug bounty trends that we see these days
and I I think they're they're an
effective component of a cyber security
or risk management program abroad
program they're a poor component if
you're betting the farm on it right like
I don't think we need to pay for a pen
test let's just have a bug bounty like
no like that's a horrifyingly bad idea
and there are organizations that have
kind of gone down that road you're like
no no that's not all right but this idea
that there are a whole group of people
that are getting into applications
security because of bug bounties it's
actually kind of fascinating because
it's it's it's like was it fiber or
whatever you just ask people like you
can just go pick up a website be like
what are the rules of engagement okay
I'm gonna go attack it and see what I
can find
that's actually kind of neat right it's
it's just mercenary pentesting there are
parts of it still kind of make me a
little nervous but all in all if we're
if we're building more people and
getting more people in this industry in
kind of non-conventional ways I'm okay
with that as long as the companies are
participating understand how the quality
of some of the work they're gonna get
out of here I've worked with companies
that have gone down the bug bounty route
and there's definitely this like hey we
got a bunch of interesting stuff and we
got nothing that's interesting right
like although the volume was constant
like if they got a constant volume of
stuff but there'd only be one or two
things out of a hundred that were useful
after the first month or so and and
there are other instances that hasn't
been the case but the vast majority that
I've seen they get a big oomph at the
beginning people get their money and
then that's about the end of the useful
stuff mentorian early on helped cement
immensely for those of you that have
been in the field a while you've been
asked these questions for those of you
if this is new to you you are probably
asking yourself these kind of questions
right now like I I'm amazing number of
times that I'll give a talk at a place
and someone will come up to me and be
like okay I'm not doing this kind of
thing but I'm thinking about it how do I
get started I gave a talk at the
association of the US Army in in DC a
couple years ago and during the before
the talk I was having one
in the cafeteria at the convention
center down in DC this guy you know I'm
just sitting there by myself this guy
comes down sits down next to me and we
get to talk in and I'm like he's like
you know what do you do and I'm telling
them and then why you asking what he
does this guy graduated from West Point
okay cool
he's a ranger all right that's pretty
badass and he's got his MBA wow man you
know how to kill people and make them
feel dumb like I'm in flux that's really
he's a nice guy but he's clearly like
off-the-charts smart like talk to her
play 10 or 15 minutes I'm like so much
respect for this cat right like the fact
that he's put his life in the line he's
been deployed and now he thinks the
greatest service he can do to this
country is work procurement at the
Pentagon god that hurts me so much and
so then I'm talking about what I do he's
like man cybersecurity is so fascinating
but I just can't figure out how to get
started in it like your West Point rains
your MBA and the thing that's
challenging to you is how to get started
in cyber like holy we are doing this so
wrong right like god damn man so I
actually like called him in the middle
of the talk that I was giving like had
him stand up like let's talk about this
guy I'm like oh that's probably
dangerous but it worked out here you
know can i hack back with someone hacks
me I mean people ask that question maybe
not in that way but I'm reminded back 15
years ago we were doing community
wireless networking stuff in Northern
Virginia trying to build a big nest
network of companies and an individual
sharing Wi-Fi connection so you could
just move around Northern Virginia and
get free internet bait you know off of
everyone's home Wi-Fi it whatever is a
grand utopian socialist like socialism
and Bernie was in the back room guiding
us all so one guy comes to me at one of
our meetings it was like hey I got an
idea I got a business plan I think it's
gonna work I said what's that he's gonna
I'm gonna drive around the area and look
for like open access points and when I
find them I'm gonna find the businesses
associate Wayne I'm gonna go in and say
hey I see that your wireless network
might be vulnerable if you give me like
I don't know five thousand dollars I can
fix it for you I'm like just so we're
clear your business plan will be viewed
as extortion by other people is like no
I'm just trying to help but like dude
they have no idea when you come and be
like I know something you don't know
that bad for your business
you give me $5,000 I'll tell you about
it it's like I'm gonna call the cops
I'll be right back you know like oh my
god so I'm all hooked up on the
microphone now there we go
can you still hear me okay good Oh
dodged a bullet is it okay to attack a
website I learned like again people
don't ask that necessarily they like so
I was running this free web scanner
against Amazon last night like let's
talk it's like eight things we need to
cover like right now first of all were
you going through tor can anyone find
you like you know people learn from
people that have been around because
we've all made mistakes right like I've
made so many mistakes in this space and
I'm more than happy to help people to
learn from those mistakes
and it's the same thing like I swear
when I'm learning in like fly-fishing I
the number of times I did this and was
just like I don't know what to do
because I have two problems one three I
want to keep fishing and I can't right
now because I have like this basketball
sized pile of in front of me that
does not gracefully go out like we saw
Robert Redford earlier in the movie
right you're in the in the movie I'm a
movie I'm not a movie
that's my ego right there like I just I
just stepped right in it
so secondarily this lines really
expensive right and you're like I
just torched a bunch of it right so
because I'm not gonna untie that
nonsense and then third that the nail
not that you have to use to connect this
to the monofilament it's complicated and
every time I do it I have to Google it
like I have a special tool that I use
but the tool doesn't describe how to use
it it's just as weird you think so I'm
in the middle of water balance in my
phone I got two lines what try not to
drop the phone the fish are all like got
it guys terrible it's really just the
worst so but then like I'll talk to
something like why does this keep
happening and it'll be like some real
subtle thing like your hands here
instead of here like no and now I don't
make giant basketball sides knots of
crap anymore like that's great I wish
someone told me that before your gears
matter but humans matter more this was
awesome this this talk and besides
Vancouver it's AI is now on its third
research and out resurgence third birth
if you will in the in the 60s and 70s
symbolic computing will save us all
right
we don't need faster computers we just
mean
more abstract programming languages we
need Lisp and like that to make our
life better and if we can teach
computers to think symbolically
we will win and that did not work out
and then in the mid-90s we thought wow
we have a lot of computing power will
build expert systems and they will be
like AI and that will all work and that
didn't work out and now we like I
have the cloud and we have so much
horsepower in the cloud that we just
solve problems by running at them as
fast as we can like if he's run against
the wall eventually the wall will like
move right like that's what the AI model
is today just push really hard for a
long time and eventually the system will
learn it's such but and it's
funny how much of this stuff just still
turns out to be stats right like finding
the standard deviation isn't machine
learning it's math like it's not that
complicated but we keep finding it now I
worked with a company that was trying to
do automated discovery of denial of
service through an AI system and I spent
months explaining them how the internet
worked right literally like here's
autonomous systems here's BGP here's how
route flapping happens all this kind of
stuff and they're trying to find all
like build the AI sustain a magic AI box
that they thought eventually could find
denial of service attacks and one day
I'm like you know you could just look at
the amount of traffic and if it's bigger
than the pipe it's a denial of service
attack there's nothing more kathai well
yeah we could so humans still matter and
will continue to matter in this space
for a long period of time it's the same
thing here like if you and I were to go
fly-fishing right now I am still a
shitty fly fisherman like I will admit
it I'm not very good and the difference
in the amount of fish that I will catch
between a 50 dollar rod and an $850 rod
are probably zero right not a
statistically important amount of fish
well I catch will be the difference
between if I use those two rods mentally
I think I will be a better fisherman if
I buy that rod but I know in my heart of
hearts I suck and this one will be just
fine right it hasn't stopped me from
landing somewhere in the middle so
closer to the no no right um information
security is dangerous if you're not
paying attention fishing can be very
interesting you're not paying attention
I don't know what this thing is it is
real it's somewhere in South America and
you can catch them before they catch you
it's like pokey it's like lethal Pokemon
so there are things that we can do in
this space that cause harm right we can
hack back like that causes harm we can
and this is an interesting one like I
I've worked with clients who do and sit
you analysis they let the attackers stay
in place so they can observe them okay
like I've this thing that makes fire and
I'm gonna put it in the middle of this
pile of tissue paper let's hope it
doesn't catch all the tissue paper on
fire right like it's this is incredibly
dangerous and what most organizations
aren't geared up to do this it sounds
good most of time most organizations are
better off like yanking them out
restoring normal operations and getting
on with their life I've been involved in
breach response where they won't spend a
lot of time figure out who is breaking
in and after two or three months of the
same people breaking it all the time
like we can stop with the forensics
analysis it's the same people like we
don't attribution is not important stop
getting broken into that's the important
bit detonating about we're like we've
seen that go bad right like hey I do
malware analysis at home now my home
blew up right like this oops
IOT is hard even speaking out about
high-profile attacks will get people in
trouble right there when you piss off
organized crime groups and stuff like
they won't come find you as it turns out
right like when you put ask Brian Krebs
right how many times has he been swatted
a lot why cuz he called people out right
people out that don't want to be called
out and then inadvertent hacking like
oops I inadvertently hacked no right
this is how you gonna fly through your
pair of glasses but that's somewhat
terrifying this is happened to me a lot
this is the situational awareness like
I'm doing something I'm not paying
attention and also like there's a huge
pool information it's like a cartoon
right like if you look on the terror of
my face and then the waiters spill up
and I'm like floating downstream like oh
well I'm a water sale a big fat wire
sale very quick story about a river
otter I was fishing on a protected trout
stream in Wisconsin and I had a hike it
was like you got a hike a mile through a
cornfield so I go in this cornfield I go
down the freakin dog huge steep slippery
and back maggot all the way at the
bottom I'm so exciting is like this is
supposed to be the greatest transfer in
Wisconsin the Kinnickinnic River and I
was fishing on the K I was all excited I
get all my gear on and I see a river
otter
like upstream like 30 yards I'm seeing
honor in a while again the water I'm
fishing and then
there's a river otter downstream like 10
yards making noises at me like that's
weird and the river ours over here
making noises then running through the
bush and the behind me and I'm like oh
my god
and I'd like half an hour I'm like there
is not a trout within 100 yards of this
place so this otter is scared them all
off right because no trial wants to me
new this goddamn otter
so like screw this noise so I go walking
back to my gear which is up on the bank
and the otter swims in front of me and
disappears and I realize I put my stuff
on top of its den I like ah man that
otter is pissed so I go climbing up and
taking my stuff off and so I mean it's
an ordeal
right like I gotta take off the fast I
gotta take off the boots add tape
oscillators and I'm sitting there I got
waders around my ankle I'm like kind of
weasel it up the otter jumps up like for
me your sneakers away jumps up under the
bank stands out by others behind legs
boys hit me and I'm like what like I've
literally said what with my arms
outstretched and he's like and he starts
like bitching toward me like I grabbed
my tube that I keep the rod and I'm
thinking I'm gonna have to beat a river
otter to death right like I thought I
was gonna die here to commune with
nature and it's done and he decided at
that point that I was not gonna
you just took up okay yeah yeah I don't
think he's that smart I think it large
abstract thing is making me angry I
think that's all he was really thinking
but anyway I did not kill a river otter
that day so not that day that dance
my lawyer advised me very specific
language around wouldn't declare I have
not killed her actually that was the
Carter page answer I know nothing about
the dead moose either like I have no
idea so so information security is
predominantly white male
totally not okay right this is not
something that's good for our industry
it's not good for society this is a
complex topic both why we are that way
as an industry and also the impact that
it has on us right the fact that we
don't have the diversity that we should
makes this week we're not accomplishing
everything that we could be doing we're
not giving back to the community we
could be doing so in in both these
instances there are organizations who
are trying to make it better that's not
to say you can't do things on your own
to address some of these root causes but
I think that there's good work that's
been going on a s
and project healing excuse me project
healing and trouts unlimited have youth
outreach programs and outreach programs
to disabled vets that I think have been
very useful to make trout fishing and
fly fishing more inclusive and part of
the community yes is a organization in
the DC area that does stem outreach in
schools year up call special attention
to Europe Europe is an organization that
the way that they're structured is
they'll take people adults from 18 to 25
ish who have kind of the desire and and
an education background to be able to go
to college but they don't have the
academic ability or the exceeding the
economic ability and not just from a
financial perspective from the cells but
the fact that they may be holding down a
job because they're having to take care
of the grandmother or the brothers and
sisters or whatever it is you know we've
got people living in areas where one or
two job supports a family of five or six
and so people at 18 and 19 aren't able
to go out in the community and get a job
or they have to go out in the community
get a job and they can't get an
education so what year up does is for
those people they say okay you're gonna
come and get six months of intensive
training eight to five everyday and it's
around business management IT or
cybersecurity and it's it's eight to
five that show up in business attire
every day like not whatever like I have
a collared shirt like the guys are all
in suits
the women are in and either you know
they're dressed in business attire as
well this is a more complicated subject
for women like what constitutes business
attire and we have that whole discussion
but they they then go through everything
from the the technology and the the tech
aspect of their job and also how to
interact with your co-workers how to
write reports you know what a business
meetings actually like how to
communicate effectively all these kind
of things and then it's really cool and
and so then then when they're done they
have industry partners that they'll
reach out to and you basically get a
six-month intern and so these people go
out in the field and they'll get jobs
interning for six months in their in
their domain and they they're very
sensitive to like hey we're trying to
find companies are close to you or
within your means to get to because
sometimes people don't have cars they
have to ride mass transit so they're
trying to find
you know ways to be able to make sure
that they're successful in that domain
that whole time they get paid right so
when again this program they're getting
a paycheck they get a stipend so if they
were working somewhere if they were
working at McDonald's or working at the
dry cleaner or whatever was their doing
they can get paid to get educated and
then at the end of this process they
have the education and they have the
exposure where the company they're
interviewing with then they can go get a
job a lot of the companies that they in
turn would pick them up and a lot of but
even if they don't they're the the rate
that which these these students have
jobs after six months is something that
rageous like 93% have jobs so they make
a $40,000 or more which for some of
these kids who are making like sixteen
thousand dollars a year it's
life-changing for their families right
something less changed for themselves I
mean so the whole damn family gets a
benefit out of this so the way that this
works is the companies that that bring
the students in they pay about twenty
six thousand dollars which is about what
you're gonna pay a six-month intern
anyway but they pay that fee two-year up
who uses it to fund their entire program
in combination with other fundraising
that they do so if you are a hiring
manager if you're a company that is
hiring today looking for interns looking
for a junior staff and you're in DC
you're in Baltimore you're in Wilmington
you're in Philadelphia or you're in
Boston or Chicago there's a year up
there please reach out to them at least
get to know them build a relationship
they have two cohorts a year they I
think they come out like in February and
August when the when the internships or
when they're ready you know and then may
vary locality locality that's the
Baltimore one but I would encourage you
reach out to Europe if you want after
this meeting or after this puck I'm
happy to get in contact with my contacts
a year up I can't speak highly enough
about this program it's a fantastic
program the guy who started is I mean I
don't get motivated by much I'm kind of
an asshole
I really had probably more wrapped up in
myself than I should be this guy's
humbling to listen to talk to you like
he is I mean the guy who started your up
is really really an amazing cat so with
that information security is a lot of
fun
so why fishing even if you're not
catching fish so my advice to you
especially for those of you they're kind
of getting started find the stuff that
you love you know fly-fishing if it's
the gear if it's the flies if it's the
traveling to exotic locales like you
know focus on that if you're in security
you know if
you're a forensic analyst winter yeah do
the stuff you like doing I've discovered
much as I like standing around in water
and not catching fish I really like
tying flies the fly tying workshop
earlier today I'm not very good at it
but I enjoy it it's very relaxing to me
I feel like I actually get to build
something I mean it's not and we do
stuff in cyber all the time and all you
see is like I have a bunch of files
somewhere and like a web page or
something like that like of a bunch of
little hooks I hide stuff to that fish
sometimes want to eat I think it's kind
of cool and and for me I mean as much as
I like to fish I'm busy I don't have a
lot of time but I can do that kind of
clock at night let the Black Knight sit
down tie some flies and enjoy things so
anyway with that I don't know if there's
any questions guys
she looks skeptical well I told you I
was gonna closer to it you're like oh
that's okay but yeah ii beartrap
I had a bear trap on each plate all
right sweet well thanks for playing
along with this little science
experiment if anyone does have any
feedback on on how to make these two
topics tie together better than I did
I'd appreciate it so thanks
[Applause]
you