she is for coming I realized that
there's a whole bunch of you know talks
activities other things you could be
doing people could be chatting to so I
really appreciate your kind of turning
up to see my talk is dungeons and
datacenters which is kind of covering
some of my thoughts and violence that
I've had with sort of experiences social
engineering recently so so so Who am I
my name is Tom I've done way too long 15
years in InfoSec so I consider myself
kind of long-term listener first-time
caller as far as this sauce was
concerned it's my first talk hence why
I'm kind of bracketed as being a rookie
the ridiculously long combination of
letters there means that I'm a senior
subject matter expert for advanced
intrusion testing at Lloyds Banking
Group which is the repeated three-letter
acronym way of saying that I kind of
manage scope and design and perform read
team testing for Lloyds Banking Group
I'm a avid gamer of pretty much any type
so you know from computer games through
to board games through to card games
if basically gave me a tennis ball and
said throw this at a wall and you'll
score some points I'll probably sit
there for a few hours
a massive psychology language and
systems nerd so any of that stuff I
absolutely love it it takes up a bunch
of time I'll read anything about it kind
of dig deeper and kind of look at
outsource stuff and then also I must
kind of social engineering junkie so
it's one more special isms that I fall
under the subject matter expert bit of
my job title I kind of started digging
into it probably six or seven years ago
and then since I've been doing red
teaming in the last sort of three or
four it's become kind of a lot more
focused and I sort of decent part of
what I do day to day
so what I'm gonna do is kind of go down
the rabbit hole go through red teaming
what it is a little bit social
engineering how that fits in and then
we're going to go into the bits of
social engineering that I want to talk
about the bits that I think are
interesting and there's some stuff that
we can kind of learn about how to deal
with people and how to you know
appropriately social engineer them that
sort of thing so I've interest who works
in a Red Team offensive security or that
type of thing or for a company that has
got that cool so for you guys I hope I
don't teach you how to much how to suck
eggs for the start of it and in the last
part of it you'll get some sort of
useful information out of it so that
quote there is the in theory water red
themers you know it's a independent
group that challenges an organization
etc etc etc sounds really cool you know
is really appealing and probably one of
the more more interesting bits of
InfoSec in my opinion in actual fact
it's it's isn't hacking it's hack it's
really really heavily bureaucratic and
regulated hacking with like 80 percent
reporting and that isn't any different
when you work for a bank it's probably
if anything a little bit worse
so scoping red team engagements and that
sort of thing and what you include and
what you don't is a real art
particularly when you're dealing with
sort of a large organization they don't
want you to go everything's in scope
even though the ideal for a red team if
you can approve anything is that yes
everything's in scope so as a whole
bunch of those arguments that go on on a
day-to-day to their life but hopefully
going to talk about some of the more
interesting bits so social engineering
within red teaming so red team is meant
to be a holistic way of testing you
meant to test kind of everything in the
entire environment allowed people break
stuff down into being PPT I use kind of
pppt I always have to check that I've
said there are around peas so yes so
covering people process physical and
Technology whenever we do tests so when
people talk about social engineering
they tend to go this is the bit we're
interested in you know this is the bit
where people talk about the humans being
an organisation's biggest weakness or
there's no patch for human stupidity and
all that solve really really bad phrases
that don't encourage good behaviors in
your user base in actual fact or I tend
to find that the really interesting bits
tend to come when we look at the kind of
intersection between people process
technology and physical and how like the
people monitor those controls how they
use them that sort of thing so you find
a lot of vulnerabilities in in the way
that the people interact with them and
in a case of kind of the blue team which
is the only kind of blue thing I'll
probably discuss for this talk like the
defense's you can put in place there are
still some and if you look at Defense's
in terms of technology or process
controls or physical controls to stop
people doing the wrong thing then that
does actually prevent a quite a few
social engineering attacks so from
breaking down social engineering I break
it down into kind of four main sections
so ocean stroke recon which is a massive
subject in its own and is the foundation
of pretty much any social engineering
you do if you want to do good social
engineering you need good ocean a recon
fortunately I haven't got as long in
this talk as I'd like to kind of dig
really deep into how to do ocean recon
that sort of thing but you know it's an
essential thing you can find a whole ton
of stuff out there online on it so then
we've got fishing which is you know the
most well known you know really high
volume stuff and you know I think the
figure is 65% of breaches start with a
phishing email that sort of thing
then we go up fishing which is phone
social engineering and doing over the
phone and then the bit I'm always good
to that there isn't a word that starts
with itching or ends in itching is
impersonation which is the in-person
physical part they see where you go in
talk to people and actually get them to
do what you want in person so I'm going
to cover these two areas mainly cause
fishings kind of a thing all of its own
and phishing impersonation cover a lot
the same type of skills a lot of the you
know dealing with people dealing with
individuals conversation rapport that
sort stuff so if you break down phishing
an impersonation so it starts off with
the ocean recon phase right the start as
I said it's a whole whole world of
interest and details then we go on to
kind of pretext development this is
where you're developing the person that
you're going to be when you are social
engineering someone when you're going in
when you're calling them you know this
is how you define what it is that you're
going to do then you go for what is the
bump or initial approach with phishing
this is really really simple so this is
the bit where you know they pick up the
phone when you're doing impersonation a
bit more complicated it's the bit where
you stop being a
stranger to them so you answer put your
questions as you approach them in order
to kind of put my ease stop them
questioning you too much then we go into
building trust and rapport which is what
normal people would call a conversation
but when you say when you do social
engineering there's a whole bunch of
other factors that you're trying to do
at the same time as having that
conversation and then achieving your
objective so trying to get someone to do
something they may or may not want to do
in order to help your attack or or
progress what it is you're doing so as
we go to kind of further down the rabbit
hole these the bits that I'm probably
gonna focus on that bumps or approach
stuff is it's kind of fairly low-key and
not something I'm gonna go to detail on
but they're the kind of protects
development how you work out what you're
going to be how you gonna be approached
it and the building trust and rapport
section the bit that are kind of the
main meat of your social engineering
engagement cool so I'm gonna go over
some of the stuff that I use as kind of
weapons at my disposal so as I said I've
done a bunch of social engineering
research but a bunch of reading about it
as well as a couple of different
training courses that sort of thing I'm
a social engineering pentest
professional and master's level social
engineering expert from social engineer
dog but on top of that there's some
extra elements that I've sort of used in
order to help me with these dilemmas and
problems so psychology and sociology
huge subject whereas social engineering
as an idea has been around for like
10-15 years obviously psychology and
sociology have been around for hundreds
so there's a whole bunch of tools a
whole bunch of stuff that lets you
dissect how people work what they think
that sort of thing and it is where a ton
of my research time goes is into
thinking into this so another thing
which is kind of quite awkward for most
techies and that sort thing improv
acting so the really really similar part
of social engineering applies this is
kind of the the impersonation section
you know when you're there when you talk
to someone you kind of want to be able
to come up with ideas discuss new things
and kind of edit what you're how you're
behaving and what you're talking about
in order to apply better to the target
it's also the bit that at least I find
is the big fear of social engineering is
that part of going oh my god and we
stood there and I'm gonna choke I'm not
going to know what to say I'm going to
panic actually The Improv acting stuff
really helps with that because you're
put on the spot like twenty times and
every time you do it
and then kind of the the big nerd
influence and what influence the title
the talk I think it puts me second on
the nerd hierarchy on the geek hierarchy
slightly below furries um I've been
doing kind of D&D tabletop stuff for
like 15 years I've been a larper for
like well over half my life in the last
few years I've run seven or eight
different events for people where we've
built entire immersive worlds we've kind
of you know developed characters for
them things to interact with done like
20 different pretext generations which
we define as you know roles for them to
interact with that sort of thing and
it's a really really good opportunity to
study human behavior human interaction
in kind of weird settings so like very
very difficult in real life to watch
someone who's scared for their life but
I get to do it like 20 times every event
which is great you know and and going if
I give a person X Y Zed information
what will they then do with it which is
something you just can't do without well
occasionally associated new you get to
do that but as I've kind of done it I've
seen the parallels between the two quite
a lot so dioramas and thoughts which is
kind of the main focal point of this
talk which is kind of issues or problems
I've experienced whilst doing social
engineering and the tools or ideas that
I've used in order to help kind of fix
them
so the ptex development part as I said
realized really heavily on ocean and
recon that little diagram is one bit
that's really important assess what you
can and can't do so like I would fail
miserably to impersonate an Olympic
athlete a pregnant woman or a brain
surgeon and like you kind of have to
accept that but that being said in some
situations you can go I'm going to
impersonate a brain surgeon because I
need to do it for five minutes to this
one guy before I leave him away and
never get asked questions about it again
so it is kind of possible to learn some
things very very quickly I crammed at
one point to be an interior designer in
the space of two and a half hours and
managed to carry off a relatively
successfully for like an hour and a half
in a discussion with people kind of you
have to understand what it is you your
pretext needs so what you're trying to
accomplish with this social engineering
engagement and then look at who you are
and what you think you can be within the
timeframes you've got
so sorry just checking back on that so a
couple of dilemmas that I face when
doing this is what preparations should I
do because that's a really kind of hard
thing to decide there's a whole whole
world of preparation you could be doing
you then what's useful what's not and
then there's a thing about how perfect
is too perfect for your pretext you know
if you're approaching someone exactly
how detailed you want to make it and
what you want to talk about so one of
the things of course want a spontaneity
versus preparedness style Emma so you've
got a temptation to write a full
autobiography you know you've got you
know you're going in you pretending to
be a certain person and you want to
write all the details you want to
prepare everything if you like me you
want to kind of design everything put it
all down make sure you've got it all
embedded in your mind that sort of stuff
but if you lock yourself down too hard
you lose the ability to kind of
improvise when you need to when you're
talking to someone so if you approach
someone and they're you know kid is does
football then you want to be able to
switch your pretext to going yeah Mike
it also does football you establish
yourself as part of a tribe with them
you build a link with them you start
building trust and rapport and you can
then leverage that further on to get
what you want so being prepared is great
as much as you can remember it all like
that's one of things I tend to find as
well is that you get to a point where
you've gone I'm not gonna remember all
the details of this I'll just remember
certain key things and then kind of be
spontaneous spontaneous with the rest
but even like spontaneity requires a
basic amount of background knowledge for
you to leverage in order to know what to
do with it so I use this which is
Whitney Maxwell's kind of breakdown of
digital footprints I'll turn it on his
head and go okay like different
categories of stuff so core intermediate
peripheral information so things like
personal preferences likes and hobbies
really good things to be spontaneous
with really good thing to connect with
people on and talk about a little bit
you need to do a little bit of research
on anything that you're going to be
spontaneous about that you're going to
bring up so you can at least cover it
the kind of I've heard it termed as
being the related songs man so knowing a
little bit about everything so you can
use that to better leverage your pretext
when you're talking about the kind of
intermediate stuff so categories like
you
hometown employer religion you want to
do make sure that's consistent research
you know in the facts that you can come
across as someone who works for company
acts or who lives in town X you don't
beat them going all whereabouts in you
know whereabouts in least you live and
you're going all by the car park is you
know absolutely dreadful so you want to
make sure you know enough details that
you can say that if you are questioned
in normal conversation about it
you can still come up with the right
ideas and then kind of peripheral stuff
which is the end of an individual facts
about you that's tough you need to know
it because everyone knows their
individual individual facts about them
but it doesn't need to necessarily be
researched or linked into anything or
anything like that
as long as you're consistent with it and
you're not giving you know you know
introducing yourself as Bob to person
one and then Kyle to person two you
should measure the time to find so the
other aspect the too good to be true
dilemma so this is something I've seen a
couple of times whilst doing social
engineering people are naturally
suspicious of anything that's too
perfect
so you do eurosam
you find out everything about this
person that you're gonna be targeting
and you're like right I'm gonna write
the perfect pretext he's into
photography his kids do football
he's wife's a chef so you show up with
you know your cooking book under one
hand your phone your camera onto the
other one and start talking about how
great your kids football was and he's
gonna look at you and go that feels
wrong because that's too close to me and
normally there's more differentiation
between you and strangers you mean
unless this is gonna be you know unless
you you pretext this that that guys are
gonna meet your soulmate you probably
don't want to be going to that level of
detail so what I find is that there's a
kind of a role play game technique
that's really useful here so sit down
and go write that list of what I am or
what I could be and what pretext needs
build out list it out in a big page and
then go I'm going to choose one of those
at random rather than necessarily I'm
gonna go straight for this first one
that I've made that's absolutely perfect
so take all the elements split them out
and then use a kind of random generator
to go yeah I'll be this because then
it's not going to be precisely spot on
and perfect
cool so this is a something that comes
from 1730 when they started defining the
properties of actors in plays and that
sort of thing but it's something that I
find really useful so my brain naturally
works and approaches stuff and I'll go
here's the details here's the facts that
saw stuff this sort of thing is the
thing that I never really think about
unless I'm kind of forced to so I won't
go through them all but a few of them
like you know the dramatic need of what
you're trying to accomplish kind of the
attitude of the character that you're
trying to portray the pretext at you
developed that saw stuff and then like
weaknesses and mannerisms are good ways
to kind of differentiate yourself break
away from being the same thing every
time you do it and kind of also help you
load better into what I consider to be
kind of different brain VM in that you
are then that thing and you're that
person so as caring pretext generation
so I'm going to go on to kind of
developing trust and rapport so this is
the foundation of every social
engineering attack really really heavily
leverages body language and and that
sort of thing I'm not going to go into
detail on that because there's a lot of
people who covered it books by you know
Ian man Paul Ekman Joe Navarro as well
as talks by Chris Hutton Aggie shark
Ian man a whole bunch of other people so
sociology kind of defines a breakdown of
conversations into form and content so
you cannot kind of analyze them
independently of each other and an
aspect of the form of conversations is a
thing called flow which was defined in
2014 research paper by Guttenberg post
MERS an owl so there is defined as being
the way a conversation is experienced as
being smooth efficient and mutually
engaging and as a social engineer I read
that description and went holy crap I
want that in every single social
engineering conversation I have if
you've got those three elements then
that conversation is going to be going
well you're gonna find it really easy to
develop trust and rapport and that
person's gonna be a lot more compliant
when it comes to it
so talking about the form part of it
there's the classic social engineering
advice you know you match you match the
tone pitch speed and volume of the
person you're talking to you've got a
bear in mind that when you've developed
that pretext before you've L this
character that you're going to be whilst
you're doing your social engineering but
if you try and do this stuff too hard
because sometimes break that so that's a
conscious decision you need to make as
to whether to you know if your planks if
you want to be someone who's nervous or
apprehensive or you know excited then
you might be talking a lot quicker than
normal you might be kind of like putting
more herbs and and pauses into your
conversation so you don't necessarily
want to match all those if you still
want to come across as the same kind of
aspects one of the things yeah never try
and do accents like unless you've got an
accent that you know 100% you can pass
for that person if you're put into that
city then don't don't even try and do it
learn from Sean Connery you know stick
to whatever your traditional accent is
and the other thing that I've found that
isn't included in that se advice I don't
whether it's a positive UK thing because
you know we shift around kind of accents
and formality and different places so
much but changing varying your formality
so abbreviating words not using words
that are too long or doing the opposite
and being really formal with something
can really help to kind of put across
your needs what you're trying to do what
you're trying to accomplish that sort of
thing so one of the other things I found
is that a lot of traditional social
engineering advice is you dealing with
an individual you know you approaching
that one person and getting them to do
what you want and it's really really
rare that well it's pretty often that
you'll find that that person's in a
group of people and that's a very very
different situation to approach so what
I'll try to do a lot of time is when you
first enter a group conversation look at
positions of body blading and feet so
like where your hips shoulders head
pointing and where your feet are
pointing that can help show kind of how
the authority and flow of that
conversation goes who's important who
you like who that sort of thing and then
you can kind of match that to some
extent to make sure you fit in now
another one of things that that kind of
traditional social engineering advice
comes along with is being kind of
synchronous being similar to the people
talking about same things you know
agreeing on every sub
that sort of thing and matching them in
a whole bunch of ways actually sometimes
you'll find especially positioning group
conversations that you want to be what
they call alternating or complementary
so this means that you have a value to
add to the conversation you're not being
the same as what they're saying you're
adding something new but you need to
make sure it's not a conflicting thing
so add something new that kind of
couples on to what they've been saying
and then listening out for common
grounding noises so this was defined by
someone called Kasim or a researcher
called Kashima which is the noises we
make during a conversation when we're
not the one talking that confirm that
we're still part of that conversation so
they're yep's aha that sort of thing
listen for those and see what the ones
that are that are used in that social
context and try and mimic those when
you're agreeing to stuff it's really
good like it's like psychology wise it
establishes you as being part of their
tribe even though that tribe is just
people in this conversation it
establishes being part of that and
instantly kind of connects you to people
so onto flow it's as I said it's really
a ephemeral concept measuring how well a
conversation is going it's kind of key
on the prompts for transfer of focus
just to be able to kind of assess how
well it's going so if you listen to two
people who've got really good flow
they'll be hardly any gap between one of
them finishing on the other one starting
and people won't talk over each other
they won't interrupt as much like he'll
naturally kind of bounce between people
and they'll pass the different amounts
of focus so that focus transfer is
normally less than 200 milliseconds in a
good conversation so if you're thinking
for more than a fifth of a second about
what you're gonna say then it can make
it seem like you're not really part of
the conversation and like the
conversations going awkwardly flow comes
really easy for people who talk a lot so
these days especially you know your text
your email you'll slack or whatever I've
started trying to force myself to
actually call people on the phone and
talk to them because like exercising
those muscles is super important and and
if you're not doing that then you kind
of start falling out over the way to
make good conversation so there's a
really good improv accounting game for
when you're doing social engineering
with a group of you or a pair of you you
want to make sure the flow between you
is kind of really strong and
you're not going to you know talk over
each other you're not gonna interrupt
which is a really simple game involving
counting so the concept being the
between you you need to count to 20
you're not going to just take it in
turns you're gonna say whichever number
you feel like saying and then you after
about four or five times of doing it and
talking over each other way you both say
to at the same time or you both so for
eventually get to the stage where you're
naturally picking up on that person's
kind of body language and cues that
they're about to speak and you'll stop
talking over them so much and being able
to fill up that with whoever your social
engineering with means that when you end
up with your target you not likely to
kind of enter in that same situation and
they'll find it a lot easier to enter
into the flow of your conversation and
then the other one which is really
really good for active listening so if
you're talking to people then a lot of
the time you'll be sat there thinking
about what you're going to say next
rather than what they're actually saying
so there's an improv game which involves
starting your sentence with the last
letter with the last person sentence
that's really really good and is really
good for forcing you to listen right to
the very end of a sentence before you
start the next one if you can do that
with that same lack of talk too much of
a gap then you become a really good
active listener people really start to
kind of engage with you and talk to you
about stuff and that's really good you
can do it deliberately if you go to
someone and go hey let's you know do
that game whilst we're talking you can
have a regular conversation whilst
applying that and likewise you can apply
it to people who aren't really paying
attention so if they do even if they
don't know that you're playing that
improv game you can do it and kind of
just force yourself to wait till the end
of a sentence before you think about
what you're going to say so content so
content is what you're actually gonna
say to you target you know is this it's
the things you're gonna deliver the
things you're gonna discuss so you
always want to let them lead and kind of
use the work that you put into your
pretext earlier to let to help kind of
shape and and direct the conversation
and make sure you've got stuff to add
you want to try and break bring people
into helping you so people don't want to
back out after commit to doing something
people will find that if they've started
doing something for you they'll carry on
doing that something for you all go
carry on doing something else for you
you know really kind of get those stuff
in early to know what you're kind of
framing to get them because you're pull
for what you want to do later
so having another person to shift and
blame - for any kind of effort or rule
breaking the need is really really
useful so going oh god my boss is asking
me to do this or you know or my wife
wants me to do this because she'll be
really upset if I don't people can
empathize with having a you know
potentially grumpy partner or a
pain-in-the-ass boss
and so they'll instantly kind of put
that puts you into one of their tribes
as well and then also if they're feeling
if there's sort of negative feeling or
they don't want to do what is you're
asking then they're not directing that
you they're directing that at some guy
who's off in the background here they
never meet and then they'd be aware of
the need to pivot so pivoting is one of
the things that gets discussed quite
often so it's a situation where the
target is either intentionally or not is
changing your pretext or kind of the
frame of your attack so situations where
it feels like they're putting you into a
situation where either they're correct
or you're correct so if you come in and
go hi I'm Dave from IT and they go well
I know everyone from IT then this is the
point where you need to kind of pivot
and go or actually I'm a contractor or I
only started last week or basically find
a third option in order to be able to
give them something that makes them feel
like they're still correct
you haven't lied to them and they can
carry on about their business so
roleplay games are kind of discuss this
is being an option three traditional
difference between kind of tabletop
role-playing games and that sort of
thing versus computer games is that
they'll always be kind of an option
three because you're in the real world
and you've got everything to work with
this under the Sun so there's a really
good improv cornerstone for this which
is the yes and game so someone make
something up the next person goes
yes and so you basically confirm what
the person said and then add something
to it now when you're doing social
engineering you end up a situation where
you need to pivot that's because they've
said no book to you which is a really
really hard thing and tends to break
down in profit improvise those who
improvisation so there's a few
role-playing games and saw tabletop
games that are really really good for
practicing this so there's one called
The Adventures of Baron von Munchausen
which is a one set of being a like late
1800s kind of adventuring Baron where
you go this is the
easy story I made up and then someone
challenges you and you need to come up
with some idea going yes you're right
but this is why that's right and I'm
still right so kind of learning those
things to do in order to be able to kind
of still confirm that they are correct
and that the challenges is valid but
answer it and move on so this is
something again super easy to practice
with friends you know I play a game
called well terms bullshit with a friend
of mine and I'll say something that's
that is nonsense always you know a lie
that's made up they'll call bullshit and
go that's bullshit because of this and
then your immediate response to that
needs to be yeah but this is actually
why it's still true and and you kind of
have a vague argument where you're not
actually arguing really easy to practice
with friends a really good thing to kind
of develop and kind of work from there
so that's kind of getting towards a
conclusion a talk I think I covered the
key stuff I wanted to thanks for
listening so the takeaways whilst social
engineering engagements even working in
part of a red team and it being actually
part my job is it's something that
doesn't happen all the time actually
finding Talent ways to practice is
really easy so games like that type of
thing like one of my things recently has
been trying to start a conversation with
three strangers every day which is
really really difficult especially if
you're in London on the tube you get
looked at like an absolutely crazy
person but trying to find ways to you
know use words at the very least and
then a bit of conscious effort and kind
of research and a bit of planning can
change your in bonus to a Christmas
bonus so people who are way of TMZ and
stuff will understand so going from
taking your intelligence and kind of an
analytical mindset and that sort of
thing and using it towards conversations
and discussions can mean that you
actually come across as being really
charismatic when actually just
substituting it for a whole bunch of
stuff you've learned and practiced and
then whilst the humans are the last line
of defense and all that sort of thing
they can actually be sometimes helped by
process and technology controls and
physical controls to stop and doing
things that they really really shouldn't
be so if you want to contact me and talk
to me about any of this stuff afterwards
or my contact stuff down there Twitter
Gmail I hang around on the many hats
Club discord and in the SEO
and Red Team channels so always happy to
chat there yeah cool any questions so I
struggle to give direct examples as part
of the fact so I work I work for a large
bank and they've gone I can't talk about
any actual details of stuff like that
but so if stuff when social engineering
stuff goes wrong especially if it's kind
of a really key pivotal moment tend to
find that it can massively skew things
it raises suspicions in people that's
all things so a lot of the time it's one
of those things where if it starts to go
wrong you can't really remediate and fix
it unless you can pivot well and kind of
transfer it off at the time then you end
up in a situation where you're going
right we just have to avoid that person
that subjects that that protects these
ballots because you don't want to kind
of carry on pushing something if people
start to get suspicions it's a real real
slippery slippery slope so yeah so there
is some degree of kind of going here's
my get-out-of-jail-free card I'm going
to walk away ideally just leaving and
going we're just going to leave that and
let it be someone who's vaguely
suspicious and hasn't reported it and
hopefully doesn't so we tend to try and
feed it back so we don't do it to
individuals is one of the kind of
cardinal rules because for social
engineering anyone can trip up anyone
can make those mistakes and you don't
want any organization kind of
persecuting the individual for having
made the mistake that anyone can make
but yeah we do kind of go this is the
type of thing you need to be looking at
but a lot of the time it's just talking
about like awareness of the fact that
this is a type of attack and then kind
of encouraging critical thinking so
people actually go is this really what's
going on rather than just naturally
assuming yes it is
cool well I'm gonna be looking around
here in probably outside smoking for the
rest of the next half hour and then I'm
about for the rest of the day so feel
free to catch up then cheers thank you
very much
[Applause]