[Music]
hi everybody so today we're trying to
show you how you can turning your BMC
into a revolving door so here is a
fabulous pair ago Alex on Gaza and
myself shall fetch Annie if you need
something more about us everything has
been already leaked on internet so feel
free to go there
[Music]
sorry guys is not working
okay oh no it's okay
[Music]
so let's first for the first
introduction so we're talking about BMC
so desmos management controller so we
are focused on the HP system it's ILO
BMC so this talk was covers a version
for that has been an entire middle of
2017 and but also we are introduced some
part on io5 about Eylau itself it's a
standalone system so there is a
dedicated ARM processor there is a few
more stones an on-chip dedicated ram
chip did you get the network interfaces
and the last but not least you should
know that if you plug the server so if
you make the power on the server I lost
at you don't need to boot the server to
that I do need to be start it's already
a start as soon as you plug the server
on the power about the design one really
interesting features on I low so you
have a direct access to the O's memory
so it means that if you can open access
an idle you can reach with a DMA the
Aust
memory we come back to later on g-spot
this year it was being the Euro of the
BMC there is a lot of presentation
around BMC some people that published
during blackhat so there is a guy from
immunities that introduced a lot of
children are between BMC from Dell from
Drac also from HP ILO ourself and the
people from Eclipse terms that also
present some stuff and the cyber micro
BMC there is also the our stuff so
that's a publish in the beginning of the
year and in the middle of the years
about all we can compromise the web
server you know we can compromise also
stream where as a previous research that
we publish and allow us to make a good
to detect a good reliability one of them
is a bypass of the authentication on the
web servers and the other one was very
interesting is a remote command
execution which allow us to have a
direct access to the O's memory with a
DMR access
the last part of the previous research
it's all weekend back doors I love for
film where and now you can add the
militia stream wherein I love for and be
persistent and add some fish sauce to
either so all this stuff has been
already presented so feel free to be
back on the link that we provide
previously now in terms of the red
teaming so I don't know for you but I'm
come from the pen test field and
environment so as usual if you grab the
password from ipmi you can say okay I
know the default password from your ipmi
so what I can do is just to reboot your
server on the ISO and then booting the
system and this I saw and rich the
associative data that not be encrypted
on the our drive but if you do that you
are not really still see and Minnesota
can catch you easily because yeah reboot
of the system was not really a steal see
now as a notch of the very empty that we
pre published previously what's changed
a deal
change and deal because we can really
have a direct access to the memory so we
can ask more discs right we don't need
to reboot the system we don't need to do
something about the operating system we
just reach the memory through ILO and if
you can backdoor the frame where you can
have a persistent way and it's not
correlate with the operating system so
you can store some malicious code in the
ILO which the operating system without
any interaction of the operating system
so that's why it's really still see and
really discreet if you can with Ram
that's really good
for pen tester because if you can do
that you know that PCI leach for example
although use this kind of attack you can
unlock the windows of Education you can
work across some provide K or some
secret in the memory so you can do a lot
of think if you can redirect is a memory
by the way if you know a PC PC ouch this
tool can be interconnect with our attack
and maybe in the future we can publish
some result about this kind of tools
in the best world what I know
infrastructure or what arena of a
structure should be looked like it's
like that you should have a stop protein
but you should have a dedicated in in a
cable administration Delon you should
have a sexual DMZ and initially the back
end so usually no one nor across can
reach the onion villain but if you can
compromise the aust enriched Idol in 420
is there is a lot of ILO has been
exposing internet it's pretty well but
it's like that people just plug I go and
internet and you can reach it so if you
can break I hope you can reach the
routing system via ZD Emma but if you
already have an access to the I know you
can also have a lateral movement from I
low and on the administration's Ellen so
it means that you can compromise the
other i/o interfaces and if you
compromise also those are either
interfaces you can compromise the O's
ill safe and then you can have a really
interesting lateral movement on the amid
fashion villain that I say if you
compromise I low but let's see maybe you
can compromise us to reach I low so
that's why Fabian maybe make more
information about that hi everyone so as
I just told you we first focused on
compromising the ILO to then compromise
the host and for this specific research
we try to see how to compromise the ILO
drive directly from the from the host so
we can compromise the I love from both
sides so quick recap of the architecture
of an HP server so while there are in
fact two really separated systems in the
server so the the first on the left is
the main CPUs are usually an intel cpu
with x86 architecture running a standard
operating system so here linux kernel
with all these process in new zealand
and on the other side so you have this
arm CPU running real-time operating
system called integrity which is not so
different
on the classical operating systems you
have a kernel and if I use tasks running
in userland so task is the name in fact
for like processes in a normal operating
system and these two system will
communicate through the PCI Express link
so hole which will be said in this part
applies on idle for but can also be
valid for the new version I defy with
some slight changes so to to analyze how
the house was able to communicate with
the ILO we first started to look at the
available tuning the Linux channel has
an offensive driver called HP ILO which
exposes some character devices to
communicate with I low
it requires root permissions on the
operating system to be allowed to talk
with these devices and on the other side
you also have HPE proprietary tools such
as HP and CFG which allows to get and
modify some configuration parameters of
the ILO and finally when you download
the firmware update for Eylau it embeds
a binary which is called flash I love
raw binary which allows from the host to
install a new femur of the on the a low
so it shall be able also to understand
the communication mechanism with the
with the idol if we look at the idler
from a Linux point of view it is simply
PCI device which can be seen with the
RSPCA command and if we look at the main
memory mapping we have values chunks of
memory which has used by these drivers
and which in fact allowed to communicate
with the ILO the communication is done
by channels we have usually between 8
and 24 channels which are set up in
these shared memory areas and these
channels have a simple micro structure
on the other side there is a specific
task which is called chief for channel
interface which is in charge of
receiving the messages from the host and
underling them so
what it does is simply waiting for
messages from the host dispatching the
correct command to a specific command
and ler or sending the command to
another task because you can talk
directly to other other tasks the the
message from at it quite simple you have
a land command ID a destination ID which
tells which task is the final
destination and finally a specific data
for the fod command and the important
thing is that by default there's no
authentication so the host is considered
secure from the from the high/low you
can you can always by default talk to
the ILO from the host about the commands
which are handled by chief we have more
than 100 commands some simple commands
such as getting setting some some
configuration settings the network
configuration of the I load the server
information etc and some are more
dangerous for example you have cumin
cumin 70 which allows to read the ILO
EEPROM containing all the factory
setting of the ILO which includes the
default administrator password usually
Nilo this password is not changed
because it's quite convenient it's
written on the server so you can use it
if you forgot the other passwords there
are commands also to flush a new
firmware so command 15 + 52 and finally
there are also commands to add new
accounts on the ILO including
administrator accounts so to show you
how is it to communicate with ILO from
linacs here is a simple communication in
six lines of Python which use the
command 70 I show I should before to
tribute trial the content of the EEPROM
so you can see that with six lines of
Python you can reach drive the default
administrator password stored in the
indie drama so know that we studied this
commands we focused on the firmware date
command because it was quite interesting
for us it involves complex file format
parsing it has various signature checks
and if we find Aven error
in this indiscriminantly we might be
able to flush a modified firmware with
by bypassing the signature checks and
another advantage is that this the
ephemeral dick process is available both
from the from the host and from the web
server interface of the I hope so
a vulnerability needs would be would be
trigger about by both both sides of the
ILO so let's have a look at the few more
deep process so first when you decide to
flash in your firmware the firmware is
sent to either chief if we if you ask it
by your body host or the webserver if
you ask it by the network interface this
firmware is sent to a new task which is
called fume which is the firmware update
manager this task will perform a first
validation of the file format and the
wall signature of the frame where it
will then ask the integrated kernel to
perform additional signature
verifications and if everything goes
well it will ask the SPI service to
finally write the firmware on the spi
flash so recap of the firmware file
format so the film is basically composed
of three blocks first as a fingerprint
header then some certificates and then
the HPI image blob which is the actual
firmware in the fingerprint part you
simply have the hash tip and the
signature of the wall HPI made via mail
so this is this part which is handled by
the film task so this HP signed Phi
Gamma fingerprint header is passed line
by line by fume and the hash and
signatures elemental verified then the
hash of the HPI image block is computed
and the simulator is checked with the
hot coded HP public key if we look at
the HPI image block h it's in fact
composed of three other blocks there are
the channel and signature components
which are compress
and signed and also a small bootloader
which is not compressed and not signing
it's a an arm assembly step during the
boot process of the I lo first the boot
order executes it has code to load and
verify the key on our signature then the
channel which with load and verify the
user and signature but the boot raider
is never verified in the boot process
[Music]
this is the the the verification of the
signature of the user lanolin images is
done in the canal there is a specific
channel task called GK IMG which exposes
a specific resource to Jerusalem tasks
it also exposes ten common handles and
rows and for example command to allows a
user on task to ask to verify the
signature of the channel and userland
components so it will first decrypt the
embedded signature it will compute a
hash and compared to the decrypted
signatures and finally try to decompress
the the the the image to be sure that
the compression is a key and we also
found out there's a specific handler
also to change the key used to verify
the signature it would be important
later so quick recap about the signature
check in fact signature are checked in
three different steps first steps in the
fume task the wall hpmh signature is
checked the second part in the channel
we in which userland and channel image
is a signature also checked and finally
when the I low will boot there's a kind
of secure boot chain when where channel
and user land signature object but the
bootloader is not signed and the
bootloader is never checked in the inter
boot in the boot process so it means
that with a single userland
vulnerability Nilo
we are able to write a new firmware on
the on the flash by asking the SPI
service then the bootloader can be
modified to allow
loading a channel with an invalid
signature in turn the channel can be
modified to allow the loading of a user
on with an invalid signature and finally
we can insert a background in the
I know user lanlan so we then had a look
at a few mas
handling the fingerprint header and we
quickly find this specific function in
which it passes the ID header and we saw
this with this call to the function red
line in red in which local stack buffer
is passed without any any size so this
is not always a good idea and if we look
in fact at the redline function we can
see that the no check on the size of the
buffer so there's a he retrieve your
buffer overflow in the passing of this
header this means that it could be
exploited we first tried to exploit it
without code execution because it would
be easier so we wanted to just redirect
the exaction flow to simply bypass the
signature value validation and let fume
continue to filter a few more but in
fact we had the problem with the D check
in the canal which will fail so we
couldn't do that so finally we decided
to exploit it with code execution by
your watching a specific shell code the
chance here is that the I lo system does
not have security mitigations of such as
a SLR or no NX so a shell code had been
returned in the framework file which is
loaded at the fixed addressed memory and
we can just jump on it and then the the
shell code content can simply be to talk
to the SPI service to ask him to
actually write the firmware on the flash
or we can simply change the GK image key
resign the firmware with our own key and
let fume continue the process normally
so this vulnerability has been reported
to HP in May it does be it impacts both
I look for on which we did the research
and I love 5 the new version but she has
been available it is both remote and
local code execution because you can
either export it from the web server of
the ILO or from the host running on the
server so well now you can tell that
while there are several vulnerabilities
in I low
dangerous okay I will disable it on my
server so here we disable the I'll on a
1-over server so you can see here that
Idaho is disabled but unfortunately when
you disable a Leo it's only disables the
network part on one side but from the
host i lo is still running you can still
communicate with it so here's the the
code example I showed before to retrieve
the content of the IOA prom so even if
you disable the I lo you can still
communicate with it on on the host you
can still flush back door somewhere and
then well so we already proved that
firmware backdooring was possible it was
the subject of for previous presentation
on i lo we added in fact an end point in
the web server to 200 s to have direct
read and write memory access on the host
and install memory on the back door and
now with the new vulnerability we are
able to do it directly from the host and
even if i lo is disabled so we can
install a persistent host back door in
the ILO hardware and then these back
door will push and memory only back
draws on the host and now comes item 5
the new version of a low and so I will
let Alex to tell you about that so in
the middle of 2017 HP released a new
version of servers which is a generation
10 of HP servers which embeds a new
version of i/o systems what we wanted to
know what where motivation was simply to
assess evolution of the attack surface
it was not to compete when a
vulnerability research campaign was
that's not what we are looking for and
our focus was really on a specific
feature which could be a game changer
from this servers which is a silicon
root of trust but they call it a silicon
would have to ask something like a
secure boot so the idea is to have an
odd rare root of trust with our own
processor as it which will validate the
firmware of the ILO's first and then the
trust will be transmitted through the
next steps so we needed a nutrient to do
here about one unreadable server not too
expensive it has a giant n it is urgent
n so it has a low five and that's on
this adware that we were rocking just
few quick check on the Mo's abroad we
can see there is was some memory on the
below on the top of the picture we have
the flash memory the same as on the ps4
watch ready and in the middle we have a
low a low chip we didn't found
information about this I load ship
specifically from the film where we
discovered it is built around cortex a9
M IRM processor but we don't know what
it's secure boot capabilities is
cryptographic capabilities we don't know
about that
just findings also when we are
researching some marking of the
motherboard we discovered some export or
customs documents which may be linked to
a restaurant corporation Chinese company
that may be responsible for the design
of the ball so we have a new system so a
new humor format we needed to analyze it
the film where is 32 megabyte it's
wrapped into an HP image sign container
exactly like an ILO for it contains a
good block ten thousand bytes at the end
of the frame rail and at the beginning
we have a list of modules there is to
copy of each modules must probably for
fault tolerance when writing in nor
memory each module is described by radar
and is of course sign just to give you a
preview of the reader here for a channel
we have hue important fields at the be
at the very beginning and at the end we
have a magic we have a type which will
indicate what kind of module it is if
it's a Canon user on or one of the tubu
traders we have the CRC's and at the end
of the module we have possibly two
signatures or the module we found only
use one signature okay so know we are we
are able to pass later we are able to
pass to pass sir is the list of all the
modules that are embedded within the
camera
we so there are 10 of them including the
bootblack Aegean so just to know to give
you a preview of the boot chain of the
idea for our system so we have the boot
ROM which is located inside the ESSEC
which will pass the shank to secure
micro boots then to neighbor 9 which in
terms will go to the canal and then to
the user none we don't have any cues if
they have developed this bootloader
secure micro boot and by 9 by themself
or user apart from I don't know I know
their company's SDK of we don't know
about that if you have the information
we would be very interested so no we are
going to try to attack this secure boot
and we will begin by is a very start of
the boot chain which is the boot rom yes
about oh it is rocking is that the boot
rom will need the DDR memory and map the
world firmware into the memory at the
top of the memory at the eye addresses
it will then first verify the signature
from SMB 0 header so one at the very top
of the memory which will check the eight
first eight thousand bytes then it will
verify the signature from smb1
header and if everything is good it
which we go so armed with that vector
and then start the execution of the
first stage boot for secure microbots
its own your guess about the behavior of
the bottom now as a secure micro boot is
a minimalistic first stage boot Raider
it does very few things UCP
installations it seems to access some
kind of persistent memory with some
configuration information yes speaking
about the processor it's an RM but it
doesn't use at resin at all some
interesting point is that this first
stage bootloader actually exposed a
quite large ipi something like sixty
functions and it will then load next the
second stage would further which is knee
benign in most in the nominal behavior
when secure mark boot load the next
stage booted or it is past configuring
what we have called a configuration it's
like a job description job description
you wear in memory you have to look for
the next module to load
what kind of modules you are looking for
where to wear my movie you will load the
reader the boom boom is the main body
the actual code of the next modules some
security parameters we will come back to
this point later and yeah to find the
module in memory it applies a quite
basic algorithm matching the start and
end magic with the module types speaking
about the types passing the array is
quite simple frier in this canal
configuration we have three possible
types that can be loaded a B and C and
from human we can have the description
of these different types another in very
important field of this current
configuration is a security parameter
actually two bits are more important and
users the first one tells you if the
boot will be verbal or not and the
second one will tell you if you use or
not at work with purposes though this
creep repressor is only used to to
compute the ash of of the module for
integrity so oh all the module was a
cryptographic integrity of the module is
verified or the signature is verified so
as we saw before up to two signatures
can be used and stirred insider the
signature is the basic error say one
using a 4096 bit key and at the end of
secure MicroBot we found a flat array of
binghams which actually contains the
exponents that will be used followed by
six public use so if you remember from
the ADA we say there is two index
actually this index will tell you which
public keys you will select from euro
store and to verify to decrypt the
signature that are embedded in the
reader and then to verify the ash that
of the actual module next modules body
so that's how it works something
interesting we discovered while we were
seeing is that when it computes the
integrity of the next module some fields
of
are not covered by by Seleucia she's
also integral the ash computation so
there's four bytes that are emitted from
the adder so it was quite strange we are
a bit suspicious around it and we were
looking for and actually these two index
fields are not covered by the integrity
kind of strange but actually we didn't
found some way to exploit these things
one hypothesis could be that it is used
for post of cross signatures by
different entities but you know just for
fun we'll just keep in mind that the
index fields some looks suspicious so
now we progress into the boot chain we
have bootrom as ready to secure micro
boots secure micro boot has studied near
benign and then the benign will try to
load the kernel actually to do that it
will reuse the primitives exposed by the
second marker boot API it will ask which
we call a function which is something
like IDL open and secure Mac robot will
verify the signature of the canal load
it into memory and if everything is good
nearby nine will jumps onto the color no
we are in the kernel next step actually
I love 5-channel as almost the exact
same code as the one that this present
is secure microbots
but almost the canal an interest one
single public key which is called the
legacy key it actually is the same as
the same as the one that is used to sign
I love four components so back into a
low five channel we have a function that
we have called Lots neutrons that will
try to load one of the two other two
signatures from zero and actually inside
this function there is kind of a broken
logic first it will try to load the
first signature from index 1 and it can
fail and on the and the next it will try
to load the second second signature and
load legacy
the second resiliency key from the
second index and or guess is that at
this time the developer made the
hypothesis that even if even if the load
legacy key failed for index - it means
that the first one I succeeded find x1
but which is actually false so what
happened
what can happen is actually the load a
Jesse key will fail for index 1 and
index 2 and the two signature fields
will be left untouched and at the end
the kernel will compress as a ash value
it has computed with the module tested
in memory with an untouched
cygwin field and actually this time it
is quite exploitable yes
so all that we have to do to exploit
this is we will extract the fume rare
and yet I know 5 user on the compressed
insert whatever whatever we want
backdoor into it and then we compress it
then we will set index 1 and 2 to rock
values update all the sizes and CRC's to
be correct and we will simply compute
the cryptographic hash of on you by door
userland and we will update cygwin
filled with ash value farmer Bob just
that just like that and then we can use
the vulnerabilities that have been
planted to you for example to purge the
fume where and it should Rock actually
not quite yet we will see why
actually we screw up a little
and all that we got at the time was
bling humans are broad the server wasn't
started at all but I know services seems
up like SSH or web server but seems
quite broken or unresponsive we were uh
not able to flash anymore a new VMware
so we are kind of stuck we needed more
information when we are doing researches
on I loafer we had some solid put from
our micro servers so that's what we did
we started probing some pins on top of a
low 5 system to see if we can get the
same as I had put so we got to logic
analyzer and studied probing on the
mossad app free for us there is two
slots or four pins which provide a
celluloid put one of them seems to be
for us a power management controller the
other one for
I do systems so yeah we started plugging
into this I would put also to plug into
the flash to write specific bits at some
points just an example of the output of
the program management controller but
more importantly we get the logs of the
ILO systems and at the end of it we we
found that there was some kind of error
in the loading of the task of the Ilia
file system and using that information
we were able to see where or whether our
mistakes actually actually we screw up
when we were back during the new user
none we add some bad decompression cards
that we are the reversed back when we
are doing some River some researches on
a low flow systems and you can use a
very light error in the elf processor of
the interview system so the system is
Alfe running but not enough and that's
why the kernel does not pop some
recovery FTP server so we fixed
everything we flipped one byte directly
writing the new flash memory to frost
the kernel to enter into recovery mode
partially did image him where to restore
same States and then we fixed for the
compression algorithm which by a TN z 27
and I also at the end we discovered that
we doesn't need to recompress or use
backdoor dues around because we have
enough room in the film where to leave
it and compress so now we'll show you a
demo where we have a backdoor femur if
we can switch to the video okay so here
the the demo you have the celluloid put
the host running Linux and finally the
attacker laptop so if we first check the
ssh banner of the ILO everything is
normal for now and now on the line x
house we will try to flash a backdoor
somewhere here it embeds the exploit for
the previous will never reach in fume
and we also modified it to change it to
indexes to bypass the secure boot so if
we first try to flash it well it tells
us that it can flash it because the
version is lower than the version
currently installed but well if we ask
him kindly it will allow us to to do the
journal grade so know the actual
flashing starts this part has been
accelerated a bit because it takes a
long time to send a film where and to an
effectively flash it on the on the spi
flash and well when the flash is indeed
the ailu reboots and we can see that
while everything goes well the I lo
finally gets its IP address and now if
we check the ssh banner we can see that
we successfully changed the the banner
and there's compromise the ILO firmware
thank you thank you
so at this point we're able to push
whatever use the known we want inserting
backdoor into a web server component ssh
components or whatever we want we will
put it this to HP e at the beginning of
september and they release quite quickly
fix i lo v 1.37 then i meet a local
bypass of security restriction in few
more updates but with this fix we have
some big insanity actually because we
reversed all they did the fix so of
course the canal logic is fixed so the
the logic error is corrected but first
stage second stage would color a still
totally unchanged and in the we have
actually legitimately sign venerable
channels and what an attacker could do
is to build some kind of Frankenstein
firmware using our venerable channel and
new new modules new user on bio modules
so we don't know oh the under or if
they're able to endure the revocation of
this venerable
sign kernels so it's a big issue we have
also tried to downgrade a firmware to to
update to a fixed version of the
fumarole
I load SATA 7 and that no greater to a
venerable Russian and it rocks perfectly
so it's a big issue because we still
have a nature an attack vector at a
physical attack vector like typical
sebacean attack but also logical in
a new vulnerability is found in the web
server or anything it could and we can
access the SPH spi flash memory sorry we
can do the exact same thing so to
conclude we about thrust for our system
we have a very large attack surface both
on the administration and on the
production side like Fabian demonstrated
we can attack i lo from just as well and
that's very important
and patch system are going to get right
already it's a dreamland for lateral
movements network is relation is a
must-have but as we saw it's not
sufficient this asset should really be
monitored
and up-to-date keep up to date very
carefree some very simple hardening can
be done we can you can disable I play me
over on you can also disable XML data
output which will will use some
information Nick speaking about I lo v
no not specifically some good news and
new features I cannae over run is
disabled by default which is great
there's new HTML console and lots of new
features are like backup things like
that but at the cross the system design
is but it's basically the same eyes I
love raw it is still as the integrity of
rating systems but there are still no
are during the first scenes s like we
should expect seller onyx in a that and
of course we can expect more
vulnerabilities in this codes the
silicon root of trust secure boot is
clearly a step in the right direction it
should have been a killer features to
prevent long-term compromise of this
asset long-term compromise of the I love
5 p.m. where but actually right now it
seems like totally enjoyed by Rick
design and a flawed implementation and
of course there is this big questions
about the possibility to replicate the
signatures of the neural channel we've
asked the questions to HP many times
that do you never receive some answer on
this point
yeah we just before closing this talk
we'd like to thank so HP pay such a team
because we are doing these responses we
have built some kind of good working
relationship with them we appreciate
that - thank you or cell or teams
just give her a couple of days and we
will publish the script and tools we
have used for history on a github
project for this I know researches and
just be focusing and so we'd like to
share some quotes we found why we're
asking the code something we always
appreciate the regressors and also we
would like to say hi to handy which is
he was here and yes thank you very much
for your attentions and if you have any
questions no or during the conference do
not hesitate to come to us thank you
[Music]