[Music]
[Applause]
so uh hi everybody everyone my name is
Sergei and my co-presenter yeah couldn't
come so I'll try to do everything alone
and so I I work for a company called
shape security where we try to detect
automation on what we try to detect an
unwanted automation on web traffic and
in the air works for Facebook is a
research scientist security research
scientist and it's kind of I will be
talking about mix of both worlds where
we try to it's kind of mix of detecting
automation and fighting fraud at
Facebook
so yeah the topic is about links and
cloaking but before we get to cloaking
we'll figure out like what is cloaking
and why how did we get there so people
like to share content for like various
reasons people use Twitter Google Ads
Facebook posts Instagram posts posts and
there is people that are interested in
showing the content to as much people as
possible so somehow most of us have
trust in links posted on social media
and like content providers like for
example I know we don't really know
what's behind that a to green concert
link like we do you don't know what
would happen but somehow we trust that
Facebook or whoever wherever I took that
screenshot from probably half at
Facebook like they verified that link
will take to a to green concert website
or like here we say bility pass silky do
it and we trust it so and yeah it's kind
of true because content providers
providers
have a defined way of figuring out
what's behind that link before they
allow you to publish it like for example
I tried to make a Google post and I
mentioned zero nights and I put the zero
nights that are you URL there and right
away I got this image and a little text
box and yeah like for example the same
Facebook has a defined way of of pulling
out this information from this website
before it's being posted before it's
being published like they warned you
that your website is going to be visited
by one of these three user agents
Facebook text external heat or face face
but or whatever and they even give you
the list of IP addresses from where this
bot might visit you and it's like three
hundred twenty IP addresses that you can
whitelist if for example your post is is
not published yet or like I don't know
you are not expecting BOTS and you or
you want to whitelist that particular
bot and yeah are there any restrictions
of course there there are there are some
restrictions are like worldwide like for
example on Facebook or that's Adsense
screenshot from Adsense like you cannot
advertise adult content or like for
example I don't know like alcohol is a I
have a note here that for example you
can advertise alcohol anywhere except
maybe Afghanistan Brunei Bangladesh
Egypt Gambia Kuwait Libya and so on like
yeah some content is restricted
partially some content is restricted
everywhere and but there is still people
that probably want to share that
restricted content and make money out of
it and what they do they use cloaking
and what is cloaking cloaking is a like
a website or a service that serves one
content to BOTS and another content real
users like this is an example we took I
made this screenshot this night it's
some like ad ad post on Facebook about
something and if you visit it
the mobile device it gets you to it
redirects YouTube like empty Facebook
marketplace page and if you visit it
from a real browser and as a real user
it actually like redirects you to this
article I don't know example of cloaking
for example like legitimate ways
legitimate cloaking some websites for
example can serve totally different
content to mobile devices than to the
desktop browsers
that's not cloaking that's just that's
convenience we'll be discussing
malicious ways of circumventing
moderation at content providers so yeah
what's cloaking in 2007 I I found this
description of cloaking from like from
an article from 2007 and basically
they're saying cloaking is a system that
has they basically have shared list of
IP addresses from which they expect bots
to visit their web sites and they
exchange that shared database among each
other and serve one content if user
agent is from list of these database is
from this database and another content
to everybody else and in 2018 like this
is a list of features of one of the
cloaking services they offer a lot of
things like you can filter by by
anything like by geolocation by
fingerprints of operating system or
fingerprints of browser or like
fingerprints of a user you can like I
don't remember like of course IPS and
essence and residential versus mobile
providers that you can do everything
with with the traffic you can filter on
on Twitter with everything and let's go
to classification of cloaking systems
there are but you can divide them into
three parts like naive stalkers and
intermediate and like really advanced
so naive one just basically just request
that user-agent sends to this cloaking
service and it checks if IP address is
in the list of bots or like user agent
matches but just like officially how
officially facebook tells you how they
are going to visit your website that's
enough to verify if it's about a little
intermediate a little more sophisticated
cloaking services will also maybe verify
that HTTP header order in the request
matches header order of the advertised
browser like if you know for Chrome for
example is this order header and it
doesn't match you can probably think
assume that this whoever is visiting
your website is not really honest and
it's it's not really the browser that it
advertises it is so maybe you can make
decisions and block on that or you can
use like TCP stack fingerprints or like
client hello like supported ciphers from
the request and make assumptions based
on that but that's it
there is no like client-side information
collection and the advanced one is where
it's basically combination of whatever I
just described plus they load the
JavaScript into your browsing context
and they try to survey as much as they
can
like for example try to access what
information is exposed through WebGL API
or through canvas API or like what fonts
are installed on your system and based
on that they like build a fingerprint
and make decision based on that and
here's a like an example of knife system
they have like simple dashboard or you
can you can you have campaigns and
everything and I can just click a track
how many clicks are there how many like
how many visitors or organic visitors
you have how many identified bots
visited the link that you published and
the set up is something like that you
all you need to do is just a register a
domain name and then buy a VPS and
configure it and then specify two URLs
and pass it to this cloaking service
provider
a good URL and the bad URL and and and
they generate a like a PHP file
specifically for lamp stack and they
give it to you and what happens later is
when request comes in basically it goes
to your VPS and then your VPS run this
runs this PHP from which extracts some
information from the request from the
browser and it sends to this API
cloaking API and API makes decision and
gives you back either good link or bad
link and you forward that link to the
user agent and basically this is the PHP
that they give give you they read hang
on what they do they just extract the IP
address and maybe some like headers and
and then reply back with with good or
bad link and it's really like cheap it
starts it sits this is what you get for
$150 a month oh yeah this is the payload
that comes back from that API and is
forwarded to the is actually executed on
in the browser it's basically a
JavaScript tag with one line in it
window that open open and like you good
or bad URL and I was moved to advanced
cloaking system it's much more expensive
or not much more but like it's more
expensive and for example they are
pretty sophisticated in the dread
probably you cannot read it but like in
there in the red box they uh it's not
very interesting they say that use HTTPS
Everywhere to avoid mixed content errors
in the browser because they actually
they don't read errect you to a bad page
but the page at the top URL stays the
same and they load bad or good content
in an iframe which is like fullscreen
iframe so through that they they avoid
changing the URL in the address bar from
good to bad or from bad to good
and yeah that's why you need to use
HTTPS Everywhere to avoid mixed content
warnings but there's an interesting
thing there saying that for example like
if they say that please be aware that
Facebook may use its mobile application
to track the visitors very visitor visit
already rekt chain so they know that
like if you post something on Facebook
they are going to use something a mobile
application emulator or mobile device
emulator with Facebook application
running in it and it's some some extra
information for us yeah you probably
can't see but in initial configurations
the campaign setup page you can define
what to filter on like maybe I can see
it on my screen yeah it's like for
example they say block alt or proxies
proxies or allow only residential I
Internet service providers or like apply
some global referrer filters because
some bots known to put a specific refer
in the in HTTP request referer header
value in HTTP request and then once you
set up those basic things like
everything is ready and they let you set
up it's as PHP mode cloaker or
JavaScript mode cloaker or hybrid
approach the PHP one is the one from the
net naive cloaker example so they
extract some information from initial
request and make some decision make some
decisions based on that and JavaScript
one is they load the JavaScript into the
victim's browser or like whoever browser
it is and they collect some fingerprint
and send it back and you can use both
things to make decisions oops
oh yeah it's it's kind of similar that
once you set up everything they give you
an archive with PHP file and some
JavaScript file and it's really easy to
set up and it's it's also not very
readable but basically what happens when
browser first
for the page a cloaked URL you get some
it runs some PHP code on the server and
based on that it generates some HTML
file with javascript file and the
JavaScript JavaScript that goes to your
browser then they request the
fingerprinting JavaScript from actual
cloaking service then they run it make
some decision based on that post it to
the cloaked website and cloak website
forwards it to the cloaking service and
then cloaking service makes decision and
replies with this or that like basically
this is the payload that eventually
comes back with good or bad URL it
doesn't really matter and pay attention
to this lower function wind function all
they do they inject they probably
document.write it so no they did assign
an iframe tag to to the body of the
parent document so basically your URL
never changes but the content is a
full-screen iframe with either good or
bad contact content based on if a boat
was I then if user agent was identified
as a bot or a real visitor and it's just
couple of screenshots from their
underground forums where they clearly
know that for for example Facebook or
YouTube just using simple PHP based
cloaker
is not going to work like people suggest
I used for a use Pro cloaker for
Facebook or YouTube because while
Facebook or YouTube says that here we're
going to use this official crawler
that's going to go visit fetch the
content from your website obviously they
are gonna verify whatever they fetched
later with something some other crawler
that's more user more real user like and
they are not going to advertised well
when when is the second crawler going to
visit your website or how many times or
what's user agent going to be
anecdotally
there's fraud among these cloaking guys
as well
one of these screenshots is the real
cloaking cloaking services website and
another one is a clone of it which just
collects information and steals clients
from the real one and the only
difference is one is much more expensive
than the other and then this is a
screenshot from their forum where
somebody warns people that oh there's
this website just clogged it's calm and
there is a fake just cloak it's with
like s in the end which advertises to be
also a cloaking website but it's
actually they're stealing credentials of
that first website users and like
misleading them and I don't know
stealing all kinds of information and
probably credit cards and things like
that
so there's a fraud in there as well some
of their presentations advertise these
numbers and as far as I know they are
pretty realistic and look at the
difference like survival time for a
cloaking URL that's like published in as
an ad on Google survives for only two
weeks while on Facebook they promise it
to survive for three months I guess it's
because Google is in is in better
position to have crawlers that are more
human-like and like it's hard to detect
that this crawler is not a real user but
it's like a crawler because I don't know
they have chrome and they have probably
Fork of chromium that is really like
you're a real user here's some thoughts
like Public Information nothing
internal from how companies try to
address these problems they will get
ready wrecked chain if cloaker is dumb
enough to dumb enough to redirect you
like publish one link on the ad or in
the
say Facebook post and then once you
click it it read it read reacts you
either here or there they observe the
ready right chain and just may make
decision based on that
and like in which cases it won't work
for example the iframe that advanced the
cloaker that used i frame and so
top-level navigation never changed it's
gonna bypass this kind of detection or
another thing is the content analysis
itself so you compare landing page for
crawler and the official crawler and
unofficial crawler that tries to look
like a real user and like I don't know
you can compare it just one to one or
you can compare the HTML structure and
you throw away the text nodes from the
node from the dome or like you can get
rid of the images and just look at the
text or you can actually compare text
nodes so there are many approaches but
it's prone to false positives like for
example because server can actually send
different context based on some
information like geolocation or device
type and you can figure out is this like
cloaking happening or the content is
different because of legitimate changes
or like if it's an official crawler you
might not send ads to the page so it
might look completely different and yeah
unlike big-scale if you try to automate
things like this you might have lots of
false positives
another approach they may take like
Facebook for example right they control
the entire page they control the frames
where ads are showed so what's the UPS
them from observing what happens to the
real user just run script that monitors
what where the iframe content was loaded
from they can do that but it kind of not
not really what a good thing to do
because it deals with privacy because
they are gonna know what
or what is a particular you what
particular user is interested in like
maybe I don't want to Facebook to know
what ads I'm clicking it because it
reveals my private information so in
fact they don't do that and they don't
even share a day also for the same
reason they don't share that information
with other networks because it's a
leakage they can try to get rid of some
PII some some some information that
people might think it's a privacy
related like for example they might
throw away the IP address that clicked
in an ad on a Facebook page but then
it's a lots of information like without
IP address it's not really helpful to to
analyze that there's some research
around there are many for example there
is a white paper by by these guys and
they discuss algorithms on content
comparison for example one of them is
called like sim link they try to find
similarities between the pages without
actually which is pretty smart like they
hash the structure of the Dome they
throw away some content they don't throw
away some other content they throw away
images for example they throw away
iframes
and it's for example that one is fast or
there is another comparison algorithm
that is slow but more reliable and like
it ignores the private information but
all these algorithms are based on an
assumption that your algorithm gets good
of a both bad page and the good page and
then they compare it but what if you
just don't get the good page at all
sorry bad page because cloaker
identified you as a clue as a crawler
and never served you with with the bad
content at all so it's kind of like
tricky yeah and it comes to the how good
are you at emulating a real user with
your fake crawler with your crawler and
yeah we will just discuss several
approaches for example one can just
replay a real traffic that they
collected from real users at a scale
it's not really that easy actually
because even not very advanced cloakers
are putting some timestamps for example
in in a JavaScript that runs in your
browser and collects fingerprints and
you have to figure out automatically
like you have to like if you are gonna
do that at scale you have to figure out
where is this timestamp you have to
regenerate regenerate the timestamp or
anything else that's in the that's a
variable in the request and you have to
change it and like it's not doesn't
really work well or if you are replaying
the same payload and you sent the same
fingerprint for everything or not the
same like I have let's say you have 10
samples of payloads that go back to this
cloaking service it's also not very
smart because their fingerprint is
collecting your graphics card
information from WebGL API or something
canvas based or like fonts your going to
send only ten possible payloads and
whatever these guys try to like do some
analysis they can easily figure out that
this is a bot plus you're still gonna
run in some docker container you're
still gonna run say headless Chrome in a
docker container so you're tcp/ip stack
is gonna be the same all the time your
TLS is going to be the same because
Chrome's have are gonna advertise the
same like ciphers a headless Chrome is
gonna advertise the same same cipher so
there's two there are two ways to detect
you you can oh yeah actually we were
talking about just replaying the traffic
what else you can do we can just take a
headless Chrome and automate it and
running around it in a docker container
and like emulate real user if you don't
modify the chrome chrome it's
like there are things that we'll review
that this is automation controlled
browser right away for example navigator
web driver property or navigator object
is going to be true because I
implemented it in chrome and in Safari
and some other people implement it in
Firefox but these days like all modern
browsers will actually tell you that
they are automation controlled unless
you modify the source code and recompile
it and hide this property it's not
really easy to hide the fact that the
user agent is automation controlled or
like user events depends how you synth
synthesized the user user events because
if you create a user event from
JavaScript all the events are going to
have this is trusted property set to
false so you have to be careful there
and all you can do you can just modify
the source code but it's really hard to
maintain the modify the user agent
source code unless you are the vendor to
you actually the manufacturer of the
user agent like Chrome or Safari and
yeah it's not really easy as well as
well and for mobile device emulators
sure it's cool but say it's hard to fake
sensor data because every real mobile
device user is going to have some
sensors data sensor data that it's like
it's not the same and if you're going to
replay it for example or fake it or
January train the random numbers for
sensor data it's all identifiable
because it's gonna stand out from the
real sensor data that they they're gonna
get there's a startup or company called
Illuminati or Illuminati I don't
remember they offer to use real people's
devices to proxy traffic through it and
the advantages your visitors are having
real residential IP addresses but it's
totally identifiable because they are
all going to have first you can only use
it for mobile traffic second they are
going to have the same thing or similar
fingerprint because
what the startup is doing here that they
just create an instance of webview and
they use that web webview for like
proxying traffic and those web views are
gonna be the same yeah just a summary so
so cloaking is to a cat and mouse game
and kind of infinite cat and mouse game
and it's always there's always be a
conflict of interest between two sides
like advertisers or like content
providers and people that want to make
money by delivering that content to
certain groups of people and yeah one
side has more money than another and as
long as basically yeah they make more
money by spending some money on cloaking
it's gonna exist unless you make it
financially it shouldn't make sense to
spend any money on cloaking and the
algorithms are good like scientific or
say scientific approach is good but they
all rely on the fact that you can get
both good content and bad content and
you can compare it after that but it's
not true actually in many cases they
assume they are getting both but they
are getting for it so they are getting
fooled by they're being fooled by
cloaking services and you always you
might get some good content but it's not
really good content because they try to
fool a a crawler and basically yeah it's
not that easy and and yeah since I work
for a company that tries to identify
automation unwanted automation of the
website I can say that this advanced
cloaking cloaking providers are not
really too much different from what we
do except they know who they are looking
for they are looking for particular like
BOTS by a big guys like Google Facebook
and Twitter and in my case were trying
to find any BOTS and
they are kind of in better position
better position and they are doing
really good and I think it's going to be
a bigger problem in the future and I
guess that's my life's last slide that's
it
[Music]