(calm music)
(applause)
- Hi everyone,
So, not the immediate,
post lunch period,
but we're gonna
talk a little bit
about something that's
near and dear to my heart
for reasons that I hope will
become a little bit apparent
called threat
indications and warning,
so first, a little bit about me.
I am a network defender
first and foremost,
so I got my start in this
field in the U.S. Navy.
Did that for five, six
yearsish, or whatever,
and then went over to Los
Alamos National Laboratory,
where I ran the
incidence response team,
so very much U.S.
government focused.
However, now I kinda
do the same thing,
but more or less
on my own terms,
so I'm working for a
company called Dragos,
which may be somewhat
involved with CTI summit.
Might have a hand in
running said organization,
so he's my boss, and
I have to be nice
and maybe say something
nice about the company
at some point, but anyway,
that's kinda where I am now,
but like I said before, my
background was a naval officer,
and he's like oh,
you're at a CTI summit.
You musta been a naval
intelligence officer.
Well, you know, not
really, actually,
so this is always, kind
of, what I've thought
about intelligence analysts.
Not to say that
that's a bad thing,
but that really wasn't
me 'cause if you look
at how the Navy
organizes things,
is that there's this overall
information dominance,
I don't know what the
hell they call it now,
anymore, actually,
community that includes
the weather guessers, the
information professionals,
and whatnot, but it also
includes intelligence
and then in a
separate career track,
that I was in, called
information warfare,
and the reason why
that's important
is because that
community really dealt
with technical information
to try and provide
to the war fighter, to drop
a sort of DoDish buzzword
immediately, as much
actionable information
as immediate as possible,
with just enough information
to make it actionable, so really
trying to be time sensitive
and relevant, and that's
why I'm here today,
because what we're
going to talk about is,
from an agenda perspective,
just what's the role
and purpose of intelligence.
That might seem like a
nonstarter in this crowd,
that well, everyone
knows what the purpose
of intelligence is.
Well, it's good to remind
ourselves what that actually is
to make sure that
we don't wander
into self-licking
ice cream cone land,
but then in looking
at that, let's examine
exactly what intelligence
operations are
in the state of the
now, how that's applied
in a CTI sense, and then
what that leaves out
or what that might
leave to be desired
as result, and then
go into an explanation
of what I feel to encompass
indications and warning
within a cyber defense
set or mindset,
and then we'll look at a
couple of recentish examples
for how this might be
applied in practice
and some recommendations,
so first off,
why intelligence, so everyone
makes fun of this quote,
but this little bit of
Heideggerian wisdom here
that Mr. Rumsfeld
issued once upon a time
really does kinda get at
the crux of the problem,
like okay, we know the
things that we know.
Fine, that's all well and good.
It's nice to try and
fill in those gaps
that we're already aware of,
but then in a longer term
perspective, like, well
what are the things
that we're not even aware of
yet that are on the horizon?
What are the items that are
gonna be developing over time
that we need to make sure
that we either develop
collections for or gain
some sort of visibility on.
Now, that's all well and good,
sort of in a frictionless,
spinning in the void,
vacuum sense or whatever,
but in order for
that to be grounded,
intelligence to be meaningful,
intelligence to
be anything other
than just its own, little,
self-massaging exercise,
you could swap
about another M word
for that if you
have a dirty mind,
is to make sure that you're
supporting operations.
Intelligence that
just kind of exists
for its own sake, what
does that actually do?
What does that actually provide?
Like, it might provide an
interesting book report,
and this is where I
make fun of the guys
at, like, the Office
of Naval Intelligence,
like oh, that's a cool report.
That would have
been great to see
about a year ago when I was
actually dealing with this.
It's still good stuff,
but identify who is it
that I'm trying to support
from the strategic level,
the people who are sitting
in the really high offices
with the fancy suits
or fancier suits
or lots of strips on
their things and whatnot,
or is it the people who are
really low down in the weeds,
that actually need
to act on something
within the next hour, maybe
even the next 15 minutes,
and how am I producing a product
that's relevant to the
needs of the audience?
This was brought up earlier
in Amy's discussion.
Know who you're communicating to
and why you're
communicating to them.
What is my customer, and
what are their needs?
And so as a result of that,
at each of these levels
of support that you're providing
to different types of operations
or different consumers,
intelligence, to be
relevant, has to be,
well, relevant is one
of the items up here,
but in addition to that, it
needs to be timely for the scope
and what you're trying to
discuss and accurate, of course.
If you start getting
crap information,
you're not gonna
have a very good
or happy consumer for very long,
and applying these to the
different types of intelligence,
so okay, strategic intelligence,
and I think Mitch just
did a good example
of talking about that
in the previous talk.
Let's get an idea for what's
going on in the big picture.
What's happening
out in the world?
How does this apply to my,
thinking of what I need
to plan out for the next year.
Maybe even five years from now,
what's the overall
thrust of events?
Well, then at a slightly
lower level to events
in question, you get
the operational level.
How are we gonna organize
my day-to-day battle rhythm,
my cycles of events, my
actions on a daily basis?
What sort of things do
I need to look out for?
What are the adversary's
tendencies, behaviors?
How are these emerging?
And then, at the lowest level,
and most immediate level,
at a tactical level,
this incident is
happening right now.
This event happened
five minutes ago.
In order to try to get
to those magic numbers
of minimizing
adversary dwell time
or getting your best
possible time to detection
for a malicious event, how
am I providing information
that's going to enable
a defender to respond
in the most immediate
sense in order
to disadvantage the adversary
and advantage the defense
to have, you know, be able
to win that engagement?
So, I think this slide comes
up in the SANS CTI class.
I've never taken this class.
Rob likes this one a lot too,
so I'll throw it in here,
but it's important to note
because it defines a general,
sort of funnel that we're
used to between raw data
and then magic
happens or whatever,
and at the very end
of this pipeline,
the sausage is made, and
you have intelligence.
When looked at from a cyber
threat intelligence perspective,
though, what are we really
focused on, typically?
We do a really
good job with data.
Swap out data for IOCs,
and it's an argument,
like, IOC is actually
an enriched data set,
but not the way it's used.
We'll talk about
that in a second,
and then we talk about the
pretty intelligence reports
that come at the end.
What you'll notice,
though, is that phase one,
collect all the
things, phase two,
phase three, produce intel.
Something happens
in the middle there,
and maybe we're missing
something as a result,
so from an intelligence
reporting standpoint,
I think everyone in the
room is familiar with it
because we see these often
in marketing attempt.
I'm sorry, public
intelligence reports,
for examples of
campaigns or intrusions,
and I do intelligence
work right now,
and I produce some
of these reports,
so I'm happy to call myself
out for this as well,
but it is what it is, but
malware analysis reports
and other sorts of
items that are produced
after an event takes
place and following
a not insignificant period
of analysis and production,
so we have lots of
headline examples,
and I'll let everyone guess
which one is the bad example
of this group of four,
but in looking at this,
like this seminal, APT
1 report, for example.
That was released
after years of work
into an intrusion set
and ongoing activity,
so it was, you know,
defined the field,
for lack of another
way of looking at it,
and so you can't
discount it at all,
and I don't want to in
any way, shape, or form,
but in the sense
of what it provided
for defenders, it
provided a great overview
of past observed activity, some
of which was still ongoing,
but for those who
had been impacted
and were out Mandiant customers
during that engagement,
they were kind of
left out in the breeze
and had to make do on their own.
Okay, so what about something
a little more immediate?
Well, we're all familiar with
indicators of compromise.
I think every time someone
says indicators of compromise,
Kevin Mandia makes $5.
As a result of
that, we have this,
in an ideal sense,
you want continuous,
contextual observations,
but unfortunately,
in practice, and I'm sure
we're all used to this,
a lotta times when
we see an IOC,
it's something that's
just sort of out there
on its own, absent
the sort of context
that we need to make
it ideally actionable.
While its purpose
is to facilitate
speedy information
exchange, which is good.
Timeliness could
be highly variable,
and that accuracy component
that we talked about
can be less than ideal,
depending upon your sources,
so as designed, IOCs started
out as a really great idea,
like, let's try and
provide an enriched means
of detecting and
communicating threat data,
organized around
technical observables.
Like, we can do a whole
'nother talk about this,
which we don't have
time for right now,
but there's something
to be said for that
as a concept, and we probably
never really explored it
as deeply as we
could or should have
because in practice, this
is what IOCs look like.
This is the Grizzly
Steppe report,
the first one, which everyone
likes to kick while it's down,
and as you can see here, the
enrichment is completely blank
for most of these items as well,
so you just get a bunch of
IPs, domains, hashes, etc.
Like, what do these do?
I dunno.
Maybe we should block 'em.
Well, the problem
is that as you start
getting this generation
of indicators
that are then passed
and forwarded around,
it's like well,
we wanna make sure
that we're acting on these
as timely as possible,
so let's automate our
sharing and maybe automate
our blocking response actions.
That sounds great, except
you wanna block Google,
that's how you block
Google, and I'm not saying
that that's any one
particular organization
is better or worse than another.
I've made mistakes
on this as well.
Like, oh, this IP popped up.
Like, oh, it actually hosts,
like 30,000 other sites,
including Catherine's
blog on cats
and Jim's stationary
business and whatnot
as well as this malicious stuff,
so there's a lot of scope to
have errors take place here
that generate both
false positives
and also give the sense of
a false sense of security
that oh, I blocked
all these hashes.
I'm good on that, Lee.
I recompiled this in a
different environment,
and then you used UPX on it.
Bye bye hash matching.
So, from an intelligence
coverage perspective,
IOCs are nice in that they
allow for quick alerting
and sharing but at
the cost of accuracy
and context in a lotta times.
I have a hash that's out there.
What does it mean?
Reports are thorough by design.
Hopefully they're
thorough by design,
but they're historical in nature
and typically arrive long
after a campaign is complete,
so it's nice to get a
perspective on what's going on
within the environment, how
these threats have evolved
over time, but if I'm
trying to use that
as the basis of my
day-to-day operations,
my day-to-day defense
of the network,
it's not gonna do me
all that much good,
so our current gap
is in the middle,
hence the title of this talk.
It was not simply
randomly chosen,
so there's this
information step,
where we've enriched
data to some degree,
but we haven't gone all the way
into producing a full-scale
intelligence report.
In this sense, we
really want to make sure
that we're supporting
operations.
In that sense, daily operations
needs intelligence feedback.
This is a very important
aspect of how we can insure
that we're not just
constantly reacting,
but trying to stay
on that bleeding edge
as attackers evolve and
adapt their capabilities
and specific instantiations
of behaviors over time.
Raw indicators are insufficient
for doing this, though,
and finalized intelligence
is not timely.
We need something
that bridges the gap
between the two, providing
enriched information
with an indication and
warning of threat behavior
that can be both informative
and time sensitive
within certain parameters.
That's a lotta words, isn't it?
Where does this even come from?
Well, like I said
before, I was a crypie
in the military sense and
not an intelligence officer
in the classic sense, and
in my past background,
indications and warning
relates to, most often,
time sensitive signals,
intelligence information
passed to tactical
units, out forward
in order to allow them to
react in near real time
to events as they unfold,
sharing just enough information
that allows for a
ship at sea, aircraft,
tactical unit on
the ground, etc.
to know that hey, this
radar at this bearing
in this range also is
associated to this platform,
and it's doing this
right here and now.
That doesn't say,
like, well, I know
that the, you know, pick a,
the Russian Northern Fleet
or whatever is currently in
the middle of an exercise.
Well okay, that's
all well and good.
That's the intelligence report,
but like hey, I at
least need to know,
or whatever, that this ship
is underway out of its port.
That's something that
I need to react to
in somewhat near real
time and not wait
for the final
assessment afterwards
'cause really what
we're trying to do is,
just as we talk about the
stream of alerts or warnings
that come into a
SOC environment,
is we're trying to
provide information
that allows defensive
teams to formulate
and tailor their responsive
and defensive posture,
towards what's going on
in their environment,
so that you're not
surprised by something,
but also to try and ensure
that you're not overreacting
to every little
thing, so just saying
that, like, oop, range
bearing signal, react.
Well okay, that
doesn't tell me much,
but if I can add a little
bit more context around that,
like oh, this particular
radar is associated
with this platform, which
happens to be the same sort
of platform that is capable
of flying X number of,
you know range, and
carrying this variety
of anti-ship missile.
Suddenly, the people down in
the combat information center,
they care a lot more about that
little piece of information
than they would if
I had just provided,
like, yep, we've got something
out over the water over here,
but how does this relate to CTI?
The gentleman is
in the audience,
and I'm gonna quote his
book, so Richard Bejtlich
provided in The Tao of
Network Security Monitoring,
which everyone in this
room has read, I'm sure.
If you haven't, you
should fix that,
but trying to relate the
concept of how I&W works
within the military
scope and trying to see
how that relates to
the practice of CTI.
I think this was a
initial step for it,
and not to criticize
him, but it's like oh,
there's a whole lot more
that we can talk about here,
which is what we're going to do,
so this isn't necessarily
a new concept,
but I think it's a
criminally underexplored one,
and maybe it's a little
bit too military centric,
but it's an idea that, I think,
really satisfies a glaring need
in how we're tailoring
intelligence operations
to the actual practice
of network defense
because if we're
differentiating indications
and warnings from
traditional CTI,
we're avoiding attribution.
Now we're certainly enriching
information with a little bit
about what a specific
indication might mean.
You know, that this malware
is capable of this behavior,
but I don't necessarily
care that it's Fancy Bear,
Goblin Panda, Fozzie
Bear, whatever.
I just care that
this is associated
with this sort of attack.
Here's where it lies
on the kill chain,
or because it's a
security conference,
it aligns to these
attack methods,
and how does that then allow
me to tailor my response?
I don't want to necessarily
get adversary intent.
Like, this is going
after the nuclear secrets
at the, you know, DOE
National Laboratory.
Like, maybe they are,
but at least I can orient
around what I'm seeing from
that technical observable,
what I should
maybe plan for next
in terms of defensive response
'cause what I wanna focus
on is really differentiating
and categorizing threats.
Is this something
that's wormable?
Is it something that
is going to require
interactive operation?
What are the next steps
that would be chained
to what I observed
within my environment,
and what other sort of
items can I relate that to
from a response standpoint?
Thus informing defenders
and enabling a more educated
and more tailored response
to what's being seen
instead of just oop,
we caught malware.
Wipe and rebuild the box.
Close the ticket.
We're good and done.
That's never a really
good answer, by the way,
but having said that,
this isn't to say
that CTI has no role whatsoever.
Rather, this is all part
of the circle of life,
the circle of incidence response
in cyber threat
intelligence, so really,
you could look at this
as being intelligence
provides that
strategic overview.
What is the lay of the land,
and where are our
adversaries going?
What are we observing in
adversary trade craft,
and communicating
that information down
to your SOC personnel,
your incidence responders,
or to a dedicated,
sort of, indications
and warning personnel, that
sort of technical inject
into the response
feed, and then insuring
that the day-to-day
operations are supported
by shaping what's observed then
in available telemetry
in light of what we know
about the broader
intelligence picture,
so providing that enhanced,
sort of, information,
so that when a raw IOC
pops up, I can orient that
based upon the broader
intelligence picture
to what that means in practice,
and hopefully I
can do that in less
than half an hour every
time every time, ideally.
That's never gonna
happen, but we can try,
so having said that, at the
same time I&W provides feedback
to traditional cyber threat
intelligence, though,
because it allows
traditional intelligence
to then see how the
environment is evolving,
what's going on in terms
of attacker trade craft
and behaviors, so
that it can then form
an iterative process.
That intelligence
remains broadly relevant
and continuously
up-to-date but then ensures
that it's also feeding back
down to day-to-day operations
so that your SOC personnel,
your incidence responder, etc.
doesn't have to wait six months
for the biannual
intelligence review
or well after a certain
incident is done
in order to incorporate
that into what they're doing
tactically on a
day-to-day basis,
so really what we're looking for
is this nice,
little, gooey center
of a overall defensive process,
where you have cyber
threat intelligence
connected to day-to-day
security operations
through a enrichment based
upon what operational needs
are required.
That makes sense
for everyone, right?
If it doesn't, that's okay
because we're gonna talk
about some examples now and
how this might look in practice
and where we might get
better, so to start off with,
I'm gonna wear the
hair shirt on something
that I worked on
as well as ESET.
Again, I don't think Rob
Lee is involved at all
in SANS events, so
Crashoverride Industroyer
is complete news for
everyone in this room,
but for those who don't know,
this was the 2016
Ukraine power event.
Multiple people worked on it.
This seems like it was
fairly well covered,
but if you look at
the timeline here,
the event itself happened
December of 2016.
Okay, power went out.
Power went out in 2015 as
well, and it ended up being
the result of a cyber intrusion,
or however you wanna phrase it.
Maybe this one was as well,
and as early as January,
we were getting hints that,
like, yep, it's cyber.
Like well, we need a
little bit of evidence.
I want someone to
prove this to me,
but it probably is cyber,
but then it wasn't until June
of that year that
ESET and Dragos,
again, disclosure, my
current employer, Dragos,
publicly disclosed
what happened,
and even then, if you
looked at what happened,
the information was mostly
around an ICS specific tool set,
so if you're orienting this
around the cyber kill chain,
or the ICS cyber kill
chain, specifically,
we got information about what
happened at the very end.
We didn't get any information
for how they laterally moved
into that environment.
No information about how they
got into the ICS environment,
let alone how the IT
environment was breached
and what movement
happened there.
That didn't happen until,
and this is only going
off of public reporting,
October of 2018,
where a white paper
was published by me
that went into a larger data set
that was made available
that accompanied
a lot that intrusion
information,
and it was really
only at that step
that you could really provide
any sort of threat indication
and warning for how
this attack took place
and how someone could
defend against it,
so from a raw data
sharing perspective,
if we're trying to do
this on a timely basis,
I'm happy to say that's
a complete failure
because the even
happened in December.
You didn't see your first IOC,
or meaningful IOC, until June.
That's a good seven
months between attack
and identification, where
similarly situated organizations
where pretty much left
twisting in the wind,
so there was really
nothing remotely actionable
put out very shortly
after the event,
so is that a information
sharing failure?
Is that a lack of trust failure?
I don't know, but from a
immediate data sharing,
we didn't do a very
good job there.
From an indications and
warning perspective,
we eventually got to
a point where someone
could have provided
a electric utility
with enough information
to say that hey,
if you see these sorts of
items in your environment,
it might relate to this,
therefore you should try
to orient your response
towards a potential
power outage event.
We got there, but it took over,
well, about a year in
order to make that happen,
and that also seems
unsatisfactory.
From a classic intelligence
perspective, though,
people got marketing
reports out of this.
We had reporting in 2017,
black out presentations.
Again, I took part
in all of this,
so this, I'm wearing
the hair shirt here.
We did a good thing
there, but I don't think
that we sufficiently armed
and augmented defenders
who actually had to
take care of this
to respond in a
meaningful way until much
after the event took place,
and these adversaries
have likely shifted to new ways
of operating, so not so cool.
Let's talk about something
a little more recently
that I didn't work on.
The Shamoon part three
because we always need things
to come in waves, and
Shamoon part three,
much like Return of the Jedi,
was kind of a skimpy knock off
or whatever relevant to the
earlier items in the trilogy,
but at the same time, it
still a destructive event
that hit various oil and
gas related contractors,
didn't hit Aramco this
time, as far as we know,
in the Middle East area.
Was covered fairly
extensively quite quickly.
Multiple vendors, so
let's see, Chronicle,
Semantic, McAfee,
who else is up there?
Talos, Unit 42 of Palo Alto,
everyone had a blood post
within a couple of
days of, I think,
the first sign, publicly,
that this was going on,
was a Tweet because
it has to be a Tweet,
and yeah, so from an immediate
response perspective,
like oh, this looks pretty good.
Like, we were getting
information out publicly
to defenders quite rapidly
on how this malware
was operating, how it
differentiated itself
a little bit from
earlier iterations.
That looks pretty good.
Well, then as people
started looking at this
a little bit deeper, its seemed
like there might have been
a little bit more going on here,
so we had multiple
vendors, McAfee, Anomoli,
I'm gonna get to
FireEye in a second.
It's like hey, there's an
APT33 link here, we think.
Like okay, that's interesting,
but at the same time, how are
we getting that information,
and if this is part
of a broader campaign,
then where was the
reporting prior to the,
again, the final
stage of the attack,
delivery of effects on target,
that would have
enabled defenders
to avoid the catastrophic
wiper situation
in their network, so
then we got a report,
and I'm not trying to
say that anyone's doing
a bad job here, so
someone's going to quote me
out of context, like,
Joe shit on FireEye.
No, that's not what
I'm doing here,
so FireEye published
a report that went
a little bit more in depth
for how this would have
played out over time,
which was really good,
but the question
here is, and again,
this is only going off
of public reporting,
how does this
relate, necessarily,
to what we observed in
how this attack developed
over time, and was
sufficient information given
to or provided to defenders
that they could have
taken action on this
before, after the fact,
saying, like, oh, all
your computers got wiped.
Well, here's the story
about why that happened.
Like, thanks, I can brief
my CSO a little better now,
but he's still gonna fire
me, so from that perspective,
did we do a good job?
And my answer here is maybe.
Like on the one hand,
we're certainly seeing
a greater willingness
on the part
of threat intelligence vendors
and other organizations
to really,
whether it's something
like Drunk Binary,
for example, going out
and reporting on hey,
this hash is related
to Fuzzy Snugly Ducks,
induckinator, intrusion
setter, or something like that.
Go look at it.
Well, maybe it's
verified, maybe it's not,
but it's something to dig into,
but the thing is, is that
we really need to make sure
that to provide that truly
actually information,
just finding that it, at
the end of the attack chain,
does very little in order to
empower and improve defense
throughout that entire
sequence of events.
You're really just
leaving organizations
at the mercy of,
like, well hopefully,
we're not the ones who're
going to be on the timer next
for when this wipers going
to go off in our environment,
so to the extent that,
could we have done better?
Well, it really depends
on that APT33 attribution
and what sort of
eyes on target we had
on that behavior over time.
If it's true that
this was part of a,
and it's only certainly the case
this was part of
someone's extensive,
over a period of
time, intrusion,
get into the environment,
figure out what to do
in that environment, and
then drop a cyber weapon
to do nasty stuff or whatever.
Like, yeah, there's probably
multiple touchpoints
that we could have identified,
but if it's a campaign
that we knew about
and that wasn't sufficiently
communicated before the fact,
have we empowered
defense sufficiently
so that they could
have taken action
to prevent the catastrophic
situation at the end?
So, overall, I'd say that
all of us could be doing
a better job here, but the
question is how do we get there.
Of course, not
everything can be public
because I like
paying my mortgage.
I'm sure some of you like
paying your mortgages too,
but there's gotta be
a way of doing this,
so what do we do then?
So to wrap this up with some
high level thoughts and etc.,
indications and warning
bridges a critical gap
between that raw data,
which may be accurate,
may be not, doesn't
have much context,
and the complete
intelligence report
that gives the entire
picture of what happened.
Security operations
benefit from this
by having indications
and warning built
into their battle
rhythm, so to speak,
because it allows them
to respond to things
more accurately, more
robustly, and to minimize
that sense of dwell
time for the adversary
or enhanced time to
response for the defender.
Unfortunately, in
a lotta respects,
the current CTI process, it's
not that we're deliberately
like, screw those
SOC guys or whatever.
I wanna write my
ten page book report
and submit it to Virus Bulletin.
It's not that we're
doing that necessarily.
It's just there's a
sense of not seeing,
not identifying
where the link occurs
between what we do from an
intelligence analyst perspective
and who it's
actually supporting,
what our audience is,
and what their needs are
to do their jobs
more effectively,
so and finally, for that
process to remain informed,
this isn't saying that
oh, you CTI analysts,
go off to your ivory
tower and do your thing
because it doesn't
matter for operation.
It's like, no, it matters
very much for operations,
but it has to be part of a
broader intelligence cycle
that's built into it a
understanding of and a need
to inform day-to-day
defensive operations,
so if we wanna apply this to
operations, what do we do?
So, from an analyst's
perspective,
whether you're a vendor or
you are an embedded analyst
at an organization,
demand I&W support
or build it out where
it doesn't exist.
One of the ways to do
that, and this doesn't
necessarily mean, you
know, I have to spend
the next two weeks
reversing this binary,
but if I get a domain
name, if I get a hash value
or something, pull the sample.
What's it do?
What's it relate to?
Can I enrich this in some sense
instead of just passing on,
like hey, this is bad.
It looks like Emotet.
Like okay, cool story, Bro.
It's like no, here's
a domain name,
and by the way, the
registration information on this
matches the same
tendencies that we've seen
in 28 for the last
three years or whatever.
They don't do that any more
because that got burned
publicly, but that
was a valid way
of identifying newly
registered infrastructure
that you couldn't be
fully confident that,
I know this is
related to Fancy Bear,
but I have some information
that makes that more useful,
and I can proactively
respond to it,
so a lotta that links
to understanding
at a behavioral level, and
this is where traditional
intelligence comes into play,
how do these adversaries
operate, and what do I look
for beyond just identifying
those atomic pieces
of information?
From a sharing
group perspective,
we privilege either
sending the TLP Red report
that we're not supposed to share
to all of our buddies,
or sending up an IOC feed
to move things
around between nodes.
That's cool, but we need
to start figuring out a way
to communicate not
just what we see
at that initial data
collection point
and then the after action
review of all that happened
but how to communicate
with our peers
in sharing groups,
other organizations,
friends, goofy Twitter
groups, and whatnot
what sort of
behaviors we're seeing
to inform that I&W
process, and finally,
from a vendor perspective,
which is where I'm
currently sitting
in most of this,
identify a means and
start feeling comfortable
with reporting items before
you get to the whole story.
There needs to be a
certain level of humility,
almost, that in
collecting information,
that we don't need
to wait until we know
the complete answer in
order to provide people
with some sense of
what's going on.
You can do that, but I think
that that disadvantages
defenders in light of what
the attackers are doing
because they're not gonna wait
until they have a complete
sense of what's going on
before delivering
effects on target
or stealing something
and what not.
They're just gonna
fulfill their mission
as they're able to do so.
We need to adapt ourselves
to that life cycle,
and instead of, put
ourselves in a continued,
backward looking format,
try and keep pace
with how attackers are operating
and report that information
in as real near
time as possible,
and maybe that means designing
a different kind of product.
Instead of delivering
things in the five page,
written reports,
come up with, like,
tippers with a standard format
that defines what
we're looking like.
For example, what would
this sort of look like?
And this goes back to what
we sort of talked about
with what intelligence
needs to do.
It needs to be timely.
If I'm getting this a week later
for an event that's
gonna lead to a wiper
within 24 hours of
install, like ha ha.
I better see that before
that wiper starts detonating,
or else I'm gonna be very upset,
but it also needs
to be descriptive.
We don't just want
the raw IOC sharing.
We want context around that,
how this observable data orients
to known attacker behavior,
what we can then theorize
from that behavior
in order to tailor response
and subsequent actions,
which is the last
part, intelligence
needs to be actionable.
Just saying like,
oop, here's a hash.
This malware's bad.
Our product blocks this.
That sucks.
When I was on the other side
of actually taking in reports
and whatnot, that
always just stunk
trying to read because
that doesn't really tell me
a whole lot to do.
Instead, actionable in the sense
of here's what the
indicator means.
Here's what the observed
behavior indicates,
and by the way, here're
different things
that you can do to
either look for it,
identify it, maybe
even kick it out,
and these don't need to
be necessarily written
every single time.
Presumably, they are
relatively static.
Alright, so I am timing
this excellently,
and I think I'm done.
- [Host] Thank you, Joe.
(applause)
(calm music)