so next up we have a topic on cloud
governance with infrastructure as code
with kyverno and cross plain and the
speaker for that is dolis Dulles is a
customer success engineer at nermata uh
they manage production kubernetes
clusters for namata and also works with
customers for issues with their
kubernetes deployments nullus is a
certified kubernetes administrator
developer and AWS solution architect
certified and is currently pursuing a
master's degree in computer science wow
well a bunch of accolades they're
amazing stuff and without further Ado
let's bring on dolits
hi everyone that's me
thank you for having me
really looking forward to your talk do
you do you want to maybe talk the
audience through real quick what you're
going to be sharing and uh what you hope
for them to get out of this
yeah so today we're gonna talk about a
little bit about what is cloud
governance and what is IAC and then I'll
talk about how cross played and keyword
no can help us and is in all of these uh
can provide Cloud governance um with the
help of policies
so yeah and I have a quick demo so maybe
I can quickly show that what exactly I'm
talking about because before a demo
nobody understands what exactly it is
sounds amazing well everyone who's
watching be sure to drop your questions
in the chat so we can relay it over and
with that I think we're gonna let you
take it over so thank you so much for
being here and really looking forward to
your presentation sure thank you
okay so uh let I think I've already been
introduced but I'll quickly just uh talk
what about about me and then we'll talk
about today's topic so my name is Dolly
Sharma and I'm a customer success
engineer in nirmata and today we're
gonna talk about crowd governance with
infrastructure as a code which is also
called as IAC with giverno and cross
play and these are some of the agendas
that I have on the screen that we are
going to cover today so we will start
with what exactly is IAC and then why do
we need IAC with their current
challenges that we see and then how
Cross Pin and kivano can help address
those challenge or even why do we want
to use that in the first place then I'll
quickly give you a demo and then we'll
wrap up the session
so to start with let's talk about what
is IAC so IEC is nothing but
provisioning and managing the
infrastructure through code that means
it's just codifying everything and which
looks good which is great but why do we
need by IAC so with Legacy systems we
have seen that administrators actually
need to manually deploy and manage all
the infrastructure along with the other
dependencies which require some amount
of time which requires resources and
then it requires special skills now IEC
uh this entire concept or approach
reduces all the time and then all the
time that we were doing things manually
it actually automates that so now
engineer don't have to do these things
manually they can only Define the
building blocks of the project where IEC
can actually framework this and then it
can do all the heavy lifting in order to
create and shape the infrastructure the
right way which allows a faster time for
the market
now this really
States and it's very clear that it
increases the speed of deployment but it
also cancels out all the potential error
when you're doing 10 things manually
clicking here and there and then a cost
it also reduces a lot of cost along with
all of these now not only that but it
also improves your consistency of
infrastructure we all know that there
are configuration drift that we see
often due to mismatch between Dev and
production and these can be due to many
reasons this can be due to ad hoc
changes or any updates and later on we
realize that oh there is a rift that
happened in our environment so IAC can
address all of these and then it can
improve these infrastructure consistency
it eliminates all these gaps and once
you have all your infrastructure set up
in a form of code these code is
auditable it's repeatable this approach
will help you to scale down or even
scale up your environment so think of a
situation or a scenario where you want
to scale down your demon bring it up in
an entire different region IEC can help
you do that you have a code and you can
just scale it to n number of
um in N number of region or actually
bring it up in just one click so it
gives you a good workflow transparency
and a structural arrangement of actually
provisioning your code which is pretty
awesome and sounds good but what are the
current challenges that we see today in
IAC
so IAC current challenges are that there
are some security risk we see that are
associated with IAC security risk like
there can be misconfigurations there can
be data exposures there can be access
privilege that you are giving with the
help of your code to the infrastructure
or due to the development and then there
can be compliance violations that which
are not compliant according to your
organization now while security team is
looking to enable all of these check at
different level they don't have the
entire visibility in a developer's code
now this becomes a really big challenge
when you want to achieve this without
Bridging the devops and a secops gap and
this actually creates friction between
the team and then there is coding
dependencies we have so many tools out
there which have different language they
are written on you have to look for
people who know those skills you have to
build up a team and then it creates a
over uh
an extra task of actually managing all
of that and then regardless of how
consistent you want to make your
infrastructure there is always
configuration drift so you have to
manually reconcile it which can cause
different kind of issues like a mobile
deadlock or maybe you have to have a
Time window where you do this
reconciliation memory and things like
that so these are some of the challenges
that we see in IAC today and how cross
plane can help you address this is
so cross plane actually uses kubernetes
API which means that the team can
orchestrate all of their infrastructure
and Cloud using Cube cuddle so if you
are using kubernetes or if um the team
is aware about Cube CTL they can use the
same Cube CTL CLI terminal using which
they can provision their infrastructure
using the same terminal they can
actually provision their infrastructure
and crossband can be implemented as a
kubernetes add-on so now the cluster
which is useful for your workload
deployment can actually help to create
and provision your infrastructure
so also Crossman uses kubernetes
declarative fashion so you don't have to
do the manual reconciliation you just
tell cross paint what you need what is
the desired State and automatically
reconcile that so all the time Windows
all the deadlock challenges is something
that you can cancel out and since all
your configuration files are in a form
of code you can actually Version Control
them and once you watch start version
controlling them you can track them you
can manage them you can restore it back
to any potential change not only that
when you're troubleshooting or you're
finding an issue it becomes really easy
when it's everything is version
controlled and you can actually roll
back to the previous version whenever
required and since cross plane uses
standard yaml format to create
infrastructure you actually do not
require any language to learn and this
can really be helpful if you want to
provide provisioning of infrastructure
as a cell service so for example a
developer who is actually creating an
application using the same yaml
something Sim similar or some a similar
yaml can also be used to create an ec2
instance before he is actually deploying
an application so now this reduces all
the dependencies between team and now it
can be actually used as a self-service
model
which is awesome but there are some of
the security challenges that we talked
about there are challenges like how do
you make sure you have that perfect
check how do you make sure that they are
not
privileges that you are providing while
you're creating an easy to instance or
how do you make sure that that
particular infrastructure or the
particular
virtual machine is in a particular
region has all the check has proper
security groups and all those settings
that you do if you are provisioning the
infrastructure that's where kivano can
help you have those checks enabled a
little bit about keyword no so kivano
means govern in Greek language it's a
cncf incubated project and it is a
kubernetes admission controller it is uh
built for kubernetes so that means all
the policies that you're deploying and
all the uh application deployment which
you're doing for keyword no is all
kubernetes Native so writing a policy is
a saml file it is as easy and as simple
as you write or deploy a deployment file
and using kuberno you can validate
mutate and you can generate kubernetes
resources so how does it work is you can
actually write policies and you can
write policies to validate your
configuration and give or no can give
you that checks according to that or
then you or else you can mutate the
existing kubernetes resources or you can
generate new resources so you can
provide all the triggers that Giver will
check for and it can generate new
resources that will give you a whole lot
scope of doing a lot of automations
around so which is good kivano is it
does a lot of things crossbane helps you
in
um infrastructure as a code model but
why do you use cross Pane and keyword
how to use it and why to use it in the
first place
so Cleveland with cross plane why do you
use it
so it actually addresses the IAC
security risk that we talked about which
involves accessive privilege which
involves compliance violations so what
keyword node does is it enforce the
guard rails by deploying those policies
so now even though you're providing
cross plane as a self-service you have
all the proper check set up you have the
visibility though enabling the
self-service model and then you know
exactly the security posture of your
cluster so what kivano does is it scans
all your deployment and then it provides
a report for you that you can have an
entire visibility of what are the
vulnerabilities what are the violations
that are happening from in accordance
with your uh validating policies or all
the policies that you have created it
not only blocks or audit those it also
provides guidance to the developer so
um if one of the yaml or if one of the
resource has been blocked by keyword no
it actually tells why exactly is block
so that the developer gets a guidance he
can go back he can fix his yaml and then
come back and then deploy it again and
writing a policy equivalent is extremely
easy so if you know kubernetes if you
know Amazon tags you'll be able to write
your own policy from day one
fibono also can mutate things and it can
also generate things so you can have
cool and all those new use cases for
automations in your infrastructure and
also kiwano has a CLI that you can use
in your cicd pipeline so now think of it
that you are using IAC in your pipeline
which is which is provisioning
infrastructure and then kuberno CLI is
using and validating all those
infrastructure before it is even
deploying to the cluster so that's
that's that's how you can use kiverno
with cross plane now enough of the
talking I'll just bring up my screen and
I'll quickly show you how does it look
and what exactly I'm talking about
okay so
um just checking a little bit of mine
so I have a couple of
um yaml files over here I have a OneNote
kind cluster and I have cross plane and
keyword no already deployed in this
cluster now what I'm going to do is I'm
gonna show you what does an instance
yaml file looks like Forex taking a step
back how can you create a simple ec2
instance in Cross plane so this is what
a yaml looks like and this is a simple
install dot instance yaml and if you'll
see this is as a normal yaml and you
have all your settings configured over
here so you have your details of subnet
your image ID you can add a lot of
fields which are supported by Cross Pin
and then creating a ec2 instances as
simple as
applying this yarn so once this is
applied you will see that the instance
will come up and then
you will see that it is created now if
you do Cube CTL get instance you will
see that the instance is coming up and
this is the ID that it gives you now if
I can check the ID in my AWS which I'm
doing on another screen
you will see that this instance will be
coming up and in a in some time it will
be up and running
now in a similar way you can also just
so I can show you this is my instance
and it is already started initializing
so in a similar way you can also create
S3 bucket and the I'm just going to
delete this before
in a simple way in a similar way you can
also create an S3 bucket and the yaml
for this is over here so you'll see here
that this is a bucket uh Yemen looks
like and this is I have I've specified
my region over here as specified if you
want to block Public Access and all the
settings and all the configurations you
do when you do it manually when you
create an S3 bucket this is all possible
by your yaml file so you can edit
everything over here and you can you can
watch and control it you can put it in
GitHub you can share it you can audit
this going back what what were the
settings I configured it initially so
all those things are possible when you
start codifying all of all the things
so this is how creation of
infrastructure is easy now talking about
the other side how do you make sure that
the privilege are on point how do you
make sure that this bucket which I'm
creating is in a particular region or
when we talk about Cloud it's all about
cost and cost management so how do you
make sure that when you're creating an
easy to instance the instance type is
exactly small nobody is just bringing up
a big instance and just creating it and
just you know your cost is spiked
suddenly
um so how you can do is you can create a
keyword no policy and you can have
proper checks at your instance
provisioning and this is one of the
policy I have so I'm just gonna I think
I have it here already so I'm going to
show you this one this is the policy I'm
using so this is a keyword no policy and
these are some of the annotations which
I have the messages and just so that I
know what policy what is this policy
doing and then I have a validate
uh this is a validate policy and I have
it in enforce if I change this enforce
to audit it's not going to block it but
it's going to audit it so it will help
you to know what exactly is happening in
your cluster and this is a rule you can
have a couple of them so these this is
one of the rule that I'm I'm adding over
here this rule is applicable to instance
and it's going to validate with this
pattern so this is my pattern and it's
saying that okay the Pat the yaml should
the instance resource should only have
T3 medium this is the pattern it's going
to validate from and if this is not P3
medium it's going to block that giving a
message to the developer saying that
this is not allowed so that whoever is
creating it knows why it is blocked in
the first place so let's see how it
looks like so I'm gonna just create this
policy first I have pivoto running over
here I have the entire setup but I can
show you how it looks it's a single pod
I'm running and everything is the entire
setup is ready so
I'm going to deploy this policy and
if I see this policy is true it's an
unfortunate perfect
I'm just going to check if my instance
is gone which is and I'm going to apply
the instance yaml again which I did when
I was creating an instance
and the moment I do that it tells me
that it's denying that request it's
blocking this instance you cannot create
this instance and the reason being is
that my instance have a M1 medium which
my policy doesn't like because I've
clearly said that you should only use a
T1 medium or two t t three medium
something like that which is uh not M1
medium of course so your instance type
is wrong and it tells you exactly gives
you a message that
using any other instance type apart from
this is not allowed so I can go back I
can fix my Amazon apply it and there you
go
so yeah this was a short demo or quick
demo of what it looks like now I'm gonna
just go back and
talk through the other set of things I
wanted to cover
okay so we we uh
I think I'm shutting the wrong screen
okay so we covered couple of things and
what are the key takeaways that
um that tells us that uh from the
session what are the summary or the key
takeaways that you want to we want to go
away with first is that we need IAC IEC
is wonderful at school it helps you to
do a lot of wonderful and cool stuff but
it has some of the challenges and it has
some of the things that needs to be
worked on first is that using right
tools like crosswind will really help
you it will help you because it doesn't
have any dependencies of any code
anybody can learn it the learning graph
is really cool you can provide it as a
self-service so that's that's pretty
awesome and then the other side of that
is the security side so using keyword
node we can actually add those proper
checks when you are creating an
infrastructure and you can provide the
infrastructure provisioning as a
self-service
so yeah this was some of the things that
I wanted to cover short and sweet
um if you want to know more about
kuberno you can actually go and Kevin
dot IO we have more than I don't know
like 200 policies now and we have
policies at for every type for every
service of kubernetes uh you will see
there and we have a channel in cncf and
kubernetes so if you have anything and
you're quite active there so if you have
anything if you have any questions just
uh put a message in the channel and we
should be there to help you out
okay so any questions if we have
anything
so first of all amazing talk
um I I think we have a question just
around what are some of the interesting
production kubernetes issues you've seen
at your job because it sounds like
you're working with lots of different
clusters there so what are some of the
cool things you've run into
so a lot of them I think
um
it's it's it depends I have run into a
lot of security issues and we have run
into a lot of networking issues issues
like you know your worker group is not
able to join your cluster because of the
security groups so yeah a lot of issues
that
um you you think that it's it's a
kubernetes problem but if you dig deeper
it's more towards your security issues
or your networking issues or Moto as a
Linux issue so everything is related I
would say uh it's it's just not
kubernetes sometimes
I I'm also really curious by the way if
people are really interested in this and
want to get more into kubernetes and
doing security for all this stuff like
do you have any good resources you
recommend people go like either books or
websites or blogs or people to follow on
Twitter you know anything like that yeah
so um I would say that we could um to
know more about security and to know
more about what kubernetes security is I
usually started with understanding
kubernetes basic security and CIS
Benchmark what exactly it talks about
and what exactly are the standards so
that is something we should we should
always have a look and something to keep
in the back of our pocket the other
things is we should start understanding
and thinking about security at day one
often I've seen that once anybody is in
production they after up after they are
in production line they start thinking
about security which is not good because
you're already live so uh something to
start with at day one and then you can
start thinking about proud to write a
policies from day one how to uh at least
have best practices and and PSP policies
to start with and then later on you can
Harden or you can you know make it more
strict but to start with PSPs and to
start with best practices that day one
is something that I would suggest we can
go in q100.io we can have a look at CS
Benchmark and what are what all
kubernetes actually suggest in their own
documentations
amazing well thank you so much for the
presentation that was incredible I
learned a lot myself so thank you for
dropping some knowledge on on me over
here
same here I I'm not one that knows quite
a bit about kubernetes and all that
space but uh what you presented was
understandable and I am particularly one
to call out and mention that I like the
developer experience was in mind where I
can turn on that audit mode for instance
or just reporting kind of mode and that
way I can learn before I go any further
beyond that so thanks thanks for
pointing that out
awesome and thank you for joining us
having me