right we've got to keep it on time here
Brian enough chatting from me and you
and more chatting from our uh keynote
speaker for this session uh welcome all
from permit.io
[Music]
I seem to have a cloud over my head in
this uh in this layout here but let's uh
add your um your slides to the stream
and uh Brian and I will get out the way
and the floor is yours or
thank you hi everyone I'm excited to be
here uh today we're going to talk about
dark dark is a framework
um a methodology to work on devsecops
um a little before we dive in a little
about myself my name is or Weiss my
background starts in the intelligence
score in the IDF but at core I'm a
developer and a security practitioner
nowadays I am the founder and CEO of
permit ioa Access Control solution we
basically enable you to never build
permissions again and I'm also honored
to be a Snick Ambassador and try to
promote cyber security and best
practices for developers or around the
world
um move out for Virgie Let's uh Dive In
so one of the challenges that people are
facing today and it's probably the
opening statement for almost any talk
you hear today is the complexity of
software uh the software stack that
we're building is getting bigger we're
adding more parts we're adding more
layers uh there are a lot of weak links
that are added into the chain and this
just translates to a lot of attack
surfaces essentially attack surfaces all
over the plane and a lot of times when
we try to communicate with our team
trying to communicate with vendors that
we're working with trying to communicate
with customers we're serving trying to
communicate between Dev Ops and security
uh it can be very challenging just to
wrap our hands around all of these
surfaces and sometimes it can feel like
we get lost in the dark to kind of give
an example here so we can understand
what I'm talking about
um I have an example here of a
healthcare startup that does something
ever basic for a healthcare startup it
connects with something that they Deploy
on the hospital side and then they
provide a machine learning driven
service with a back-end part and a
front-end application to their customers
which include both patients and doctors
that work on that data they have data
scientists working in the background to
build a machine learning model to train
it and load it to be used in inference
they have the platform Engineers kind of
uh
coping and planning everything and
obviously r d building all of the
elements here
and just looking at this picture I think
it's already kind of jumping out all the
different points were valuable and
sensitive data is flowing through the
system where proprietary aspects of the
system like the model here
reside and can be translated into a tech
services uh and into vulnerabilities
that we have to take care and just
trying to communicate what's going on in
this picture and trying to cover all the
areas that's kind of going to take a
while especially if we're going to do
this in a way where we're connecting to
other partners uh or vendors or
Solutions
um this is extremely clear when you
think about security questionnaires so
anyone who's ever built a product assess
offering or another one that you cater
to a different company you are probably
familiar with these documents usually
long spreadsheets that you need to fill
um just to communicate the Baseline of
how you do security how your product
looks and how it's going to affect the
security posture of uh that customer
you're interacting with just filling
this out can drive someone insane I know
I feel probably thousands of these by
this point and it can be very stressful
annoying and also very hard to work with
um so that's kind of at the core of the
problem that we have uh the plane
surface itself and the attack surfaces
within it are constantly growing it's
hard to communicate it's hard to work
around it's hard to find where we have
gaps and potential weak points that we
need to take care
and this is where dark comes in uh so
dark is a new mythology a framework that
is focused on being very quick to
provide you with a quick top line so you
can communicate quickly within your
company between devs and Ops with your
customers maybe instead of security
questionnaires uh with other people and
give you a very quick picture of what's
going on help you find every all the
points that you need have covered for it
enable you to zoom in on different
levels so you can have an overall
picture but also apply dark to more
subsets of the problem and everything
very consistent with best practices and
no less important tools that we can
apply uh to the problem itself
um so let's talk about what dark is
comprised from so first of all dark is
the five layers of uh basically every
application so no matter what we build
these five elements are going to be in
existence there and we need to take care
of them and not taking care of them is
uh immediately translates into potential
security vulnerabilities so the first
one and I think uh our host here
mentioned it at the beginning of the
talk here
um supply chain that's a really hot
topic now and
um so managing dependencies that
dependencies of the software you're
building software you're providing is a
critical thing so dependency that's the
first layer in dark and we basically ask
how do we secure the software supply
chain that we're providing this second
part is Access Control how do we connect
other services how do we connect other
people other identities to what we're
building and how we do so in a secure
way
um is a classic question we move forward
to run time how do we know that the
software that we've built is going to
behave the way that we expect
configuration how do we know that we've
set and configured the software that
we're deploying to run in the way that
we expect and want and lastly the
container how do how do we set up the
containing environment how do we make
sure that our software is running uh in
within the box within the servers within
the cloud that we intend and in the way
it is intended to work
so those are the layers and now we're
going to cross them with the best
practices
these best practices are really going to
be our light in the dark here something
that you can take with you apply on
those layers and be able to say uh if
you have any gaps in your security
um the first one is matching is code so
that's really a classic one and becoming
more and more popular knowing that uh we
have a very mature ecosystem with how we
manage complex things as code for
developers now we know that we can apply
this to basically everything else we can
apply these to policies to
infrastructure to configuration to
basically all of the layers that I
mentioned mentioned before so we want to
see that we can apply management this
code across that stack
zero trust that's also a very common uh
best practice we need to make sure that
what we're building has zero trust and
no need to know basis kind of baked into
all of its layers this will really
affect how we compile or how we build
the software itself and how we connect
different uh software components between
one another being event driven that's
just a necessity of modern applications
if we're moving too slow if we're not
real time if we're not responding to
changes both in the customer demands or
in our infrastructure we're going to
have a bad time so being event driven
that's a must nowadays decoupling That's
a classic from software development just
making sure that only the parts that
need to be bundled together are bundled
together and that we have tools that
allow us to separate the different parts
that we have if we don't do so because
of the complexity of software today
we're going to end up with spaghetti
code or spaghetti
architecture within a very short uh
window of time
uh lastly the two uh more high level
ones a unified view unified view just
means that we are able to monitor the
entire layer in a way it is easy
aggregated and we can connect it to
other systems and have it approachable
here we understand that first of all
everyone is becoming a developer and all
the stakeholders have to be involved in
security we can no longer apply security
as an afterthought so we need developers
to take care of it at day one but we
also need to enable all the other
stakeholders product security compliance
even sales and support we need to enable
them to chime in on our security posture
or at least be part of the conversation
otherwise we're going to have a bad time
just trying to communicate so these are
our best practices and now we're going
to layer them on top of the layers and
uh so now for each dark layer we're
going to look at the each of the best
practices and we're going to ask how are
we implementing the best practice and
even more specifically how are we
applying tools uh to implement that best
practice so we know we actually solve
the problem and we're not just talking
about it
so I'm going to run quickly through
um kind of these overview of layers I'll
mention the top tools uh that I think
are worthwhile knowing and then we'll
try to bring this all together back to
the example that we've uh set on the
stage for so uh dependency our supply
chain so
um I'll highlight managing things as
code so s-bomb software build materials
is becoming a very commonplace thing you
can find uh tools for that both in an
open source project called spdx and also
within sneak cloud
um I'll also man mention things like
backstage and uh Port IO get Port IO
um starting to manage all the different
software components that we have in an
approachable way that the developers can
manage share with one another maintain
track of what's going on uh that's uh uh
becoming super important and super
critical uh and these are tools that are
becoming popular to solve that there are
other things here that are maybe worth
mentioning classic sneak for your open
source dependency
um and obviously being event driven here
translates very easily into cicd
um access control
um so Access Control has multiple layers
by itself so we have uh application
Level Access Control infrastructure
level access control
um
and obviously it continues to the
network level physical level and we need
to cover that across the space uh
policies code is really solved by great
projects like oppa and uh now fresh out
of the oven AWS announced the policy
language and engine called Cedar
um zero trust is really managed by the
classic concept of doing policy decision
points so instead of having Access
Control baked into our software we have
a separate microservice for
authorization usually called the policy
decision point and we have services like
permit IO and like uh spice DB that we
can use to implement that microservice
for authorization instead of building it
on our own
um so those are like a few quick
highlights for
um Access Control moving into runtime
um here sneak code also comes in for uh
our decoupling aspect I also want to
highlight Falco Falco is a really great
project for uh runtime application
security uh really can produce quick
alerts it's uh also becoming a very
popular cncf project uh gatekeeper with
oppa again uh comes in for policies code
and Docker is a classic uh for
containerization and basically creating
that zero trust element between the
different runtime components that we
have
um configuration I'll mention
um configuration checking tools like
confest the tree and Chekhov these are
also becoming
um I think a very common tool in the uh
Arsenal that the developers and devops
use today
um get UPS is a mythology to be event
driven around configuration is a very
common place and we're starting to see
configuration Management Solutions uh
that make it more approachable with
things like configure and again
backstage that I mentioned before
lastly container
um so here obviously Docker Helm charts
with kubernetes and oci images really
shine management tools for the overview
of it like datadog and Prometheus are
very commonplace and we're starting to
see some maturity of brown making this
more approachable with projects like
raft velocity and n0
so we went through the layers now and we
looked at common tools or at least
examples of common tools that we can
bring to the table to try and manage all
of the best practices that we need to
bring in
um and we saw that for each layer we can
look at each of the best practices and
we can uh apply it in a general fashion
just in general how can we go about
making sure that we have the right best
practices and tools for whatever we're
building now let's take this back to the
uh specific example that we have here so
we can do two things one we can create a
quick picture of dark to light up this
entire thing and that's going to be the
next slide but we can also talk about
having different points I can look at
for example how the data scientists
connect to the machine learning model or
how the CI CD connects to the back end
how are the platform Engineers uh
connect to the uh cicd and the backend
for each of those we can create a dark
map we can apply the framework for each
point so I'm not going to do that for uh
now but I'm going to do this for the
overall picture and you'll see that we
quickly get a um basically a component
that enables fast communication a quick
summary and the ability to kind of zoom
in on the parts that we want
um and let's just jump into that so if
before we looked at each of the layers
separately and we asked in general what
we can apply here here we're looking at
all of the layers together and Crossing
them uh in a table with all the best
practices and we're applying this to the
specific case of that Healthcare startup
that we saw before by the way that
Healthcare startup is a real startup I
didn't mention them their name here but
this is based on something that's
happening in reality I know them because
they're a customer of mine within uh
with permit IO
um so for example we can see that for
the access control part permanent i o is
a solution that they use to solve both
decoupling creating a unified View and
making this approachable for the other
stakeholders and also with firminole and
opal the open source project behind
permit i o uh they are able to do this
in an event driven sense like many other
players uh they're using sneak both for
their supply chain and both for their
runtime security
um what was interesting in the picture
that we saw before man maybe I'll I'll
uh go back is that there's both a cloud
component and an on-prem component so in
this table I've kind of broken it down
both for on-prem and for the cloud and
that kind of floats up some issues so
for example in runtime being event
driven they're using Falco and and a web
application firewall
um to monitor in real time what's going
on with their
um running code but for the on-prem
solution they don't really have anything
so immediately just off the bat looking
at the slide we immediately see where do
we have gaps and in this case we see
that we have a partial Gap
we can also see that there are errors
that are complete gaps so for example
for they have around configuration they
have a lot of gaps they're not event
driven the configurations are deployed
once uh with the uh basically with the
build so you build it once if you want
you have to redeploy everything to
change configuration uh so they're not
using anything like uh feature Flags or
anything like that and for the on-prem
option it's completely
um
um not event driven uh they have to
deploy uh sorry they have to send a new
image to the customer to have any
configuration change on that side
um so obviously it's not decoupled it's
bundled into that image and they have no
way of viewing this or making this
approachable not not for themselves or
their customers
um
obviously what we're covering here is
that specific case for that specific uh
customer of mine
um different scenarios that you'll run
your software uh the interaction that
you have with your vendors or your
customers would produce obviously very
different uh slides very different uh
dark Maps but you'll get these dark Maps
quickly it won't take you long you can
probably if you take your average
mid-sized SAS offering it will probably
take you just a few hours a day at most
to map everything that you want into our
dark map and then you can use that to
communicate internally you can use that
to share it as part of security
questionnaires or maybe in the future
instead of security questionnaires and
you can use that to also find gaps in
the software that you have or in the
solution that you're building
um and I think this slide really kind of
sums up the
um the way that dark can really light up
our uh look into our security posture
so kind of Summer summing summarizing up
uh what we talked about dark is relevant
for anyone building software developers
uh devops sres appsac and everyone
managing the overall picture Architects
security analysts appsec the management
team
um and it can be a valuable tool to
speed up processes on both those sides
um for the management this can really be
a guiding principle when you're starting
to build something new or you're
refactoring something you're working or
new architecture you can start with a
dark map to kind of quickly highlight
where you have answers answers for
things and where you have gaps that
you'll need to address soon and this can
be a way to communicate between
organizations uh again I really think
that security questionnaires are a pain
in the ass and even though we have
companies like panerase making them
easier to approach uh it's still very
cumbersome to work on so I'm really
trying to encourage this and this can
also be a good way to communicate
security as part of your docs so a lot
of documentation for SAS offering today
is our product stays include a section
on security having this as part of that
security section would really speed up
um someone's ramping up into the project
and them being able to find the answers
for what they need and how they can make
sure that they product that they're
reviewing is meeting their standards for
developers this is uh for foremost a
checklist uh you build something you
want it to be secure you can go through
the checklist
uh through the dark map to make sure
that you have an answer for all the
different things you're connecting
um and this can be also a baseline for a
SWOT analysis to understand where your
strengths are where you have gaps uh
where you need to invest your time when
you're dealing with technical debt
um and in the end of the day this can
also be a good way to decide which tools
you need to invest in knowing what you
have in place knowing which gaps you
have prioritizing them and understanding
uh which ones are more critical can
enable you to decide which tools are you
bringing on next are you upgrading your
observability are you adding runtime
Access Control this can this map can be
a baseline for the discussion of what
you should tackle first to minimize your
technical debt and to
um basically meet all the best practices
that you need to meet
um so now I'll pause for questions I'll
say I'm available for questions later uh
you can find me all across the internet
is orwise o-r-w-e-i-s on GitHub on
LinkedIn on Twitter and you'll be
surprised how responsive I am uh for
questions
um if you want this deck and you want
the framework itself you can find it at
permitio blog dark uh dark dark here is
obviously the arcc
um and uh it's available for everyone
and if you're interested in best
practices and other
um Concepts that I'm driving you can
also check out this blog on uh permanent
IO for the five best practices for
building Cloud native permissions
um
hope you enjoyed the talk and I think we
have a few minutes left and I'll be
happy to tackle questions if there are
if there are any
all right thank you so much or and I yes
let's put Matt in as well and let's
change the view for a second to
this oh I will I will put the overlay
away away so we can actually continue
that like let's do it like this or and
we just put the little logo in that's
that suits far better uh thank you for
this talk or I don't I don't see any uh
uh questions that didn't that were not
yet answered in the in the in the chat
but
um uh uh I would love if you would could
um
share the links that you have on the
Discord as well so people can't click on
it because it's very hard to click on
slides obviously uh because I think that
the whole the whole story about dark and
how to implement it uh I want to get my
my hands on it and actually try it just
to see if it fits
um so thank you
happy to share those and I think
um uh that's something that I really
want to encourage people to do this
thing that I've presented here is really
geared towards Simplicity and being
quick so you shouldn't like thinking oh
should I adopt a new methodology should
I adopt a new framework
um I think you should put that question
aside and just give it a try
um I think most people and most other
companies that I've used this framework
with you quickly find gaps that you
weren't necessarily aware of before so
even if you don't end up implementing
this uh end-to-end or across your stack
uh this will enable you to figure out
things that you might necessarily not be
aware of and that will immediately
improve your security posture just by
raising awareness
we have I had a question that I've been
interested in your thoughts about I mean
I I I'm always fascinated by um oh
actually we've got a question yeah we've
got a question coming in from the from
the hop-on framework so or where does
API security come what are your views
about it
so API security is a component of itself
um that you definitely want to have I
didn't map all the different uh
components that you have I mapped the
best practices
um and APA security you'll have both
access control I think is a significant
part of it and while you go through the
best practices you see you end up
basically acclimating API security both
in the access control aspect and in the
runtime aspect
um so the challenge with trying to build
a framework around
um specific components is that it
doesn't end there's always another layer
being added so and that will make this
framework complex instead of simple so
that's not the direction I went with but
I think dark definitely touches on it
and anyone building anything with an API
going with dark to light it up will
definitely touch on IPS security it's
unavoidable yep gotta guess I guess so
so thank you for that mad you had
something so go ahead yeah I mean I'm
always fascinated to see that folks are
still managing trying to manage things
using spreadsheets these days you know
especially in the era of modern software
development where you know an
application might have hundreds or even
thousands in some cases of dependencies
which is just uh you know that's like
trying to uh fit a square peg into a
round hole right I mean you're just
never going to be able to track things
like that and and look at the risks of
them
um I I still think that the the answers
for how we do that are still emerging I
know we've got a couple of talks uh
later on today
um that are that are around the same
space I mean I I I guess uh the other
thing was when we start to look at uh at
complex uh application architectures and
as as you pointed out in some of those
diagrams you know we're we're often also
having uh having requirements on
external Services right that we're using
we're using SAS things within our apps
you know what what are your thoughts on
on kind of how we quantify risk for that
right because you know do we just say
here's a risk boundary that's somebody
else's problem and that's enough or you
know
so I think uh first of all maybe to
touch on the spreadsheets so I'm not
saying here that you shouldn't have
those spreadsheets it's okay to have
them it's a good tool if you want to do
a deep analysis I think they're they're
really not
um a good tool if you want to
communicate between boundaries which is
kind of the other part of the question
that you're alluding to or touching on
um so if you're working between vendors
or between customers or between
different departments if you were
passing around spreadsheets everyone's
going to have a bad time
um it's just not something that uh
people can digest fast enough to build a
conversation so you can add those
spreadsheets alongside something that
will give someone the ability to ramp up
quickly and communicate quickly around
the sensitive areas
um and going to your second point so
um dark doesn't really touch on um
prioritization directly it it's more
focused around highlighting where you
have gaps and then you there's more work
to be done around prioritizing them
um but I find that the especially with
security
um if you're prioritizing things without
a clear unified view you're basically
missing out
um because uh the weakest link principle
might be hiding uh the actual thing that
that if you don't take care of all the
other work that you're doing is
basically meaningless yeah so it's I
think it should be foremost managing of
you being able to communicate around
that having the discussion of what we
have in place and then being able to
prioritize uh maybe in a future uh
update to dark like dark 2.0 maybe I'll
add something around prioritization but
I haven't tackled that specifically yet
great well thank you very much super
interesting oh we've got one have we got
time for yeah we've got time for one
more question I think we've got one uh
do we have that on a on a banner Brian
or should we just read that one out well
let me put this on a banner in okay well
I'll read it while you're typing so uh
how does threat modeling fit in with the
framework and how does threat modeling
fit in with permission management
oh that's uh that's a lot in one
question
um
so I think threats and I kind of touched
it with the SWOT analysis
um so the gaps that you have
um are almost always translating into
potential threats and risks that you
have so
one and that's kind of also kind of
touching I guess on your question before
so once you have those gaps in place you
can map them into risks and threats and
then you can prioritize them and then
you can create models of them and then
you can even have simulations around uh
tackling those threats when they happen
um it's not something that this
framework
specializes in uh but I think it's a
good enabler to do threat modeling
um in terms of
um modeling threats and connecting them
to permission management I'd say that
it's around policy and policy is code
specifically in general managing policy
in complex applications is becoming very
very cumbersome if you try to keep all
of that as know how and documentation
that you have proprietary code for
um you it will be very hard for you to
keep modeling the threats or the
friction points that you need to protect
um with your uh permission management
for the software components You're
Building If instead you decouple out
your uh authorization if you decouple
that out and you have your policy uh
managed separately as idealist policy is
code in a unified repository then it's
easy to have a source of Truth and then
that's our truth you can model you can
track you can test you can do benchmarks
on
um and
um you can also
um have code reviews on it which is uh
an amazing feat that is impossible any
other way
um
and said that in addition uh if you use
tools uh like obviously I'm biased here
but if you use something like permanio
you also get low code interfaces that
generate that code for you so that way
you can have the security practitioners
work directly on that policy as code on
that source of truth without having to
uh necessarily be full-blown Developers
fantastic well I think that's actually a
great segue to our next speaker so we'll
uh we'll leave it there thank you again
or that was super interesting and uh
let's uh drop you out