yeah sure thing all right our next
speaker is
and he's a senior security architect and
and math developer so Raymond is a
security ninja open source contributor
and Senior security architect at
Emirates National Bank of Dubai he is
passionate about devsecops application
and container security he added 17 000
plus lines of code to end math
um holds industry certifications like
cks and cka Etc
everyone speaks and delivers training at
International Security conferences
worldwide including black hat Defcon
hack in the box and multiple others he
was recognized as one of the MVP
researchers on bug crowd and identified
vulnerabilities in several organizations
he also published an IEEE research paper
on an offensive attack in machine
learning and security who is also part
of the renowned Google summer of code
program
all right and bremont will be talking
about the s-bomb
so s-bomb the inescapable way of
tracking dependencies
amazing welcome everyone and so looking
forward to your talk I think I was just
telling uh earlier when we kicked off
devsecond that you know I think in 2022
if you say s bomb three times like a
genie appears so I don't know if you
agree with that because it has become
one of those words that everyone you
know it's become a buzzword but it is
just one of those things that is so
crucial to I guess security as well so
I'm really looking forward to this talk
uh we'll bring up your slides as well
and promo and I will just tuck away in
the background and let you take it away
yeah sure awesome
and thank you both for the amazing
introduction and I was speaking about as
bombs so I'll just get started quickly
just a quick introduction about me I
guess already the
they have introduced me so I'll skip
this slides and what to expect we'll
discuss about why s bombs are required
and what it is and how
you can use as bombs
so they why before diving into the wild
let's just see some of the recent hacks
that happened
on various companies and open source
projects
so one of the famous hacks that happened
was on the faker and color JS where a
developer himself corrupts his
package and
releases a false update
if you see the figure JS it's having
around 2.6 weekly 2.6 million weekly
downloads
and similarly colors this is another
package which has got 20.7 million
weekly downloads
and figure has around 2600 dependents so
it means if Faker JS package is affected
it will subsequently affect 2600 more
packages
and similarly colors package is being
used by 20
000 plus dependents so one of them gets
affected
the ripples are gonna go through
multiple other packages and if someone
else is using these packages those will
be affected subsequently
and one of the other attacks that
happened was on the python Library
called SSH decorate where the attacker
has back doored the package to steal
your private SSH keys so they can use
that to login into your remote servers
and
do nasty things
and there is another attack called type
of squatting
it's mostly based on brand hijacking
where they just tweak one or two letters
in the package names and try to release
a false package
for example kalaroma is one of the pipei
package but the attackers released
something with cyl o u r which is mostly
used in the U.S terminology
and this package has a malware dropper
that will
come onto your machine once you install
this package it will automatically
install the malware on your system and
tries to copy your
crypto wallet numbers like for example
if you see here
this is the actual it will replace the
targets uh cryptocurrency value so
whenever you want to send money to your
person a it will replace it with this
attacker Bitcoin address so you will
never get to know but the money will be
transferred to the
attackers Bitcoin account
so this is also one of the hacks that
happened
and log4j is one of the most famous
vulnerability that came in the recent
times that triggered the entire
the start of supply chain security and
its awareness
so if you I want you to observe the
timelines
the issue was first reported on November
11th and on December 1st they first saw
this vulnerability being exploited
and on December 13th the first patch got
released so from December 1st till
December 13th
the exploit is available publicly and
even on December 9th it got exploded on
Twitter and everyone has access to this
but there was no patch available until
December 13th
so from December 1st to 13th the
vulnerability was being exploited and
people has no clue about it because
there was no official patch on that
and similarly since it got super famous
following on the other days there were
multiple other vulnerabilities that
the researchers identified and
those have been patched after a while
so if you see here on December 14th
another vulnerability got published and
it got passed on December 18th
so that's an issue and there are the
other hacks that happened in the past
two years
on these open source packages in
Homebrew PHP code curve vs code and
multiple others
so this is a one of the reference thing
on by tag security you can go here and
read more about the other hacks that
happened
so why do these supply chain compromises
happen what's the primary reason for it
I truly believe it's because the
attacker knows your system better than
you do
he knows more about what kind of
packages you are using or what kind of
services you are exposing and you don't
have any way to track these things or
even if you are tracking them you need
to have actionable points just having
the information will not help you need
to make sure you are utilizing the
information that you have so that you
can take some
active measures
so according to a research done by Wiz
and ey even after 10 days of
the log4j team released the patch only
50 percent of the companies have patched
their systems and 55 50 of 45 percent of
the companies still left their systems
unpatched despite being a critical
vulnerability
so why do you think
this 50 of the companies did not patch
the system is it because they're
negligent they want to get hacked or
lose reputation no none of these are the
reasons
it's purely because they don't know what
to look for they don't have insights on
where this log 4J is being used on their
system or any package for that matter or
if the package is a dependency or a sub
dependency of another package they don't
have any visibility on these components
that's one of the reason companies like
to fix these things and the attackers
tend to identify this in the first place
so s bomb comes here for the rescue and
as bomb refers to the software bill of
materials and this is how it looks like
for example this is the s-bomb generated
for an nginx Docker image
and you can see it lists down all the
package information that your image is
having along with their versioning and
their licenses and a lot more we'll go
through them
so the what
so just to give it a simple analogy
I'm sure most of you might love
chocolate chip cookies
so when you want to make one or when you
want to understand how one is made you
need to have the complete list of
ingredients that Source the quantity and
how long you have to brew it and
everything
so s bomb is similar to this
instead of giving information about
chocolate chip cookies you will have
every detailed information about this
software or the components that are
involved in building the software their
versioning their licenses when they got
released and if there are any cves if
there are any vulnerabilities associated
with those packages it will give
information of them as well
so how can you
look for these packages so how can you
look for these vulnerabilities or how
can you generate these response
so there are several tools available on
the public and one of them is Trivial
made by Aqua security
you can use this to generate the s-bombs
for example here I'm just looking for
the vulnerabilities in the images I
haven't generated the s-bomb yet and it
shows there are around
1258 vulnerabilities in a standard node
image
so how can you get this information into
an s-bomb
so you can have this similar command
executed where you have to specify the
type of information
and
it will generate the s-bomb for you for
example let's say you are building a
node.js application and you want to
identify what kind of licenses are
involved with the different packages
that you install on the node.js
application for example as most of you
might have tried building a node.js
application and it downloads so many
dependencies
so in this case just for this standard
node.js image there are so many packages
that involves 131 different types of
licenses
and they we are able to get this
information through generating the S
forms and then passing the output
and listing down for The Unique ones
so you can read more about this over
here
and just having this information is not
helpful you need to visualize it
sometimes it's easier to visualize
rather than just seeing the things so
there is an amazing project called guac
as for graph for understanding artifact
composition
it looks something like this where you
can pass your s-bomb information once
you generate them and then it will
visualize it for you and you'll be able
to go more deep into it and it can get
as complex as this where I'm looking at
the packages in the cube controller
manager container
and it will list down all the binaries
and what is dependent on where
and just to show a live interactive demo
so this is a Docker bash image and it is
having all these dependencies
so if I go to this one and I can just
click on the expand graph so if there
are any other sub dependencies or
something else depending on this package
it will show you all the list of
information over there
so in this way it gets much interactive
and you might some might prefer this way
of
visualization
so you can definitely try out guac for
to explore more into this
and also it's good to have these as
firms generated with all the list of
information but it's equally important
to secure them
so six stores is another open source
project that works towards securing
these artifacts and your Docker images
or any artifact for that matter
so I have released the six story easy
web guide It's a practical approach on
very easily getting started with six
store and securing your response so you
can definitely have a look at it and try
to secure your s-bombs as well
and even s-bombs have been so famous
that even the NSA has released their own
guide on securing the supply chain
artifacts and they have explained more
about
how you can secure these s-bombs and
about other things like vulnerability
exploitation metrics and stuff
okay
so what are my thoughts my feeling is
supply chain security is open source
security
most of the open source code used by
people isn't updated and hence you need
to have a proper way of tracking your
dependencies and when something happens
you'll have the complete information
so that you can take an immediate action
that's where I feel the responsible
player crucial part
and you can connect with me on these
social medias
on Twitter LinkedIn and this is my
website
I hope this is useful and just at least
getting an idea about what a sperms are
and how you can go ahead
let's get me started
thank you so much for that everyone I
think it was really really good and I
think we just had careful chat
mentioning as well that it's good that
someone's actually
um covering goac as well because he just
covered salsa so it actually
complimented that really really well and
not to stretch the analogy because salsa
and guac I always find that a bit funny
but um and that was a really good
Insight I think I I liked you know how
you kind of explained the things with
the chocolate chip cookie I don't know
about anyone else but I'm not sure
yes I think it is really really
interesting and and the fact that you
said you know that attackers do know
your environment often better than you
do I think that's a really good thing
that you mentioned because it is very
true with the world of Open Source
um you know it often it is out there for
everyone to see exactly what goes in
that software as well so that was really
really insightful and thank you so much
for joining us and you know sharing your
knowledge here as well
um I'm just gonna quickly see if there
are any questions but yeah if anyone
does have any questions that they want
to pop in
um do send them across but otherwise you
know um ravanth has generously shared
his details as well so I'm sure he'd be
happy to answer any questions they have
in the future