okay so we have the next speaker in line
um so we have Kai fasan uh Kaif is a
quarter by Passion and a Haku by
profession he started his journey in
Tech as a software engineer but soon
fell in love with the art of reading net
sofa his knowledge of development and
cyber security has naturally led him to
application security space where he
currently is working as a product
security engineer at atlation
kaith is a big big proponent of
education and open access to it
knowledge he regularly volunteers to run
cyber security workshops at various
universities
um giving talks at local meetups and
conferences as well
um he is also the co-host for the
amazing YouTube channel everything cyber
where he shares Hands-On and
conversational videos on Tech and cyber
security his videos Target uh
intermediate level professionals and
helped them to gain expertise through
practical content
um today's talk for Kaif is uh based on
securing our software Supply change uh
Jane's using salsa framework welcome to
devsec con kive and hello okay thank you
for joining us uh I'm particularly
interested in this because you know I'm
very interested in all things supply
chain Security even though it is a
buzzword and I'm really interested for
this particular one so what we'll do is
We'll add your slides over here and
kavika and I will go off to the
background I also did want to take this
opportunity just to thank avika so she
will be heading off it will have another
co-host joining us but thank you so much
for co-hosting and kicking off death
second 2022 with us uh and Keith I will
say let you take it away yep thank you
so much kavika for hosting and I think
you did a much better introduction to
for myself than I ever could so thanks
for that as well
um hello everyone welcome to my talk on
securing the software supply chain using
the salsa framework
I think kavika already has given a
pretty good introduction on myself so
I'll not spend any more time on this
slide and get started with the talk
directly
so let's try to understand what today's
agenda is about
we'll first try to understand the
landscape where a framework like salsa
is required and then give a quick
introduction to salsa
understand what value it brings and
lastly what does salsa not cover
cool let us understand the landscape and
I'd like to do that with sharing two of
my favorite memes
um the first one being
us from coming from a soft engineering
background
um yeah it's safe to say that it's just
not just me a large portion of us also
rely heavily on Outsourcing our sort of
work from stack Overflow and a lot of
other places and that's actually the
beauty of it as well like very few other
Industries are as open and collaborative
as I.T
aking it up a notch and we're so
confident in these kind of projects in
open source that many of our large-scale
Enterprise softwares which are used by
millions if not billions of people often
rely on small open source projects
which also
brings us to the other side of the coin
that
supply chain attacks has been one of the
biggest considerations and issues in
cyber security because in software so
far we really haven't put in a much
thought on how does how does these
components have been produced are they
safe to use and whatnot and that led to
various attacks like the lock for Jake
caseya solar winds and much more
and it's not just the vulnerability in
third-party libraries that are causing
so much pain in the supply chain we have
seen visibility of what we're using and
how is a big issue for folks who are
involved in the log 4J incident we had
to scramble a lot to figure out that hey
which of our products and repositories
uh do use lock4j and figuring that out
was hard similarly the Integrity or
figuring out whether our software has
been tampered or not is a big issue and
it's just not our software that we put
in front of the users the software that
we are getting from open source from
different vendors is that has is that
Integra is that say secure as well is a
big question
and the lastly the remediation even if
we know that something is broken how
quickly can we replace it from our
supply chain and oftentimes that period
is long enough for attackers to
compromise
and all of these issues are quite
complex on their own and they deserve
their own lightning talks and if not
in-depth talks if I'm honest in my talk
I'll Focus explicitly on the Integrity
side of things because ensuring that our
software has not been tampered with is a
big challenge
let's look at the typical software
development lifecycle on one end we have
the developer creating the source which
then get gets built and then packaged up
for the users to consume it and
throughout this phase there are lots of
areas where tampering can happen
all these attack factors make
secure software development very very
hard because is the build we created uh
secure has it been tampered is the
software again we're giving to the our
clients and customers is has it has the
attacker managed to slip in or do
something with it figuring out all these
things is very very difficult and that's
why we've been seeing so many
large-scale attacks
attacks like solarwinds is a big example
where the build platform was compromised
and it was a very very complicated and
complex attack
so how do we ensure Integrity of our
software how do we make sure that no one
has tampered with it
and that's where the salsa framework
comes in
the salsa or SLA slsa stands for supply
chain levels for software artifacts and
fiction affectionately called as salsa
it is basically a checklist of standards
and controls that prevent from prevent
tampering from happening in our supply
chain and it's just not just a big list
uh that we need to follow it actually is
like a road map that people can
gradually use to secure their supply
chain and the best part is probably it's
vendor neutral and it's industry
collaborative uh framework that is led
by the open ssf foundation which is
backed by huge organizations like Google
Microsoft atlassian and many other
so let's look at some use cases of salsa
and the first one is obviously for
organizations who want to make sure that
their software hasn't been tampered with
and it's not just one size that everyone
needs to conform all the organizations
can use salsa according to their needs
to
achieve supply chain security and
following the different salsa levels
we'll get we'll look at them in a second
and zooming into that organization
security organizations can use salsa to
securely consume open source software
and it's not just open source software
it's also the software we're getting
from our vendors and our third parties
and other places we can use salsa to
ensure that the software they created
and the software we are using are
actually the same one and nothing has
been tampered with
so how does salsa actually does that
to understand that we need to be aware
of a few basic terminologies now these
terminologies are going to be used a lot
throughout this presentation as well as
if when you explore salsa by yourself
you come across them quite a bit so it's
quite important that we covered them
the first two major ones I'm going to
cover are two big words provenance and
attestation so what do they even mean
provenance is basically
some very viable information that helps
us understand whether a piece of
software has been tampered or not so it
is information like where when and how
something was produced
that's basically it
and the other word is attestation
think of attestation like a certificate
an automated way provenance can be
verified so oftentimes it is machine
readable metadata about different stages
of the software development life cycle
and different stages of that software
and using that certificate we can show
that the authenticity authenticity for
example when the software after it is
built and before it is packaged
attestation is can be like a certificate
where we we can go like is this software
secure it hasn't been tampered with if
if not then we we continue using it
the other two ones I want to cover is
artifacts and sdlc artifacts is
basically a general way of saying that
this is a piece of data it can be
anything like a file a commit or even a
container image
and then lastly something I'm going to
use a lot is sdlc which is just an
acronym for software development life
cycle but in case anyone is not familiar
with it I thought I'll just give a heads
up
so going back to the question how does
sal salsa ensure integrity
it does it by two basic pillars which I
like to feed it as I as I like to view
it the first one is attestation the
other one is hardening
so remember the problem that throughout
our software development life cycle we
had no way to communicate that hey or
check that hey this is has this piece of
software been tampered has some
malicious actor been uh com has made it
compromised so attestation using salsa
and things it uh the checklist is
provides to give attestation throughout
that software development life cycle you
can basically check that whether
something has been tampered or not
so throughout that life cycle it it's
something some similar to a certificate
is generated that that can be used to
verify the Integrity of it and the salsa
steps uh prepares your infrastructure
for those
um Integrity checks
the other part is the hardening so we
are not just relying on the certificate
but also the salsa Frameworks if you
follow the different steps and the
levels it will help your entire software
development environment to be more
secure and resilient especially against
tampering
so what again the two ways salsa really
provides value is that way of
certificate generation and attestation
and the other one is hardening the
platform itself
and
the way you do it is by following the
salsa levels so again remember the
roadmap we spoke about that hey salsa
provides you a roadmap to gradually
improve it and these are the levels that
form that road map so in level one you
have more simple and easy to easily
adoptable things to do and all the way
to level four things get much more
complex to implement but as you are
climbing through the levels and
implementing different things in salsa
you're securing your supply chain more
and more
and if we look at the all the different
things salsa provides you uh this
lightning talk will become a full-blown
boot camp honestly so we'll we won't get
to cover every single aspect of it but
we'll see how salsa provides the
protection it's a different layer by
some practical examples
let's zoom into the source side so again
this slide is very content heavy you I'm
not expecting all of you to read it you
can look these things up in the Salsa's
website slsa.dev which I'll link after
but this is to show that salsa provides
you with actionable steps that help you
climb the levels one by one
and this is for things like source for
your build your package and many other
things
but what exactly salsa is trying to
achieve here
if I try to distill that previous slide
into this high level things what salsa
is trying to do is establish a change uh
his uh have a change history which we
can then go and verify and validate so
we can then go see at any point of time
if anything has changed what has changed
who changed and when
similarly for source which is a lot of
the case out the source code
only trusted people can add and update
the code so
the higher you climb up in the levels of
salsa the more authentication and
authenticity you need to be able to add
and remove code similarly unvetted code
cannot reach the users so if you distill
all those steps it just becomes to these
three high level things that salsa is
trying to help you achieve
similarly let's have a look what are
some of the things salsa is trying to do
with build
again it provides us with a lot of
actionable items from making our builds
scripted and automatic to hardening the
build environment by making it more
isolated short-lived and no internet
access and different things and as you
climb up the uh the ranks and the levels
the harder and the stronger your
environment becomes
if we again distill those things
regarding the build salsa is just
providing us these three key steps the
first one is automating the build
process so there is less scope of
intervention and someone so someone can
manually intervene and puts put in some
malicious stuff and tamper with it and
it's not just a build process salsa
focuses on the environment as well so
making the environment isolated from the
internet making the environment
short-lived and a few different other
tactics you can really Harden the
environment where your software is being
built and packaged
and it's not just the hardening of the
build process and the package if you
follow the salsa steps and the checklist
it gives you the ability to check your
bills throughout that process what I
mean by that is let's say you have made
a build you can then programmatically or
manually check is this the build that I
was supposed to get did anyone manage to
put in some malicious piece of code or
any dependency or anything like that
that can also be achieved
and all these is uh done via something
called the provenance the provenance
allows you to verify all these things by
giving you a Common Language to validate
this externally and internally so what
it means is we can tell to our customers
that hey this is how we are doing salsa
these are the different steps and this
is this is actually what we're doing and
it's not just about telling it they can
also verify that the software you have
created and the one they have is is the
same one and how that's where when you
achieve the things may have mentioned in
the provenance section allows you to do
that and it's not just for the customers
we can also require salsa from our
vendors we can ask the vendors to
um
for half certain salsa levels and they
can show us on that they're maintaining
it and we can go and verify it using the
provenance rules
so
all these are great but salsa is not a
silver bullet
there are certain things salsa doesn't
cover as well and I'll cover a couple of
things I've I've talked about so far
which is the source and build so if you
have things like not following the the
practice of least privilege or if you
have vulnerabilities in your code salsa
can really help with it
similarly if the source control itself
like git is compromised again that's not
something salsa can help you with that's
an additional thing you need to secure
similarly with the build
if your environment if you if you're not
building from the secure environment and
from somewhere else
all this effort you've done it really
becomes again fruitless
similarly if build platforms like one or
Travis Ci or GitHub or Docker or
whatever it is has some issues again you
that's something salsa can help with
salsa is more focused on the tampering
side and tampering only
well that's all I get to cover in a
lightning talk if you want to know salsa
in depth and you want to figure out how
to establish that in your company go to
salsa.dev or just Google salsa framework
you can also check out guac which is not
a framework coming which pairs up nicely
with salsa and I'll make one last
Shameless plug to wrap up my talk like
kavika mentioned I run a YouTube channel
with a friend called Everything cyber
where I create similar long and short
form contents like this so things like
Hands-On Labs thought experiments
interviews with industry experts and
much more you can find the Social Links
for that as well as the links to that
the slides both PDF and canva in this QR
code thanks all from me um thank you for
listening and if you have any questions
feel free to ask them thanks
amazing thank you so much for that okay
if it was really I think salsa is one of
those Frameworks I think you did a
really good job of like breaking it down
in 15 minutes
document dedicated to that so but I
think that was really well done and
thank you a good mention for guac as
well I don't know how far they're going
to take the whole self and what yeah
of it like all the names at least it's
easy to remember right like we love our
acronyms in uh cyber security uh I do
have a problem here joining us as well
so we previously obviously had uh kavika
co-hosting with me and now I will have
promo co-hosting the next hour with me
uh but before anything just wanted to
say thank you for the talk uh carefood
was lovely having you on dev second we
will move you to the back screen because
we do have the next speaker the fun
thing about lightning talks is you know
they're quick and fast and you know they
come really quickly but thank you so
much for joining us thank you