all right so our next talk uh in line
with the devsecops theme of the event is
we have uh John coming on to talk with
us about simplifying infrastructure as
code security now before you bring John
in I'm going to give you a little bit of
his background so John is the co-founder
and CTO of scizo hopefully I'm
pronouncing that right where he's
responsible for the research and
refinement of cloud native Security
Solutions including contributing to open
source projects and Industry standards
focused on zero trust devsecops and
Cloud security
he's also a Sans author for the SEC 540
Cloud security and devops automation
courses
um an Ians faculty member recipient of
the 2021 startup innovator of the Year
award and active member of the cncf tag
Security Group he's also the founder of
the Steel City infosec Meetup the
pitstack collaboration space and is a
core organizer of b-sides Pittsburgh
in his free time he enjoys mountain
biking weightlifting chess and spending
time with his family sounds like a
really interesting dude so why don't we
bring him in Brian sounds good
thanks for having me I didn't have to
read all of that
I'm not gonna sell you short okay people
need to know every detail about your
life in order to get the full experience
you know that's what we're all about
here okay okay there we go okay cool
John is the name of the company a play
on on CSO like uh yeah yeah it's
actually pronounced see so
um technically know how you pronounce it
but it's my company I get the pronounce
it how I like
oh yeah it's a play on CSO it's also a
Japanese term that means like neat clean
and organized so the idea is like
complexity causes security issues keep
it simple yeah love it I I apologize for
completely butchering that and I only
now get it as soon as I heard Brian say
it I was like this makes perfect sense
yeah yeah no worries no worries
well um yeah so John what are you gonna
be talking about today I mean we know
simplifying IEC security but what in
particular are you going to be uh
teaching people yeah so um I've done a
lot of different rollouts of
infrastructures code using different
tools and I've made a lot of mistakes so
this talk is mostly about outlining
those mistakes during the rollout and
then particularly the adding security
into those more distributed larger
deployments we're going to focus on
terraform uh for a bit because that
seems to be the most popular one but you
know I've seen terraform deployments
that have hundreds of different repos
just internally for their terraform code
and like how do you scale security out
to that that large uh without messing it
all up and breaking developers builds so
that's the idea
amazing well hey we're gonna pass the
the stage over to you and looking
forward to uh learning a bit more about
IC security so take it away yep sounds
good
cool
very cool there we go hi I need my
little typing thing to work I love this
uh hi everybody my name is John ziola
welcome to my talk on infrastructure is
code security
so uh this is this is really great I
think the timing is perfect coming right
after Dulles uh so I don't have to cover
a lot of this uh background stuff but
just a quick primer to myself I live in
Pittsburgh Pennsylvania and like was
mentioned I work at this company called
CSO the co-founder and CTO and we get
mid-sized tech companies you know that
use uh Cloud native Technologies sock 2
ISO 27001 bedramp things like that and
in ways that don't frustrate your
developers hopefully uh I teach some
Sans classes I do a conference in fact
that's the mug that I'm drinking out of
today
uh security Meetup uh community and I
love doing open source thing so cncf is
where I post most of my time spend most
of my time but I also do some work in
the open ssf
all right so we're going to kind of
Breeze through the background here
because like I said that's already been
uh been covered in the prior talk uh so
what is infrastructure's code it's
managing and provisioning computer data
with these machine readable definition
files and really that's the key these
these machine readable definition files
you could consider them code you can
call them configuration too I won't be
offended
um but you know it's it's one of those
uh two things that's what we're talking
about here so what does that actually
look like so for the rest of this talk
we're going to focus on terraform and so
here is a little bit of terraform as an
example you can see we're making this
generic AWS instance called server we're
making one of them you know pretty
pretty straightforward
uh but it's really what's really cool
about infrastructure is code is you can
use it to build one thing and then you
can use very small changes to that to
make hundreds of a thing right so now
we've got 100 of these servers instead
of just one just by changing that number
from a one to a 100
very awesome uh but now we need to think
about security right and so if you think
about security here what what is that
Ami you don't really know what is in
that Ami is it vulnerable has it been
patched Etc
um so we need to know as a centralized
security team maybe what is in this
infrastructure's code that all of these
distributed teams are deploying
so that's a quick introduction but uh
here's your infrastructure's code it's
rotten to the core I love this this
there was a report done by sneak in 2021
that talked about infrastructure as code
and they described how 63 of companies
reported that they're just starting out
seven percent of companies uh are
implementing the current best best
practices meaning 93 of companies are
reporting themselves as not doing that
and 41 of these uh respondents said that
the barrier was unclear benchmarks for
security and this is something that
really frustrates me like as someone who
spends a lot of time developing I can
appreciate as a developer like how do I
know this is secure or not that's really
maybe not my domain if I was a developer
uh and it's our job I think as the
security teams to uh clearly inform
development teams on what's okay and
what's not okay and if we can't automate
that and distribute it into their
pipelines and um make it easy for them
to understand good or not good that's
kind of our fault as a security team and
not necessarily the Developers for
writing insecure code so that's
something I like to kind of bring on to
ourselves but it's all right we're all
in this together uh we are going to try
to work on a solution here so
um just another quick primer specific to
terraform there's a couple of phases of
maturity that environments often go
through
um when they're implementing terraform
or as their infrastructures code tool of
choice you'll start with this like
all-in-one approach where you might have
a repository a couple repositories and
you get these really long uh
terraform.tf files and it would look a
little something like this this isn't
long in fact this is fairly short but
you can imagine it would just keep going
and keep going and keep going here we've
got a light still light cell instance
and uh it is using a random name from
this block down here everything is in
this block to make that server uh all
you need to do is pass in a couple of
variables right uh and make sure that
you have this the script
um pretty straightforward so that's how
infrastructure code would typically
start but then as you mature you'll
start to use these things called local
modules a local module might mean that
you have a file which is up top which is
really just pointing to code somewhere
else and then you've actually got that
code that's somewhere else right so
you're going to point to it pass your
variables and now you've got a little
bit of a decoupling but it's only file
based so you can see here we're pointing
to the modules directory in the same
folder structure git repository so
that's like the first step of decoupling
but really the pansia uh is these remote
modules where you have a similar sort of
approach the only change here is that
that source is actually another git
repository and what's really special is
that you can have this revision at the
end so you can use a commit hash or a
tag or something along those lines or
Branch name
uh and you can version pin those so this
allows you to decouple you can make
changes to your module and then the this
code block at the top sometimes called a
live
um is is decoupled so your module can be
changing a bunch and then you can update
your live to the latest module when it
makes sense especially if the module
doesn't meet your needs etc for whatever
reason so you get to this point you've
now got a mature infrastructures code
terraform-based stack that's awesome
uh and now you want to implement
security scanning so all right so how do
we start from here well you might go on
the internet you might find a tool uh
kicks is the one that I'm going to be
using in this example it's from check
marks I think it's a pretty good tool it
does infrastructure as code scanning
um and so you'll have to change
directory into you know the right folder
that has the terraform you want to run a
terraforma knit first because you need
to pull in all your providers and your
dependencies then you run your kick scan
okay great but we've got more than one
environment so now we're going to change
into the environment uh to directory and
do the same thing we're getting a little
fed up with that so now we're going to
put it all in one big line CD and and
init and and scan okay great and if
you're like me you'll keep getting fed
up running the same commands over and
over you'll start making monstrosities
like this so now you're trying to like
automatically detect where the terraform
is using a find command using push D to
jump into that right place run those
couple commands and then pop D to jump
out of it you're also now outputting
results uh into a certain directory so
you could look at it later all right
we're getting better uh we're getting
better but there's still lots of issues
here um so we've done this we we ran
this big one-liner and we've got 100
repositories of terraform and we get our
results so we start taking the book of
the results and you know if you're
anything like me when you look at these
numbers you give it a little something
like that
um so 12 000 findings 2500 highs and
this is actually a real result from
um a this is uh from one of my clients
where I ran security scans this is one
of their repositories of which they had
hundreds
1200 findings okay that's great so
um what do we do even do now like how do
you even start like okay you can start
at the highest but there's 2585 of them
all right we've got to do something
about this
um and then you start to dig even
further and you might even find out
something like this so in the check
marks kicks documentation they say that
they don't support custom modules at all
so this mature approach like if you've
read the book terraform up and running
they recommend having this sort of a
design well this is this is explicitly
not uh supported by Kicks but it's not
on their
um readme.md you have to go under docs
platforms MD go to terraform modules and
find this one line in there that was
actually added because I asked them to
add it because they didn't support this
right so all right great we've done all
this work we have all these findings and
kicks doesn't even support our
deployment mechanism well that's not
that's not great so we've we've made a
mistake right
um and that happens to all of us I'm
hoping that everybody here can learn
from my mistakes I've made these many
many many times
and so you can look at a repository like
this IAC security tool compare I love
this repository just kind of outlines
the different options that you have to
do security scanning
um against different infrastructures
code environments you can see Kix is on
here but so are lots of others sneak is
a great tool Terror scan my favorite of
these is actually check off for for most
scenarios but Cloud rail has its own
uses all of these have their own Niche
but checkoff is my generic favorite
so I ran into uh that I encountered all
of these different tools I ran into lots
of issues deploying them detecting files
and then you need to manage whether or
not you fail the build or not right we
don't want to make our developers angry
we maybe even want them to be able to
disable security for a time period
um but still gather information there's
all these things that we might want to
do and if you've got this in hundreds of
different repositories now you've got to
manage all those different repositories
you want to centralize things right so I
made this tool called easy infra short
for easy infrastructures code and the
idea is that I would just make a Docker
container open it up on the internet
employ a lot of these tactics inside the
container and allow you just like flip
them on and off
so here's a deployment example with
Jenkins but this is very similar for uh
if you're using like gitlab with gitlab
runners or GitHub actions or pipes it's
all very similar ideas but with this
Jenkins CI example I think it's really
um nice to see like on the left is
before probably what you're doing before
implementing easy Iron front and the
right is after and if you look closely
enough you'll see that only one line has
changed and that's the environment in
which the commands are being run so this
terraform init validate apply those are
just happening inside of this container
instead of this one and magically the
security stuff is just happening like
that's the that's the main benefit that
easy infra brings all you have to do is
run terraform in the easy infra
terraform container and you get
terraform security if you run ansible in
the easy infra ansible container you get
ansible security
Etc right it's completely transparent
uh and there's a whole bunch of
different uh features I don't have a ton
of time to go through all of them but
there's a learning mode feature so you
can find out if it would have failed the
build but don't actually fail the build
bring that Telemetry locally and uh
evaluate it
um they have centralized logging and it
supports 38 different destinations so
everything that you can expect from your
splunks and Elk Stacks to syslog Cloud
watch S3 buckets you know whatever it's
all supported it has an arbitrary
hooking framework so say what easy infra
is doing is in what you want to do you
can install a hook and do whatever you
want to do you can bring your own
binaries you can bring your own bash
scripts and it will hook the terraform
commands or ansible commands Etc and run
what you tell it to do so you need to
provide some sort of custom Telemetry
your repositories are special in some
way and you need to do something a
little different that's all built in
and a bunch of other stuff too right
and just because I don't have time to
roll for them I could do a demo if
everyone would allow me but
um
uh this is what uh just a quick grafana
dashboard and a low-key environment
setup would look like so you can see
here we've got all of the times that
easy infra had security turned off but
ran so this allows you to deploy easy
infra and make sure the basic things are
operating the right terraform versions
are being detected so the cool thing is
it actually Auto detects the right
version of terraform that the code
requires switches to that version on the
Fly and then uses it for your commands
so you don't have to hard code any sort
of versions you can put it in the code
as the terraform required version
uh and um so you want to make sure that
that sort of stuff works and it'll
centralize logs even when it's the
security scans are turned off so now you
know when your security is turned off
and that information is just really good
but then there's other basic things you
can know when it runs but found no
issues that's a good thing when it round
and uh when it ran and found an issue
but didn't fail to build so it was
suppressed it would have failed the
build in the future if you turn blocking
mode on but it's in like audit mode so
don't fail the build and then down here
is when are you actually failing the
build how bad is your environment uh
getting blocked or stopped or slowed
down Etc and then at the bottom we've
got our raw logs
so like I said I do have a demo set up
but I think I'm pretty much at time here
so
um
uh yeah let me know should I go forward
with a demo or
do we have some questions
I know we do have one question uh that
came up in the middle of that but uh I I
don't think we'll have time for the demo
just to keep things succinct here but I
appreciate you offering to do that John
and that would be fun to see maybe in a
future session
um so I know uh really quick Randall was
here to introduce you about knowing that
you were talking about containers there
and that's like a buzzword you say that
like three times that brings up our
buddy Eric and so we kicked Randall out
and we're now bringing on Eric to help
talk about this stuff too so everybody
say hi to Eric real quick
hi Eric
what's up Eric welcome learn to unmute
myself like normal hey everybody yes so
the one question we had was uh I believe
it still applies to infrastructure's
code comments and discussion around
there
was if you had any suggestions on tools
for other types of infrastructure as
code like for example cloud formation
cdk for AWS things like that
yeah so a lot of the tools that I was
talking about have support for multiple
infrastructures code systems so like
check off supports home and and things
like that sneak I believe supports a
bunch uh kicks definitely supports a
bunch in fact if you go to like the
check off repository and you just scroll
down a little bit
um oh maybe it's not in here
um
they they do have a whole list of
uh logos and things like that that they
support here it's a little bit better it
doesn't work great on the dark mode but
terraform kubernetes grpc cross plane
plumony you know all this stuff so these
vendors are support you know multiple
different deployment mechanisms and then
uh in Easy infra I actually just did a
huge refactor and I'm going to be
supporting that in Easy infra too so
cloud formation is is high on the list
cross plane Etc
nice thank you for that uh Eric Micah
any questions for John I'll check the
chat at the same time as well
nothing here I was able to uh come back
uh just after you started so it was a
great great presentation thanks a lot
John
awesome yeah for sure excellent stuff uh
I don't see any questions in the chat
but I guess one more thing for you John
if folks want to get in touch with you
ask you more questions about this stuff
afterwards where's the best place to
find you
yeah so the project I was talking about
is available on GitHub C2 loc slash easy
infra yep there we go and then uh if you
want to reach out to me you can hit me
up on LinkedIn it's just my name John
Zola
awesome awesome great stuff
well thank you so much John appreciate
you coming on here and chatting with us
about that and teaching us about
simplifying IAC we'll see you around bud
thanks for having me okay talk to you
later see ya