yeah I definitely do so um
next up we have Frederico hakamani and
uh he is a Brazilian a pomerency an
engrocker fan of good software Legos
he's a brewmaster
and he is I can confirm a jack of all
trades but I refuse to say the part of
his bio that he put forward which is
master of none he's mastered a lot of
things and
um I'm really glad that he's gonna speak
for us here today
um he and I work together at OCTA and uh
we we've talked at various conferences
and he's an all-around great guy in
addition to being an amazing
technologist and we were we were having
fun with ngrap before before he went and
went to work for engrock so it's cool to
see you there now too Frederica
Let's uh let's bring him in
there he is hi folks
good morning good evening I don't I
don't know where you are I know this is
happening around the world so happy to
be here so happy to see pretty familiar
face uh thanks for the intro man man
yeah
I I tried to measures up by creeping to
some things
um I'm here to talk about one of these
we're not tripping acting yet
it's web hooks it's it's so fun so hope
you guys can see my screen
not yet not yet you need to share your
screen and then we can add it to the
stream we're also getting a little bit
of echo
oh oh I'm getting it cool let's see if
it gets better now
uh
is it better now there we go
okay
audience right so shall we uh kick it
off you ready to go
yeah all right all right there we go
okay thank you thank you guys thanks for
being here I'm here to talk about to
talk about ways to make security better
my name is Fred again I work at ingrock
um and I'm here to touch to touch three
things first just quick recap of web
hooks him security sites so there are
some things on the architecture that
that when it comes to security
second I show you some of the finds oh
I'm getting some Reverb
um
let's see
let me switch to the built-in mic yeah
it could be everyone though
okay
just you know a little little visit from
the demo monster it happens oh yeah uh
it happens to me all the time
is this better
I think it is better okay cool wow
looked off his weeny wire today
um okay so continuing with where we were
um my goal is to go through three things
specific recap of web books more from
the security side show you some findings
of a research we did with over 100
different web hook implementations in
talk about things you can do to make
webhook security better whether you are
a listener in your consuming those
whether you are serving others with that
in with that together in the third eye
pin actually give you some action or
give you some things to do to help the
community make better web hook security
so let's get going
um this is a quick presentation I'm
going to share this link with you later
so you can have access to the Dax
um
as webhooks starting with a quick intro
many people already are familiar with
web hooks because if you see them you
love them right web hooks are one of the
best scenes ever most important things
uh it allows you to build applications
that react to events so instead of let's
say to a traditional API if you're
integrating with video go the next video
all the time hey if you have a new
message I can work on just send an URL
to Twitter say tell me when it happens
instead of me calling you all the time
until it sends you that it's great for
twilio it's great for you because
there's no overhead there there isn't a
bunch of calls going on
however that changes the game a little
bit in terms of security
the first thing is that most of the
security responsibilities that would
typically go with the two idios side of
things let's say the provider it goes to
the consumer so in a pulling strategy
Twitter is checking your authentication
for Keys it's checking your offs they
implement the dolls and all bunch of
things whereas on the web hooks that
responsibility most of the times relies
on the listener's side
and the second thing is that related to
this
that you don't necessarily need to do
all the security stuff in order to be
successful or functional if you will so
this is me creating a something to do
crazy stuff with my CD if I get a web
hook notification from GitHub and
because I'm a lazy developer I didn't do
a bunch of stuff on security there's
just a to-do for YouTube and that's
actually uh bad in terms of security and
not even doing Authentication
the these ones are fairly know if you're
familiar with web hooks but there's a
third caveat
there are so many different ways to
secure web Hooks and it's so easy to
ignore that because when you think of
web hooks you think of simplicity
uh so at engrock my current gig we
started implementing webhook
Integrations for service we're doing
over there uh module and the first time
we started scoping for this work we were
like yeah it's going to be simple we're
going to do a bunch of deals but after
going through many different of those as
a responsible developer we started
seeing some differences that makes work
make work for us a little bit harder uh
and it liked about in our heads so the
first thing is that when starting
implementing security for web hooks
seven out of 10 web books will present
some differences even with most web
hooks using uh hmac signatures so you
signed a body you send it over and use
that there's a way of doing
authentication and message Integrity
many do in different ways so half we use
we're doing coding with base64 the other
half with text they will they will hash
different parts of the message it goes
all over
and only a few percentage of web books
will Implement more controls which you
should be leveraging as a listener so it
gets very hard to do it right
and as a responsible developer as well
because uh security do not necessarily
stand in between the success and getting
that web hook call done done uh you end
up having to read a bunch more docs and
have to build a much more than just like
getting that get started and run with it
so the getting started will just get you
to understand the webhook message but
adding security around that in a right
way requires you to go through a bunch
of different documentations and explore
how that thing would work
foreign
nice thank you for showing you all the
problems we have in the world what we
can do to fix this
so the best way we can see we could
think about when we tackle this problem
we would look at that we started
actually cataloging those scenes as we
were implementing the Integrations
ourselves we thought that why we cannot
change the world we can make it a little
bit better to help people spot the
parents and see how good looks like
that's in a website called webbooks.fyi
that you can go and check it out
yourself I'm gonna go through some of
the findings we got from this place and
share some easy ways and strategies you
can do better web hook as a listener or
as a consumer or as a society
starting with the providers so if you
are a set service or if you are creating
your service and you want to send web
books to people these are some of the
things you can do that are very easy to
do uh in general and that will help
people a lot providing amazing
documentations but obvious always good
Implement security when you send a
message as well don't treat that just as
a responsibility to The Listener data
feeds you can do in this front improve
secret Keys strong encryption and
hashing signature payload leverage the
payload and signature not only for body
but others implementary plate prevention
versioning compensatory controls uh the
listing is like a shopping list like how
do I do this how do I get this right uh
the suggestion here is to copy from the
grades
um there are many great patterns
implemented throughout the industry not
necessarily consistently but when you go
through those things let's say webhook
security and you see things like how do
I do one-time verification on how do I
build amazing documentation you can go
through web hooks FYI and see what you
need to do or what are the grades to
copy from great example of that square
would tell you how to which events you
can listen to how you should subscribe
to events or stripe does a great job
with telling you how to retry a web Hook
when something doesn't go right
insecurely copy the grades you should be
good on that front use this as a catalog
please
as a listener these are some of the best
practices you can do
um you say yes
ensure you you are actually leveraging
security rather than just putting the
to-do like I did with my node.js app
restrict access my ID storing secret
segmenting rotating using robust
algorithms calling back the service if
you're not sure and one thing you will
notice is that many of these spanners
are the sync patterns you're using When
developing safe web apps or apis so if
you pay attention very well to those
endpoints you're providing you should
have that same level of attention to how
you listen to the world
there are some things as an industry
that's a little bit hard to do but see
it's important to do so there are some
standards uh you're seeing some of the
most popular ones here uh you can see
the ietf HTTP message signatures which
is very promising so they're trying to
uh create a spec for signing entity
messages because
ATP message signature is the most
popular authentication mechanism in web
books it will certainly influence uh the
whole industry in the right direction
same goes with Cloud events they are
both trying to do the same thing so one
is ietf the other one is by the cloud
native Foundation
um also there are other fees specific to
security like the open ID share signals
and secrets and the rest hooks it's an
initiative from that year uh this is
something that's going on here
because there are many standards there
is a let's say a arms race here to see
who's gonna win or who's gonna be the
most prevalent one uh as an individual
you can contribute to some of those or
you can actually help build awareness
yourself
here are some of the ways to to help out
the the industry
um
everybody that develops a web hook or
consumes a web hook uh is in a unique
position if you're a responsible
developer you will need to do some of
those things we talked about right you
would need to parse the documentation
figure out the things that needs to be
used and how to use them so if you're in
the middle of doing that go to the
places where these things are being
cataloged and tell the world about it it
could be both in web hooks FYI and also
the awesome web list from RE real adult
that's really really good actually we we
recommend that as well it's a great
place and if you're a provider follow
the good patterns uh see what good looks
like from other providers and also list
your provider uh so proud that you're
there
um this is my call for you to action uh
go and figure out help us out I'm here
to answer any questions you have about
webhook security I can go into some of
these deep items for you tell some of
our findings we have that in a blog as
well that I'm gonna share uh we walk
through all the different patterns all
the things that are right the things
that are actually kind of scary and even
uh frustrating about the experience
uh with that oh that's it back for
questions
foreign
I dropped in a quick question would you
say on the slide where you were showing
the various
standards like open ID and HD would you
say any one of them is ahead of any
other at this point like is one kind of
emerging as a leader
I many of those right now they are on on
the draft specs and they are on on like
open for comments they really like the
ITF message signature
and uh Cloud event it's it's hard to
pick a fake one they they're very good
they're doing scenes that are very hard
to do
um I'll give you a good example so Cloud
events they they are very opinionated
about
uh including your payload and signature
the header
in a certain kind of header so uh let's
say you're making a a web hook call like
the message tells you some information
that you should be taken forward but the
header might tell that many times great
example is a time stamp so headers
typically carry a timestamp to to
prevent replay attacks
Cloud event is very opinionated about
the timestamp it says it should be Unix
uh so that like takes a lot of
hesitation on how it should do and you
should uh include these headers as part
of your signature and then there's
versiony as well so I really like their
work over there uh I'm not saying ITF is
not doing a great job as well uh so it's
it's an arms race it's great for the
industry
thank you I've been using web hooks for
a long time and I've seen just in terms
of like security patterns over the years
things have sort of shifted I remember
originally when web hooks were first
sort of gaining popularity there was no
concept of validating a request or
figuring out who sent it
um I think eventually people sort of
move to like having a shared key sort of
model
um do you think like what do you think
is happening in terms of the security
side of web hooks just in the future
given all the changes that have been
happening in the last handful of years
yeah
um web hooks they they are a very
interesting space because like the
mission number one two and three is
building for Simplicity which I I
Honestly Love uh but it also makes
security challenging at some time so I
see hashing hashes it still has a great
way of doing that some some
implementations are trying to add uh
oauth you know trying to add inside that
that that's amazing at one place because
if you use let's say jokes uh it's great
because there's key rotation happens
automatically but or else it's hard to
implement so
um what you're seeing in the marketplace
these days is like
hashing of more things in things that
add additional security
so timestamps is an example version is
another one
um
there are many many interesting
implementations out there there are some
people also using just the jwk parts to
distribute Keys that's really sweet and
interesting uh yeah but there is still a
lot of things using basic authentication
out there uh I believe in our research
we found 15 percent of implementations
using it a bunch of implementations
using xiaowan and hash signatures that's
kind of scary
I actually have a couple Production
Services I run as hobby projects which
are still using basic off for a variety
of these things yeah
um
yes
um compensatory controls
share those with us live right now yeah
let's share right now
don't think so I I don't wanna I I don't
want to tell which ones but I can tell
where to look at uh there's a web hook
directory in webhooks.fyi and you can
look at the signing algorithm using use
by own some of those and the security
controls they're implementing or not
um while this should be used for good uh
it can also provide you some information
of things that need to step up
ouch awesome well do we have any
additional question or if you have any
additional questions for Frederico
please drop them in the chat right now
before we pull in our next speaker
um I also did see someone suggested uh
people check out this uh awesome web
hooks repository on GitHub so thank you
for sharing that and um yeah if there's
anything else you want to plug Frederico
are there any cool projects you think
people should check out or blogs they
should read or people they should follow
on Twitter this is your chance to uh get
the plug out there yeah uh awesome web
books is is a great place to go for uh
we draw we we got a lot of inspiration
from there
um as for the great examples uh I really
like what
strike is doing Zoom came up with a
brand new web hook implementation that's
very elegant as well uh and there are a
lot of great people catching up fast so
um spot is doing a great job with
versioning these are some like examples
I wish I could point that one example
and say like follow this company they're
doing amazing work but unfortunately
that doesn't exist today which goes to
show that we have a lot to do with about
hooks in terms of security but
um those are some of the cool things I
can point you towards
awesome
well thank you so much for coming by
it's so good to see you and amazing talk
yeah uh yeah thanks again
yeah thank you guys uh so great seeing
you all
um all right yeah see you it's in your
Fred