but with that without further Ado who
wants to introduce our keynote well I I
I'm gonna do this why don't we do this
why don't we say I'm gonna read you the
introduction and not name the person so
if you're watching the stream and you
can guess their name you are going to
get extra prizes so drop the name in the
chat if you think you know who we have
coming up but this person is an
international speaker
panelist and Cloud security thought
leader an advisor with over 11 years of
expertise and business risk management
and Leadership she's the co-founder and
producer of the globally top 100 ranked
technology podcast and wildly popular
Cloud security podcast she's also a lead
program manager sneak she's passionate
about making Cloud security knowledge
accessible through Global and local
initiatives like the global Cloud
security and devops communities
and with extensive experience in
leadership risk management and regulated
finance and insurance Industries she's
passionate about nurturing Future
Leaders and advocates in Cloud security
so any guesses who are amazing keynote
speaker is
okay we saw a hint there all right let's
welcome her to the stream welcome Shelby
thank you for having this is quite the
crew over here
thank you guys
is most famous for yelling at Developers
yeah that could be the meme for 2023 I
think
you know the the one thing I didn't
include in the intro which would have
been too much of a giveaway is that you
just hosted the devset con uh apj
session just you know eight hours ago or
so so first of all thank you you did an
amazing job it was so good and so fun
thank you fun fact uh it is 4 am here in
Australia and also this morning when I
woke up I realized all my slides had
crashed so that was so fun so I've had
to so apologies if they're going to be a
bit Scrappy but um because I've had to
redo them all but I was like you know
what this is exactly what uh what my
talk is about open source and this is
what exactly having open source
sometimes can feel like when you find
out there's a vulnerability and you have
to like kind of scramble together so I'm
in the right mindset for the talk but
yeah it was quite a fun morning middle
of the night let's just say that
well sometimes thank you for uh being
such a trooper
absolutely
well without further Ado everyone we're
gonna let Shelby take it away so she'll
be thank you so much and excited to hear
what you have to say
amazing thank you guys
perfect thanks everyone for joining and
as I was telling um the awesome hosting
crew over here that this morning I did
realize when I went into my slides that
half of them had disappeared but
um I said you know what let's just look
at it as a positive and I'm gonna put
myself in the mind frame of often what
happens when you use open source
software and you realize that there has
been a vulnerability in it you know that
can leave you scrambling for things at
the last minute as well
um so you know I'm sort of gonna channel
that a little bit today and I'll
probably put that into the ethos but um
I think the team has done an amazing job
of introducing me so I'm not going to go
into a intro about me obviously if you
look me up or Cloud security podcast you
should be able to find me but let's get
into it so what is open source I think
most people attending um this talk would
be familiar with what open source is but
I just thought I would level the playing
field a little bit I'm also a big Harry
Potter fan so I've tried to put a bit of
Harry Potter fun in there just to you
know sort of uh keep everyone upbeat
so open source obviously as everyone
knows usually would be some sort of a
source code that anyone can inspect
modify or enhance
um it's pretty much you know software
that other people can improve on
um just a couple of quick terminologies
obviously you've got people who maintain
it who would be the maintainers but also
there are people you can modify or
enhance the software and you would be
normally classified as contributors
there's a couple of sources that I've
put on the bottom which have a lot of
information about open source so if you
do want to sort of find out more about
Open Source you know do look those up
and they have a lot of information in
terms of what open source is all about
so I will leave you to look at those
ones um so while we go through the list
of the um this talk I would like you to
sort of think about this that how can
you protect something that you haven't
built and you don't maintain so that is
pretty much what the mindset we've got
to be in when we're thinking about open
source because you're using software
often which you obviously haven't built
um but you're also not maintaining as
well and you know how can you protect
that we might feel a little bit like Ron
Weasley there with his expression
um so it may surprise some of you but
may not surprise some of you as well I
think there's been a lot of talk about
open source software this year because
of and I'm not going to mention uh the
word we must not mention uh so far so 70
to 90 percent of modern application
Stacks use open source software so as
you can imagine that is a lot of our
software out there currently that is
using open source
on the flip side it's only about nearly
only half of organizations out there
that actually have an open source
security policy in place so a lot of
Open Source software that's being
currently used but only half of it that
is currently being secured in
organizations or organizations are
thinking about policies to secure that
so one of the reasons why people do use
open source and um disclaimer I am a big
supporter of Open Source I think it
allows for a lot of innovation to happen
a lot of collaboration to happen it
allows a lot of um you know people to be
able to create new things because
they're building on something that
that's something that's already amazing
that's out there so there's you know if
you look at open UK which is the body I
think of earning open source in UK and
looking at different things there's lots
of really good reasons why organizations
use open source on the flip side there
are a lot of challenges as well that um
organizations do have when they're using
open source as well I think often
something that you would hear is that
there is a cost to using open source
even though it is often a free software
that you would be utilizing there is an
inherent course in terms of things that
you would have to put within your
organizations be it in training or
resources that you will have to put in
place so I think this this slide for me
which is out of that particular report
and again you can check that out if you
want in its entirety kind of summarizes
quite well what are the top benefits and
challenges
so what is the real danger with open
source software
um obviously we know it's widely used we
know that a lot of organizations
probably don't have a policy in place to
maintain it but to just to demonstrate
and there's a lot of examples out there
and I think earlier in the apj session
there was actually a really good talk
where someone actually listed out a
GitHub repository that they've got where
they've maintained a list of all the
open source hacks that have happened or
open source vulnerabilities that have
been known in the last few years so I
would probably plug that in later at
some point but there have been a lot but
I just wanted to flag a couple so this
is one particular one and it wasn't so
much a breach but a security researcher
was actually able to demonstrate that he
was able to attack a lot of these large
companies like apple Microsoft PayPal
and what he did is he uploaded a malware
to a open source repository which
included things like Pi Pi npm and Ruby
gyms it was automatically distributed
Downstream so what happened is anyone
who was using this open source
repository was able to receive this
malicious package automatically which
meant that you know this would um this
would impact their open source software
that they were utilizing
um so this was something that they
demonstrated now obviously this is
something a security researcher had done
so they did advice that you know this is
what I've done I understand that he was
able to get a bug Bounty for this and I
think overall he made I think 130 000
that's what I've learned and also an
award from um Apple I think for sort of
doing a responsible disclosure but that
is the real one of the real dangers that
just using a widely used open source
repository
um it can sort of you know affect a lot
of large companies so a lot of large
companies were using these open source
Repository
now he has done a really good blog as
well on this sort of talking through you
know his um the way he was thinking and
how he went about it so there's a really
nice blog I've just popped it on there
as well so if people want to sort of go
and have a read of it and really
understand what went behind that attack
that is there available for you guys as
well
okay so before I go into the next slide
I think I'm just gonna give a disclaimer
warning because I know this uh word sort
of triggers a lot of people just because
you know it caused so much stress to all
of us end of last year so a little bit
of inner peace and I'm talking about
log4 shell so obviously log for Shell
was something that ruined a lot of
Christmases um last year and it was a
sort of a really good reminder that what
um open source software when there is a
vulnerability in there can mean for us
um there is a really popular
um Java logging package which is your
Apache log 4J and that had a
vulnerability which could allow for a
remote code execution to happen and that
could be done just with a single
malicious code now um log4j is actually
really popular there's been over 400 000
downloads of this particular software so
as you can imagine it is widely used and
if you were anywhere within devsecops
security in a developer landscape you
would have heard about this so but I
just thought this this really sort of
drives home the message that there there
can be real challenges with using open
source
and just in terms of the impact from an
attack perspective there were over a
hundred attempts um just in the early
days every single day and in the first
week there were about almost over 800
000 attacks that have happened so the
scale of Um this can be quite large
going back to that 70 to 90 percent of
organizations actually utilizing open
source in their software so I think I've
set the scene for you know why open
source is something that we should be
concerned about you know we've open
sourced as I said
um but now what
so you can sometimes feel a little bit
like the miffler over here losing all
your gems uh when you know you're using
open source and all your vulnerabilities
and you find that there is a
vulnerability so I just thought that
would be a good imagery to put you in
so what are the certain things you can
do and I think this is where you might
start to notice my slides have gotten a
little bit scrappier because these are
the ones I've had to redo in the last um
you know 10-15 minutes
um so there's a few things out there
currently in terms of you know sort of
looking at open source and how do we
sort of attack something like open
source to be able to resolve it so the
first thing is community collaboration
so there's a lot of community
collaboration that is happening there is
open ssf which is part of the Linux
foundation and we will go that into that
a bit more there is Project Persia sorry
and you can't check that out as well
again a community collaboration looking
at ways to improve open source also
government bodies so the White House has
obviously gotten involved with open
source with their Federal mandate about
s-bomb and as I previously mentioned
there is also open UK that is another
body that is looking at open source
um just being from Australia I thought
it would be worthwhile just mentioning
you know we do have a an open source
industry in Australia as well that is
looking after that as well in terms of
tooling you know there is a few things
that you can do to look at your open
source so you can use static code
analysis a tool like maybe sneak and you
can complement that with a test or
assessed which is your dynamic or a
static application security testing
there are lots of really good Frameworks
that are coming through so if you have
been watching this since apj we did have
actually a talk about the salsa
framework and someone who actually went
into the complementary guac as well so
that is another framework that you know
a lot of companies have been utilizing
to sort of look at their open source and
how do they manage that there is also a
secure software architecture from cncf
so for the purposes of this token
because it is a 30 minute talk I would
love to sort of go into all of these but
you know there just isn't enough time to
do it justice so I will just be focusing
on openssf so open ssf is a governing
body that that has come together really
with a lot of as you can see
organizations that have decided you know
what we do need to do something about
open source open source is something
that is being widely used within our
community
and this is something that we need to
really come together as a community to
address that and you can see all these
companies have come together to sort of
take a few initiatives to Target you
know how do we make sure that the open
source software that we're utilizing in
our programs in our software are secure
and I do encourage you guys to just sort
of go and look at open source they have
a website which talks a lot about that
but what they have put in place is this
um this plan which is called the open
source software security mobilization
plan
um now if you look at the components of
it there are 10 components in there and
all of it kind of would make sense to
you so there is things like you know
security education looking at risk
assessment looking at the adoption of
digital signatures and and I know we've
had a talk um in the apj session and I
know Randall who introduced
um me as well he did a talk on you know
what digital signature and code signing
does mean and you know how it what it
does mean for you your software as well
about memory safety incident response
doing better scanning and code audits
data sharing let's just talk about
s-bomb and that as well and also
improved software Supply chains there
there is a bit to go in there and they
actually do have a entire report that
talks through it now just for the
purposes of this talk you know I would
love to sort of dissect each and every
part of this but I've decided to sort of
pick three top things
um I think we're going to be talking
about digital signatures so you know
what can we do with digital signatures
to secure our open source software we're
going to be talking about code audits
things you can do with your code to
secure your open source and also I know
everyone's probably heard s-bombs quite
a bit but I think I truly believe it's a
conversation that needs to keep
happening so we will sort of delve into
s-bombs as well so those are the three
components from the open source software
security mobilization plan that we'll be
focusing on
so the first one is the digital
signature of software so all the open
source software that you consume in your
organization you need to know that what
you're consuming is exactly what you're
in you're intending to use it for when
someone creates a particular software
um then it's modified often the
challenges that you do not know what the
modifications have been and if you were
intending to use that software for a
particular reason have there been any
changes so what the open ssf is
suggesting and they're proposing is they
want to drive some improvement of these
existing signing tools now if you were
at qcon earlier this year you may have
heard about Sig store
um which is now generally available so
that is one of the tools that is
available and it's really encouraging
that adoption of these open source
projects to make sure that you know you
know what open source software you're
using who was the author of that and
what are the changes that have been made
for that open source software now
they're hoping to do this through
various different ways is obviously
adoption of tools is one but also things
like you know training for the
maintainers who are a very very
important part of this and I think
um I really resonated with something
um that was said at the kubecon keynote
that we don't give enough support and
probably credit to a lot of these
maintainers who are you know sort of
maintaining these open source softwares
you know as a side project and out of a
labor of love so just doing more support
and training for that
um also the goal is they are looking at
the top 200 projects that are being
utilized across the board in various
different organizations and something
like I love 4J would have been part of
that and looking at ways to improve
software signing for those softwares so
that is one thing that has been
recommended
the other one is about third-party code
reviews
um so we're looking again at the most
um critical open source software by
having third-party firms do sort of a
code review for these and you know doing
a report that would be available for
everyone to find so if you're using a
particular open source you will be able
to look at that report and understand
you know are there any vulnerabilities
that I need to know of they are hoping
to cover the top 50 in the first year so
that's what they're currently working on
but the intention is that in the next
two and a half years they'll cover the
top 200. so you will be able to sort of
go back to this public report that
they're going to publish to be able to
see okay if I'm using say a log4j what
what does that code look like are they
certain things that I need to be aware
of as well
perfect
and again s form so I think I know I did
say this in the apj um session as well
but I I've been told that if you say s
Bond three times in 2022 a genie appears
so I'm gonna see if that Genie appears
for me
um s-bomb for anyone who isn't familiar
which I would I don't think there'll be
many people in uh in this cohort but
it's just a software bill of materials I
know one of the speakers before
um give an example of it being a recipe
of a chocolate chip cookie so it's just
pretty much everything that goes into
your software what is the ingredient
list as a lot of people have tried to
sort of explain it that way and they are
proposing that we need to do things to
improve as bomb tooling and training to
drive the adoption
um a lot of companies are providing s
forms these days but just in terms of
you know what the qualities of those
s-bombs is and how organizations are
actually utilizing that s-bomb at the
moment I think a lot of organizations
are still sort of looking at s-bombs
going yes if I do
find that there is a log for Shell
happening and I know one of my
software's uses a log4j I can go back to
that so there is that simple sort of
trajectory that people are mapping out
but I think what they're proposing is
that a little bit more sophistication so
working with developers to improve that
tooling also sort of baking in security
into a lot of those open source software
as well and sort of baking in that
s-bomb there's also a talk about a lot
of Education to happen in that space as
well so they've proposed things like you
know training having different templates
and pace and obviously Community
advocacy so just normalizing that
everyone who's creating open source or
any software is creating s-bombs and
also sort of consuming it now s-spom is
something that is mandated in the US by
the federal government for anyone who's
wanting to sell to the federal
government but it is something that is
being advocated in other countries as
well so in UK there's open UK in
Australia as well the government
actually encourages companies to have
response and utilize that
so that's all well and good I know these
are initiatives that we're talking about
and the reasons why I wanted to mention
these is that for organizations if you
are working with open source software
this is these are the kind of things you
do want to be thinking about you do want
to think about your s-bomb from the
software that you're consuming but also
software that you might be Distributing
you do want to make sure that the
software that you're using has been
signed there is that code signing in
place to make sure that the Integrity of
that software is good and you also want
to look at things like code audits so at
the moment I know open ssf the report is
not out there but you can be doing
certain things to do that code audit as
I mentioned things like you know static
code analysis
um and if you want to you know
complement that with a test or assessed
so this is something that the open
um ssf actually have on the website but
this is something called The Open Source
program office and there is a lot to go
through but I thought from my
perspective um this is a good takeaway
slide um that I had in mind and if as an
organization you're looking at this and
going okay am I really using 70 of my
software is open source and a lot of
organizations don't realize how much of
their software might be open source
um you may be thinking okay you know I
appreciate that something like an open
ssf is working on this projects but what
are the certain things that I can do
today to be able to sort of you know
look at these things because you know I
cannot be waiting say a year to start
doing certain things and I think this
slide that they've got over there
um you know kind of summarizes it quite
well so these are real actionable things
that you can put in place today to look
at how you can improve your open source
security so obviously focusing on
education I think it's one of those
really simple things that we often talk
about but it's
um definitely not to be underrated you
know talking about this within your
organization and making sure that
everyone understands what the
implications of opening using open
source it definitely allows you to move
faster and innovate but on the flip side
we do need to know what the cost of
doing that is multi-factor
authentication I know we had a really
good talk from OCTA about that as well
again that is one of those things that
you know it's worthwhile implementing
just making sure things are secure
you're using a combination of tools in
your pipeline to detect these
vulnerabilities so openssf actually has
a guide for security tools so if you go
on there you know they kind of talk
about different tools but the takeaway
messages you know no tool is perfect it
kind of has to complement you know the
culture that you've got within your
organization and what you're using it
for so there wouldn't be one tool um
fits all in this case but you know that
is something that you can do we spoke
about you know adopting something like a
six door or a code signing as well
um the software bill of material
adoption
um then you want to obviously monitor
your overall health of the open source
projects that you're using as well so
the Linux Foundation actually has this
thing called LFX that you can utilize
and they also have a chaos toolkit so
yes what I'll probably do is so I did
have a resource slide at the end of this
but obviously as I've had this great
experience today I will um pop these
resources into the devsecond Discord
Channel um you know all the resources
that you can kind of go into to to be
able to sort of you know look at all
this information and implement it in
your organization there are also some
really great guidelines that are
available as well so in a nutshell I
think um what I wanted to really sort of
wrap up with is open source is great I
am very supportive of people utilizing
open source it is great for Innovation
um but it does come with its own cost
and there are some great initiatives
that are happening across the board and
of open ssf being one of the big ones
out there currently so I do encourage
everyone to go check that out look at
their open mobilization plan I've only
obviously flagged only three of the
components but I think each of the
components that they're speaking about
and I will kind of maybe just flick back
to that are equally important and I do
encourage everyone to look at that and
sort of implementing something like that
within their organizations
thank you so much for everyone's time
well Shelby thank you so much for that
presentation that was incredible
thank you I hopefully I did all right
for time I was trying to kind of keep a
track on am I going over or not you're
fantastic yep
this is this is how I imagine you say
F-bomb
[Laughter]
yes I I was trying to sort of you know
like maybe not say s-bomb enough I think
there's like few buzzwords for 2022
which you know you kind of like don't
want to say it but I think that they I
think someone said that you know things
are buzzword for a reason sometimes and
I think I spons one of them yeah yeah
and bringing up Vlog for Shell so close
to the holidays again or so close to
that anniversary yeah
yeah one of the things I always find
super just fascinating about open source
and Security in general is uh I I think
about this often but like apparently and
I just Google this to make sure I'm not
going to give anyone some fake uh
information here but Isaac Newton is the
one who said if I have seen further It
Is by standing on the shoulders of
giants which is one of my favorite
quotes of all time and I feel like in
the software world it's like one of the
most relevant things to you know
literally everything we do because you
know when you're building applications
today you're using so much work that
people that have come before you have
built and it's all just open source
stuff all the way down to the kernels of
the operating systems that you're
working on most of the time and it's
just so impressive how much like the
collective human knowledge and like
sharing of that knowledge has like
enabled for today's stuff
but it doesn't come without risk and
there's all sorts of things you need to
do to use those tools in nice ways and
make sure you're not like breaking
things and causing problems but
absolutely loved your presentation
thank you so much
yeah 100 I see in in over on the hop-in
platform Hannah said that's fantastic
talk as well she'll be however and is a
little disappointed and I agree with
Hannah there was no Genie that popped up
when you said s-bomb three uh I know I
was hoping for that I think one of these
days maybe I need to save 10 times I
think maybe it's not three yeah
ask any other questions for Shelby
I think I have a genie image here we go
I
love that
I think I'll leave that for my next talk
the third time I say it you know Brian
Club pops up
the beardless Brian Clark also we gotta
talk about Micah's uh photoshopping
skills there because I don't know what
he did to my face but it looked really
copy and everything
you know
[Laughter]
all right awesome
foreign
I do a really good job at that so
thanks for having me well she'll be
thank you for joining us and thanks for
dropping some great open source
knowledge on on everyone
um if if people want to connect with you
what's the best way for them to get in
touch do you have anything you want to
plug yes so I think yeah if you look up
Cloud security podcast I think you
should be able to find us um I'm usually
on LinkedIn is probably the best way to
find me but I also do hangout on the
devsecond Discord as well and that's
where I'll be popping in uh the handy
links or for this talk so yeah that's
another place you can find me
amazing well Shelby thank you so much
for coming and uh we will talk to you
later take care thank you all the best