all right we're about ready to get
started for the next one Micah do you
want to do the introduction
sure I would love to because uh not just
because I know Mandy but I do know Mandy
he's awesome so Mandy Hubbard is uh
passionate about software quality good
processes and great documentation
he spent almost 20 years in QA
leadership roles where she focused on
ensuring the best experience for end
users
and when she discovered cicd she was
immediately interested because she saw
it as a way to expand software quality
so
um you know she wanted to create
processes that made it easier for
developers to run tests while also
preventing developers from merging their
code until tests were successful so we
didn't like Mandy us developers we
didn't like Mandy for a while but now we
do now we do we love Mandy now but we
didn't at first but now we do
um but you know uh there was a time when
developers were not too keen on you know
test Suites running if you're old like
me you remember those times
um so I'm really excited to hear Mandy's
session and uh let's bring her in to say
hi
hey Mandy welcome hello
first request is that you unmute
yourself
it's just a requirement
to see you everyone I feel like I'm
amongst friends today
you are for sure
very cool so
um what do you what are you talking
about today I have it right in front of
me but I'd love to hear you just do a
little intro for your talk before we
share our screen up there can you see my
screen
no not yet but we will don't worry okay
cool just uh just chatting a little bit
yeah today I'm going to talk to you
about zero trust security and the zero
trust security model specifically
um how to utilize it to secure your
kubernetes cluster how's that sound oh
neat that sounds awesome
good well uh when we uh we'll we'll take
a step back and we'll add your screen
there and take it away
awesome thank you
all right well thank you everyone for
joining me today to talk about zero
trust security
um Micah did a great job introducing me
but um for anyone just joining I'm Mandy
Hubbard I live here in Austin Texas I've
lived here since uh moving from Tupelo
Mississippi right after high school to
go to UT it's a super great place to
live I have spent most of my career in
QA roles
um I really was focused on creating good
experiences for end users at that time
those were customers of our software
um I pivoted into developer advocacy
kind of taking that same passion for
giving in use is the same experience but
now my end users are developers and I
work to help utilize um their feedback
to create great products to facilitate
good software development
um like Micah said I am pretty much a CI
CD nerd I didn't know it existed
um back in my early QA days and once I
found it I was immediately in love it
was love at first sight uh because
without a solid CI CD pipeline quality
code doesn't really matter because we
can't ensure that the right bits get to
the end user so I'm really interested in
cicd I'm currently a senior software um
senior software developer I'm currently
a senior developer advocate for
architect.io architect is a dependency
aware deployment platform for deploying
your applications to kubernetes to
handle the dependencies and we can
deploy to your external kubernetes
clusters or you can deploy to a free
preview environment in the architect
Community Cloud which is really cool for
being able able to get early feedback
and do iterative development and so on
so if you get a chance I'd love it if
you headed over to architect.io and
signed up for a free account check it
out and um let me know let me know what
you think
um so yeah I like I like developing
software I like quality I like processes
but I do have some more human interest
um I really like cats especially my cat
Theo who will make a visit later if
you're paying attention
um I also really like crystals and
astrology and Kundalini Yoga and a bunch
of kind of woo-woo stuff that I think
rounds out my technical edges pretty
nicely but today we're going to talk
about zero trust security we'll talk
about the zero zero trust security model
which will lead us into talking about
the kubernetes security model so you can
understand how the network works by
default
we'll pivot into a brief introduction of
kubernetes services so you can
understand how to use them to facilitate
zero trust security
um that will lead us into
kubernetes Network policies which is the
Highlight
um of this talk is understanding how to
use those to secure your network and
then we'll walk through a really simple
example so you can get an idea of the
types of policies that you would want to
implement in your old cluster
so let's start with the zero zero trust
security model
because the zero trust network is simply
a network that operates according to the
zero trust security model
um now the zero trust security model has
been around for a long time I think I
initially saw 2005 but when I continued
doing some digging
um it's actually first was first uh
established in the early 90s if you can
believe that but it's really a Hot Topic
in software development these days in
fact in January of this year the White
House actually issued a memorandum
specifying its own zero trust security
architecture for any federal
applications and it stated that it's
going to begin requiring agencies to
meet certain cyber security standards by
the end of fiscal year 2024 so zero
trust security is really at its peak
but what is zero trust security it is
thank you it's a philosophy a model an
ideal and a goal it's not a prescriptive
set of actions but it's more of a North
star to aim for in setting up your
security policies
um it could be implemented in various
ways using various tools but at its
heart it is a trust no one approach to
security
and one of the main tenets of the zero
trust model is that there is no safe
network security uh no save Network
perimeter you know back in the day when
we talked about networks we to use the
old castle and mode analogy where remote
is your VPN and if you could get across
the moat then you had the keys to the
castle and as long as the drawbridge was
raised you were safe because you had
remote or your VPN well with zero trust
security there really is no network
perimeter that is safe if you think
about it with cloud computing you may
have resources in different Cloud
environments hosted by different vendors
some of your resources may still be
on-prem and they all need to communicate
in a safe way so you really have a lot
less control over your network perimeter
than you did back with you know the
security models that we were used to
before Cloud came into the picture
and um but we're going to stick with the
CL the castle emote uh analogy to
explain zero trust security a little bit
further
um with zero security imagine that you
do manage to get across the mo whatever
security mechanisms are in place all
you'll find is a locked castle with a
huge iron door that you can penetrate
and if you were to penetrate it you
would simply find a bunch of other
locked doors and the best stuff would be
kept behind doors that you didn't even
know about you know a bunch of secret
doors
um because uh a big tenet of zero trust
security is unlisted IP addresses and
undiscoverable services I.E these doors
you don't know about
um the less we advertise our resources
uh the less likely an attacker is to
find a way into the network
um you know on the same note like you
don't want to advertise your resources
that hold your private data if an
attacker doesn't know it exists then
they can't really go after it so that's
why we lock things down and only
services that need to know about other
services have that information it's not
just publicly available
another important concept with zero
trust networking is that resources that
need to communicate with each other will
need to reconnect and re-verify
frequently so it's not enough just to
create an initial connection and then
run indefinitely
um though there will be periodic read
reconnected re-verify efforts so that if
someone does infiltrate a particular
resource they don't automatically get
access to every other resource that it
has access to because there will be a
reconnect and we verify process that an
attacker won't be able to get through
um so zero to security really focuses on
the uh principle of least privilege
which just simply means that your
resources should have the absolute Bare
Bones minimum privilege information is
necessary to do their jobs there was a
time when we gave resources access to
all of our resource all other resources
just in case they needed it it really
made development easy because you know
he needed to consume resources they were
available to you to work with and you
didn't have to set up a bunch of
security protocols during your
development process but once you get to
production
each of your resources needs to be
locked down and you take a real um you
know intentional approach to which
permissions that you give those
resources again so that if an attacker
does gain access
they don't have the ability to move
laterally through your network and
compromise all your resources
and then finally a really big tenant of
zero zero trust security is that you
should transmit your security Telemetry
data to a logging system so that you
have it available in the event of a
breach it's first of all going to be a
way you can identify that a breach
occurred and then it will also allow you
to quickly find the root cause of the of
the breach find that vulnerability and
shut it down quickly without this
Telemetry data you may not know that a
breach has occurred until you know
there's a much larger consequence from
the attacker down the line so it's
really important that you log your
security Telemetry and use that
Telemetry regularly to ensure that your
network is secure that there aren't
unknown attackers
right so that's the zero test security
model that we use when we Implement a
zero trust security network
so now let's step into a quick talk
about the kubernetes network model
um once you understand how networking is
set up in kubernetes by default you can
understand why it's so important to be
intentional about your network security
um first and foremost all containers in
the kubernetes cluster can communicate
with each other even across nodes as you
know your cluster is going to consist of
various nodes and on those nodes you
have pods which then run your containers
and without an explicit Network policy
on your kubernetes cluster all of those
pods are going to be able to speak with
one another all the containers are going
to be able to speak with one another and
they're going to be accessible by the
outside world
so all connections to and from your pods
are wide open to all traffic which is
definitely not a secure way to run an
application
Additionally the way that you would
communicate with those pods and
containers and the way that they could
communicate with one another is with an
external IP address but since pods by
their very nature or volatile that's not
a stable way to um to access resources
in your application stack so that leads
us into
a quick chat about kubernetes services
so kubernetes service
is an abstraction that represents a
logical set of PODS whereas the external
IP address is tied to a particular
instance of a pod at runtime that's
going to change a service is kind of
like a pointer to whatever pod or pods
happen to be running at runtime
and this is going to act as a single
entity to the outside world and what's
also cool about using Services is that
it acts as a single entity to your
developers so developers typically
aren't
um as enmeshed in you know Network
protocols and understanding low-level
networking Concepts just by interest
um but when you use a kubernetes service
you can really distill your application
components and the way that they run in
your kubernetes cluster down to a set of
boxes that really look very similar to
your architecture diagram and then
developers can look at the set of
services and very easily know what sort
of communication to set up between those
because that's the way they architected
the application
um so with the kubernetes service you've
got a reliable point of entry from for
the outside world and also between
Services running in your cluster
and then they're going to live until
they're explicitly destroyed so even if
your pods aren't running you're still
going to have uh the notion of a service
until you explicitly destroy that
service
um and so that'll stay alive and you can
bring in pods as you wish but that
service is going to be a constant
so we've talked about the zero trust
security model
and a little bit about
kubernetes Network that's set up by
default when you have a cluster a new
cluster and then we touched a little bit
on kubernetes Services what the benefits
are and why you would want to use them
so now let's jump into
kubernetes Network policies
so kubernetes Network policies are how
we're actually going to specify the
connectivity between the different
Services specified in your application
stack
you're going to use kubernetes Network
policies to specify your Ingress and
egress rules between your services and
the outside world and between the
individual services that comprise your
application stack
um as I'm sure you're familiar with
Ingress refers to traffic coming into a
pod and egress is the traffic going
outbound from the pi now you can
certainly configure your egress rules
very granularly as well
um it's not as necessary unless you're
running a very tight application like
Financial systems are something with
very sensitive data for the purpose of
this conversation we're going to focus
on Ingress but know that you do also use
kubernetes Network policies to configure
your egress rules and also that they
must be configured separately for each
service so in other words it's not a
bi-directional communication you have to
specify what traffic is allowed into a
particular service as well as what
traffic is allowed out from a particular
service and there are multiple ways to
specify which traffic is allowed to and
from
um here are a couple
um here on the slide you can use
namespaces IP blocks um you can use
labels
um you can even lock it down by protocol
and Port so that even if the traffic is
coming from a trusted resource if it's
coming on the wrong port or it's their
own protocol it's not something that
your you know service is expecting
there's no reason to receive that
traffic and it would deny access to that
traffic so you get really granular
control over what traffic is allowed in
and out of the pods in your kubernetes
cluster now um the cool thing is that
the way you set up kubernetes Network
policies is by specifying them in a yaml
file again this makes networking network
security so much more accessible to
developers because developers know yaml
that's a familiar language as long as
you you know take a look at the spec and
see what's required and a developer can
very easily put together a kubernetes
network policy manifest using yaml
versus having to understand low-level
networking protocols and stuff like that
so once you have created this yaml file
you'll apply it to your kubernetes
cluster using the kubernetes API
um so you may think I configured my
Ingress and egress rules I've locked it
down by protocol and port and really
satisfied with it I'm ready to go I've
applied it to my kubernetes cluster
but you might be surprised to learn that
if you apply it to your kubernetes
cluster it's not going to do anything at
all until you
enforce it using a network policy plugin
so a network policy plugin is
responsible for actually enforcing those
rules that you applied to your
kubernetes cluster via your manifest
file and typically Network policy
plugins conform to The Container network
interface or cni spec and what this
allows is um well first of all cni
provides a a bunch of libraries that
facilitate development of the plugins
um so that makes it able to be very
feature-rich but also cni really aims to
make container networking plugable if
you use a plug-in that conforms to the
cni spec it's going to work not only in
your kubernetes cluster but if you were
to move to say Amazon ECS or um
openshift or Cloud Foundry or some other
container runtime environment these
plugins are going to support most
well-known container runtime
environments as well which prevents you
from being you know locked into it a
single runtime environment
um so plugins are installed on your
cluster and you'll want to look at what
plugins come install by default at
architect we use two plugins called
Calico and psyllium and we found that
for most of the public Cloud providers
those are already available but there's
some cases where you may have some other
default plug-in installed that year on
your cluster that you'll need to
actually uninstall before you can
successfully install these and of course
you'll want to reference the spec for
the particular plugins to you know set
up your gamble file to take advantage of
their features and you'll likely want to
use more than one plug-in because they
each plugin kind of has
um some specialty that it um that it
offers and so you can use a combination
of plugins to get a really rich feature
set for configuring Network policies
okay so now we've talked about
kubernetes Network policies hopefully
you have an idea of how to specify them
and have an understanding of you know
the types of network policies you could
use to enforce those I'm sorry the
network plugins you could use to enforce
those policies
um let's just take a look at a simple
kubernetes Network policy Manifest this
manifest is used to deny all Ingress
Ingress traffic to all pods it's um you
know simple yaml probably looks familiar
to all of you and then
um this one is a little bit more
involved this one breaks it down first
of all it's got Ingress and egress rules
and it specifies an IP block it uses
protocols and ports
um to give a real granular approach to
network security
so that's what it looks like
um that's how that's the meat of
kubernetes network policy right there in
that file
so now that you have an idea of you know
what's going on on your network by
default what you need to do to secure it
um you know about policies and plugins
and a little bit about services to help
facilitate this
you're probably wondering but what
policies do I specify and that's a
really good question but like most
questions in software development the
answer is it depends it obviously is
going to depend on your application
stack what sort of communication you
need between resources what sort of
communication you're going to allow from
the external environment but for the
sake of this conversation let's take a
really simple application stack I'm sure
we're all familiar with applications
that consist of a front-end an API in a
database and I want you to take a minute
and look at this diagram and think of
these as
um these are all Individual kubernetes
Services obviously not the internet
that's our outside world but front-end
API and database represent kubernetes
services for the components in our
application stack and this represents
what connectivity looks like in a
kubernetes network cluster by default
and before you apply any policies you've
got complete bi-directional
communication with external users and
the individual services within your
application stack and you have full
bi-directional communication between The
Individual Services in your application
stack
so the first policy you would want to
apply is a deny all Ingress policy which
we saw manifest for in an earlier slide
first thing you do is you just lock
everything down tight and then you begin
opening up access as needed
and the next thing that we recommend is
that you use an API Gateway an API
Gateway is going to serve as the entry
point into your applications tag it will
intercept traffic from the outside world
perform some authentication and
authorization which is out of scope for
this conversation but obviously a huge
part of network security and then it
will decide where to send the traffic so
the first uh or the next rule you'll
need to add to your network policies is
um a rule that allows Ingress into your
API Gateway from the outside Network or
the internet
and then that Gateway is going to send
traffic into your application stack
that's obviously going to be your
front-end application
um and so there'll be an Ingress rule
that allows traffic to flow into your
front-end application your front-end
application will then need to send
requests to your API and the API will
need to communicate with your database
to get data from and send data to uh
back in database for storage
so
um this is a diagram of a really simple
application stack and the network
connectivity you would want to set up
with kubernetes network policies
um so what you you don't see is any
communication with the individual
services and the outside Network or any
communication between say your front-end
and your database or your database and
your API Gateway because it's not
necessary so if someone were to
infiltrate
um your API they could only send traffic
to your database they couldn't send
traffic to your front end and vice versa
so this is an example of following that
privilege that principle of least
privilege where we give the bare minimum
access necessary to perform the job here
um and this is something that's going to
look really familiar to your developers
because when they plan their
applications it's a bunch of boxes and
arrows and when they plan their network
security using kubernetes network
policies it's a bunch of boxes and
arrows it's really accessible and it
allows you to start thinking about your
network security very early on in the
development life cycle
all right so that's it we did it
um we've briefly touched on the zero
trust security model we chatted about
the network the kubernetes network model
we spoke about kubernetes services and
then we talked about kubernetes Network
policies that's all you need to know to
get started with zero trust networking
obviously that's absolutely unsure zero
trust networking has a lot of components
and we focus on this small subset of
kubernetes network policies and what I
hope is that this has piqued your
interest and giving you some really
accessible information to go and start
looking at implementing security using
this model on your own so
as promised Theo's here to thank you for
hanging out with us today we hope you
learned something and if you have any
questions
um I'll be around for a bit after uh the
presentation we've got chat and then
after this broadcast I'm always
available find me on Twitter send me
questions if I've got answers I'll send
them your way if not I really love to
learn with you and start exploring more
about zero trust networking all right
thanks everyone
excellent thanks so much Mandy that was
a great presentation and uh yeah we'll
we'll push questions into the chat for
folks to ask you there if you if you
don't mind checking that out when you
get a chance not a problem I'll do that
have a good one