there's a lot of why's that we're going
to talk about today why DevOps why
security what are we supposed to do
about it
so we'll just dive in first things first
why does DevOps matter anything this is
gonna be a very like interactive talk
why does DevOps matter anyone doing
things faster faster faster which means
faster time-to-market
[Music]
making it easier to reproduce what you
did responsibilities yes all of these
things all these things these are
business reasons right yes you gotta be
faster in the competition policy you can
survive yes better communication between
teams yes very much so
businesses do what they need to do in
order to survive and succeed so DevOps
companies I don't think they don't
necessarily have all the answers but
they are inherently flexible they can
iterate according to market feedback and
business needs as everyone has said the
faster you can go the less you spend on
product development the fewer person
hours are required to deliver a complete
solution every iteration is an
opportunity to deliver greater business
value so DevOps is great DevOps is gonna
save all of our organization's DevOps is
going to give us this tremendous
competitive advantage I want to do a
reality check and say let's be real
about where we are DevOps is still the
new cool thing which means it's not
totally mainstream puppet has been
publishing its state of DevOps report
for three years now and the 2017 version
of that
port says that 20 27 percent of
organizations have made the switch that
means that there are not I'm not really
good at math on the spot 73 percent that
if not right so the vast majority of
organizations have not made the switch
Gartner also has published a number that
says 25 percent of global 2000
organizations have adopted DevOps so why
is this word all over the place you
might think that everyone is using a
DevOps model except for you but even if
most organizations are thinking about
making the switch many haven't yet and
in my experience working with devops
teams they're either teams that were
born in DevOps
or an organization which has a component
which is sort of trying DevOps out so I
think it's great that we have meetings
like this to talk about this stuff
because there's still an awful lot that
needs to be figured out I think that's
that's what is very exciting about this
space I also want to as part of this
reality check talk about automation
there's a lot of cool things that
automation can do but let's not forget
that the only things that can be
automated are the things that we already
know how to do and we've gotten to such
a standard process that we can do the
same thing over and over again and we
can teach a computer program to do it so
we talk about automation the most
commonly automated tests are integration
tests component and unit tests
performance tests that being said manual
testing is still very popular for things
like user acceptance test usability
tests and story level tests
organizations are having a tough time
automating everything which makes
perfect sense there there are some
things which rely on a human opinion
and and spending time and money trying
to automate things that require a human
opinion and a human brain does make
sense so there are things that are gonna
be automated and there are things that
are not gonna be automated and guess
what your customers are human so that's
why when we talk about user acceptance
and story level tests these are the ones
that are not automated and guess what
the people who are interested in
attacking your software are also human
they're not they're not computers so how
is the role of security changing you
know perhaps the folks in this room who
are the DevOps folks
rather than the security folks have come
from an engineering background and a
security background all those two are
not entirely exclusive you know you
might be asking the question well we
have a security team why won't they just
take care of it of course as we've
discussed in DevOps developers have much
more power and changes happen quickly
which means there's not always time for
a traditional large scale security
review that means it's critical for
security to be built in to the
development culture and also into the
development and the deployment processes
so I want to talk about DevOps and how
that's changed things for security
people so ten years ago and you know
it's all a spectrum right there's so
many different organizations with so
many different approaches but generally
speaking there's an approach to security
that said we're an M&M right we're soft
and squishy on the inside melty and
we've got this hard candy shell and it's
all about protecting the perimeter
security would insert itself at various
steps throughout the software
development lifecycle and have an
opportunity to review and improve things
before they went on to the next step
that works great in a waterfall software
development method all
J another thing that we had was
on-premise data centers on-premise
workforces who were using Organization
issued mobile devices to do their work
so today things look really different
than they did ten years ago when it
comes to technology so now we've got a
vendor situation right my organization
does not develop all of the software
that it uses we depend a lot on other
organizations to help us build our
product whether that means sending your
code to github or code ship you depend
on other organizations using open-source
code I know Black Duck is here you
depend on code that's been written by
someone else and there's risk involved
in that and I say it goes both ways
because most of our organizations are
also vendors of some sort if you're not
a security vendor you're selling
something if you're a business and so
your customer is now also going to have
additional questions about your security
if you're hosted in the cloud if you're
using a DevOps methodology why should i
as your potential customer trust you how
do I know that by incorporating your
product into mine that it's going to be
secure because cloud has really changed
the way that network and system
infrastructure works there's a bigger
focus for security professionals on
applications and particularly api's when
infrastructure is code then it's code
security that matters and finally we've
got mobile workforce employees of
organizations are everywhere and they're
connecting with their own devices which
are not always totally can
rolled by the organization they work for
so the landscape is changing here's the
next question for you guys which is why
do you think that security matters for
DevOps it's too easy to ship back code
and what happens when you ship bad code
bad things happen bad things happen and
maybe in like DevOps words unplanned
work happens and rework happens which of
course takes the place of planned work
and then you don't get those benefits of
DevOps that we talked about in the first
place any other thoughts on why security
matters for DevOps
yes
moving security left fixing security
issues sooner rather than later is
cheaper one more time yes security is a
part of quality and it inspires people
perhaps it encourages people or requires
people to write better quality code
including security yes when you want to
go fast traditional security doesn't
work as we just discussed the landscape
is changing security needs to change too
thank you so I'm I'm gonna actually talk
about ten companies who are killing it
at DevOps and for each one I googled it
and I look to see where security
featured on their web pages so Adobe has
a public facing security statement Adobe
is a company that may or may not have
had some security issues in the past and
they need to convince their customers
and their users that indeed they are
secure and security is a priority this
is a business imperative for Adobe
Facebook also has a security page
similar reasons
Amazon AWS cloud security because how
could AWS run unless the users believed
that it was secure fidelity has a
public-facing security page Walmart who
knew that Walmart was a DevOps shop but
tech Deacon says that it's one of the 10
companies killing in it DevOps Etsy is
like a yarn shop right but they had
Shayne Lackey and you know he did the
whole DevOps security thing over there
also public-facing website arguably
marketing using security as a
competitive differentiator use our
service we want you to know that we're
secure don't be afraid to use our
service because you don't need to worry
that we're not secure Netflix Target CEO
got fired shortly after the security
breach and this was a guy who had worked
his way up right this is not like a new
CEO who came in a breach occurred you
know person has moved out this is
someone who started out at like an
entry-level made his way up established
a history at the organization
security breach is one of probably a few
things that led to that person being
asked to leave the company Sony
Nordstrom so I'm awfully pragmatic when
it comes to why security matters and
there are really just three reasons and
I really just think it's one reason so
the first one sales support and
acquisition if you're trying to sell a
product and your customer or your
require wants to know what your security
situation is you better have a good
answer number two
the company wants to avoid negative
press headlines we saw a few of those
when we looked at the top ten companies
killing in a DevOps the company wants to
avoid negative press headlines resulting
from a security breach but let's think
about that for a moment because isn't
the reason that any companies cares
about press because it doesn't want bad
press to affect their sales or their
potential acquisitions Verizon and Yahoo
I think Verizon got like a four hundred
and eighty million dollar discount on
their acquisition following the breach
so I think that means we're really just
back to one reason which is sales and
acquisition and bad presses is perhaps a
part of that compliance this is why I
joined the ebay security team because
the company needed to comply with PCI
and Sox other organizations may need to
comply with HIPAA gdpr is becoming a
thing or another requirement in order to
do business or meet a customer
requirement I've actually heard of
organizations that choose not to meet
compliance requirements again as a
business decision because it's business
trade-off to say well we need to invest
X amount in order to be compliant you
know and if we're not the the the risk
is gonna be Y amount and so we're just
gonna take that business risk at the end
of the day it's all about sales and
survival and business so there is
another reason okay so this is so this
is weird when you google when you're
trying to do a presentation and you're
trying to find a slide that shows a C so
sleeping at night you get all sorts of
inappropriate images and so I chose this
cat wine to show like what's another
reason for security so your VP of
engineering so you're director of DevOps
so your seaso can sleep at night and I
think again that's because ultimately of
sales
there's this idea that one should not
put a 200 dollar fence around a five
dollar asset
the whole reason DevOps exists is to
help the business the whole reason
security exists is to help the business
so in 2002 Bill Gates
sent out this memo and it was about
trustworthy computing and if you've read
the media it seems like an awfully noble
cause let's take a look at some of the
specific text in his memo over the last
year it has become clear that ensuring
dotnet is a platform for trust where the
computing is more important than any
other part of our work if we don't do
this people simply won't be willing or
able to take advantage of all the other
great work that we do so Bill Gates sent
out this company-wide memo and it's
because Microsoft was starting to get
questions about its security and it
didn't want security to get in the way
of its sales it's all about the money
I'm sorry it's all about the Benjamins
there I wish I could figure out a way to
have like you know one five second clip
of a song play like right and I'm sure
there's a way to do that I I'm sure I
will figure it out for the next time
that that I do this presentation so what
is a person supposed to do so say you
are a VP of engineering say you are a
director of DevOps and you have to go
and do security where do you start
I've heard numbers like there's 8,000
security vendors I've heard numbers like
there's 14,000 security vendors even if
you have an awfully open door policy
when it comes to security vendors
there's an impossible way that you could
hear everyone's pitch and try and decide
what it does it you need to do so maybe
you would look to frameworks and
standards there's a super cool framework
called the besom besom was started about
nine years ago it's a descriptive model
of software security activities and it
has a hundred and twelve controls that's
a lot of things to be able to have to do
that's a lot of things to even go
through and decide which ones are we
gonna do one hundred and twelve control
elements this is an old slide I actually
think there's a hundred and thirteen now
so ISO ISO makes standards they make
really good standards ISO 27001 ISO
27000 - there's a cloud version which is
ISO 2720 ISO 27001 seven and guess what
it costs a hundred and fifty dollars to
even get the standard besom is free I
did the conversion on Google from Swiss
francs and there are a hundred and
twenty one control elements how are you
supposed to do that so you could go to
another organization called the Cloud
Security Alliance and you could look at
their cloud controls matrix 133 control
elements this is the job of a security
policy analyst and I think there are
like some people in the world who like
going through this stuff I'm not one of
those people even though I did do that
job for a while and so it's enough to
make a person's brain explode right even
if you are a security professional even
if you do have security background and
experience and if you are not then it's
just like it's
just too much it's too much so how can
we simplify security for DevOps security
is about preventing bad things from
happening because if you release low
quality insecure code bad things will
happen what does it mean for a bad thing
to happen it means you're doing
unplanned work which means that you're
taking time away from planned work and
it means that you're doing rework which
again means that you're taking time away
from planned work it's also about trust
so somebody had mentioned that culture
is a big part of DevOps and I've been in
enough organizations to see scenarios
where the culture of a team works and
people are actually working together and
they actually trust each other and I've
seen scenarios where people don't trust
each other and what are some mistakes
that security people make which results
in other people not trusting security
when the security person walks in and
says look we need to do security here's
a list of 133 things and then the dev
ops person says clearly you don't
understand how this works and the
business person says clearly you don't
understand how this works so it's
important to again remember that DevOps
exists to support the business security
exists to support the business I think
it's important for security
professionals to spend as much time
learning about the business and learning
about their organizations flavor of
DevOps just as much time as they spend
learning about the latest security
breach the latest security vulnerability
so here's my simplification instead of a
hundred plus controls there is this
framework called the NIST cybersecurity
framework and I like it because it's
easy to understand and it's very
pragmatic the approach is based on
responding to an incident which is the
way that security actually affects
organizations in 2013 President Barack
Obama issued an executive order titled
improving critical infrastructure
security and it was all about enhancing
the security and the resilience of
critical infrastructure and maintaining
a cyber environment that encourages
efficiency innovation and economic
prosperity so whereas security
traditionally perhaps has been seen as a
blocker and a stopper and a weight for
and a Delayer
this approach is different this approach
is saying look we need our critical
infrastructure and it can be extended to
other organizations and businesses to be
efficient innovative and prosperous so
this executive order calls to the
development of a voluntary risk-based
cybersecurity framework and here you go
these are sort of the five components
and I think it just makes sense right so
I'm gonna even simplify it for you one
step further and take it from five
things to three so we've gone from 133
120 113 down to five and I'm gonna say
we're going down to three three steps to
doing security for DevOps
the first is to identify what's your
business environment and what's your
DevOps process the second is to prevent
and there's an analogy that's been used
in security that says you know doing
security it's like taking a multivitamin
doing security it's like brushing your
teeth and that's fine but
the results of brushing your teeth you
know they're not like so immediate so I
I prefer an analogy that says if your
business depends on cars to deliver
product on time
those cars need to have regularly
scheduled maintenance they need to have
oil changes because if you take the time
to do all changes and regularly
scheduled maintenance then you will
prevent the car from breaking down and
not being able to deliver whatever you
need to deliver on time so is this
concept of preventive maintenance and
what I really like about the NIST
cybersecurity framework is it puts it in
the context of an incident so the the
remaining three components of the NIST
cybersecurity framework are detect
respond and recover I've sort of bundled
that together and said we're gonna call
that react so we've got five minutes
let's go through each of these number
one identify learn about the business
again
DevOps exists to support the business
security exists to support the business
spend as much time learning about how
your business works and about the DevOps
process and toolchain as you spend
learning about the latest security
breach or vulnerability it destroys
trust when a security person walks into
the room and talks about something
that's either irrelevant or theoretical
that just that just that just doesn't
that doesn't work for this trust thing
right a DevOps professional has to
believe that a security professional is
actually there to help them not to get
in their way not to slow them down not
to prevent them from getting their work
done so learn the business understand
the business how do you do that go to
your business process owners and ask
them what their objectives are and then
make a list of things that jeopardize
those goals understand what the value
chains are in your business link those
business objectives to how technology
jeopardizes
make sure you consider your supply chain
who are your vendors how are you
connected to them what are your
dependencies if your service code goes
out to github encode chip you know
potentially you're giving them secrets
what secrets are you giving out how do
you manage those secrets how do you
connect to your back-end database how do
you connect to your third-party api's
this is threat modeling this is
understanding how are your systems
architected ask questions like why do we
trust github why do we trust coaching
why would our customer trust us and
eliminate scope where you can so Y
process credit cards if someone else
that's like all they do and they're
really good at it and then if you don't
do it and they do it then you don't have
to deal with the security part or if you
do process credit card information other
sensitive information you know keep it
in one place so that you don't have to
apply all your security controls all
over the place you can just apply them
to to that place where they are number
two is prevent so awareness is really
important culture
what do devops people think about so I
started my career at eBay I was there
from 2005 to 2010 in 2014 there was a
massive data breach what happened
eBay employees were fished and how do
you prevent something like that from
happening because there's all this tech
sols automation there's all these
controls at the end of the day there are
people who run your business and one of
these people know about security and
there are tons of organizations who will
sell you try and sell you computer based
training and there's some CBT that's
great there's some CBT that's not great
and instructor-led training and how much
of that training is about those 130
cloud controls that 120 ISO 27 2707 teen
controls that 113 besom controls how
much of that training is theoretical and
not relevant why
not build your training based on actual
incidents that have occurred at your
organization and every organization if
you're doing some logging and monitoring
and learning has had incidents and on
top of that maybe you're doing something
like on demand pen testing and you're
finding out real ways that real people
could exploit your systems policy and
procedures you know there's a place for
these things in both the traditional
security world as well as the DevOps
security world things that matter a lot
in DevOps change management who's making
what commits were those reviewed were
those approved even if it's just by a
peer and not you know some sort of ivory
tower person even if there's a whole set
of changes that can happen and get
automatically approved you know but
there are these high risk changes that
need to go through a change review board
not every change needs to go through a
change review board but there are some
that should and what are those for your
business what are those critical
critical components that could cause
something to blow up reducing technical
debt so this is where I get into like
oil changes for your car I am out of
time we're gonna go super quick update
your software implement your vendor
patches figure out a way to do that on
demand security testing I talked to a
director of DevOps and he says look we
do a lot of cool stuff we work with
vendors we'd like to work with vendors
to tell us that what we're doing is
actually what we think we're doing like
writing secure code react this is about
responding to an incident detecting do
you know when an incident is gonna occur
logging monitoring alerting responding
do you have an incident response plan in
place what about your supply chain and
recovering when you have an incident how
do you incorporate that into your
prevention controls key takeaways
security has to be business driven it
has to be on demand it has to be built
to fit a culture of trust in closing
businesses will do what they need to do
to survive and succeed if their
customers need agility then they will
evolve to accommodate
that security needs to spend as much
time if not more understanding the
business so they can integrate and be
effective the difference when it comes
to cloud and DevOps is that security can
be a business driver as customers need
assurance that the products and
solutions they are buying and
integrating are trustworthy and secure
sorry for running over time if you have
questions we should talk about them
thank you
[Applause]