good afternoon everyone first of all I
would like to thank Chaka Khan
organizers to provide such an amazing
opportunity oh actually I cannot imagine
that one day I will have a chance to a
major public presentation with varying
sleepers short others and such kind of
shirts it's a very awesome ok let's
begin my name is cloud and i'm working
with pilotto networks and on the
antivirus our research and development
that's all I think others are no it's so
important so let's begin the topical is
about Elias malware so some people are
missing that seriously though our iOS
mobile really but the situation is that
over the past three years this is a
whole list of the new areas new iOS
malware family's been discovered and
let's take a look at the red one all
read all the great ones are the mail
wheels that ever affected down
jailbroken devices and all italic ones
are those male well that even indeed I
post official apple store so I think we
could say from this reader that this is
a problem now oh also considered and I
believe that most of us should only use
non jailbroken devices in the daily walk
in knife how many people jailbroken you
for all rooted your Android devices how
many people here only a few I think
three or four people do not okay anyway
the problem is that even you don't
jailbroke and your phone is still risky
this is what we are talking we were
talking about today we were talking
about how a non jailbroken iOS malware
were pretty
used massively and then how to how they
were distributed and then how did the
evo since and lost how the mid profit
but before that i would like to award
some confusion first of all is a risky
or malicious in most cases when we talk
about male well it means that it had
malicious behaviors but today lots of
areas feminists that you can now say is
so bad or so malicious cause of the
restriction of the system assistant is
still pretty secure save you so you can
you say is risky that's that's what so
today we are using the world malware but
the risky well the potential and wanted
a publication in the future we are all
included the second is that the in the
world or pork there are really many many
excellence security researchers in
spiritual academic researchers on the
approval concept of Alice malware in the
past eight years but today we are more
talking about the real the actual
attacks ending for example when we
talking about windows or android or New
York malware that usual means that those
male well were are spread out exactly by
some automatically way without users
knowledge user even do not know it but
on la's we will see then more families
are due to need user to do some
interactions with the devices for
example to in storage to click it to
impose something we will see many
examples of that way and then lots of
Elway's Mel well do orange inflow from
or targeted some regions in the world
for example China so Oh some people
asked me before that why do we really
need to care about
if it's just the original problem the
answer is first of all some of the
feminist still affect all users around
the world for example the Xcode goes
affected I think more than hundreds of
countries around the world another
answer is that some technicals that they
developed that they used were more and
more adopted by other attacks around the
world for example are about about two
years ago I found the real lookers that
use the enterprise certificate to talk
non jailbroken devices and you know
about are about half year later they
were true one is begging teen another
one is up name is the one click fraud
those 20 you all learn from it and use
the same way to a talk not jailbroken so
the lots are the doctor concept is a
design flaw or code validity the pounds
of very awesome vulnerabilities that
been discovered year by year which could
lead to like information leaking or are
used for jailbreaking that's what we are
not talking about today we are talking
about we will talk about some few design
flaws you can also say is or ability but
it's no some are it's know some awesome
reversing things but some is actually
made by some design problems ok let's
begin the first is how to produce the
male well of course phalangeal broken so
of course you could you could develop
single male well just the on demand but
another problem is that how could you
massively produce them the first of the
first day technical start to children as
they are compiler this is not a new idea
this is actually idea that presented you
know 30 years ago Bay so do for 30 years
ago back in Thompson
in his a lecture of cases a Tony Award
so contention chosen as a setback make a
back door in the c language compiler so
that each network sewer compelled by
zero genetic compiler will accept a back
door username and password that one is
pretty complex and that you need many
technicals of our compelling theory but
later in about two thousand nine there
was a malware actual in the world
malware family being discovered that it
will infect the Delphie compiler and
this one successfully taught meaning
computers remove thousands at least
thousands of developers computer so
later Stuxnet stock snake also is no
directory choice genetic compatible is
it also learned from the idea that it
targeted the true chain of plc devices
let's use the in the industrial control
system and everyone know how stocks net
successful to deliver the goal so in
lower days on i chose platforms how easy
could we infect the exco xcode the
owning compiler for airways app the
answer is single day just one single
name this file these r LD dot x suspect
fell is actually a text FL and it
includes many of our configurations used
up for linking so there is a default
value of the linking parameters and you
could add a fourth load with a pass to
object fell after doing this one single
and change everything in this object
fell every call the inside each will
become will be linked the intro your app
so you could using all tricks to a
automatically launches code during
runtime
this is actually the trick used by the
famous Xcode ghost this Trojan at the
first are the hunger chosen at about
seven versions of Xcode from our from
about our remember is 6.0 to 7.0 beta 2
and the top the ad hoc existed in a
six-month days without being discovered
but actually the term impact continuing
till today this morning I also saw some
new samples that were infected by this
chosen as the compiler and then the
target uploaded these Xcode installer
into some public cloud storage and file
sharing services anything he deals and
successful SEO and so he posted some our
blogs as well as opposed to own the
developers phone say that okay I
provided a central downloading Mason for
xcode and you could download it much
faster than from able of visually and
these posts are so popular that when i
discovered this mail well as socially in
google by xcode anode or xcode in
english and engineers and fun in the
first page of google results except the
fibers of visual one in the first and
then the next 19 countries are all
chosen as one yet that's a super
successful SEO and then after the the
reason that developer 120 downloaded
from in this way is then first of all I
post CDN for downloading especially for
developer resources than Odin has some
problem in some regions also developers
usually disable the gatekeeper cause of
some other developer development tools
popular tools something to note signed
by any certificate so you
ugur disabled at least able to sew it
successfully in fate developers make
computers and then at last it infected
7000 apps in apple store and these are
hundreds of millions of users around the
world the worst case is that this
malware is actually vulnerable that is C
to traffic is so HTTP so you can hide
jacket and through Hyde regular comments
you could reach an API named openurl
which is pretty dangerous that you could
through this API and fake the comments
to a install arbitrary ad by fishing or
you can even display some messages or
display a dialog article user to improve
anything so till now I have no idea how
many still a lamp yeah but when these
families is a lab that this
vulnerability may lead to a serious
problem anyway is it only discovered
after half year always be made by some
reason that some developers recognize a
blow more traffic of their app of their
own app and also this this is a
interesting story right our this malware
infinitely infected a super popular
social network app then even the other
himself not expected so that app brings
hundreds of millions of users which are
actually do is the little silver which
hosted in amazon's AWS armored of course
could have accepted the so huge
significant traffic but the problem is
that that guys are created card I've
been out of money because of so many
traffic so thus it was overdone and and
then all the connection will will be
like one to two seconds which make a
huge delay our huge delay of the apps
launching and finally that social
network jeans
the problem so I was suggestion to
prevent this problem is that you are
enable the gatekeeper and check the ex
college integrity I verified I post
method the method of cost effective the
problem is that a viet i check it is
spending about two and half minutes i'm
thinking that how many developers will
always perform this checking every time
you compel a single program by like two
or three minutes but the problem is that
you do know this is already need you to
download a trojan eyes compiler xcode
installer actually you can using any mac
OS x or advil or spare well to locally
in figure that single land of
configuration fell everything's down and
also you can even detect whether it is a
in the procedure over campaigning and
then infected in time you reeled him
also those that the true chain or said
you for a developer in his computer
there is load owning a single compiler
you may using other tools to improve
your like code quality or approach our
speed up your development or do
something for example you can children
as a kid right so these are further
problems that nobody could prevent or
provided a effective way to resolve the
problem another problem is that
third-party code is will also may be
risky these are full are examples of
whiskey soda party SDKs they've been
discovered in the parts of the years so
they will collect like contact
information or device ID they will our
performance a remotely control take your
pictures
record your audience incision and you
can see the affected like thousands of
apps in apple store oh this is another
result there from academia our research
from this year's Auckland conference you
can see that about in the official apple
store about 3% of apps included a
potentially harmful library France to
the party and loss of them are actually
cross plane phone that exists in both
Android and iOS and they have a lot of
sensitive behaviors so the first
question is that why these SDKs has a so
many insensitive about risky code I
think the answer should be that partly
because of that they would like to
collect users information to our ok
Somali this is actually a abused over
users privacy data signal question is
that why i think the sdk code is used
risk and is a considerable problem the
problem is that ipod do have a very good
design sandbox 400 for iOS app but let's
think about it don't matta new Android
or iOS or other plane phones the apps
sandbox is designed in the in the pan in
the bundle in the boundary of app it's
just the perhaps everything inside the
app share the same commission share the
same user and share the same data which
means actually as a developer you
adopted the code from third-party you
your UN don't know foreign to the party
and those third-party code could
theoretical to take control of all your
data and share all your permission could
do ABC so the problem you said how could
you trust the day how to resolve this
problem as we develop a soldier so that
only use well-known choice awards SDKs
and also it's necessary to perform code
review to us both source code and the
compounder is our the binary code
so another one is repackaging
repackaging is the main reason that I
enjoyed our mail well being so huge
number it's so it's so owning or set the
major of age who are basically we
produce Android malware so now this
technical come to a OS platform so you
now is you could dick download some app
from apple store and decrypt the same
bisexuals and you add a dynamic library
into that i bundle and then you could
patch the main bundle executable by
adding a load command over load develop
and then fix the mac ojeda then you
resent the app by your own or
certificate personal development
certificate and you could distribute
about some ways out I'll talk about
later so this is actually happen on
malware for example this one tiny tiny
we'd be our repair dude every chart you
can be considered in the load command
they always say there is a load library
by the executive lapels and pointed
through a PNG which is actually
microfilm and this one has ever ended
that will read the visuals are data and
upload your charting log as well as your
password okay why people you install
those kind of pirated repaired apps or
games there are many reasons for example
mostly recently or we know that there is
a very popular game this is a what's the
name pokémon go how many people here
play pokemon go oh pretty many well so
pokemon gold there are two requirements
one is that in some regions over the
world pokemon gold dunno provide service
the signal you said to play it you you
have to go outside and then to capture a
monster but the problem is that some one
to know one to go all set
or maybe for example if there is a
pikachu in da in White House whatever
you do walking into whether he'll say oh
hello Obama I want to capture monster in
your desk right so the requirement is
that you need to figure the GPS but if
your iphone is not jailbroken how to
figure GPS the way is Rebecca the game
and then provided a developed to provide
it affect GPS location to cheating with
again that's a requirement so although
after you produce the thousands of
malware how to distribute it the first
way and the major way is through the
enterprise distribution so under prior
distribution is used it so it's another
way these are besides of the apple store
it's a way they're provided it
accomplished so that you could
distribute your own private app to
employees without public access and
without the ipod's review so that nobody
know your internal code to gain a to
enloe into a are under prior
distribution program everything you need
trees use some documents of your company
and as well as a little money and also
you can even buy a such can double
account or program certificate from the
underground market or you and you if you
if you indeed cannot pay one-half
bitcoin you could pay three dollars to
get his signing as a service that's a
lesson else to build since you know in
the underground anyway this one this
method has a long history being abused
by the parotid apple store but then our
since the bell local it was a or begin
to abuse by the malware so this order is
released after you send your abs through
the enterprise certificate you could
distribute it through a protocol damn
the itm SOS and the only thing you need
to do is is embedded at this URL into
any
to a traffic and then the user will
being promoted but well well see a
dialog Larry's ask you whether you want
to install which kind of sins note that
it is seen in this dialog is totally
under your control so you could add many
of chilling scenes like fission to your
user toward to trial based Oscar the
entry in storage and actually this has
already been combined with lots of other
or traditional ad hoc basis like the
traffic hijacking all our rituals are
being used in you know complements the
website a decision so a pretty powerful
message were distributed oh by the way
this also used it for some apps
self-promotion Oh for example well when
I visited some top-ranked news website
in u.s. I also saw some similar problems
huh so besides of enterprise there was a
program which is free that is a personal
development so here which it begins to
freeing about half year ago I pires
restrictions that as a personal
developer you should this is only for
your own taste so you can only install
the new 100 devices but what
unbelievable is that the jig helpers
these amazing feminine even trying to
abuse this program our previously nobody
nobody's think this is possible because
it the restriction is no way to bypass
but this one is smart that he
implemented everything in the Xcode to
apply the certificate and then use it to
generate a true Pro a valid certificate
from ipod server through your iphone and
then the download front front front
sewer from the mail we also see two
silver downloaded and same app and then
send everything in your own do
in the devices and then story in the
devices so it's a saint poor devices and
abuse this program the benefit is that
first of all is totally free and the
second is that I poke a note I'll say
this make hosted at Apple will open
thousands of certificate and no idea but
anyway this happen so medication is that
first of all if you are installed or
running it's underpriced that you can
send apps I Pavel ask you to double
conference that you translate all and in
the after the OS 9 you need to even
click many times to a topic on fringe
and also every turn get a report of
malware of new discovered mobile app or
real will recover revokes abuser
enterprise certificate but the problem
is that first of all if you want to get
another one that's really low cost and
the second is that even i provoke lead
in the silver set there will still be a
catch in the infected devices so how is
joyce is no courage or revoke the
certificate lists every day or every
hour are in actually courage in act
three to seven days so it will kinds of
results so after you revoked it or it
will take about three to seven days to
be effective in your devices this is do
a window i have also reduced as a valid
a date of personal certificate but
mostly ridiculous ones that is thinking
what months ago we're going to pour a
new or personal certificate from ipod
sewer and the micro instance system told
me this one you see our is in effective
right now i will no idea why that's a
totally new account that new certificate
anyway the next one is that you could
try
to a natural male well under the apple
store so I put two has days are
cultivating but no details so nobody
know how they do it stayed even it
dynamically automatically or manually no
one knows but there are pretty many ways
one just the first look the first method
is amazing is it's not that you could
I'll pee yourself you could exploit
yourself so you you embedded in our P
vulnerability in your own are so sorry
it's the option won't be obviously
exploited measure okay you invaded it
one billet in your own app and then we
exploit basic by the network traffic to
change the behavior but this is a silly
measure of this all that la successfully
over offense or talk to apple store but
a neighbor sees is used by drill mail
well before and the second one is that
you could perform code obfuscation to
this is assumed that the ipod will have
some experts you perform manually review
to your code and also this could bypass
some now security guys that are also it
could bypass and automatically rose to
detector code so the ones that you could
target a certificate data for example
these are examples that freedom of the
instant age in the in steady will our it
prevailed functionality like who viewed
your Instagram pages this is a
functionality that the Instagram
operation is not provided but these apps
provided our actual you can steal social
i bestow back who cares about who kills
with me or or in study Tector insta
analyze everything exam you will still
feel awesome apps like that but these
these are apps we are actually uploaded
the password you imported through the
sewer and also there were some our apps
that will steal what happen the first
message to our with the
to apple store is that you could perform
checking of the environment of execution
for example you could determine the
geolocation you could determine sample
the IPO juice you could determine the
language of devices this is assume that
the manually reviewing of the of the
ipod's region is performed by some
people in some locations in specific at
hand so for example you could provide a
app to apple store and disable the
normal functionality through network off
for like two weeks after two weeks are
it past the cultivating you could enable
it again through network traffic so for
example this is a male well that during
the if you access it by devices in
English all or acts are visited are
outside of the channel you will see it's
a english learning app so i can imagine
that i post waiting guy are listening
the good morning or it's time to wake up
something a crab but actually if you are
accessing enough from the IP address in
china your Gators are so the party apple
store yeah it's a soda party apple store
clent app in official apple store I
can't imagine I can say okay the North
why's that actually you could just do it
is the ipods those cold ratings and use
far far away from what we sort is not
restricted at all okay so for example
this one actually saw same way it
contains so many insensitive AP is and
so many sensitive streams in the code in
plain text that we could read pretty
many of rules to college 21 it let's
actually high advantage but it bypassed
i will store again again and again i
really doubt the cultivating to resist
ok so the medication is that first of
all you could
movies for apple store but there is no
remote Keaney which means if you have
already been infected I volcano remotely
iron storage to mitigating a signal
problem is that you could theoretically
adopt a more restricted review but the
most nervous the most original changes
so that you know your body months ago I
pollen also that all apps code review
our time will reduce the front a week to
a day I can image how could they improve
the code review in this way so another
way so choose through the USB so all at
the first you could using any USB
devices to install malware into your
iphone for example you can you can use
it you can use a rechargeable power bank
to install malware and you will actively
even joint so after that Apple added a
functionality that you are hardcore the
computer and resume the phone to verify
each other to authorize each other so
after then they will well look on SDC
one which uses this trust relationship
that it will infect your laptop at first
and it assume that you have laptop well
connected to your phone which has
already been paired so after that under
that assumption it's really install
malware into your phone this is totally
in background nobody ever mentioned our
even notice the baggage how to mitigate
though are some technical way for
example you could ask a user to confer
inch every chance that you install
something through USB cable but that not
happen then medication didn't implement
it yet so the nozzle line is a fair play
me in the middle don't be afraid about
that world that that's just a name and
this is actually idea
and medicine that design for at the
first designed for ipod about i think is
15 years ago that's a first generation
of ipod it's not iphone let's use it for
the music's drm protection so the
logical is that you purchase the music
or app from apple store and then
download it to your pc or your mac and
then you think the your installed these
apps or sink this music from your pc or
mac to your iphone or ipod so the sink
presidio is that the device will send a
soon as and data to your phone out sort
through your computer and you computer
make a response to your phone which me
are this procedure is used that you
approve that the computer has really
purchased valid beautiful app from the
Apple Store so i will have some design
that from the from the ipod ipod a
design that first of all or issue has
restrictions that each apple ID could
note banded visa and most of five
computers but you to know restricted how
many iphones or ipod or ipad you could
use so because I think maybe because I
the first they are into any apple store
on iPod so anyway and the second that
you're in production is only really one
with the app is no readable visa I apply
these know really believe is the devices
so which means that if I downloaded an
app from apple store and you downloaded
one through ten oh dear hope you are you
exactly the same they are protected by
the same key okay and so I posted a is
that it related the security of this
brochure is this drm really on first of
all computer also education has a
maximum limitation second there will be
a physical connection between a computer
and your iPhone however the main the
middle in this way ad-hoc will purchase
app and then the transfer
the authorization data to vicens pc
which actually do note you purchase it
in before and then using a big
conspiracy to install app okay so in the
HTC One roadhog will submit have to a
hostile and the author himself
downloaded the app from apple store as
well in the in the same time the itunes
clenched we are also downloading out
also authorization data of this app to
attacks our sewer so at all will impeded
this app into the windows client which
is malicious and also it will deploy
these apps authorization data in through
the city whose ova so the windows clench
will be installed that you are weaklings
pc and weakens pc will fetch the also
eight authorization code from the front
of little silver so now in the victims
pc it has an app installer it has them
also as code the code is prepared for
the attack but due to apples design flaw
that also incision code could also use
the by victim pc and then this victim pc
performed being be in the middle visa
iOS devices so successfully the app are
installed into a device and then after
all the behavior of these families so
mostly critical behavior is that it will
upload the password in you in 40 ok how
to mitigate this ad hoc no way actually
this earth hug will report it through
apple in three years before two years
later after two years the SDC will occur
but till now there is no enemy get
through this ad hoc because the problem
is that for example you could offer your
fund the ipod
tourism is a malware I just said amazing
is that immediately remove it right just
to remove it if rival store but in this
earth hug even you remove the jab free
ho store since the also code has already
been deployed that release it was over
it will be continuing avoided it it will
use the forever you have no way to to
revoke their also code cause back
because of the design that wine is
owning combined bending is the embedded
I for yourself it's relevant with the 15
species you really went to be z OS
devices it's really went to be the ipid
so that that's just the leg deployed a
privately I'll distribute a private the
key that you can note you cannot stop it
to decrypt that the poverty or clears
data it's just like that way so I keep
his plane because I don't think there
will be some way in currently design to
resolve the problem the nozzle line is
abusing MDM MDM is powerful you could
use it to control devices in many ways
and there were someone behaves been
disclosed in plaza to years but it will
also be abused by till now at least the
true melville families that abuse the
MDM are bad fishing of course cheating's
and people okay q10 let's have a
positive to evil so do something evil
first of all we'll be using private api
privatized defend bedzie it's an API
exposed by the SDK or by the system run
time but it's not documented also so you
can also call it undocumented API so I /
only expose the pretty safe ap is for
normal developers but itself in the
early assistance poor installed apps it
were using some more sensitive variants
which is private for example or in these
are friend work you could see that ipod
owning talk
you three ap is to get some baseline
information but actually if you analyze
that our frameworks binary code you
could see that code in the exported
samples there are pretty many of good
stuffs or bad stuffs for example you
could use these ap is through a gate a
list of all installed application which
is disallowed by able so the capability
of abusing private api could you could
use it to take pictures record videos
audios use an older versions of areas
you can even use it to receive or send
short messages or even make a phone call
so combined together you can really do
something or the medication Apple has
already adopted is that first of all
ourselves sensitive resources handle
image region has been redesigned for
example the short messages handling are
currently can only be sent or received
by Apple's own app our second is that
lots of unnecessary private if James had
already been removed the Bible and stood
and mostly effectively that are argued
on another layer of security protection
that is entitlement so entitlement is a
runtime checking our sorcerer is no
drunken chicken entitlement is a all the
signing certificate based our permission
model said I'll say that for example if
you want to install an app you need to
have an indictment of mobile installs or
install item but that one I / when the
issue to normal developers so after that
are accepted for the private api you
could do whole pageant to yourself hot
patches are actually the codes are self
uploading self-updating or call Stan
loaded and dynamically execution is this
a lot available
symbolic for security reason however you
could buy passage the babe housing is
pretty likely to appear but it's not so
complex like all of you you need to
control the return address but you could
adopt a similar message you're using the
scribbler like javascript i'll do a
scribble scribble language treated as
data and then you in painted a a neck
javascript engine in your own app to
reduce script as data but but this data
will drive your engine to you take you
the code right so Abel cannot disable
that bass tones is there was some very
popular hot paging from work like just
as your wax patch these are really
popular in a developer community cause
developers to have the requirements of a
performer hot hedging this is because
anytime you want to update your app the
apple store I will have to drink with
each review it that will be another week
so if you have a critical security issue
of our stability issue you will need to
wait one week to make your update BD
stealing apple store and you will be
with like for one day two months is for
users to install it to update it right
but this whole patching you could
immediately affect you so our developers
welcome this kind of technical but these
techniques cause will be abused by
malware to implement a leg remote
controlling or sensitive calls hiding at
the stretcher or which is exactly the
reason why I people would like to
disable it also you could to run time
manipulation I just said that any code
in that protein an app could do
everything include
real data also could manipulate your
code so you could actually do hooking I
just listed introduced the example of
the pokémon goal the program goes GPS
are and our GPS proofing ourselves the
implementation is justice through this
way so you could using the sacred which
is popular for jailbroken community and
Captain Hook a decision or you and you
could customize your hooking code to
manipulate your abs run tang and change
all behavior so hooker data so this is
an example this is tracer previously
people believe this is hacking teen it's
actually not this is a is the company I
think anyways I can remember this is a
company who produced the commercial
spare well for jailbroken devices before
and then also job a half of the heck
intensely King it copied a song called
from hugging him and repacked you the
intro facebook skype whatsapp telegram
which had a seizure and using enterprise
that you get rude in fact non jailbroken
phone use the mask vulnerability to
culver existing apps to read their data
and use the runtime hooking like this to
add some more interface to Absolon code
so there including sailor you charting
history so there are some design flaw
due to tell our skivvies and make profit
i also skip this because this is no so
technical you see justice and durations
through the underground market so if you
are interesting you could discuss with
me of name let's review the approaches
that we can see there are lots of ways
to produce it to distribute each you
could do some evil since even in the
description of the sandbox and you could
make profit in some way so takeaways
first of all Mel well especially a less
Mel well it's pretty different with
traditional malware or windows or
android plan
on it to note should be out manually to
know peace process or dedicate it to no
need to be general it do note to be a
transparent or now interactive it could
be many many different forms or ways to
perform the top the second takeaway is
that they are worried are some practical
although low-tech but still practical
the effective way to a don't you talk
and some technicals has been mitigated
but some still haven't or have no way
and through this through research on the
approaches and through research on the
reasons through the reasons I think we
could our fund more in the world later
so there are some security suggestions
of the most important is thinking that
do not install app from third party or
send bank rossii certificate also you do
need to protect your pc and mac computer
and as we r do network for prevented hog
leg is malware are thank you that's all
sorry about we have two minutes for FA
are for questions any questions no okay
cool thank you again