thanks a lot I'm having a terrific time
at this conference I've never I've never
been here before and I hope you guys are
having a good time to want to thank the
organizers and the the guys that and
women that read the papers and and all
the volunteers and stuff like that my
sponsors is just a great thing so I'm
delighted to see all you people here and
I mean a lot of people here for this
hour of the morning and I'm a little a
little surprised that you're all here
instead of at the beach where you know
I'm sure it's a lot more fun and I'm
only partly kidding about that i mean
the title of the talk is hunting
government back doors not like
announcing new ones if i was announcing
new ones you know i feel entitled to
this kind of an audience but no this is
really more about the journey i'm going
to talk about some of the ones i've
tried to bring to light others have
brought to life over the last decade or
so but it's it's really more about the
journey and where it goes from here I
think they're there is a substantial
point2 talking about that though for
journalists and for researchers like
yourselves government officials
executives and regular people who i
think i'd be pretty interested in this
if they aren't already there at some
point as i said and going back over what
we've learned and thinking about what we
still don't know and thinking about how
we we did figure out what we know and
with that hopefully we can figure out
how to start drinking out the rest of it
so you bear with me but there is a sort
of a long arc here that were that we're
trying to get to where we find out more
about this stuff just a level set on the
slides I'm not really a visual person
there that I was 200 deaveon had 200
slides I'm gonna have 18 and they're
really great for resting your eyes if
you want some place to look other than
me but they are not the foundation of
this talk they're just illustrations
that's that's just the way it is so
sorry about that
so Who I am why I'm here I'm my name is
Joe man my byline is Joseph and I've got
the profound good fortune to be working
as an investigative journalist at a
solvent company which is something that
I wanted to do when I was in high school
five years ago or 10 okay 35 and it's a
wonderful privileged job and with that
especially if you're at a large media
company that is solvent I think there's
a lot of responsibility so with that in
mind I'd like to ask your indulgence for
the first part of this talk as I talk a
little bit about the ethics of choosing
to report on this stuff I don't usually
hear a lot about ethics and security
cons and my best guess is that it's
because ethics are kind of squishy and
knowledge isn't and everybody has their
own ethics and it's pretty hard as a
general rule to convince somebody that
their ethics are wrong and your ethics
are right so instead people just try to
pass on knowledge and let people do what
they want with the information I don't
really disagree with any of that but
having covered tech security since 1999
I feel like one of the tricky bits of
the industry is that there isn't a lot
of discussion and there's something of a
vacuum or at least a DMZ when it comes
to ethical issues there's no course on
ethics that I know of its required in
most computer science majors or EE
majors and for that matter there's no e
major or computer science major it's
required for success in security so even
if it was required and i'm not sure what
instruction folks would get and if
sometimes wish that there was there for
some kind of like a 1-800 ethical like a
hotline not so a hacker researcher with
a question could get the answer right
away from some great guru but to help
facilitate a discussion about it for
those who aren't used to it I'm
regressing here but I just want to give
you a general alert that I take morality
see
seriously and before I get into a talk
about finding back doors that you know
involve some pretty heavy issues I'm
gonna I'm gonna frame it in moral terms
my day job use acid technology projects
reporter Reuters which is one of the
oldest and largest and the single most
global news organization on the planet
and one committed to journalistic
integrity and independence that said I'm
hearing today and my personal capacity
as the saying goes I previously worked
for the Financial Times for the Los
Angeles Times for ten years Bloomberg
back with nobody had heard of Bloomberg
and before that the Charlotte Observer
North Carolina where I started out in
North Carolina back when in gastonia
back when budding reporters started out
covering small-town cops instead of
going directly to some you know website
without any editors I've also written
three books to which are at least partly
about the security world all the rave
the rise and fall Sean panics Napster a
lot of people don't realize that Shawn
Fanning was a hacker and he got a lot of
help from other hackers so that that's
one aspect of that of that book and then
probably the more well the more relevant
one is that one fatal system error which
is a deep dive into organized Russian
cyber crime and its partial protection
by the government there that book is
structured around the true adventures of
a private American security Wiz in a
Welsh police detective who teamed up to
identify catch and get prosecuted three
mid-level denial of service attack
extortionists in Russia who were
attacking Western companies and they
were eventually sent away to eight years
in Russian prison if you know much about
Russian jurisprudence you will know that
that is an extremely rare occurrence
even now despite a narrative that
includes hookers guns and drugs it ended
up in the official published reading
list of the US Strategic Command and was
compared by New Yorker by The New Yorker
magazine to the novels of stieg larsson
the girl who kicked the hornet's nest
series
I'm giving a little detail on that book
not merely because it makes a great gift
but but also because i want to stress
cue that I'm an equal-opportunity
reporter I know that my work on fatal
system error made Russian intelligence
concerned enough to have me tailed when
I was over there the Federal Security
Service RFS be also directed the
interior ministry or mvd not to speak to
me on the grounds that I was probably a
us by in addition I'm one of the many
reporters who've written deeply about
Chinese government supported hacking one
of my pieces from late last year
revealed that Microsoft investigators
looking into the hijacking of hotmail
accounts belonging to journalists human
rights attorneys in China Tibetans and
wiegers abroad had been hijacked by the
mainland government although Microsoft's
most senior leaders elected not to
announce that fact or for that matter
warn the victims so I want to be clear
although most of the reporting on back
doors that I've done this far has been
about what has gone on in the United
States that is not because I have it in
for the United States I'm interested in
all back doors and I think government
back doors are especially interesting
because they are forged in the name of
the people I've done the most work on us
back doors because that is what I found
the most information about I do think it
is possible for you this journalists to
do good work on Russian or Chinese back
doors but it is usually easier to report
about the goings-on where you live and I
think there is also a moral obligation
to do so if you can I'm willing to
entertain an argument that says the
Chinese can't write critical things
about the Chinese government and the
Russians would be well-advised not droid
critical things about the Russian
government and therefore American
journalists would be the most use
writing critical things about those
government's rather than beating up on
our own which after all allows the most
freedom of the freedom of the three but
I would be more receptive to that
argument if I in my peers had not
already spilled so much ink and
slaughtered so many electrons talking
talking about the cyber horrors of
Russia and China before it merged in
fairly dramatic fashion that we were the
Siberia STUV the mall
though it now seems that everyone is
pretty much doing everything they can
get away with on the internet the u.s.
is in the awkward position of being
first and best with the most structural
advantages and the most vulnerability
all once is it ethical to seek to
uncover one's own government's back
doors it's a fair question I'm not an
absolutist but I'd like to start with
the words of inventor philanthropist and
college founder Emile faber knowledge is
good here's how I approach the issue
first if I can find out about it there's
an excellent chance that a rival
government can find out about it if not
a malicious hacker this part is similar
to the consensus of the security company
excuse me security community in finding
bugs and disclosing them responsibly for
a bunch of iconoclastic authority
defying and somewhat anti social
creatures there is something awfully
close to unanimity in the belief that is
it a good that is a good thing to find
software flaws warn the vendor and then
war in the public of course some will
sell the information for money to to
private or government buyers everyone
has to make a living but almost nobody I
can think of what's outside perhaps
certain FBI officials believe it's
morally wrong to warn people about flaws
the next question is to what extent
government back doors are kind of flaw
again some people would barely recognize
this as a question I'm not one of them
what if it is installed only in an
obscure piece of gear manufactured
outside of America and sold entirely
overseas and let's say it's marketed
especially to violent extremists if that
sounds too far-fetched please google
mujahideen secrets i can wait mu j aah I
de en if at least some of you agree that
that's a valid target for back door and
perhaps one that researchers and
journalists shouldn't be falling all
over themselves to expose let's look at
the opposite extreme perhaps something
crafted here and widely used here and
abroad say Google
or gmail iOS Windows Facebook and so on
I've been dealing with spies and ex buys
and spy contractors and spy helpers for
more than a decade one thing I've heard
from several of them is that even when
something looks all purpose it is not
for example say there's a piece of code
hidden inside of an operating system
that will work as a beacon for US
intelligence but only when something
else happens such as visiting a specific
website with another bit of code then
there's a secret handshake and the game
is on this may limit the number of
targets and incidental surveillance
subjects it may even do so in ways that
conform with the judgments of the
Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court
which interprets FISA maybe it even gets
us close enough to the mujahideen
secrets example that most people in this
room wouldn't have an issue with it but
there are still a couple of problems
first if the self-imposed backdoor
restrictions limit the targeting to say
anyone I pgo mapped to be probably
outside our country that may be good
enough by intelligence agency standards
and the court that oversees them it's
hard to know but the FISA Court does not
block any surveillance of non-us persons
on the grounds that the American
Constitution is for Americans well that
may be correct as a matter of law that's
not much comfort if you're not an
American which is most of the world and
now that they know this is happening
it's a big problem for Microsoft Google
and all the other companies with the
majority of their business elsewhere
second about those self-imposed
limitations my spooky contacts tell me
that the back door has half of a playing
card and the other half gets supplied by
another someone or something I'm sure
that's what happens at least some of the
time but if you used to give anonymous
intelligence sources the benefit of the
doubt 10 years ago do you still or given
that they used to say they did not
collect information about Americans
under oath before Congress has the
burden of proof shifted a little bit in
your mind third I said multiple sources
have told me the self limiting story but
there's also evidence in the other
direction I've heard from one source
that a large chip maker
was asked to put in a back door and
declined I've heard from a second source
that a large antivirus vendor was asked
to put in a back door and declined I
have heard from a third source that a
large pc maker was asked to put in a
back door and agreed an eco cell founder
of the messaging app wicker says she was
asked if she would allow back door as
well none of those four cases included
any caveats about it working only in
Afghanistan or only for convicted felons
or anything like that and of course we
looked at the back doors that have
already come to light day two appeared
to be all purpose the first time I
reported in depth about back door was
ten years ago in 2006 I've never spoken
in public about it about this before the
New York Times had reported the previous
December the end of 2005 that the NSA
was eavesdropping on some hundreds of
international phone calls and emails
without a warrant within weeks a
colleague and I the LA Times wrote that
the NSA also had access to all domestic
calling records that is the metadata
that eventually outraged everyone when
USA Today and then aided by Snowden The
Guardian reported the same thing back
then after that story appeared I got a
tip that it was bigger than that that
the NSA controlled access to a room in
the ATT building on folsom street in san
francisco room 641 a that received a
perfect copy of all fiber optic traffic
flowing through that hub which was the
city's largest that's the room there I
was one of the first people to see in
that photograph eventually I would get
schematic drawings illustrating the
diversion the whistleblower on the
record former co-workers corroborating
his account and current and former
administration officials confirming that
they collected data in this way although
at the time it was still widely believed
that the NSA did not collect information
on Americans if some of you are familiar
with the story but don't recall the LA
Times breaking it it is because we
didn't the editor the newspaper took a
call from Michael Hayden the
NSA chief turned Deputy Director of
National Intelligence and then he spiked
the story the contents of that phone
call were off the record so I will not
describe them here but when it later
came out that the LA Times had decided
not to run what had proved to be a very
significant story the editor of the
paper was quoted as saying that we did
not have a complete understanding of
what happened to the data collected in
that room interestingly that is still in
dispute the whistleblower 18t retiree
Marc Klein gave his account to the
electronic frontier foundation for its
use in two lawsuits one against the
company and one against the NSA one of
those two jewel vs NSA is still pending
if you can believe that one might hope
such a fundamental issue as whether the
largest private telecom in the country
can turn over everything it has to a
setup arranged by an intelligence agency
charged with avoiding us snooping would
be something that could be fast-tracked
for a resolution kind of important right
but there was the lack of standing
argument that the plaintiffs did not
could not show that they had personally
been eavesdropped on or otherwise harmed
and the trustees state state secrets
dodge and then there was the sweeping
amnesty passed by Congress which Obama
was against before he was four and that
ended the suit against AT&T in truth my
editor was right ten years ago when he
didn't when he said we didn't know
exactly what happened with the AT&T data
and we still don't know now room 641 a
could be what we now see his classic
upstream collection as the Snowden
documents called it but for all we know
the the the phone company keeps
everything and only hands over metadata
or information from specific accounts
called out by the FISA Court or maybe it
all goes to Maryland and only a certain
number of people control through it for
contact chaining going out what used to
be three hops and is now two hops from
its terror suspect we don't know for
sure maybe the legal process and jewel
versus NSA will ultimately tell us the
answer and maybe it will not
the point is it's pretty interesting I
believe it should be reported given the
convoluted and often unknowable chain of
custody involved in these sorts of
issues I've come to the conclusion that
back doors are back doors whatever they
are collecting which brings me to
another recurring theme who is doing the
collecting philosophically most of the
security community probably agree is
that all back doors are bad maybe unless
it's one of their own shortcuts for
remote support and again it can often be
an oval unknowable exactly what's going
on but as with targeting I think there's
a continuum if undocumented access that
circumvent security is a reasonable
definition of a backdoor then a tech
support loophole is arguably the least
worst then there's the more general
purpose corporate access like the Sony
digital rights management rootkit
debacle not to be confused with any of
the other sony security debacles
organized or independent hackers leaving
themselves a means back in are probably
worse than that another country having
access to all customers or product X is
very hard to distinguish from that but
arguably worse still and then there's
the question of where I put my own
countries back door as worse than all
those say using an American company to
spy on Americans like an annoying number
of answers I think it depends as a
threat to an individual it actually
depends wildly if I were in an extremely
repressive place and I was a bit of a
dissident I would rather have the
American spy on me than my own
government if I were a nice friendly
democracy I might rather have my own
government spy on me than the Americans
if I'm literally talked about myself to
pet it depends what I'm reporting on and
therefore like what day of the week it
is but which is the bigger global
problem your own government or someone
else's well if it's another government
doing it then your government can
protect you if it wants to if it's your
government doing it then there's nobody
who can protect you that's one reason
that I think that these sort of own
goals
might be the biggest fish to catch and
the other has to do with hoe pacity an
industry truism is that security through
obscurity fails in the end because it
will eventually be worth someone's time
to pawn the plumb the depths and
discover the truth at this point we
expect country a to attack company
Company B it's in the nature of
scorpions to sting but what about
country be attacking come company be
attacking or seducing or hiring that's
obscure in this country and I think it's
pretty obscure in every country and
therefore it's worth while exploring
companies are stuck in this intersection
actually a couple of intersections
they're stuck between customers
worldwide and various governments as
well as between democracy and the needs
of a capitalist entity to make money
they're responsible to their
shareholders and to some extent
accountable to their customers but
they're pressed more often by subtle and
unsubtle pressure from the government's
that come in infinite variations if
Satan were to appear on earth and that's
assuming that he hasn't already it would
be smart for him to do it through
Microsoft and Apple and Disney and
coca-cola and it would be up to us to
figure out what was going on so if you
agree with me that all back doors need
exposure no matter what they are or who
takes it how do we find out where they
are usually we don't that's one of the
bigger lessons that EDD Snowden brought
us from Hawaii and all the more reason
that when we do find one it has a lot of
instructive value as you know they're
going to great many stories based on the
Snowden documents covering all manner of
things as an aside and I don't mean to
sound ungrateful for the information but
a majority of the published documents
have been about NSA techniques and
capabilities if you accept the fact that
your country is going to have an
intelligence agency you will probably
want them to have pretty awesome
capabilities I think more important
questions are how they got those
capabilities and even more important
than that
they do with them and I wish we'd had
more stories on that so far I think we
haven't in part because of access
limitations what Snowden what's known
and others could see and in part because
the agencies have been reluctant to
explain very much on those on those
points there's been something of an
exception with the phone calling
database to the CDR is calling calling
records because that stoked a lot of
initial alarm and on the way to some
fairly substantial changes some of the
most substantial changes post knowdon't
in the law we learned a lot about how
this was actually used it took a while
but the NSA says that in 2013 there are
only 423 423 queries of that database
that doesn't sound that terrible but we
but that's a that's a that's an
exception mostly we don't know how the
stuff has been used we don't know what
happened to the AT&T traffic on folsom
street we don't know how much
information from Facebook and Google and
others went into prizm the database of
internet company data and we don't know
what came out the other end we don't
know how widely the NSA has deployed in
point exploit to exploitation and
overall we don't know how many backdoors
there are how they get installed how
often they are checked or what they've
yielded we do know some things we didn't
before on September 5 2013 the New York
Times and the nonprofit ProPublica
jointly published stories based on stone
documents describing project Bull Run a
long-running effort to weaken us and
international encryption standards and
win access to traffic encrypted by SSL
and other systems the publication said
that the effort began from the ashes of
the failed Clipper Chip campaign to
openly require backdoor access and
hardware and that it depended on secret
court orders and persuasion as well as
the subversion of standards now the
Clipper Chip fight was a long time ago
so if you weren't around this is what a
clipper ship look like
I hope you weren't around back dinner
might see something funnier now some set
some facts were excised from the
articles at the request of intelligence
officials and the first articles did not
name something called the dual lip to
curve drbg pseudo-random number
generator often known as dual EC but
they said that stone memos appeared to
confirm that a fatal weakness discovered
by to Microsoft engineers in 2007 was
engineered by the NSA which developed
the encryption technique and got adopted
by the national institute of standards
and technology which is required by
statute to consult with NSA and then by
the the International Organization for
Standardization which is a group of wood
known as iso which is group so
sophisticated and expert in figuring out
how people should standardized things
that they pick the initials that they
choose to go by the initials ISO even
though their name is the international
organization for standards and in fact
the initials do not track the order of
the three words of the name of the
outfit in any of its three official
languages but nonetheless the NSA
internal memos uncovered by the the
publications describe the getting this
adopted as a standard was quote a
challenge infinite in finessing the
glues in those stories were enough for
cryptographers to figure out very
quickly that they were talking about
dual you see it was also obvious to NIST
less than a week later that body which
is run by the Commerce Department
announced that it was seeking new input
and whether to drop to Lisi as one of
four crypto standards it had blessed
back in 2006 and that in the meantime
people should stop using it hi did not
have access to the Snowden files so I
didn't have the luxury of combing
through all these classified documents
and picking which to make public note to
those in government service here today
there will be one slide at the very end
with classified material from Snowden
technically classified material still I
warn you before it comes up instead what
i did is i looked at the funeral ii
newly
which documents that had just come out I
read up on dual EC and I talked to
experts what I found most surprising was
that people had been poking holes in it
for years as the Microsoft engineers
Shoom alan ferguson had pointed out in
2007 whoever picked the initial constant
if they did it in a certain way would be
able to predict the output and read
whatever was encrypted with dual EC the
more I looked into it the weirder it got
Xiumin Ferguson weren't the first to say
something to look distinctly off about
dual EC some others said they hadn't
bothered to complain because they
assumed that nobody would use it
especially when there are three other
choices to get certification for some
government contracts one of the
defense's that's been raised for dual EC
was that whoever adopted it could pick
their own constant but if they did then
they didn't get automatic certification
finally it's not like dual EC had
amazing other wonderful qualities that
might have mitigated the fact that it
could be back doored in fact it was
orders of magnitude slower than the
other alternatives in other words it
stunk even before was exposed as rotten
now if you're a technology vendor has
gone through the trouble of getting
certified for one thing or another you
tell people so that you can get hired by
folks that need a certified vendor so i
found a list of tech companies reporting
that they were certified for using dual
ec knowing what i did about how lousy
duals ec was at this point i found the
long list on here to be depressing but I
can still see how some company that did
a ton of business with the government
and companies that mimic government
requirements would want to be certified
in every possible way so then I started
looking about looking for the biggest
impact of dual EC looking at that list
again how did dual EC make its presence
the most felt who jumped in with both
feet I went through the list again
looking for who would have played a
major role in the tech ecosystem and one
company left out of me the company
called RSA now RSA is not enormous but
it put dual EC in a toolkit that was
widely used by many other companies in
securing websites and communication
potentially spreading the taint vary
widely and here's the thing that really
struck me it may dual EC the default
that means if you're using the RSA
toolkit you could put in some effort and
pick one of the three other demonstrably
faster demonstrably non back durable
number generators but if you just did
the easy thing and went with the
showroom model you got the worst and the
most suspicious of the bunch if you're
young or new to the field you may just
no RSA as the company that puts on a
somewhat larger version of Chaka Khan in
San Francisco ever here but why did that
conference now the largest security con
in the world get started it was to
organize opposition to the US government
crackdown on serious independent
cryptography it started in 1991 the same
year as a proposed law to mandate
backdoor access for law enforcement
which failed setting up the Clipper Chip
fight RSA's founding fathers led the
fight against that ship to you can see
why so why was their creation the
company RSA apparently doing more than
anyone else to spread it back door I
spent a lot of the next three months
trying to figure that out and in
December 2013 I published a story saying
that RSA had taken ten million dollars
in a federal contract that required it
to use dual EC as the default the crux
of that story came from two anonymous
sources and I'm certainly not going to
out them here but I can tell you a
little bit about how they came to light
because I think that might make it
easier for others to do similar work and
I think this work is important early on
in the process I tried to come up with
hypotheses but how this deal might have
come to pass and who would have known
about it and I thought about the winners
and losers internally and externally who
would have been pleased about that kind
of a deal and who would have been angry
at the time and after its exposure I was
looking for a specific act between
specific people at a specific time but
was critical to zoom out and learn the
context in our essays case and in many
others corporate structure and culture
are important RSA had been founded by 3m
mighty cryptographic codes and was
initially hostile to number of
government initiatives but it had merged
with the seller of secure access tokens
and was on the road to being bought by
much larger storage company EMC a key
patent was expiring and as that was
happening prestige was leaning
scientific stars left and sales people
grew relatively more important to the
company once you know that much it's
much easier to approach people and try
out theories they are the old
researchers there are the new
researchers there are old and new sales
people and the government you've got
people inside the agencies that are
proud or chagrined and their overseas
overseers ditto and perhaps other arms
of government that were caught napping
and woke up mad the more research you do
the better chances you will be heard out
and given a confirmation or an argument
or a tip or an idea about whom to see
next I should say to that there are
multiple ways for backdoor to be created
and I've learned through the years that
until you know which is the case you
need to adjust your reporting for all
the possibilities first there is a
straight-up appeal to patriotism from an
agency to the CEO of an American company
if that CEOs American at least pre
Snowden I believe this is much more
common than people realize CEO doesn't
write code or make design decisions
though so there are some fingerprints
left when those commands are given
second there's a classified contract for
goods or services that includes the
special item or an unclassified contract
with a classified annex it is important
to note that this does not have to come
with a capitalized and quote ated notice
on the back that says you now to agree
to help the US by and all of your
customers whenever possible it just says
hey use our random number generator or
equivalent we need it for certification
or some internal benchmark or so earning
here can get a raise or because it's
classified and don't ask any more
questions this sort of a deal brings in
more possible sources including business
development people specializing in
government deals third there can be
hacking via a low-level insider or forth
from an outsider or
even stay with me of an insider by an
outsider when the insider never knows
what happened credential theft is one of
the biggest sources of some of the worst
breaches right the same is true if you
want to muck with somebody's code or you
know just do it for later fifth is the
exotic stuff like intercepting packages
and other supply chain hijinks that take
real effort and I'm going to leave a
possible sixth final way as a ? a secret
court order which means there would be
legal sources for what happened the new
york times and propublica stories on
Bull Run said the NSA effort to defeat
cryptography use secret orders in
addition to standards version but there
was little detail and as noted they also
said the NSA used less sinister things
like super computing power and money
obviously the fisa court approves
specific tabs but a court-ordered
backdoor has not surfaced in the snowden
cash i've been trying to find out about
any that might be there too and i've not
heard of any my sources who reach as
high as the White House have told me
they don't know of any either but it is
possible that this could be one of those
things where some companies get a court
order and don't fight now there's get a
quarter and do fight I don't have a lot
of evidence I can share for that it's
just a theory but i think it's worth
exploring for a couple of reasons one is
Apple versus FBI the Justice Department
found a federal magistrate it could
convince that would not be a radical
reinterpretation of a 2 century old law
to force Apple to write code that would
hack into its own devices this sort of
thing typically happens under seal but
it came out this time because the
government thought the light of day
would be on its side we're talking about
a dead terrorists work phone after all
but Apple can afford some pretty good
lawyers some pretty good PR people and
the tide was going the other way when
the government suddenly found a
different means into the device which
underst unjust which unsurprisingly had
nothing on it are there similar life
cases against smaller and or less feisty
companies where the government has
prevailed under seal we don't know but
it seems to me that that's possible and
that's in conventional courts what about
the always closed FISA Court
many advocates are only heard if they
appeal in 2013 The Guardian reported
that Microsoft had given pre encryption
access to the NSA to hotmail excuse me
to Outlook email in response Microsoft
told the publication when we upgrade or
update products we aren't absolved from
the need to comply with existing or
future law enforcement excuse me
existing or future lawful demands future
lawful demands people have looked and
they have not found any case law given
giving a legal rationale for that stance
they have to comply with future lawful
demands if they can't find case law that
supports that interpretation maybe it's
because there is a secret court ruling
with that interpretation in Microsoft
can't say that it's just a theory
there's another reason to for this some
companies are complying with orders and
others aren't possibility and that's the
history of national security letters
which are these magical papers that
force all kinds of access without a
warrant and historically come with a gag
order even though courts ruled that they
only apply to specific types of metadata
for email including the to or from
fields some FBI agents kept sending them
out to new targets with a helpful
addendum listing the sorts sorts of data
that other recipients had deemed
responsive a Justice Department opinion
sidestepped the issue of whether the FBI
had to avoid looking at information that
was voluntarily supplied to it and
attorneys involved in such cases believe
that at least some smaller companies
just threw up their hands and turned
over everything including email content
and equivalent material isn't it
plausible that officials could also get
a secret court order that a company turn
over X even if there is no way to get X
without backdooring or hacking their own
products and then sit back and watch the
company squirm the New York Times
suggested that this was happening with
wats app a few months ago and that might
have only come out because Facebook the
Facebook unit is fighting it I do not
believe that every company
of every size would engage in such a
battle especially if they couldn't even
claim credit in public for standing up
for their customers speaking of the
public relations aspects of all this I
want to sound a brief cautionary note
about the hazards of reporting on such
matters as a journalist you're writing
about governments and companies with
significant resources and there can be
serious repercussions even if you're
privileged enough to work for a large
well-funded company with the stomach for
long-term investments of time and energy
and the possibility of drama with a
capital D you cannot be wrong or you're
part of the problem and even if you're
right other things can go haywire the LA
Times did not publish my 18 tepees 10
years ago so that didn't help anybody
and after my first RSA story I soon saw
the best example I had ever seen of what
investigative reporters call a
non-denial denial I'll put this up as a
slide but I'm also going to read it
recent press coverage that's the ah I
was going to put a funnel slide as a
slide but now I'll just have to read it
recent press coverage has asserted that
RSA into entered into a secret contract
with the NSA to incorporate a known
flawed random number generator into its
be safe encryption to libraries we
categorically deny this allegation that
sounds pretty definitive right I mean
I'm in big trouble huh where's the
original story yeah there it is quote we
have worked with the NSA both as a
vendor and an active member of the
security community we have never kept
this relationship a secret and in fact
have openly publicized it our explicit
goal has always been to strengthen
commercial and government security okay
it doesn't always say anything except
that they have contracts with the NSA
and that security is good quote key
points about our use of dual ec d b RG
drbg and be safe are as follows we made
the decision to use dual ec as the
default and be safe tool kits in 2004 in
the context of an industry-wide effort
to develop
newer stronger methods of encryption at
that time the NSA had a trusted role in
the community wide effort to strengthen
not weaken encryption okay so yes they
used to only see and this certainly
doesn't say it wasn't the NSA's idea
quote this algorithm is only one of
multiple choices available within be
safe tool kits and users have always
been free to choose whichever one best
suits their needs we continued using the
algorithm as an option within be safe
tool kits as a gained acceptance as the
NIST standard and because of its value
and phipps compliance when concerned
surfaced about the algorithm in 2007 we
continued to lie honest as the arbiter
of that discussion in other words series
contrato gophers said it stunk but we
stuck by it because the nist said it was
okay last quote witnessed issued new
guidance recommending no further use of
this algorithm in September 2013 we
adhere to that guidance communicated
that recommendation to customers and
discussed the change openly in the media
RSA as a security company never divulges
details of customer engagements but we
also categorically state that we've
never entered into any contract or
engaged in any project with the
intention of weakening our essays
products or introducing potential
backdoors into our products or anyone's
use so no intentional introduction of
weakness and we don't talk about
customers now this came out on a Sunday
evening before Christmas it sure looked
like a straight denial I had to read it
three times before I hadn't clinched the
first paragraph and last are the fiery
denials especially the first no secret
NSA contract to introduce a known flawed
number generator note though they don't
mention Reuters or me personally
certainly after my article came out a
lot of other media wrote about it
quickly and some got key facts wrong
including several who asserted that we
had written that RSA knowingly
backdoored its software so they could
just be denying those stories and
perhaps not minding if people
interpreted it as denying mine as well
let's look at the details they're not
denying the dual EC was bad they're not
denying that they had an NSA contract
they're not even denying that they adopt
a dual you see because of a 10 million
dollar secret contract if all those
things are actually true
how could they say they did not have a
secret NSA contract to include a known
flawed number generator I believe the
answer is in the word known that word
could be read two ways the most
straightforward way would indicate the
dual EC is now known to be flawed but
after reading it a third time I saw
there was another way to read the
sentence that RSA did not know that dual
EC was flawed then I'll read it one last
time recent press coverage has asserted
that RSA entered into a secret contract
with the NSA to incorporate a known
flawed random number generator into its
be safe encryption libraries again I
never wrote that are as a new was a
backdoor at the time given what I
learned about the cultural change at the
company I believed it was plausible that
those who proved the deal did not know
many geniuses and cynics were gone I
suggested as much in the original
article quoting one former employee
familiar with the deal is saying of the
government side quote they did not show
their true hand you might say that I am
torturing the meaning of the word known
I would prefer calling it enhanced
interrogation but imagine your company's
integrity or intelligence and certainly
its efficacy had been attacked by the
most distributed news service on the
planet and then that was stretched
further by many others you took 20 you
took 48 hours to respond and then if you
had the opportunity to simply and
truthfully tell the public that you had
not accepted a federal contract to use a
number generator most people see as an
NSA back door why in the name of all
that is holy would you not do that
despite the increased intricacies of all
this in the sunday night timing majority
of the media actually got it right a
number of other major outlets such as
the BBC falsely reported that RSA had
denied my story and they did not correct
that when when contacted so when people
complain to be about the media I listen
there's one broader point I want to make
here you folks and a lot of the public
now realize that the intelligence
agencies and their contractors spend a
lot of time looking for flaws and
software you should also understand that
they devote similar energy to looking
for holes in the law and in language
they see it as part of the same mission
what general Hayden in his most recent
book called playing to the edge the
strident non-denial denial was not the
end of the RSA story f-secure chief
Research Officer Miko hit Bonin and at
least eight other speakers at RSA
canceled their talks and several spoke
instead at a spontaneously created new
rival called trustee Khan in March 2014
that's not there either odia wasn't a
visual guy in March 2014 I reported
their team of academics from Johns
Hopkins the University of Wisconsin the
University of Illinois and elsewhere had
found that our side not only adopted do
we see but they had they'd used a second
even less widely known tool developed at
NSA's information assurance directory
called extended random that exacerbated
the RSA software's vulnerability it made
a version of be safe crackable tens of
thousands of times faster quote we could
have been more skeptical the NSA's
intentions RSA chief technologist Sam
curry told me we trusted them because
they were charged with the security for
the US government and US critical
infrastructure clairee declined to say
curry declined to say if the government
had paid our say to incorporate extended
random which brings me to another source
of optimism for those trying to root out
back doors government elements have more
money and probably more experts on their
on their side certainly when you include
their corporate allies but on the other
side you have whistleblowers and
government in the private sector you
have journalists and you have this big
third flank the academics and other
security researchers like yourselves
includes including some who work for
companies that have been compromised or
their rivals to companies that have been
compromised there's a fourth vector as
well the wild card of geopolitics some
security firms are seeing themselves
more lied with their home governments
and are therefore incentive to look for
problems in other countries the research
community some which feels betrayed by
NSA has done some amazing work grade
papers came out on dual EC and extended
random and they would do the same for
the last set of backdoors I want to talk
about at juniper networks last December
that company put out an extremely
unusual announcement just four
paragraphs before brief Q&A which was
prepackaged and the quacks was this
quote during a recent internal code
review juniper discovered unauthorized
code in screen OS that would allow a
knowledgeable attacker
to gain administrative access to net
screen devices and decrypt VPN once we
identified these vulnerabilities we
launched an investigation into the
matter work to develop an issue patches
for the latest versions of screen OS now
screen and wes is not junos but it
controls some VPN products and in
firewalls with so many vulnerabilities
identified patched every day there's
real risk that announcement like this
will get missed but fortunately more
more people know what to look for and
they will speak with each other and
speak up unauthorized code is an amazing
admission in case you ever see it again
is not just a flaw on a program this is
something that was not supposed to be
there it was not authorized to be there
people saw that they started digging
further asking questions and reverse
engineering the patches and it emerged
that there were two separate things
there was an SSH backdoor and there was
also a change in in a constant in some
other program and he show of hands who
knows what the change in the what the
what the constant was changed in any way
dual lip the curve further work showed
that the change has been made in 2012
which is before Snowden made dual EC
famous and that the original
implementation of dual of dual EC in net
screen was in 2008 now a bunch of other
changes as with as with RSA there a
bunch of other code changes at the same
time that made dual EC work as a better
back door and there's some obfuscation
for example there was a different random
number generated number generator that
was also used in tandem with it but
there's an exception that says that that
other non tainted random number
generator wouldn't always be invoked and
in fact that turned out to be in every
single case that the program ran so that
that one that random number generator
never came into play at all it's very
impressive to me what happened in less
than a month after the initial
announcement which is that which is that
juniper then pulled all of duel we see
instead of just putting it back the way
it was in 08 after the exposure that was
really encouraging to me
I asked um I asked general Hayden the
spring what he thought about no basis
which are nobody but us capabilities
that only the US can exploit and he said
he's lost a lot of faith in the ability
of no basis to stay nobis we don't know
a lot about what happened to Juniper
still but if they put in if the NSA
indirectly or directly put in dual EC
got to put in and then that was
converted by some outside party then
that is a pretty compelling argument
against Novus now what can we do what
can we do if you don't think novices are
a good idea what can be done about them
the simplest answer would be to change
US policy it's subject to regular
reviews and it was and verifiable that
could protect American companies and
actually help their end their users and
actually help those companies abroad
unless the other other countries follow
suit and also make similar verifiable
pledges not to backdoor anything if it
sounds crazy that the US would forswear
backdooring please consider that the
blue ramp ribbon panel appointed by the
White House and stones wake recommended
that the government do exactly that at
least at least four core encryption here
we are beginning on page 216 of the
president's review group on intelligence
and communications technologies we
recommend that we recommend that the US
government fully support and not
undermine efforts to create encryption
standards not in any way subvert
undermine weaken or make vulnerable
generally available commercial software
and increase the use of encryption the
end of the government should make it
clear that the NSA will not engineer
vulnerabilities into the encryption
algorithms the guard global commerce or
demand changes in any product by any
vendor for the purpose of undermining
the security or integrity of the product
or to ease NSA's clinic clandestine
collection of information by users of
the product the White House has adopted
many of the panel's recommendations but
not that one but that could be changed
even that probably wouldn't get us
everywhere because technically it
wouldn't be the NSA demanding changes it
would be a court and this says nothing
about lucrative contracts or patriotic
persuasion so even if the White House
flip flops we would need a commitment
from vendors like a triple your money
back sort of guarantee which could
conceivably happen if big buyers jump up
and down and demand it tools that would
help this process include third-party
code audits and more regular giris
processes processes for committing code
another thing that would help and this
works in the short term as well is good
old-fashioned embarrassment one of the
scarier slides to come out of the
Snowden files was this one and if you
have a clearance I believe this is when
you're supposed to avert your eyes or at
least do deep breathing exercises it
shows the requested annual budget three
years ago for computer network signals
intelligence enabling was 255 million
back doors are a big part of that along
with influencing cryptography standards
and there are other pieces to such as
collecting what's available from
cooperative carriers and analyzing for
entrusted systems for flaws but still
255 million dollars recall that the RSA
contract was for a mere 10 million the
vast majority of backdoors have not been
uncovered but the RSA and juniper
experiences also make clear that there
are real penalties for companies when
they do get found out so if you think
that fewer companies should make such
deals one good way to move toward that
goal is to help identify the other
participants in such programs as I said
before there's a shared interest among
researchers who are in Clyde in this
direction whistleblowers and journalists
like myself so if you belong to one of
the first two groups and are interested
in making contact with the third here's
my favorite slide how to get a hold of
me for the rest of you I'm looking
forward to your questions thanks very
much
yeah Mon really yes in the back oh thank
you that's very nice appreciate who's
who's running the who's running the
efforts in question if it's a if it's a
DoD sponsored supply chain thing which
is what I think is the longest tenure
maybe maybe um you know there well it's
been sort of deprecated it seems to be
the NSA has a really important defensive
mission and if general Hayden's opinion
that maybe the snow peas thing is less
countable on than it used to be I could
see them I can see them doing really
good stuff on there but that would be
for DoD stuff and their suppliers and
it's going to take a long time to fan
out elsewhere and I think there's
there's deliberate vulnerabilities
everywhere to say nothing of accidental
bones yeah me personally um well I my
first rule of op SEC is not to talk
about my op SEC but I take pretty
serious precautions I mean me against
the nation state is a really screwed-up
situation let alone multiple
nation-states mob members anonymous and
whoever else I pissed off but I don't
write the really key stuff down
electronically names of my sources I
don't write that down thank you
and by else before they drag me off here
no okay thanks very much