well here we are if you could please go
back to your seats we now have two
exceptional speakers I'm sure you know
at least one of them they've been asking
me to allocate 55 minutes and ensure
that that time is available so please
introduce yourselves thank you very much
thank you for being here
my name is Alfonso I guess some of you
know about me I have come here with
Miguel so these are contact details
twitter accounts and everything welcome
here today to tell you about a very huge
a type of research that was conducted
about this world there has become so
fashionable artificial intelligence its
application to security with all the
technologies that exist in that
environment we'll talk about security in
graph databases will tell you what they
are why they are useful and tell you how
security is and this type of
technologies will tell you about the
most famous databases and tell you about
the type of the types of attacks that
you may encounter we'll see a number of
demos that's what I'll talk some of them
are relatively complicated so we've
we've done some shooting videos using on
some others we cannot perform over the
internet for legal reasons so you'll see
a number of video clips
so we'll do our best to try and prevent
getting into prison today this is
contact details things we do well Miguel
is an telecommunication engineers with a
master's degree in cyber security
he loves city apps his gold prices and
awards all over the place and different
hackathons you've got the information so
that all what are we going to talk about
first of all we'll tell you about graph
databases we'll also talk a little bit
about machine learning but just a little
bit to let you know how to apply this to
defensive security and after that brief
introduction we'll focus on basically
the one graph database which is most
frequently used neo4j and if we have the
time we will also mention things about
Orient dB
we're not sure we'll make it because
it's come well sticking to the time
allocated will be a bit tricky
we'll see brute-force attacks we'll see
deos attacks how to create ransomware
anonymity hidden channels data leaks of
all sorts we'll go into more detailed
things later on and we'll have to think
how to deal with this because they're
quite sensitive and after that we will
release well it's been released already
an auditing tool called graphs scan or
ground will give you a link so that you
can download it and play around with it
so we'll start why graph databases I
wonder if you've come across this type
of research but in recent time it's
basically new in the last year we've
made quite an effort to try and
understand how these algorithms work
algorithms that focus on machine
learning for defensive security
there's we've seen a number of attacks
but we would like to talk about the
algorithms how they work and how they
can be cheated there are technologies to
mislead about images in many different
ways and there is a huge amount of
interest in lots of technologies all of
them are really cool technologies to
process huge volumes of information so
that you can extract intelligence from
it
information is power well that's a lie
because anyone with access to Google
what will be powerful and that is not
the case what is really powerful is some
intelligence and that's why larger
organizations large institutions and
companies and the intelligence agencies
use all sorts of technologies to try and
correlate data and establish
relationships that allow them to extract
useful intelligence intelligence that
does give power these were justified in
Tartu but anyway we are focusing on just
one thing just one very specific type of
technology which is graph databases why
graph databases well because these
databases allow you to store information
in a graph we'll see about it later we
will show what it means when we say a
graph and the good thing about these
technologies is that they allow us to
play around with relationships and that
gives us added information on lots of
things in cybersecurity you you can do
higher intelligence you can do for
detection many other things there's not
too many comparison charts on what the
best technologies are this is one of the
very few that you can find and in that
chart you can see that alpha 2
technologies the most important one is
neo4j and or in DB for that reason we
have focused on the main one and then
orient EB I think both of them account
for some 80% yes
80% between the two of them there's lots
of attacks to all sorts of analytics and
machine learning systems but we'll see
about that in a later talk
before Miguel comes in and jumps
straight into the databases before we
define what a graph database is we
wanted to show you a video so that you
can see what you can do with this type
of databases with something as common as
Wikipedia can you commute a video I
wonder if you know this project this is
a representation of Wikipedia in a graph
we were excited about showing this in a
huge screen Wow
it's a cinema screen or for us as you
see that power comes from the
relationship between entities news from
Wikipedia always give you references and
you see how the links are established
there are different sizes if you connect
to the internet this is very resource
consuming well this is a graph with
water notices and nodes here Wikipedia
is represented as if it were a galaxy
we would not have time later on but this
is beautiful
this is so cool
it goes on for another one and a half
minutes anyway will revert to the main
topic near 4j the unity technology
obviously then last you to store
information as graphs relationships and
entities neo4j gives you that
functionality it will be neo4j and in
orient DB this is open source there is a
large active community and it is
natively based on notes and
relationships and it's got other
characteristics like labels you can have
properties inside their relationships so
it's very powerful it's then very easy
to look for information it is heavily
implemented in large large number of
companies a lot of money has been
invested on it you cannot use the free
version for production environments but
for startups can use it freely there's
different open-source systems or
open-source projects where you can
upload your use case and see if you can
apply graph chart so grow a graph
approaches to anything you want what is
so powerful the the query language
cipher in order to match a node use
brackets relationships asked by a
brackets in a very simple way you can
search for information within the graph
visually and you learn very quickly this
is an open source project open cipher so
that anyone can use it
companies are not too willing to do this
that way because you'll end up bar
having to resort or neo4j but it's quite
an interesting approach anyway there's
different modes for the shortest route
you can use directly this way but the
interesting thing is the security and
the configuration I mean this is a
conference so that's why we're talking
about it it's been evolving different
releases
at first it was a pseudo sequel thing
but then they created it from scratch we
know some relationships stored in the
corresponding places but without
security you could connect freely you
could do whatever there was no
authentication in Def Con 21 there is a
proof-of-concept in github where they
open a shell it opens a shell well that
was fixed in 2016 with the latest
released at that time with
authentication based on basic HTTP if
you're in the same network you can see
the credentials they used they're more
user friendly browser by the way you see
how it has evolved to become something
that is much more pleasant
at first it was much more technical it
was like a user administration interface
but now it's much more focused on
business they've added the HTTP port
which is a good thing although you have
to install the certificates yourself and
they open a remote shell for cipher
toodle queries that has no
authentication but in the tests we have
conducted we have found none open
because that port is not enabled by
default so people are wise and they
don't bring it up in the new release
which was launched in London during
Connect new functionalities were at it
but they didn't do anything about
security it was just a basic thing and
it was not until the very end of that
year that they implemented user
management you can create more fun when
you surf from that version or because
you only had near 4j and that was it the
good thing is that the passwords you
need to change the first time you get
into the system will see what problems
we have we have found there is a version
there's something in in version 3 the
where they disable HTTP and then they
bring it up again I don't know why they
did speed up please
on other services were added that
release gets rid of one endpoint you
don't need to be authenticated to see
what version you're dealing with and the
the licensing quite interesting there's
there's no logs of queries which is a
problem but the most important thing
about this is that authentication is
enabled by default and it's not exposed
to the Internet when you install it and
start it it is localhost it cannot go to
other computers this is the typical
situation throughout the world have
something like 33,000 IPS that could be
near for Jay but mask on and Zed map are
not ready for this type of services so
they give you a response even if it
doesn't exist they give you a response
but it doesn't mean that they exist so
in total we believe that there would be
something like 1300 and you would say
what the heck if it's not enabled by
default if it's not exposed to the
Internet
how come well in some cases they diff
expose them to the Internet but they've
used passwords I'm connecting from home
no one knows my password nothing should
happen well as we saw the system is
neo4j by default if you haven't changed
it in both cases user and password if
you get in it means it's empty because
the there's two restrictions for the
password one that you don't use neo4j as
a password and the second requirement is
that it has at least one character
there's no limit to the string okay it
is a good idea to a certain extent
because we believe that it could be
exploited if I make a much longer
password it will take it you have you
can have a password for up to 20
thousand characters neo4j will not
respond what we have to see how to
exploit that we haven't been able to
exploit it because
tasks this is the configuration if I
want to expose it to Internet that's
what they do the authentication is
stored in the ass file 256 which is not
ideal but anyway if you delete the file
a new password is generated end of story
what happens if you try to apply brute
force I know that the user is neo4j
if it's neo4j I only need to use one
thing which is possible it but it's got
a system to block you and give you five
seconds delay so you can you don't keep
crushing the system with password
attempts it does it her IP so there's
different attacks you can waiter every
five seconds that's very slow or you can
use open proxy lists that allow you to
send requests changing your IP every
times
so no five-second delay in that case an
additional functionality of the
mechanism in place against brute force
I mean came per IP is very easy but
there is a flaw in the design in this
database it allows you to send the key
that you want to use to authenticate and
if you're right in the same request you
could use as the new key but does not
mean it means that you could send
requests and change the key without
getting response so I could try a clear
password if it works I will just go for
a default password whatever it is in
attack number three so if I don't need
to wait for a response if an attacker
had access to systems from which they do
they don't need that a response I don't
know they're hacking a device in an IOT
device to just send requests where we
can amplify the attack precisely because
of that incorrect validation IP third
validation changing the password is not
properly carried out the correct way to
do this is that you will sending it
yourself you didn't response them then
you send in your request for the new
password if you do
that way you are implementing that
response you could you could do it using
tor whatever these attacks have been
implemented in the tool we'll see it at
the end of the talk it is a way to
automate and go through the barriers
there will be barriers in the demo we're
about to see you'll see the code that
was published in github you take the
proxy list you configure it to launch at
request per proxy using different IP
every time so it accesses you see near
for Jania for join creates a new one the
attacker says ok I'm going to attack
using this dictionary it's a very silly
example but when we tested it in the
real world it worked
we don't we just didn't want to go from
one IP to another in this case we
studied we did a study with five proxies
why proxies is enough when they block
you for a certain IP they don't remember
what IP you were banned at so you don't
need to have a long list of proxies and
now we have the demo itself people never
cease to amaze us you may not be exposed
to the Internet and you may have
authentication and disabled but people
are also they give you security but then
you get rid of it you get rid of
security and you give full access to the
database with all the permissions
because there's only one user who is an
administrator here you don't even have a
user ok now Alfonso will tell you what
can be done to resolve this problem
at the end of the day this is typical
problem on floor design and security and
whether technology can be safe or not we
always have humans behind the scenes and
we don't manage risks too well at the
top you see the typical stuff when we
started testing the day security for
this type of database is well you look
around to see what people are doing when
we first did this CAPTCHA know there
were some 300 databases without
authentication someone has edited the
configuration file and said ok I'm
publishing it in the internet because I
wanted to be stolen from me that was the
idea the creation files as you see them
so this is some malpractice in
configuration a problem that has a big
impact on everything we do as we will
show in a few examples later on there is
a note here on all of these databases we
have the relationship with Olivia
releases community and enterprise as
millions said before the main difference
between the community and the enterprise
releases is that the enterprise release
implements from additional security
measures for example logs to log queries
amongst other things but the Enterprise
Edition is very very expensive here you
may have an idea why do people use the
community version because it's cheap
well it's free the community version has
been used by companies and that should
be doing should be using the Enterprise
version if new 4je wants to make money
well they should go to the internet and
find out who's using the community
version when they should be using the
other one if we pick on us I would
remind them that they really need to
look farther beyond a disclaimer at this
point most of the time on this
presentation has been reporting
cases how to minimize the impact of
everything happening happening in the
internet because there's lots of things
what we're about to show you now husband
reported some people have may have not
closed it because they just didn't feel
like it but we reported about this
months ago there's lots of data has been
an anonymized we just want you to get a
flavor of what goes on a list and in
this example we'll see all this but at
the other day we like this technology
and we would like to see it improve so
let us hope that no one gets too angry
and now very quickly we'll show you
examples some were about someone in a
faraway country found
I'll go fast
so we have two different versions we
give it colors we've got lots and lots
of information sighted information so if
you look at that in detail but can you
copy well you could copy sensitive
information when I say sensitive
information I'm talking about hundreds
of thousands of emails keys to access
remote servers telephones hundreds of
thousands research data research
databases
so in general data and of course there
are some minor Knight databases not
important databases but some data are
very sensitive and we'd like to give you
a more specific example and to show you
names ok don't get frightened everything
is under control ok examples what is the
problem with these database logically
someone could take your database analyze
your data and see what's in there but
when you detect that one of these
database is open an IP open IP then you
could go to port 80 where you will have
both database and websites and then you
could interact to don't think about
modifying data only we will see other
did attacks later on you can do many
things so a couple of interesting
examples suffering since this website
recommended you movie so database was
fully exposed and we could play around
with it so this is amazing so companies
who do that do analytics and they are
not protecting their own databases this
one I love it is a streaming platform to
learn the Bible so to root it ago when
we were talking about malware in android
I don't know whether you remember that I
shared a case of a Turkish person
exchanging recipes about marihuana in
Turkey or he also talked about : so this
is Rick
parents I don't know why well these
people seem to be cool and then you
connect it there and then you get to see
gospel of st. Paul's but ever so this
here there are security issues that
perhaps we I just want to discuss and
then in terms of databases for apps
shared by friends instead of playing
doing nonsense with your friends you
just download the full database and then
well it is easier to find the girls so
there are many cases are there many
sensitive ones and we had a couple of
them that were highly sensitive these
being one of them we refer to it as the
dealer car dealership case we are not
going to give you lots of details about
it but we'd like to give you some food
for thought
basically these case is about companies
público algorithms this is a database
that we found when we were profiling we
found it nine months ago when we during
research we scanned the Internet's to
see what was open primarily to report it
we wanted to report any sensitive cases
in Spain this case was found in much
lasya so when you connect through me r4j
it gives you some labels back and that
information could remind you of a car
dealer imagine what car dealers are like
we left the database for few months for
four months we didn't do anything with
fear and then in summertime we went back
to it because we were surprised we were
we were we had doubts and said well I
don't think we are so cool in Spain
and then we went back to the database
and what we found was a bit my heavy
stuff we reported it to cart there to
the civil cars I would like to thank s
Issa he fixed the problem fast and I'm
showing you this case just for you to
reflect shortly but all these aspects
are so trendy about analytics
transferring data to third party if you
do analytics the security of you
equipments are the same as any other
security because perhaps those
analytical equipment require some
security as well so these database was
did not have any authentication on
purpose and it was exposed on the
Internet
on purpose so there is a malpractice
here but it softly and also these
machines if there is someone with ill
intentions could be easily hacked we
rule it out a year ago because the
security of that machine was so bad that
it made me think that bad boss honey
pots so someone with in intentions after
dumping these databases on the internet
could have crashed that machine and gain
access to the net to the network so what
I mean is that if you are doing
Christine no important things with the
internet be careful of sensitive
information like here we don't have
authentication but it is not only about
consulting data so we prefer to do more
interesting things and the first thing
that comes to mind one has what has it
been disabled well some connectors are
likely to do that because it didn't
decided to have any other type of
authentication and they decided to that
it's better if you disable it however
but the good thing is that with the
actual cipher you cannot only make on
such information to edit it to tamper to
delete
but there are also other things that you
can do with it for instance cover
channel inserting information without
impacting the drive so dump someone
else's connects afterwards and rinse it
so we will show you injection attacks
examples in the end we created our
auditing tool and that's who we wanted
to be similar to SQL map that is to say
tools for databases with specific
languages these are examples perhaps one
of very familiarize with it some
sentences in this language allowing you
to dump databases so as me well said if
I have access to database the most
important thing for me is not only
stealing information because I can do
many things in database said survey say
may allow me to crash down the machine
or the network or run somewhere and I
could also amplify a denial of service
attacks if you are not careful with that
so what I say it is people use community
therefore it is very important that you
introduce security into community and
not very much not in enterprise which is
not that much used so when you think
about editing information you go and say
well someone with the role of analyst
I'm going to give it a role of fun min
and then you will be able to access the
system but however there were other
nicer cases for instance in terms of
products but you could change the price
of the product but you can lower the
price of the product in case of near the
400 that are open but however there are
nearly a thousand Terenure open and well
if you had a small dictionary you could
extract information from there imagine
the most classical model the database in
SQL you can change prices you can do
very many things
so with authentication you can access to
some elements of the browser and
interesting enough is that you may use
their API to consult their own API to
see their data whether you are
authenticated or not if you edit a
password they don't let you do it but if
you insert a u're URL you are generating
traffic and we don't understand why why
that happens and actually if your
intention is not only stealing
information but using the machine to
amplify attacks they have design flaws
but you can send out that request to the
database and doing it through that so in
this case I don't know but that you can
make loops where we can send a query but
that is not a mystery so the idea would
be to send every question so that the
and asking for to do that thousand times
Soviet is doing something that it often
doesn't but we can also ask you to send
out spam outside also denial of service
in neo4j waits as long as needed
to give you a response back so you can
make it you can ask it to create a large
number of nodes to introduce them in the
database to may overflow the RAM memory
sometimes the machine is crashed down
and the thing is that ok well do I
change to change the timeouts but if you
do that you may be denying yourself
because some requests are very lengthy
and if you disable to some out you
wouldn't have time to send your queries
so in this demo this may look a bit
strange but here
you will see us making a number of
requests I'm going to create as many in
Texas as possible in the database
indexes will allow us to consolidate
database however they are very large and
the drive gets easily full then it also
allows you to load information from the
outside so you may go and say charge
these CVS from the internet and import
it to the database I found one of
several gigabytes and then when you
launch the requests you just don't have
to wait so I've after the seconds if
they don't get and in response to stop
it because the server's continue to run
and then it starts to import and import
data and the good thing is that when you
create so very many notes that you crash
down the machine completely so here you
see it on the left it is very difficult
to show you because you are both victim
and attacker and if I did it on the
machine
the I could not make the recording and I
couldn't do actual didn't I have service
to reals equipment because I was not
interested in that
so everything will be uploaded to github
suffered you to have a feel the attack
see in the tool for my memory and for
the drive so if you can inject traffic
so actually it only request a couple of
queries to crash down the server so if
you can inject two requests we do denial
and then we crash down the server
because the database would end up taking
up all the memory or all the storage
capacity so let us talk about ransom
please do not get anxious about says
well how does it work we moonless our
words and in the last months is being
trendy to infect databases because this
is a cheap thing to do well you find it
with no keys you connect to dump
database you encrypted
therefore it is relatively easy to
infect many machines with drops by Mikah
use this slide yesterday this is a
typical current ransomware map and we
wanted to look at that in neo so imagine
that an attacker manages or succeeds in
injecting requests what could he do well
if someone can send requests I can
export the database I cipher it and then
I import it and then after that you pay
prabhava if your database is of 4060
giggles this is costly and sometimes you
feel lazy about that and then we decided
to create our own own ransom
so let me tell you that we will not be
releasing the code it is not in the tool
we will not be publishing it with just
play videos for you to see how it works
but this is just for you to take into
account new feature so database how an
attacker could use them and then I will
tell you how to how we could mitigate
that so we looked into the cipher
language and we started to look for nice
functions there is a nice function the
name of it is replace what you said okay
it's like this one and replace it by
this other thing and what are the
advantages here well the calculation is
made by the server and not by the
clients so because the server calculates
that this is cool because if I can use
it I could do I could make a ransom and
the database will cipher the information
therefore we sent out a query and then I
would left and I don't care with a
database is 50 or 100 gigas we are not
going to sell you in greater detail how
it works because we don't want to give
you lots of
hints so you need to have well tuned
cryptography then you come and self
replace these by that and then hid
scenes for you additionally there is
also we find what analysis systems have
that is to say relationships so this
tells us how nodes relate to each other
so instead of siphoning data what
happens if I remove links so this is a
very easy ransom I just delete the links
I just copied them important and that's
it so we are going to relate them so
this is a video of the ransom so in the
demo you see well we have our database
in neo so this is very nice bulls the
bolts move and then the secret machine
will launch the ransom through the
replace function etc so if this is a
community we will not be able to see
what happens unless we pay so all the
links are broken and information is
shown below encrypted so some things for
instance the dates are not encrypted but
we just did it on purpose so you see
that all the relations have been deleted
now we will send we will send that
reverse so suffering is fast you send
out two queries and it does it for you
recovering that C is costly because you
have to make introduce the relations but
the attacker would only do that if they
get the gram 'some so you download the
relations map because it is no receipt
to find out the relationship between the
nodes but if you just send a query to
get an information and then you read
these database and then you import each
of these
relations that is to say you create them
this is not difficult it was harder for
me to record the video so for you to
have a feel what we didn't test it in
real life but we believed that in
between 500 minutes will be enough to
cipher all the databases on the internet
that is to say between 400 and 500
database in some minutes so of course
you have to tune it because you sent out
two queries to an IP and the server does
it for you and then you channel that
through tor you name it and that's it
and of course you need to know how to
inject it either through breaking
authentication if there is no
authentication or if it's simply you
don't do it or also through connectors
but sometimes connectors do not allow
you to inject so this is what we wanted
to tell you all the basics that I wanted
to tell you about neo4j lots of work to
be done but after a year we have gotten
interesting results
so Orion DB is the large competitor of
neo4j well we just want to be friends
with them ok because they are very much
into legal claims etc so some companies
are using it already however some of the
things that in terms of security do not
really make sense this one has more down
has more than one CVE
and the version they're using is the one
that we have downloaded the thing is
that they upgrade every two weeks for
whatever reason they upgrade every two
weeks ok I just don't want to overdo it
here so how does it work do create the
Orion DB server and contrary to neo you
can create several instances in the
database how
the work is asking for password every
password the first time you run it you
may either enter your root password or
to just enter click enter and it creates
one for you what is the problem you may
access routes even if you haven't used
us user before so therefore if you try
it and you get the password it allows
you to access all the databases default
port is 2480 HTTP you have to set it up
from a scratch I tried it I couldn't do
it and there are also strange things it
creates a database by default known as
Grateful Dead concerts we are looking
into how to explode it from here every
time to create a database does not
generates a default user but 3 so in
just in case you have a being a breather
and writer and with you can try the
three of them to see whether if you have
to create to delete the database every
time to create it and what is worst is
the manual there are some things in the
manual that when you try to do them you
cannot do them because they do not
happen so the default users it's very
trivial but it creates like three users
per default and for every database that
you create you have these three users
three users for every database it gives
you three default users and there is a
strange thing that is not well
documented in the manual so so that
database is a good and three points to
carry out the injection attacks trying
to crush down the machine or to launch
attacks outside
contrary to neo4j well often the
security of neo is better than that of
DB but we prefer Orient's be preferred
orient in terms of licenses orange also
has community and enterprise license and
the difference is about performers
collation in terms of security they have
very similar sort of product is as
secure as insecure as near what is the
problem that we often have well what we
are telling you is about the version
that you may download from the internet
and the main problem is that there is a
huge difference between what I say in
writing and reality there is kind of
lack of coordination there we'll give
you an example you may get any orient
Erebus and to list all the databases
without authentication why is that we
Justin know the documentation said that
you need to authenticate yourself but if
you Jonathan tickets you can list all
databases if you have a user by default
you connect to it and if not as Miguel
told you fruit allows you to remote
connect Lee so that you can do brute
force attacks through that so therefore
they make it very easy for you to list
all the databases so that you select the
ones you can launch the attack to and
then they'll also that tells you about
the different versions so all these
without authenticating yourself just
reading and some typing breathing and
typing this is as much as you need to
know how to do so by default are going
to be exposed to the internet and that
is not recommended in this documentation
but do you do well do you go through the
countryside for walk there is nothing
you can do about it so perhaps this is
the main reason but we have found many
cases of many highly respectable
corporations because using it because
they read perhaps because they read is
the commutation and they believed it so
on the Internet where can we find these
changes but this is for you to have a
field
I run 214 or ENTV servers I don't know
what the difference with me
is an Orion TV server may have more than
one database may have n databases so
actually 240 but we have some 153
databases how do we know those figures
well despite you authenticating yourself
or not you can read lists all the
databases
salvations and less number of versions
this is chaos I don't know how they
managed to different versions there are
like some hundred versions so this is a
brief summary of what you find on the
Internet
someone from a remote country could
consult for instance out of those 433
databases
Mahara nadir have default credentials
out of these 400 databases this one
Grateful Dead concert so the name comes
from a rock group rubber band from the
80s but I haven't heard about it before
so 104 or Grateful Dead concerts so
actually the problem is that these
documents are really poor so if that
database is open you can make injection
attacks and there are other attacks that
we are not going to share with you
because we are validating it other sects
were allows you to escalate privileges
and to become the root of the server so
we cannot show them to you because we
are still seeing some failures no
protection against brute force logging
attack so that is a free-for-all you can
make as many attacks as you want so this
is about the Australian government
Miguel will tell you more about it
yesterday I was a bit concerned because
they are not they are ignoring us with
in reporting cases for many months now
and they
have not closed the systems yet so this
is a nice case because it says you about
the test environments and the production
environments so if you have doubts as to
whether to attack them or not they tell
you that all the environments are set up
in the same place and let us see what I
can do so the issue the thing about
creating your own cart systems for
equipment management mobile apps speaker
alarm systems through voice over the
Internet here we see like five thousand
personal details not one about
artificial intelligence
so using these graphs is very trendy we
do sit and this is the Bible thing
Korean Korean priest talking about Bible
again we see the same thing I was
following him on YouTube and then well
there is parallel database and summarize
or ent be summary so in half of the
cases the dorama is by default is not
deleted when I found cases were users
were deleted but the database was left
there you make you can make injections
the same as near but in northern TB
listing database to me that's a huge
mistake you can see whether it is
production or not you can tell it by the
name then in case of roots you can do
breadth-first through route and if you
have access to e through any as a user
you may then know the database only
after sending a query and then you put
it locally bring some other information
of the server this is a brute-force
attack the code is on top it's very
simple code and
then on the right we can see that if you
gain access to several information you
can see who has connected to the
database even if that is not your
database so you can see the clients who
are using the database command a command
say use time to spend so this is a tool
it's your own github so we hope that you
like it it is the first time that we do
it this is a Vita version we will be
adding other databases another at saks
this is for you to start having this
type of information for instance like if
in a blue team and the red team to want
to have a script to control security and
to see how do you come mitigate problems
related to this technology well this is
there for you at your disposal but the
good thing about it that we have it is
ready for you to creative reporting
Jason so it looks for neo4j and it finds
or NTB it gives you all the possible
information do we investigate some and
we don't get all this if you could go
back for a second
typical attack that gives you
information footprinting and similar
things on authentication you get
everything you got brute force attacks
you go do s attacks nothing but
ransomware but some do you have all the
others you can turn it it you can turn
all the requests that is integrated in
the tool so you can do your tests don't
be too wicked but you can perform lots
of tests conclusions we're doing quite
well in time the talk we gave in order
to prove that we like these technologies
we use them in internal projects and we
believe that they have a long future
ahead of them
but obviously you need to learn from
mistakes in the past and not make them
again be it in default configurations
brute force protection based on IP
address I mean that comes from 90s
password policies I mean this is 15
years old not sending queries to third
parties trying to work on mitigating
injection attacks of someone in a sensor
than a denial query how to manage time
it's complicated but it can be done we
didn't want to be too flash with the
things we're saying if we had used brute
force we might have achieve 80% but
about 600 database is exposed everywhere
public institutions private
organizations organization our layouts
some banking things it was a mixed bag
really with a little bit of everything
we wanted to give you a figure in
gigabytes but we decided not to do it
because when you connect you get the
information but the data doesn't imply
that you've got useful information it
could be 50 gigabytes but perhaps you
only have three gigabytes of useful our
details so this is just to give you an
idea of what we're talking about with
basic things like reading the manual and
I'm distrusting but people can may say
there should be enough we will mention
some basic things some countermeasures
but allow us to think about a comment
that was published recently by a sir
I guess that most of you know say sir
which has a lot to do with this world of
ours without profession we rely more and
more on technology but technology is
less and less safe because development
doesn't take place in accordance with
best practices quality testing is not
good
and when you do things in pentesting
well these are the things you come
across on a daily basis these are just
some basic recommendations obviously the
design flaws things that you cannot
avoid you can mitigate at most but do
your best and try at least
people don't authenticate yes you cannot
prevent a brute-force attack because
there are design flaws but you can put
technology around it or don't get rid of
the technology there of the security
technology comes right a fault with
neo4j the flaws that we mentioned by
listing the database well that's part of
the design there's nothing you can do
about it
they'll have to think so that was that
that was it from us contact details on
the screen if you want to ask anything
now whenever
well let me jump the queue again have
you thought about correlating all the
databases that you have found like
creating a meta that database that would
show graphs of the graphs that you have
found and see what common attributes may
be shared between the nodes to try and
derive well I'm missing my own review
know that I'm crazy about this I don't
know about Miguel but in my view we're
reaching the limit here what limit are
you talking about or what border well we
know each other I think that would be a
good thing but don't we mustn't be too
wicked okay I'm in this research this
investigation has been funny and amusing
enough people are more or less aware but
I don't know to give you an honest
answer it's trivial you you use the
range download the labels you're doing
one afternoon but correlating neo4j or
ODB with information behind that it's
cool if you correlate the information
with the service that's where you find
the real problem questions from the
floor I don't see any hands okay
down here please have you ever tried to
go through those websites where you may
suspect that they have our database to
do some sequel injection with this this
type of database well I don't know if we
made it clear when we talked about
injection attacks there are applications
where you can send cipher queries to to
the server but those specific cases
wouldn't allow you to launch the query
from the time the connection between the
client and the server was correctly
configured but then the database was
exposed so they would attack the
database directly more questions on
theses comment in my opinion what
happens after 30 years of awareness
training education events it's not
people are not still not aware we should
impose penalties and sanctions on people
that don't care less as those people
that are have installed and configured
their system in a really bad way I think
we should push for real penalties severe
penalties I'm talking about prison
prison sentences for exposing personal
details or penalties for up to millions
of euros things aa hit them on the head
with a stick I know but it's complicated
yes
I mean people could get hold of
information and kill someone because
they extracted information from a
database yes I know but a huge fine
William would imply the company would go
bust yeah I know about what happens with
them when a doctor makes a big mistake
what happens when the doctor is drunk
goes to the hospital and is drunk and
someone dies at the operating theater
what
purrs when a when a sysadmin leaves data
exposed should someone pay for that
should someone be sent to jail for that
let's leave it there questions okay well
thank you very much indeed