all awareness of those not yet born good
morning everybody thanks for coming
we're now going to listen to Kathina who
will tell us about the book
he's a daily experience at work and he's
going to tell us about his tricks as
well when they had to encounter some
challenges and he will probably be
talking a lot about poker if I will
continue with him please remember you
can vote the under his talks with a
Kovac system and you may follow if there
is another talks Nico seems to be
winning so far
thanks very much craftsmen everybody I
am going to talk about they develops
from the scratch to heaven or hell my
experience develops after all is just
the framework and technology defined by
a child and delivery value to the
customer and I want to tell you about my
experience I started without knowing
nothing with the mouse in the state of
the art in which I've stayed this has
been paradise or heaven let's let's see
these are my coordinates my name is I
think I have developed I have studied
the development of a computer
applications I'm studying the computer
engineering right now and I collaborate
with smart IRS technologies and you have
my data
I contacted that there as I have
explained this is just one idea and the
idea is as follows we'll have a master
node which is here and then we have a
number of nodes that connect to some
sort of green and environment and we
have it indicated with the radius
service with the database and they all
communicate using the zero M cube and
messaging system once I propose this I
said oh what a mess I've got myself into
will I be able to get anything out of
this
so finally I decided to take on this
challenge in order to cover it round one
we're going to install darker which is
one of the environments that's very much
used in the website now in Windows I
have Windows 7 unfortunately and the
poor thing it's elderly I call him my
legacy do we have tools to be able to
work with docker in Windows with Windows
7 we'll look at the web page we have the
docker toolbox that provides us what I
mean some tools to be able to use docker
and one of them is the Quick Start
terminal and when I go in he start
writing itself and I find this back
so I asked myself what's going on here
so I try with kinematic alpha which is
another tool that allows us to boot up
like a docker and I find I come to the
same message so I go into the VirtualBox
and I have this screen coming up so I
proposed something and I'm not going to
be able to achieve that but even not
even I'm not going to be able to handle
docker so I panic then you start to
Google then you start searching Stack
Overflow and then you see that docker
toolbox uses with 12 box to virtual
sizes to make a virtual liner to execute
docker with it but this virtual machine
must have the same architecture and the
host but my processor does not have the
technology to virtualize that and I
tried with my Ubuntu 1404 and I get the
same ever so what happens at this point
I started stop thinking and I thought
I'm not going to be able to achieve
anything but if I if I have a native
Ubuntu why will I not be able to execute
docker I tried it and I still talking
there so round two we'll try to do a
hello world with docker
and this is the environment we're going
to set up our Linux host and we're going
to connect with our talker machine so
our index is going to be very simple we
will connect to a port generate a server
that will send a request and we do a lot
immediately in the docker file I
installed the whole library the ABP
wherever it cars with whatever suitable
so we execute we generate the container
and once we're going to post it in bust
and we look into it and I get into the
conclusion we can modify the doctor file
and we have heritage we can inherit from
a machine that's already there and we do
not need to move in that the will and we
can add whatever we need so we did the
same thing I tell it that the I tell the
part of my document to connect with the
court of the local machine I can vote it
and from the local host 8888 I did the
message and I tried the same thing with
school and I got the same result so we
can connect to the document and now we
are going to add 0 mq and we can have
this scenario we're going to have a
server that will do a push and they
gotta member to a pool so in both we are
going to have a KS what will the server
be like we're going to buy new 9th out
9,000 port and it's going to send a
message every 2 seconds
hello and the number in our backup file
is also going to be inherited from node
6.9 and we install all the libraries
needed the run command we've introduced
all of the commands at once
and that's because a container is
created only by everyone and it's a
single layer with all of those
executable commands and what will be our
customer are like our client like it
will go to that network interface and it
will just write in the log the message
and the docker file is the same so we'll
try and execute the execute the server
here to your left and it sends the
messages and we see the client it stays
there so we're in panic again and what
why is that because when you generate a
docker container it believes it's alone
in the universe and it's waiting for
somebody within that container receiving
that message but because our client is
not connected to our server
it doesn't receive anything so what's
going to be our Superman right now
docker compose
with docker compost we tell him that
this client we're going to have to
environment variables y is going to be
where the client will read this or the
server has given and in the other one
it's the server where the message is
going to be written so the server over
here is going to be translated into an
IP and docker compost links that server
to an IP and now we executed them if you
can see it works
okay round four we're going to introduce
our babies so what's the architecture
going to be like we're going to have a
server we're going to have two clients
signed one we're going to have the same
message as before
hello with one number and in client and
to receive also the message and each
server has a very client to be able to
connect and in this scenario we're going
to do as follows this server will
introduce you to the ready service
information
our first customer when I offered giant
when I receive a message with a multiple
of three to the counter will go to ready
server and will recover the cool
information and time to if the message I
receive is multiple of seven it will
recover retrieve diva header information
so what will our server be like we have
two interfaces over here - socket we're
going to do push and two addresses where
we're going to be listening the address
hi and the address sweetie we're going
to use readies and we set up a client
and with elect to report and to the host
where the Redis is and if you see this
process M here here and here it's going
to be an environment variable that we're
going to introduce into the dockerfile
our server the good thing about red is
is that it's able to manage the data
structure and here I say that our key is
going to be Goku and power is going to
be 1 million and the same thing with the
header
and if you see down here we have both
the hola message in this video message
salvation through the high in the city
and its messages cetera to second our
dockerfile
is going to be just like before we will
only add the library that allows us to
manage this so what will our client one
be like we're going to connect to the
address the high addressed and in our
network client and if down here we have
multiple of three we will go and get the
Goku key and bring it people have no
ever work enjoyed and same thing waste
client too
but in this case we activated with hints
witty the address will be that of
Swilley and here we have the multiple of
sanam same thing
and what would our dr. Campos be like in
this case we have our server this is an
improvement we'll give a name to this
container we call it
and here when this applies both to the
high in the sweetie addresses and then
the port where we're listening and the
part will be ready and the image for
where this is a basic one that we have
in the docker hub in this port we have
two numbers because the port of my
daughter machine connects with the port
of the local machine that executed and
this depends on means that this server
depends on like this until that it is
not running it does not begin and with
this link we say there is a end link
with this component
okay customers but sorry client we have
this environment viable both for the
ready sport and for the container and
the address where we're going to do the
pool try and one - it on high and burn a
client - on sweetie
in our clients have been both on the
server to listen through 0m q and and it
also depends on valleys and you have how
it works as you can see when client one
you have a multiple of three for the
other message we go to revision we
retrieve the information we have about
Goku and here when client to receive
this really message with a seven
multiple we go to paddies and we take
the Meseta information in that case
and here I also want to show you how it
works look at the 21 is both multiple of
three and seven
and when client one is multiple of seven
we go and retrieve that information
listen here so they are asynchronous we
receive it in both and in with both
because of the recent recover the
appropriate key round five we're going
to add post agree to do all of this
environment so what we architecture
likes right now we have our server here
up there and it will connect with your
post grade which is also on a docker
machine we have a client one client to
Anna Klein three client one and two are
going to receive the same messages that
we've seen before and client three is
going to receive one more message which
is the one I've called and words also
with a number so it's one of these
clients based on the number of the
message will go to ready service to get
information and if it's not there it
will go to the database and look for
that information and sell it to that is
but I'd see what circumstances we can
find first of all the server goes to the
database and brings information from
three characters Goku Vegeta and peacock
client1 when it receives a message which
is a multiple of three just like before
it will go to Reggie's and retrieve
information about Coco but that
information can have expired and then it
will go to the database and recover that
information next you will go to Reggie's
and leave it there and it will have a
10-second TTL and if the whole cookie
has not expired it will trigger trying
to do the same thing but in this case
it's going to be multiple of five and we
try and three it's going to do the same
thing with people I want to show you the
server here because we have to add a
library that we have from j/s which uses
properties of JavaScript char connection
is going to be through some environment
variables and here we are desirey
you will publish the connection and here
we have some he/she helpers here we have
a map of the fields I have in the butter
in the database together with the name
of their table and with this mark I that
data
I insert all of these data at once you
don't have to go into a pie insert you
can do that straight away
this is the connection and this is the
query insert later in the columns so
that it knows exactly what to place them
and if we have no air flow we get that
information to the login if there is a
mistake
so what our client going to be like when
they try similar to what we had before
this part of the publicís is the same
in this part at the bottom is going to
be what changes when it comes to
directly to the database
here's the first checkup with you we go
into client 1 & 2 but client 3 is the
same inclined to as well
so we have the Goku key exists and if it
does exist no problem but if it doesn't
it here we retrieve that information and
we go to the database we retrieve that
information we put in the screen and
insert it in the Redis and here at the
end here's when we have the expired
Goku expired and here is where we
inserted and here's where we define it
lifetime and if it hasn't expired we
retrieve it directly
okay this is the dockerfile of Postgres
i used the image of phosphorus in the
docker hub and I've added and change and
with this one application you copy a
file that I've called in it DV dot eight
and I included in the docker entry point
and so once with one pot grey runs
starts running it is whether we have an
SH or an SQL file and it runs it against
the database and this is our e in it key
B and we are generating the model that
we're going to create when it comes to
in certain data in the database so we
have made up a user for the database the
database in the model a very simple
table but with these we can generate any
model the one for the database our
server has change with it and we no
longer have the Redis access and we've
added the beauty provide and there are
some details that I'd like you to note
and one of them is the wait for it over
there and the other one is the one with
mentioned will be that will make it not
no longer acceptable and the same thing
happens on the client work
gaaaah so what happens when I see that
everything's here Oh postcard wonder
Salvador intent of Excel and this brings
Heartland server when I want you up to
server solution era and everything else
you can scale it
and did it work so these sorts out the
beginning option you choose again song
also a Lakes and volume scrum doesn't
ensure though that whenever a server the
games another one
whenever the games will be in ready
state so which tools do we have for this
we'll have a wait for it according to
official documentation here I use the
wait for it mister isn't it what how
does it work
repel entire container America we give
you the route in the container service
and VAP and one this server Z we
services right is raised this command is
executed likewise for the customer side
there is an improvement here we have an
environment variable depending on the
services that have a dis local compose
and I also have an environment variable
file where we have the key and the value
and this is a result on yoga strike and
execute everything for Cosmo one two and
three we see that they're working for
the wait for it and here we see the rest
of the components on how they work so
whenever we have one message that is a
multiple of three look here
so the customers are kind of next
customer
wangala hello Goku is expiring rallies
here comes out on the database and
inserts it in XK Islam is the same one
we reject a customer here it is a
multiple of five
and since these executed every two
seconds from the multiple of 3 to the
106 only 6 seconds passed and we
recovered Algonquin bodies automatically
which because of the same thing happens
there is a multiple of sudden and
various and how that value recovered
from our database ok
while we have message number nine more
than ten messages passed since we
inserted it something happened before
because who else would recover things
inserted and here we have the Vanessa
case ok another these verticals
comparing some with AER Hallie mind so
need to work a lot on the container or a
grid concept we have a muscle now that
we have mentioned we need to keep
working on these muscle to are minimal
things so I like to develop much more
complex application to implement
everything the house being orchestrated
and I like to play with cuban apps focus
juan using docker in the cloud and may
be looking at the possibility of using
relish muscles life they trace maybe I
could use masters life database or our
security so if something may be improved
because another wall room for
improvement but if you have an 80s
please let now and this is it really
thank you very much
it won't ask for your mother
are there any questions I can barely see
everything here if there are any
questions please speak up
okay just a final comment on housing to
stock like all speakers and seem to went
through coastal papers as involved in
speech to be through here why because
he's I'm his Godfather under from the
film print esophageal or not is the
first time he comes to give a speech and
I thought it was important that he would
be here for his own means so please be
on time when we come back at 3:30 after
lunch thank you very much everyone