negative clues laboratory and he's going
to tell us about security in mobile
phones I thought of you who worked on
this no it's terrible and he said tell
us interesting to us okay thanks very
much good afternoon thanks very much for
being here I know that I on a Saturday
and I almost for it's a good time for
our nap but I think the talk is going to
be interesting enough so that you
postpone your nap your siesta till the
next talk
okay I've been introduced as a
mathematician but do not worry I will
not do like vowel I'm not going to bring
here any side room right now I work for
A+ Laboratories as safety in the area of
safety and I know many of you will know
a plus as certifying an entity the truth
is that we work on software and hardware
assessment and among the products we
assess are they trusted executed
environments fractured execution amounts
and I decided we decided to preserve
this talk because analyzing other talks
on the te issue we realized there wasn't
enough emphasis made on te what it
offers what advantages other to its use
in our idea is to answer those questions
and analyze as well vulnerabilities in
the TE East designs I think this will be
useful as an interaction to this world
but many things will be left to say
because we do not have as much time as I
would need to explain everything so I'd
like to start by explaining why he
appears probably many of you might know
what a secure element is but for
everybody else a secure element is a
highly productive chip bouncy step on
which we execute on OS and to which you
you legate cryptographic operations and
then they also be used for storing
important asset in the system
so what do we find these kind of chips
on credit cards DPM is ringing new ID
3.0 from the Spanish government and
these are basically hardware solutions
where production using hard work
regarding software where do we find one
of the most of standard and similar
signature element is the hypervisors and
the whole world of neutralization we can
find applications such as a host card
emulation or the OS such as Android
wrong time
in this battle between hardware and pure
software solutions we need to locate the
class of execution DTE it transcends a
solution environment te which combines
hardware software enlargen software we
need to think the device that uses a PE
will execute at least two operating
systems in parallel one of them is a
rich operative system and we need to
think of that concept as our unloads on
us or windows and then the Transit
Authority system we delegate told those
operations are are critical and we want
to protect so what do we need to
understand by critical operations key
generation later ciphering but also the
verification of a fingerprint and now
the software layer requires Hardware
elements to give you the property such
as isolation or secure start
these may be totally new for some of you
but in fact many of your devices that
you have here nowadays are using a TV
already in fact maybe have already
interacted somehow with a te e
application such as touch ID or Samsung
pay delegate part of their services to
the T but we mustn't think that it is
just exclusive for smartphones or
tablets everything we know such as IOT
devices are also using this technology
to protect a part of the system's assets
we shouldn't be surprised if the next
intelligent flip to Alomar smart fridge
we buy protects our shopping list using
a te
and now that we're be more aware that
this is something quite noticeable and
tangible I like to be like the surgeon
to explain what the inside of these kind
of products is like I'll begin talking
about the hard work regarding design we
need to think that fortunately there
isn't a single valid design
Poynter doesn't seem to be working
well it doesn't matter thermal effect
any of these three designs for example
if it allows us to have an isolated
execution environment from the rest and
interface route you can delegate the
operations we define as critical might
be perfectly valid
maybe some of you are thinking well with
the type a model looks like the secure
element concept in fact regarding design
looks like the secure element the new
this presentation will see that we
require some characteristics on the TV
that accentuate a secure element on a TV
but please bear in mind the type B
modelling because that design with a
truss on technology that will debate
next is based on the main feature of
this design is a device resources are
split between the exclusive use for the
TV and for the rest of the device
elements
so plants suck trust so you know what II
probably in about class zone is the main
hardware technology to you say te it is
a mining Hardwicke Knology because most
devices we use he use AR M processors
and this technology has been designed
for or by era there are other
technologies such as internal and they
implement being tell SGX
which is equivalent across the zone
which is to the large number of devices
that use this technology it's important
to know at least how it works first song
is based on the fact that the process of
course may be executed in two estates a
cure that is associated to the processes
executed in the trusted operating system
and the non secure estate those
associated to the processes executing
the writ operating systems such as
Android iOS and so on these estates of
the processors are represented in a bit
there is a soul in a register called
secure configuration register or or SCR
and when that B equals one
it refers to the unsecured state or non
secure state 1 the bit is 0 it refers to
the secure state any real research here
we'll see that refer to that bit as a
non secure fit
for whoever who may not know of this
give the is the execution mode chart for
a erm Francis or and in the last line
that's where the magic happens
so how does the processor get into these
level three of module mode that we saw
earlier standard way is instructions
call secure monitor call the kernel of
the operating system will execute that
the other way is through system
interruptions and while the processor
reaches his level three there is a
module called secure mantra does the
state change and that is within the
trust so firm were the part that might
be very interesting is that the source
code of these feed word of his firmware
is public and you may find is on github
without any problem however it's
important to bear in mind that whenever
the processor core reaches a secure
state it will have access to all the
resources of the device thus the
importance of having a robust design for
the tes
so far off talk about the processor you
may remember the design on which it was
sound technology is based allows to
spread the resources of the device
between those exclusivity and those for
the rest of the system Theresa will need
some controllers that are specific
hardware controllers allows the free
little transactions looking at the title
processor and this is useful in topics
related to configuring internal and
external memory regions are for the
exclusive use of the T and it's also
useful for peripherals you can mark the
referrals that are only for exclusive te
d access it prefers not everything is
either black or white
just imagine the case of your device's
screen we're not always using the screen
in critical activities sometimes we use
it to watch a video or to read something
in the newspaper but other times like
when we type a password we like the DTE
to manage this kind of peripherals
therefore we'll need our controllers
during execution time arrival of
changing the state of the corral
sometimes we have no other choice and
allowing for this type of flexibility
and here we have the internal letter C
diagram that uses this technology I
don't expect you to understand that
every single thing that appears here it
is important however to look at the part
that are marking red I refer to those
specific Hardware controllers are
appeared to be able to filter from
suctions according to the stages of the
processor I do understand that this
image of the samurai warrior may be
shocking but it's quite easy to
visualize here which are the part which
are the parts of a samurai warrior armor
no matter how is Maul apart maybe that
part is lacking the warrior will be in a
vantage in the fight with an opponent in
a bottle and something's Murrell happens
with this analogy if here's one single
component of the ones you mentioned no
matter how small it is we're actually
opening a whole system oh we're not
protecting it fully I can show you the
more than one of these devices I mention
at the beginning but are using te that
you're probably using do not have the
full on
you'll be able to have this table later
on with the slides and this is just a
summary of what we've seen so far in
these trance trust some technology and
it's important to highlight the middle
column refers to application processors
that we use in our phones and the last
column refers to micro post processors
there are usually more related to IOT
devices okay so to finish with the
hardware part let's talk a little bit
about this safe or secure storage
mechanism as we've seen our will needs
higher layer elements such as firm water
no matter how well he's on a robe honest
a pure hard part is if we don't have the
security and a trust and confidence on
the film work we're executing is one we
wanted the whole system will collapse
therefore it's necessary to use these
secure thought mechanism was all that
allowed well we need to begin with
trusted source that we call the root of
trust and thus you should be image found
in the ROM once assaulted
the rest of the system images will
initiate until we get to the users
operating system image in each stage
we'll need to verify the signature image
to check its authenticity paint
everything please not use some closest
mechanism for te solutions however it's
important to highlight that this is one
of the pillar were there security is
based
and as I was saying Adee has Hardware
elements as were as a software layer
regarding the software on the one hand
we'll be interested in the trusted
operating system and here we're
including everything from transit
applications cloud applications
executing these operating system as well
as in the vessel components we'll also
be interested in certain elements of the
current operating systems what I call
the client applications which are the
applications that will use the services
provided by the classic applications as
well as the rest of the elements in the
operating system that allows for the
communication between the client
application and the transit of parity
system so in my opinion which artist
friends
or benefits of these new social layers
where instead of having one operating
system we'll have to while we translate
the protein system will be a reduced
operating system we access in a very
controlled way but we can negate all
with critical operations
on the other hand regarding marking the
peripherals are secure in these trusted
operating system we can delegate drivers
management therefore we can talk about
faster peripherals and last val
isolation property isn't just happening
between the two approaching systems are
in fact internally within the trusted
operating system we want to execute
applications in an isolated way so that
no other traffic application may have
access to resources that are assigned to
the other processor application another
thing that this is more clear in this
chart where we may see what happens in
fact in a device exclusive security by
DT where we have the two operating
systems and is taking around the trusted
operating system is something that we
don't see he's being executing
background on the other hand
even though I've mentioned that these
are two isolated operating systems the
isolation is not complete on the one
hand
we'll need a communication channel
through which we can request things for
example I needed a password when your
channel to answer a question on the
other hand if you notice we'll need a
shared memory buffer because whenever we
request the password a transit
application will generate it
the public part in the case of area
symmetric password
might be the the object of desire of the
transit application oh we need to keep
in mind is that the aim of this new
model is that our current systems such
as Android Windows Linux iOS our
operating systems for leisure while
these are the ones called fossil up
rating systems other ones are currently
out the hard work and I think that will
better understand this idea with an
example so here we have a possible
payment nap model within a te this is a
simplified model but I think you will
understand and visualize quite well
which operations will should be the
gating the transfer operating system and
which components need to be controlled
in these transit operating system so
let's think let's say that we're going
to pay something we begin the
transaction and Penman the regime is
required since we consider this a big
operation related to a transit
application let's say that the
fingerprint sensor is trusted so the
driver is money by the transit operating
system we fingerprint from the user and
once we have it in the database you need
to check the that fingerprint really
belongs to a use of the has permission
to make a purchase if everything is ok
we need will need appropriate token and
will generate a cryptogram that will
sell back to the user operating system
so they can continuous on fashion out of
the device
after you as you may see here is not a
full payment application model but we
can visualize quite well which elements
will have and which operations will need
to be delegated to these new models with
two operating systems
and to finish with this software part I
like to mention that fortunately
there are possibility to work with free
operating systems in this case opt e
with a public coding github the may be
useful to develop the software layer of
a key he and I mentioned this project
because I think that he has a very
active community which is something
quite important from we refer to open
source projects and since he doesn't use
the pen on soft floor but disciple
solutions also need some has some
hardware
there are several platforms of support
being able to execute the supporting
system ok so could there be a security
conference where we learn talk about
vulnerabilities of course now believe
you're not different vulnerabilities and
problems having percent in the last few
years like equipped eee products more
vulnerabilities found I would like it to
arose in code in the cloud who does fled
to integers in intelligence of flow and
three parameters errors and there have
always been problems in the tea design
personally the second type of
vulnerability of problems is that one
are most interested in it is arguable
but to some extent are narrowing the
code may be solved
however a narrow design may lead us to
fully discounted product and next I'll
show some of the design problems and
seem more interesting
and some of these problems come from the
daily work
our piece of research on DT of welcome
highlighted at the Grahams the ouvea
gems are the optional extending their
own services on us ee
some of the primitives at the Aria could
extend where things such as writing
memory reading and memory copy with the
Associated problem that through wow
these new primitives one of these memory
regions
I was exclusive for the use of key could
be vulnerable
my question is the following
how come that the transit operating
system developer ensures certain
properties when in fact they lose
control on the system could be necessary
to extend certain services of a te well
that should always be done in a
controlled way and mainly we should
never allow the modification or
complicity of critical services such as
the case authority in the regards memory
so what would happen if we have a tea
with its trusted operating system and
also peripheral such as the fingerprint
sensor that it may not be managed by DT
well here a malware has access to around
grade or our iOS will be able to
compromise some extent that peripheral
if we use that kind of device it is
clear that all the peripherals may be
clear there may be critical must be
managed directly by the trusted
operating system however this is not
enough the communication bars existing
between the fingerprint sensor and the
te e is not protected with this measure
and we could have an attacker that
connects directly to the boss and
obtains all the information and here
other countermeasures may be necessary
for example here we have up as example
but a sign for the communication between
the fingerprint sensor and the TE
last year a piece of research was
presented on the cars memory management
in process of the use transit zone
through these piece of research it was
discovered that these processors are not
using the flash function in the cache
and even though is not possible to have
direct access to the cache memory set
ours for the TE usage that were able to
recover the AES code in the cache memory
through timing talks these are complex
attacks these highlights eternal problem
existing between performance cost and
activity because eventually not having
or not going out that flash operation
it's only done dream proof at times in
the changes of state in the processor it
is funny though I didn't remember I
talked about another hardware solution
which is Intel SGX and the solution also
presents a similar problem because it's
vulnerable designing attacks in the
cache
I don't know which of you know how
side-channel falling hmm accounts work
because you know these are hard with our
techniques used mainly or to a large
extent to assess the security of our
credit cards for example so how does the
side channel a cock work let's say we
have a chip that may carry out siphon
cryptographic operations we have a
message that we want to cipher through
that chip the first thing you will do
the chip is to load deciphering thief
appropriate one we transfer all
messaging is everything else okay we'll
get a ciphered text
okay so if we assess if we're able to
assess the temperature the electrical
consumption
the electromagnetic frequency of advice
while these cryptographic operation is
being carried out who could actually
obtain the code or the key with which
old message has been ciphered so what
happens in the case of falling action as
do not remember something we have a text
of a watch cipher we have a chip that
carries out those operations and we may
obtain this type of tax at the end well
if we apply
mechanisms and disturb
the function on the chip
for example through laser glitches and
similar things and us as a result after
the serving which said we might be able
to obtain cypher key or any other thing
that we want to achieve and obtain so we
just thought about testing these kind of
italics on a plate or a border using
strands own technology and enriched at
the operating system level for us it
will have V ot although it is true that
this type of boards are general-purpose
bores that do not implement physical
measures in terms of hardware at hard
work ethic and this type of attack on
the 100 control measures at the software
level that can make it difficult or even
impossible and attack of the nature I've
mentioned but also at the technical
level and for us compared to a secure
element this type of processors have
features they are for instance
multi-core multi purpose processors that
also make the analysis of this type of
attack
harder so we decided to try and see what
happened
would would be missing here some
anticipation device with music or drums
or whatever but what happened was that
we managed to bridge the implementation
of air as a with a fault injection and
tied channel attack in a platformer that
I've mentioned it is true that as I was
saying it doesn't make it make much
sense to adopt hardware protection
mechanism bad list software protection
mechanisms that at least make this type
of attack harder because we don't know
who our adversaries are and in it
becoming cheaper and cheaper to do side
channel attacks at this point I'd like
to thank my colleague in luleå
Gabrielle but I'm here talking about it
because she is the one who's put it in
practice and I think she deserves the
recognition
and finally before te e there were
different protections to protect system
assets one of them are replayed
protected memory clock and these are
partitions that exist in our flash
memory since 2011 and where the writing
and reading operations have to be done
in an authentic ativ way so what happens
you will want to store a critical asset
in those partitions well we either
cipher that information beforehand or
these do not protect confidentiality and
why do I say this that may seem obvious
because even duty is being used although
it has been used by the T because it's
not an exclusive measure we do not know
if there's another application who also
has the key to do authentication
operations on those partitions and to
finish with this part I decided to list
some of the recommendations
that could be used by somebody who
wanted to design a tea and perhaps with
all the information that I'm giving
today perhaps next year in the route
that one of you will be here presenting
your development of a tea and then you
may keep them in mind in case I have to
assess your designs I don't have to
scold you for for not listening properly
to me in the rupee so after this talk
which is perhaps a bit dent in terms of
material in content you may be wondering
about this technology is really
worthwhile in my view it is technology
that halfway between secure elements and
exclusive use of current operating
systems that we've seen on their own do
not offer and offer enough protection
it's true that compared to a secure
element they do not have so many
protections at the harvard level they do
offer some functionality such as
protection or adding a security level on
top of peripherals which it's impossible
with a secure element to another hunt at
the level of costs most of these devices
processors that use AR em they will
allow us at least at the harvard level
to implement a te so i won't won't have
to spend a lot of money and finally
maybe is surprising to some of you but
due to the to its architecture
particularities t it's being used for
purposes such as samples environment
from malware analysis
if you do searches in Internet you will
see some papers and some documentation
about this but of course that's not the
perfect solution if I have to say also
that I don't believe that perfect
solution exists as to the problems that
I think are more important to emphasize
in these technologies nowadays there is
a huge shortcoming in terms of
standardization but easily in
application development you will not be
able to go tomorrow and say I want to do
a trusted application as of today that's
not possible because it's too close that
environment and then in terms of
security as I'm sure you will have
realized in order to have a te you need
a lot of parts and just like we've said
we've said with hardware we will need
all components because otherwise your
Armour is incomplete we need to have the
operating system we have to be able to
trust that it will not be delivered to a
third party already tampered with
perhaps with the access API to the
operating system and I think that's also
one of the problems we do not know
whether the key you using in your mobile
right now how has it been set up and
finally regarding civilizations there's
also a difficulty of hardware
integration I'd mentioned at the
beginning that the if it were code is
open you can access to it and there are
projects of trusted and operating
systems that opens as well but even if
you have all of that nowadays is going
to be very difficult to integrate all
that in a real platform integration with
hardware is very difficult however magic
on your software development
I believe it is a solution that's here
to stay
I don't think it's a passing trend I
think we will see it in more and more
devices it will have all I think it
solves some problems that were present
in our current devices what I like
better about this type of technology is
the peripherals management in fact that
they can be isolated from the fact that
Android or lives may be managing putting
critical peripherals but the great
weakness is that in time it should
continue to be a closed environment in
which the sector won't allow any of that
any of us can choose to participate ok I
hope you enjoyed this talk and above all
I hope had been able to teach you
something about what attracts trusted
execution environment and you have
questions now or later on I'm unwilling
to answer
anybody's brain enough I do have a
question have you estimated the overhead
that trusted a introduces in operations
with crash zone an estimate of the
overhead that trust zone and adds or any
te we haven't done so but we could do it
if you're interested I do not know okay
think okay thanks