[Music]
tell me
Roman empezamos
Ola seola orondia Nam on pasar con el
segundo de la primera la primera charla
de de ser Davos at na mo amar a oh man
hablar sobre dev ops ii ii ii no
socialism at Davos II - do you know ma
RK no que no cuenta Oduya after a
antithyroid I said Allah Allah not
possibly a SATA we summon our keepers
peace in the midst a third lap a time
sort of power or do we need a valid
legate the weighty decision Public
Allies number and every Nicola loses a
when Allah presented in a manner of
sipping tea we empathize London for
Villa Alison Duke is Christmas sermon
cultivate a master feed a laugh induce a
coma solamente muchas horas del Plata
mastico de la la otra - WETA esata
condos tipo de de caso de y della della
ragione hurry hurry
yes ok so ok so local fauna fun to sell
on ya de un poco de vino de vino Blanco
Ajo pimienta say Kalinda para que se fun
day si como con la palabra suta esta
super bueno un par de perder bed in that
potentia sin embargo a seat and either
cholesterol so noise noise Gortat open a
Khmer nose no cereal I said cemente it
was nice syndicate Apollo para comer
nantes hacer ejercicio via a communal
Ofra for a football a novel escape una
una pieza media y es un patent vernal no
intent a comer lock en la cocina
okay am i I am a monolayer and I spent
over 10 years in the world of the
information security I had gone through
several Chinese companies in Group A
Cappella courtroom I'm also in caja de
Henares a security officer and from last
year I collaborated with the walking and
security masters and since 2014 I took
the car my family and we went to suit
Allah and I'm working for the company
could ask a security this company is
part of the cholesky group
it's the Swiss company based in
Switzerland and started halfway through
the last century at the beginning they
did quality sound recorders that
newspapers are very journalists use a
lot also in Hollywood to record the
audio tracks of films and in the company
has a couple of phosphorus so in the
technical department and in time they in
the 90s they moved towards a friend
pay TV signal because the recording was
not and so much in demand and in fact
the koudelka key group might not bring
about but an aggravation might be more
familiar to you at the end of the 90s or
or in to the beginning of 2000 you may
have had to look for the an aggravation
and to see certain things on internet
without pain and I this is what I've
been told of course I never did such a
thing and some five years ago the
company decided to start working in East
fear which is information security
and they created google ski security and
they amongst the services they offer are
the managed security services and for
that they set up two socks and the first
one is in Switzerland in a small village
from 5,000 inhabitants and it's good
quality of life and they have not only
from do but it's also a quiet place
perhaps on in winter and early Monday
morning they are 1015 degrees below zero
you're in hurry to get to the car as
soon as possible to hit the car up and
what you easily can find is that they
caught a car that was black in the
evening is white this is not the best
way to begin the week having to go for
the shovel and but the company takes
care of the workers and when they decide
when they were wondering about where to
set up a second talk they said let's
look for a place that it's nice for
countries that do not like cold so much
and they thought that an exciting
thought it was a good place it's not
cold that is true they were hesitating
between the Amelia desert and Phoenix
and finally because of market reasons
they chose Phoenix and and it is true
that it's not a troll' cold and if you
think a Madrid is hot in the summer try
this and why am I talking about socks if
we are indeed about the track
the Department of managed security needs
a number of applications for instance we
have a portal to interact with customers
where they can follow their security
incident and look at the state of the
devices for managed security they can
download reports etc we also need a
tools for analysts to be able to do
their job so they can do the triage of
alert in a more efficient way we need
the tools to automate all report and all
of that was done by a small department
with the for developers in fact for
external consultants a couple of years
ago the backend front end and then
Christie who did a bit of everything
he'd done analysis he could help in
front-end and back-end they were
developing at the time the first version
of this customer portal and they were
using a waterfall approach they done
rickwaa site collection with the
business they had done the business
analysis through weeks a month the
couple of months negotiated the contract
and they started to ready to code and do
the prototype and a profit they took a
few months I think six nine months to
develop the portal and when it was
almost ready for delivery and go to
production we realized that that portal
that was based on the requirement
collection done a month before was no
longer good
there was no longer appropriate and why
because the world changes very fast but
the information technology world changes
even faster and security computer
security changes even faster the a year
ago the this company had a single sock
in Switzerland less than 12 customers
all from Switzerland in a year later we
have two socks we have over a hundred
customers and most of them are in the
United States so these requirements that
were defined in the year and a half ago
or two years ago are no good anymore so
because apart and has changed radically
another problem that we encounter
another situation is that we have a
traditional model we had the developer
on one side and operations the people
who had to take that software in in
maintaining in production and we have a
wall of confusion in between the two
department in our case in fact this was
a physical wall because we had an office
where we for developers and I was with
them and behind the wall we have the
other people the information technology
and if you wanted to talk to them you
have to go along the corridor and go
into their office and if one of the
first things we did was to break that
wall and have an open stage where
developers and operations work together
this world of confusion be it physical
or or or a virtual wall what it entails
is that communication is complex between
the two sides and why is that No
well complication is the communication
is complex because you look at things in
a different way when you're in
development or in operations and you
look at things in a different way
because you have different goals the
goal of development is they get paid to
develop new things and and who push
change but people in operation and
prioritize a stability and changes for
them sort of disrupt normal operations
and in that the main reason for tensions
to come up between both Department I've
seen this often in big corporations in
banks where these teams need to report
to different people and that way you
find a lot of tension between the
different teams
something has happened is that due to
this lack of communication in this
difference in mindset when you want to
bring the production and you release it
becomes harder and traditionally you
need days or even weeks sometimes to
prepare release and even if you've
tested it thoroughly what you're going
to bring to production and the
developers can swear that it has been
tested and there'll be no problem but on
the weekend because this is usually it
happens over the weekend when in in at
5:00 a.m. but it often happens that what
had been tested thoroughly in couldn't
fail - fail and in that means and you
have a big problem and that means that
the morale of the team is not very high
people in developing are not so
motivated and people in operations are
also tends when they have to bring the
production and you release it for the
business the perception is as the
technical teams and the development
teams are not efficient I I've been told
that a presentation cannot be successful
without the picture of a cut so this is
mine so the organization realized that
it had a problem and that's the first
step to solve any problem to realize
that the problem is there and they
decided to look for a solution and they
considered moving through to to trial
methodologies I have to say that a
Chinese and DevOps is not the same thing
that's clear
but they are like the the good kabooms
and in the in the good weather is better
wine they are not the same thing but
they got together incredibly well so as
I was working in contrasting they
proposed to me to become part of the new
team they were going to set up and at
the beginning I hesitated because first
of all because I've never been very a
child I struggled with cartwheels when I
was a kid so I wasn't that clear about
this I had no experience in development
for me development in fact was what
these people do to introduce
vulnerabilities in applications
developers look like nice people and
they gave us work and that's good but
and no experience in that area and I
decided to accept because it was a
challenge an opportunity to learn new
things and also to to be able to come to
it for free and then make a presentation
so I'm happy with my decision because I
haven't said that but I come from
Catalonia so getting anything for free
it's great I'm not going to explain what
a child is because Paul did that already
in his presentation and I'm sure you all
are clear on this but I just want to
mention that my role as product owner
what I do is the the cloud part to
maintain the backlog to prioritize in to
tell the team what one needs to be done
and when the Sprint is over to make sure
that what's being developed delivered as
part of that sprint is what the business
is expecting pin
their child manifest I'm sure you are
familiar with as well I just want to
make two comment everything is important
but the first line to me is the most
important one individuals and
interactions over processes and tools at
least in arcades it's been key to really
launch the whole agile process and for
it to really work and I'm sure you also
know that but I want to remind you that
the agile manifesto is not read it just
the one through the left is what needs
to be done in the right hand run does
not need to be done that's not the case
here in the left hand side is very
important it's more important but you
cannot forget about the right hands and
when we decided to go for this change
the reaction on the side both of
development and of the business were
similar and the reaction at the
beginning was like this they were
skeptical for different reasons
development thought now they call this
agile but it's going to be more of the
same and it is that the business is
going to have an excuse to to change
priorities every two weeks so it's going
to be hard for us and for business
they're also worried they were worried
thinking that perhaps agile and DevOps
we're just going to make development
have an excuse so that the rather than
work they'll start and playing with
docker and in fun technologies
it's not an easy change it's a cultural
change shifting towards a divorce model
it takes time it's not that you have to
do it little by little it's better to do
it at once and really a jump into doing
develops and agile sort of full-on but
the time you need to get to see results
and see an improvement is not short here
it's not that you start with a child
tomorrow and in a couple of Sprint's
you're working at high speed in fact you
need an investment and from the company
sorry to really produce results it's
also true that it's a cultural change
it's not just something that affects a
development department it'll change that
affect affect globally the whole company
the whole company or at least all
deportment departments that are going to
interact with the development and
operations if you just change
development but there but the rest of
the organization departments are not
willing to play with the new rule along
the new rules it's not going to be
successful it's also important if you do
not have experience on these issues and
people having any experience on the
divorce or the agile world before and
it's good to have a help from outside we
had a consultant company and for me it
was very positive because I had no
experience prior experience but also to
raise awareness in the other department
that had to interact with development so
that they could understand what the new
rules where it was they could expect and
what they could
another important element was the
integration of those consultants those
who wanted to were offered a job in the
company two of them accepted to be
higher than the others continued as
consultants and then we increased the
the size of that department but we say
in-house people and that's important it
helps in terms of teamwork and
motivation if people are in-house and
not just consultants who are here today
but maybe come tomorrow communication is
crucial and it's crucial in terms of the
transparency that the development team
the develop team provides the rest of
their organization to explain what's
being done why it's being done which are
the blocking points and why a certain
technical architecture has been chosen
transparency is crucial for that and
it's also very important for the
business to be able to to communicate
and to make the development teams seen
what's the vision for the product and
where you're heading for what you want
to do and it's also very important when
that when you convey the referee light
for a new functionality that you should
focus on why rather than the fact that
it has to be done is a silly example and
it's at imagine that the business want
an application that it's a red button in
the middle of the screen and that's what
they demand from the development team
and
these teams as I we already have code
for a for a yellow bottom in the middle
of the screen and why should we write a
new and rather than using the one we
have but if they if business tells us
I need this application or this screen
with a red bottom because I need to
check if my users say a half dozen ism
so that will encourage and motivate me
that the team to to do so and or to have
the red one and they may actually have
this have offered the option of perhaps
having a also a green one or they may
contribute suggestions related to the
motivation and the reason for wanting to
have that red button in the middle of
the screen so talking further about a
trial one of the things that love the
misunderstandings that are sometimes
there is that a child doesn't mean
planning that's not true because that's
what I get paid for it into maintaining
the backlog is a way of planning and to
the fine priorities but it is true that
traditionally you did plan him at the
beginning of the project quite a
detailed planning with all the
brainstorms etc whereas here what you do
is you focus a lot on what's going to
come in the next few weeks and what
farther away you just leave sort of
define the outline what do you think
would be needed but you don't devote
that much time because I've made change
afterwards
this is one of the issues that has
generated more tension between business
and development because business at the
end of the day is quite used to its
project plant and it's a gun
diagrams and to having the information
that the project will be over on the
15th of June in or the 30th of June at 7
p.m. and then the project finishes at in
the Christmas but if they have the
project and they feel safer and that's
an important part of the cultural change
but I have to accept that this is no
longer possible and they have to accept
it because otherwise perverse things can
happen like like that the estimates are
taken as deadlines and that means that
that the working that it complicates the
working of devotionals if the business
is not willing to play and each of that
line if you think about it it it's it's
really petrichor if I were a development
they told me I had a deadline I would be
worried I in the PMP certificate doing
that and because I I have want to get a
certificate for doing this talk I'm
going to give you a bit of theory any
project nothing at a scope has a
frigging in some time to be carried out
and requires some resources and in my
experience the scope is too big and the
time and every sources are too small I
haven't ever found the project or
participated in a project where this is
not the case and this cold tends to to
be predefined you want to do a house or
a bridge or whatever and
and you calculate and you have your
resources and then you make an estimate
of when you'll have it 15th of June and
then it will not happen until Christmas
at the time is flexible and if you do
not want to be flexible because you want
to meet the deadlines then you have to
increase resources if we move to the new
agile model here time is fixed every two
weeks every sprint you're going to
deliver a new version of the product but
in this case what means to be flexible
at time is fixed and then the scope
needs to be flexible so you estimate
what you're going to do in one sprint
and you try to do it sometimes you do
more sometimes you do less and sometimes
you do exactly what you have estimated
with that paradigm piece different in
this way one of the issues we wanted to
launch from our I personally would have
liked to lunch was not to do CLE reviews
but but peer programming to have two
developers working with a single
computer we have not got there the team
has tried it but it's not something that
we do all the time because it's complex
for the business to accept that we're
going to be more productive if we have
the two employees working on the same
computer but what the team decided to do
what this try was peer reviews once you
something's over you ask a colleague to
come they discussed the code and they
decide why it's been done one way and
not another and this has several
advantages
you can find a way to improve it because
your colleague tells you or because when
you are explaining it to somebody else
you realize that there is a way in which
you can improve it and it also helps to
disseminate the knowledge of the code
and throughout the team because you're
given support 24 by 7 if you are you get
a phone call early hey on a Saturday
morning it's good for you to know not
only your code but what your colleagues
have done testing is always a complex
issue and I am have it
a colleague that says that testing is
the dark side of development so this
picture felt to me to be perfect in the
traditional approach it's something that
you always leave for the end and when
there's more pressure and more rush so
you find that if you want to meet the
deadline then you always videos testing
you know quality is going down but but
you take that risk because you want to
to meet the deadline so what we did for
testing was and this was decided by the
test by the team itself its developers
the ones who are programming the
functional tests they use protractor for
the front-end power to automate
everything to do with testing and have
it within the continued delivery part I
also want to mention quickly some of the
scrum rituals and how we have
implemented them they were not invented
by rituals were not invented by scrum
they've existed always with humankind
but scrum has adopted them it's about
repeating things predicting about social
interaction taking place in a safe
environment because things are usually
dying a certain way the same time and is
it employees in same movements and these
makes us feel safer and those
interactions become easier the
best-known scrum ritual illy daily the
daily meeting the last for 15 minutes
hours are more boring than the
soundtracks meeting you don't find any
aliens around but if he does something
in the future let you know and we've got
this Lobby here because it's one of the
points for the evolution can be mostly
seen in the team always hearted one year
and a half ago daily miss Graham was a
daily meeting it always lasted more than
15 minutes swiss people found the art to
discuss certain things and the were
endless meetings and people just talked
a lot about what they did the day before
to prove that they had done a lot with
the colleagues and with the bones some
things have changed a lot now we do talk
about what was some day before or we
think I'm doing today but the main focus
is in what we need from the rest of the
colleagues Omar I mean need to review
this because I'll finish I need someone
to help me with Unicode or how is
problem I learn now how to solve it
could anyone please give me a hand and
we'll go together
another very important ritual is
planning sprint planning and grooming
the backlog and here we use planning
poker I was a bit accepted skeptical at
the beginning should we use cards at
work but I was pleasantly surprised
because it's very effective since people
like discussing things and gives you
have to estimate something but reaching
consensus if you take hours and if I do
my job well and things are well defined
and the team understands it well the
estimation would be very homogeneous and
will be very quick and easy to reach
consensus regarding how complex is not
solely
here's the demo now's the time to show
off ensure with our colleagues form we
have done without a spring it's also
important to get feedback ASAP by your
business and then here's the most
important ritual the Sprint
retrospective
involves reviewing what we've done the
last two weeks seeing words being good
what's been bad what could be improved
so far this is most effective continuous
improvement implementation point at the
end the team decides on one or two
initiatives one is usually not regarding
things that we need to do to try to
improve we test them for a couple of
weeks and then we see whether we turn
something acquittal chant change the
chair a coffee machine daily scrum time
till we use anything the team things
might improve one of the results of
these initiatives was the following we
started using scrum in two weeks
spring in at some point the team decides
to follow a combo team
subbed in spring we do continuous
development flow and whenever the team
will be available they will get the same
story the same item to have the most
priority at the time a few months
circumstances changed
and a couple of months ago the team
decided to go back to scrum and
established a two-week sprints which is
okay so eventually the thing here is
this is very useful to have continuous
improvement and it also allows your team
to self-organize the negotiations
internally as much is about doing
sprints or compounding these classes and
reaches a consensus the very important
thing here is checking what works for
the team and one of the node works you
need to choose a tool the fed's well
within that process if you choose a tool
well for example the beginning we were
thinking of using year in kids there's
your one so the consultants gave us a
good idea they said well wait a little
bit begin with user blackboard or
whiteboard with handwritten pulsates why
what works what doesn't this would be
the columns in a different way and see
what works for him after some time
you may design which tools you're going
to use and then you can use the one that
really works for your team I'm sorry
about the proton the function this is
quite basic because that's a key
position because the way which they need
to protect the team is very important
they need to avoid interferences and
having intelligent people asking for for
things for the team we need to try the
priorities and that person Pio shows you
a business which is an example situation
where things are being done in a certain
way so this is an important position
even though at the beginning it may not
look like it
you're not programming code that's what
developers are there for so initially
thought that I would be there and I
wouldn't be doing much but after a unit
half of seeing that is a very important
position not there's a lot of work
involved so now I'm much we're going to
change and go back to management
security services and we're going to
have a new protocol now I have quickly
talk about DevOps
because in our how this works Afghan
okay we're trying to link these two
world development and operations and the
aims of it deliveries has continuous
impossible so that the effect works well
so we can not might be as much as
possible developments do not need to
send a package to operations every three
months if we do things in a continuous
way we know that it's going to work okay
the realization that we start our makeup
by developing teams split the product or
to the service recipients then we have a
cross sectional infrastructure team even
series to all these development teams we
have development and infrastructure
profiles which are within a scrum team
and eventually participating the rituals
I participated on the daily tasks and
chlorophyll developers your teams are
out of the scrub to horizontal to
measure more networking councils there's
a guy in the middle there because there
are a few profiles because are not hard
on their knowledge it find where is able
to program Java code and deal with
infrastructure content and this helps
cohesion for the team
technologically speaking the business
was volatile beginning these rows a good
excuse to use very good tools and we
really enjoy using them Misaki with heed
for research and development docker for
production from the applications how in
docking containers and chess and puppet
to ultimatum standardized infrastructure
that we can Monteiro and that's all -
for monitoring another concept that we
focused on a lot of infrastructure team
has worked on quite a bit in Lancia is
to implement a key infrastructure as the
code which is used to get processes and
tools that have been traditionally used
for software development and apply them
on infrastructure level and thing to
have
a version control in the infrastructure
to be able to automate tasks
infrastructure wise and to be able to do
a robot one of the things do not work
properly there are some things be
improved some challenges that we need to
solve these are the most important ones
for us right now we are certified in ISO
27001 that doesn't always link well with
the agile concept and we developed
program documentation you tell the ice
water that we are regard yarder and we
want to have the code functioning
instead of investing in documentation it
will be difficult to persuade the
auditor so we need to work a bit to find
the mill round will allow us to keep
that certification and visitors used to
getting some indicators and here we need
to improve because transparency and the
way in which communicating in which we
communicate the size of things isn't
always the best I think he may be
improved
Parul action yesterday we used to do pen
testing
before each release because we do the
release every three months so if every
week you're gonna do something new we
can undo pentacene so we need to improve
the way in which we put the security in
continuous delivery and we also need to
improve how we manage technicals that
this is unavoidable we need to live with
it you need to find the middle ground
and assume that is okay because we need
to move fast but they shouldn't be a
burden for long-term long-term
development and there are challenges
were also opportunities eventually
results in agile are all about transmeta
so let's also automate security si was
mentioned earlier it's important to
avail of the proteins you have that
automation and dust pump how security
controls are
that may range from automating
evolvability scans or long-term access
for infrastructure whenever there are
different software changes going to
automate is not difficult because tools
are expensive and they tend to generate
many false positives but also we should
try to automate as much as possible with
researching or vulnerabilities there's
nothing else here right now it's very
quick to develop a punch to the plotter
punch one series henkaa vulnerability
you do not need to wait for weeks
remember the Taliban to employ a
punching all the systems and all the
technology passed to between six and
nine months fortunately this is not the
case anymore if you want to deploy a
punch
now infrastructure it just takes minutes
and just to finish a like to reinforce
we take what messages the one hand are
something that this is a cultural change
if you use change the government team
they decide to use Sajal maybe things
will improve maybe that much to be more
motivated on get a faster development
but here you're not going to use the
full potential but the Dobson ahjimmae
provide because the Russell departments
need to want to play these agile them
three hubs you see we need to automate
develop some nodular all about
automating so let's try to automate
everything including security because it
is really the only way of doing things
is like for having Fault in the code in
agile and evolve models things need to
be automated if we need to have security
it also needs to be automatically memory
prospectives
for me this is the most useful apply for
each one is a very powerful way between
continuous improvement so we'll need him
to be afraid we need to test experiment
see what works if it works we keep it
and if you got some work which is is
guarded I can prevent something else
and that's it for me I won't do it fast
there was the answer was it pressed
according to the tongue constrain so I
would like to thank you again for
wanting me to use the speech here I hope
it was interesting happening we have
plenty of time for questions if you have
any car guna preguntan any questions and
even more over here when we tie wrap it
thank you very much I like to ask
whether you're developing oil for all
sorts of solutions whether you keep
following abrasion methodology for other
changing changes we do not have so much
business uncertainty as a real question
well we're actually working Angela for
everything how's being invaluable
globally Oh initially working with a
service like a service for to
development for management security
services available in the engineering
teams Vulcan software has roughly
migrated to these agile and the bumps
model however I've you need to do short
term specific projects sometimes made it
might make more sense to use that
original approach for a one-month
project if you do it with an agile team
that is already available and how the
boundaries and availability to develop
that project you can do to that job
however if you need to set up a new team
you might make more sense to use a
waterfall approach is that if project
uses model instead of setting up agile
because you need a certain history to
see the benefits and one month might not
be enough any other questions
hi congratulations for your speech
imagine the one other challenges was to
integrate security and these whole
process I want you to know whether
you're really approaching some sort of
initiative in this regard
well we become reusing the process we
already have for automating the
functional test so that within that
process we can have use cases for
security and soft testing security for
example usage games we are a plasma
cannot see the data we post from another
customer and by the way this is quite
easy to automate from a functional test
point of view even though this case is
all about cyber security right now
implementing initiatives you go beyond
and we're doing vulnerability scans
continuously they are not really
integrated within the part so we do not
detect those vulnerabilities until they
are in production but if we're able to
put that in the pipe we can detect it
before it goes abruption
and then block it instead of
implementing that change that will
introduce on vulnerabilities but this is
one of those codes
where we need a bit more experience and
I think that in general in the market
those are lack of solutions by little
manufacturers provide tools and there is
a growing market but there aren't that
many solutions that you can easily
integrate in around here there was some
question hi a couple of questions first
you started describing the times you
have before you to maintain the new
modes these are about six months and are
you now managing metrics regarding how
you manage reuse those times with some
specific examples kept remember oh yes
the production of any really is two
years ago remember that we need about a
week so two or three days to three
people to prepare the release and there
are a couple of days and several people
doing the functional tests manually
before going to Karachi and here now we
need less than one hour to have a new
release ready for this ready to go into
production this will be one of the
examples of time reduction my second
question is focus on the teeth there was
a slide where you mentioned how
different strong team is ready to other
people and are more interested on
infrastructure
how exactly were changing how the pneumo
impact on the lives of people who are
managing the infrastructure well in my
opinion
this is much easier for them and
sometimes the business itself easiest
ask you to do something but that doesn't
happen that often it is your it is
developed with the developers who ask
for things what I wanted machine I want
to change some rules whatever if woody
used to be a very rigid process where
you need to open up a ticket and wait
for quite a few days or two weeks but
now you need to wait you have them there
you can talk to them and say okay how
urgent is it can it wait until tomorrow
can they be done today I think that
there is less visibility there is more
visibility when you understand why
things are happening is much easier for
them to explain why things cannot may
not be done today and why they need to
work to wait until tomorrow before
however they used to be much more
confusion we have time for one more
question and this is the last question
we have time for well thank you very
much for your question I do have a
couple of questions who needs to
automate the security tests the security
people developers do I need to learn
Jenkins
that's my first question
and I'm a second question is very
interesting to apply to other the plugs
at least in our case they're quite
tricky we charge each other third party
cicada parties such as Microsoft IBM and
so on we have experience with that we're
doing in doing third party part
regression tests so exploring other
things I have a really bad memory sort
of hopefully remember both questions in
fact I can't remember first one now okay
it's not not politically we solve that
with the ratio of 1 to 245 our company
works in security that many people who
know a lot about security during the
class will develop ants we don't have
security specialists and we can not have
someone the ideas dealing with security
exclusively to program these tasks
eventually is a challenge and this
something we month we need to improve
but I think that we really need to how
the possibility within the scrum team to
be like security champions to have that
security vision not full-time because
not that would be science fiction
morale they should be able to advise the
development team and look at the
security tests take into account the
risk count that application so they can
decide whether they need to implement
and that implementation your contains
delivery needs to be done by the
developers or by the infrastructure part
and these are people who are really
going to pile up the technical side and
then regarding second question okay
third party parties eventually there is
no big difference regarding how to
employ a third party part or your own
software part if you have the
infrastructure as a code and you've
automated the tests when you do an
infrastructure change it's quite simple
you apply the patch in your integration
environment and you make sure your
application keeps working other systems
keep working there is no big difference
between the third-party patches and
you're wrong applications patches that's
one of the objectives eventually or
getting the ropes together so that you
can have same process for infrastructure
and development
well just to finish a big round of
applause for Omar and we would like to
thank you for your presence thank you