it gets it in the
yep
of course I'm just
Valley por nada como Townsend encinia
okay since this is a cinema let me show
you that picture on world is name I'm
Peppa Villa I'll tell you about a
project where I've been doing some
research with my PhD thesis director I'm
a PhD student at India software which is
messages here in Portola plus my Twitter
account on my URL where there is a draft
of this paper in them with a little more
detail so I'll do my best to speed up
because I'll tell you about many things
so before I start cron was a black focus
on the answer recently it renders things
with HTML so here I good this is a good
list of things where you could start
now several tenders like their lists
where you can actually ask questions you
can talk to developers if you're
interested in a specific functionality
you can find things pointers and
references of our code in their lists
that can be quite useful design
documents these are Google Docs used by
developers
for the current project with diagrams
potential designs of new functionalities
most will be out of date all since
they're implementing 24 by 7 is terrible
why did you think when they implement
something it will probably be very
different from what you've read about in
the design document but to give you an
idea it should be handy
bug track well the same story you can
search for specific functionalities or
bugs in functionalities and there are
always references to the code no way to
move around and finally if you don't
want to install them if they install
anything locally this URL gives you all
the source code for chrome with
references of different sorts so it is
quite handy to browse
I'm going to be touching on many
different things very quickly if you
really want to go into detail come over
and let me know so a brief introduction
event-driven programming event loops and
the timing side channels channel on
event loops they state what we will see
a very simple idea in chrome EDP is a
programming paradigm for gear is
basically for web lines in fact the
standard itself for HTML 5 says that you
should use some EDP and we're talking
about software and hardware networks so
far however which is getting non
synchronous packages so this is a way to
program these devices also for the
server side it's working quite well on
the server side Java Python this all
sorts of frameworks where you can use
event loops the main benefit is that
throughput is quite reasonable with very
little sumption the flow of the program
is actually determined by the events or
the messages that we get in a
conventional program we will have a main
than a function is and that would define
the flow the execution flow with an
event-driven program we define what
events we're interested in and what we
do when we get them so whenever we get
an event from outside it could be
hardware interruptions or net wave
messages that would trigger the function
we're interested in okay so it is widely
used the idea about events looks very
simple here we have a FIFO queue now
this fashion and then we have a very
simple loop we're talking about messages
or events they get to the ticket here
and the first one in is processed the
important thing here is that processing
when printing a message if you make a
blocking call like for example accessing
the hard drive data of the network it
handles it in a non synchronous way it
processes the event it delegates the
task to a worker the worker that can be
another computer another process another
thread and that way it keeps processing
the other events coming in or whatever
comes from the other clients that is
what makes throughput quite reasonable
so with that very simple idea we have a
concurrency model which is very simple
for the developer because they may they
may get away from other tasks but what
happens when this event loop is shared
between different parties between
mutually distrusting programs in this
case we have an attack and attack us
sending messages or tasks to this event
loop and is measuring the time that each
one takes to be processed so we measure
the time between two consecutive events
and we see what delay we have if we see
a bigger delay we may infer that a
victim Wolvie has sent the message or
that it is processing a message not from
us from someone else so keep that idea
in your mind because this is what we
will be using in Chrome to do some cool
things well the Pope is the name of a
project anyway why Chrome well I chose
chrome because it is a white the most
widely used browser a lot of people say
that it is the safest some argue that it
might be Microsoft edge but it is the
first multi-process browser anyway other
browsers are catching up I have to say
informs
I'll give you a rundown of the
architectural firm so you have an idea
about the attacks the same origin policy
I assume everyone knows about just in
case let me explain it this is the
security policy implemented by browsers
since the dawn of time in origin with
the scheme's a domain unopposed and it
prevents the scrip to this executed in
origin a accessing origin to origin B
and the main problem with this so this
is a very restrictive policy so
developers wanted to do more complex
things in the internet so they wanted
additional functionalities
specifications api's the ecosystem gets
bigger and bigger and that means a much
larger surface for attacks in turn
leading to failure mistakes errors we
have overlaps between different
technologies and we have new
vulnerabilities as you can imagine this
is what you justified moving to a
multi-process architecture the main
benefit with chrome is that unlike the
other browsers at last time which had a
monolithic architecture which is one
huge process they said okay let's start
from scratch and do it the right way
first time around what are the main
benefits of a multi-process architecture
like that in chrome well they have a
main process the hosts process or the
browser process and then they have
smaller processes renderer processes
ideally each origin or each one of web
applications is executed in an isolated
way in a different process we are
isolating each website that security
because these processes are sandboxed
renderers would not have access to
system api's only the host process would
have access when the render process
wants to access the network to see what
the user is doing or to see the follow
system it has to communicate with the
house process when people say sandbox in
chrome they usually mean this and then
we have better fault tolerance if we
have a one single processor for whatever
reason one tank crashes one time crashes
that's it everything crashes when we
have a problem with chrome and a tab has
a problem we don't lose the other tabs
in Chrome each and every process has a
lot of threads here I have included only
the main ones which are the ones we
should be interested in in the case of
the browser princess we have the main
thread which is the point of entry for
all users actions user actions are how
rivet and entry into the browser goes
through this process and then the
input-output threat of the house process
which is the one in charge of
communication between processes and also
of handling access to the network the
filesystem and so on in the case of
renderers the main thread Raceway the
most important thing happens javascript
assess executors here rendering pages
style the input-output thread of
rendering system one that is used to
communicate with the house process so
all messages to request a privileged
action will go through the input of the
thread the other one will go through
certain compositor thread each one of
these threads implements an event loop
of them like the ones we saw before so
communication between threads and
processes is there for message delivery
between event loops
to make you see for yourselves I'm sure
you know this in chrome if you go to
preferences we have a really beautiful
task manager where we can see all
processes we see that the host process
can you see it from the back
anyway each tab occupies a different
processing space plugins are running
isolated processes there's a special
process to handle access to the GPU
but this is what would happen in an
ideal world we can isolate completely
all origins all applications from the
web at the end of the day of running
code you cannot trust because JavaScript
it may be interpreted in the sandbox but
it is executed in your CPU after all so
in an ideal world we would isolate them
in individual processes the processes
take up memory in order to strike a
reasonable balance between security and
memory usage which is one of the main
problems with Google with Google Chrome
you apply different policies to map
these into different businesses the main
policy is processed beside instance
which defines a site as the registered
domain which is the TLD plus the domain
your user you have registered under
protocol so any sub domain even with
different origins will have the same
site a site in France is the sites that
are connected and connected means that
our scripts that is execute being
executed in a certain obligation as a
reference pointing at another window ok
however there are some exceptions to
this and for example when we have an
iframe when we have an iframe on a page
we don't care about the origin from EBL
comm we can load a Volcom both will
share the same process why is this a
case well since we need to have a
reference implementing these iframe
asunder different classes would imply an
overhead and complexity to manage the
communication between processes and an
overhead on
communication so I friends are the
exception then we have link Thailand
navigation when you click on a link in a
certain page under target for that link
opens a new tab instead of refreshing it
within the tab you were in this new one
has a reference to the opener tab in
that case that's happened regardless of
the origins will keep sharing that
process and the last exception is when
we go beyond the maximum number of
processes for Chrome this is defined the
maximum number is define based on the
RAM memory that is available in the
system and that is usually 30 devices
for 4k 4 gigabytes of RAM and up to 70
when we have 8 gigabytes or more as soon
as we have that when we open a new tab
an existing process will be reused in
the case of the house process there is
only one house process for tabs even the
ones that are opened in without animals
browsing all of them will go through the
input up of thread for the host process
which is unique by the way for the side
isolation project which is a project
launched by the guys over a chromium
they started working on this and I'm
sure we see results throughout this year
they're basically trying to solve all of
these problems with exceptions to
reinforce this isolation between sites
even the granularity in terms of
isolation of processes will never be the
same as the one at the logical levels of
the origin because origin and site are
different concepts the different
granularities if you like so quickly
what we will do now
is to spy on those event loops they do
resource passing star calculation layout
painting JavaScript execution and the
most important thing here for this event
loop is that every time we execute a
JavaScript function is that function
actually is being executed it blocks out
the entirety event loop when you go for
while equals one this is a task that
cause v8 it starts executing it and the
event loop is blocked so you see this
the tab frozen because nothing is
happening there's no sign acylation no
layout node when brain nothing so
depending on the length of the
JavaScript are using it will get logged
for shorter or a longer period of time
name problem here when when two vendors
are sharing the same process the main
thread is also shared of the same event
loop is shared the in products are
thread for the hospital set is another
event loop will be spying on and I'll
give you a couple of examples to explain
how it works on the one hand we said
that this is the entry point for user
actions so in the main thread for the
house process we get a click from the
user and that click from the user will
go into the input upper thread of the
house process which which will do
multiplexing and send it to the renderer
which is in the for in the foreground
only to the tab that is active now the
rest don't need to know about this
because this is irrelevant information
for them and then we have the opposite
example which is a renderer executing a
request what it does I can't see
anything without my glasses but thank
you Roman
if I don't see it it is not illegal from
the main thread we want to do a network
request ok so we go to the input up a
thread for the red thread this renderer
will send a request to the input/output
thread from the host process and this in
turn since he wants to do something with
that blocks everything else will
delegate the task into a worker which is
a pool of sockets or threads that the
process has to do network requests as
soon as it is done it will say that it
has completed everything in the event
loop in the productive thread for the
health process and will send the signal
to the renderer telling it that it has
completed the task that means that there
will be a message in the main thread for
the render process which will trigger
the call back to that request I'll focus
on those ones for the idea that these
events are widely used the QE for the
GPU process is another event loop
workers shared and service workers work
through a leave a loop API sand
extensions well the same thing and to
show you that this is all through I
think I have enough time I'll show you
something I'll show you a tool which is
in chrome body fault you probably know
about it
I'll zoom in this is the profiler
so I have a very simple page I've just
defined a listener for whenever I
someone does click then alert this show
the alert blocks the execution of
JavaScript a big signal in the event
loop which is what we want to watch so
we click here there's many options so
that we can do tracing in different ways
we click we move the mouse enough right
this is it
this is what is same rated by the trace
here we have all the processes in the
browser this is a host process and here
we have all the threads and the house
process we have a male thread we have
the input up the threads and the ranch
here we have the renderer which is
basically the page that we have executed
their here and we have different threads
the main thread included to show you the
visit room but first if it feels weird
but it moves this way so it's quite
funny yeah
we see a set of locks these are
executions this is a frame graph or we
seal the internal calls produced by the
event if you click on them you will see
a link to the code where that function
can be found and you see that in the
main thread we are getting the signal
this is Malik's placements this is sent
to the input upper thread and then put
up a thread sunset through the renderer
you see this here this is what the mass
displacement cursor does without any
JavaScript we have functions that are
executed on blocks our event loop for
approximately half of a millisecond -
Giulia cursor displacements because the
the periodicity is 8 milliseconds and
here we see that I click got it got in
it gets to the input up as fresh for the
redress and then the callback is
executed the alert we have executed we
see the flame graph here we see the
event handler for JavaScript we're
invoking v8 which is the JavaScript
engine for Chrome we execute a function
the function
- 1.5 seconds this is to give you an
idea this is a simplification of
everything but this is what is actually
happening in the transept an alert on
the function blocking the event loop
you
sorry now is a spoiler
I was a bit of a theory then I'd move on
to certain practical scenarios where it
would be interesting to do things or
where people predefined close event
loops I think the most likely scenario
would be malicious adverse events many
occasions residents are loaded into
iframes because the SOP protects us from
malicious advertisements it will not be
able to steal the content on the page
but because this is an iframe and we're
sharing data to the code that is
executed by this advertisement can
monitor whatever is happening as we will
see this can disclose information about
what the user is doing another thing a
complex channel as well key numbers I
will not go into the details at amount
of time the main question is how can we
post our tasks from a website using
javascript tasks into the loops in the
render is main thread that's why we
execute JavaScript in JavaScript when
you execute a function you see that a
task is created a block sees answers
what it is being processed when the
function calls another function that
happens in a synchronized way not it no
new task is created it is added to the
course panicked if we call as our
functions or there is a loop we will
have a single task which gets huge and
whether it is we don't want that we want
to have a large number of separate tasks
so that those we want to spy on get in
between so it's non synchronous calls
that's a solution not what most
developers use is timeout the idea is to
have an operation that is taking a long
time lucky the event loop for more than
16 milliseconds
well you split up into small portions
you do work timeout
I'm in between you can re render the
page and the user doesn't have any
feeding that this is getting frozen the
program with timeout is that even fresh
Ellucian even if you use 0.1
milliseconds you've got problems
so resolutions are not enough and then
with non active taps signmark goes all
the way up to one second so no way the
solution is to use the API from
postmessage which allows us to post
messages in our eventual recursively
I'll show you the code hosting a large
number of tasks to measure time now the
new when it is closed there are many
more with ecbs mmm have other options
with a put up a thread we have two
techniques one we force a network
request which will go to be put out put
thread when it goes back Michaels back
we measure the time these fine lines of
JavaScript are all that is needed to
monitor the event loop it is incredibly
simple we define a loop function self is
a reference to our window so we send any
message with not interested in the
content we save the timestamp performer
now there's an API that gives you an
accuracy of microseconds in the
timestamp and then will you find the
event handler for all messages and send
the first message once we do that what
we have is a very short function which
stores a timestamp which is executed in
a non synchronous way many times these
are tasks in the event loop what we will
have at the end is a vector of
timestamps we subtract them is their
consecutive to now we have the timestamp
between two events the trick is stead of
using a normal array because of the way
this is implemented in Chrome that will
generate a lot of garbage collection we
will use our last type array and it
would make it quicker in the case of
spying on shared event loops in the
input upper thread for the Hospice's
this is an example the idea is the same
as a form we store this timestamp
what we do is send a network request
with an on route runcible IP when you
get to the input up a thread
it says no this is mirror it gives us an
error message we measure and we cache
the error so that it invokes the
function again a bit more noise a bit
more latency because we are
communicating between processes and the
input up our thread is sending it to a
worker it's a bit slower but it gives us
a resolution of some 500 microseconds we
can do it better with the shared workers
this is like a spread of JavaScript but
it's executed detached from act of the
rendering and the idea is that all
communication with the shared work is
what goes through the input of the
thread in that case we would have the
spying website that hosts process and
the shared worker what we do is define a
shared worker which is simply responding
to all messages getting to it the spying
website as a function which is
equivalent to the one we saw the
beginning it stores the timestamp it
sends a message the message is returned
because that's what the shared worker
does and we do it again okay so we save
it on the time stamp the time stamp
we're saving now it's a runtime trip
through the input up a thread for the
house process until the shared work is
reached a little bit more noise but it
gives us a my precision accuracy of 100
microseconds if the input up of thread
is congested we will see delays in the
trace that we generate this could
improve if instead of savings time
stamps on one side we save them on both
sides on the shared work on the spying
website and then
we match them this is the idea with that
very simple telescope that can be
executed in their website we would
generate an event delay traces in one
second we will have some 45,000 time
measurements main problems we have lots
of noise because javascript is very
noisy it does just in time consolation
it does garbage collection injective
functions are optimized after certain
time this has been executed certain time
a number of times so we assume that next
time it will be this way if you take a
little bit of traces you will see the
effect of JIT compilation at first the
function is very low but in a very very
little time you gets optimized on it's
much quicker the garbage collection past
it is non-deterministic and the problem
is that this is executed in between so
the other JavaScript and that can
increase delays spread into leading a
finite number of course introducing
noise during the time they use CPU and
now I'll show you the three rules of
concept that I put together very simple
the first one is basically webpage
identification through these traces I
measured the event loop as a website
opens in a new tab and then based on the
trace I try to determine what website
that was and at least rug timing
information thank you very much
so in the case of travel information so
that we are here is to detect keystrokes
and because we kind of affect the key
that has being stopped so we just detect
the time the time when the key was
stroke therefore we know what happens
and therefore this reduces the entropy
of the buzzwords
so we can producers as a password
interrupted entropy and the Wesker
scenario do get to see the length of the
password so DC's the view of this trace
of even relays so they have been
recorded for five seconds so we can see
that they are quite different they have
a difference when I came here I hadn't
done any machine learning before have
induced and in machine learning and I
tell you what I did basically two things
came to mind for me to approach this
topic first of all was reducing what is
most classic which is just feature
instruction and one is also do you see
support the new machine and dynamic time
rubbing they are they are the first one
is that you have any trace of encoded
traffic or time event delayed and here
you try to generate a vector for each
feature where you go and say we have
sent out this amount of packages in one
direction or also the time that it's
like for these packages to come and go
so we need to have an expert we need an
expert to analyze all these traces
manually and to then become features and
then support vector machine but I'm not
going to go into that but for you to
have a feel if we have vector with two
features that is translated into a plane
we train it with many of data that we
have and then support vector machine we
try to generate a model that would tell
us about the line that separates two
clusters clusters of the different
elements and then the other one the
other approach is dynamic time wrapping
this is the one that I chose the main
advantage of this one is that we don't
need very many samples to deliver the
model
to train the models so we have some
serious as well here this allows us to
see the vectors of our traces we see
them in the form of span cereal so these
are measures over delays and instead of
calculating the distance helping us
measuring the difference between foods
I'm serious what we do we want to
measure the difference between the two
time series in the case to premium
distance we will take the first element
that is to say cereal elements of series
amb we just subtracted with some all the
differences we move the square roots and
the index at the same time and that
gives us a distance we the differences
is multi separate it is similar and if
the distance is lovely it's not as
similar however you have a trade were
uneventful but it occurs varies the
moment the trace if kind of most we are
comparing apples with them oranges this
is what times up does it finds the
optimal alignment between two traces and
then the it measures is calculate the
distance the problem well computational
speaking this is a bit costly with
dynamic programming you can do that in
quadratic time and to make it more
efficient you may establish a lower
bound to make it faster and to find an
optimal solution so the solution exactly
here here we see the trace of event
delays we may generated by Google calm
therefore I am monitoring that then in
this is uploaded in a different Google
come up and then I generate the trace
and also the youtube.com/
the matrix in the middle is drawing the
working path and this is the alignment
between the two traces if what impasse
moves diagonal means that we are
aligning many Google points with one
with a single points of YouTube
DCC intuition our fear and if it moves
but practically this is the other way
around so several duty bonds are being
aligned with a single point in Google so
in the end I run a number of experiments
to see whether this works or not
I took 100 sites i extracted several
traces so I just couple of different
machines with different OSS now what I
did was the following
I'd use one single trace of each page as
reference this is machine learning with
a single sample I just need and I'm just
using a trace of each space and if you
give me tragic that I've never seen
before I compute the dynamic time
distance with each of the points and I
just then take the closest the nearest
point and these are some of the results
these are basically the parameters is
ranges in advance that with the paper so
with the best parameters we've reduced
only one secondly the monitor for only
one second we get up to 62 percent
success rates if we use two seconds and
that goes up to 75 time in between two
and four seconds its rate is more like
the same this makes sense because most
of the sites after two seconds they just
do whatever they I expected to do I'm
not going to go into cross-validation
these are the results of the experiments
that I won and now in Turkish rock
climbing information that the other
proof of concept that I did we've seen
that the mouse displacement is crawling
creeps
auto-related into a JavaScript blocking
that event loop and usually the patterns
that are generated because of the
different periodicity or shape or length
allow us to identify to harmony with a
vermin
ten minutes ago
basically this is the aperture of a tool
I'll show you later on it is an HTML
page drawing graphs and basically this
square box is the zoom of the trace that
we generated and we can see whether each
of these Peaks much is the movement
these placement of the profiler when we
do some Google profilers understand
things that's very nice however you can
adjust that later on to see how long it
takes for an event in real world because
the profiler is introducing lots of the
code that is executed in the middle so
therefore in the performanc says
seriously impacted so we said this is
more or less one point milliseconds
delay separation is AIDS so we see all
these Peaks in blue so if you see this
trace you come and say well the user is
displacing this mouse mouse and then
well the same goes for clicks if you
want to focus on clicks so this is what
you will see if there are no event leads
list they're defined in JavaScript to
listen any events but if page defined
several events well the pattern of each
event will look differently
therefore I did the following I looked
at the aspect the look of the battery of
a keystroke in Google so we hear two
consecutive events the case down and the
key press so we'll go back to element
inspector
so when the user strikes key a Java
Script function will be executed every
time to strike the key JavaScript
blocking the event loop and this is what
we are seeing here so what was my
experiment about I took several
passwords and then I set up element
emulating the big thing it it scripted
pop-up of Google logout which is a
typical event because of about has a
reference unshared event the site the
webpage can spy on yes and I introduced
a keystroke with a delay between keys of
between hundred and three hundred
milliseconds and on the one hand I got
the information of selenium that transom
sells me and then I also get the
timestamp that I identify with my super
elaborated technique of machine learning
to recognize buttons of keystrokes and
then this is the technique that I use
I'd use this piece of JavaScript and if
I go through the trace that inducer
creates a free rights and by looking
through consecutive events between that
range between 100 and 300 milliseconds I
get a success rate of 91%
so therefore in 90% of the cases I
detect the length of the password as
well as a millisecond where each of the
keys have been pressed I know that I'm
going fast
and now I'd like to show you coverage
channel that I implement a few days ago
basically we have two different
processes one of them is sending silly
and request to monitor the event loop
and the other one is sending out lots of
noise if now it is above specific
threshold we get either one and if it is
below the set of threshold we get
receive a civil this is a proof of
concept very simple to implement you
could implement it more carefully and if
so we do personally that comes to mind
for instance imagine that you have a job
doing weird things in a weird domain if
you filter it and if someone is looking
at that in the dev tools you can see
that that is making connections outside
if you wait for the user to open less
clear service do juice bar coverage
channel and then from domain that looks
harmless you can use it to send
something else so if you like our
channel well I will upload this one
together with others and they github
these are good funny and I'm nearly
finished now look scan this is what I
did take a look at the graphs
well first of all to draw the graphs and
understand the traces you want to see
inside to do things there and to see how
all that is translated you say okay in
this page of doing this and it generates
a super trace that I can easily identify
and this will actually do so
okay so I started
this is the trace has been generators
after in defying on the input up of
Fletch of the host process and as I told
you before about utilization before is
shown there become displays of ourselves
here there so means amount so this is
the advanced displacement as money to
that as I was doing nothing but if we
repeat the closet now I open it up so
this is very slow and we see more
activity more things taking place here
not very many things but this is for you
to have a feel about it and the case of
rendering this is even clearer because
there is less noise so then here one
thing is that I have to clean this up
I will publish it very soon so this is
very simple you've seen the JavaScript
code and I juice it for quick viewing I
just didn't want to be nice I just
wanted you to have the identify buttons
well and if you want to create a logo
feel free to do it and then
countermeasures one of them will be very
limiting the way which tasks can be
posted and if you do that what happens
do just crushing or ruining the
streaming of webpages it has a huge
impact on performance to the one could
be reducing the performance of
timestamps
that is to say so that you cannot see
that as microseconds but at a higher
time of right so there are different
possible ways to measure times not only
milliseconds but also in - seconds you
can do that with your browser so judges
you can use make a silly loop and then
starting a counter and every time so
when you finish the request you just
take a look at the counter and that is a
pseudo thick initial phase pseudo check
of execution there are many ways to do
that you can either reduce the
solution while reducing the resolution
of IP estimation sense is not a good
solution is useless announced full
isolation the problem with that is
granularity of isolation so with you
compromises sub-domain or if there is a
subdomain that you don't fully trust in
terms of like the nests of it executing
and malice malicious code but the issue
of the house process continues to be
there or the expansion the plugins that
does not fall within these site
isolation projects and this is something
that happened to me when I was when I
finished the run in my experiments and
then out of the sudden my laptop our
credit to the last latest crumb and the
thing is that they have implemented the
CPU throttling so it means that when you
have it up in the background the use of
this CPU is limited and I didn't like
that because that was a problem for me
but well people started to complain
about that because for instance you are
on Spotify you're listening to music and
you have it in the background tab then
the music stops playing and developers
said look if the API is in the
background and if they use the Audio API
that I've put it in the foreground if
you do that to bypass that so we had an
impact on me however there are different
ways to bypass that so the conclusion is
as is it said before so if you find that
an exploding from that is perched on the
face
and in logical failure can be easily
patched however with our channels they
are very difficult to mitigate because
securities may indeed factor of chrome
that requires will have to stability not
to take up lots of memory they have to
run fast so you'd really need to fight
an intermediate point so that everyone
is happy and secure and nearly finish in
future other browsers
one of the first Firefox is moving
forward and multiplex which is different
architecture from that of Chrome but
without taking a look at the
architecture the details loosing the per
second you can see a similar situation
with the loop events so the problem is
there with other browsers therefore I
have good rhapsody I'm curious to see
what will happens with sever it is the
new engine we made in vests I want to
see how event ellipse up dose is there
and as I say I was curious about about
it and also improving attacks these are
proofs of concept covered channel
identification of website I use only one
trace to learn if you use more traces
performance goes up a lot and then even
do this very generic is not only
exclusive of browsers so we have to see
what other environments and then website
sounds and you have to see whether we
come on attack them as well so thank you
very much for your attention
so we are doing good with time so we
have time for two more questions for two
questions I have a question I was about
doing the typical ad on that because
plug-in that you go have it in there
opens up so that is running therefore
that it is creating noise well many
people ask me just the opposite I think
what happens is you introduce the
scenario of malicious they're plugging
always running well in our Christology
can do fingerprinting through malicious
plugging and to the diplom what they are
used to detect them through event loop
yes you could do that any other
questions
all right thank you very much pepper
what about I remind you that you can cut
in hose in Calvary