the operations are security architect I
do what I can I do what he allow me to
do there was a similar talks last week
in Ayodhya of the is a conference with a
couple of slides that were very similar
and funny enough
you
those services would not be impacted in
those areas but most of us have services
in North Virginia and that was the
reason for our problem the same girls or
or for Google cloud platform as I say
they use different terminology they
handle the redundancy in different ways
but when we deploy services using code
we can deploy them in different
geographical areas in a very simple way
in a very quick way therefore the
perimeter that we need to take into
account when securing everything is not
whether we open the door the entire
cloud all those things an attacker can
can access take a look at this this is
not complete this is a three layer
architecture in so it automatically this
is a deployment made by us for managed
services with redundant data bases with
all the redundant things with this nut
security device in place
and this I don't have to access their
computer all the instances to change
everything to change anything because
these are little boxes am is as they
call them they have all the services or
the configuration the Harding and etc if
we want to update it with just update
the instance in the configuration has
self scalability or Auto availability
depending on the number of users
concurrent connections we can scale
horizontally and so on and so forth I'm
telling you all this because we can do
it in a matter of minutes just imagine
what hardware this would take months but
in the world of cloud this is this is a
Muslim but it can be extrapolated to
anything this is a matter of minutes
literally from the point of view of
security both for attacking and
defending this part user scaling group
is very important it can happen that at
a certain point in time we have n
servers or M minus 1 servers or n plus 1
servers depending if you ask me how many
virtual machines we have operating near
as all cisco I couldn't tell you
probably 500 600 800 it depends we don't
really know and it's not really
important to know if we have the right
type of controls in place so
this is a much larger deployment not
just for production this is production
development and so on and so forth as
quick as you see there this deployment
is based on a template is software after
all in order to support a certification
for credit cards in this case with log
on monitoring etc all providers talk
about the concept of a shared security
model as all courses with mobility zones
depending on the type of service were
using whether we're talking about your
computing at two for example it's IAS or
the database services saas depending on
the type of configuration you have so
most providers tell us that they're in
charge they're responsible for the cloud
and you are responsible in the cloud
that is important because when we
respond to an incident we really need to
know what is our problem and what is the
providers responsibility this is a song
all providers are moving toward
something wakeful for forensics as a
service they try to give you as much
information as possible so that you
don't have to contact them although they
always say please contact us if there is
any problem all of those new types of
attacks you would like to know about
so what challenges complications and
differences that we have when responding
to an incident obviously based on the
nature of the incidents in the cloud I
have a couple of tables the bit scary
because of their size I will not go one
by one particular do this the fact that
we may have infrastructure deployed in
different countries in different regions
there is something that we really need
to take into account in terms of legal
jurisdiction and the fact that we have
replication of data we may have data
replication in s3 sake bar amazon in
different data centers they may be the
same same region but we can configure it
so that we have different countries that
can add complication when trading things
back to the origin and knowing where
information is at any point
this is not really zeros and ones not
purely a digital or technical
information but something we need to
take into account and knowledge forty
percent of my time I explained how
things work to the different developers
three different consultants because I
say everything we do now developing the
infrastructure so a lot of mistakes
happen in fact all providers are in a
constant struggle to see who delivers
more services who has the most of the
more powerful services and they keep
introducing new things so you need to be
updated all the time at an incredible
speed if on top of that you're doing
security for you have to change your
view on services that are already there
on how you could be attacked I'll talk
about settlers computing the first thing
developers do is try doing things in a
server less environment until something
happens and that's when they call us so
we need to preempt those situations when
doing PR for insects in the cloud
there's lots of things there's lots of
differences with conventional forensics
documentation for example the crime
scene documentation obviously you don't
have the documents anything because
there's no crime scene as such you need
to document the type of infrastructure
or recovering the leader data well it
depends where where the data where was
the data in the first place depending on
the storage you'll see different options
will see the storage options in a second
and then analysis itself on many
occasions when you have a drive that you
have to analyze the analysis of that
drive doing a timeline of whatever will
depend on the speed of rotation of that
day of that drive in the cloud you have
instances amazon has launched an
influence called X 1 32 xx-large that's
two terabytes of ram 128gb used an SSD
drives 20 gigabyte network plus thirteen
dollars an hour
just imagine that I want to do a
specific analysis for one and a half
hours it will cost me thirteen dollars
but it will be very short I mean that
flexibility I don't have in the real
world in the physical world because this
is real so we have pros and cons as you
can imagine as regards storage options
this is important this is where we can
find data that we need to consider based
on the type of analysis and the type of
information that we need to go for in my
case when we analyze our own accounts or
analyze customers accounts we have
encryption things to take into account
encryption considerations volumes
encoding criteria there's many types of
storage I know providers provide all of
them let me talk about one very
important element which service you
should usually disregarded in the cloud
here at the bottom I say is simera when
we bring up an instance by default
unless we say otherwise the storage of
that instance of that virtual machine is
a female if I stop that virtual machine
that's it it disappears if I stop the
instance what and there's many services
that are brought up that way it's like
disposable virtual machines I don't need
to save or record anything but what
happens if i had an intrusion well that
gets lost so i need to know what i'm
configuring and how i'm configuring it
in order to preserve information but
this there's lots of places where you
would need to look for information and
analyze i need to know about them
when talking about protecting ourselves
automating hardening and automating with
the incident response we need to know
specific details about the
infrastructure that i'm using and i need
to know how those attacks take place
since I know amazon best i'll tell you
about things that are specific to amazon
web services and i'll show you specific
attacks on that platform most of them
are based on the specific concepts that
i will explain in a minute these are the
keys and the accounts in am of them do
you the root account the root account in
amazon is the email address the password
you use to access Amazon Web Services
okay additionally you may have a
multi-factor authentication code if we
have enabled it but and this is the main
account okay this account allows me to
go into my invoicing if I have domains I
can manage them so high level stuff like
paying for an additional support land we
can create instances we can create
services we can manage the technical
side but we shouldn't do that the root
account is the one that allows us access
but that should be used only for
administration if you're using your root
account to bring up instances you're not
doing things correctly we know that you
do that you will use what we call
identifier identity and access
management accounts these have these
have a username and a password we may
have a token as well an mfa code and
this were useful support a week we can
configure it for single sign-on if we
have an external access provider
like Google or something like that and
then as part of identity and access
management for how the uses that
deployed infrastructure we have roots
and something which is very important
policies which are little files small
files of texture tell us what we can do
with only every services bringing up
instances databases of reading writing
or reading and writing very granular
lots of details and quite complex if we
want and then Rose which are set of
policies and all of that can be applied
to the instances no por que muy
importante Laura day ahead and i will
tell you more about it because it is
very important when it comes to make an
attractant to the persistence but each
user or each user accounts running tests
in amazon has number of keys access keys
and these are the keys that we used to
interact with sdk or the command line or
we see a live from amazon so this looks
like these on the screen we do see from
our workstation of a windows manner too
much just to interact with amazon to
launch any commands we may also do sits
in an instance in amazon to run tasks
within that and we can also do sit in a
nap imagine a nap storing data in a
three those keys are used to say look I
am whom I came to be let me run these
tests these keys are stolen if the
liberal who doesn't over history he may
upload them in github by accident if
these keys are used to a user and to a
role with more permits permissions than
expected so if we are the attackers we
will be fully delighted because we would
allow us to do very many things and we
also have tokens tokens are
recent amazon launched them to better
protect keys is a temporary Keys
associated to educate and then we have
the key pass which are our couple of
purple as cessation although they also
use for the cloud so on as I said about
the keys sometimes when we are doing an
intrusion we are in a machine with an
over the disk physical or virtual for
some reason we know we know that we r rd
Amazon Web Services machine many people
that know these advanced of a log onto
the machine where within each instance
instance in amazon's you have the
metadata server
within each instance we'll have you are
all similar to a piper I don't know
whether you are aware of this 169 and
this gives us information about that
instance to configure applications and
other tasks that we run every day in our
virtual physical machine have such a
service discovery etc this means that
anyone accessing the instance can access
that from a pool you to curl and you can
access that Carolyn gives you the name
of the instance as well as some other
type of information imagine that we have
exploded and up and we executed a
command so if you do that we get that
information and some to note that
metadata server also has keys we get
them by making it cool we called we can
call the api and if those keys are not
associated to a protective role which is
not which is often the case this will
allow us to launch virtual machines to
create a couple of keys and therefore to
move laterally and if that account is
associated with physical accounts that
is to say hybrids accounts by a client I
can move to the actual infrastructure of
the client provided I can that I can
move laterally so we are just taking
advantage of pure configuration which is
often the case and even if you have no
concerns do you have poor configuration
you can generate 32 our tokens so once
you have that you have everything you
can create new policies so I'll show you
all this this was manual but i'll show
you an automatic attack it takes just a
few seconds we are talking about
commands cool
an API therefore that can be made
automatic so once we are in a machine
how can I make the most of that
institution escalate privileges the
cloud etc and what else can I do in
terms of as other than compromising keys
etc I can i govern phishing attacks my
son often senses messages and these
instance will expire because we will no
longer be using the harbor etc and that
instance in that is in that hardware and
then it senses out in a URL so we've
seen phishing attacks F run there there
are very many attacks so this one of our
poisons am I am I are kind of like I saw
that allows you to started seeing you
our system and then we have also a
marketplace that can be accessed by
anyone
for bringing I've seen configuration
failures and also infection through
party services so they have issues of
security and to monitor you they need a
couple of keys and they are only writing
keys and I said well it isn't we advise
you to rotate to change the keys so
hybrid attacks as I said before and move
more specifically configuration failures
especially with regard to identity in
management's and as I said before there
are new things are there all the time
for instance server list seven else is
known as functional as a service this is
basically about functions executing code
in a server una managed server where you
don't have control of the seven or the
scalability or container what that is
started high availability no nothing to
justic execute the code to get a
response and you can also link it to an
API gateway the best known lambda it was
the first one then that was followed by
Azure cloud functions and Google Cloud
supports Python Java shisha etc and you
can use it for many things well so
attractive and also to defense we use it
to check on figuration status to
generate reports to ensure that no one
changes security group which is kind of
like firewall rules etc but who audits
seven lives at the end of the day seven
else's code well these could be the
topic for a different presentation but
I'd like you to bear this in mind now
I'd like to show you an exact match King
attack we have a working group and known
as sec response
we developed applications to also my
totem our tiles incident response and
this is about stealing keys so either
geha or just entering an instance to
have the keys to configure the keys and
then you use a supper which is a sandbox
or suffered less in Python and then do
take it from there the attack on account
you make lateral movement to generally
they had persistence etc and you may
ending up to destroying the full
infrastructure of the clients is that
were to happen that would not be the
first time that it happens because some1
some companies had to tell under
companies because some punish the keys
and the keys were has lots of privileges
so this is for you to see how fast you
can make an attack so we are deploying
zappa this is a valence amazon service
can you read it takes a few seconds
depending on your internet connection
and then it generates roll with the name
trolley will trick you it will generate
a nappy ABI gateway it's a new thing of
amazon amazon and it has no security
groups it controls no ports it also
generates a website well that you can
access to and you can sit off instances
generate new instances security groups
etc etc so we have to be very very
careful with what we publish
sorry this is the second video give me a
sec we have to be very careful with his
security office our accounts and as I
say attacks are automated and this is
the case we can also automate defense
another attack wall very interesting
tool kids actually same author than
Sabah if you are very interested in this
well you have you must see this video
sets a minute very good video there you
will see an exact we've played havoc
filtration several s with lambda is a
wonderful video I recommend that you
watch it but unfortunately the colleague
skip the DNA of amazon and the code
could not be published but as i said
that the sensation is well seen and
there are other tools such as metasploit
do you also have very good examples in
Daniels account known as aw own it is a
bit older but it sells you about the
things that you can do and then talk
presented that RSS SI it last week how
am i doing with time good ok so now
incident response how can we know what
is happening but we are in the cloud
sometimes we've seen that in through
email as i showed you before or
sometimes easy we population is proper
we can see the users are having that
have logged on and also i mentioned to
some of you but sometimes we see an
invoice for a high amount of money and
this tells you that something has gone
wrong
also internet articles also sharing the
experience with this big Bill's of
Amazon so if your keys having stolen and
Joan infrastructure in the cloud has
been used for instance for mining
bitcoins etc which is very frequent in
you make contacts amazon supports and
they will not judge you for that or they
give you your money back because they
also fight him very hard to stop that at
the end of the day clouds of providers
are selling the liability so that we all
move to the cloud then also logs and
other also through third-party tools i'm
not going to delegate lots of fun to
this but imagine that all the monitoring
and control systems of tradition and
infrastructure and do not are not
applicable in the cloud because it's not
only about looking into the your network
or your instance you have to look above
that because at the end of the day we're
talking about aps for instance in the
distillation of esta basura cotta you
don't install it in the cloud as you
will install it in a traditional network
for several reasons that we may discuss
offline and later on or CMS traditional
cm is not one hundred percent applicable
or useful in the cloud therefore
whenever have an incidents there are
different surfaces or things to do i'm
not i don't want to frighten you with
this workflow this is kind of just a
task list when you see one of the first
incidents when i saw the first incident
i said ok but i'll have to do
compromised instances whether that comes
from api keys then i decided i figured
out what I had to do to talk to anna's
and amazon to generate an Inside Man
tickets nearly all this stuff
we automated sewing amazon opening a
support ticket is also ultimate it so
i'll just to do that with the script and
things that are done differently for
instance obtaining information about
around our instances and send you about
instances but we are not not only
instances also virtual day machines your
daddy's databases and doesn't say very
many services and we have to get all
those data isolated the machines etc I
know this is added to information about
the infrastructure so here we'll have
these systems gathering information and
all the API traffic that is generated in
these accounts and often it is
configured in one region or in multiple
regions often this is not so enable and
we have to enable it if we receive a
good attack with lots of preventive
trees can be disabled and more advanced
on tax instead of three families they
encrypt it if yours is not encrypted so
therefore your control system will not
be triggered but when you go and see
what happens on your API to kind of see
anything because it is encrypted and to
just don't have the key for it and we be
CP flows this is the entry and output
traffic that can also be locked that can
also be register this is nothing enabled
we have to enable it manually and as I
said some of these tasks can be
automated and they are automatic now
and they last year I wrote enough an
optical about how to do all that blue
scripts and also how to automate
analysis with fitting tools how to do
that in the cloud that's what I
published and then in August twenty
sixteen people from set response now
collaborating with them they presented
it soon in black hands it is an alpha
it's missing a number of features but i
think that the future does the way to go
it allows us to found a number of tasks
that will be long in time it allows us
to automate them and to natural enough
for one instance but for multiple
instance and it also allows us to gather
information from old services from all
services to be later analyzed so there
are a number of commands and the scripts
that are used for that and now I'd like
to share with you too with his threat
response so that's a bad things is your
kiss is stolen it tells you how to
cancel that key to gather your
information as fast as possible amazon
well you know that your kids having a
soul in neither because amazon sells you
that because amisom has a number of
crawlers looking for keys on the
internet and often amazon let me know
about that quite fast and then
evidence-gathering we do detect and
compromise instance and engine launched
a command so that your instance is
isolated so that it connects to the
instance and that's a acquisition of
memory so we because we are working with
minus how do we apply a memory in line
as well we might use line in this case
we have automated the following do
connect to the machine you take a look
at the colonel then you have a
repository of line modules of colonel it
is downloaded the memory is done turned
you can apply run volatility become etc
it's about automating all that I show
you the demo now
well
Thermal could be life this is Heidi
management I have an account in
Emerson's developer account how to say
these key the key is by developer
identity access management of Madison
this is an example account and these are
countries activated so I have the idea
accounts to access the API all through
the command line turkey may be locally
so that the rotation of the amine of
programmer or the metal metadata server
or other server well configured or
hard-coded in an app which should not be
the case because that would be
malpractice but we find that and that
may be in an app that we uploaded to
github firm it up now we know by
accident so we run these commands he
compromised then number of tasks one of
them being disabled it does not relate
it just disables it and keeps the trays
and if that key is associated to an SDS
token servants cannot be revoked in this
case time is reduced so what simple code
is generated that can be added to our
final report this is disabled on as you
can see
then we may also have compromised
machine in this case can you see it from
where you are I'm assuming it is some
selling is the instance I'm extracting
information from vasim house that have a
public IP but may be the case that I may
have to skip that bastion host and go
one layer below so this is the user the
instance connects with and this is my
private key SSH most of instances in a
lesson I considered in this matter so
this up with Python that's the following
scene below it analyzes all the
resources for my song in that region as
well as in other regions it generates an
inventory extracts information from
memory that dumps the memory as well as
all the metadata and additional
information for that specific instance
and then that is the stools in a bucket
of Amazon I'm either created or amazon
has won by default so the length of time
depends on the size of the memory we can
see here and here the instances is
stopped and it has taken it to a
security group to isolate it this
security group is about the firewall
rules on top of instances and services
it would allow only the IP of the
researcher to gain access to it often
this custom manual but in this manner in
command is enough to automate all that
and as I say he it also stores
a shot of the machine that that time and
also that could be very helpful in with
those machines here we have TMP output
per console and this is a mission about
the memory that has been touch it
we've seen how to attract her to
reaction and incidents and now examples
well because ammunition of what we have
and then hard mean both automated well
in terms of protection I told you how to
access in metadata server if permissions
are not welcome figure that could be a
problem some people don't know that have
that in the instances well in lenox you
can prevent it in this manner with his
rule says that Oliver's can make a query
to query to metadata metadata server
could be very interesting it will be
very interesting for you to introduce it
in your heart and in your script as I
said cloud trail helps a lot detect
security problems but it is not enabled
by default caltrain gathers all the
costs that are made to the ABI and that
we also want to analyze and if you want
to find out about the repercussions of
not having a good configuration you may
look it up on the internet and find
examples of companies I had to close
them because the keys had been stolen
often this is used to configuration
failure and that cannot be corrected
through using multiple accounts instead
of using one account for everything one
accounts for development for production
for testing we have very many accounts
or just for different tasks so it is
good to isolate services so what can we
do to ensure that the aiming ipod is
secure apply everything that c is
benchmark tells us these processes
provided by the Center for Internet
Security will have them for Amazon
liners for windows for all oh
as is they are very good we use them and
actually you also have one for amazon
web services this is a tool i will be
showing you now playing as liners and
see liners up-armored or using local
tools such as 0 square e 0 sec are k
honza network telemetry also free
collecting the calls i have made to the
API and also pen testing i introduce
this star because to contest you'll have
to have full permission if you can test
in google and amazon without permission
that's illegal you may run into legal
issues you have to request permission
for that you let them know about the
environment where you will be pen
testing and database they'll give you
the mission files and as i say 26
screenshot a couple of services in a
mother and a nurse here with the list on
the register of all the calls made to
the API this is cloud trail and disease
operation insights of Asura which is
cultural as well as other sixes make
correlations amazon has bad for several
services and as here has has that
unified in a single service okay honey
Javed ceremony his presentation about it
other tools
well those links will be available as
soon as I finish my presentation that
will be available in github they will
also have the code of the demo day I
just showed you well other than the
tools that we have from providers I very
much like openness cut it has a fixed
option it may generate and script to
make an automatic hardening so it
generates the scripts for you and the
Prowler this is a tool that we have
developed you know linux everyone knows
linux for linux it is a linux full
amazon and it is based on the Seas CIF
benchmark i will show you right now to
execute the script and the fakes of
photograph of you security we did it
because we wanted to know this data
first letters of each of these accounts
and then to see which is the final
result after the hardening i will also
be shall we do security monkey which is
a wonderful tool which is great
especially when you have very many
accounts in amazon so for that what is
happening I very much liked it because i
know but i can see what everyone is
doing at every single time especially
when they are making sailors with
sometimes they are and I know not least
doing things that are not right and as I
say very many tools and some of them
very very powerful as you can see there
are many more tools for Amazon because
I'm as earnings older than other
providers but everyone is aware of
Netflix not only known for its serious
but they also have a security department
and develop what I develop and lots of
tools that they published security
monkey ada feed oh very interesting
tools and as an overall hardening i
recommend get secrets
these are hooks providing a preventing
developer publishing keys to four
repositories
cloud formations these summer sounds
studies for deploying code often this is
done through template through Jason and
Jamal Jamal I have templates this is
from the sea is generated by amazon
disease official it allows you to enable
services controls ultimate detection of
several attacks you do that only by
deploying template it is automatic you
don't have to do anything manually I
recommend you to do it for all your
accounts it will be available after a
few minutes now in few minutes so also
different lambda functions to optimate
all these security controls
so the tool that will have generated for
the assessments of security of a becomes
is known as Prowler it right through
different points identity management so
more critical users less critical users
those with password policies welcome
figures and not as good well whether
gartrell is enabled for all the regions
or not so when I talk about only one
region but all amazon regions so as I
said this gives me a number of view
about my security this is one of my
favorite tools which is acutely monkey
as i say security monkey makes the query
through everything in the Amazon API and
never 50-minute e makes a diff and if
there are changes it's actually about
the changes and has a number of controls
and then the changes controls about
changes relating to security services
security group is open and alert is
triggered and arranged by level of
severity so you can make comments about
the salad
here I'm only showing you one accounts
but when you have 20 to 50 accounts
which is often the case in large
corporations it is very highly
complicated to access all those accounts
and see what happens but so here we have
the accounts indexed by severity danger
level so you have a point of view that
is quite wide about everything that is
happening policies that may well
may-maybe incorrectly configured roles
so you have it all here and with that
i'm almost done as soon as i have a
connection i'll upload everything here
in fact everything is based on a
template you have all the commands and
you can replicate so as a summary
automation for everything including
hardening everything is possible in
terms of automation encrypt everywhere
with your own keys separate accounts use
MFA leaf privilege beware of your
developers who know nothing about
infrastructures and then buy bitcoins
just in case questions
the same egg magalona did I go beyond
the time questions please stand up
because there's no way within see your
faces okay I'll jump the queue myself
would you like to deliver this talk on
as all talking about internals because
Microsoft is sponsoring and we have
exile here we can talk to him you do
something in parallel something cool yes
I could try I could give it a go I would
need to match the elements from one
platform to the other in fact I had a
chat with Deanna about this yes
absolutely
don't go to the break because we will
use a few minutes to tell you about
something so please remain here any more
questions any disasters you have come
across yourself directly apart from
companies going bust someone that has
been impacted in a big way well a
department I will not mention any names
publish the keys generating instances
without noticing what they were doing we
got the money back from amazon by the
way we have an account let's call it the
out-of-control account and there's been
quite a few shocks was that account we
now have a role where I only allow
people to deploy infrastructure in
couple of Regents and we some reduce the
amount of incidences if you're not in
control of the physical location it can
be a disaster because they set up things
in Singapore and it's just don't notice
one more question nothing well thank you
very much Tony
for