foreign
all right hello
one two one two
hello
yeah I know I just
uh
I just I was getting in the way of my
size
yeah that'll be fine
good good morning everybody
um hello and welcome to my talk my name
is Jason Spencer and my talk is called
an iot War Story
just quickly a little bit about me you
can find me on Twitter at breaker of
science I'm a security Analyst at Orange
cyber defense where I've been for the
last three years what I enjoy doing in
my personal time is surfing golfing and
uh
he can't
um so this talk will go through kind of
the emotions of an assessment it's from
scope fails to the learning I required
to do an assessment how clients put
things together I'll then focus on two
different hacks I did and then driving a
struggle bus up Sony pass trying to find
a solution
um the original title for this talk and
maybe what I should have kept it at was
amqps AWS API iot assessment or acronym
soup and how to deal with it
um I was on an assessment about a year
ago and I read through the scope of work
and I said something something's off it
was an API assessment but it kept
referencing Some Cloud components and I
was like maybe
but I don't know so go to my friend
Simon who worked on the scope and I said
hey dude what's what's up with it
something something just seems off
um so he says no no it's all good the
cloud component just ignore that this is
a Swagger assessment very basic you know
got asked for the Swagger files in the
kick off meeting and you'll be fine so
you know feeling like this is a pretty
standard assessment I decide super
confident I'm gonna walk into this
meeting with my notes everything I need
I'm you know I'm confident I can tell
this client what I need
so big smiles in a meeting with a lot of
people and I say hey guys can you give
me the Swagger files
genuinely that's fine started laughing
at me
um so I'm starting to feel a little less
confident in this meeting but I'm still
I still know what I'm doing so I say so
then he just starts spouting at acronyms
at me just throwing words all over the
room like we're all just supposed to
know what he's talking about AWS amqp
iot and
I was like what
and then he had the audacity to stop
look at me and say what do you know
about amqp
let me tell you honestly I had never
heard this term in my life
I kind of felt like a deer in the
headlight the first thought I could
possibly have is well you Simon
you've
you've got me in trouble
um didn't really know what to do
just sweating means
um thinking you know like what well
um
fortunately one of the first things I
learned when I joined scenespost was the
best hackers are the ones who know how
to Google well so whilst he was throwing
acronyms around the room I thought to
myself the best thing I can do right now
is to Google the thing I know the least
about you know right now I didn't even
know if amqp was an acronym
so fortunately I had done that I Googled
and one of the first things that um
came up on the Google search history
Google search was differences between
amqp as end mqtt and I figured you know
if there's differences there's got to be
similarities so I said to the client
well I don't know much about it but I
know mqtt and I know they're basically
the same thing and it must have been
true because he bought it
um
so it kind of did feel like a bit of a
superhero moment or jumped over the car
you know
feeling pretty proud of myself I could
go on and do this assessment you know
sweat off the brow moment first thing I
had to do was tell Simon that he was
wrong he didn't know what he was doing
he shouldn't be my my boss and he sucks
but then after that I needed to figure
out what to do so now we're going to
talk a bit more about the boring stuff
the learning that you needed to do in
order to perform this assessment and
then some hacks
we did
um before I jump into the learnings we I
needed to have a look and understand you
know what is this what is this
architecture what are we actually
tasting
um before we get into the nitty-gritty
of what is amqp
so this is the client's architecture so
a device or an iot device is speaking to
a manager that manages that iot device
with mqtt that manager speaks to a
message queue with amqp consumer reads
off that message queue with amqp and
pushes data onto a global data Lake and
then from behind all my numbers and then
from there a customer portal uses an API
query to query that data Lake for data
relevant to them
so as I said in my original bed this is
an amqp AWS API iot assessment so the
AWS is this rabbitmq endpoint lives
that's the cloud component the rabbit mq
endpoint is an a AWS the pi Gateway so
we're testing not from the iot device to
the manager we're not testing from the
consumer to the data lake or from the
customer portal to the data Lake it's
simply from the manager to to the revlmq
um
API Gateway so I had to say that I
assumed to the breach of that manager so
that I had credentials in order to
interact with that um
service
but just for interest sake let's have a
look at the section here all right so
one of my very smart colleagues George
and later Rogan and William repeated it
had to test this attack Vector here
so unfortunately in a rather trivial
start to the assessment for the client
George was able to
boot the machine in recovery mode add
his own root user and as the Brits might
say Bob's your uncle he had everything
um
so George has a bit of dumpster diving
and one of the first things he aren't
was configuration files lots of fun
things in there but most importantly for
me the rabbitmq credentials
an important fact about this manager is
it is delivered to the various customers
so it lives on site at the
different customers and isn't managed to
controlled by the specific client we're
testing which means it opens them up to
local physical attacks which George's
attack is implausible which makes my
attack plausible because I was able to
get the credentials
so we're going to assume we're going to
go from the manager from here on out so
we can just erase this and just assume
we have control of the manager and we're
trying to push data to the
portal
so now as I said before we're going to
discuss some basic stuff
learnings just to understand what iot is
you know for those who may not know it's
just things connected to things it's
quite simple it's sensors or Internet
connected sensors that have
itself or its environment and push that
data to a hub or a Gateway that Hub or
Gateway will either analyze the data
there or it will push it further to get
analyzed somewhere else in our
we're pushing data to a Gateway which is
then pushing data onto the cloud in
order to get analyzed and then we'll
push that data back to the iot device
so one example of using
icons that are using
ways in order
so they have
cause
see where there is traffic and push you
down a Direction
faster for you another example is
wearing a smart watch now in my instance
my SmartWatch is gathering data about
its environment me me my heart rate my
vot levels my sleep patterns it's
pushing that data via Bluetooth to my
Gateway my cell phone which is then
being analyzed and pushing that data
back to my watch
so we use iot in our lives
um
to live
smarter easier life you know we want
everything to be kind of maintained or
be in a state of homeostasis
so for for businesses we want iot to
help our customers experience to save us
money to save us time in order for us to
further
sorry in order for us to make the lives
of our customers easier because everyone
else is doing it if your job if your
business isn't making the life of the
customer easier they'll go somewhere
that's faster for them to get out of the
shop
on the flip side however it adds risk so
increasing our attack surface every time
we add something to the internet right
our digital footprint expands so a Smart
Lock which might add security because
you can check remotely if I
locked you know
log in on my phone and have a little bit
of extra usability because I unlock my
door before I get home before I get to
the door however should that be hacked
of course that app opens up further risk
for us right if that can be opened by
anyone
so most people who have iot in their
lives probably have a little Raspberry
Pi hosting some sort of Home assistant
and they use it to just manage their
home environment their life right you
know on my own
was talking to my boss about this and he
was showing me his
heart said how
he said how when he's on his way home
he logs onto the platform checks the
temperature of his rooms and retro and
correct that so that when he gets home
he can
now what if I could modify the
temperature he is seeing
um
you know if if I could modify the
temperature here seeing he might do the
adverse of his intention he might make
the the room hotter than it already was
um
now this wouldn't do anything serious
other than really annoy my boss
um but what if instead of was his room
it was a fridge or a set of fridges in a
warehouse and we could ruin the produce
well that's that's the Crux of our
attack you know I'm not attacking the
iot device itself I'm not
the data lake or the customer portal I'm
trying to modify the data that's seen at
that customer portal in order for the
data that's being sent back to
to negatively affect the iot devices on
the way back now if we were scoped in
order to test the iot device itself sure
I could try and send illegitimate
commands in order to make the
temperature hotter itself on the device
however I can if I can push data
to the customer portal and get the the
legitimate command from the customer
portal to affect the room the device the
iot device will have no way of verifying
that it's incorrect and will just act
so naturally the first thing that we
might ask when you hear amqps AWS API
iot assessment is what the hell is amqp
so an advanced message queuing protocol
system is quite simple it's actually
just it's like a simple queue it's mqtt
or anything else it's just a data comes
in and it puts on a queue and it comes
out the other end um
amqp is an application layer protocol
but it's also
um it defines the network layer and the
high level architecture of the broker so
when I when you see rabbitmq that's just
the specific implementation there is
other
amqp defines how that broker must work
now you can also you can also Implement
certain of your own rules but there are
defaults that need to be implemented in
order for A2 5
um so to start this let's try and
understand what exactly a queue is
all right so cues are extremely simple
in their design generally they're
comprised of three parts a producer
self and a consumer message queues work
asynchronous communication method
meaning that a producer does not need to
wait for a consumer to absorb
or deal with that data that's being sent
in order for the producer to keep
working
sorry a nice example of that is when I
send an email to Leon Leon is way too
busy and too cool to talk to me so he
never replies
so I can keep doing my job I don't need
to wait for him otherwise I
cues Works synonymously in real life as
they do in message queues and that's in
a first and First Art manner which is
first in the queue first out of the
queue
clients or the producers and the
consumers whereas the server is the
middleware so that's the broker that we
were speaking about
when I originally gave this talk to Leon
he's unfortunately for him had to sit
through it many times
showed him how amqp works and even him
who is much smarter than me said dude
that was so complicated I have no idea
what you're talking about
so we're going to be using the analogy
of me going to buy an apple
in order to understand how this works
now Woolworths I'm just using because
their cues work synonymously with
rabbitmq whereas if I went to pick and
pay we separate into different tools
this is
so if I was to go shopping at Woolworths
for an apple
um
I joined the queue with my Apple I stand
behind this lady and when I get to the
front I can buy I in this case am the
producer the apple is my message and
in this case after he's passed on the
message he happens to pass that apple
back to me but what the consumer does to
deal with her message is not my business
I just need to give it to him
this is me getting to the front
so
sorry so again we're at Woolworths there
is not just one queue there's many cues
so now I'm going to go through the
concept of how consumers work
so multiple consumers can come to work
every day so it Woolworths there's many
consumers I am
in dark yeah the fourth person with my
Apple I will the first lady will go to
the first person the second man goes to
the second till the lady there the third
person goes to the third till and so on
uh sorry the first till again if two
consumers came to work that day
important facet of how rabbitmq and
Woolworths work is once I go to till 1 I
don't go and show my food till number
two that is only
um visible to the first tall person
so if I am chosen by the first Hill
person that is who will see my data and
that is the same as with rabbitmq if I
am the first person in the queue I'll go
to the first person who subscribed to
that queue that's the first consumer
now the next question we might ask is
who can consume now at Woolworths same
as at um
in rabbitmq we have the ability to find
exactly who can do it so obviously
somebody from Pick and Pay can't go and
stand behind account in Woolworths and
say Hey I want to serve you so you need
to be authenticated to serve somebody
scribe but the next thing is okay cool
but can any Woolworths employee go from
anywhere in the world well Woolworths
can say anybody with a badge can go and
stand behind accountant and help people
well which also has the ability to say
hey only people from this very specific
Branch can go so in Rapid mq terms if I
have a very specific IP address then I'm
able to consume all for this network
but what happens but
Woolworths also can say okay cool but I
don't just want anybody in this Branch
to go I want people in this Branch who
have a who have been hired as a counter
worker so again in rabbit mq terms that
would be somebody who can subscribe to a
very specific virtual host which I'll
speak about in a bit more detail now
um so somebody from a very specific
Branch so an IP
in a specific virtual house so rabbitmq
has the ability to say only certain
people can consume or they can say
anybody who's got credentials
so again we're at Woolworths and now
we're in the food section but there's
actually two cues I lied to you earlier
there's one cue that everyone can go to
and there's a second queue where only
people who have 10 items
item now the second cue is what would be
referred to as a routing algorithm right
so do I have 10 items or less or not I.E
am I just have Kia with my apple and if
I am then I'll join the cube so in Rapid
mq terms that would be an exchange of
type
direct or the default case for how it
works right so the default way is if I
match the routing algorithm I'm allowed
to join that queue an exchange is
what we use to buy
messages onto queues so it it routes
it's a routing algorithm to buy messages
onto queues so do I match it or not in
the default way built by the remedym
cues
framework is a direct queue now this
reaching algorithm we either have 10 or
we don't have 10 items so if I do have
10 I join the queue if I don't I'm not
allowed
now naturally if I were to have more
than 10 items they're going to say get
away from here you've got two bags full
of items and this line is only for
only for people with less
but what if you go shopping are
equivalents on a Saturday now let's be
honest it's it's a it's a show on a
at lunchtime on a Saturday everyone's
there buying their lunch their weekly
groceries and you know
so there's very few people who are
actually there buying 10 items or less
so if sorry
if this was the case a Woolworths
employee might say to you hey come with
me let's join the shorter queue
even though you have more than 10 items
now in rabbit EMQ terms if I was on an
exchange of type fan art that would mean
that it doesn't actually matter if I if
I have the
have the same data there all I need to
know is where the exchange lives I.E
entered Woolworths that means I can go
on any cue now it will just push me onto
a queue because you're in
now speaking of different cues
I'm now going to go through the concept
of virtual hosts all right so if we have
a look at this diagram in Woolworths
there's
we've got a home section here donated by
the Apothecary section
we have a clothing section which is
donated by the um the Sporting Goods
section and we have a food section which
I'm
not those are the only images I can find
uh so we have three different virtual
hosts right so I can go and Shop in
Woolworths anybody who walks into
Woolworths is immediately authenticated
right so let's just assume that you have
credentials to speak to revenue
so the next thing is if I was to go
shopping in the food section well now I
would be expected to pay for my goods in
the feeding section because that is
where I am now authorized
purchase Goods right so I have been
authenticated by walking in the shop but
I'm I'm only authorized to pay for my
goods in this section that I currently
am
um but wallet again has the ability to
have a LAX ruling of this you know
sometimes I've been at Woolworths I've
filled up a trolley I've looked at the
queue and I've said well the Homing
section is dead empty I'm going to
so if I took my close to the clothing
section and pay for my goods there I
have been authorized to to shop in a
different virtual host
what this means is in rabbitmq terms I
can say only people who shop in food
section have to pay in food section or I
can say look as long as you're
authenticated go and do whatever the
hell you want I don't really care
so a virtual host
is kind of exactly what you would
imagine it to be it's a namespace with
its own exchanges with its own cues with
its own bindings and everything else
but how we authenticate to that is
secondary to authenticating to the
rabbitmq node itself so we first
authenticate by walking into Woolworths
and then we authorize ourselves by going
to the queue we're allowed to go to
go to so essentially this right this is
a message broker all right so we've got
a producer that can send into a virtual
host
sorry
um
into a producer that can send a message
into an API a broker API endpoint the
broker has one or more virtual hosts and
each in each virtual host you have one
or more exchanges which have a binding
to one or more cues and that queue can
be consumed by a subscribed consumer
or one or more subscribe to Consumer
consumer so before we go on to the hacks
and stuff let's have a look at the
client architecture again it's trying to
understand exactly what is going on
so as you can see here we have each
manager belongs to a separate company so
a manager belongs to a company it has
one or more iot devices those iot
devices send their device information
a device ID to a message queue broker
the consumer consumes all of that same
sends that data into a global data Lake
and then each customer portal will
send an API query to the global data
Lake and ask specifically for the data
on um
so some important things to recognize
here is obviously they each have
sequential device IDs this is not just
within the organization
this is cross-organization so divide
the first company if I was a second
company and loaded my
ISX I'm device id2
when we hit the rapidmq endpoint we have
an exchange of type fan art now
remember about that is it doesn't matter
if I
obviously going to get important
so this is an example that I set up
with a aimqp fan art type on the
exchange with a routing algorithm of us
dot hash and that's us Dot
wildcard so it can be anything I just
needed to know the US start or in this
case because it's fan art I didn't need
to know anything as you'll notice down
here the routing algorithm I actually
sent it in with is DN I don't know
but I sent in D and I was still able to
push
foreign
that is obviously then sent with mqtt
onto a data Lake and then from there the
API query works
cool so why are we here all right so
we've had to endure a pretty stressful
kickoff meeting
um next we had to take a step back learn
figure out you know what
went on
everyone's a little bit confused
um
but I'm sure you're all thinking give me
what I came here for this is cyber
security and I want to see some hacking
so next I'm going to go through two
different attacks that we did an evil
producer and an evil consumer and then
I'll go through how we struggle to find
so the evil producer now we are all
sending into the same queue it's all
going to the same data Lake and
everyone's just querying from it so I'm
sure all of you who are sitting there
were thinking Jason this is obvious
you're just going to send into your uh
to the other device ID from your manager
from your company that you own you're
going to use those credentials send into
the manager and
it ruined because they're now pulling
all of my data
obviously I can produce tons and tons
and tons of data so I will overshadow
any of the data that's being sent by the
actual device and
in this case
when I did this
[Music]
unfortunately for him had to sit through
this many times on about the fourth or
fifth time he looked at me and he said
Jason how did you do that like how did
you save traffic it I said what do you
mean like I I wrote like a tiny little
python script and Leon was quite angry
with me he said how have you waited this
long to tell me that you actually wrote
something for this now I
did wait that long but that was just
because as you can it's nothing
impressive
but Leon said well you've got to put it
on get for people to look at so it's on
get now
um and because it's on git I had to
delete all of my other crappy
repositories so nobody could see that
um didn't need anybody looking at like
Cuda programming it was dog show up
there
um anyways yeah so a couple things that
you needed in order to interact with
this endpoint so obviously I needed to
create a connection with
I need to create a channel connection
so I needed to know where the host lived
I could get that from the configuration
file and then it was understanding what
virtual hosts there were you know what
other data I needed in order to connect
to it now this was amqps so it was
slightly trickier although all I needed
to do was add context and say I didn't
really care about any certificate you
have so I didn't verify anything just
saying
just sent the information that I needed
was the virtuos that was the tricky one
to to find but because the client was
very nice they gave super verbose
credentials and I was able to actually
interact with the management node
so I could
I could use a radnimq CTL tool that
they've created in order to interact
with the rabbitmq node and from there I
could pull what cues were in use what
exchanges were in use so I was able to
get like the general information that I
from interacting with the rabbit mqctl
tool I then used a pica Library which is
a python Library used in order
published data you can consume data and
you can actually start a server
there so I created a connection and then
it's a very simple tool um command where
you just need to publish the data
knowing a routing key again didn't need
to know that so I just wrote anything
there to the fan art
exchange and then it was pushed on and
then of course
um the important thing being the body
where I'm sending that this refrigerator
is running at 69 degrees so hopefully
they'll hopefully they'll fix that
foreign
okay so the next attack that uh we
looked at was well as I spoke about with
like Woolworths you know who how
restrictive are you being when you say
you can consume all right now in my case
um not was the answer
so I could create my own evil consumer
um which would read traffic off of the
the queue now as as you'll remember the
first consumer is going to read the
first message because they've created
the
I'm the second consumer so the first
message comes in from a company and I
can read the second message off now
that's obviously important for a couple
different facets the first being
customer two never actually receives
their data
so they've like lost their availability
and the second being that I have read
sensitive information
yeah so
one important thing here is obviously
they've now created a single consumer I
can create hundreds
hundreds so if I have 100 consumers they
will read the first message and I will
read message to
and then they will read message
because I have the ability to create as
many as you want I can pretty much make
what they legitimately see
invalid or you know useless because
it'll only receive that every hundreds
Maybe
so again the how
um
again very simple you just create a
connection string and then I needed to
create a loop in order to continuously
consume so it didn't just kill off the
after the first
read and then it's just a basic
to consume so I needed to identify in
this case where the queue was not
necessarily the exchange so I used
rabbitmq to view
from so I could read where they consumer
so those are the attacks and now I want
to have a look at
potential Solutions and what
struggles we went through to why they
wouldn't so the first thing we thought
was well you don't you don't have a
virtual host well let's let's separate
each client each company into their own
host
the data will go to different places
you know I can't send to your virtual
host and then you know it'll go
up one thing I forgot to mention
I'll tell you so he has a little story
when a while back I took my friend out
to a fancy restaurant
they they only served one like you
weren't allowed to pick your meal you
have to eat what they were eating and it
was like it was Squid Ink with like some
puffed popcorn I didn't really
understand it and I Can Only Imagine
can only imagine that two ships came in
that day and one was like I am making
squid and goo and the other Chef was
like I'm making popcorn so they were
like well we're serving squid ink and
popcorn
um
in when you have many cooks you know
everyone's got their own opinion
and everybody says this is the way I'm
doing something so
the person in this case who created the
squid ink part said this is not going to
work a virtual host will not work
because I'm using mqt
no virtual Hearts this is something we
learned in the Google search differences
between mq
mq2q
so they said there's no way that we can
work with this because virtual hose
won't work so I tried to assure them all
rabbitmq uses at least the root virtual
host so you are you just don't want to
separate it more and they said no no we
know what we're talking about and I've
only done this for a week at this point
so I'm like all right well you know
which one
um but technically this wouldn't have
worked anyway and the reason for that is
it actually doesn't matter if I say if I
can't send into their virtual host
because we're all going into the same
data link
so if I send my traffic with the
incorrect device ID to my virtual Host
this gets consumed by the global
consumer and pushed to the global data
Lake then customer one is still going to
read or 4
of information so it doesn't actually
matter
so the second thing we thought of was
well let's not
let's not say that the attack is
impossible but let's like reduce the
likelihood significantly so we'll we'll
move it away from device IDs and we'll
put really hard to guess Goods
now
the person who was in charge of the
popcorn
said to me well we've already agreed to
device IDs and I am not going to touch
Goods that's that's too much extra work
sign up SLA nah that's not gonna it's
not gonna Not Gonna Fly with us so I
said all right cool but technically this
wouldn't have worked anyway and the
reason for that is because we have the
evil consumer so I have created a
consumer I can read awfully
feel the sensitive of information
regarding that good and then of course
once I have see once I have the good or
I have that sense of information I can
then send traffic into the queue and the
case
so so what do we actually do like how do
we how do we solve this so personally my
first thought
um you know I kind of still feel like is
the problem is we have this global data
Lake right we're just dumping everything
into the same place and was that using
the customer portal to like query it
the custom floor has no way of verifying
what data is valid and what data
is it their sole job is hey is this give
me everything for my device ID
um
but you know that's is that's not a
solution we can't just say it answer the
problem so what do we do we need to we
need to actually try and help our client
right so
can't just say well put virtual hosts in
because they can't do that we can't just
say well do Goods because you know they
can't do that so we need to come up with
a solution where they can actually
the final thing we thought of was all
right well let's set the data that goes
into the manager and we'll sign that
data at the manager level
the consumer can decode that message and
then re
manager has sent something with device
id1 and they are sorry device id2
then it will go into the data Lake if
however they send something for device
ID
three they need to log that drop it and
report and say hey why are you sending
traffic in for the wrong device ID
only valid messages should actually ever
get to the data Lake
the next thing we obviously recommended
well not obviously is you know you
shouldn't let everyone consume so they
said no well we need to consume in order
to
traffic back from the
cut advice we need to
so the best way we could say do that is
you can only consume off of a very
specific virtual host so in this case
you should have a virtual host at least
one going forward and one going
backwards and you
so that this
yeah so in conclusion you know
at the beginning of this talk I said
well I
that is the way I felt in the beginning
but
had Simon read the scope properly he
said he never would have actually put me
on this assessment so I wouldn't have
had the fun the learning opportunities
that I did I did so instead of freaking
out running around like a headless
chicken and swearing in Simon a lot you
know take a step back
we'll figure it out and
it's a lot more enjoyable than doing a
normal web app
yeah so we have iot in our lives to make
ourselves easier you know make our
environments
and more more maintainable smarter but
when you put things in correct together
incorrectly it can be a bit of a mess
and lastly you know third parties can
distribute the workload
when you have too many cooks in the
kitchen you're bound to end up with some
weird squid and goo and popcorn
yeah uh lastly I just want to say some
thanks to some of my colleagues who
helped me both on the assessment
um
Simon for messing up the scope
Leon for helping me with this talk
um orange and then besides and you guys
for
throughout the thing
um I I really hope you did enjoy some of
it or all of it um
yeah or message me on
Twitter
the breaker of science
sorry I don't know
drag me from
essentially
if we are you know seeing data that's
out of sync should we not delete that at
the customer portal
you're on the way to the customer portal
the fridge should only be running at 25
. yeah you look at data trains if
something's way over
with invalid data
hopeful that if you were to implement
something like that as an attacker I
would hope that I am
but I do think that that's a very valid
approach and something that you should
add on
something that you should analyze
um is that data at at various points
like at the consumer level if if we are
seeing something invalid that's why you
know we look
at is coming
yeah I think I think that's a very valid
way of approaching it I just think that
there's security and depth means you
need to also account for the fact
thank you
all right folks we got a 15 minute break
at quarter past three we're gonna have
dial track one we're gonna have Nintendo
Here track two there is also sorry guys
there's also a workshop on osit
happening right here in the registration
area
now we have the lunch as well yeah
cool
huh
testing testing yeah that's good that's
good yeah I think so
morning everyone it is still morning
yeah
all right so uh names in tando I'm about
to have a you know do a talk on cloud
security securing a core banking system
in AWS
I don't know if I should kick it off or
let people settle in or but I'm gonna
start it off actually
ball rolling
all right so like any other talk the
best place to start is just two
give you a little bit about me
and um yeah so
comsite graduate who's uh
pretty much just a family guy you know a
wife and a kid actually I got married
last week so yeah
um
I'm Shackled down now
um yeah chess enthusiasts I actually
participated in the world's first
chess.com World Championship
and I sucked
I I didn't make it past the open
qualifiers but I will try again next
year
um
before I move on from chess actually
this year was a good year for chance you
know as I said
chess.com open World Championships but
also
Magnus causing them the whole butt plug
thing
no you guys you guys know nothing about
it
yeah for anybody who doesn't know
anything about it just have a chuckle
yeah so I spend most of my days
um you know Jason the gentleman who did
the previous talk I think Mr Spencer
he spends most of his days breaking in I
spend most of my days keeping him up
um so I'm on the blue side of things
and yeah another interesting thing about
me I'm an open source evangelist so if
you give me
proprietary software side by side with
open source software I'll almost always
choose the open source
so yeah human me
I just want to get to know a little bit
about the crowd the audience please do
humor me and participate in this
um hands up if you regularly work inside
or work in AWS
okay keep your hands up don't take them
down hands up or keep your hands up and
take your hands down keep them up if you
use kubernetes regularly
nice keep your hands up still if you've
deployed a core banking system in
kubernetes
I like that
that's pretty cool it's actually quite
crazy
um were you at hexcom
not it's uh it's always one guy in the
audience but
questions
Okay so
about the talk
yeah we're we're going to be just
discussing you know like I said
initially
um the security of the cloud which I
think is a very important topic and uh
just to set the problem statement
I've got two slides that'll kind of show
how important this is and why we need to
take this seriously the first slide I'm
not going to go through all those points
you can read them for yourselves the
first slide just shows that 10 of the
world's I.T infrastructure has migrated
to the cloud now that's not such a big
number right
10 percent who cares you know
but juxtapose that with this next slide
which says Cloud security breaches have
surpassed on-prem breaches for the first
time research done by Verizon 2021 tail
end of 2021 how is it that 10 of the
world's infrastructure is being breached
more than the other 90
. that's a big those are two big facts
there so so for people like me you the
blue teamers even the red teams I'm not
gonna I'm not gonna take anything away
from the importance of what you do we
need to take this seriously you know
um because you don't want to be another
Facebook you don't want to be another
LinkedIn you know you hear it all the
time another one got hacked today blah
blah blah but it's up to us
keep that from happening and hence
topics like this just to spread their
awareness spread the knowledge
all right so that's that
let's jump into this
AWS
humble Origins I think way back when
started off as just a collection of you
know simple storage service which is
still currently it's Flagship ec2 the
compute service
um and that's still today
those two Services comprise most of what
we use AWS for
um but yeah I'm not going to talk too
much on AWS for now I want to Pivot away
and just kind of discuss
the core banking system for another
on the left
we have a gentleman that I you know I
look up to this guy
at Dr Mohammed yunus he is a Noble Peace
prizing holding gentleman highly
esteemed gentleman for those of you who
know in the audience he's also known as
the father of micro Finance or micro
credit
um so just to quickly Sprint through
like what he's done here and just the
origins of of finraxi and finnure Cloud
native
um the gentleman started a Grameen Bank
uh and then went on to start the Grameen
foundation in addition to other Grameen
you know subsidiaries green and and and
During the period of around 2004 and
2007 and before I before I go on what I
love about green bank and what speaks to
me on this slide is the fact that you
know look at the title it says bank for
the poor and that speaks to financial
inclusivity being on the African
continent that really touches a chord in
my heart you know so so the origins of
phenorexia and so to speak kind of seep
through
um you know uh the the code speaks to
this this motto this Vision this mission
statement
so yeah
2004 and 2007 there was like a burst in
in in commercial activity in the back it
grew quite substantially
and during that period they began
working on finnurex CN Under the
Umbrella of myfos x
that got handed Over The myfos X Project
got handed over to the green Foundation
under the myfos initiative
which then handed the project over under
the fineract uh incubator program in
2011 it then subsequently graduated as a
top level program in 2017. now that's a
major knot of approval from Apache just
charity of the software and and then
somewhere in the mix there finnurexcn
came out fineract mifos X is a monolith
then they broke that down into
microservices in order to make a cloud
radio and Cloud native
all right so let's speak a little bit
more about
these uh microservices the building
blocks of this core banking system
so if you have a look there what we have
is
a set of services at the bottom under uh
so you have you know member
Administration which and then you have
membership notifications verify ID
fineract services including Office
provisioner Accounting deposit uh and
and customer one of the more important
microservices in this diagram is the
identity microservice which is the
authentication server for finrax CN
which is underpinned by a system called
Anubis
but as you can see very simple diagram
coming in from the left from the front
end hitting the Gateway and then going
through to the microservices where
finally information is stored in the
data store
another picture describing the same
thing but differently we have all the
micro services
and and your nosql and SQL Cassandra and
postgres respectively storing all the
data
all right so just as an FYI to those who
actually want to go and check the
software out the software is quite I
wouldn't say limited but it it does what
it's supposed to do but if you have to
bring the software into your own context
you know you have to build upon it and
expand upon it and this is kind of a
slide that speaks to that where you had
additional micro services that worked in
tandem with that set of core banking
systems in order to expand upon for the
context in which that software runs
member Administration notifications and
verify ID for those of you who don't
know verify ID
it's a real-time interface into the
natural person's registry which is just
home Affairs allowing you to verify in
real time you know whether someone is
who they say they are and that's for the
you know kyc process for those of you
who are in banking
all right
Okay so
I don't want to belabor too much the
point on on finrax the end so we'll move
on from there and begin jumping into you
know more of the uh architectural level
discussion kind of dissecting
um the system in a greater context
um
no Cloud talk is complete without a
short description of the shared
responsibility model and the catchphrase
goes AWS or your cloud service provider
is responsible for security of the cloud
and we as analysts and Engineers are
responsible for security in the cloud
this this
you know concept comes in later on when
we're kind of unpacking the kubernetes
side of things as well but it permeates
almost every aspect of your interaction
with AWS
so over here
we have that in a more you know uh
tangible View at the bottom you've got
your you know AWS Services your regions
your azs your availability zones your
compute and Storage
you know S3 EBS Etc and your networking
vpcs
etc etc which allow whatever workflows
you're putting on AWS to achieve your
business objectives and then at the top
that's where we're responsible for
security and uh you know whether it's
secure encryption of data at risk
encryption of data in transit
configuration of those systems we play
at the top AWS plays at the bottom
another kind of diagram that shows this
but with a little bit more context
specific information is this one which
shows our core banking system I I don't
know if this is really legible for your
reading guys but I am apologize I
apologize I can't zoom in unfortunately
so we have the core banking system we've
got the member Administration couple of
you know the gravity Gateway et cetera
Etc everything above the foundational
Services is for us to configure and then
everything below is for AWS to to worry
about
all right now
this brings me to what I call the golden
thread I've just uh quickly had a brief
Sprint through the architectural aspects
of the system that we'll be kind of
discussing
um and now the golden thread of what I
call the security landscape in AWS you
see on the left you've got IAM you've
got single sign-on you know and then
you've got cloudwatch inspector etc etc
what we're going to be doing as we go
along is we're going to be ticking boxes
off on this landscape as we go through
each section and try hit as many boxes
as we can in order to ensure a secure
environment
again not very legible but I will zoom
in this time for you this is um you know
a I would say a very basic architectural
diagram you guys have seen far more
complex diagrams and uh but this just
serves a purpose just to emphasize what
I was speaking about in terms of the the
golden thread that I showed you just now
so you see traffic coming in from the
corporate offices via the VPN you also
see traffic coming in from the internet
into the environment most importantly I
want to bring your attention to the
first thing that the end user hits which
is a load balancer that's associated to
a ref and has a assert attached to it
for encryption of of traffic in transit
higher the AWS certificate manager
again very very basic public subnet
private subnet nothing complex but just
emphasizing a point here and if we go a
little bit further we see at the back
we've got our eks cluster with an auto
scaling group that you know spins up
nodes or spins them down accordingly and
then right at the bottom we've got our
CI CD pipeline that's uh you know got
Version Control and Jenkins
um you know speaking to each other
so now if you if you are paying
attention to the golden thread
previously we see we're already starting
to take a couple of boxes
we see the waft being ticked off we've
got a VPC being ticked off cert manager
VPN AWS Shield so already with you know
the security of your infrastructure
starts architecturally and that's the
that's the that's the idea here to say
let's design a secure infrastructure
before you even touch a line of code
before you even configure a single
service you know
foreign
so
this brings me to the section on
securing the stack
so in this section I'm actually going to
um there's a nice there's a nice way to
think about securing the cloud 4cs right
securing the cloud
no matter what cloud service provider
you're using which is the slide we just
came from so it's curing the cluster
securing the container that's from a
kubernetes perspective and then securing
the code the four C's so we're going to
start off with
securing the cloud the previous slide
and the next upcoming slide will speak
to that as well and let's just jump
straight into it
so
hands up for anybody who has ever worked
with the control tower or deploy The
Landing Zone nice nice all right so
um
just a way to explain this a control
tower is a way to provision a
multi-account environment right for AWS
now what that does for me the the best
way to think about it is you wouldn't
want to put you know an FTP server mail
server DNS server all in one box it
becomes too much of a risk in terms of
the number of services that you're
exposing on it
this is a similar concept you're trying
to split up multiple different aspects
of your environment into logically
separate areas logically separate
accounts so you know in security we've
got our core tenants right we've got the
principle of least privilege you've also
got the principle of need to know think
of this as the principle of separation
of concerns right so you don't want to
have one account being too high risk
that account being compromised in the
whole thing going down
so yeah let's let's jump into dissecting
exactly what this diagram shows
in the top
account the root account we have the
control tower and organizations
control tower is just your orchestration
for this multi-account Landing
Landing whereas the organizations allows
you to manage it's the UI the interface
for the administrator to manage this
multi-account Landing Zone
coming to how we authenticate into the
landing Zone we have
the directory service on AWS and then we
have single sign-on what I see most
companies do most companies that I've
interacted with
actually
because I mean that's the that's the AWS
NATO version of the service usually most
people come in with their 365 as your
active directory and replace that top
icon with the with the aad
and then after that the users inside
that active directory will then use
single sign-on on AWS to authenticate in
and then this is a very very important
section in terms of
the architecture that I'm showing you
here
if you look we have multiple
organizational units uh one for you know
each specific section note the asterisks
on the applications
OU which just basically means you know
multiple of those so multiplicity and
you'll have whether it's your uat mat
sit product etc etc as as many as as you
want from from a business perspective
but right at the end on the uh end there
you have the SCP the service control
policies and this is one of the key
aspects to securing a uh Landing Zone it
is an organizational level uh way of
saying what services can and cannot do
which services are allowed and which
aren't allowed and inside each service
what can be done and what cannot be done
paying attention to this is critical
all right so going into our application
accounts maybe that's Dev prod whatever
the case may be we again we see service
control policies except this time on a
per account basis but what we also see
is right at the bottom there IAM
policies so the combination of
organizational level scps account level
scps and IIM policies that's the try
factor that really is the the Beating
Heart of security in an LZ so to speak
controlling these three is Paramount to
ensuring that you've got a grip and a
lockdown on this LZ
all right so moving to the networking
account again just speaking to how we're
separating the concerns so that if one
of the vpcs is compromised not all of
them are compromised and that also means
not the entire infrastructure has been
taken down giving you time to respond
from an incidence response perspective
before the guy pivots and takes down
more of your system
so we see a couple of vpcs egress shared
VPC client VPN VPC it was a quite
self-explanatory the egress VPC allowing
people traffic are allowing systems
traffic out of the network the shared
VPC for all the OU's hence the asterisk
on it and then the client VPN VPC
allowing VPN clients to enter the
network
okay last but not least we've got the
audience account
the audit account is actually quite a
key account
because it contains you know all your
key
for the you know the things that you'll
be encrypting
for example you'll have an EBS volume
that requires encryption so you'll have
encryption at rest
and you will store the key to encrypt
and decrypt that volume inside your KMS
key store and that key store lives
inside the audit account making this an
extremely sensitive account I've seen
I've actually seen LZ deployments where
the KMS key store is taken out of the
audit account and put into an account
called the crypto account however you
know refined or granular you want to
make it is up to you but the key points
don't put the key store in other systems
where for example your VPC resources
will reside
so for those of you have been paying
attention
you'll notice
security Hub and guard Duty icons in
every single account and
um
if we go down inside the audit account
we'll have the central guard Duty and
the Central Security Hub account so
effectively you're having all those God
Duty which is threat intelligence
effectively and security Hub which is
compliance management coming into this
Central account for Auditors and
consultants and analysts to review and
act upon those upon that information
all right so
this is a I think quite a an important
structure if you haven't dealt with an
LZ before dig into it it's quite
important
um and yeah but let's move on
and as you can see the golden thread
we've ticked quite a lot of the boxes in
the identity and access management
column again I'm sorry for the
legibility
and at the end there you see control
tower being ticked and you've got KMS
and yeah and VPC flow logs also being
ticked there so a couple of more boxes
being ticked in our security service
landscape on AWS
and it's important when you're securing
an environment to bring especially one
in AWS to bring as many of the tools
that you have at your disposal to
perform against real threat actors
all right so this brings me to this
section of the talk which
um what I would call
the the core security offering that is
provided on AWS so you have a
combination of your guard Duty again
threat Intelligence coming in from you
know various logs VPC flow logs S3 API
logs etc etc and then you've also got
your security Hub which is your
compliance in this picture unfortunately
I forgot to include PCI that is one of
the compliance standards I'm sure many
of you actually deal with that regularly
but we've also got the AWS foundational
standard and the syscom clients all of
that coming in and hooked into some sort
of alert system that allows you to see
these alerts as they're generated as and
when they're generated
this is the you know again a very core
basic model for security on AWS so let's
expand upon it you have on your right a
couple of new services
you've got Macy which hunts down poppy
information
um you know it's it's so easy to to slip
and Miss uh you know a data store or a
repository of information that's got a
lot of client data and it's happened
I've seen it happen you want the
machines to help you out with that
um
then you've got your IAM access analyzer
you know how are the outdated keys that
need rotating are there any users that
need to be removed because they haven't
been accessed accessed in a long time
then you've got your SSM patch manager
now to be honest SSM is the systems
manager is an amazing tool
it's more than just a patch manager for
example
recently we had to configure a weft
right and uh and you know you've got a
couple of ec2 instances in a client
environment you don't really know what's
running on them so we deployed an SSM
agent onto these machines that kind of
scrubbed the system and told us what
software was installed you know node PHP
etc etc created an inventory of that and
then that allows us to then go back to
the weft and refine the rule sets
accordingly you don't want to just throw
all the rules on the web that really
don't make sense you know if it's a
Windows box you don't want to put Linus
rule sets you know so
so that's quite a neat feature of the of
the security manager and actually it
goes much deeper than that but patching
is one of the big things that you want
to use that for and then you've got
inspector which you know we used quite
recently to to scan for the log4 shell
vulnerability across all containers that
were that we're running in in multiple
environments
okay now as Security Consultants
Defenders attackers you know one thing
we don't want to be doing is adding to
the problem you know if you're going to
be
configuring a security architecture like
this you don't want to be the guy that
allows the guy the other the bad guys in
and um S3 really is one of the ways
which a lot of companies have found
their pants down because of
misconfigurations
all right now so you might be asking me
how does this architecture fit into the
previous architecture which I just shown
which is the landing zone right uh
notice I I emphasized the guard Duty
elements of each account and you're
seeing God Duty and and security happier
so indeed what you have is you've got
the main audit account feeding security
Hub information in from all the child
accounts and that is the architecture
that we'll be going for when securing
the environment
right so that brings me to the golden
thread yet again and notice now this
time
um how quite a lot of the boxes are now
finally ticked off unfortunately
um and Ivan I don't know if Ivan's here
but unfortunately this column here is
something where you know I I was at a I
was at the hex-con conference and Ivan
had mentioned
it's such an under supply of incidence
responders in South Africa you know and
I I'm proving that right now in
preparation of my talk I didn't even I
didn't even touch that that column there
um but for the most part it you know
you're seeing the light starting to
switch on across across the the server
the security service landscape
all right
that brings me to the end of
architecturally how you would go about
securing you know your your cloud and
in fact let's jump into
kubernetes environment where the code
will be running
so a couple of you guys already know
kubernetes are I kind of asked that
question at the beginning what you'll
notice if you're paying attention I will
come back to the snacks I'm getting
ahead of myself
so let's just start with a brief
overview of how kubernetes is put
together so you have your API server
which is one of the more critical
components in the in the in the
architecture that's what the Kube CTL
command line application interacts with
when an administrator kind of interacts
with the cluster right then you've got
your Cloud controller manager the icon
at the top there and then you've got
your hcd hcd being well before I go to
NCD Cloud controller manager being the
API to the you know cloud service
providers resources
and then you've got your SCD which is a
distributed High availability data store
which stores the state of the cluster
now
compromise of either the API server or
the SCD data store is akin to the root
on a Linux box
so that's that's what you want to
protect right at the beginning of the
offset
be thirsty
so all right so then we've got our nodes
recall in the previous uh architectural
diagram the simple diagram that we had
that auto scaling group it's actually
responsible for spinning up the nodes
which are just regular ec2 instances
um inside those nodes what you'll have
running is the kubelet
um and
the kublet via the container runtime
interface manages the pods inside your
nodes and then you've got the coupe
proxy which is the physical
implementation of a service in
kubernetes now for the eagle-eyed
audience member you'll notice there are
two elements missing here there's the
regular controller manager
controller manager I'm not going to get
into too much detail here but has it
manages controllers
one of them if you ever want to get into
kubernetes research one of them that
you'd really want to look at is the
admission controller it before a part is
scheduled it will then mutate and verify
certain elements of that pod or that
manifests before scheduling it on pod
and then you've got another thing that's
missing here is the scheduler
schedule it says okay cool
you've given me a part let me find a
note to run it on and then and then the
couplet will say okay I've got I've got
a pod now
let me find a container let me put the
container inside the pot so those two
systems the scheduler and the Kubler
work hand in hand to deploy the
workflows that you'll be that you'll be
using to uh to run your systems
all right
another view that I'd like to kind of
give you is the flow of network traffic
right so you've got your red line coming
from the admin to the API server very
very important to protect that
then you've got your end user coming in
through the services you know that'll be
an HTTP endpoint that they'll be
interacting with and then you've got
your container registry where the Pod
pulls its containers down from the
internet from uh assuming it's a it's a
it's a public container registry
all right now let's discuss
some of the attacker entry points I've
already mentioned that
um
you know the API server as well as the
hcd server are high value targets those
need protection at all costs then you'll
have your service I mean anything that
the end user can get to the hacker can
get to as well right
um and then you've got your node and
your Kubler over here there's there's
some actually really neat
vulnerabilities out there uh one being a
container Escape phone on the crio
runtime most runtimes today actually I
think the majority of of kubernetes
clusters run on Docker but um couple are
really neat crio vulnerabilities out
there for the round researchers and then
you've got your registry which stores
the images which will end up running as
containers
all right
so
let's begin just unpacking
um you know how each of these elements
can be protected to keep the you know
the the threat actor out
before I go any further
um for those of you who do work in the
environment you'll notice
that I've kind of cheated
I've added those two blocks there and if
you're on a AWS cluster you'll never
actually see the control plane
you won't see the master note it's
invisible to you that ties back to you
know the shared responsibility model
that's something AWS is in charge of uh
you know securing however that being
said there is a certain degree of
control that we do have at this point
here which is control over the API
server
so let's jump into that so what you have
is most of the time you want to have a
rollback system protecting that but in
this case AWS implements that rollback
system via IAM you don't have to worry
too much about that what you can worry
about is who has access to the API
server if you make that API server
public what you'd want to do is you know
whitelist certain trusted IP addresses
that can access that API server
preferred method the recommended method
is making your API server private and
then using perhaps a jump box or a
Transit gateway to connect to that to
that to that private API endpoint
again so I'm going to move on to the
next slide but as I move on to the next
slide you'll notice I've put an x on API
server I've also put an x on NCD
datastore you cannot control anything on
the hcd data store that's AWS so hence
that was just for information purposes
all right so
pod security policy
what you want to do is when you're
running a pot inside a node you want to
control what level of access that pod
has to the underlying host whether it's
got host ports access whether it's got
host network access etc etc that's done
via the you know pod security policy as
well as in combination with the network
policy I'm so sorry that this can't be
read properly but I hope I'm narrating
it properly for you guys
um
and one important thing to know about
the Pod security policy is that for
those who deal with this again regularly
this is deprecated as of version 1.21 of
kubernetes and I think it'll be
completely phased out end of life by
1.25
and then I'd like to pause for a second
and have a Shameless plug
um
and have a little bit of a questionnaire
to see who wants these uh you know
synthesis goodies I think there's a
couple of shirts in here key holders
socks chocolate cups for anybody who can
answer the next question for me which is
and I'll I'll give it to the person who
gives me the most correct answer I'm not
sure if everybody's going to get it
right but it is easy
um so we're moving away from the Pod
security policy to protecting the
registry anybody want to have a shot at
how you protect your register your hands
up you know
is there
nice okay that's actually
there you go
anybody else want to give it a shot I
mean there's a couple of things maybe we
split them up
nobody
the gift is yours man
so a notary server right signatures but
in addition to static code analyzers and
actually something very interesting a
friend of mine showed me earlier on this
week is chat GPT
uh in terms of secure code reviews or
static code reviews
um have a look at that but yeah so a
notary server you'd wanna you'd wanna
you know there's two options here that
you want to play with one you're gonna
go with a third-party hosted notary
server uh the problem with that is that
you're not going to have all the
signatures you know you're gonna you're
gonna you're gonna take what you get
other alternative is you know creating
your own
privately owned notary server which then
uh leaves you with the job of creating
those signatures yourself and then of
course
um you know open source or proprietary
scans of those images uh using a static
code analyzer
all right
okay protecting the service like I said
earlier on the same way an attacker can
get to the uh the back end is the same
way an end user can get to the back end
is the same way an attacker does and how
I've had success in the past is
converting the service to an Ingress of
type nginx and then enabling the mod
security rule sets with the old core
rule set on there so the mod security
plug-in excuse me with the OS core rule
set now you might ask yourself but
Nintendo let's just the duplication of
the weft that you showed me right at the
beginning
but if you look a little bit deeper and
for those who have played with nginx
it's it's you know you've got a lot of
control over some of the security HTTP
headers and that gives you control over
what the attacker can and cannot do so
that's a very very cool uh combination
there that you can use to protect the
service and then last but not least
you have the AWS resources that are
sitting on the cloud such as your EBS
block but block storage
what you want to do here is you want to
have an IAM policy attached to a service
account that you force the Pod to run
with so that pod cannot access what you
haven't given it access to even if it
gets compromised right
all right so so that's a that's a pretty
neat one to block that attack Vector as
well
I don't know how I'm doing for time
it's like I'm I'm good
so yeah
um
and that brings me to the end guys of
you know securing kubernetes which also
means it's the end of the stack
um
did say that there are four C's I'm not
a coder so I'm not gonna lie and stand
here and tell you about how to secure
the code
um you know I I'll tell you about how to
secure the infrastructure but I do know
that secure code reviews does get you a
long way again I'll name drop that uh
that thing again chat GPT check it out
um in terms of you know the feature of
secure code reviews but yeah that's the
uh that's the end of uh what I have to
show you
basically I think the the take home here
for me and I hope this is what you're
taking home is you know a multi-layered
approach to security which is the you
know which is the standard you start off
with securing the cloud the cluster the
container
um and at each level you wanna you wanna
observe certain core tenants of security
like the security uh the principle of
separation of concerns which we saw on
the LZ and uh this is the principle of
least privilege which we'll see when
we're associating a policy to a service
account but other than that
um that's all she wrote Guys
uh thank you for your time
do we have any questions
awesome
go for it sir
yeah so that's actually an interesting
question we've been working on 40s
um very recently uh for East West North
South traffic inspection on AWS so um
yeah it's something that I'm coming up
across in the real world and uh yeah you
point out a good point the fact that I
don't have it in my slides but it is
something that you'd want to look at but
uh yeah I think next time around with
version two of these slides I'll add it
in there thanks
100 percent
thank you
were you gonna ask something
yeah
so
actually
no because
we we found we found it difficult to get
God Duty into kubernetes so we ended up
using you know open um proprietary
software which I don't like to always uh
lean on we use Prisma specifically Swiss
lock kind of um to to gain to gain
insight into into the cluster
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
okay so there was a Trend Micro
conference that we just recently
attended with the team and um so
instance metadata service version 2
imdsv2 right
um there's a couple of server side
requests for jury attacks that can go on
it and um we got that feedback from God
Duty in the Island region so we're
sitting there trying to secure this
cluster
from this imds V2 attack and we're
noticing wait hold on if soft doesn't
scan for that finding so there was an
AWS representative at the Trend Micro
conference and I'm saying to him
so you're saying South African security
admins have to fight this fight with
their hands tied behind our base
and um and then he just left okay okay
I'll get back to you you know and and
but it was a valid question because
you're running scans in Ireland which
pick up this very bad vulnerability same
scans in Cape Town the Cape Town region
do not what does that mean for people
like us who have to protect information
that resides in South Africa because
government wants the information for our
citizens to stay here poppy right so
yeah so that's a that's a big one that's
a very very big one I don't know if I
answered your question or if I went on a
tangent there
okay cool
yeah now 100 that I've seen them I've
seen them in practice and I'm speaking
to AWS and I'm telling them you should
ask fix it you know and uh and yeah
they're trying they're trying I guess
cool
yeah
yeah not 100 100 I agree with you man I
agree with you any other questions
yeah
you say Falco okay cool is that a
service mesh type of uh
okay okay
cool
thanks I'll remember that Falco Falco
thanks I'll remember that man thanks
yeah yeah
yeah so
you know how I'm going to answer your
question is I've I spoke to a couple of
csos and I'm like
you know companies getting hacked csos
getting sacked it's a it's a shame you
know when a company gets hacked and then
the CSO gets sacked you know
um so the answer to to your question is
how far do you want to go you can look
at it from a commercial perspective
you're paying more for that peace of
mind and you're offloading that risk
that you know you're no longer
responsible for if it gets hacked that's
how I would look at it you know and um
but you you're paying premium for that
for that peace of mind you know because
now you're that Cesar who's spending
more money than you should be but you
know that if somebody gets into your
network you get to point the finger you
know so that's another way of looking at
it you know
foreign
yeah
um
so SSM is pretty cool now for that uh
you can you can kind of associate into
it using your browser without having to
expose it
um so you run the instance you put it
you put an agent on there an SSM agent
on there and you'll be able to interact
with the terminal via the browser
without having to you know set up keys
and things like that
um and using putty or whatever to
connect over the Internet uh you'll just
be you know HTTP your way into that
so yeah so that's that's kind of um
without revealing too much about how we
do what we do that's that's a good way
to do it but there are other ways to you
know skin that cat as well
I'm running out of water guys
better wrap up
any other questions
thank you so much
hello hello
there will be a small break uh lunch
until one o'clock
there's also a CTF Hector box CTF
happening at the moment if you guys go
to our website you'll get all the
details in there
sure
Gmail
cool thanks everyone for coming I think
we're just going to give it two
ready
cool
first I just want to say thanks to
everyone who came
so I'll be speaking on abusing AWS
permissions
so firstly who am I or if you're an AWS
Nerd Like Me AWS STS get quarter
identity
my name is Jason I work at gmail as a
cyber security engineer and I've been in
the industry from a decade which
is roughly five years which I'm
basically dog years in this
and I left my email address there in
case you want to contact me
quick agenda what we're going to do is
we're going to cover some basic access
principles within AWS I want everyone to
be up to speed with what everything
means before we jump into something a
little bit more fun
ever seen any
cover
cool so first things first
this is the flow diagram that displays
whether an action can be executed on a
recent release or not this is displayed
by this is given by AWS the source is at
the bottom and we just
first we look at what AWS does is there
low policies for
policies also
or status
other than that we started SCP
control policies which are organization
part I think
and these are things that we're gonna
connect
I just want to mention that
an explicit deny means that you state
the this resource cannot perform this
action
where an implicit deny means that
there's no allowed permissions
so now by default
as I said these are the two we're going
to focus on because I think most
companies focus on these two
so at a high level what is a policy
right
policy is a document that contains a
number of statements that determine
whether or not an action can be
a statement generally has an effect
action and a resource as well as
sometimes
you can also add wild cards to this
which is
so we're looking at resource-based
policies essentially if we go back to
you can see that resource-based policies
the the logic is looked at first before
identity-based policies so what I mean
by this
firstly the resource-based policies can
allow principles outside of the current
account to interact with
and a lot of companies Focus their
efforts on ensuring that their identity
based policies
but
if your resource-based policy if someone
creates a resource-based policy that
allows an action
is no identity part
well then all the safeguards you've put
in place around identity based policies
are essentially essentially as good as
this gate
and there's also some permission
permissive options available directly
from the console so if you're in the AWS
console
um there might be some very permissive
actions that can
take what I mean by this is we've
buckets I decided that we would look at
simple notifications it's
I'm definitely going to undersell the
service it's a really cool service but
essentially what it allows you to do is
send people send emails and sms's and
other notification types to different
Services as well as users
and when you're creating an SMS topic
from the console this is the access
policy options that
from the console
and what I find quite interesting is
that you given with the basic options
you're given some very limited
options to choose from only the topic
owner everyone and only
so if we look at the first one right
only the topic owner what exactly does
that mean
right and the only way to really see
what that means is to look at the policy
on the right
as you can see from this policy it has a
whole bunch of permissions publish
remove permissions set topic attributes
and so on
and on the resource and then it has a
condition
so any
within this account can perform those
actions by default and this is the
default
default so essentially this policy is
permissive by default
if you created this resource-based
policy regardless of what permissions
you have given
other use other IIM entities such as
users or roles
if there are no explicit denies then
they would be able to perform those
actions by default
now what I found more interesting is the
one that says everyone and the little
description says anybody can publish
so what does that actually mean what is
anybody in AWS
so if we look at the policy on the right
show it says principal AWS star
that means that's a wild card for
anything that means any AWS account
anyone who has any object Within
an or IM entity could perform that
publish attribute
so essentially what you're doing by
clicking that everyone is allowing
anyone in the world to publish to your
topic
and if you click to everyone for the
Subscribe action then you can
send some quick look at identity based
policies these are policies that are
attached to users groups and roles users
are intended to be real live users so so
human people
roles and and roles are essentially the
service the service board users that can
can attach multiple documents to
any of these
some actions that are
allow that entity
or permissions or give someone else more
permissions either in conjunction with
other actions or just by themselves
there's just a quick video
so just a demo on what we've just spoken
about I'm going to show you that I've
created a user
named Jason
it's me
no group so no inherited permissions
either they actually have no permissions
they've been given absolutely no
permissions
so because they've been given no
permissions it's in implicit deny
so let's look at the
end if we look at the topic I created
this topic using the default basically
just giving it a name and clicking next
next
policy document
or the access policy
we stated any AWS account can interact
with this
perform any of these actions and
IM entity comes from that account
which it does right it just doesn't have
any permissions given to
so now we can just see here
and I'm logged in as that user and I'm
going to create an additional
um we saw that there was only one user
I'm going to create an additional
subscription
and we run it because
we go back
in testing three which is the one
we can see that testing three was
and that's because if we look at
the stock this flowchart here
we can see that resource-based policies
are evaluated before identity based
policies
essentially meaning that the permissions
given to that user unless they've Fallen
explicit deny
don't actually matter
and that's what I meant by this gate uh
Focus all your effort on identity based
policies it's not very effective against
resources that have resource-based
policies
so now how can we apply all techniques
or old mindsets to these new Cloud
problems
so we've all heard of Bloodhound I think
there's no one in this room who hasn't
heard of that hunt which allows you to
see uh different
how things can interact with each other
different resources is a similar tool
for AWS that was written by Craig
which is very cool and it allows very
similar things but because of how many
permissions and how many different
resources there are and resources are
added literally all the time we need to
apply our hacking mindsets when looking
at stuff like this so I'm going to show
you the demo that I'm going to show you
is a path that these tools actually did
not pick up
and now we're going to jump into the fun
stuff
so what I've done is I thought I'll take
the Capital One hack as an entry point
to everyone I think is familiar with
that
um we've been testing a web app and we
see
we seeks a call to this web service and
it sends in that parameter so what we do
is we change that
URL parameter to google.com or any other
website and we realize that it returns
that data to us
familiar with web application
security you'll know that this is a
server side request forgery ssrf and we
can essentially have the networking
capability of the server we can make the
server perform HTTP requests on our
behalf
cool so the first thing I would do is
first understand is that an ec2 instance
performing NS lookup to see if there's a
DNS name attached to it
and we see that it is an ec2 instance
if you're in the AWS environment or
you're very familiar with AWS topics
your spidey sensors will be absolutely
tingling at this point thinking is there
a role attached
because you have ssrf you have the
ability to query the metadata service
and you might be able to give
credentials
so let's jump into a little bit of a
demo
first things first I'm just going to run
my
srf vulnerable web app
to save time
and essentially the metadata service
allows us to query information about the
ec2 instance and at a fundamental level
we are allowed to actually obtain the
AWS credentials for that role so it
works the same as a user account right
it has an access key and a secret key
so if we run this
basically what I'm doing here is I'm
querying the meta service to find out if
there is a role attached and it came
back with yes there's a
there's a oh sorry about that
so I query the metadata service to find
out if there's any IEM security
credentials attached to this or a role
and there is a role it's called ec2
Lander role
so now we can do is actually obtain the
credentials for that role by just using
the same endpoint the AWS metadata
service endpoint
and now we see that we have the access
key and the secret and the secret key as
well as a token
so if we do an AWS sorry
sorry so what I'm doing is configuring
my local AWS instance let's give it a my
local AWS CLI
uh as with live demos looks like it's
already broken
okay cool well let's just start again
looks like it's taking a bit of time
internet slow
cool
so this is the file where your
credentials are stored when you
configure the AWS service
decision took
and kill the whole line but I can't
remember what the variable name is
but essentially what I want to show you
is that
it's not you're not required
okay but anyways what I'm trying to get
to with this is we can see
we have ec2 Lambda roll on this instance
ID what I'm trying to get with this is
those credentials don't have to be used
on the specific ec2 instance that the
role is attached to you can actually use
those credentials wherever you want they
work just like normal access tokens
cool now you have compromised AWS
credentials now what what are you going
to do with it right if you're doing a
pen test your goal is to find all
avenues of attack right
but if you're doing something nefarious
or a red team what what is your goal and
generally the da equivalent is all
actions over all resources which
essentially allows you to perform
whatever you want on whatever you want
assuming
that there are no scps in place or
resource-based policies stopping you
from doing what you want to do
so the first thing we're going to run
here
is we're going to use our newly found
credentials
to find out if we have what what
policies we have attached to them
for this we're just going to use the CLI
and we have three policies and already I
can see one that is awesome if we look
at these policies over here it would
have the AWS account ID if it was
created within that account if it says
AWS there's a managed policy which
essentially means AWS manage that policy
and it's available to any account so you
can use your own account to see what
permissions you have without doing
anything weird and if we look at
one of the interesting policies
AWS Lambda full access this is also an
AWS managed policy
I'm just going to have a quick look at
it and look at the permissions so the
Assumption there is really that you'll
have all permissions over
Lambda
but we're not one
once a roll
so what's interesting here is if you
look at the description it says grants
full access to AWS Lambda service AWS
Lambda console features and other
related services
we're not going to look at all of the
statements we can already see that we
can do anything on Lambda which
essentially means we can create a Lambda
that we want execute whatever code we we
want if you're not familiar with Lambda
essentially it's something that allows
you to run code without thinking of the
underlying infrastructure
and then this is the statement that's
also quite interesting so what we can do
is we're allowed to pass a role
essentially attach a role to an AWS
instance sorry an AWS Lambda function
what's quite cool about that is if there
is an existing role with different
permissions to what we already have
we automatically gain those permissions
because we can execute code with that
and that's
exactly what we're going to do
so just to show you that we're still
that user even in this console in this
terminal
cool we are
and I'm going to create the Lambda
function
a pass a role that we previously found
through that
that one is not to go
if we look at the roles
if we list all the roles in the account
essentially what we're looking for is
one that allows the principle so the
service to be
lambda.amazon.aws which corresponds with
the policy that we had so we can only
pass policies for that service
um
towards the end but essentially you
would look at these
closely
this Vault roll
what I see that is quite interesting is
SSM Lam
B manager
SSM stands out to me because that's the
service manager within AWS which is
essentially something that allows you to
control all ec2 instances that are in
the SSM Fleet
we can run code push software
control those ec2 instances
so that's quite an interesting one to me
and if we look at the permissions
attached to that policy
to sorry to that role
we can see another AWS managed policy
and I know this policy pretty well
essentially what it is is it allows all
permissions to be performed
um
all SSM actions
which it will allow us to push code to
instances in the fleet allow us to view
the fleet allows to view instances
within that Fleet so let's have a look
at that
ssms
so we have two instances
within this Fleet right we have the web
server that's the if we looked at the
account ID versus the
uh we went back up we would see versus
a role that is assumed that has that at
the end we would see that we compromise
the web server we also see this admin
host
is quite interesting so what I would do
is I'd go look at ec2
and see exactly what this admin host is
because essentially we have full control
over that admin host
so this is the easiest way to look at it
if we see the admin host actually has a
role attached to it
and this role is an ec2 admin
so now what we want to do is we want to
create a Lambda function that allows us
to compromise this ec2 admin account
because that ec2 admin account has all
actions
over all over
so our initial entry point through ssrf
allowed us to compromise a web server
which had a role attached to it that
could create an AWS Lambda function
which work had the ability to pass a
role to any function that we
and that role allowed for full control
over the systems manager which allows us
to run a command on an ec2 instance that
has a role with all actions over all
resources
it's a little bit of a mouthful but
let's picture
so now we're going to do is actually
create this Lambda function and I'm
going to focus on the console because I
think it's a much better visual
representation than kind of just looking
at live
code on the screen
so we looked at how ec2 instances obtain
their credentials using the metadata
service
let's have a look at how Lambda
functions do it so Lambda function is
doing a bit of a different way they do
it by using
environment variables
the first line of code we have there
is just to print out the environment
variables
so if we look at the environment
variables just like with the metadata
service we can see that there's the
session token and if you look through
the rest you'll find all the rest of the
credentials so that's how it works it's
not it's
now what we're going to do is actually
add to this Lambda function
the ability to run a command on the ec2
this command will query the metadata
service on that instance and return the
credentials for the role attached to it
so essentially we have the ability to
also view the SSM commands that have
been run the history
find the output production
and like all demos it broke
cool
up in the tree
okay
cool see that it did succeed
look at the outputs
we have the access key and the secret
key which essentially means we can use
these credentials outside of AWS in our
own in our own local CLI and perform any
action over any resource we are
so I just want to go through
something quickly
when I was performing this presentation
to a couple of my mates
they asked me this question
and I actually kind of forgot
they said yes you can
policy is here by default but someone
needs to be able to guess they are in to
do that right which is essentially your
account number and the topic name that's
something we call security through
obscurity
and to put to give you a physical
example
um
it's essentially if you had a house on a
relatively busy street and you kept your
keys in the pot outside you told all
your friends and family
um
if that's good enough for you
um sure good luck but that's definitely
not good enough for most people who
love security
cool so now we're
we've got all of the Power well not
quite there's only two gems there it's
only within this account
we have full admin over over everything
essentially
so what could we do to actually stop
this from happening
three main things I could think of
really is prevent detect and remediate
and we hear stuff like this a lot these
very high level
prevent this to take this thing
how do we do that
and it really does depend on the
organization whether you're going to put
acps in place to stop certain certain
creational resources or only allow like
a white list of if your company only
creates ec2 instances instant
instant that don't
whatever the case may be
but the example I work at a Dev house so
um if you do too you'll be somewhat
familiar with this if you use Jenkins
and what we do is we have two things two
things really
one we have custom modules so we try and
Abstract the security away from the
Developers
the module for instance would be like
for
um S3 buckets if all S3 buckets are not
allowed to be public in the module it
won't even give you the option right
you'll just create a bucket and in the
background it'll ensure that it's not
public it's encrypted whatever other
compliance policies you have so we have
a compliance step that also checks to
ensure that that's in place in the
pipeline we want these things to fail at
the pr stage because it fails that they
apply we're going to have an account
with half created resources
detect and remediate so we don't know
what we don't know right and we have a
community that we can rely on AWS has
something called security Hub which
tries to detect most configurations not
specific to what we spoke about today
but definitely other misconfigurations
that's a great tool to use there are
other open open source tools out there
such as Prowler and Scout Suite those
are things you should definitely be
making use of on a regular basis
and then remediate do you have a process
to remediate these things what what is
it and what are the timelines are you
sticking to those timelines do you have
a security posture
um
where you review these things these are
things that definitely
and yeah just saying conclusion what I
wanted to add to this is
the tools are very good but also we need
to apply our hacking mindsets to some of
these things like this path we found
here was not a path that a tool found
but it's something that we could we
could see because we understand the
Technologies right we understand that in
ec2 instance
with an ssrf vulnerability with would
allow you to
grab the role we understand that being
able to create a Lambda function
and attach any policy that is or any
role that already exists would allow you
to
essentially abuse that role's
permissions so these are things that we
need to think about when
when doing assessments or creating these
things
scared to ask this but are there any
questions
yes sir
sure that that for SNS specifically or
for other resources
yeah so essentially anyone with
permissions to view they are in will be
able to find it
um so just to to uh jump onto what the
question was the question was those Arns
in the SNS topic is that something that
people would be able to find
right and just like the example of the
physical security where all your friends
and family know where the key is
everyone who has view of only access or
read-only access or any permissions to
view that within your account which will
probably be your entire Dev team
would know what they are in is and if
you're using that Arn in other systems
that are not AWS related they would be
there too so
pretty dangerous to to rely just on that
also the Arn is your account number and
the topic name
it's not something that
people may not be able to get
any other question
yes sir
sure so the question there is how do we
maintain the compliance policies within
our Pipelines
so
we have a security team that does that
we're constantly looking at new things
we also utilize other open source
Frameworks or research that's being
published so like security Hub is a
major driver for us
um
yeah so that's how we find that
compliance and again those compliance
steps fail at the pr stage right so that
PR can't be merged
so the developer will see that it's
broken and why
as soon as they try and push that code
any other questions yes sir
correct
yes
okay we'll have a statement than a
question so the metadata service there's
two versions uh
opening version one is still the default
so if you create an ec2 instance through
the console AWS console it'll be created
with version one
and it'll be vulnerable to if you have
an ssra vulnerability you'll be able to
call that
that's a very good question I like it
when you when you say permission
boundaries
are you talking about sorry we've got to
go back quite a few slides
I am permission boundaries over here
so look how far along the line that is
right that's after
resource-based policies and it's after
identity based policies
sure and uh what about resource-based
policies
and ACP so I think we try and focus as
far to the left as possible
but but yeah that's not something that
we've actually explored
uh really does depend on the
organization I've said before I think
scps is a very good one if you have a
lot of accounts and you want to enforce
certain things on all of your accounts
but it really does depend on the
organization
the question there was just the first
one was have we considered permission
boundaries and the second one was are
there any other guard rails that you've
thought of putting in place
any other questions
yes sir
the question is is the the tools within
AWS the the permissions within AWS not
good enough or not um
was that or that we need to use other
tools I don't think so I think that AWS
allows you to do whatever you want with
whatever you want within the account how
you you misconfiguring it is is really
on you
um but yeah there are tools out there
that help you identify these things and
guard rails in place just to
help you stay within those
um yeah there are some really good Cool
Tools out there
cool well you have my email address so
you can always uh email me
thanks everyone for coming
all right folks are going to do a break
uh next talk 150.
are you gonna hold the microwave
speed this far away from
my cheat notes are coming through there
how's it okay there we go hey
I think so I've got one there we go
sound good
okay
all right hello everybody
thank you for joining me for the pre-t
shift
I'm going to do my very best to keep you
all awake
but I offer absolutely no guarantees
so before we kick off
the perfunctory who am I
my name is Robert Lynn
I work for Mobius binary I live in Cape
Town
like random facts retro video games and
beating the system
and I know I've got a cue from my
director just to mention Mobius binary
is hiring if anybody is interested
so I am actually a returning speaker
I spoke at a B size in 2016 on a wildly
unrelated topic
so yeah coming back here it is still at
absolutely as nerve-wracking being up
here
and I'm still filmed filled with an
overwhelming sense of imposter syndrome
so here we go
but from 2016 until now I still have my
beard so in a never-changing world it
has remained constant
so this feels like a sort of dating
website you know where I'm telling you
all about myself like I like um
video games and long walks on the beach
and pina coladas and all of that
so once we're talking about confessions
you've heard some of my personal
confessions
confessions and caveats let's talk about
some regarding this presentation
so
first up the data in this presentation
was part of academic research so please
don't hold that against me
if anything putting me for it
the presentation is not going to be all
the research thankfully for you and for
me there will be Snippets of it
although as the heading is
got to do with crypto I am not a crypto
Enthusiast actually
and the idea for this talk like all good
or and bad ideas came out over a couple
of years is this possible can we get an
idea about the world of crypto jacking
it's going to sound a little academic-y
because it is but I'm going to do my
best to not make it sound that much and
while I will share the results
it's really more about the process
and and with that process hopefully I
can help somebody else with a similar
project or a similar idea or something
like that
so the state unfortunately is not the
current state as of the 22 as of 2022 it
is a little bit older
and we can thank covert to that because
I would have really liked to present
this back at the time that I actually
did the research
but it is entirely repeatable so if
anybody else wants to please go ahead
and it's not an in-depth talk about
crypto not at all if anything it's an
inch deep and a mile wide and not the
other way around
so when we're talking about the
prevalence of crypto Mining and crypto
jacking what exactly are we talking
about and in the context of this talk
it is a monetization process in which
the visitor of a website Computer
computational Resources are used to mine
cryptocurrencies
for the owner of the website or somebody
else
so it is an attack it can be an attack
but it can also be legitimate and so
therefore a process
so with anything like this there's
always a couple of ethical questions and
first up how did the scripter mining
stuff get onto the website so there's a
couple ways it could have got there that
somebody could have breached the site
and embedded it in the code
the webmaster himself could have put it
there
without any consent or the webmaster
could have put it there and asked for
consent do you mind me mining crypto
while you visit my site
so consent is a is a tricky one
especially in this regard because it's
really difficult to ascertain whether or
not the end user even knows what they're
consenting to
in the case of it being one of those
sites where the webmaster openly
he puts it there and tells you that he's
doing it and asks you to consent
so a couple of Studies have been done
around it bleeping computer did one
where they revealed an enormous
percentage of users actually didn't mind
their their resources being used to mine
a bit of cryptocurrency in the
background as long as those pesky ads
aren't being displayed
but once again do they really know what
they're consenting to
The Pirate Bay torrent search engine
which I'm sure nobody here has ever used
they were caught out using some crypto
mining stuff and quite a while back
without even amending their privacy
policy and after that was released they
put a little cheeky caveat on the side
saying well do you want ads to display
or can we do mind a little CPU Cycles
being used for you know for us to mine
so the ethical questions are there if
anybody really wants to talk about them
we can chat about them a little later
but back to the actual talk what are we
talking about and so it really is how
prevalent browser-based crypto mining is
on the internet
which mining variants are preferred
for crypto jacking which internet
service providers which countries
they're in
which currencies are used and most
importantly the process as to how I got
to all of the above
and of course it fit into the b-sides
2022 Mantra it's all done from home
so the result which hopefully is a data
set containing varied and hopefully
accurate and relevant crypto Mining and
crypto jacking data
a repeatable process that anybody else
can facilitate and continue enriching
such a data set
and a data set that can be used for a
visual representation
so some of the technologies that were
used and when I was making the slide I
was like damn I'm sure I use so many
more but actually pretty simple pretty
pretty basic stuff and we've got bash
we've got python we've got python pandas
library multigo Jupiter notebooks neo4j
virus total and the last icon is the max
mined geolocation database used in math
IP addresses to your locations
so when we talk about they in the
context of this talk
what are they talking about what are
what are they that we're talking about
they really is browser-based crypto
mining scripts and we can go really deep
talking about these
crypto mining scripts and there's a lot
of depth to it that's not the intention
of this talk it really in a simplified
version It's mining code embedded into a
website source code that makes of the
makes use of the visited CPU during that
visit
so now that we know
what we're looking for kind of I mean
the embedded mining code in websites
how do we find all these different
variants and all these different
crypto mining scripts how do we know
what we're even looking for and the last
thing I wanted to do was go on a large
study and try and find every single one
of these scripts out there I think it
would take me forever
so luckily I came across a really really
useful list called the the no coin ad
block list
if anybody's heard of it very useful and
it's commonly used in a lot of these
plugins extensions browser plugins even
for phone devices and what these do
these plugins
you you install them and when you visit
a site that has any of the embedded
crypto mining scripts it will pop up and
say hey this site has a script it's
going to mine cryptocurrency of your
browser while you visited and these
these extensions are powered by this
wonderful little text file
known as the nocoin list the bottom of
the site you can just have a look at it
and for reference sake
that's what it looks like I know that's
that's really difficult to see but it is
a text file just with lists and lists of
different mining variants
and yeah these text files
plug into the into the extensions and
they warn you if you're hitting a site
to them so fantastic now I've got a list
of these of these variants
these mining variants I know what I'm
looking for
but here I get hit with the real big
problem
that was the easy part how on Earth am I
going to find them in the world of the
internet
and and this part started really
bothering me I thought oh god what have
I done so
my options and I started
searching around and checking out for
some vendors very sign and PIR they will
give you DNS Zone files for DOT
com.net.org domains you do have to fill
out a couple of forms to prove that it's
for academic research
so that was the option that I was going
to go with then I'm thinking okay I've
got to now crawl all these websites
download all the HTML
I mean the landing page is at a minimum
and then match all the source code with
my entries
in the nocoin list and I mean that that
that's horrible that's horrible so
thinking about this oh my god what have
I done I've got I've got a crawlia a
total of 128 million domains
um I mean the bandwidth required to do
that I couldn't even start figuring out
the storage space
the actual computing power to sift
through all of this and at the time that
I did the research that no coin list had
587 variants that I was looking for so
I'm now looking for 587 variants in 128
million pages of source code how am I
going to do all of this
how am I going to pay for all of this
and most importantly I'm just freaking
lazy man I don't really want to do this
so poking around
came across an amazing resource I don't
know how many of you have used it but
yeah it really saved my life called
public www.com
and that's me in the middle there
thinking I'm going to be stuck with
manually crawling the site and then I
see public WWE coming along and I'm
happy and most importantly this was
supervisor approved from a research
perspective so I was given the go-ahead
to use it which which really made my day
so having a look at the site itself
just to give some context it has the
source code index for 504 million
websites which I mean even kills what I
would have been able to do in terms of
128 million and it's got some other
really interesting things that you can
you can use it for you can search for
specific Technologies in source code
sites with similar analytics ID names
WordPress themes references to code or
comments even sites that mention your
name
and no I do not work for them I have no
affiliate deals none of that just really
really useful
so before we get too stuck in and too
involved in the whole process just a
quick note on coin height because it
comes up quite a lot in coin hive
really was the crypto Miner the crypto
jacket in this case's best friend
because they provided these amazing
services for you to embed your mining
scripts into sites you own or sites you
don't
and as people visit and their resources
get used you get paid and literally
their slogan was monetize your business
with your user's CPU power so there was
there was no hiding it
and also before we get too stuck in
Monero and and coin Hive just like
perfect marriage
the coin I was built for Monero which is
really the most useful at least one of
the most useful
currencies for browser-based mining
being Asic resistant and enabling CPUs
it was perfect for it so we could once
again we can go really deep on this
topic
not what I'd like to do at least at
least not right now
um
but yeah so the two of them perfect
perfect match
so the way coin I would work is you'd
sign up get a nice token include that in
the API calls when a user comes to your
site that script is loaded connects to
coinhive
authorizes the user's token to receive
input for hashing once a valid hash is
found gets committed to the coin I've
pull and then eventually they pay you 70
of that reward in Pocket 30 sort of like
the poker table at a casino
I also had a couple other interesting
Services capture service which was
quickly shut out and the short link
service all of these with delays on
pages so that mining can take place in
the background
but back to the actual research so
kicking off I've got I've got this
access now I've paid for this access to
public ww API access which is about
fifty dollars and I've got my list of
from nocoin of the variants
that's literally how I'm starting off
I've got nothing but a list of no coin
variants and this access and by just
running my for Loop
of every single my folder basically
simply just takes every single entry in
the nocoin list queries it and what I
get back is a CSV file of each of those
domains I'm sorry each of those variants
So in theory there could have been 587
that's how many entries there were in
the nokoi list
and this is an example of one
so it gives you all the sites that have
that source code in it and it gives you
a little rank as well after the comma
like an Alexa rank
so this is where I start plugging
everything into Jupiter and python
pandas
and from that initial kickoff
I found 27 981 instances of crypto
mining scripts from that list
and of them there were two 25 204 unique
sites hosting these Scripts
of that 587 files entries in the file
305 unique scripts were noted so 285 I
didn't even come across at all
and the top 10 which I refer to quite a
lot as the top tens here really
accounted for 76 so
a small amount of them really being the
bulk of it and if I compare the problems
I had when I was worrying about how I'm
going to do this and what am I going to
use and crawling and downloading I mean
this took 20 hours over five days and
resulted 10 Meg of raw data so it was an
absolute pleasure
so taking a look at some of these sites
that had crypto mining I thought let's
match them up and see if there's any
decent Alexa rankings any any popular
sites that we might know that have
crypto mining scripts in them that we
didn't even realize
not so much but the Wiz products and the
Wiz marketing.com bizarrely enough were
pretty high ranked on Alexa
um I mean top thousand is is very
impressive and and they were hosting
some some crypto mining scripts there
I've noticed I had a quick look through
these again
it's been a couple it's been a while and
farm easy.in number seven is still it's
still running and still doing its thing
so the most prevalent miners
no surprise we did speak about was was
coin Hive and auth mine and the two of
them together make up 38 of
the entire population of the miners and
almost mine is run by coin Hive as well
or at least was and that's the the
consensual version so if you want to run
the site and you want users to consent
to having their resources used for
mining you can sign up for auth mind
authmind interestingly neither of them
exist anymore
and in fact as I was finishing up this
research they didn't exist either the
head closed down so 38 of the market
when you no longer exist is pretty good
going
um previous research showed them having
about 75 to 80 percent of the market
tied down so they were definitely the
the ones to go to if you were looking
for your your end-to-end crypto mining
solution browser-based
so taking the 25 000 unique URLs that I
had I thought now it's time to have a
look at the IP addresses see what I can
see what I can dig out of that
so DNS resolution was my my obvious
choice and mass DNS is what I use for
that of that list of unique URLs about
15 were unresolvable totally
over three thousand so left me with 21
984 IP address is valid
and that I can now have a look at
so I plugged those into the the max mind
the geolight database
and I basically did a simple count of
the number of occurrences of each of
those Geographic locations
and with that I was able to find servers
the number of servers 91 different
countries hosting crypto mining servers
South Africa had 106 IP addresses
hosting crypto mining
variants which rank 25th out of the 91
and just 12 of the countries were noted
as just having one IP address
so the actual geolocation itself
having a look through the count in the
top 10 the USA Top in that list with 42
percent followed by interestingly Iran
Germany Russia some of the usual
suspects there those are the guys are
the most servers hosting crypto mining
variants
so at this point it's worth just having
a little checkpoint
as to
the data set I've got
so I've got domains
what the miners found on those domains
I've got the IP addresses
and I've got the geo location and that's
the data set that I have at this point
in time
so my goal now is to take this data set
and enrich it a little bit more and pull
some more data out of it see what I can
find see where that goes
so the first thing I did was integrated
with virustotal
and just like some of the other services
virus turtle is a really interesting and
useful API service for academic research
so if you can prove that you're doing
this for academic research they'll give
you free access to their API
and with that API you can do some some
interesting stuff you can get domain
categorizations
can check whether or not it actually
exists in the virus total database
determine if there's any known malware
samples associated with it and you can
get some DNS and who is information
so once again just a simple for Loop
going through all my domains and hitting
the virus total endpoint
gives me examples like the following so
once again I got a bit of a problem now
whereas before
doing my initial loop I had CSV files
loads of them 587.
I thought it was a lot now I've got 20
000 nested Json files one for each
domain
and the fact that I'm working with
python pandas data frames and I'm pretty
much CSV Centric
makes things a little tricky how am I
going to get this back in how am I going
to add this to my data set
and so with enough messing around with
bash and enough grip and awk and TR I
was able to chunk it all together
and put it back into a workable CSV file
and import it back into my data frame
so that's just an example of what that
data frame now looks like the enriched
data frame
you can see I've got the bitdefender
category which is one of the domain
categorizations I've got the domain
which is really the URL or at least the
the first part of the URL that the force
the force Point categorization the URL
the rank the miner found the IP address
and the geolocated country
so already a bit more of an enriched
data set to work with
so looking at some of the actual domain
categorizations I know this is really
difficult to see but the main one for
Force point which surprisingly is
potentially unwanted software so
no surprises there but other than that
we've got business and economy newly
registered sites information technology
and actually compromised websites which
is this one here
which did pique my interest because
that's most likely well sites that have
not put it there on purpose sites that
have been hacked and have that have had
mining variants embedded anywhere
but Defender categorizations were
a little bit sparser not nearly as much
data
but similar type of of categories
business parked blogs computers and
software porn
and a couple others with not as many
categorizations
so because these two were
so vastly different in terms of data set
sizes I just looked at percentages
and with that I could see that across
both there were definitely similarities
where a Bit Defender and force Point
both at about 16 to 18 percent
and computer software and information
technology between six and nine
sex travel news and media similar
percentages of those domain
categorizations so we start getting an
idea of what type of sites are actually
hosting these mining variants
so firstly I apologize for the
the horrible annotation
but I am fiercely loyal to Microsoft
Paint
and I
really yeah that's the one I use and so
these are the top 10 endpoints
essentially the top 10 IP addresses that
have domains with crypto mining embedded
on them
so that first IP
I mean has an enormous chunk has you
know over 2 700 domains hosting crypto
mining on it on one single IP address
and the reason I've circled them and the
reason I've used different colors
the red I'm going to show visually from
an IP address perspective and the green
I'm going to show from a data
categorization perspective
and with this I'm going to use neo4j
so first up this is what this is with
the neo4j prep these are the nodes so
taking that that python data frame
I was able to turn each single entry
into a different node into a neo4j node
and then write the queries in order to
visually show me what it looks like
so what we'll see next is basically the
world according to me if you could
visualize what crypto mining or at least
crypto jacking campaigns look like
so this is the first example on that
list case number one
this was the IP address that had over 2
000 domains on it
so the red dots are the actual domains
the green being the mining variant and
the blue being the IP address
and so from a visual perspective this is
what that server looks like and how it's
mining the little blocks are the areas
that I'll zoom in on
just to give a bit of context so you can
see what we're actually talking about
that being the IP address and that being
the over 2000 domains hosted on it and
interestingly these are all Iranian
and the other side of the coin showing
the mining variant
in this case it was fisacral.com
so continuing to visualize and to to
show the world what I think if crypto
mining looks like from my my patent
perspective I took a look at one of the
other IP addresses
and this one had an interesting strategy
so it was a single IP address of course
with 238 domains split perfectly across
two mining variants
and just to zoom in and give that
context we see the IP address all the
domains and all the domains with that
specific variant on it
another pretty picture of it all and
this one actually being an endpoint
that's a Google CDN
so
it's an expected output in terms of all
the different domains and all the vastly
different variants used across these
domains so as opposed to it being a
single IP address it's actually a Google
endpoint
and here you can see all those domains
and all those different variants tied to
it
a closer screenshot giving that context
so instead of actually showing you know
more patterns of IP addresses and
hosting
from an IP perspective this is it from a
domain categorization perspective and
this one I found particularly
interesting so this is a single IP
address with 116 domains on it hosting
crypto mining
but all the variants on this being auth
mind which is the consensual one
so whoever's running the server and
running these sites is doing it
ethically as possible as everybody would
have to consent to it and that makes
sense if you look at that domain
categorization at least in the top
picture
it's all around shopping and so these
sites are less transient less dodgy been
around a lot longer and have been
categorized valid
and so it makes a lot more sense having
a look at these patterns
on the other side
a domain categorization example of a
site that's certainly not running
anything consensual shows you what that
pattern would look like we've got 92
different domains
and all sorts of different
categorizations and different variants
within them
and yeah definitely not uncommon due to
the transient nature of these domains
most of them being uncategorized and the
ones being categorized being categorized
as potentially unwanted software and
pornography
next I thought I'm going to plug this
into multigo and have a look at these IP
addresses themselves and see what
they've been up to
so we know they're running crypto mining
variants but what other dodginess has
been going on
and so using that the virus total API
key I can get two types of data back
detected communicating samples so
samples that have communicated with IP
address or actually downloaded samples
plug it in
gives me some interesting stuff and so
this IP address in particular is a
particularly naughty one
it was number six on that list of the
top ten
and it hosted 111 domains with crypto
mining but it actually had about 12
different hashes detected to it so
whoever was running the server was was
up to a lot more
than just hosting crypto mining they had
all sorts of other malicious campaigns
going on there
and I thought this is probably an area
where there's potential for more
research seeing what's going on with
these IP addresses and the ones that are
diversifying their campaigns
so the last area I'm going to talk about
is the particular coin itself
a particular area to dig into
and that being jse coin
so JC coin was third highest on the list
of most common variants
and this one required a little bit more
effort outside of my data frame so I
just created a new data frame just with
the JSC coin mining variant
and pulled HTML from all of those URLs
there were 1 700 of them
and the way that the way the JSC coin
minor loads
it actually has the users account number
in it so you can start tracking the user
themself so we can see the bottom four
all have the same account number being
one one two one seven three and so this
gives me some insight into
the campaigns running
not so much the user himself but I can
see how many different sites they have
working for them and whether or not
there's actually any value to it
so we're going to have a look at one one
two one seven three as an account holder
and see if this is actually profitable
as well as a couple others
it turns out one one two one seven three
had eight domains
working for him whereas 15838 had 228
different domains with his user code so
this guy's got a lot of domains
running you know running sites
code embedded and I got wondering is he
making any money of this or he or she is
is as profitable
and quite interestingly JSC Cohen who's
also since closed down
offer a developer API key that lets you
query balances
so having a look at 15838
um
well before I even get to his balances I
took a look at every single one of those
domains and every single one of the
domains
was this landing page with that domain
for sale
an embedded Bitcoin exchange link
an advertising Banner and the mining
script embedded so whoever's running
this was really trying to diversify
there Revenue not very pretty not very
good looking
and that really
proved it in these balances because
15838 had a USD balance of 55 cents
regardless of those 228 sites with the
with the mining script embedded maybe he
or she is withdrawing those funds I'm
not too sure the other one we saw the
one one two one seven three
had a negative balance so definitely not
not making a whole lot of cash doing
this
so I thought what I would do then is
have a look and see
actually who is out of the out of the
user accounts that I do have access to
who does have some money in the bank and
one of the instances
about being account number 9250 had two
and a half thousand dollars in his in
his JSC balance which really got me
wondering what what site is this guy or
girl running
and it turns out it was the re the brand
money can't buy
um that no longer exists and it was
ranked yeah over 300 million 30 million
sorry in Alexa so not a very popular
site but somehow that balance was pretty
high
so the conclusion to draw from this is
who knows where the rest of those funds
are coming from because it's very
unlikely that it was from crypto mining
so with that
I will send everybody off to T with a
couple of wild well a couple of
conclusions and next steps so the world
of crypto jacking is is wild it's
decentralized there are so many
different variants and so many different
miners out there that there's really a
lot of space to explore and research
more
yeah yeah
especially since coin I've and JSC coin
are gone there's there's a lot of place
to rerun this and see how what the
ecosystem looks like now and who's
taking up that space
um there's also areas to look at in
terms of crypto mining on phones mobile
phones
as well as the into the profitability
you saw at least JSC coin didn't seem to
be
as well as
deeper trails around those individual IP
addresses what they're up to what
they're hosting and are they
diversifying with other malware as well
as into any specific variants
and so any questions comments or insults
I could see it from the source code
so I could pull all the different URLs
Associated to each user account
yeah
but now yeah they've closed down too so
that's that
yeah
well
so what's really important to me was
really the data analysis of it was being
able to have the problem and to how am I
going to figure this out and how am I
going to crawl the internet for a
specific concept a specific term without
using Google and take that and put it
into a data frame manipulate data so
believe it or not these are the
highlights from my research
I could have gone into a lot of more
other areas that I didn't include that
would have knocked everybody out so yeah
these were the highlights from that yes
no
not from my not from the limitations of
my research so there are lots of things
I left out I couldn't cover I couldn't
cover
um assembly
I couldn't cover
obfuscation this was really the bare
minimum and from here it's a point to
potentially research more
through University through University
through academic
um
no not really unfortunately
fortunately not
so I mean that's really decentralized
and that's on an ISP level
and I don't think anybody I don't think
anybody's actively hunting and looking
for them it's really sort of up to the
individual to get those browser
extensions and those lists to protect
yourself but from for what I covered it
and what I found nobody's nobody's
really looking at that level
yes
yep
exactly yeah
then you miss it so the no coin updates
periodically in fact even daily I think
that list so this is definitely point in
time
and it is that game of cat and mouse
signature based what you find today you
won't find tomorrow
yeah well you wouldn't really be aware
of it
unless you are running some sort of
detectors a blocker
that's why a lot of these sites here are
out there the Alexa rank sort of even
though Alexa's gone to a lot of these
Technologies are done
was the area I was looking are these
popular are these sites that we know of
well that I know and the answer was
really no besides the Pirate Bay
so it was from what I found it was
webmasters
who had signed up to the consensual
service
the consensual
variant
so no one seemed to be offering
consensual services with an unconsensual
variant
so some coin Ivan Monero being by far
the most prevalent gives you the option
go coin Hive and do it unconsensual
we'll go auth mine same currency same
rate but doing it ethically and
consensual
um I don't only the JSC one that I
looked at in that one said user that had
one banner and one
one embedded script for every single
endpoint but other than that
unfortunately not believe it or not yeah
I mean this research took me in
the ballpark of
nine months to
to cover it all so lots of areas to to
go deeper if if anyone is interested and
and if anybody wants all the commands
all the the pandas the Jupiter notebooks
the
the other neo4j queries everything is is
open and free I'll share that happily
all right thank you
oops
followers
sure
sweet cool can you guys hear me
I
cool thanks for coming to my talk
So today we're going to speak about a
special bug that affects a lot of smart
contacts and there was over one billion
dollars at risk during its peak and this
bug was also awarded the world's largest
bug Bounty ever paid ever so let's get
into it
so
just a bit about myself I'm ashikamin
I recently became independent a few
months ago but before that I was working
at Isidro for two years that's where I
learned about smart contracts and I
think some of the isider guys are around
so if they are you should definitely
listen to them they're super duper
talented and produce like the most
amazing work so shout out to isiro
um in my spare time I like to play ctfs
and I play Under the team name tested
Stick Sandwich the team is just me I'm
the whole team
um but I don't play for points so I just
do it for learning just for fun and when
I do have anything like noteworthy I
will write about it on my blog so
at ashik.za you can see all of my CTF
blog posts and there's also just social
media handles if you guys ever want to
get in touch so Twitter is probably the
best
um I don't really like this code this
code is
full of spam so I'll probably miss your
message but Twitter is pretty good
beyond that I also post about my
research so a lot of my research is
about bug bonus so during my time at
isilo I focused on bug disclosures and I
kind of posted all of the different bugs
that I've disclosed over time so today
we'll be speaking about one of the bugs
I disclosed and escalated as well so
the bug is about booking smart contracts
and in particular speaking proxy
contracts but to get to it I'm kind of
going to build up all the requirements
that we need to talk about a bit right
so I'm going to intro smart contracts
into the requirements that we need for
the bug speak about the exploit speak
about the impact and then talk about
escalation and then later then we can
talk about impact and any of the
remediation
cool so what are smart contracts right
so IBM says smart contracts or programs
on the blockchain and they run with
three determined conditions are made but
I mean you can Google it and you'll find
10 000 definitions but basically there
are blockchain programs right but what
does that mean so
usually people talk about smart
contracts as
analogous to vending machines
so
the reason they use this analogy right
because vending machines don't have this
idea of a con right so on their own
vending machines don't do anything so
until someone comes up and puts some
money in selects an item then this is
some kind of output but so smart
contracts sort of Behaving the same way
there's no notion of con job so they
won't act on themselves right there has
to be some entity interacting with a
contract before something happens so
there's usually some kind of external
either human being or even just a script
that's running
more importantly a smart content has two
very important things and that's just
code and state so the code is compiled
by code but we can write it in any
language so solidity Viper and there's a
couple of old ones too
but the state
yeah so the state is the other part of
it and the state is basically the
storage of the contract and that's just
holding all the states variables so
anything important related to like
metadata or anything else right
cool so because smart contracts live on
a blockchain and not just on a server
somewhere it inherits a lot of
properties but the main three ones for
today are irreversible transactions so
when you interact with any smart
contract or anything on the blockchain
there's no way to reverse the
transaction so
once it's done it's finalized right so
if you are an expert at blockchain you
will argue with me and say
it's not true because you can
technically Fork the chain and pay
someone pay all the miners to get it
right
but like for today's purpose it's not
really true right so we can just call it
irreversible
and then the next property uh is atomic
transactions and this just means that
transactions happen as ease so it either
happens altogether or none at all right
and this is very important so if your
code hits a revert at some point later
in the stack the entire thing goes
divides back basically and there's no
State changes committed so that just
means that everything happens at once or
none at all
and then the last property is immutable
code
and
this is the most important month for
today
so immutable code just means that once
you've deployed your bytecode there's no
way to change it right it's there
forever and
it's just never going to change you
could hard code some parameters to pause
your contracts but there's no way to do
anything else
uh there is
a special Edge case of immutability and
that's called self-destruct so there is
an instruction on the blockchain that
you can use specifically for ethereum in
ethereum style chains where you could
wipe out all of the state and wipe out
all of the code so in that sense it's
not super immutable because it's either
on or off right but you couldn't edit
the code
so I mean if you're a Dev which I think
some of you guys are you might be
now who wants to write immutable code
that's like really scary right so this
has been an issue I mean I try to get
this graph where
I'm trying to show that there's been
three billion dollars worth of damage
that's already been taking place because
of immutable code
but I couldn't get an exact estimate
because there's also things like private
key compromises and insider trading so
it might be higher but the point is that
it's a high number
in the billions
so there's a very real need for
upgradability
but unfortunately this is a double-edged
sword because upgradability comes with
its own issues that cost even more money
to be lost
so
to talk about upgradability and how it
works we have to first talk about how
smart contracts communicate with each
other at all right and the first way is
a DOT call
so that call works in the same way you
might think a normal computer computer
program works and that's just by one
contract calling another one and the
state changes
committed to the call to the contract
that we called
like
uh pretty straightforward so as an
example in the slide
if you had a call transfer the token
balance on contract B state would be
updated
the next goal is delegate call and
this is basically what's called a code
copy right so instead of the state
changes competing on the initial
contract so the Target contract is
converted on the initial contact line
and
what this means is the code at Contract
B is copied and those State changes
applied to contract a
so you can just think of delegate call
as copy
and this two things we can use together
and form some kind of mini architecture
and this will be enough to have an
upgradable pattern right so
what we do is we separate the bytecode
from the state by using two separate
contracts with respect to one or the
other
so
we call the proxy contract the one that
holds the state and the logic contract
the ones below the bytecode
so if at some point we find some buggy
issue in the logic contract we can
upgrade the logic contract by simply
pointing to a New Logic contract at the
bottom of the slide this is like a tiny
diagram
cool so those are two ingredients that
we have we have upgradability and we
have
self-destruct but the last ingredient
that we need for our bug is just to talk
about initialization so when you deploy
a smart contract there's a Constructor
that runs which is the normal function
that you consider in a normal computer
programming
but in this case
because State and the logic are separate
we need to initialize the proxy
contracts separately so we need to
assimilate a Constructor to get the
state across
so the way that works we just hard code
a special function and make sure it only
runs once
and usually just like a normal
Constructor there's access control that
happens
that gets provided to different users
when the initialization takes place
cool so
this is the first iteration of the bug
and before we talk about the diagram and
have X actual exploit works we need to
just talk about the assumptions that we
need to make so in this case we need to
assume that our logic contract has some
kind of delegate call
right so just taking on that assumption
there's an exploit that we can do
so one is that we check if the logic
contract has been initialized because if
you remember
the state of the logic contract is not
important in our architecture at all
so we can additionalize the logic
contract get any of the access consoles
needed if it's been initialized
and then we can deploy our own contracts
because it's permissionless anyone's
allowed to deploy contracts and in this
context we can include a self-destruct
instruction
so what we could do is using this
delegate call that we assumed we could
upgrade the logic contract and destroy
it
right so what does that look like
so once the delegate calls performed our
bytecode ethology contract is wiped the
logic state is wiped so this just means
that the proxy points to nothing right
and this is the first iteration of the
brick
but
this is just temporary so it's only the
first iteration and the Plexi
administrator could come in and say hey
I've seen the brick as kind of an issue
but no problem we've included
upgradability on purpose so we can just
go in and upgrade the proxy point to a
New Logic
sorted out
cool so let's just chat about impact
even though it's only a temporary brick
it's still pretty bad so the logic
contract is permanently destroyed right
once it is destroyed there's no way to
get it back because transactions are
irreversible as we
um the assets that are on the epoxy
itself so if you have I have a much
million dollars worth of tokens those
are not accessible at all while the
proxy is pretty so until an
administrator comes through and upgrades
the contract it's locked in
and this could also be made more severe
if there's a time lock right because we
have this sort of trust admins to not
just hot swap our logic at any time so
we sometimes there's a time lock
involved where you have to commit a code
for maybe seven days or 14 days and
people are allowed to check out what the
code is doing before it's applied so
your assets might be locked up for a
little while
and the next thing is epoxy knob so when
the proxy is damaged and just becoming a
brick there's no hard-coded diverts
right so the code just Maps through and
that just means that any calls to the
proxy itself after the brick means that
there's just nothing happening so if
access controls are relied on the proxy
then we just bypass those access
controls and this happened in rbv2
and then the last one is just
reputational damage which isn't like a
real big issue but I mean I wouldn't
trust my money with someone this code
got big fight
cool uh so let's talk about profit
the first profit mechanism is exploiting
the knob so in Ave V2 their contracts
are vulnerable to this exact bug and if
it was exploited it is possible to steal
a couple million dollars out of the
different contract because there was an
up through the access control
um
but it never happened though because
there was someone who disclosed
responsibly there was actually no
exploit so we'll go
the next way is shorting the lock token
so if your contract has a bunch of
native tokens ftt token or any other
token you could show it the token
beforehand exploit the contract and then
of course panic and you'll make a lot of
money this also has never happened
before but it is some way to make money
and then the best case is responsible
disclosure which is sort of what happens
in each case with this bug right so for
rbv2 in the example uh the Whitehead got
paid twenty five thousand dollars for
disclosing which is not bad
um
it's a sort of on par with critical bugs
of web 2 right
cool so we already spoke about the admin
upgrading to a fresh logic contract but
if you're a bug bunny hunter
you could think cool what are some of
the things you could do to fix the bug
if you find it and one way is to just
initialize the contact directly without
using your malicious contact
right so that just means we're going to
pick the contract as is but not in a
malicious way
and then petrifying the logic contract
so that just means as you deploy the
contract The Constructor automatically
initializes the logic so that no one
else can reinitialize it
Okay so we've done good we made twenty
five thousand dollars we prevented a
couple million from being stolen uh the
admin is a bit annoyed but they've
upgraded the code their code but we can
do a little bit better
so when I say a little bit better
there's a special branch of proxies
where we can escalate the temporary
permanent one
and that's the uups proxy so how does it
work
it's very similar to our original epoxy
but with a couple differences and the
main idea behind is to highly optimize
the proxy itself and what that means is
that the upgrade mechanism is moved from
the proxy to the logic
so this just also means that the proxy
itself has no right functions at all so
the only way to interact with the state
is to delegate delegate go into the
logic concept
and
everything else sort of works as is the
initialization provides access control
as usual
um and in the main point of the UPS
proxy is that the upgrade itself has
delicate which
so
this is what the upgrade mechanism looks
like
and only two main steps one is to check
that we have authorization to perform an
upgrade and the second one is to perform
the upgrade itself right so authorize
upgrade once initialized you get those
controls to do it
cool
looking at the upgrade mechanism we can
see this delicate goal right in this
delegate call is
allowed to run at any time provided is a
bit uh send some data in
and this just means that anyone that
upgrades can always perform a delegate
call right and if you remember this is
performed on the logic contract
cool so the actual exploit for permanent
trick performs in the exact same way as
the previous one where if it's not
initialized okay initialize it with her
own malicious contract and call a
self-destruct
so everything looks the same but the
differences are in the way the actual
impact works
so part of the impact is that the proxy
now points to a logic that is
permanently destroyed and the proxy
permanently points to nothing which
means there's no strain changes again
so any of your assets are gone forever
right
and updated impact so
one of the main things that's different
is that the proxy itself points to
nothing permanently the similar impact
is that the logic contract is
permanently destroyed
and the third is that your assets are
locked forever so if you have a couple
hundred million let's go on forever
and then plug synapse are working in the
same way too
cool uh so
when I was working at iocyto I disclosed
this bug to five companies two of these
are not mine but two of them were also
undisclosed so I just thought something
with other pictures on the top right
hand side is from ddub and at the bottom
is John Taylor
and just on these five contacts alone
we managed to save over 15 million
dollars from being hacked right and at
the time
uh I thought cool this is probably a bit
more of a widespread issue so I spoke to
Kyle it was my boss at the time and we
decided to escalate this issue a bit
further
and we hosted a meeting with open
Zeppelin which is the author of the uebs
proxy and when I spoke to them
we just told them hey you know look we
found these five contracts it might be
an issue
they said yeah actually someone came to
us a couple days earlier they found the
same issue and we've started the
remediation process and
that process was demonstrating every
single blockchain and they found 150
other contracts that were vulnerable
uh so luckily they found it right
but
what did they do they detected all of
their contracts across different chains
they updated the source code to include
a 55 logic so that all of it is fixed in
the future and they've monitored their
solution so basically every time there's
a new deployment
they will check whether or not they're
vulnerable and just fix the
vulnerability as inside so favor
so
you might be thinking will be done like
everything so that there's just no more
bugs
they've detected everything on every
chain
source code is updated they've
monitoring for new uh vulnerable
contracts surely there's nothing else
and except it was just one more bug
right there was one more and that
affected wormhole
so
Wormhole was vulnerable to this exact
bug in a slightly nuanced way
we're an anonymous Whitehead found
700 million dollars at risk and just for
the disclosure alone they got paid
10 million dollars
I wasn't the white that they got the 10
million if it wasn't me I wouldn't give
this talk I would be on the beach
somewhere or something
um
but yeah cool
cool so that's it for me the last couple
takeaways is just that part of the
reason this bug slipped through everyone
was that it wasn't a code level bug so
all the top auditing firms trailer bits
open Zeppelin everyone missed this bike
because it is a state dependent bug
right and what this means is if you're
on the sort of looking one way and no
one is looking the other way so if
anyone's interested you should 100 start
learning how smart contracts work and
I'm sure you could find some of your own
bugs
cool I hope you enjoyed the talk
I'm happy to take any questions too
100 so there's a bunch of different
online materials
um
I can send you a list personally but
I've mainly focused on trading from the
security side so there's some more games
where you can learn about solidity and
you can learn about how vulnerabilities
work on Solarity and plenty of ctfs for
sure cdfs can definitely upscale and
find these bugs for yourself
yeah
so the question was is there any way we
could find these bugs automatically and
always remediate them as is yeah
um so not right now not that I know of
any um the idea is mostly Grassroots so
as bugs are discovered they usually come
up with blog posts and talk about how
the bug was discovered how to remediate
it what to do next
and unfortunately
most people don't like to disclose their
bugs too right I've worked with people
and they've asked me very
you did not publish a certain bug that
I'm sure affected another contact so
there's no real easy way unfortunately
but hopefully like with incentivizing
like 10 million dollars worth of bugs
I'm sure it'll come out
not at the stage
yeah I mean I think the nice thing about
bhagbanes is that you can just drop most
of your assumptions about any kind of
library or any contact lens if you think
this one thing is secure it's it might
not be right I mean Wormhole had 700
million and looking at Walmart on its
own I might think cool 700 million is
quite a lot of money I'm sure it's safe
but they got like three times for 300
million in a different case so
um you could start anywhere you want
really and I think the main thing is
just to do some upskilling in the
beginning for genetics and once you're
comfortable with that and
whatever you feel
comfortable do you mind explaining zero
trust
that's true
yeah absolutely I mean the main thing is
that different functions have different
access levels right different access
controls you don't want anyone being
able to upgrade the contact or
um so you can definitely bake in Access
Control for certain addresses for
certain accounts
um but not everyone does this and that's
why they get hacked and that's why this
three billion dollar is gone but uh yeah
I mean the code is quite genetic so it's
quite granular in the sense that you can
hard code any kind of Access Control
that you want and prevent certain
messages and prevent certain calls or
delegate calls or any kind of message
you want but you'd have to hard code
that in depending on your needs
cool thanks guys