good afternoon everybody this basically
is a continuation of what Ellie and dave
has talked about in all kinds of details
so what we want to show here is analyzed
some of these schemes actually a subset
of these schemes and look at how they
perform in some realistic network
scenarios we specifically consider two
types of IP passed without mechanisms
one is one of the simplest ones look pre
alternate and a second one is what I
think alia pointed out as medium complex
u-turn alternate the kinds of
predictions we look at is a pure link
failure that means we assume that when
you detect a local failure then it is a
link failure and use our alternate next
are based on that but we usually cannot
distinguish between router and Link
belly or so if the neighboring router is
really the one that failed then actually
we may see some loops we may not see it
in all cases but at least in some cases
to protect against that we can do a
router plus link failure protection
basically we do not use the neighboring
router as the next half okay so that of
course reduces the number of cooperates
but that avoids getting into any
possible loop situation when the router
actually did pale in terms of
performance measures the first one that
you look at is the coverage or
efficiency essentially we just want to
say that if there is a failure if there
wasn't any IP passed it out then some
amount of profit will be lost for some
period of time we may debate up with it
is 200 millisecond 500 milliseconds or a
few seconds but until the IGP
convergence happens we will have some
failures and how much of the traffic can
be saved by doing this IP faster around
convergence by the way the same thing of
course we could do when using mpls the
faster it out but I am NOT going to
cover that at least about what this car
since we are only talking about IP
passed it out in terms of the second
point is in terms of from for a service
provider perspective is that what is the
cost of providing this this IP faster it
out for example someone
could say that okay we can provide this
great 50 millisecond convergence but you
have to keep one hundred percent more
capacity in the network then I don't
think that most of the service providers
will be interested in that so what we
wanted to see is that if we do some of
these mechanisms then how much extra
capacity do we need in the network in
order to actually make it work all right
we consider two networks we name them
network one and network to the first one
is a IP backbone network with 36
doubters and about 49 links in this case
we have a point-to-point traffic matrix
between every pair of routers and this
network and traffic matrix is roughly
similar to an existing network and this
is the one of the ones we will look at
the second one is what we call network
to which is a boat a combination of
backbone and access network and this is
one of the networks actually we similar
to actually one of the networks that he
planned for future in both cases as I
said that we have a network and traffic
matrix for network one we also wanted to
see that if we can quit the network a
little bit we change the topology little
bit add some links here and there and by
doing that if we can improve the
convergence okay now in terms of what is
the meaning of I guess coverage one
could define copper ideas how many
destinations are reachable during this
failure condition that's one way of
looking at it but we really want to look
it and we got it from a traffic for
points point of view because we have
seen that there will be some
destinations which are not reachable but
they are not carrying any traffic but is
there may be a small number of
destinations which are not reachable but
they may be carrying a very large amount
of traffic so what you really want to
know is for a given failure scenario we
define X as the amount of traffic that
will be lost if we did not do pastor
doubt and why is the amount of traffic
that would be lost if we did do pass
figure out that means that is the case
where we do not have an feasible
alternate next time okay and the
efficiency will be X minus y which is
the amount of traffic that is lost
divided by the total amount of traffic
that could potentially be lost expand as
Y over X that's a simple enough major
now important thing to notice that this
is not uniform in any
network we see that there are many links
where this number could be hundred
percent but there could be a few links
when this number could be say ten
percent or something pretty small okay
so what we will show here is the overall
average over the network and we average
about all possible failure scenarios in
one case all single link failures in the
other case all single router failures
okay these are some initial results and
for Network one if we did only Luke pre
alternate then we saw that in terms of
traffic the efficiency was about thirty
three percent if we do look free and you
turn on turn it that is a big jump at
least in this example the jump was from
thirty three percent to eighty eight
percent now of course that is not true
for every network like just as you see
down there for network too we did the
exact same study we saw that even with
Luke free we could go to eighty-nine
percent which probably is quite
reasonable already and if we do of
course Luke pre plus you Tron there was
one hundred percent coverage by the way
we did say that in this example there
are a few destinations that are not
reachable but those destinations are not
getting any traffic under no failure
condition so we did get hundred percent
coverage even with very small
destinations not being reachable now
another thing that we did is that in
network one since we knew as I said like
the good part of the network coverage is
very high there are some trouble spots
in the network where coverage was not be
getting very very well so we added some
strategic links in there and we saw that
there could be a jump for example with
Luke pre it goes to forty three percent
and Luke pre plus internet goes to
almost hundred percent active
ninety-eight percent we did actually
other studies for example as they
pointed out that we could solve this
problem using it or design and we can
actually in this particular network we
did at the potential design where we
could change things efficiently so that
both kinds of coverage could be close
two hundred percent so that again is
something we can have in their back
points back pocket but from a network
provider perspective what I would like
to see is that we don't want to change
our network design just to fit in for
this IP past it out we would like the
algorithms to be fast enough but of
course not too complicated but I gardens
to be smart enough so that whatever
topology we give it should be able to
solve that so from that perspective i
think i can say that only look pretty
simple it has lots of advantages but it
is not the predictable that is in if we
are lucky we have very good coverage if
you're not lucky we may not but if we do
at least in this case Luke creeper
scooter or not just you turn some of the
other algorithms based on tunnel or
directed forwarding they could also give
very close two hundred percent coverage
we don't have to worry about right or
top / topologies we will always get that
kind of proper edge okay now that one
was a simple picture we only looked at
link barriers now let's make it more
complicated what happens if we also want
to protect against router failures okay
that's one thing that we want to show
here the second thing we want to show is
that we may not have passed it out
throughout the whole network we may have
only in the backbone so we show the case
where if we have it in backbone only and
or if we have both in backbone plus
access and this is the network to which
was well behaved anyway so in the link
failure case we get close two hundred
percent in all cases except that if we
did it in the backbone only and we
average about all backbone and access
link failures then it goes down to about
seventy two percent in this case
actually the backbone router was doing
past ipf a straight out so traffic going
from backbone to access was mostly being
being actually saved only the traffic
coming from the access to the backbone
side that was not being saved and that
that cost this drop in efficiency now if
we go to the last two rows that's where
things are more complicated that is we
are not going to use a next hop which is
our neighboring router with the
anticipation that the neighboring router
may have failed okay so if we do that
situation then even for link failures
our coverage goes down to some extent
100% it still stays pretty high like
eighty-six percent or seventy four
percent those kinds of things and for an
outer failure if we do it in the
backbone only we got fifty four percent
and if we do back 1 plus access we got
sixty four percent so the basic bottom
line here is that protecting from outer
failure is
significantly more different difficult
than protecting us link belly or in fact
we did one more case which i am not
showing here that is the SR LG failure
so we looked at it large number of
guests are LG's network similar to an
existing network and there we saw that
clearly just as router failure is more
difficult than loom link failure is an
LG failure prediction is also more
difficult than link failure and usually
its coverage is less than that of link
failure but we are not showing all the
results at least in this case okay so
this is all about coverage the next item
is that how much extra resource do we
need like nothing comes for free okay
what is the price do you have to pay in
order to have this great i peep a
straight out in this example the pink
arrow shows the primary path of the
traffic before any failure happens ABCD
suppose the b2c link fails so B does a
local repair and it decides that I will
go through the path a BEF d ok that the
top part alright and that's fine after a
while all the notes have convergence and
if we are lucky then even after
convergence may be a will decide ok
let's use the loot a BEF d then things
will be perfect like we don't need any
extra bandwidth right the IGP readout
and faster doubt will be the same but in
many cases we see that that is not the
case like I GP readout may take a
completely different path because that's
based on the global knowledge it could
be going through agh and d alright so in
this case okay the way we designed our
network is that we keep enough bandwidth
for all primary traffic under no failure
then we consider all single link
Belliard and all single single router
failure cases and in something actually
we also do single s or LG failures we
don't show it here for all single
failure cases we want to make sure there
is enough can do it for IG period out
only ok only the lower part so now if we
do faster it out then we also have to
make sure that there is enough brand new
to the top part as well that is during
the fast straight out and the main thing
that I'm going to show is that what is
the Delta how much more do we need in
order to do faster it out this is one
example only
in this example we did actually I gb
passed it out only in the backbone the
link utilization limit we had was
eighty-five percent under normal
condition as well as IDP read out all
sing the link and single film router
failures scenarios now if we did only
igp route we needed in this example
network 829 OC 48 and about five seventy
five thousand a 44 48 miles okay now if
we did the same problem with I GP +
fasted out and this number went up from
a 29 28 64 this actually is only four
percent increase so this actually is a
positive result that we can get was
passed it out but you don't need fifty
percent 100% mode bandwidth and this in
this example we needed four percent more
bandwidth one more thing to note is that
if we looked at the OC 48 miles then the
increase was about seven percent which
kind of means and is in this case when
we have to put extra bandwidth we tend
to put it on longer links in order to do
this thing and so the bandwidth miles
wide the increase is somewhat more but
also have to note that in this example
we are doing router failure prevention
so there are many cases where it is it
was the faster it out was not being used
so if we did use fast it out if we could
change the topology such that fast
readout will be used in all cases then
these numbers will go up to some extent
but still the good news is that this
probably not go down go up from four
percent to fifty percent it probably be
something in the ten percent range which
is what probably is acceptable because
my guess is that most service providers
should not take the fact that if we say
that IP passed without or for that
matter mpls-tp fast without takes fifty
percent more capacity well it doesn't
another thing that we can do is that
since we can have qos in the network we
may not even need to protect the whole
band do it during this IP pass straight
out and this happens only for a short
time maybe a few second or maybe even
five hundred milliseconds or so alright
so for that period of time we could make
the network design to to have something
say one hundred and ten percent
utilization which means that if this ten
percent of the traffic will be dropped
on the floor but that will be the bottom
% only the best effort traffic will be
dropped if we have to us in the network
those are the ones which are probably
not to be looking for past it out the
ones that are looking for faster doubt
is probably the top 20 30 maybe fifty
percent of the traffic and they will
still be prevented by this mechanism but
the beauty of that is that we can get
that like if you look at the last column
and the second column the difference is
very little we can get IP passed without
almost for free again it may not be true
for all topologies and all conditions
practice in one example we show here
looks pretty pretty I guess convincing
all right actually this is my last life
so I think I am being on time the main
ideas we have here is that if we do fat
I guess fast it out then what the simple
scheme to use would be loop pre
alternate it doesn't really depend on
your neighbor to do anything special and
only point drawback is that there are
many topologies where its coverage may
not be high enough like at least as high
as we would desire if we add more
complexity like you turn alternate or of
course that matter any of the other
algorithms then coverage can be made
very high maybe close two hundred
percent but still one difficulty is that
if we have to have a router avoiding
alternate paths then then it is it will
be more difficult to achieve the same
level of coverage now also it is
possible to have the IP passed without
in the backbone and we can get some of
the benefits we don't necessarily have
to use it on on the whole network but of
course if we can do it h2 edge then then
benefits is even better and and the
final point is that the extra capacity
needs of IP pass without was not not
very high at least in one example which
means that it will be oh I'm sorry okay
okay all right now I'm not going to get
it okay I don't even need to point
anymore i'm all done okay all right so
that's that's about it and if there are
any questions I'd be happy to take that
okay we have a question here okay i'ma
render virendra here I'm interested in
knowing safe my network
it's a large connection connected
network and my network is converging
after a maybe a congestion collapse or
so and if I was doing a packet tagging
for my mission critical a delay
sensitive application like during the
event of conversions in my application
being tagged in inventive congestion how
would the wii convergence work i mean
would it have a higher precedence ok so
are you saying that if we do IP pass
without then our normal igp convergence
may slow down is that right be saying
how would how would that work with
packet tagging while my application is
trying to trying to use the trying to
use the link in an event of congestion
because what I'm doing is assigning
priority to my mission critical
application but and and my network is
trying to converge just recovering from
a maybe a congestion collapse or so
during the process of convergence and my
application which is has a higher packet
tagging and is trying to go over the
link how would the convergence work with
but you're still talking about IP
network not mpls right that's correct so
not all of your traffic needs the IP
faster ear out the better convergence
time right now the rest of it you are
willing to do what it does today which
is best effort which is it waits for the
network to finish convert you know waits
for the convergence tap and your drop it
for you know depending you know 50
milliseconds a couple seconds whatever
depending upon local and network so that
if you have the utilization of the links
be allowed to be higher or as goggin was
suggesting during the convergence time
that means well more more of your best
effort traffic is likely to get dropped
right and the mission critical as long
as it was within the necessary bounds um
would get the benefit from the faster
your app hmm ok is it does that answer
your question er um kinda we can take
this off fine ok thanks ok
okay well I'd like to thank our three
panelists for their description of this
analysis going ongoing research