let's start with masking so the first
paper is titled formal verification of
masked hardware implementations in the
presence of glitches by Roderick bloom
and his course peanuts it should both be
denied killing off her staff and mangled
and giving us winter Anna start to start
with a brief summary I want to start
with the vision that we had in mind when
we started working towards stopping so
that idea really was to create a formal
tool or common effort to pull tape mask
circuits as an input and with them tell
us whether it is securely masked or not
and if it's not securely masked people
want to this former tool to tell us
where things went wrong and why this
happened
so what happen is it seems so far with
our formal verification approach we can
verify glitchy circuits and just say a
chip because I'm really referring to
other implementations and not just to a
graphic way of expressing boolean
formulas our approach doesn't require
any intermediate modeling steps for
example - we implement this in software
but works directly on the netlist and
can be applied the different designs
design stages so when you first start to
implement your our two designs we can
already
in in our tool it will tell you if you
move it and in this example the biggest
example we have a first order protected
why do we actually need from the
verification of verification of mass
hardware limitations aren't there
supposed to be any secure masking
schemes so first of all we need to talk
about what is the secure of masking
scheme and we have a very very nice way
to express sectional resistance which is
covered by a roving model which goes
back to the private circuits paper of
each hideout and this basically
basically tells you that your
implementation is sectional resistance
if it is secure against problem is death
that can attest ability to place up to
deep probing needles on your circuit and
if the attacker cannot extract any
secrets
then it's secure in this problem model
and so with this masking scheme a
masking scheme is in some way a
projection of this rule set by these
probing models on the canvas of a masked
implementation so it gives you the rules
but the masking scheme itself is
implemented by designers of hardware so
there can be mistakes in the
implementation of these schemes and also
the digital design flaw that that that
takes this circuit as an input and
process it further until it can be
produced in both many tasks it to change
your netlist and also things came to
wrong there so so we have for example
masking schemes that look at at least
from best masking perspective or a more
modern way is from the from the sharing
perspective but in the end this is
always a manual process to met in these
schemes to the implementations so
implementation requires verification and
at least in theory there are two
approaches one can finger the first
approach to verify this mask circuits is
either use empirical verification which
is the predominant form and is widely
used in practice but there's also a
formal way of proving this and so the
empirical verification works as follows
so you take for example your
you're secure a supposably security
escort you like an oscilloscope - it in
to the ball land and expect sites and
information and then you run some
statistical analysis on the power traces
that will tell you whether it passes the
test or fails the problem with this
approach is that it's not conclusive so
if you don't find a flaw
you just don't know maybe you haven't
used enough traces to to test your
implementation and if a flaw is
detective you don't know if it's a real
flaw in a way it actually origins from
so it could be on everywhere from your
from the circuit it's also device
specific and it can hardly be used
during the design phase of your circuit
so how about formal verification well
for the picture would say more than 1000
words so in terms of formal verification
terms of practical form of verification
of mascot augmentations there's really
not much there so if you look at the
software side it would look a bit
differently but you know so in the
hardware's at least when you started it
was really not much there so and with
this set
I should also talk a bit about what we
don't do or what we try to avoid in this
in our formal approach so what we didn't
want to do is a heuristic approach so
testing for example specific specific
properties of for a certain marketing
scheme this would be again not
conclusive and person for me what has
become very much popular especially in
the software world is this notion of
composability
which allows you to verify smaller parts
of the circuit
inside this composability notion and
this will then tell you if you if all of
the parts is secure and to plug them
together then in the end to your whole
circuit will be secure so we didn't do
this because not all circuits or love
math implementations fulfill this
composability notion in a
straightforward way but this would be a
one meaningful extension to our approach
and as a matter of fact so we're living
in a really fast moving world so there's
already a paper on this so it is this
paper masking schemes in the best
physical defaults they first it all that
that's something very similar to our
approach but for this composability
notion so enough said about that we
don't do we actually do so we started
with this project about two years ago
and for a long time we were really
struggling to find something that really
works so we found some brooches that
looked very promising for first corner
and doing various effects but everything
fails for higher order so at some point
became really desperate until we
remembered the roots of our information
and computer engineering education and
so I think every student that that is
something like this has heard something
back if you're really desperate if
nothing works and just go for free
analysis and so this is what we tried so
but the interesting question is now what
is a free analysis of the circuit and so
when we neglect in time and look at the
circuit and I also want to use the site
to introduce two notation I'm going to
use in the rest of this presentation so
I always
that we have a secret that is masked
inside this variable SM this mask
pattern mask M s then we have some other
masks that are denoted with M variables
and then we have some variables that are
interesting or publicly known or
something else something that is not the
security relevant but also cannot
provide security like a mask to do and
these are these public variants of B
variables here so when we look at this
circuit and when we are neglecting time
then we can just write this as a potent
equation so this is there's nothing
about time behavior but just for the
moment so the next thing is is for
expansion and for those of you who
already heard about this is also called
the Walsh transform and the way this
works is basically we take is called an
equation and to map true to minus one
fourth to one and then we can write each
equation the very elegant form so we can
write a function over the input
variables X as the as to some of the
three coefficients times to create
correct characters and the spree eight
characters are nothing else than all
combinations are possible ordered
combinations of variables that we have
so how would this look like so we would
end up with an equation that looks
something like this so is alpha here are
my coefficients and then I add them up
together times all combinations of my
input variables X here so how does this
help well there is this lemma of J and s
it basically tells us a boolean function
is statistically independent if all
variables for all there is
it holds that the subset of these
separate variables
despite the empty set although the
Fourier coefficients should be zero so
what does this mean for our circuit so
if we accept SM here the equation s
times M s so as is our secret that we
want to protect but so when we looked at
the Fourier transformation of this
circuit then we see that for that we
only have nonzero coefficients for terms
where we have s joint with a mass
together so this would be insecure if
you would have an S alone here or an S
with a publicly non variable but so far
the circuit looks secure from our
perspective what's the problem with this
is say if you go to a bigger circuit
because they're kids and later on we're
going to it expand this to all possible
signal times then this really becomes
quite inefficient and yeah if it becomes
big enough then it gets impossible to do
this so in step of calculating the exact
Fourier spectrum our idea was to just do
an approximation of this spectrum
because so we just want to know whether
certain values are zero or not and so
with our approach it so we're doing an
approximation and this can can also come
up with some of those spikes here which
only can decrease our security so we can
come up with false alarms but if the
circuit is security mask and we do this
approach
you always say it's security this is
what we prove instead of verification
then works in in three steps the first
step is that we label our inputs
according to our Fourier analysis
so this basically means that we just set
the input labels here according to a
variable which is s joint with M s then
we propagate these labels according to
some rules which depends on the Fourier
spectrum of the of the functions that we
are calculating and then we check for
some secrets without any mosques in this
case secure
so this propagation rules that we have
quite simple for for a stable signal so
when we we don't talk about about timing
so we just label the inputs for
something for this but it's a meteor
according to the barriers we have in
there for nonlinear gates like the N so
we're creating this landing here where
we joined an empty set with the first
input set of the of them with the stable
set of the first input and stable set of
second input and then we're doing also
there's a point wise difference of both
it's like next one looks a bit
differently so for this we only do the
last part here where we do this point
where step difference and four registers
and all of just one input bits we just
propagate stable sets so up to now we
don't think Lexi time so I'm going to
change this now so let's talk about
so this is really something
hardware-specific and I want to discuss
this on a much simpler or in simple
circuit as we had before
this is really just to expose a masked
secret and and some mosques and so when
we look at the output of the first x-ray
we would get s extra M s because it's
what SMEs XOR M 1 and when we looked at
the output we basically get s extra M 1
because we cancel out a mess so this is
all secure up to now however if you
assume that in the next cycle would
process a different secret so we also
have different input signals but we
assume that this mass M 1 here arrived a
bit later than all the other signals
here what we get at the output is s hat
extraor m1 which but the problem is in
the probing model in this assume that an
attacker places probably need on your
circuit can continuously model what the
circuit is doing at this point so it
would not only get this this equation
here but it will also record the
equation from the cycle before and when
you combine this you can learn something
about the difference of the secrets that
you got before this then not secure it's
not what we want to have and if if the
signals then said again this flow
vanishes and this is basically what we
call a gauge so a temporary violation of
this proving assumption so in order to
also cover this we need to extend our
rules and we also
second set here which we call the
Trenton cell which is here denoted in
red and we just do the same thing as for
the stable set for non litigates we
already have a rule this really covers
the worst case so we have modified that
but for linear dates
we're also bitches can happen as you
have seen on the slide before we're
basically going to use the same
nonlinear be true as before and then for
registered as we say his fencing set
totally disappears because registers are
blocking one cycle from from the another
and so we then just propagate the stable
set so let's have a look at this on a
bigger example we have before at the
beginning and we just look at the
transient set because is a purely
combinatorial circuit so again we are
leaving the input this before and then
we apply or nonlinear propagation rules
also for the XOR gate so we get this
empty set the copy of the first impulse
copy of the second set of the second
input and then we also get the point by
step difference and so if we put or if
you're doing this for all gates here
what we can see is that this circuit is
indeed not secure for its range in
signals and finishes because we see that
we end up with signal combinations that
contain the signal or the secret without
any masks in them and this indicates a
flawed circuit so enough to fear me we
also took this approach and put it into
a tool and our tool chain works as
follows so we take a sex description for
example based on very low or VHDL passes
with an open synthesis tool which is
called theosis and what we get from that
is circuitry in JSON format that we are
going to process further so this
contains the gates into a wire so the
connections of the of the circuit and
then we need a bit of user interaction
here because the user needs to tell us
at the input of the circuit which
signals are critical which are secrets
which are mods which are which are
public signals and what is the maximum
protection order to them
I want this circuit to be tested against
so we take this information put it into
a Python script that that creates all
the propagation rules to talk to for for
with a concrete circuit so we're going
to verify the end with this and the
constraints we're going to call see
three sets over and this is them going
to tell us whether the circuit is secure
or not and if it's not secure we can ask
for where ways to follow kated and what
are the signals that produce the flaw so
with this implementation we support this
instance of our verification approach
with write a few exemplary circuits that
are out there so we started off with
verifying some basic building blocks of
master circuits like the ice W in the
Kitchener and gates which are known to
be thought and also of course indicates
this and we also tried some other
building blocks like fresh fruit
implementations and gate and the domain
are in masking and gate and for this
with this verification up to 45 for
different orders of the multiplier and
so in this diagram you can observe the
time and
the verification order for four
different orders of the NPA and as you
see the verification effort grows
exponentially but what's also
interesting to see is so finding the
flaw is much easier so this is also what
we observed in bigger circuits when we
actually found a flaw then we would
found this much faster than if we solve
this flaw game and run the verification
on this but of course we also tried it
against bigger circuits so we tried this
for example for Tomcat Jack s ports so
we're first order verification took
about 20 seconds for a verification
about 25 minutes files S box times APN
and biggest circuit was the main event
which took between 5 and 10 hours of
parallel checking in order to verify
this to be a secure circuit so this
brings me to the conclusion of the talk
and I want to end with a positive note
on the verification of masculine form of
education of masking so we really think
that there is hope for practical form of
verification of math circuits and that
this really can be counted only an
alternative but the replacement for
empirical and theoretical methods that
are nowadays the predominant form of
verifying this math circuit we feel that
that there's still a long way to go to
cover everything and to make this as so
efficient that we can improve complete
circuits and for higher protection
orders but there there's also lots of
room for improvement and one way to go
for example is this
possibility and the combined form of
this composability notion and so on so
there are really some ideas out there
how we can improve our approach this is
just a first step so thank you so we
have time for some questions you have a
circuit which is secure without glitches
and then with glitches it's insecure and
the circuit is very big then the problem
is that okay you have to decide do I
mean is it really insecure or not
because in practice I don't know if you
want to make it secure against glitches
it will be like no much bigger problem
registers but the thing is so we have
this table set rules and the strengths
and set rules and so the first thing
that we do when we practically verify
because it's really a tool that we use
when we going to implement new new stuff
then we so this is really a practical
tool that is already news the first
thing we do is we just test for this
table set rules this doesn't have this
huge exponential blow-up so this is
what's really much much faster than for
and also buying these trends in set
rules so this is the first thing we do
before we go to the transistor is their
scope ID to add some probabilities in
the in this setting like to say okay
what's the probability of actually
having a glitch like because I don't
know no so we don't take concrete signal
timings into account because this can
also completely vary so if you are going
to produce an ASIC for example and you
take two different devices then this can
also have completely different signal
timings
or let's put Barry in when you have
different environmental conditions you
could I don't think this would make
things easier actually so right now I
think it's better to just verify against
the worst case then taking create signal
time since account because also this
assumptions that you would have the
signal timings is not realistic so I
guess when you to orange checking is for
checking each secret like yeah this is
what we're doing with just modifying the
labels at the input but just removing
the other secrets like some with taking
a SS pots you have eight secrets in
there right and very fine against all
this if it is time to see what you want
to do is in parallel and so what we're
doing is we're taking all the
wavelengths that we would have but just
removing the seven other secrets thank
you public variables for instance or
you'll just remove the notes that we
keep the mosques okay because this is
what we need because it can also become
insecure because okay thank you okay
let's swing for speak here again
[Applause]