[Music]
iris scans belonging to all of his
authorized users and when Alice wants to
access the resource she takes a fresh
scan of her iris and tries to use that
to authenticate so her fresh scan is
going to be similar to but not an exact
match for the iris scan that bob has
stored so they're gonna need to do
something tricky another application is
authentication based on physical
proximity so here the passwords would be
something like noisy and low entropy
environmental meetings and this would be
probably useful in the very near future
when self-driving cars are everywhere
and they want to help one another
navigate their surroundings by sharing
information about what they see so in a
situation like this it would be pretty
important for these cars to prove to one
another that they're actually nearby to
prevent some remote attacker from
feeding them all falls in for
so authentication based on shared
imperfect secrets or passwords is a very
active area of research and we can sort
of categorize this work based on what
password problems it deals with so first
does it deal with passwords that are low
entropy and when I say that a password
has low entropy I mean that it's
possible to hit on the correct password
realistically by brute force enumeration
so maybe a 30 bit string I would
consider to have a lunchable
the second question is does this work
and deal with passwords that don't match
exactly and might have some noise so we
can see it the related work as partially
filling in this table the nicest cell in
this table is the high entropy exact
match cell and in that cell we have
privacy amplification so we still need
something because even though the
passwords are high entropy and exact you
can't they might not be uniformly
distributed so these privacy
amplification protocols are very
efficient but they pay for this
efficiency by having some leakage about
the password used and in the high
entropy situation that's totally fine
because there's so many bits of entropy
that's throwing out a few is totally
totally ok but because we have some
leakage we can't directly apply these
techniques to the low entropy setting so
in the low entropy scenario we have a
different set of protocols called
password authenticated key exchange or
pink and in these protocols it's very
important that there be no leakage at
all about the passwords so in particular
they even prevent offline dictionary
attacks by an active participant or a
man-in-the-middle so anyone who doesn't
know the password that sees a transcript
of
of execution that they either
participated in or just observed they
shouldn't be able to then use that
transcript to test their password
guesses so moving to the fuzzy match
setting in the high entropy scenario we
have information reconciliation and
robust fuzzy extractors but these also
have some leakage just like their exact
match counterparts and for the same
reason they don't translate into the low
entropy world and in fact the only thing
we have in the literature for the low
entropy fuzzy match setting is just
generic two-party computation in the
unauthenticated channels model so this
is this is something we can use really
anywhere in this table and it tends to
be pretty inefficient because it's so
generic
so in our paper we focus on this cell in
the table for the first time we
introduce a new primitive which we call
fuzzy paths but I thought to get a key
exchange or fuzzy peek and we define a
fuzzy pink and we give two efficient
constructions of this thing so next I
want to talk a little bit more about our
security definition as a pig so like I
told you before if Alice and Bob share
two passwords that are actually close
they want to be able to talk to what I
doubt there and as a result of this
conversation they want to both hold the
same high entropy session key K and any
active or passive man in the middle
should learn nothing at all about the
passwords or the key as long as that man
in the middle doesn't already know
some password that's close enough
if the two of them don't have passwords
that are similar
so maybe Alice's password is curiouser
and Bob's is can we fix it in this
situation they shouldn't end up agreeing
on a secret key and neither of them
should learn anything at all about the
other's password and this should be the
case even if one of them is malicious
and doesn't follow the protocol so there
are a few complications in defining a
fuzzy peak and the first of these is
that well for any key agreement protocol
it's very important that the protocol be
composable key agreements is never the
ultimate goal whenever you want to agree
on a key you probably want to then use
that key in a different protocol so so
you want to make sure that the protocols
remain secure even if other things are
also being executed the second
difficulty is that just like cake we
really need to be secured against
offline dictionary attacks we're dealing
with low entropy passwords so we want to
make sure that malicious participants
and men in the middle even if they'd
like save to transcripts they can't then
use that to test their guesses so the
approach we take is we generalize the
universally composable functionality for
peek given by kinetically V Katz Linds l
and Mackenzie and I'm not gonna tell you
anything more about this definition it's
the full definition from the paper so
next I want to tell you about our two
constructions so the first of these uses
regular non fuzzy pink together with
something called robust secret sharing
and the second uses garbled circuits and
some of you might find this pretty
alarming because I said earlier that I
really wanted to avoid using generics a
party computation inefficient and here
I'm saying I'm gonna use like one of the
most famous
Eric to party computation schemes but we
actually don't use it in the the
straightforward way we do that something
special specifically for fuzzy pink that
is actually pretty fast so these two
constructions even though both of them
realize fuzzy pink differ in a few ways
the first of these is what notions of
similarity between passwords they
support so until now I've just been
saying similar for it for some notion of
similarity and the llaves carpet circuit
construction actually supports any
efficiently computable notion of
similarity but the pink and robust
secret sharing construction is limited
to hamming distance the yamas garbled
circuit construction pays for its
generality
with lower efficiency and so both in
terms of the number of rounds and
computation it's more expensive so I
want to start by talking about the less
general but more efficient construction
and because we're talking about hamming
this distance I'm gonna assume that our
two passwords are of the same length so
this construction follows a very natural
templates
our two parties Alice involved they do
share a secret it's a problematic secret
but a secret nonetheless so we're gonna
have one of them without loss of
generality looks a Ellis pic the key she
wants to agree on with Bob and encrypt
it to Bob using their shared secrets as
the encryption key so using the password
as an encryption key and this is gonna
have to be some very special form of
encryption because this this encryption
is going to have to tolerate error in
the encryption and decryption keys it's
gonna have to work even if the
encryption key and the decryption key
are a little bit different but even
assuming that we have this magical
encryption we have the problem that's
the encryption key the password is low
entropy
and any eavesdropper who sees this
ciphertext is going to be able to really
narrow down the options for the session
key just by trying but just by going
through the password space and trying to
decrypt so we address this by turning
every single character of the password
into a high entropy key we're gonna
expand the entropy of every password
character and Allisyn that we're gonna
do this using pink so pink is a tool
that takes in low entropy objects that
match or don't match and gives the
parties high entropy objects that also
match or don't match based on whether
the low entropy objects dead Alice and
Bob are gonna run pink for every single
character in their password and whenever
the pass of the password characters
match they're gonna get back the same
team and whenever they don't they're
gonna get back different keys and at the
end they're gonna have this list of what
we're gonna call character keys high
entropy character keys that match or
don't match depending on where the
corresponding character said so one
crucial observation here is that it's
very important for neither Alice or Bob
to learn whether they agree on any given
character so imagine that Alice's
password is what I have here but Bob's
password is we can fix it so if Alice
learns whether she agrees with Bob on
any given character despite the fact
that she doesn't know her password close
to Bob's she's gonna learn that you know
his first character isn't P and for low
entropy passwords this is this is a lot
of leakage this is not acceptable so we
introduced a you see definition for a
new flavor of pink which we call
implicit only and this new flavor of
pink specifically has this
pretty that neither party learns whether
they succeeded in agreeing on a key so
they don't have key confirmation and one
of the famous paid protocols EK e two
actually has this proper game this
implicit only property and that's the
paper protocol that we use all right so
now when alice does this magic
encryption step instead of using her
password as the encryption key she's
gonna use her list of character keys and
bob is gonna use his elusive character
keys to decrypt so this magical
encryption really quickly it works
through a combination of robust secret
sharing of the message of the secret key
came together with a one-time pad
encryption of the secret sharing using
the character keys as a pad and this is
very similar to the code offset
construction of jewels and wattenberg so
I'm not gonna give you any more details
about this I'm gonna leave it at that
and next I want to talk about our llaves
carbothermic instruction so like I said
earlier this one is more general but
less efficient so one of the tracks
yesterday heard a lot about you asked
raffle tickets already so I'm not going
to spend too long introducing them I'm
gonna be minimalistic here
so yeah Scrabble circuits are a
two-party computation scheme where the
two parties play different roles one of
them is going to be a gobbler and one of
them is gonna be the evaluator so the
GAR player takes the function that they
want to compute and garbles it and she
then sends this garbled function or
garbled circuit to the evaluator and the
evaluator is able to evaluate this
garbled circuit and learn the function
outputs and there are a lot of steps
here I'm skipping but really high level
notice so the way we can use something
like this for quasi pink is just have
one of our parties garble a closeness
circuit so the circuit is gonna take
into two passwords us inputs compare
them and if they're similar enough it's
gonna output
you know Alice's chosen session key and
if the two passwords are too different
it's maybe not gonna output anything and
then Bob is gonna evaluate this the
problem with doing something like this
is that you have scrapple circuits offer
asymmetric security guarantees so
they're secure no matter what the
evaluator does the evaluator can be
malicious and still won't be able to
learn anything at all about Alice's
input apart from the actual computation
output but Alice the guard Blair has to
be something honest if she chooses to
instead be malicious there is a lot she
can do to screw things up she could for
instance just garble a totally different
circuit she could garble a circuit that
always returns the same key this fooling
Bob and to agreeing with her like no
matter what his password was so like I
just said yeah up there kids don't
guarantee correctness against a
malicious cobbler and they actually also
don't guarantee privacy against a
malicious cobbler
because if Alice garbled something along
the lines of a circuit that just returns
maybe a few bits of Bob's password once
she learns the function outputs she's
gonna learn information about Bob's
input that she shouldn't have learned
the upside is that JavaScript circuits
are actually really fast as two-party
computation goes there are a lot of
transformations out there that durin see
correctness and privacy in yowzer most
circuits against either party be
malicious but the downside of all of
these is that if you consider
pre-processing a part of the computation
the overhead is going to be pretty high
there's like a lot of cool works here
that I did
over the recent years there is one more
transformation which is called dual
execution which has a very small
overhead so it's only twice as expensive
as regular gas car what circuits but the
downside of dual execution is that it
gives one bit of leakage to the
adversary and especially in our setting
when we're dealing with passwords that
have very low entropy one bit of leakage
can be crucial we don't want that so we
modified the execution to eliminate this
leakage when it matters
specifically for fuzzy pink so all right
let's have Alice garbled is closed in
this circuit like we did before and
instead of outputting yes the passwords
are closed or no they're not closed this
circuit is going to output a yes or no
key so it's gonna output the yes key of
the two passwords are closed and the no
key of the art so she sends the circuit
over to Bob Bob is gonna evaluate it and
learn one of the one of the two keys and
because this isn't secured against a
malicious car player against malicious
Alice we're gonna do this whole thing
again in the other direction also
so now Bob gets to play the role of the
garb ler Alice has to play the role of
evaluator and as the evaluator she can't
cheat so what alice is gonna do once we
do both of these steps is she's gonna
take her own yes key she's gonna take
the one key that she learned from Bob's
circuit she's gonna XOR them and the
result is gonna be her session key and
Bob is gonna do the exact same thing on
his side so if both parties were honest
and if both circuits decided that you
know yes the passwords are close they
are close in this picture
then clearly these two are gonna
actually agree on a key if they're gonna
be exhorting the same key so are the
same two the same pairs of keys if if
the passwords are actually far then
Alice is gonna be using her own yes key
but Bob's no key and Bob is gonna be
using his own
yes key but Alice is no key so they're
gonna be exhorting two totally different
independent pairs of keys and they're
gonna end up with different session keys
now let's say Alice is trying to fool
Bob into agreeing with her well as the
garb worm she can cheat
she can make Bob you know get the get
hurt her yes key out of her circuit even
if his password is far away from hers
but since she can't cheat as the
evaluator there's really nothing she can
do to learn anything about Bob's yes key
this blue key over here so there's
nothing on malicious Alice can do to
agree with Bob when their passwords are
actually far so we can view what we just
did as a variation of dual execution in
the general case so dual execution has
very symmetric guarantees no matter what
the correct computation output is dual
execution guarantees that you know both
parties will either get the correct
answer or no that cheating took place
and it lets an adversary get one bit of
leakage we make a trade we say that okay
well when the computation output is yes
when the correct output is yes we're
gonna let the adversary still have their
one bit of leakage and we're also gonna
you know give up on correctness we're
not going to have any correctness
guarantees but in exchange we want
better things in the case that's the
correct computation output is known so
not only do we want a correctness
guarantee we also want to eliminate the
one
bitch so this actually turns out to be
the perfect trade-off for fuzzy pink
because in in fuzzy pink intuitively we
only care about security against an
adversary that doesn't already know the
password and if the adversary doesn't
already know the password then we're in
the know case so in the no case we're
guaranteeing that the adversary can't
learn anything about the password and
can't fool our parties into agreeing on
a key but in the yes case when the
adversary already knows a password
that's close enough the adversary can
fool the other party into not agreeing
with them which they can really do
anyway just by using a random thing as
as their password and they get to learn
one additional bit of leakage which is
also arguably okay because they already
have all the information they need in
order to agree on a key all right
so in conclusion there's been a lot of
work on key exchange based on the
imperfect secrets we're the first to
look at the low entropy fuzzy match
setting and we give you these security
definitions for this new primitive cause
fuzzy cake and two different
constructions which are on different
points on the sort of efficiency
generality curve so are probably useful
in slightly to friends scenarios all
right thanks everyone for listening
yeah
[Music]
right so a malicious man in the middle
gets to execute fuzzy pink with each of
our Alice and Bob if they want to and
each online execution gives them one
password yes but so he learns an end of
to clinically so he gets to basically
try to get this so he he gets both
answers not just a man's but that's
really as good as we can do something
like take can you say something about
the model and assumptions assume the
first instruction is any fake in a
second you see RS your random Oracle
what do you need we we do use ers and
something very close to the random and
actually the random Oracle in both of
them I think yeah okay thanks again
[Applause]
[Music]