their patience as we get starting to
have hopefully you're all in the right
room this is containers and no we won't
be talking about your mama step water my
name is el marques and I'm a technical
trainer for the Rackspace private cloud
I also do a lot of community evangelism
a lot of just going out and recruiting
new people to the industry so normally
this is where speaker gives you their
street cred right like they give you
their alphabetical pedigree you know I
haven't RHCs a Norwich de and none of
that matters today I stand before you a
newbie I am brand new to containers and
the way that they say it is the best way
to learn something is to get up and
teach it right put your money where your
mouth is
so that's what I'm here to do today
there are times that throughout this you
may have a question that I don't know
the answer to so this is where I ask you
how many of you have experience with
like lxd docker kubernetes all right you
see these guys that raise their hands
especially my friend there in the back
these are gonna be our subject matter
experts so you know what if you have a
question don't feel like I might go and
ask that I'm gonna embarrass her like
I'm okay being embarrass we have people
here we're here to learn so we're gonna
do today is we're gonna start a journey
and this hold hot got started when I was
asked to write a course on getting
served not certified in kubernetes not a
big ass except for the fact that I had
no idea what kubernetes was so I went to
our subject matter experts and I said
what is kubernetes means that container
orchestration and of
you hear the crickets or we have no idea
what that means can I get more well you
know it helps orchestrate your Linux
containers quicker you literally define
what I'm asking you with the words that
I ask you to define that's what I do I
don't see my journey hey so what is
commands well it has to do with docker
and some ports but honestly you can use
any form of containerization technology
behind it
so we'll be addressing both docker and
Alex deep as well as other forms of
machine containers but our journey
really needs to begin with
virtualization because it's what most
people are accustomed to so the journey
today begins with a simple computer when
you go out and you buy a computer took
our tech snob hats and put them away
from those people it really doesn't
matter what the OSS they buy it because
they have applications that they want to
use so it could be Windows it could be
Linux it could be Mac OS it doesn't
matter but then you have a few of us who
may be software developers they may be
deploying and testing code they may be
like me and I work off of a Mac from
work but I work in OpenStack so I have a
Linux box and then came the time that
everybody in my house Wow I didn't want
to be left out I wanted to play too so I
got a Windows box then I started
learning in my career and I needed a
development center and I needed a laptop
to be able to travel with and then
suddenly I wanted to do a multi node
deployment so my office ended up looking
like this it can't be the only one in
this room who hasn't room in their house
that looks like this right so what
happens when you start needing to travel
when you want to be able to develop when
you when you go I have seen a few of you
walking around with two
laptops in your backpack like more power
to you but I turned to virtualization so
what is virtualization well that is key
I would say that virtualization by
itself is actually not a technology it's
more of a concept it's separating the
underlying hardware from the operating
system it's done through the use of
hypervisor technology so we take the
computer that we have and yes this is
back to the basics to some of you but
it's important to understand these
concepts before understanding the
separation that occurs in containers
take a type 2 hypervisor and you install
that on top of the operating system so
here I have Mac and on top of that I
have VirtualBox running and in my ritual
and Bob's environment I have two
different virtual machines each running
its own operating system so I actually
do have one running Windows and I have
another one running Linux each one
supports its own binaries and each one
has their own applications what does
this enable me to do this enables me to
use one of my boxes as my OpenStack
deployment because OpenStack releases
every six months so every six months I
have to learn something from the bottom
up and I'm gonna pose this environment
we're talking I'm gonna be celebrating
when I go more than 24 hours without a
kernel panic so I can't do that and they
come up here and present and go all
right guys I don't know what's going on
with my computer I need that separation
occurring so what happens though if I am
let's say working for a larger company
where I have need to have even more
separation so I can do something like a
server on servers we generally installed
type 1 hypervisor --zz now type 1
hypervisor x' because they don't have
that level of operating system in
between are generally agreed upon to
have higher performance availability and
security so let's get to the separation
when we we create these virtual machines
really just create
another set of machines it's basically
you can kind of treat a virtual machines
like its own computer the issue is that
it requires that resources be allocated
to it from the host machine so let's
just say that I went down to Goodwill
and I got this server and it has 16 gigs
for the brain so I allocate a VM with 8
I allocate another one with 4 everything
is going according to plan but what
happens what I now need to duplicate
that original VM now this is where some
people pop their collars and they tell
me oh L it's simple all you do is you
configure your hypervisor to allow over
allocation of resources oh yeah don't
you turn off one of the computers you
wait for it to release its resources
back and then you create you can imagine
that if you're running multiple
environments if you're testing and
spinning up code and making changes this
gets to be a long and tedious process we
go back to the spinning and chairs look
and we're waiting for our code to
compile nobody wants that
so that waste of time that kind of
stressful situation is what led to the
development of infrastructure as a
service companies support as we know it
now the cloud McCloud was great right
this enabled us to have resources
whenever we want it done and we could
just spin them up and delete them
without having to manage all of that
infrastructure but we still had an issue
and that was under utilization of
resources you had to buy these cloud
servers in a predefined size we wanted
more for our money and that in my
opinion not an expert here but in my
opinion is what led to the development
of containerization if you go out and
you look about containers and you
especially if you're looking in a docker
they represent containers it's like
these big metal containers that are
meant to go across the ocean and survive
that's not what a container it when you
think about containers I want you to
think about Tupperware but no not your
mom
I'm talking about that cheap piece of
plastic Tupperware that you get at HEB
when you buy the lunch meat and then you
throw your lunch in it you're getting
your trunk for a week so you just kind
of throw it away and pretend that never
existed that's what it contains but due
to the lack of what a kind of a
predefined definition of what a
container is most people think of
containers is like this brand new
technology it's new and it's exciting
not containers actually began their
development with the chroot command in
1982 or in sorry 1978 and it was adopted
later by BSD in 1982 containers have
been on this earth longer than I have so
we had the development of the jell
command most limited there's no this
then we had the exciting stuff happened
we had Google get involved and Google
has some deep pockets they began their
work with processed containers in 2006
now do not get me wrong Google was not
the only company that was actually
developing and helping to spur
containerization technology but they
were by far the loudest they were the
ones willing to go to conferences to
talk to open it up to open source so if
you are a little bit of a nerd like me
and you're willing to read my papers I
encourage you to go out and seek the
board papers Borg as in Star Trek and
just delve into them it is a great story
I thought I read it as a story it is a
white paper but what didn't cause and
what the need was within Google that
caused them to put so much money into
the work of process containers those of
you that know about kubernetes
kubernetes is actually the open source
software version of their board project
so sometime around 2008 I believe Google
and all the other companies
go to the Linux kernel summit and they
sit down and they start hashing this out
what do we really need
what is the use case what are you doing
for this and the result ended up being
Linux namespaces they were adopted into
the Linux kernel and so basically of
your Linux kernel and your namespaces
live within it the namespaces work very
similar to a type 2 hypervisor because
what they do is they restrict the
resources that a process to has to on
the host so where I'm gonna kind of go
open source community here who can tell
me what a process is and explain it to
me like I'm five
it gets scary right when you're new even
the simplest thing you've been using
forever when you get called upon it just
kind of starts giving you that like I
know but I don't know how to say it I
put this slide in because I want to
challenge you guys that when someone
comes to you and they're new to this
technology and they ask you a question
remember that moment because think about
how much vulnerability it took for them
to come up and admit that they didn't
know all right that's just my little
preaching there so what's the process
alright so process is a set of
instructions for your computer to
perform so it's basically taking a list
saying computer I want you to do 1 2 3
or 4 go and prosper but Linux is a
multiprocessor operating system which
means it's going to be doing this more
what more than one process at a time
which means that a lot of these
processes belong to the same application
now it would not really suit as well if
our application couldn't talk to itself
it could report back to itself so we use
Linux namespaces in order to provide a
separation for these processes from the
global environment it becomes how we
secure our multi-user multi application
environment and so when I say namespace
every when I say containers this is what
I'm talking about we all get to this
point all right cool people are actually
naughty
alright so we begin first with our inter
process communication names
now this mess but this namespace does is
it offers a message queue for each
process to be able to communicate and
receive messages outside of its own
container so we have process a running
and one container process be running the
container they belong to the same
application so because they have a
shared namespace they're able to
communicate with one another as
containers need to be ephemeral this
means I need to be able to get a
container kill it off put a brand-new
one in its place and I need my
application to act like absolutely
nothing happened we needed the UTS
namespace this is called the unix time
sharing namespace now what it does is
allows for isolation of host names for
each container now some of you thinking
all right cool the process has a host
name like whoop-dee-doo what does that
mean what means that you're not having
to reprogram your code every single time
you can now use commands like host name
or you name as unique identifiers for
that container so next we needed our
mount namespace our mouth namespace does
pretty much what the name implies it
controls what filesystem mount points
were visible to each container now
mostly people use Linux know that
normally when you mount our unmount a
filesystem
it's going to be presented and affect
your entire global environment what the
mountain namespace did is that provided
a way for you to say you know what only
container a has access to this USB disk
or only to this you know NAT server
whatever you're using and ok so after
that we needed a way for us to isolate
our processes the PIM namespace allowed
for each container to have its own
process ID numbers this did was it
healthy and it systems need to have hid
one within each container the pin
namespace allowed us to have the
functionality of being able to develop
on this computer shut down the process
within the container move it to another
computer spin it back up and ensure that
we didn't have pin number conflict now
that we had the ability to have pin 1 we
needed the ability to have a root user
within that computer without having to
give route access to our entire computer
so this became the last night to kind of
thought this became our new security
feature which allowed us each container
to have its own UID and GID
user IDs and group user IDs so let's say
that we were to have a security breach
and we were to have an application or a
person be able to break out of the
container this would ensure that they
would then become just a nobody user
within our hosts now I know in this room
a lot of you are sitting there thinking
well I could do this and I could do that
yes attacks are getting smarter so with
this we've had that mean we're talking
this is the bottom of our building here
you know we go from namespaces to our
docker files to our kubernetes
containers to our key visors to our
cotta containers so I don't want you to
understand believe that just because you
use a namespace you're suddenly secure
right putting that out there ok so next
we needed a way to our last namespace is
we needed a way to have networking so we
have our network namespace our network
namespace creates another copy of our
network stack this means every single
namespace it's gonna have a network
namespace will have its own routing
tables its own firewall rules and its
own network devices it's important
though to note that currently mi-joo
this could change probably within the
next two to three weeks because
development is occurring here you can
only have one network device per network
namespace so you're gonna have to start
using things like virtual virtual
tunnels to be able to connect between
network namespaces just wanted to get
that out there you can also use bridging
as most of you know but I know that like
everything I've just said might have
just gone over
some of your heads might have been like
alright I get it I don't even know it's
important so normally this is when I
would drop into a demo but you all know
that the Wi-Fi has been kind of
questionable here so this is why I'm in
this day let's pretend together we are
now logged into my boom - 1604 cloud
server and the first thing I'm gonna
list out our IP table rules yes nothing
much going on here it's just a simple
cloud server but I do have felt
abandoned all some of you may have used
it felt to ban scans or logs and bans
IPS that show malicious signs such as
too many password failures all right so
then once I get here I'm able to go in
and I use the IP net and s network
namespace ad just telling it to add and
the name of my new network name space is
going to be sampled when you go out and
you try this by yourself that you can
use any naming convention that you want
I'm just not very creative alright so
then we do in p9 ms and it listed out
what this actually did though is it
actually created a mount point inside of
bar run net NS and at which network
namespace after I already told you so
that there is actually a way for my
network namespace to exist even though
I'm not running any processes into it so
if that's how that exists without any
processes in it alright that's pretty
cool but what the interesting thing is I
can actually drop into that network
namespace so once I do that I have
executed in my network namespace being
the name sample a bash shell I want you
to notice that would happen is as soon
as I win
some kind of off the example here but
what happened is I became the root user
now if you recall every network
namespace has its own IP table rules so
if you look here and you compare them to
the one from our machine you can see
that this network namespace did not
inherit the felt to ban application so
this means that if you had applica if
you had networking already set up to
allow certain ports to go into your host
this doesn't mean that they would be
able to reach your namespace it has its
own its own set of rules all right so if
I do an IPA you can see that I actually
do have networking available in this box
I can bring it up the reason I do this
is all right so in this box you can't
really see it too well but I'm logged in
as a root user so I jump over and now I
am actually just on my sample box I am
not in the network namespace and I can
actually start pinging that network
namespace so I kind of have my own
little machine inside of my machine
without running a virtual machine
without running an actual docker
container this is the beginning of kind
of where the story starts all right cool
so then I go back and I have my network
IP addresses one thing that I do want to
mention that I started to earlier sorry
I'm looping back his luck say that I
come in and I set up this container to
allow for a webserver so I allow 80 and
443 get my website going and everything
going I'm good right no because my host
machine still can't accept that traffic
so my container is completely or my
namespace I'm sorry is completely
isolated despite what rules I've said
here all right so when I exit my
container I can list out my key table
rules but this actually I wish I could
tell you I did it on purpose but I
forgot that the moment I left my
container I lost that root access so
this is an example of what would happen
if you were in a container and able to
break out
you wouldn't inherit those
abilities we use this a lot in
applications such as OpenStack
applications like a software such as
OpenStack what we can do is we can have
a whole rack of servers which are
running the OpenStack software we spin
up VMs within it and we can allow
whatever range of IP table rules
networking communication to occur within
those VMs not configure the hosts and we
basically have a standalone environment
that we never have to allow access to
from the outside world okay so the next
thing I want to show you guys that's my
IP table rules is you've homework
everybody always asked me after I get
done with this talk is how do I get
started working with containers like my
companies using if they want me to learn
I don't even know where to start
spin up a Linux server go into LS go
into LS going to proc do an LS and I
want you to be able to explain to me
what these directories are most of you
are like all right what's the PS those
are my processes okay cool but how many
of you have actually gone into the name
space directory means put it out you
can't see you two out here but I have my
UTS my user my pin my net get to the
point where you can explain this to I'm
not even gonna five-year-old so you can
explain this to a ten-year-old if you
get to the point where you can tell them
what is occurring inside of this
directory and why I went into stuff
stealth is a directory that allows you
to get information of the process that
you are currently using or who you
currently are hey you get to this point
and you can explain this to your boss
you are above I would say 90% of the
people who are currently involved in the
container community that's how you get
started all right so now that I've laid
the groundwork for you we can jump into
what we know as containers so let's talk
about machine containers machine
containers are referred to as operating
system containers because they're a
method of actually instead of
virtualizing the hardware we're now
separating it and virtualizing the OS
they differ from machine containers in
this way or I'm sorry virtual machines
so like I said in my previous example I
have my Mac I get VirtualBox I can have
a lineage
container a Linux VM and I can have a
Windows VM no problem you cannot at this
time do that with machine containers
Microsoft is doing some amazing things
currently with add your containers but
they're not quite there yet so currently
if you use machine containers you'll be
limited to the Linux OS but it does mean
that I could have let's say my boon to
1604 cloud server be running a boon to
14 what LTS I believe be running an
alpine container and be running a CentOS
container no problem let's see that at
work all right so I'm going to be using
a what is it a program called lxd Alex T
is an extension of Linux containers and
you can use is you can do a Lexi list
cool
I have no containers the command that
you're gonna use is Alexei launch then I
am using Ubuntu 1604 I've said this like
15 times so at this point you guys
probably know that is these exact same
image as the server that I am on once
again
I'm not very creative the name is a boon
to container I do LXE list and you can
see my machine container is up and
running it's as simple as that to get
started using containers all right I can
do at sea or cat at the issues and you
see that I am a fact using the same that
that is in fact my operating system so
like I did with a network namespace I am
going to I'm sorry jumping ahead of my
son so like I said before you don't have
to use the same OS you notice the
command changed here it's Alexi launch
images the reason I had to put the word
images now is I am no longer using the
image that my server is um is built from
so I have Alpine 33.5 named Alpine
container do an Alex e-list cool boom -
1604 cloud server running two different
machine containers I can now actually
execute an ash shell the reason I do not
use bash is Alpine Linux is a tiny tiny
version of Linux that is so small that
it
not incorporate bash into it naturally
so when I do an app show I can say Who
am I and apparently I'm the user but
that is the root user I can once again
cat Etsy you choose and prove to you
that I in fact and now using Alpine
Linux 3.5 so maybe a baby saying you
know what I really don't need this at my
system like I am working with micro
services I'm working with these simple
little scripts that all I need is just a
small isolated environment so I can run
the script see what actually occurs
without having to spin up an entire
virtual machine right application
containers are probably what you're
interested in application containers are
also referred to as process containers
because we like having a lot of names
for things in the tech world this is a
way to provision a standalone
environment for a single process and you
guys may have actually only heard of one
of them and that is docker that is
because docker is the world's leading
software platform and it was developed
to build a single application Linux
containers and so with docker it differs
a little bit from machine containers
because let's say I want to run a web
server application so I might have three
containers one which has Apache one
which has MySQL and the other which is
run Java is before you notice that
within our machine containers all three
of these applications would be running
within the same container any questions
to this point
quite you can't ask questions I promise
all right so some of you may be asking
them all right how do we get to the
point where I'm running Apache or I'm
running Java without having an operating
system like how does that work what
occurs through the use of the docker
image now a docker image is is a series
of read-only layers stacked on top of
each other and it begins with a base
image so base image could be Sint OS it
could be a boon - it could be something
custom made by your company currently
primarily Linux images like I said
adjure is doing some amazing things
right now and what docker does is it
puts a read/write layer I'm sorry on top
of your
you only learn and so it makes use of a
copy on write strategy or as we love
acronyms in this tech world we call it
cat well Cal says is that all of the
processes and applications are going to
be sharing the same binaries and
libraries and application files until
one of them needs to make a change
once that application a needs to make a
change it will make its own copy on this
readwrite layer and it will make changes
here but all of the other applications
and processes that are using that
library will would continue using that
base image layer so changes and copies
are only made when an application
actually needs to so let's say for
example alpine linux because i love
using it and we put our rewrite layer on
top of it and i want to update it any
changes that occur would be written on
this layer this point though i must add
a some of you hopefully are asking like
where do I even get a base image how do
I get started in this process we do so
by going to the darker story this is
where you can get a plethora of images I
might not have to say it in this room
but I think I would be negligent not to
just because an image is available on
the docker store does not mean it as a
trusted source I am NOT responsible for
what you do so if you want to play
around go to a company that you trust
would that be a red hat with a view sent
to us whether it be Alpine pull your
image then your gonna create an Alpine a
docker file with the docker file is
alright docker what do I want you to do
so in this docker file this is really
simple if you decide to go play with it
you can run this exact same thing and
get it running off the ground all I'm
saying is hey from the docker hub
because I haven't defined anything else
pull the latest version of Alpine now
there if you go into the docker hub you
can see that they offer a history of
different versions you can just replace
latest with whatever you want I want you
to then go and update it and then I want
you to add H top now just looking at
this docker file can anyone tell me how
many rewrite layers are gonna be either
so rewrite layer yeah there you got to
read write layers are generated by the
issuing of a run command
every single time you see run that's
gonna be another layer that I'm building
onto it you can see that here
all right the Kommandant you're gonna
use once you get that docker file
written is gonna be sudo docker bill and
that dot is just present working
directory
take the docker file out of this present
record directly am working directory and
from it we're going to so we say hey dr.
do that docker goes back and reads our
file and it starts working so from the
Alpine library it pulls the latest image
pull complete so that's one action that
it took and it gives me my new base
image that is the ID from any base image
step two so now I'm in another layer is
it runs that update I want you to notice
though it says running in it created
another container based off that base
image that we just pulled to do this
work in once that's completed it removes
that container and my next room command
builds another container for this to
occur you can kind of see the latency
starting to build here especially if
you're running a lot of commands alright
once that has been removed
it is built successfully one thing
though that I do want to note is the
image that I have highlighted here is
only available in your cache because you
actually never told docker that you
needed this image it's just one of the
process or one of the steps that has to
be taken to get you to what you want it
so it's kind of interesting and the
reason I bring it up that is in your
cache is if let's say you decide to
create another image taking the exact
same step with the exact same based
image it we're actually a curse quicker
because it already has it stored in a
local cache I said that enough times
there okay once it's completed we've
successfully built and we now have two
images the base image that we pulled and
the one that we wanted it to create if
you're like me and you're a visual
learner this is what we did
Alpine update H tub yay new image but as
I had I stood up here in kind of
those out for you hopefully some of you
are getting into scripting or already
script you could do something simple
like this and just to cut down on your
run commands despite the fact that I
have now run three quote-unquote Linux
commands I only used one run command so
that image will only have the base layer
which is already on my system and the
one container that it's gonna need to
build cool so why does this matter well
you can use it more than just building
images you can use docker to run just
single little bits of applications so
one of the ways that I like to show this
is through a program or an image called
well saying how many of you have used
Linux cousing I go look up Linux cafe
it's fine it's something to entertain
your kids with and make them think that
you you know do amazing things as I know
the Linux admin or whatever you do
alright so I run and what you're telling
you here is docker go to the docker hub
from the docker hub and the docker
repository right it's going from the
docker repository pull the image well
sing and well sama say hey say cow say
hello world now I paused it here because
I want to show you if I was doing this
live we would have to sit here and wait
for every single one of those layers to
pull now imagine if you're automating
this across hundreds of servers or
thousands of containers it's definitely
gonna add to your latency so I'd
encourage you if you don't script to at
least play around become a little bit of
a bash monkey there and play around with
it and try to get your container I'm
sorry your images as small as you can
but what since completed we have our
well sting hello well so at this point
I've been talking for good half hour
we've covered virtualization we've
covered machine containers we've covered
application containers we've gone into
docker and how docker images built
that's a lot of stuff so at this point
you may be wondering if I have all of
this available to me why do I even need
kubernetes like why is kubernetes
the new heart right now lay aside
imagine it took me about half an hour to
get here to build you guys through this
imagine if you have an infrastructure
that goes across multiple cities states
countries with hundreds of servers
thousands of virtual machines
I mean terms just spun up there two
million virtual machine and I was like
three years ago I don't even know where
they are now you imagine trying to
automate this using ansible through
danceable but that's just gonna be a lot
of work there so that's what kind of
crew Nettie's does kubernetes becomes
our container orchestration hey took me
half an hour to get you there but now
you understand what container
orchestration is so let's say that I
have an application let's say that I'm
using and I'm not gonna pick on a
company cloud service a I have three
cloud servers predominantly when I was
building my application it would be
written to the environment in which I
was working in inter vendor lock-in it
became very difficult for me to switch
from pod computing a to cloud computing
B because I would have to write my code
I'd have to get everybody back in their
kubernetes offers a way to be able to
kind of break apart from container um
from that vendor lock-in because I now
write my application to work with my
docker images my lxd images whatever
technology you're using and so when I'm
ready to maybe I don't have any I'm not
leaving cloud server maybe I'm just
increasing my presence I can now move my
application from one cloud computing
company or one OpenStack bill to another
and it all starts with setting a desired
state now some of those of you that came
in because your company is interested in
kubernetes and that's what you're
interested this is the part where you
start listening because what you want to
walk away with is understanding the
difference between your desired state
and your observed state kubernetes the
entire job all it actually really does
is it sits there and it watches your
system and it says does this system live
up to the rules and the regulations that
I have been given that it should live up
to I'll get into what that actually
means though so the kubernetes maintains
a control plane record of kubernetes
objects on this
and it runs in a continuous loop to
manage those object states it begins
with the base unit of deployment in
kubernetes this is where we get our
vocabulary in base unit of in kubernetes
is the pot you can think of a pod is
kind of just like a small server living
inside of what is known as a node we'll
get to that in just a second so even if
let's say you want to run a tiny little
script inside of one little container if
you're using kubernetes it's going to
make it inside of a pot it does so
because it can use this pod as a base
unit of replication so every time you
say you know what I want 15 versions of
this script running it can just go and
create that exact same pod over and over
again now if you're deploying multiple
containers inside of a pod so I have
let's say three processes running like I
do here they need a way to be able to
communicate with each other enter your
network name space all kubernetes does
is it's making use of those Linux
namespaces that we covered at the
beginning in order to help communication
occur between these containers inside of
the pot now I did say that a pod exists
inside of a node inside of kubernetes
two more terms you need to know and that
is master node and worker node what a
worker node is is it could be a virtual
server it could be a physical server it
can be whatever it is that you want to
use but it works kind of like a you
could be it like this IBM it what it
does is it allows a place for you to be
able to have all of your containers
existing inside of those pods and it has
different applications inside of it
different api's that allow it to
communicate with the server going like
yep I've got you know 14 pods running
hey this one pod broke it allows that
communication to occur to the master
server the master node which is what I
told you guys about as end users of
kubernetes you will only ever
communicate with a master node the
master node is what takes your
instruction and it checks its
environment of worker nodes so one thing
I should have mentioned I'm sorry is you
can't have and you will have you should
have multiple worker nodes I mean you
should have maybe one man
stir and hundreds of workers and what
the master does is it combines all of
its resources into what we know as a
cluster so you don't actually ever need
to care where your application is
running as long as it's running right so
it's a collection of processes running
behind a single node those of you in
larger corporations your company may
have multiple servers configured as
masters only one is actually acting as a
master the others are called leaders
they're just sitting there waiting for
the master to die off and as soon as it
does or something happens they hold a
little election one comes up and it says
alright I'm the master now it's there
for redundancy so I've given you guys
all the terminology if you have any
questions on that please ask I know I
went through it kind of quick but I know
everybody just kind of gets bored with
the vocab lesson so let's pull it all
together I have my master node I have my
work now I told you guys that it's
really just kind of silly to have one
worker node you're not really using
kubernetes so we're gonna expand our
environment into three notes but I look
that's us right there and we want to
have more than one version of our
application running so we issue an API
command or we can use a lot of the
services such as CTL or a GUI if that's
what you have access to to tell our
worker node hey you it our sites getting
kind of popular I want two versions of
my web app running right now so
kubernetes goes ahead and sets up that
work but let's say that you know what my
first picture I'm building this in my
office and my roommate has decided to go
in and sweep and he unplugs one of my
machines right that's wayne kubernetes
says you know my job was to ensure that
there were two versions of that app
running and it moves it to another
system all right so let's go ahead
back in - um we're server so you can
tell maybe it's a little small I'm
actually logged into a different server
this is the master node of my kubernetes
cluster and what I'm gonna be showing
you guys today is a way to interact with
it using the cubed CTL command cube CTL
just makes the API calls to the master
to get the information that I need back
really simply so the command is as
simple as cube CTL get nodes those are
the nodes I don't actually have to go
out and do the authentication and put
authentication string and send out an
API call every single time I want
information I would be negligent to tell
you guys or juggling not to tell you
guys that there is a GUI available for
kubernetes I just thought it would be a
little silly for me to sit here and do
command line for everything else and be
like alright guys watch me push these
buttons so we're teach you a little bit
of command line here all right
like I said cube CTL is super simple hey
I want to know what pods I have in my
environment
it's what do CTL get pods this is also
written by I believe Linux admins and if
anybody knows a Linux admin we are the
laziest of the lazy and if we can script
it we will so you can actually use kill
cube CTL get Pio because pods was too
long all right all right now we talked
about namespaces so if I do cube CT I'll
get an S one thing I want to point out
these aren't your Linux namespaces
kubernetes also uses the term namespaces
to differ
the way that it differentiates is name
spaces within kubernetes are a way for
you to give have multiple environments
within your company so let's say that
you know what I do have limited
resources I only have X amount of
computers and we all kind of share them
through the use of kubernetes I could
have one environment for my development
team one environment from my prod team
and one environment for my team who
perhaps sections off things that have
been compromised and does investigations
and each one of those environments can
actually share me can actually have the
same names so instead of let's say I
have my practice namespace I contain if
I
created Ella's container one I couldn't
create another L containers one however
that name could exist within any other
one of my namespaces that it's clear as
matter did that make sense so if
something happens I can be moving my
server around without them without being
afraid of you know the name clash all
right let's see if there was anything
else that I wanted to point out oh one
important thing that I learned the hard
way when you go out and practice this if
you kill off your namespace everything
that lives in that namespace will be
gone and you will not be able to get it
back that was a lesson hard learned all
right so if I do cube CTL get pods and
you notice that when I did it first it
said that I didn't have any resources
but now when I tagged on that all
namespaces suddenly I do have a pot up
and running that's because whenever you
use whenever we just go in and it's just
your basic build it's automatically
gonna put you into the default namespace
if you create any resources and you
don't tell it what name to put it in
it's automatically gonna put it into
that default namespace
I put Leah that I want to use kubernetes
and I like the web app example I don't
tell you guys I decide that I want to
run a web app this isn't an image or
anything like I said I'm not creative
that's just my naming convention but I'm
going to be using the image engine X and
because I'm pretending it's a web app
here I'm going to be exposing port 80 on
the container now if I were to run this
could you from the outside world connect
to this box or connect to this web
server no because my actual machine
hasn't been that I would need to set the
application rules to my machine room my
container is exposed but I haven't
allowed traffic in from the outside
world it can't get to it
and in samples of things like OpenStack
that's fine because I'm having all my
communication happen internally okay so
I do my cube CT elves get pods and cool
there's my pod up and running let's say
that you know I closed my lid here I go
on and I come back another day and I'm
looking at this and I wait I was there
any web outlet I don't even remember I
was doing to delete the pod should be
simple enough right
cube CTL delete pod and I do the name
we do it get pods to confirm accept that
my app is still there maybe tell me what
happened
so not a restart it created a whole new
one because if you look at the name it
step I know but it's important it didn't
restart it it actually did do it instead
it went in and it deleted that container
but then I created a new but a new one
because I told it that that's what I
wanted it to do all right
that goes back to our desired state and
observe state now there's actually a lot
more to it what I actually did was I
didn't create a pot I kind of went
behind I created a deployment which is
what tells kubernetes to get that going
but kubernetes within itself is a
monster on its own I guess I got a
little nervous today and I talked a
little faster than I usually do because
normally I am like at time but I do want
to offer the ability to you guys if you
want to know more about not
containerization kubernetes by itself
how you get an app and you get it
running we have a class going on next
Wednesday normally we sell it but it's
not your guy's fault but I couldn't get
everything into one so if you want to
attend it it's how to get a Hello roll
up and running in kubernetes feel free
to go to training at Rackspace comm use
that promo code and you can take the
course for free it's free sorry percent
free
you can hazy okay all right cool do we
have any questions oh sorry sorry I
thought people were done taking pictures
so it's about hour-long webinar you can
attend it from your desk I don't know
I'd have to ask my I mean if I guess
that's depends on your boss
[Music]
yes public service announcement yes
and we'll go over one question that I
generally get that I think is actually
really important is most people always
ask me you know like why would I use a
container instead of a virtual machine
or why would I use an application
container instead of a machine container
and I don't think it's a valid question
because the answer is use all of them so
one thing that I do when I'm going out
there and pulling images that I don't
know first of all I'm using might like
what I call my partner computer the one
that always gets reimaged anyways
because I'm going to break it and then I
have a virtual machine running they end
up having an application which I'm sorry
a machine container inside of that or
something like Potter containers and I'm
running it inside of that so I'm like
sandbox in my sandbox for my sandbox I
so there are it's really important to
know that this technology is not use one
or another like all of this is nested
virtualization so don't ever feel like
you have to pick one you know you have
to use docker I've used docker on top of
my lxd container before just go have fun
that's my big messages go and play with
this and break it and delete it and
start over yes
it is I believe next Wednesday at 10
a.m. we do to this code will actually
work for the second one but you've
already sat through it we have another
one understanding containerization so if
you know somebody maybe from your
company that might have wished they
could have been here today you can give
him this code that way is this
Wednesdays coming up and they can use
the codes check the website to make sure
I haven't
[Music]
[Applause]