this is going to be a history lesson for
some of you and I'm looking just judge
we gonna be the case for others it's
gonna be a little trip down memory lane
right so we're gonna talk about you know
what is the order how do we get to Patch
Tuesday why does this thing even exist
for me to destroy it here today so
number one if we look at vbscript and
it's kind of funny because I I saw this
post earlier today on Twitter's about
you know a year 2000 was so great all
these things that occurred you know as
anything this sounds like yeah that
shitload of vulnerabilities that were
going on because of VB spur if you look
at these just show hands real quick as I
go through this who remembers Melissa
all right
the I love you virus code read ninda why
was vendor name Nimba named min min
don't write admin backwards right plus
you know all these occurred in the year
2001 and it was like one after another
after another we were just getting
hammered with this non-stop and
guess who's getting the big black guy in
all this yeah exactly
it was Microsoft so Bill Gates came out
with this memo in 2002 early 2002 oh
yeah January and it was basically a
cease and desist order to all of his
developers stating that basically they
were to go through and do a code review
no matter what the product was what
product group owned it period
no more development this one offer like
six months all they were doing is
security architecture and code review
they were doing this that they
should have been doing to begin with
right secure coding so from there what
ended up happening is this hodgepodge of
various patching products feature packs
solutions being brought in
from Microsoft and they got really
confusing really quick how many of you
worked with SMS back in the day how many
of you know what SMS stands for not
short message systems management server
was Microsoft's earlier version of SCCM
how many of you guys use SCCM know what
it is okay you're gonna get some more
exposure to that because that's kind of
what a lot of this is but you know we
had everything from the Windows Update
web app critical update notification the
SMS feature pack automatic updates the
Windows Update agent and then finally
Windows Server Update Services ooh
and that was like in a two-year span how
confused do you think that marketplace
was so all of this ends up leading into
Patch Tuesday in October 2003 where
Microsoft said that basically were going
to give some consistency because all
this that was going on wasn't work
and it gave the consumer the users the
enterprises no structure no format how
many change control meetings do you guys
like to attend my number on that is it
right and we're going to talk about that
later too because I think there's ways
for you guys to get down to one a lot of
them around patching so basically
Microsoft brought this on now over the
past 15 years now can you believe it's
been 15 years that we've been asked this
yeah over the past 15 years a few of the
vendors have other vendors third-party
vendors have also got on this right but
not everyone and even of those that have
kind of followed into Microsoft's you
know Patch Tuesday some of them don't
even do it on
we basis some of them it's every two
months all of them is once a quarter
some of it some of them it's by annually
so even that gets a bit confusing right
so 15 years later we still can't get
this stuff right I told my wife I
wouldn't cuss in this presentation
because I'm on campus now this is all
information gleaned from a an article
that was just published what is it June
so a couple of months ago you know the
only 60 percent of organizations over
the past two years have suffered a data
breach and their statement is that it
was basically for vulnerability which
they had attached at 60% they hadn't
passed yet they do the vulnerability was
out there they knew it was applicable to
their environment they knew the
criticality of that vulnerability and
yet they still weren't passion
half of those or another study from the
pony bond Institute said that they were
hit with one or more data breaches in
the past two years you know half of the
organizations and that I think if we
build affirmative Ito there was like
some 2,000 organized
worldwide not even that 30% or 34% of
those said they knew their systems were
vulnerable to the attack prior to
serving occurred in that big bridge so
we have some horrible horrible
statistics here coming from you talk to
your organizations around the world
so 86% of the vulnerabilities reports
paying with patches last year so they
had these vulnerable systems they know
that they're applicable to their
environment there's patches for 86% of
them again they're still not being
applied you know all this is just saying
we have this compounded problem here so
clearly these zero days are really not
as much of an issue as they were before
right yeah zero days used to be that oh
moment and you know we're in a
firefighting mode immediately and we
were going through this on a very fast
clip recurring almost monthly with one
vendor to the next but how many zero
days have we seen this year it's been
very very few right so what is the
problem
first we have to come to grips with the
facts the other 90% I like to call so I
hate to disappoint you guys but
Microsoft really is really is in fact
Microsoft
over the past 15 years has become very
good at what they're doing they have the
largest most complex in the Evolved sock
in existence and if you want to argue
that with me and start talking about
fire Ari and some of these others I will
put your and check like nobody's
business
there are billions of sensors that they
are monitoring and aggregating data from
every single month there's nobody who
comes anywhere close to Microsoft's
Intel when it comes to security threats
and vulnerabilities that exist and it's
not just their products they're looking
at everything so
let's get into some of the statistics
here so when we look at Bonner ability
reports and this is basically taking
from-- see details comm you can use miss
minor whoever all the data is the same
right it's just which feed you want to
consume from but i I pulled all this
from CDE details last night so this is
all the data that exists in 2015
Microsoft accounted for 9% of the
vulnerabilities that were reported by
the top 50 vendors by NIST Mayer CD
Telecom 2016 only 7% of all those
vulnerabilities were attributed to
Microsoft in 2017 last year 8% so in
reality columns are in 9% to date for
this year so in reality no more than 10%
of all those vulnerabilities reported
have been attributed back to Microsoft
and when I say Microsoft I mean anything
that has a Microsoft name associated
with that particular executable
environment whatever so you know Windows
7 Windows 10 2016 2012 you know 2008
office Internet Explorer edge you name
it if it has Microsoft's name associated
no less than or no more than 10 percent
so what does that mean when it comes to
all of our patching efforts
well most corporations today use wsus
for patching right right show then how
many of you guys have wsus
to patch your Microsoft so it is a very
capable solution I'm not going to take
away from it at all it is you know for
SMEs small to medium-sized businesses a
perfect thing you know essentially you
just synchronize it with Windows Update
comm you know hold on the updates
approve which ones you want fire them
out
use your group policies to determine
which endpoints you know get those
policies and which patches and you're
pretty much done right so it is a very
capable solution for being able to bring
all those updates inside the perimeter
and being able to control the flow
distribution of it right so it works
it's a whole lot better than that
hodgepodge of that I showed you
earlier now for the traditional
enterprise and how they're looking that
patch management it's a lot different
right because there's a lot of
complexities that go into distributing
patches when it comes to having five
thousand ten thousand a hundred thousand
systems globally how many of you guys
work for a large-scale corporation so
you get what I'm talking about you know
the pains this is kind of that whole oh
your windows inside our build ran into a
problem and needs to restart
damn it I forgot to put my uh well I
forgot to put my cell phone
of instances and you tell might like
people once you build enough data in the
RSA Archer applying an update from RSA
is a huge undertaking and most people
only do it once a year so it doesn't
matter how many batches they come out
yeah s AP is coming the same way agreed
another good point so what happened
where'd I get pissed okay let's try this
again and uh mother very clean okay
okay so patch release cycles so what a
lot of enterprise organizations go
further this is actually part of one of
the articles and I wrote for ice a
journal for ice soccer it's one over the
other but this graphic window security
tips is one my old side stone hasn't
touched a year but this graphic kind of
shows what the typical enterprise has to
go through on a monthly basis you know
first we're going to have week one where
where we have those update notification
channels and that's really important for
you guys making sure that as you're
expanding your year reach into third
party vendors and starting to manage
those software updates on the more
aggressive cycle make sure you have
appropriate communication channels
established with those vendors whatever
mechanism they use for alert
notification to their customers it may
be an email make sure that email is not
going to a single individual make sure
it's going to some kind of distribution
list or ticketing system internally so
that you have you don't have that single
point of failure essentially some of o
will have an RSS feed just a blog site
whatever the case may be but make sure
that you have a means of monitoring that
communication channel from that vendor
determine the implicit bility you know
that's when the first things that you
have to do is the applicability and the
criticality rating of each one of these
see BES and knowing if it is applicable
to your environment what the criticality
the risk is to your environment right so
how many of you guys have an inventory
system within your environment for
hardware software
come on show of hands
okay how many of you actually trust the
information within that database okay
just we're all on the same page here
working from the same book and then it
goes through a limited pilot and this is
normally you know your virtual machine
environments
your test labs IT information security
those kinds of folks people that can fix
the issue themselves at because birth
then they go into pilot testing this is
typically a very limited number of users
with cross-referenced representation
different business units because what
anybody want to stop why do we use
different business students different
software they may even have different
Hardware right
I may have tough books out in the you
know oil rigs off the coast right there
may be some incompatibility because
those tough books have different drivers
and software that handle the keyboard
and display right I have different
hardware drivers for this MSI laptop
with its keyboard with its display
graphics etc yeah that may conflict with
the particular update so make sure you
have a good cross representation of
different business units and will have
different applications and potentially
hardware problems as well so that's
tends to be about five to ten percent of
the population if you have you know five
thousand users and you're a farming
you're probably going to have you know
distribution to around 500 maybe 250 we
three you're going to expand that to the
larger user acceptance typically about
20 to 30 percent addressing any issues
that are going to identify that maybe
some issue with your own builds with the
software configuration it may be an
issue you have you have to take back to
the vendor whether if that's Microsoft
or someone else you know these things do
happen
and then lastly full-scale deployment
steady-state controls in place and then
you simply allow the rinse and repeat
right because by the time you get to
this point guess what that's Tuesdays
happen all over again you start this
process it's why it's so difficult for
most organizations to be able to stay on
top of their passion because guess what
do any of you have a main headcount in
your environment an FTE responsible for
nothing but patching Patrick period that
owns your patching process I see two
three he's like gosh we put that on top
of there are other responsibilities
right that's how most organizations
operate large-scale you know enterprises
yeah they do have dedicated patching
teams evening you know because they're
not only patching Microsoft and third
parties they're also having a patch
internally developed applications as
well so it's this constant struggle to
stay ahead of the game in what happens
when you have a zero-day that blows this
out of the water yeah what happens
when Intel takes a crap all over your
environment so oh yeah so the bigger
issue like we talked about earlier is we
have this 90 percent concept right have
I found that into your mind yet 90% of
the vulnerabilities that exist in the
world today have absolutely nothing to
do with Microsoft so we have to fix that
issue but we still have all this other
stuff that we're having to manage on a
day to day basis right we can barely get
through all of our Microsoft's
before we're dealing with this now when
I talked with organizations and I asked
why are you not bringing your third
party updates for all that other 90
percent into the same process flow I
hear the same things over and over again
and that's what you just solved there we
don't have the time we don't have the
resources and we don't have the right
tools I get that I get it I've been in
these ones I've been doing this
with patch since 2003 when Microsoft did
release a feature pack for SMS now I've
been dealing with SMS in SCCM since 1998
yeah and my career took this shift into
infoset starting back in 2003 looking at
patch management frameworks for
customers how were they going to bring
that capability into their environment
using the tool sets that they already
have so one of the ways system center
updates publisher now I didn't see a lot
of hands go up when I asked the question
earlier how many of you have SCCM and
you're in bars there there are several
hands out and I'm suspecting just
because of roles and responsibilities
some of you may not be aware that there
is secm within your environment you may
not be responsible for but most
organizations today that are Microsoft's
friendly shops that are I would say
above a thousand seats probably have a
CCM as well it's almost free for you to
bring into your environment
now System Center updates publisher
while it has that System Center brand
it's part of the system's
family that whole suite of solutions
system center operations manager
configuration manager virtual machine
manager etc but this one it's really
about extending and enhancing wsus which
everybody's pretty much using right now
what it does is basically brings a lot
more flexibility and control by being
able to integrate all that third-party
updates so the stuff really fills that
void but we're gonna get into some of
the issues that I do have with them but
you can see here some of the vendors
that are included in that so I've got an
environment here and and I lose my mouse
what happened so let me just bring up
excuse me updates publisher real quick
this product is essentially twofold
so it can handle third-party partner
updates for integration with wsus but it
also allows you to patch your own
in-house develop applications if you do
have those dev teams as well so as long
as you have any of the data around the
application anything from being able to
identify the registry the binaries the
version of those binaries etc you can
say don't look for based upon this
applicability and then use this binary
to update it and then use this
information whether if it's from the
registry the file itself a directory
structure or whatever to be able to say
yes it has been patched now you can get
all that integrated into wsus and be
able to push it out the exact same way
you would
okay well you can also bring in catalogs
from partners so if I click this URL I'm
not online what's that with current
branch yeah oh yeah yeah so we're
getting Oh trust me we're gonna get to
all that okay I did connect to that
earlier that was actually a pretty slick
process for guest Wi-Fi did you see that
with Saint Mary's I normally never use
guests with Wi-Fi abuse myself but
anyhow long story
there Wi-Fi when you register you have
to put in your mobile device number and
then it sends you a text with your
username and password that's me that's
pretty slick I've never seen that before
in all the corporations I visit so
basically here's the catalogs that are
available and scup does anybody see an
issue with this
my supporting software vendors
sorry lots of vendors yeah I know give
that man an ice-cream see you at 12 uh
yeah we're talking Adobe Dell HP Fujitsu
that's it
right this product was released in 2011
it's had incremental updates and one
major update not too long ago about well
yet the number of vendors did not expand
for whatever reason Microsoft has not
been able to garner the attention of the
software industry and their partners to
be able to publish their updates as a
catalog for consumption and Scott but
remember you can use these and just flip
adobe you could probably make some
traction with at least keep in reader an
acrobat up-to-date all right if nothing
else it's good for that be able to bring
those updates in no HP Fujitsu you know
being able to keep some of their driver
BIOS updates those kinds of things so it
doesn't serve our purpose but also for
being able to work with your internally
developed applications so this is one of
the solutions that may work for you just
keep that in mind that it is available
to extend your existing wsus environment
so continuing on now enterprise he
capable third-party patching you know
this is where you end up getting into
some of the vendor based solutions there
is a cost you have scuff is free you can
download it right now it will work with
any W or Windows 10 system or server if
you're working in that environment you
do have to have the
administration toolkit forward to
install in here your desktop OS but it
is free these are not so much but look
at the number of vendors we have four
vendors that are in the wsus collectors
you know from the third party or from
the Microsoft Park or solutions that are
out there there are a hundred and fifty
plus they're pushing over 200 at this
point it's a very competitive space so
they're all competing because their
catalogues that have the vendor updates
that's their their secret sauce that's
their goal right so the more vendors and
applications that are in the catalog the
more competitive they become and they
get into this way tour so to speak with
each other but because of the way that
they work in some restrictions Microsoft
has put on the wsus api's these updates
are secured by nature because every
update has to be signed before it gets
published into wsus so it will use
that's either self sign or CA provisions
certificate to sign that update before
it gets injected and this all happens
automatically behind the scenes as part
of your set up most of them will also
remove the scuff requirement now that's
very recent only in the past year year
and a half for most of these vendors
before you were having to inject it into
the scuff catalog and then it would
update from there or it would actually
use the api's from the scuff catalog to
do that pass through integration into
wsus that's no longer the case today so
it does remove that requirement and
gives you basically a solution that you
just plug in to wsus or through wsus it
will update your SCCM catalog
so to your point both the scuff product
by itself and these third-party vendor
solutions will natively integrate into
SCCM regardless of what current branch
version you're on so i test regularly
with you know 1709 1811 whatever the
case so for 70 yeah so you still let me
let me table that one but yes i will
answer your question
yes but i'll show you in just now so
some of the main players in this space
you may want to take notes how actually
i'm hoping we're able to publish all
these to the d size site but avanti my
former employer i started back when it
was heat software heat and LANDesk both
merged informed the Avanti Brennan and
Landis owned the chaplet product heat on
the patch link product so these two
fierce competitors ended up joining and
basically the reason I put a bond to get
the top of the list if you had these two
fabulous products and not I'm not gonna
talk about Shapland even though I
was on the inside I did all the time man
but yeah they were both really good
solutions so what what a vodka did was
put all the parts on the table kind of
like Apollo 13 right said okay let's
bring home this is what we get to work
the best parts of both solutions put
them together now it's called a baktun
hatch I believe but that's what we're
what Sarah this is formally the Secunia
product Secunia it still got some of the
automation in there but it's a little
bit more manual in regards to you have
to kind of review and approve the
updates but it gives you a lot of
control flexibility they do some stuff
that Avanti doesn't do as far as their
own proprietary criticality ratings of
the updates you know so that you can
kind of prioritize your spend and focus
based upon the criticality of the update
from the vendor and the applicability
and criticality to your environment so
that's kind of a key if you need that
kind of guidance in your patch
management then you may want to look
closer at what Sarah patch my pcs kind
of bubbled up from almost the Soho small
office Home Office kind of user to SMB
now they're getting into that mid market
space so if you guys are like less than
let's say 2500 users this may be a
really good solution for you to look at
in extremely cheap I'm talking a buck a
seat right to be able to bring
third-party patching into your wsus
environment and using it to push those
updates up manage engine I highly
recommend against reason being and I
love that we're in Senate owned a
[Music]
security consulting firm based here was
doing a pen test for one of their
customers that customer happened to be a
managed engine user
managed engine head well it was it has a
web front-end so through their land and
expand you know escalate privileges and
continue to give it to other systems
they end up on this web server and start
to do their pen testing on it
and discover five honor abilities in the
managed engine product that led to
anti-authority system access across the
board on all the men that dungeon
clients in that environment I'm sorry
but if you have five vulnerabilities and
two of them essentially give you root
access on every client agent sitting out
there you do not belong in the security
business I'm on camera saying that get
out
okay so SCCM third-party software
updates from these centers you're going
to get full catalog integration process
automation complete based on management
and recording and that is what we're
going to look at right now and I love
this new feature in PowerPoint because I
tend to do a lot of click through demos
for stuff like this so that no matter
what the environment I can survive just
here in PowerPoint but this is kind of
like a live click for scenario but did
you see how I clicked in through that I
love that that's a whole new section
from this PowerPoint deck I just found
that last week okay so once you've done
the initial setup with whatever bender
now I'm using the slides that I had for
my heat software slash avanti days but
it's the exact same way now this is the
SCCM environment it may be new for some
of you guys but just to show the level
of integration
there's not a whole lot with the wsus as
far as you know what you're able to do
like I said it's good for the SMB space
it will push those updates out group
policy and you kind of said forget it
approve the updates that you're done
right you have a lot more control
flexibility applies to reporting and
capabilities inside the best CCM and if
you're not looking at and you are kind
of that environment you know I would
even say 500 systems enough really look
at deploying secm not only for software
updates you're going to see some of the
other security relevant information here
in just a minute
but those of you that were questioning
your software or hardware inventory I'm
not saying that CCM is the best but
they've been out this for 20 years
and it's pretty damn solid if you keep
your clients healthy and I'm not talking
about the client agent because even it
is self repairing now but your WMI
repository your admin dollar shares you
know those kinds of things then SCCM is
a very solid solution so once you've
done the initial configuration said
which vendors you want to bring in which
products you're interested in patching
what's going to happen is it's going to
pull down those catalogs it's going to
do some dump the information figure out
what's in your environment already from
their perspective what is it and at that
point you can say ok yeah I want to
start patching you
Acrobat you know flash layer etc so at
that point all this stuff starts showing
up inside of the SCCM admin console
right next to all of your other updates
so you know as you scroll down there's
Adobe Reader Apple washer iTunes now
we're into Microsoft Update see you tell
that by the name and the bulleted IDs
you know they're obviously Microsoft so
here we have the exact same you know
interface I customers would be pushing
out the typical Microsoft updates not
with all these other third parties and
I'm talking like a hundred and fifty a
hundred eighty different applications
that you can bring in whether if it's to
SCM or bringing it into wsus and just
pushing it out from there so I can
select a bunch of those updates give it
a name I can use deployment templates
inside of that CCM they'll still be
applicable target my collection go
through the rest of the deployment
wizard I'm not gonna bore you guys with
that now automatic deployment rules
right good part of what we need to do is
have scale we're talking about bringing
in a hundred and fifty different
applications he may only take about 12
15 of those yeah because they are the
most important to you and Russ assured
you're 12 or 15 important ones are
different than is right so that's why
those but you can bring in automation to
be able to help you adopt all these new
versions and applications that you're
going to patch but that doesn't mean you
have to have
right so how can we automate this SCCM
makes that possible with automatic
deployment rooms and you may choose to
push out particular updates I'd talk to
everyone in the environment you may want
to only use automatic deployment rules
for your pilot or maybe just for your
phase one you know your IT and InfoSec
users because it to break something they
can fix it or push it out to your pilot
because at least you can automate that
part of the patching process the rest of
it you may want to have a little bit
more hands-on control so here's some of
those automatic deployment rules best
buying when it was released at the laste
departments flash player has been
superseded or expired should be in there
the vendors Adobe they go ahead and push
it out and you'll see which collection
you're going to push it to except for so
I set up these automatic deployment
rules based upon whatever selection
criteria I want and as soon as those
updates are released I've targeted a
specific collection inside of SCCM for
them now some of the other things that
we can do is compliance baselines I'm a
huge fan of compliance baselines inside
of SCCM I use them for everything from
the operating system to match the
hardening of Windows 10 to CIS or you
know what have you whatever controls we
need to and being able to have
continuous monitoring of their
compliance with that particular base on
and making sure I'm controlling the
drift I know what that image looks like
on day one from either you know that
gold image DVD or you know that task
sequence in SACM whatever process I'm
using I know on day one what it looks
like but I have no clue on day 365 yeah
unless I have a solid inventory in a way
of being able to monitor the actual
compliance or the baseline compliance so
here I have my baselines create a
baseline now I'm actually going to use
software inventory
information to see if my systems are
complying with that baseline or not
select pad G software updates I'm gonna
expand it you use Adobe Flash Player
select whichever updates I want say okay
now each one of those updates is a CI or
configuration audio that goes into that
configuration baseline I take that
baseline target the systems I want to
now I'm actively monitoring their
compliance with those items and I'm done
in like five seconds right I can assign
administrative categories here I have my
patch management security and that just
plays out later on the reporting which
we're gonna get to you here very quickly
we get through this bit so now I've
still you know provided all my selection
criteria which collection all desktop
and server clients you see the date I
can generate alerts if X number or X
percentage of systems are not compliant
by that's specific time frame
and then how often I want to evaluate
those systems for their compliance so
all this is fine and dandy
I need reporting I need visibility so I
need that to happen two ways I need to
see a particular endpoint maybe I have a
compromised system I've taken an offline
I need to you know start going to prove
my process one of the things that I can
do is look at their compliance with that
particular base on local right so here
is the actual SCCM client agent
properties I go into the configuration
select that particular baseline that I
targeted with those CIS and I say you
report now I can look at that report
locally and determine is that system
apply with that particular baseline now
this is just to look at a local system
but there's some detail in years as I
scroll down you can see the compliance
information
severity all the CDE data about that
update which is really helpful if I
selected coffee paste it into Google
lookie there
CD details monitor now I know exactly
what's going on but I can also take that
particular CD ID plug it right into the
console and now I can see all the
relevant updates that are applicable to
that CBE detail right so now I realize
that it's not just Adobe that's impacted
by that particular update but Google
Chrome is also vulnerable would I have
had that bought that Intel invisibility
any other way so that's basically that
now the built-in reports give you that
bird's-eye view so we just looked at one
system now what is that collection
looked like that I targeted or my
overall environment how secure is it
based upon that update and as you can
see here there's a Adobe update
information now here's our Microsoft
updates so I'm getting like a bird's-eye
view of the entire environment based
upon that selection criteria so also
some customized reports this is a
community driven one that plugs right
into SCCM
now we get a lot more detail and that's
pretty much it as far as the integration
with secm any questions on that before
we start to wrap up okay so wrapping up
basically just kind of recap and where
we're out what we've covered here so you
know ultimately all these things matter
because when it comes to software
vulnerabilities and
these updates that are being released
unfortunately not every threat actor
operates on Microsoft schedule therefore
those 90% of applications out there that
are being patched that vulnerabilities
are being published they're not
necessarily happening on Patch Tuesday
schedule so we have to be able to bring
tools processes automation good thinking
into that and be able to be much more
reactive because we can't sit down or
sit on our ass and wait until Patch
Tuesday to be able to do something about
it
now all the automation controls that you
just looked at the way that we're able
to integrate into wsus in to SCCM think
about how you write your next change
control request and is it for that
moment in time that particular update or
can you theorized how you're going to
standardize your patching approach using
these tools and processes and get a
change control that says you have a
blank check if it fits these parameters
that you specified in this automatic
deployment girl or this group policy for
this particular update classification
criticality etc you get a blank check
from your change control board to let
you move forward with automating as much
of that process as possible that's
what's going to help you address a
higher number of bond abilities much
more of that 90% without having so much
of the overhead and expense for that
management process so we talked about
who the players are if you guys need
help evaluating this obviously I'm here
you know as a resource I have no problem
answering questions if you want to do
deep dive like a proof of concept we can
talk about that later so don't want to
interrupt or delay Dan brother is next
so don't change this channel don't go
anywhere
od Oh was there a change speed oh I'm
sorry
okay that's a diol thank you