six we're going to be taking a look into
the Windows registry and how we can
trick windows into believing it's had a
flash drive inserted that it has never
seen before so I am Alexander club all a
recent graduate of UTSA in the cyber
security and information systems dual
major with their College of Business I
was on their panoply team we took second
I was also a captain of the CCDC team
and president of the computer security
Association I consider myself a cyber
enthusiast it is my goal to make the
tech that we all use every day safer and
more accessible for everyone and my
master of puns you
no one knows puns better than I know
puns we've got the best puns that was no
good okay
I'd like to make this talk you know a
little me and you so don't be afraid to
ask questions I don't know where
everyone's going to be at they didn't I
wasn't expected to be thrown into this
track but I'm here anyway to talk to you
guys today so if you have any questions
you know just raise your hand if it's
gonna be answered on the next slide I'm
not gonna call on you if it's a dumb
question I'm going to ignore it and move
on but there's no such thing as stupid
questions keep that in mind
all right what's your question it can be
so today we're going to be talking about
the registry does anybody not know what
the Windows registry is okay well that's
fine because I'm gonna tell you about it
it is a hierarchical database that
Windows uses to store all the config
files for all the things every flash
drive you've plugged in external media
global settings it's used as an
initialization file in the older days of
Windows we used to have to have a little
dot ini initialization file for each
program you had installed the Windows
registry takes that and says oh you know
so we'll make it so that every user that
logs on can have you know their own set
of settings and we'll have these global
settings and everything's just pulled
together it makes it so that you can
also have less privileged users work
just well on your machine so where is
the registry located so we have these
registry hive keys that's what they call
them so you have the system key the Sam
key security software your profiles and
your 32 config this is where they
actually reside on the disk on your hard
disk so under C windows system32 config
have I lost anybody yet good good
today's focus we're going to be looking
at the the local machine system keys for
the current control set under what's
been enumerated under the USB storage
and under the USB keys itself the goal
as I had mentioned previously is to
trick Windows into thinking that a flash
drive
such as
this one or this one that the computer
has not seen has actually been inserted
into the system
yes I'm getting to that
why exploiting what can be done is
always fun say it with me it's more can
be done is always fun it also changes
sort of the the narrative digital
forensics investigations can have in you
know some court cases if they look
through and they see oh you know we're
looking for a SanDisk Cruiser flash
drive we can't find one but we think
that there may be some evidence that
could incriminate this guy let's go buy
one from Walmart and find weasel
confession out of them anyway they'll go
by an identical flash drive bring it in
to the interrogation room we found your
stuff boom full confession and this this
talk kind of flips that upside down
because so during my studies I took a
digital forensics class with dr. Nicole
baby you know huge forensics nun and she
was talking about how in the Windows
registry you have the list of USB drives
that have been inserted into the system
you can always delete the registry keys
so the absence of a key doesn't mean the
drive hasn't been plugged in but she had
suggested that if the keys are there the
drive has been plugged in I was the
first one to ask well can I just plant a
key and the class discussion ended
because my questions were to evil
so there is this neat little application
it's free and open source it's called
red shot what it will do it can take a
snapshot of your registry before you
make changes and after and run like a
differential between the two so you can
see what keys were modified what keys
were added other files that were added
and things like that whenever you
install software uninstall software or
insert a handy-dandy flash drive yes so
you're saying that login Dee will
actually take snapshots of the registry
and all you to differ
it's something that I'll have to look
into uh I'll talk more about it later
but I have more that I want to do with
this presentation so thank you I'll
definitely look into it
we took a snapshot here we I took a
snapshot here with red shot and that was
the pre snapshot plugged in my flash
drive into a computer that's never seen
it before and I was able to get a bunch
of registry keys that were added these
values were also modified and they added
some files and modified attributes so
now that we have these you know changes
in the registry what can we do with them
we can just take these keys pull them
from the registry and pop them into
another computer but not if you're just
an administrator you have to be more
than that
the registry exists at the low levels of
Windows like the the internal the guts
the heart the soul the reason that
you're here is what the Windows registry
is so as an administrator I had
attempted to export and then import
these flash drive registry keys I hadn't
merged them into one key you can't do it
as an administrator however you can as
the system running command prompt as NT
Authority being the boss I am the
computer you can do it
so how do you do that sysinternals
anyone not familiar with sysinternals
okay so uh Microsoft makes a bunch of
tools that are used for you know getting
a better look at what's going on with
your operating system the sysinternals
suite is available for free you can
check it out at live dot sysinternals
they have prospects explorers elevation
tools remote access tools all kinds of
fun stuff so what we're using today is
PS exec running it with the eye s and D
flags allows you to elevate that command
prompt that you'll pop as system so the
flags we're going to talk about the eye
flag first which lets the the program
that you tell it to run so PS exec Flags
what you're telling it to run everyone
with me okay so the eye flag says okay
we'll run command prompt so it interacts
with this desktop session on this system
since we're not you know indicating a
remote system it's this one right here
the s and D flags I'm s is for system
I'm gonna run it as the computer and D
is don't let it terminate so we have i
SD so now that we have these registry
entries and we know that we can import
them to a computer what can we do let's
take a look at a live demo now I haven't
done a demo before so I'm expecting it
to not work at all
just like the malware labs this morning
if anyone was there so here's my jam oh
no it's not
[Music]
don't look at my Google Drive okay so
while we wait for Windows to load I'm
going to talk a little bit no go away
going to talk a little bit about you
know where these registry keys are and
how you can remove them from your system
if you wanted to you know oh
delete flash drives that were inserted
into your computer so as I had said
before it's located under H key local
machine high key local machine system so
if you go in there and then find your
current control set you can then go to
the USB store and then just delete
followed that done yes right
yes
so since Windows uses the NTFS
filesystem there's always going to be
you know little traces of everything
everywhere
nothing is ever truly deleted unless you
purposefully zero out the drive or
randomize the drive and that leaves
artifacts of data deletion as well
because it's a lot more suspicious to
have zero zero zero zero zero zero zero
or a bunch of random characters in your
master file tables any other questions
so far have I lost anyone is anyone
completely lost excellent this is going
great
okay so there is this neat little free
tool from a developer called near soft
called us BD review D view if we open
that up we can see this doesn't talk
about any USB storage devices and if we
run regedit and we pull it up system
this is the current control said you
know we don't have a USB store key in
other words this virtual machine that I
just installed last night has not seen a
flash drive I exported the keys that
were created whenever I plugged this bad
boy in to my gaming computer which has
also never seen it so I was able to get
the the red shot diff from that to put
all of these keys in this neat little
folder labeled demo and so we've got the
the SanDisk keys if you just try to add
it to the registry you know as a regular
user
we'll say yes cuz you know we totally
want to have these registry values you
can't do it but you know who can yes
both of those are correct is it's the
same person so if we take a command
prompt run it as administrator and let's
CD over to my downloads directory yep
one oh I'm sorry
so PSM Zek what will my flags thank you
and we want CMD yes we agree to the
terms and conditions of using winter
rolls okay so as you saw you know
whenever just the regular command prompt
Who am I that's me this other command
prompt women window that I made it spawn
if we ask Who am I
anti-authority system so if we use reg
import gotta type the full path because
I don't have it you know sitting in my
system 32 me just gonna be one of those
days demo and then we have SanDisk one
rich successful
two successful and now if we take this
we close it out we close out of our I
get it and we wait and check this out
we open up regedit now we have a USB
store and now it talks about that
SanDisk if we open up the USB DV
mass storage SanDisk USB we scroll it
over slowly you get a serial number and
that's the actual serial number of this
drive that this computer has not had
plugged
any questions yes yes okay so the the
date you know is right now so that's
something that I've had to look into I
reached out to dr. bebe after I had you
know successfully pulled this off I
failed so many times trying to actually
get this to work I didn't think it was
possible
whenever I finally did manage to get
this besides was two days later so I was
either gonna have a really cool
presentation or a presentation about
failure and how awesome that can be so I
reached out to dr. Nicole Beebe at UTSA
and she actually got me in touch with a
mr. Harlan Carvey he's a Windows
registry expert and a forensics author
he's given me some other things to look
into and so I'm going to look into
modifying you know the the created dates
trying to see how I can fool the the set
up API log and automate all of it with
PowerShell that's next year's talk yes
oh yes okay so one of them imports the
the US beef store and the other one
imports into the the USB key itself so
if we do do do am I blind I'm blind open
and regedit yes it also adds this set of
keys in the the USB folder tree yes yes
the question was it's working here in
Windows 7
how about 8 or 10 the answer is not yet
haven't tried it yes sir it'll work all
right
maybe I'll have to try and run the
experiment running log MD see what it
makes send oh so you can
then you'll realize that you can catch
all that stuff see your activity right
you could you could switch you know CMD
instead HC and then pop stickykeys but I
feel with that edits you have to be able
to get to the Machine to be able to
reboot it to be able to switch the I'll
have to look into that
thank you there's absolutely
yes I don't have enough information to
answer your question the question was
could this be done with other devices
like network devices haven't tried it
yes I'm sure it could if all you're
doing is putting in the registry keys I
don't see why not
I'll add that to my list of things to
try I probably went a little too fast I
went way too fast does anybody have any
other questions before we maybe yes
mm-hmm
creation different times of the day
mostly it's going to de tráfico he was
great he's exactly the worse because
great service get all the institutions
are the tools of music seminars he'd
want a more perverted way of doing that
but you have to really understand what
trails you made from databases it's
think there's another way to go out for
the guy who's potentially doing this and
what Wi-Fi he uses maintains frontages
another an innovation harvest another
thing we do with for the network traffic
stuff that's how you tell they draw nose
on this Wi-Fi so I can't respond
now to be fair I'm normally a blue team
defensive kind of guy
I don't know how noisy the things I do
would be this is really my first like
foray into evidence manipulation if you
will yes resources they have detected
it's obviously an exploit that can be
used in the real question is why is it
even possible vs power for that I think
the presentation is good to show it's a
defense that you have to think about as
a security practitioner about how you
prevent someone from doing this kind of
stewardship thank you yeah just just a
little bit enough for you to freedom
Mexico
were there any other questions I know I
like completely blew through this time
so we've got some more time if you guys
one of the ask anything favorite color
it depends on the day of the week I'm
not using LP I are the last USB I
plugged into this is from this wireless
presenter now it may not it doesn't show
up as a storage device so we wouldn't
see it in this list here so the the data
protections like that enterprise would
have yeah sure
I don't have access to that I haven't
looked into too much of the open source
and I definitely don't have the budget
for enterprise I mean I just graduated
give me a job please as far as what what
I really wanted to target with this case
was more the individuals unless the
corporation and you know the individual
you know grandma down the street she's
not gonna have us be signing protection
I'm uh she's my grandma and I set it up
for her
that's a great idea yes
that's up to you guys I just proved that
it could be done you're going to figure
out what to do with it right
incriminating yourself well you can
actually take your laptop online and be
able to inject and Russ be attacked
without having to worry about only being
able to use the corporate issue USB
because it would weren't even recognized
and accepted by the system and that's
usually over that overrides whatever my
carbon black
so it's actually another thing I plan on
looking at important is so this serial
number is the actual serial number I
want to see if I can make a drive that
doesn't actually exist one that
literally doesn't exist not one that's
never been in the computer but one that
doesn't have physical form change the
serial makeup manufacturer things like
that so I've got places for this talk to
go but I didn't have my mentors get back
to me soon enough so it's like I blew
through all my slides too quick happens
all the time yes so so these these
created dates that's whenever I ran TS
exact command import there may be a way
for me to actually what was time stomped
the the values to change the values that
are reported and the registry because
you can alter the the metadata to you
know read right and accessed so we just
changed that and this is a good first
step
yes
let's find out okay so while I'm
changing the system time next question I
thought I saw a question over here
how did I what I'm not
come on yo ah it's opening too many I
did like the lamb this morning okay well
are you ready
no sit down oh look it's Thursday
let's open and regedit but let me delete
it from see this is why live demos are
always fun
yes
there you go
is the sole NT yes
haha
so there's no easy yes exact
but where's my right general where we go
VMware gotta love it right no wrong
control set bad
so we didn't have a USB store before and
now we don't so where was the key for
this bad guys we open any all right get
it just so I know where it is I didn't
write it down yes I do appreciate
y'all's patience it's an after-lunch
talk you know kind of relaxed
now it's just believe everything
okay and so we've got our system time to
Thursday we're in the past the
mysterious past
that that's uh come back over here Who
am I I'm still in t authority let's
import and import if we close that close
that well do what oh that's what I get
for not reading I haven't had enough
coffee yet well I broke it
so to answer your question yes but how
noisy is it probably very any last fall
it's questions comments concerns all
right well thanks for yes sorry I didn't
see it
yes yes you can do that so either by
modifying the the registry entries that
are already there or doing this remove
and insert the new one anybody else
going once going twice
class dismissed thanks for coming out