hello is the mic on oh cool
sounds good alright so my voice is
almost gone but that was as of yesterday
so I decided I'd come through and still
do the talk so forgive me for the
crackly voice so my name is Megan Roddy
I'm currently a senior security analyst
at reconsent a small MSSP startup I
recently graduated with my master's
degree I have a few security certs
I do this regularly this is like 12
times speaking at a security conference
and my first time with technical
difficulties I knew it'd come around
eventually
and that's my Twitter handle I'm almost
up to 600 followers so I'm almost
internet famous if you want to help me
get there so I'm not gonna spend too
long talking about gee sweet how many of
you use d sweet at work
just a few how many know what G sweet is
everyone knows what T sweet is kind of
so it's Google's like hey business
version think of it of the as the oh
three sixty five of Google it's gonna be
Google Drive Google Mail Google Calendar
all synced across the organization so as
a start-up MSSP we serve small small and
medium-sized businesses G Swedish cheap
and so we encounter a lot of g sweet
instances and so I started to learn
deeper in G sweet hence the origin of
this talk so first we're going to talk
about a bit about defer G sweet versus
traditional
and when I see traditional defer I'm
talking about your traditional Windows
domain environment a bunch of domain
connected computers emails on the
on-prem exchange server connect and your
users are connected via ad
everything's local machines so obviously
there's a bunch of different cases of
deeper but that's that's kind of what
I'm speaking about when I say
traditional deeper so I'm not going to
go too much into the red team from Black
Hills InfoSec that's this link at the
bottom and I'll share out my slides
later so you have it
but the kill chains gave me the same
reconnaissance they're gonna find out
what your G suite domain is and after
that try and figure out what it counts
exist so that's going to be recon that
you do with other email address findings
so you find out the company uses the
format of first dot last name at corpnet
so then you just generate a list based
on the list of employees at LinkedIn
some malware or breaking in through
insecure firewalls and here we're going
to talk more about brute forcing
phishing social engineering exploitation
getting those credentials using the
methods access we had Keith's
persistence and we'll talk a bit more
about that later
command and control there's there's not
as much of that command and control
aspect of malware calling home because
the attacker can access the console from
wherever they are they're not remote
going into a domain environment then
there's a lot of things they can do with
the account they can act fill data they
can abuse the account for their own
purposes so again the great talk about
how to read Team G sweep I'm gonna move
on and talk about the blue team side of
things
there's a whole range of different
incidents that you can encounter you can
counter malware phishing denial of
service web attacks and that's just a
short list starting off and some other
the attacks and these can all be seen at
a traditional environment but the the
sole ones that we're kind of really
focusing on and G suite are really
related to the mail and the file storage
which are fishing potential for leak of
information and their potential for
account abuse so those are do fall under
traditional d4q but that's the the focus
of what's gonna happen what your guess
C&G suite for the attack the G suite is
hosted on Google servers and you're
accessing it through Google in the cloud
so you're not gonna see the attack
vectors like SQL injection web attacks
because Google's got it pretty locked
down and if you do experience that
compromised then there's a whole bigger
issue it's Google's fault the platform
is owned by them so in a traditional
environment if they may have gone
through your firewalls they may have
exploited a web app they could have fish
or social engineered or brute force and
that's what the only thing we're really
gonna see in G suite deeper is that
method of getting login credentials
because that's the only way you're going
to access
so in terms of the environment again
traditional deeper we're talking about
big networks tons of computers servers
workstations network devices firewalls
and in terms of the configuration I mean
you might have a de tu Active Directory
or something like that to sexually
configure like the workstations but
really you're gonna have a bunch of
widespread configurations if an attacker
gets in they can reconfigure the local
machine settings or if they access a
network device they can reconfigure
those settings so you've got say spread
all over the place where the G suite we
have a single platform that Cloud G
suite platform and you have all the core
configurations set settings centralized
to your admin console and so when you're
trying to find out what the current
settings in the environment are or if
somebody might have changed settings
you've kind of got that single pane of
glass as opposed to logging in to 40
different types of devices trying to see
where settings may have changed so kind
of the summary of that is that
traditional v4 when we're talking about
regular d4 we talk about a large attack
services a ton of different types of
they may be responding to and looking
for evidence or artifacts there's tons
of sources tons of configuration tons of
data stored in different places where Z
sweet you've got you have to get a log
in to log in you you need specific
there's maybe a few specific incident
types that you encounter as opposed to a
bunch of different methods and all your
data and configuration settings are
contained within the platform so I
didn't spend too much time kind of going
on the whole overview because I think
that's more useful to be able to show
you guys what what I'm putting into
practice so this is the scenario details
are going to be pretty generic NDA but
this is something an actual incident I
worked so it's it's coming from it real
life it's not made up basically we got
an email saying oh so it was a company
they had a bunch of clients rich private
people and all their clients specific to
their client list it seemed like maybe
their client listed leaks like those
people are getting spam and phishing
emails related to this company and so it
seemed like someone found the client
list but they don't publish the client
was publicly there's no no way they
could have done publicly and I thought
well the only place that we really have
all that information would be in the
emails or files or contacts in our D
suite instance but we have no idea like
we weren't tact as far as we know we
weren't fished so so how did they get in
so they contracted recon to come in and
find out where we compromised so
starting this incident
we know there might be a compromise
nothing has been done because they don't
know if there's a compromise and we need
to find out everything we need to find
out who compromised them when where they
compromised how where they compromised
why were they compromised so like I said
performing SQL injection bypassing the
only real entrances by logging in
whether that was because they brute
force the credentials are fished or
whatever so you can export the law on it
logs in G's suite of all the logins
and this is the less detailed version it
just says IPD event you can also see
whether they were logging in using
single sign-on on another application or
whether they were using Outlook or
something to log on but for our purposes
we just want to see all the IPS well
here we have three unique IPS pretty
pretty easy to parse through you do some
who is see if anything strange going on
and if you did you'd find out there's
two u.s. IP addresses and then there's a
Chinese IP address and if my
calculations are right Bob cannot log in
from the US at 6:00 p.m. oven be in
China at midnight so something's were
wrong but that's all fine for this but
so a lot of it for me at the time was
manual review I uploaded a lot of them
into like a geo IP lookup and then kind
of scrolled through cross correlated
which IPS were which users so it took a
good amount of time but sure enough we
have actually found huh
strange Alice
this and then five minutes later she
logged on from India and so there was
kind of definitely sub abnormal activity
and you may think so like maybe she was
using a VPN or something that was
messing with the IP address to be a
different location but typically our
clients we're dealing with their
outsourcing their IC in cyber security
for a reason so they're not using fancy
tools that would mess with their IP and
sure enough so then we have we have this
one IP so we have the IP sorry Allah so
once once I did this work so I did all
the work and he was like wow that was
really manuals so I'm gonna make it not
manual now that the incidents over but
now you guys don't have to do what I did
so he wrote a python script you you
upload the CSV that I showed you and it
plots all the logins and it's actually
color coded so like red his failed login
yellow is one thing boom is successful
long and it's plotted on a map this is
pretty usable activity especially the
company we knew they occasionally went
into the Bahamas and stuff like that so
you know nothing strange about the
Mexico Cuba type of logins but then when
you plot this at the same time that
starts getting a little suspicious that
you have a cluster of lions in the US
and then you have these blue successful
logins in Africa a few minutes later so
this is really cool tool now that's open
source you go to that blog post it has a
link it's actually an interactive map
you can click on the little points and
see what exactly it means and so like if
I click on that point it says Alice
logged in at whatever time so now it's
all automated but before we manually
reviewed the logs so at this point we
know that there's definitely something
weird going on and we know what user was
affected
we also have the time stamps for the
logins so we know now that this attacker
has been in the system for four months
and they hadn't noticed until now and
he's been logging in from Africa on and
off over the course of the past several
months
so yeah winner is Alice and four months
ago so we start our containment phase of
incident response we disabled her
account we reset the password on her
account we leave it disabled until the
entire scenario is complete and also
Google the cool thing is you can reset
the lock in sessions from the admin
panel for a user so that attached
credentials also get cleared so that
that attacker was using cached
credentials it would force those cookies
to be deleted and that attacker would
have to real aughh in and with the
password change that didn't work so we
come back to our where are we now we
know whose account was compromised we
know when it was compromised at this
point we know that the login activity
we're seeing with the compromised
account is not happening anywhere else
those strange abnormal overseas logins
are only happening with this one account
so we're not 100% positive but there's a
good chance this is the only account
that's compromised at this point
what have we done we've disabled the no
compromised account done a password
reset in preparation for it being
renamed and we've reset every existing
session so now we don't need to know all
the things we have a few things look we
need to know how did the attack happen
how did they get in what was the account
used for once they were in and was there
any persistence in place after they got
in so first we we think about the
methods that they could have gotten
those credentials failed fancy event a
success unless they happen to guess the
correct password on the first try but
what we we didn't see that we didn't see
a bunch of attempts of failures of n/a
success so it was kind of indicative
that they they had the password at the
time they were entering it so I thought
well it's phishing that's when we hit a
brick wall because at their lowest tier
you get all the things you get Google
Drive you get Gmail all their
applications but email retention is 30
days and the attacker has been in the
system for 4 months and so our best
guess is that she received a phishing
email she of course was like no I didn't
I swear but one it's been four months
two users always say they didn't receive
the phishing email so we would have
liked to search the logs from the time
period that the login got like that
would have been our ideal thing see what
email she received at that time and
looked for the email that said like
fishing in the subject line but we did
not get to do that because it was a
premium feature so our the best we could
get due to the retention periods and the
amount of time the attacker had been in
the system is most likely based on the
methods that the
has and based on the logs we do have it
was likely fishing so then we want to
see what did they do when they were and
Google they log everything there's no
like turning on blogging it's not like
Windows where you go to do an
investigation and you're like cookie
show me those logs and I well we didn't
turn on logging so logging is all turned
on so we export all the logs the
screenshot I put there because it's uh
we use the hives if you haven't looked
at the hive case management system it's
an open source case management system
and it's a great platform you should
look it up but we created tasks to
review everyone logs analysts picked
them up put eyes manually reviewed the
activities specifically we kind of
looked at it overall but we're really
keying in on that one compromised
account trying to see what did they do
what did they walk into what did they
change any settings did they do anything
strange with email etc etc again we
ended up not really getting anything
from it it didn't seem like they did a
thing they just came for the comments
they from what it seems they logged in
and they looked around and that turn up
aligns with what we were told like heat
off the company - the thing is that
somebody was taking proprietary
information customer data client lists
and using it for other purposes spamming
and fishing and stuff so in some sense
it's not surprising it also meant that
there wasn't much more evidence to find
because they got in they pulled the
client list and they kept logging in
over the four months on occasion so it
looks like they were just sitting there
reading the data seeing what they could
use from that information so it was a
breach of confidentiality rather than
integrity so going back to persistence
this is theirs
we basically had to manually check all
of the settings of G suite to see if any
of these kind of methods exist it'd be
nice if I had all the elite programming
skills and could automate this but I
just had the ideas like because G suite
has an API where you can call the
settings so like ideally you'd be able
to call all these settings and check
them but I'm a plebe and don't program
so I just mainly check all these
settings but it said the ways you can
think about how they would persist
because obviously you don't have
scheduled tasks or startup registry keys
to make your malware ever you want run
so there's at passwords so of course I
get to the point where we say if 2fa
would have been in place new have been
good well adding to FA after if they're
at passwords may not help at all because
at passwords are free when you have like
a mail client and you have be sweet you
have to FA enabled both the mail client
doesn't know how to handle to FA so
instead you have to give it basically a
password only account that's specialized
for that use but if I'm an attacker I
have the password I figure they're gonna
finally get smart and put to FA on I can
basically sync to my mail client with
that specialized password that doesn't
require second factor token you need to
check to make sure there's no app
passwords really that the attackers
added and remove them if so there's a
lot you can do with api's in Google and
you have to authorize the API but if
while I'm in the system I create api's
that will send me information and
datoria approved it's just gonna keep
going so that's another aspect you need
to look at going back to the two fa
thing if I'm afraid to a phase I go on
the account like I'm pretty positive I
could get back in social
whatever but now they're gonna have to
FA I can add my own to sa device that I
now use once you enable to a thing like
I turn it on for you but I set up on my
phone too I could if I notice you've
enabled it while I'm in the account I
can download those backup codes so that
I can retrieve he's the backup codes
logon later in case of this person who
was really just interested and it seemed
interested in getting proprietary
information if they were smarter they
would have set up like email forwarding
and forwarded all emails to their own
personal account so that even when
you're kicked out all her emails are
still going to you so you don't even
have to log in because she's basically
forwarding you all her emails and they
get email filters similar things setting
up redirects or something so that emails
go to you that's also a method of
staying hidden once you get in is making
sure that you have email filters like if
there's any google suspicious login
alerts that those emails aren't being
delivered
so the key moral of the story is use
two-factor authentication if you aren't
logging in via the web use two-factor
authentication it's it's your password
it's like the only thing that is really
truly without a doubt gonna keep that
account secure and it was one thing when
everything was on prem and you couldn't
access email easily for outside but when
you're using gmail to log in you should
have to affect a enabled for everyone
that's that's kind of the if only they
would have moral the thing is people
think 2fa is hard and executives don't
like to do 2fa so they just say it's not
a requirement so when you inevitably
come across a company that was breached
and they didn't have 2fa on the lesson
is that like Ron Swanson and bacon you
should be prepared
as an incident responder you are going
to come across environments that you may
not be familiar with tools that you may
not be familiar with I was lucky because
working with an MSP it wasn't an
internal incident where there's an
incident and it was go we had the whole
contract signing an NDA and all that
stuff so I had a little while a few
hours where I knew what was coming
so I read every single D Suite
documentation I could actually the kind
of the reason I started writing this
presentation I've wrote it written a
blog post on it was there wasn't much on
D Ferengi suite specifically but I read
all the documentation I my company uses
D suite so I walked into our admin panel
and I clicked on every single setting so
that when I got into the clients
environment I would feel comfortable and
know what I'm doing so that idea of if
you could encounter it be prepared for
it and the the other flip side of it
though the environment can change the
core fundamentals the court procedures
related to Incident Response are gonna
stay the same yes you may click on a
different button here there or you may
check for different things but overall
you're still following the NIST Incident
Response framework of preparation
detection and analysis containment
eradication and remediation and post
incident activity that's not going to
change it's just the mindset that you
need to bring with it and you need to
adjust that mindset especially as we're
moving into non-traditional environments
we're moving into cloud environments and
other situations where kind of the
things are going to work differently so
I have to know that there's less limited
ways to get in but there's also more
ways they could in different ways they
could establish persistence I knew I
wasn't going to get a hard drive and run
memory forensics but I knew I was going
to have a bunch of logs regarding
I'd have to look at so it's that
flexibility that we need and I are
especially and defer especially as
environments are changing there's moving
to the cloud there's things like
containerization like is this like kind
of a specialty like I'm even forensic
people in this room who feel comfortable
getting a hard drive and doing hard
drive forensics would you feel
comfortable if I gave you a docker
container that you had to perform
forensic analysis on it's those kinds of
things where you may not come across it
now but there's a good chance that one
day he will come across it so even if
you can't prepare for every environment
in terms of the exact controls you need
to use you should be preparing to alter
your mindset based on the environment
you're going into my talk we ran a
little short but if you guys have any
questions I'd be happy to answer them
yeah
well in my situation the clients we work
with our SMBs
and they don't have anyone that's where
you ask them who their IT team is and
they're like well Jerry took a computer
class once and really kind of knows what
he's doing
so we don't get in contact with their
team we did I mean we did talk to the
client I say like did you click a
phishing email four months ago but like
I said like one even if they were gonna
tell me it's unlikely they didn't
remember and sure enough they said no we
haven't um there is the logs that they
do have our pretty detailed and what
what we would do in this situation
obviously this was like a one-time they
called us for IR but for our clients who
we perform regular monitoring services
on if they have d suite we'd use the you
can forward those logs to a sim with
their API so we'd get those in the sim
and even though Google's not keeping
them for more than 30 days we would keep
them for more than 30 days so that's
kind of the preparation phase of IR
making sure that you have what you need
when the time comes that you need it yep
they were using Google Drive for company
documents so um yes so it's kind of like
so it's kind of cool because it's not
the exact file mimic metadata and the
says that you see on a Windows machine
but you can't look at the files and see
the tanks date and revision history we
did review the files to see if any had
been altered there'd been no altering
there'd been no sharing that's another
method of persistence kind of that it
touch on you could set the share the
Google Drive files to be publicly
accessible so even if you kick me out I
can still go look at all those files I
shared but there's no evidence of
messing with the settings related it
seemed like they didn't have any
persistence they were just looking and
at the time we we did not have
we're not able to look into whether
there was methods of seeing who view
defile that'd be interesting for further
research but at that point we did not
I don't believe they did it was all up
there so yeah I mean it is possible
again the the date oh it wasn't clearly
there it's not in the metadata whether
it's um a downloaded it so it is
possible that they downloaded the files
locally but it's getting more research
figuring out where the evidence is for
that yep
um the you're talking about Google's
archiving functionality
yes so that's one of the paid features
where it's not on the lowest here is
like tiers two and three yeah
it I think they have it the one below
two which is like Google business or
Google teams or something but at the
lowest tier you get the products and you
get 30 days email retention logs seem to
stay on there more than 30 days it's
only emails that roll over but yeah they
there is a built-in backup functionality
if you pay the additional amount yep
any other questions
[Applause]