[Music]
hi everyone
um andy and i are really happy to be
here at devsevcon24
um really excited to tell this talk
where we're going to be telling you
stories about five different security
incidents that
basically andy has lived through in his
previous life at ciso as ciso at akmai
and talking about what they mean for
building secure systems
specifically for supporting access to
infrastructure
um so who are we i'm sharon goldberg i'm
the ceo and co-founder of bastian xero
we also have andy ellis who is an
operating partner at wild ventures andy
and i have known each other for about a
decade
um me coming from a research background
um and previously andy worked as a cso
um and um and here we are in our new
roles
as ceo and vc so um
i guess we'll just get started yes let's
do that
let's do it okay yeah so you know what
we're specifically talking about
is administrative access to resources in
the cloud
so a lot of organizations and i think
everyone here is familiar with building
systems to keep outsiders
out of your cloud you know you don't
want arbitrary people getting in
and accessing your system so we've got
firewalls we've got software gateways
we've got
intrusion protection systems all this
stuff is there but at the end of the day
you may still need your incident
responders your sres your devops folks
still need to get in sometimes to be
able to see what's going on when things
break and really sort of locking this
access
out is very hard to do for a lot of
organizations
so what we really want to talk about
here is administrative access sort of
insider access to cloud environments
and security principles that are
important to consider when you're
providing this type of administrative
access
and this is going to be a history lesson
in five acts andy what are the acts
so our act started in 2001 with fluffy
bunny
we're going to jump forward and talk a
little about operation aurora
in 2009 then the diginotar incident in
uh and then we're going to wrap up with
not petchen solar winds for some recent
history
we're going to go from a 20-year history
of different incidents many of which
andy had to actually deal with um when
they were happening in his environments
so it'll be fun to hear from andy about
some of that
okay so let's start with sort of the
classic architecture that
is still in place um in a lot of
organizations and is very dear to my
heart as the ceo of bastian xero
and so this is a bastion architecture so
in the classic bastion architecture what
you would have is you would have
an engineer that has an ssh key you have
a bastion host
that's got a public ip this engineer is
able to ssh
into the bastion host and from there can
use this fashion host to access
infrastructure um in inside the cloud
some of which may be on private
on private ips um in this particular
example we're going to give
we're going to actually walk through the
fluffy bunny um incident and so with
this particular bastion host that andy
and i have here
has an ssh key that allows access to one
of the targets that's actually sitting
on the bastion house so the bastion host
itself is housing ssh keys i want to
mention that a lot of
organizations may not have this ssh key
actually sitting on the bastion they may
have it actually sitting on the user
on the user's machine but in any case
that's what we're going to start with
and andy why don't you walk us through
what happened in 2001 and in fact in
2001 it's even worse because
many of these systems are using ssh
passwords
so just rep pretend that key is actually
a password
and in this case you know the adversary
would compromise someone's machine
doesn't matter whose it was
and they would just replace the ssh
client and what that ssh client would do
was log keys and passwords
but not past phrases this is the one
sort of saving incident
saving grace of this incident is that it
doesn't log the passphrase that encrypts
the ssh key
but when the user logs in now the
adversary has that credential
the password and then they log into the
bastion host the same way that the user
did
uses the local privilege escalation to
get root access
replace the ssh client and now when
someone logs in from that bastion host
to any machine
the adversary gets their credential and
is able to
connect further and this adversary
basically moved through a number of
environments level three akamai a number
of other places
just sort of collecting ssh passwords
and what systems they were good at
uh going after so taking advantage of
these points where you'd collect
because one user would log in and now
you would get 50 users
credentials or 100 users credentials so
it's like a really to me really
incredible attack in the sense that this
adversary just
ripped out your ssh client replaced it
with malware that x filled the keys and
just kept moving laterally through
um stealing stealing credentials in this
way and this was 2001.
2001 and and this attacker group
actually got really excited because they
knew they'd breached
akamai what they didn't realize is that
our deployed network what they really
wanted to have control of
used ssh keys to log in not passwords
and since they weren't copying the
passphrases they didn't get access to
that
instead they just had access to you know
developer systems you know
managed to steal some old source code
they thought that would be really
helpful to them
and we were very fortunate that we just
detected it quickly and were able to
purge it out of our environment
so why don't you walk us through sort of
some of the lessons that akamai learned
and that we can all take from this type
of
type of incident so first of all
important lesson
is don't try to get to perfect in an
incident
what can you do very quickly to make it
better and then incremental steps so
you know eliminate the standing
credentials we actually segregated our
bastion hosts so that the ones that were
being used
for people to get into their desktops
were not the ones people were using to
then connect out to the deployed network
we wanted to
separate those those hadn't actually
been separated you know we moved away
from storing credentials on those hosts
it took us a while
to do that so you know migrated to ssh
identities
then it was identities that were being
you know put into
an agent on those bastion hosts and then
eventually it was
a transparent proxy it's only
transparent to the user
uh where you would log in and your
credentials would
you know allow you to splice to a
forward connection to where you want it
to go to
so each of these we're trying to remove
that that single point of compromise
uh you know or at least reduce its scope
if you have that thing that is that
valuable allowing
lots of users to log into it was
certainly a problem for us
i want to highlight like the the one of
the interesting things about this
incident was that the adversary was able
to exfil these credentials
and then use them later and so what this
what this really points to sort of for
modern architectures and i think
most people listening to this already
know this is that standing credentials
are bad
right and the reason they're bad is
because if they get stolen they can be
used in the future and that's what you
don't want
right you do not want to be relying on
these credentials that are super long
lived
yeah so certainly in a case here where
you're using sort of this two-stage
credential you may be getting the user's
credential to rotate quickly is hard
but that second stage credential you can
have on an automated rotation system
so even if it's x filled it's a smaller
window that it's useful
right okay so now another classic
architecture that we're all familiar
with so vpn so why do we have vpns for
access
well because we have this notion that
the user which is out in the internet
like here
me on my laptop at home i shouldn't be
able to access these targets in the
cloud just like that
i should be they should be sort of
hidden somewhere that i can't get into
so essentially what we have is a bunch
of targets on private ips
and then a vpn that we can use to access
these targets um
and so what i find really interesting
about this is that
this this incident that andy's going to
talk us through in a second is operation
aurora is sort of like the classic
uh a classic example for why just
sticking your stuff behind a vpn is not
necessarily going to be
good enough so why don't you walk us
through what happened here
so this one's interesting in that we
don't actually know all the details of
what happened
because the adversary had such a long
dwell time
that the first way that they got in we
really didn't understand
and a challenge of this architecture in
general is the
philosophy people end up with from risk
compensation they say oh look i'm behind
the firewall
i can't have adversaries connecting to
me so if i don't patch my system it's
not the end of the world
if i don't harden the system it's not
the end of the world so what happens
here is
first the adversary gets access to some
machine
now that could be a spear phishing
attack compromises a desktop
any number of ways we don't actually
know how they first got in
certainly to our enterprise because we
get notified like a year later
from of all people google heather adkins
calls me up one day and says
hey by the way you are compromised
because we're now running the command
and control server
for this botnet because it had been
abandoned so they just
grabbed the domain name and saw who was
connecting to it but once the adversary
is in
now they're in this like soft squishy
inside and so they can move
laterally inside the environment until
they find the systems that are going to
be interesting to them
uh and they're they're often not doing
things that are obviously bad
certainly from a network perspective you
know they're not running crypto miners
that are going to be noticeable
because they're looking very carefully
for something of value
in this case you know the system in our
environment that they got on was uh
financial uh reporting software that
we use to do our public earnings
announcements
but in a lot of enterprises are also
used to do things like
validate which line of code is the most
profitable one in your business
we didn't have that module but you can
see how that would be a very useful
thing for an adversary to get is your
entire source code
indexed by how profitable every module
within it is
and so um you know in terms of the
takeaways this is the this is sort of
the lesson for all
sort of modern um modern segmentations
of of clouds and networks right um so
what what happened at akamai you know
after this after this happened what did
you guys change we started a 10-year
initiative so
sometimes you move really slow sometimes
you move fast
you know one of the things we did that's
going to be relevant in a couple of
our history lessons was segmenting our
user permissions our administrator
permissions
but really this is where we start to
segment our architecture and you know
don't base trust on
network location which many of you may
recognize as one of the core principles
behind the whole zero trust movement
that becomes popular
and who are sort of the two big
companies that push zero trust plays
over the last 10 years is google and
document
both of whom are breached in operation
aurora so what you start to see is this
movement to say
how do we do you know authentication at
the application layer
how do we ensure that you just can't
talk to ports if you don't need to
that if i'm you know a user i should be
able to talk to a web service but
there's no reason for me to talk to
any other protocol on a server because
i'm not an administrator
so we don't just say oh you're inside
the firewall
let's give you access to things and in
fact at the the culmination of our
10-year journey
we kick our users outside the firewall
most
employees at akamai by day i left were
not
ever inside the vpn everything they did
came over
proxied web you know connections so that
we
didn't trust them just because they
happened to be employees or physically
located in one of our buildings
celine brought up zero trust and i
actually think that's a great segue into
the next
um into the next sort of set of slides
so um
so this is a little bit of what xero
trust access
looks like today in a lot of products
that are out there in the market
and what's happening in these types of
architectures is the goal is to get rid
of standing credentials right we don't
want to have
alice over here you know here she is
we don't want her to have a key that
lives forever because we worry about
fluffy bunny coming in and actually
exfilling that key and using it six
months later to hack our systems right
so we want to give her short-lived
credentials short-lived access
um we want to segment access right so we
want to when alice wants to access the
server we want to first validate like
does she even really need access to this
server does she have
a policy or a role or an authorization
or whatever your system may do
that justifies giving her access right
and so one of the ways to do this is to
have alice come in
um and and go to some sort of authority
and say hi i'm alice she authenticates
to the authority and then she gets some
sort of credential that gives her access
to the targets
and in this example we're looking at
certificate authorities as one way of
getting this credential right so here's
an example of a certificate
this is going to be a short-lived
certificate maybe it only lives for a
couple of hours
and alice can use it to get access to
this target um
and you know the certificate's got the
name of the issuer her
and identity and the signature of the
issuer right but it's worth noting
that you know the big advantage here is
those end users those end machines don't
need to know
anything about alice in advance and
there's nothing that says this
credential has to be short-lived
in fact when we think about a web server
certificate which is the same thing
or a client certificate often those have
one year long life spans or multi-year
and that can lead to sort of our the
challenge here so why don't you walk us
through an incident
that exploits this sharon yeah so this
is actually one of the things that i've
been teaching in my cyber security class
for 10 years
um because it's 10 years old but it's
it's it's really
like a watershed moment i think in
insecurity for for at least for tls
so so this is what happened so there was
a certificate authority
that that was serving um assets in the
netherlands they were doing like you
know the dutch
rmv and things like this um and they
were able to issue certificates and the
way that they issued certificates like i
showed in the previous picture was that
they would sign them with their key
and give them to whoever needed them and
those were allowed those were used to
establish tls connections
this dutch ca was actually trusted
broadly across the world because
their key that yellow key that you see
was baked into
a lot of different browsers and so even
if i wasn't in
holland but i wanted to access the dutch
rmv i could like
get a certificate from diginotar that
would validate that the dutch rmv is who
they say they are
and then i could go visit their website
securely however what happened
this attacker and we still don't know
who this was um
stole the certificate authority key
compromised that key
and started issuing bogus certificates
for whatever it wanted
what it actually ended up issuing was a
certificate to its
to uh to google so that it could
impersonate google and decrypt all the
traffic that was going to google and
what it ended up doing was
reading and introspecting on um iranian
users connecting with their email this
is what ended up happening here
and why did this whole thing happen it
happened because the key the signing key
for the certificate authority
was not securely protected that was the
flaw
and so one flaw because what there's
some more flaws here
so why don't you walk us through some of
our takeaways yeah so there
that that is that was the sort of main
thing that i wanted to say there was
this key right that did you know turkey
that everyone was trusting and it was
acting as a root of trust for all of the
browsers and when it was compromised
you could compromise all you know
anything you wanted in the whole
internet that's the crazy part of this
story
right so there were two issues here one
the fact that there was just one key
stored in just one place at diginotar
which the genotar apparently didn't do a
good enough job protecting
and the second thing that was a really
crazy thing about this is the over broad
scope
so like why is my web browser trusting
this weird little dutch certificate
authority why should i trust it
you know to give certificates to google
which is not in the netherlands at all
right this dutch ca that was supposed to
be serving the netherlands only
was not scoped only to dutch assets it
was actually scoped
to the whole internet and therefore
google got compromised uh google was not
compromised but therefore they could
issue a certificate the attacker could
issue a certificate for google
so like bringing us back to the zero
trust story right when we see these
modern systems that are being based on
short-lived certificates and certificate
authorities
for me you know you need to go and you
need to look at them and say to yourself
wait a minute have we just created a
very strong
point of compromise where the
certificate authority's key if stolen
could compromise my entire
infrastructure and what is the scope of
this key is the scope
so large that i can compromise like all
my clouds and all my infrastructure just
imagine how sort of risky that could be
if you're basing your um your access on
a certificate authority
and i think at this at this point we're
we're saying stuff that's obvious for
tls but i don't think yet obvious
um in the zero trust market absolutely
all right so this is uh i've got to turn
this one over to you because i've never
done
much work witho yeah so
yeah there's lots of ways to administer
uh microsoft domain
um and there's great ways and there's
the out-of-the-box ways
and what often happens when you're
administering a domain is
your domain admins have an
administrative credential and
this is often their password but then it
gets converted into
sort of a ticket that they're going to
move around
and what happens is you know they often
do their work from some administrative
servers they log in with the credential
and now they're
on that system with their credential you
notice it's very similar to the bastion
host
and then they're going to do systems
administration and so they're going to
reach into
a machine and do software updates or
configuration changes
and again they often are using the same
administrative credential this is not a
requirement
but it is basically the default out of
the box
but you notice now this credentials in a
lot of different places in the
environment
and that can be a problem and a
challenge for a lot of enterprises
and so i want to walk you through sort
of what happens to a lot of entities in
not pecha
so not petches some ransomware and it
used a watering hole attack in the
supply chain so didn't even wait for
users
and for those who are not familiar with
watering hole attack that's where you
compromise something and wait for people
to come to you
the same way that you might you know as
a bandit wait at the watering hole for a
caravan to come to you and in this case
it was a ukrainian tax software
that if you did business in the ukraine
you had to connect
and get a software update on a regular
basis
and it happens that the admin is logged
in software update happens
and that machine is now compromised and
there's administrative credentials
available
you know this also had fallbacks where
it would you know spread laterally using
exploits
but what happens is once you have this
credential compromised
now that malware is able to spread in
the environment
and so it's just going to move simply
through the environment
compromising more and more machines
until it ends up basically with your
entire environment
if you had sort of one simple
environment and of course
does the adversary have to like wait for
um for me to show up on this box before
it steals my credential
well it actually doesn't really need to
in this case because you're there
triggering the software update sometimes
it might need to wait you know that's
why it's going to look for other ways of
spreading as well
so this one is sort of a combination of
that lack of network segmentation
and the single level credentials and so
once the machines are all compromised
it's ransomware and so ransomware does
what ransomware does
and that is it's going to sort of
basically wipe all of these machines
yeah i guess technically it encrypts
them but from the point of view of your
business now that encryption
is complete it's completely destroyed
your business and so we saw major
you know pharmaceutical companies
shipping companies were out of business
for
multiple days trying to recover from
this recently we've seen now the
colonial pipeline
we've seen meat packing and so this is a
very common attack that happens comes in
in different ways
but it's really about the ability of
ransomware to move laterally
within these environments that tend to
have sort of one tier of administrative
trust
one tier of administrative trust right
so that's that's uh
that's the the key here like when i saw
this by the way i was like the first
time andy showed this to me i was really
surprised to see that the same admin
credential was just working across
all of these machines right and that
that's the part that's sort of like
incredible in 2017 using the same admin
credentials across all these machines
even though this is apparently a very
common
way to do things because it's the
easiest way to do it it means that your
administrators don't have to think
really hard about it
you know a best practice is to tier
these and you say
you know you have one administrative
credential for administering laptops and
a different one for servers
and a different one for the domain
servers but those are still
a pretty broad scope you don't tend to
have this short-lived credential that
only works at that one
one point you know the software supply
chain clearly also a problem here
a challenge when you're forced to use a
piece of software so it's not like you
can do a whole lot of vetting
but you're getting a software update
onto a live running machine in a
production environment
you know that's a recipe for some danger
so so to summarize right i think what
what we're seeing here with this one if
i take a step back is like again we're
seeing a standing credential that admin
password and it's not just like a single
credential for a single machine like
when i i i think in the fluffy bunny
case maybe there could have been a
separate ssh key for each one of the
targets in the
in that environment right in this case
there's a same administrative
password that's allowing you to access
all of the machines in that environment
and that part is that like that's the
kind of um
the crazy part at least if you look at
this from a thousand feet like how could
it be that there's one credential but
apparently this is this is called it's
very
very very common right why don't we look
at a different one now
okay so let's go let's kind of go back
to sort of the more the
the the more modern approach to this the
zero trust approach so this picture
looks almost identical to the
certificate authority
picture that we had before um where what
we had before was that there was a
certificate authority issuing a
short-lived credential
and so this again this is a very
unlikely the ad case where we have a
single admin password that
accesses all the boxes what we're going
to do is every time a user comes in
alice or the admin or whoever she's
going to authenticate to the identity
provider
she's going to get a token the token is
going to identify her
and the targets are going to validate
that the token is correct
and allow her to come in if if she has a
valid token
right but again you know this looks very
similar because once again we have this
signing key that the identity provider
uses very analogous to the signing key
that the certificate authority provider
uses
um and so you know we get the benefits
of zero trust where we have
a short-lived credential right this sso
token
we can have authentication to this
authority we can have the authority deny
access if you don't need access to a
particular target right so we can
segment our network so this is really
nice
but solar winds okay
so um so let's talk a little bit about
the ways that this can go wrong
um so the solarwinds attack in 2020
we're
now at sort of the end of our of our
historical story
um is almost like the modern equivalent
of the diginotar incident
but this one is sort of affecting
individual enterprises and so what was
happening here
was the adversary um did compromise
some targets on the in in the customers
environment
in the in the victims environment so
imagine this thing gets compromised
and the adversary manages to actually
steal
the identity providers key and i have a
typo in the slides here that should say
identity provider
so the adversary manages to steal the
identity provider's key
and now because it has the signing key
for the identity provider it can
issue sso tokens for itself
and basically access any part of the
network that it wants
right so this is almost the same as what
happened with diginotar where you had
fraudulent certificates what you have
now
because the adversary stole the key what
you have now is again you have
fraudulent sso tokens
because the adversary stole the key so
andy i mean
what do we what do we learn from this um
you know from this incident amongst all
the other things that that
sort of we've taken away from from solar
winds you know i think we're
we see some of the same lessons we've
had before that that single root of
trust is very dangerous when it has that
over broad scope of authority
and when it's just one entity if that
entity gets breached
and it basically has administrative
access for your entire enterprise
then you're going to have a really bad
day and of course you know this
they did originally come in through the
software supply chain so it is something
to
pay attention to and so what do you what
do you have to say about this
this particular incident in light of the
fact that so many organizations are
moving
moving to an sso model for access to two
different different parts of their
networks
you know i think looking at you know how
do you actually authenticate that this
is the user who's doing it
rather than somebody who's not the user
and maybe that's velocity detection on
the user's movement
maybe it's mfa but out of band you know
a lot of people implement mfa to the idp
but if the idp's key has gotten stolen
that's not going to help you
because you know the adversary can
create something
but if you're doing a second factor at
the server
potentially that provides you a second
route of trust you're verifying that
they have an sso token
and some form of mfa or a certificate
authority that came from somewhere else
so i think a lot of different things
here um
but i think a word that andy hates which
is defense in-depth
right so we're not going to have this
debate right now but like
you know i think one of the things that
is interesting for me and really has
driven some of the some of the stuff
that we've been working on for the last
year
is is the idea that you know like this
single
route of trust for access to all of your
targets and all of your networks be it
your
certificate authority or be it an sso
provider this is not necessarily the
best way to do things right we want to
see
you know more than one route of trust
more than one place that if it's
compromised
you know everything falls down right so
in another sense it's again this notion
of overbroad scope
single root of trust is very dangerous
in terms of securing your systems
um so yeah so we've just taken our tour
our tour is complete five five incidents
that andy has lived through and i've
watched from the sidelines
um and um you know i think we have a
couple of uh
a few principles that i think we should
wrap up with andy do you want to
kind of walk through yeah yeah i think
we've we've walked through some of these
you know verbally but i think the the
key here is that safely implementing
secure access
lots of different ways it can go wrong
you know whether it's at that single
root of trust instead of multiple ones
you're using long standing credentials
instead of ephemeral ones
single flat architectures instead of
segmented ones
and weren't paying enough attention into
the supply chain
and ways that that could create a
problem for you so
we really appreciate everybody's time in
joining us and we hope that this helps
illuminate a path to a safer world
as you're all designing systems thank
you