well hello everybody thanks very much
for joining us for this best practice
session
uh this was originally recorded for our
dev set conference where thousands of
developers joined
sneak and our partners to talk further
about the industry
we presented this best practices session
in our virtual booth
and we're really excited to re-record
some of the themes as we feel like
they're really pertinent for everyone in
our industry
to have a sense for my name is brian
breckenridge i head sneak impact which
is our environmental social and
governance programming
uh and operating and and mental model
here at sneak where we're focused a lot
on advancing further diversity equity
and inclusion across our industry
in addition to bringing digital capacity
to non-profits and lots of other
organizations that are positively
affecting society
so the theme here for this discussion
was
for some of our people experts our
talent experts here at sneak to suggest
some of their approaches philosophies
tactics all the things that they're
doing to make sneak
a more diverse more inclusive uh and a
company that that
that promotes a sense of belonging to
all of our 700 plus employees
this session is uh starring to uh
folks that i've i've come to really
appreciate even though we've only met
virtually as colleagues for the past few
months
taiwo omotayo is joining us
from the plus 4-4 and he is a senior
technical recruiter here
uh and heidi king underwood also joining
us from the 0.44
or plus 4-4 over in the uk uh and is his
principal recruiter and really
responsible for
a lot of the go to market and emea
and apj which is the acronyms for
different theaters in europe and asia
for us
uh she comes to the company with a
really strong sense of allyship
uh working with underrepresented
candidates reducing the unconscious bias
that can exist
in the process with a a solid career and
tenure in this space
certainly the the you know as tywil
comes to this work as well
has joined us to make the r d recruiting
at the organization
even stronger more inclusive
these two as we were warming up for
today's session had said they'd never
been busier i know that we as a company
have gone from a couple hundred
sneakers to 700 plus sneakers in only
about two years two and a half years
and so really wanted to to give props to
taiwo for different programs that have
i would say emboldened our outreach
programs and centered
uh more of our focus on creating jobs
for underrepresented groups
and make certain that our teams aren't
homogeneous as we all know diverse teams
are are those that are performing better
uh creating uh better decision-making
patterns
uh typically more deeply um uh connected
to the work that they're doing in their
colleagues and doing their best work and
so that's what we're we're working on
here today i would open by just asking
heidi can you tell us more about
why you come to this work uh of making
certain that
our people practices here are inclusive
and and promoting inclusion
and belonging absolutely well i think
sneakers one of those companies who
going through that startup environment
um growing on a huge huge trajectory
right
you know i think we've grown what 400
it's absolute madness
and i think it's just about promoting
that inclusive environment of equal
opportunity
um you know it's it's constantly
delivering those results to make sure
that we are
a part of dni and not just using it as
you know oh yeah we've got a dni
practice but actually not living by it
um and it's just being that advocate
internally to make sure that everyone
stays on that same path
um and offer advice i suppose and
structure to people who
might be new to it you know it's just
offering that ability to say yeah i'm
here to help you
maybe give you ideas and just help keep
you on that path as well
and you were you were you were seeing
some of the work that was occurring here
and said
i i know that that's going to be a place
that's receptive to this this
perspective this way of operating is
that is that kind of the
the why it was a culture fit when you
were looking to join here
absolutely i joined as a as a contractor
and
when you're contracting you you know
you've got to go so quick and you're
you're working at pace but yet even at
that pace it was
right let's always take that step back
and focus on what
you know what are we looking at we're
looking at underrepresented talent
especially go to market
tech sales you know we don't do college
courses on this we don't have the u.s
central
attitude towards sales it's right where
can we lean for talent
sales females it's a very very under
stated arena you know getting sales
women
um or you know non-binary whichever way
wouldn't look at it
trying to get them into the workplace
and give them the best shot
it is the way that sneak has always been
at the forefront of that you know it's
okay what can we do we shout about
initiatives things like you don't have
to take every box we're willing to have
those conversations and invest in you
when you see that you really want to be
a part of it
and i suppose navigate around that
i really appreciate hearing it and and
then people get uh
that are listening to today's panel get
a chance to know your perspective just a
little bit more on what those are rooted
in so
taiwa over to you what what is it that
drives you to be more inclusive in the
work that you're doing here and
and then maybe just a word on on why it
made sense for you to join this
organization this rocket ship that we're
all work
a part of yeah um i'll start from the
bottom up actually um so my story is
actually very similar to heidi's in the
sense that
um we both started off as contractors um
and i think
you know i her time was probably
different to mine in a sense that we
were probably just like 150
as a business um and um we were
trying to scale up at the time and run
at a bit more pace than we were going
uh but it's similar in the sense of you
know you come in you do a job and you
just want to sort of get that done
i think what made sense for me to join
was um sneak
catching the importance of
representation
um inclusion and diversity at a very
critical time
um it was a time where we really wanted
to blast off and
um you know when you talk about these
groups that are quite underrepresented
it's a it's a it's a building it's a
project in itself to just
build the pipeline to even just get you
um the sort of talent you're looking for
um
and so to slaughter for sneaker a
company that wants a scale to slow down
and say actually
we don't want to be in a place in a
year's time where we yes we've hit 700
people
but you know there's a you know there's
no representation there's no diversity
there's no inclusion
um so you know for me seeing that as a
contractor
when i was offered my role here to help
build that initiative as well
um i didn't think twice right um and
um you know it's been a great journey
since because whether it's
within my team experts like heidi heidi
is actually the expert
um are being brought in on a day-to-day
basis um
and um you know you just get to see the
changes being implemented and it's not
just a tick box exercise
um but i'm you know i'm really
passionate about it because represent
you know i've worked in a lot of other
startups where it's an afterthought
it's something that you take a box with
and you don't see the action
uh behind the sort of um the talk should
i say uh but i feel like sneakers
definitely
gone the extra mile to make sure that
we're not just ticking a box here
where we know we're holding ourselves to
a high standard um and we're making sure
that we're bringing the best talent but
also trying to
um create opportunities for people who
actually feel like well
you know i'm in an industry where
typically it's driven by men it's driven
by
a particular type of man even um and
um you know how do we break those modes
it's by creating
things from the ground up so that we
actually help people on a career
trajectory that would see them go from
i knew nothing and now i'm an expert
amazing
on the daily basis i think there's lots
of peers of sneaks in the industry who
have the intent
as we've all spoken about before to
diversify their teams and
and and now it's a little bit less about
the why we should diversify the teams
even though
some people have yet to read their
research they've yet to understand that
the science that that really
bears that that that you know
aspiration out as as being a a thing to
do but but but the question is
the how and so i think that for the next
15 or so minutes on this
on this best practice session let's
start with what should you first
you know focus on yeah and whichever of
you wants to to run with this question
but i would imagine a handful of years
ago
sneak was saying where do we even start
we want to be diverse from when we're
100 or less all the way through the
journey
um you know what what's the first step
that an organization should focus on
to uh to to really pursue a world-class
dni
or inclusive hiring yeah i'll give you a
brief
overview because like you said you know
i probably started earlier but i feel
like you know heidi will have a very
clear
answer on this but i think for me you
know when we were at a place where i was
like okay how do we diversify the
workforce it was okay let's
just educate ourselves right let's let's
talk about these things internally
let's have have the hard conversation
sorry um and then see how that drives
our
you know let's let's see actually if
there's a real desire for people to make
these changes
um and i think that was the first thing
we did was educate ourselves um
and then i honestly was interacting with
other people as well how do you do these
things that you know we're not if we're
not if we're asking ourselves
um if we're having to educate ourselves
that means we don't know it right so
um asking people who actually have a
diverse workforce and that educating
ourselves through that way as well
um was very important um and not just
assuming that because you know
you know i'm a black recruiter i know
how to hire black people into tech
or you know because he's a woman she
must know how to do it
it's actually there must be a more
careful tailored approach to
actually approaching um dna um
i appreciate that through through
self-education through benchmarking
through reaching out to peers to being
humble
to not pretending to know everything and
remaining closed but remaining open
heidi what what would you suggest for
other companies listening
that are that are that are now on that
beginning of that journey
yep taiwa on the head right it's
education around inclusiveness it's
assessing
right where is id and i at right now
raising awareness it's looking at then
what are the areas that you want to
focus on from that you don't want to
tackle everything at first
right we're going to we're going to get
more races we're going to look at
ethnicity we're going to
look at gender now we're going to look
at disability now we're going to look at
you know all of these different
backgrounds and you think actually no
let's just have a look at what are we
focusing on first
how do we then look at what we're doing
is it that we are not looking at a
um you know different genders because we
have unconscious bias okay let's focus
on unconscious bias is it
okay i'm not looking at people maybe
from an underrepresented background
because i don't have that cultural
awareness okay then we need to focus on
cultural awareness
so it's not trying to tick off every
single item at the beginning
it's doing a dni survey taking in the
information
receiving the feedback of what's most
important to the people who are in the
business right now
and then it's focusing on each step as
you go that's the only way that you're
going to kick off those foundational
movements
so it felt to me like you you have a gut
check
initially you have you have like you're
looking around oh wait the team is not
that diverse the team must have walls
built around it or people may be falling
into old
default patterns of just hiring those
that that they've gone to school with or
that they
that whatever it was you you've not
interrupted pattern enough to
to move into a a more diverse or more
inclusive
approach and it sounds like education
internally externally with partners
with others that are doing uh diverse
and inclusive hiring well
it was important but then i heard
quantification and prioritization
uh any any thoughts then on on the way
that ongoing efforts as you've now begun
to quantify oh wait we are light
in areas that we are that were that were
proposing that were that were making uh
progress against
is there an ongoing series of decisions
or thoughts
or programming um focus areas that that
y'all would like to share
for folks that maybe haven't begun to
educate they've gotten their employees
involved in this they realize it's
priority
they've started to quantify and realize
their numbers aren't quite where they
want them what what types of decisions
they need to make at that point
yep i'll take this one so you've got to
i think you've got to divide it into two
right it's recruit and then retain
so number one what are your efforts to
attract and to recruit
and then what is what are your actual
ongoing efforts look like from
um identification and retention right
there needs to be a growth area
internally as well
so i think um you know those two areas
are really how you how you need to
divide it
um the the ongoing things that you need
to focus on or that i think we focused
on really
well is from the beginning is everything
around you know how i mentioned a second
ago
unconscious bias we focused on having an
internal
guide um which we have all of our hiring
managers sign up to which is
i promise to um be unbiased i promise to
come in with my best mind i promise to
explore all questions i promise to you
know basically give their best to the
candidate and be a diversity champion
um on the attraction areas we shout
about what we have
on on offer here at sneak you know how i
mentioned about women in sales we are
very much
hey we understand that women love to
tick every box before they apply for a
role
actually here at sneak you don't need to
do that we will absolutely invest back
in you
if you take that step to walk forward to
us um
and then on the retention piece it's
identifying what do people internally
actually
need to feel like they matter what are
we giving back and it's things like our
srg's rights our resource groups
um we have plenty of those you know
which is around diversity giving back i
know sustainability is another one that
you focus on right
um and it's giving that platform to go
okay here's a resource group for you but
here's an opportunity for you to grow
and to develop internally and in turn
we we offer those opportunities to
retain that talent
that's incredible why do you think uh
taiwa that the recruit
consciousness and the retained
consciousness kind of side by side are
important as you've been here now for
for a good period of time uh why is it
important to care about both there and
your tactics in there no no because the
the
basic mistake that you can make is you
know what
if we get a woman in though if we get as
many women and as many black people and
as you know change up a race and you
know it's all balanced
everyone will be happy right um and
that's it you know we've got a balanced
workforce we've got
diversity we've got inclusion and that's
it that's what we have to do right um
and actually um it goes back to that
thing of representation where are these
people
within the business right what uh
initiatives are you putting in place so
that people feel like
their ethnicity their background their
beliefs
matter at work um and i feel like a lot
you know it's easy to just go into the
recruit
the recruitment part is easy you know we
that's what we do you can put pressure
on us to get as many women for you as
possible
um and you can even just you know bypass
processes and get people in
but it's actually how do you keep those
people so they they don't feel like they
were part of like a tick box exercise
um and now that you've got them on board
that's all you know it's hands off and
they just need to find their way
at snake um so i think it's a very key
aspect of not just thinking about the
recruitment but the retention piece is
possibly more important um because
people will only be
happy at work when they feel like
actually i can see that someone is
progressing in this
uh particular role um that looks like me
or that
you know is my gender or whatever it is
and so i can aspire to that same level
of like
um uh you know i don't want to use the
word greatness because it sounds so
extreme but just like um i can see that
there's gross
in this company and people are being
rewarded for good work
not just because there's something or
they take a box right
um and there was just a little piece i
was going to add to that as well
heidi was saying is set yourself
achievable targets right don't don't
go in and think you're going to solve
diversity
in one sit one sitting it's not going to
happen it will also show
like that you've not taken in the
education piece properly
i think you've set um achievable targets
um small but you know
some that you can achieve and hit as
soon as possible uh and then also
obviously improve on
um but also uh the ones that you you
won't
find yourself compromising for um right
so you won't just
bring someone in because you're a woman
and bypass a whole process because you
think that's
what you need to do but i think where
heidi and team have been amazing is that
unconscious bias training
is constant um and people are having to
sort of
check themselves on if they're doing
things the proper way
or not just to you know just get people
in and really
appreciate that keep going yeah yes just
to add to that because i think
absolutely 100 but we also give that
platform
every single day so um just to call out
some events that we've done over the
last you know because we were just
talking about that sneak for good
and the efforts that we have with the
srg's it's things like we give a
platform to certain members
of of our community which is hey let's
let's have an actual presentation about
eid
let's talk about june teens let's talk
about lgb qt
plus let's talk about you know let's
celebrate internet international women's
day let's celebrate pride month let's do
black lives matter let's be a part of
these but it's the
it's the platform that is given to each
of those celebrations that then
you don't get a chance to let that bias
creep in because every day we're
celebrating
a different part of the community that
makes sneak
and by creating those resources
it's become and i put that down to our
people ops team and you know people like
you bro who are out there every day
thinking what what more can we do um and
it's people putting their hand up and
saying you know like we've now got a big
mama's group which is for people who are
parents women who are
you know birth givers who are either new
moms first-time moms maybe
when truly established parents out there
you know but it's that kind of group
which says hey there's a community here
for you there's a safe place
whoever you are whatever background
whatever interest we've either got a
slack channel
an srg or a celebration day in place
it's that kind of visibility i think and
then i think it
at least my own impression is if if you
enter a place and you see
and you're just well maybe you're just a
candidate and you're looking at an
organization but you see people maybe
that resemble your background or your
traditional path or less traditional
path
into that seat you're going to feel that
community you're going to feel that that
that sense of worth
and you're going to get feedback from
somebody that's instantly credible but
because perhaps they have a similar uh
approach to life that you have and i
think that's why these
these programs once they've started if
they're rooted in that authentic desire
to diversify and create that
community that family then it does start
to to feed on itself
and and the retained feeling of of high
belonging makes the candidate
experience or the candid interaction
more fulfilling
uh and maybe maybe turns up that
magnetism but then when somebody comes
in the door they feel at home they do
their best work then of course they're
growing
uh to taiwan's point of evolving getting
promoted
you know uh getting rewarded uh and
getting more responsibility and an
ability to
to share your truth in in the
environment that you're in
and grow in that i just wanted to
to to point out quickly before i go to
the last question the code of conduct
per se
for recruiters that that that daily
re-upping that promise
i think is an interesting thing for
companies to consider here
and certainly a formal bias training
that's tailored to your language and
your organization is
is important and a drum beat to to
continue to
to to hear in companies um
and then it's just that that helping
people feel like they matter i was just
going to
make certain that that was very very
clear and that can be done through
programming it can be done through
the intangible pieces just the behaviors
that people exhibit and
and creating a caring culture as the
value of of here at sneak care deeply
kind of reigns supreme in the in the in
the in the cultural
uh context um i did appreciate that that
achievable targets does anybody want to
to sound off at all on measurement i
know that's really important for people
to be more and more public about their
measurement but even internally
um you know setting goals in certain
areas at the right level and being
making those goals visible for people
did we want to touch on measurement for
a few minutes or did people just want to
want to wrap up with with other other
ideas or thoughts that they would want
to want to share with with other
companies trying to be more
diverse uh and more inclusive so either
measurement or just a wrap
up a wrap-up thought either and then uh
you know do a wrap-up with anything
um i think with measurement like as i
said just is setting
it's first of all stepping back and just
looking okay where
do we lack diversity the most in our
business right so we have several
departments you can call it r
d call it engineering but it's actually
understanding where do we find that
actually
we just have you know one type of person
in the business
right um and then setting
a goal against that right because it's
easy to say oh no you should have
a 35 goal by the end of the year or
something
but actually where does that go into if
it all goes into people ups
it doesn't mean you've diversified the
workforce it means you just brought in
more people into people-ups that help
your diversity numbers yes
um and so it's it's i think it's just
that piece where it's like look into
every department you have typically
historically
most like women for example are in
people-looks or recruitment or something
of that nature
um and so for you to say you know i want
more women in recruitment would just
sound crazy
right um so you want to go into the
harder areas where it's like
in fact we might not find a woman in
this area
right but how do we open up doors so
that we actually get women into those
areas
is where you set your your your your
sort of numbers and your targets
um and so i don't think it's easy to
quantify it generally
um because i think you have to take that
holistic approach to your business
before you do that amazing any other
thought on measurement
heidi before before we go back and round
the horn on wrap up
absolutely i think another one that you
should measure is what efforts or what
conversations are you having out there
externally right now versus which ones
you could be we
we focus very much on byp which is
um black young professionals we focus
very much in sisters in cells which is
focusing on black females within the
cells
um industry it's what conversations are
you actually having right now
externally with people who might come
from underrepresented talent right so
it's one thing to look at the
opportunities okay
we've got very few females in sales
let's go and attract them okay but what
about the
under-represented talent which can fill
entry-level roles and plug that gap
right what can we do to actually assist
better from a
um ethical perspective really when you
look at the roots of it what
opportunities are you able to offer
and which ones are you not taking
advantage of that you could you could be
better as a company
so it's looking at those conversations
if we're having no conversations right
now with people from
i don't know a female dominated
background or a male dominated if you're
a very female orientated company or
for people from different ethnicities
start measuring actually how many
conversations you start to have
because that can help to snowball as
well so it's looking at the general plus
the department level
actual gender actual racial makeup of a
team
but then it's also it's also
understanding that measurement not only
can be against those demographic data
points but also the actions being taken
to further diversify if you decided
that's your goal having discussions in
the right places and measuring that and
incenting people to move toward those
behaviors will
in fact likely bear more fruit than if
you're saying something and doing no
actions and having no measurement
against
the behaviors or the actions being taken
to to truly materialize the goal
so that seems really logical to me any
any thoughts
taiwo as we as we kind of go out knowing
that that other companies that are
trying to
to to be where we are or catch up or
perhaps even inspire us but needed one
more
one more nugget one more piece of
inspiration to go out and do this
this important work as we're building
our teams now i'll just say honestly um
don't be too hard on yourselves it's a
very difficult market
we are all learning from it um and so
you know it's it's just understand your
business needs uh run at
the pace that your business needs it to
run um and then just uh you know
be be be intentional about
you know diversity don't do it because
everyone else is doing it or because
you think it's the right hopefully you
think it's the right thing to do but you
just think oh
i should be taking this box yeah because
then it will quickly show if you're
intentional about
um about diversity and inclusion
it will show in the way your business
operates it will show in the things that
you
encourage in your business um and um
like i said earlier recruitment is the
easy part um
you know you can go out and get people
it's how do you make sure that actually
the things you're selling these people
to bring them in are sort of
evidenced in in their day-to-day whilst
they're working
i'll keep it short and sweet oh i
appreciate that greatly that that was a
tremendous wrap up that was really solid
heidi heidi over to you
oh no mine's exactly the same as taiway
right but all i'd say is
the only way that i think i have a
better understanding of dni is through
education i've been
brave enough to ask the awkward
questions you know why aren't we
attracting people from a diverse
background
why would i want to work here as a
female why wouldn't i want to
the same with taiwa i'm sure as a black
person why would i want to work here why
wouldn't i want to it's kind of like
having uncomfortable conversations and
educating yourself
around that and being willing to look at
yourself and be like i'm probably not
doing my best here
and just take those baby steps um like
taiwa said don't be too hard on yourself
right
the next edition will be how to retain
diverse talent
that's right that's right the 2.0
webinar
that we put on the best practice session
will be on that retain side and i'm
proud to say as a new person
i feel there's a lot of good work
happening there a lot of investment a
lot of authentic
effort uh and then certainly even even
the calendaring and even the incentives
and even the celebrations and the
uh the the things that that i feel like
sneak is
is indexing highly on and i'm seeing
who's getting hired to make that stuff
you know even more uh embedded even more
fundamental
so that things like the celebration of a
certain group lasts throughout the year
and lots of other ways too they're not
they're not just blips and flashes in
the pan which i i really really
appreciate
so thank you very much team this has
been a really fun best practice session
it's good to see both of you in
cyberspace again
and uh yeah hearts back to you and i
look forward to getting this out on the
blog and sharing it worldwide
thanks very much have good days thanks
guys bye