[Music]
hi
everyone from india i am priyam sang so
firstly thank you to all the organizers
you have done a fantastic job and
putting on this event
and thanks as well to sponsors and
attendees
for turning up even virtually uh
like a little about me
so i am uh devsicops engineer at
cloudell cloudell is an easy to use
cloud native security monitoring sas
platform and i also contribute to
communities such as
null it is an open security community
i am also chapter lead at chandigarh
infosuc about
information security uh at the last but
not the least i am a student of final
year graduation
so this is all about me let's get
started with
agenda of the session
uh firstly we will talk about what is
steps of corpse
uh what is steps of ci cd pipeline
and what we mean by ci cd also about
these stages
of pipeline approach and implementation
at the last the key points
next comes a quick disclaimer that in
the talk uh
in this session i will be talking a lot
about tools
so i don't recommend any tools it's just
i have used it because
i find it suitable for my my application
or for my software the language it was
there or the environment
i was using so for you it completely
depends upon which tool you choose or
which application you are working on
so let's start with def circles uh what
do we mean by depth accounts
devsocorps is development security and
operations
there for development uh cybersecurity
and oxford operation
so depths of course promotes security as
a shared responsibility culture
where in security is not a
responsibility for only one specific
team or only one person
but everyone in the team is accountable
for security
so def circles aim to integrate
security controls in the early stage
uh of software development or the
application build
rather than implementing it at the end
so
it integrates security measures from the
start of development
instead of in the last once the
deployment of the
application is done we come forward and
do the security part
and we like waste much of time or
the resources are wasted it is better
that we identify
in the starting of the software
development where
we started then comes
the second point we automate security
with the
latest tools and concepts at every level
so earlier we don't used to have any
feedbacks when we have waterfall model
or when we were having agile model but
after that we came depth offs where the
gap was
uh reduced and we started getting
feedbacks after that deficit
scale when which the feedbacks are there
and we can do the improvements
uh then and there and security is
integrated
so we can also define as integrating
security practices with the devops
process and adding sec to devops
forms that have devops instead
security and it gives the forms it
absolutes
uh what is repsicorp's ci cd pipeline
uh as steps ops refers to integrity
security
into your software development life
cycle so our depths accounts pipeline is
a set of security practices
which are incorporated into use
sdlc so sdlc is software development
life cycle
uh to build and test and deploy a secure
software faster
and easier so there are advantages of
the
depths of the icd pipeline these
advantages are
like first is earlier identification of
security vulnerabilities
and we don't have to wait till the last
stage it can be identified early only
and improved speed and agility for
security teams
and the development of the software is
secure
and the speed is increased
so firstly we will know like what we
mean by actually ci cd words
the ci in the ci cd is continuous
integration
and it always refers to
like which is an automation process for
developers successfully ci means
the new code changes to an application
or a software that are regularly built
tested
and merged to a shared repository
and ciscd in ci cd one refers that
continuous delivery
and or continuous deployment which are
related
concepts that sometimes get used
interchangeably
uh both about like automating further
stages
of the pipeline but they are sometimes
used separately
to illustrate just how much automation
is happening
continuous delivery usually means a
developer's changes to
an application are automatically bug
tested
and uploaded to a repository like github
or
we can say container registry where they
can
then be deployed to a live production
environment by the operations team or of
the
people who are doing the operations
so continuous deployment the other
possible cd can refer to automatically
releasing a developer's changes from the
repository to production
where it is usually by customers
it addresses the problem of overloading
operation team
with manual processors that slow down
app delivery
and it builds on the benefits of
continuous delivery by
like automating the next stage in the
pipeline
uh let's start with the stages of the
pipeline which
i will be discussing further so firstly
the build will start in jenkins
then okay so what is jenkins jenkins is
a self-contained
open source uh it's a automation server
that can be used to automate all sorts
of tasks
related to building uh testing and
delivering
or deploying software and jenkins can be
installed
through any native system packages
docker
or even run standalone by any machine
uh with the java and time environment
that is gre installed
so after the start build application
code is pulled from the github
we have to just write the link and it
will pull the
github code and after that jenkins
executes the initialization stage
then next step happens that is jen can
build the application dependencies that
are required for the application you are
working on
or the software uh and after that build
stage we come to scst so saa
software composition analysis and in
this
the tool i will be explaining is odc
that
is fast dependency check and after the
wash dependency check is done this
report is stored and after that it comes
sas
stage which is static analysis
and in this i have used neck and uh the
report is
stored for this then come source code
quality analysis
uh for this i uh as the application i am
using
for example is sweet crm which is in php
so i it is uh source code quality
analysis
is language based so i will be using php
code sniffer
and the report is stored after that
build happens
and once the build is done we do
dash that is dynamic application
uh security testing so dash is done when
the
application is in the running stage
and the tool uses jab that is jet
application proxy
uh so we after that store the uh report
and uh last stages as well software bill
of materials
uh the tool is cyclone dx and report is
stored so for all the steps we are doing
we are also report uh storing the report
uh you can do it at once also
so after that comes jenkins stops
running styles of app so on the prod
server and copies the updates and the
results
restarts the app deploy the app server
after that the build completes so let's
uh
discuss about all these stages which we
i have defined here in a little detail
uh firstly comes software composition
analysis
so it is a like all the tools which
i am taking over here are open source
only
so software composition analysis is an
automated process
that identifies the open source software
in a code base uh the analysis is
performed to evaluate security
and license compliance and code quality
so companies need to be aware of open
source license limitations uh
and also the obligations
uh tracking these obligation manually
becomes very tiring like
uh it's not so easy to do an
automated solution like sc and software
composition analysis
uh was developed and from this initial
use case
it uh expanded to analyze code security
and quality
so in a modern depth circumference
environment the sca helps in the
shift left paradigm so the security
uh is used in the concept lift that is
uh it
stands from starting and not in the end
after the deployment of the software is
complete
then we take care of security that's not
then it's done by shift left process
and the earlier and continuous sca
testing has
innovate like developers and the
security teams
to drive productivity without
compromising security
or quality so let's
look for the importance of scs so
firstly is that we can automatically
track
open source components and the
continuous monitoring for
vulnerability detections and there are
also
uh automated and prioritized
vulnerabilities remediations
uh licensed risk management is also
taken care
so like what are the tools over here uh
firstly the oas dependency check that
is odc so what is this uh it is a
software uh
composition analysis tool uh which
attempts to detect publicly
disclosed vulnerabilities contained
within a project's
dependencies so software composition
analysis tools
scan the open source code uh software to
inventory
all open source components and it is
important as
modern uh enterprise application can
comprise up to
80 to 90 percent open source components
and given this the risk of security and
ip risks
of open source components can be
very significant and tools to help
mitigate these
risks become critically important
so over here the code is there and when
a new branch is created
code is deployed and pull request we do
the software
composition and this is uh and quality
check
commits after that if there are any
problems we will
go and change it and do a new branch
commit and
it will again there will be a code
developed and pull request so
we don't have to wait till the
after the production deployment it is
deployed completely the tool
and come back to the remove the
vulnerabilities
but we can do over here only where we
spot the
issues
okay so next comes first
uh what uh like we mean by sas asked
static application security testing so
it is done when the application is not
in the running
state it is stationary uh it's a process
that
analyst this a project source code and
dependencies and related files
for known security vulnerabilities it
examines the code to find the
flaws or we can say software weaknesses
such as
sql injection or any other which are
listed in oas top 10
sas could also help identify segments of
projects logic
which might lead to security
vulnerability
it is also known as white box testing
because uh
as the tester has access to the
underlying
framework the design and the
implementations
the application is tested from inside
out
and uh it uh supports left left approach
uh this assassin also so identified
defects
earlier it leads to lower cost of
remediation
and delivering fast feedbacks
and providing the exact location of
vulnerabilities
and their costs
the tool for sas which i used was make a
snake and okay so
slick is an open source security
platform for finding availabilities and
the source code of an
application uh here is the report where
you can see that the cvit is medium or
it is high and we can
like take care of it if we face any
issues like it
is going to prob create a problem
then comes uh the like uh next stage
that is source code quality analysis and
uh okay
over here i will be talking about
linkedin uh lending is the
automated checking of source code for
programmatic and stylistic errors um
only so this is done by using a linting
tool
a len tool is a basic static code
analyzer
lending is important to reduce errors
and
improve the overall quality of code
using lint tools can help accelerate
development and reduce cost by finding
errors earlier
and linting tools are language specific
and thus
the tool that can be used depends on the
application being tested
or the software being used and nowadays
we have
like different lenders uh which provide
many types of checks like syntax errors
or
it can be like code standard idents
or potential problems uh security checks
so code quality analysis tools are
language specific so for like for the
application like sweet crm which are
meant
for php applications the tool i used is
php code sniffer and there are many
other tools available you can like
choose or use any which like suits your
application or the environment you are
working
a little about like the code stuffer
tool
uh so php code is different is like a
set of two main scripts that is first is
php css script and it helps to detect
the
violation of predefined coding standards
and a second
is php cbf script that can automatically
correct
these violations
okay so moving towards when the build
happens and uh
the application is a running state and
we do dust
that is dynamic application security
testing
so in the dynamic application security
uh it's done uh
during the running of the application
and it is also called
black box texting technique in which the
dash tool
interacts with the application being
tested
in a running state to immediate as an
attacker
and that's tools are especially helpful
for detecting
like input output validation
or cross-site scripting and sql
injections
okay so it is also server configuration
mistakes can be identified
and the authorization issues like other
problems
which manifest in real time or become
like visible only a known user logs in
it scans the client side and the server
side as well
so the tool uses jab tool it is open
source
and it is like man in the middle proxy
what it means is that
it
so jet attack proxy is an open source
tool
so used to perform dynamic application
security testing which is
uh designed specifically for web
applications
and it immediates an actual user where
it
interacts with the application to
perform like
various attacks at its core job is what
known as
man in the middle proxy which i
mentioned earlier also
so it stands between the test browser
and
in the web application so that it can
intercept
and inspect the messages which are going
uh sent between
the browser and the web application and
modify the contents if needed
and then forward those packets to the
destination
[Music]
uh i have also shared a report for the
job report it's just a portion of
the snapshot so over here it shows that
there is a potential excesses so
we can take care of it or remove it or
make the changes accordingly
so that we don't face this issue later
on or
we don't have someone like a security
team working at the last
of the when the application is deployed
uh then comes uh software below
materials uh software bill of materials
is
a list of components which are used to
like
assemble or create a product and it
gives out a specification
about how each component was used in the
making of the end product and a software
belong materials
refers to the list of software
components or the
open source or commercial that was
utilized to build a software solution
and it responds quickly to the security
or license or any operational risks
that come with open source use
the tool used is cyclone here so it is
available for
uh each every languages different
languages
you can use the one that suits your
application or
your environment
and this is the s form report and the
this is also just a part of this uh
snapshot
okay so here we can see that the name is
php cs fixer
and the description is given and the
license used
so this tool is automatically fixed php
code style
uh and like this we can get to know what
are
the uh like what are the components we
used
in the product
okay so we will be now covering the key
points you got to know
for the ci cd pipeline
firstly is that release is faster
yes so the failures are detected faster
and
as such can be repaired faster leading
to increasing release rates
however frequent releases are possible
only if the code is developed
and like in a continuously moving system
also ci cd like uh continuous
integration and continuous deployment
continuously merges the codes and
continuously
deploys them to production after
thorough testing and keeping the code in
a release
ready state it's important to have as
part of deployment a production
environment said of that closely mimics
that
which end users will ultimately be using
and next is that increase in the team
transparency and
accountability so ci cd is a great way
to get continuous feedback not only from
our customers
but also from our own team or the groups
working
so this increasing is the transparency
of
any problems or any issues going in the
team
and it encourages responsible
accountability
uh the next point is similar smaller
code changes as we have seen that
a portion of uh is creating issue we can
change it then
and there so small one technical
advantage of
continuous integration and continuous
delivery is that
it allows you to integrate small pieces
of code at
one time these code changes are
simpler and easier to handle than huge
chunks of code
and as such that we will have further
issues that may need to be repaired
at a lower later date
so using continuous testing these small
pieces can be tested
as soon as they are integrated
into the code repository allowing the
developers
to recognize a problem before too much
work is completed
afterward so these works really well
for like large development teams who
work remotely
as nowadays it's happening a lot and
as well as those in-house as
communication between team members can
be challenging
and it also helps in the reduction of
the cost
as the automation in the ci cd the
continuous continuous integration
and continuous delivery pipeline reduces
the number of
errors that can take place in the
many repetitive steps of ci cd
and doing so also like freeze up
developers
and time that could be spent in the
product development as there aren't like
as many core changes to fix down so the
role of the error is caught quickly
after that comes the customer
satisfaction
so the advantages like one of the main
advantages
is that cicd do not only fall into the
technical aspect but
also in an organization scope so the
first few moments of new customer trying
out like your product
is a make or break moment so don't waste
like first impression as they are key to
turning new customers
into satisfied customers and
keep like keep your customers happy with
fast turnout
of new features or any bug fixes
so utilizing a ci cd approach also keeps
your product
up to date with the latest technology
and
allows you to like give new customers
who will select you over the competition
through word of mouth and positive
reviews
at the last like more at the last point
is more test reliability
so using ci cd test uh the reliability
improves
due to the bite size and specific
changes introduced to the system
and it also allows like for
more accurate positive and negative
tests which are to be conducted
and test reliability within uh ci cd can
also be considered continuous
reliability
and with the continuous merging and
releasing
of new products and features knowing
that the quality was
top of mind throughout the entire
process that
assures that stock holders their
investment and worthwhile
so this was all about the session
thank you and let me know that if there
are any questions