[Music]
hello everyone
thank you for joining my name is itae
shakuri
i'm the director of open source at aqua
security
and i'm here today to talk to you about
random security
using a couple of very exciting
technologies
ebpf and oppa and
i want to start this talk by actually
sharing an example
this is a a real example actually
that our research team at aqua has
discovered
so this is a docker image on docker hub
that was doing something useful you know
maybe you've even used it
and if you have used it you probably
scanned it because this is what this
what we do with container images
we scan them for vulnerabilities for
misconfigurations for known manual
and so on and if you would take that
image
and scan it with any popular
static image scanner it would be all
green
all the tests would pass
and it would be seemingly innocent
except it won't because it would try to
do something
bad once you ran it and the reason
is that there was a malicious binary
hidden
in the entry point now this sounds very
um
sophisticated and maybe uh challenging
but actually
if we take a look at the entry point and
you can see
it right there um so you see this
weird-looking string here that you may
recognize as a
base64 encoded uh artifact
and you can see the following lines
which
basically decodes this uh string and
then
executes it so it's a pretty simple um
even disappointing kind of techniques to
hide something but it was
extremely effective because it managed
to evade
pretty much every static image scanner
due to the simple fact that this melissa
malicious
image was not existent at the time
that the container was scanned it only
kind of appeared at runtime after the
the code in the entry point was executed
and my point here is that
static image scanning when we discuss it
in the context of container security
you know it's a staple of container
security it's something that we've been
doing for a lot of time and it's a
really important
practice that we have managed to adopt
but it has its blind spots
and by simply relying on that
tools we were also overlooking
some entire categories of risks actually
such as the one that i just demonstrated
which brings me to discuss random
security
so runtime security is kind of taking
the the opposite approach uh in term
instead of shifting left
we're trying to shift right and to look
at
the workloads at the containers while
they run
and this is the conclusion that we
reached earlier
by discussing that example that the only
way to really know what the container is
going to do at running time is to run it
right so this is what we're going to do
and when we run the containers in the
production
what we're trying to do with this
runtime security solution
is to detect suspicious behavior at
runtime
this is the goal that we're trying to
achieve here this is
what the solution that i'm going to
discuss
today uh is going to help you achieve
and
um we have a project uh that it
that is called tracy it's an open source
completely open source no secrets
they're
uh completely free on github so if you
go to github.com
aqua security slash tracy um you can see
everything about tracy how it works
what it tries to detect and how and uh
throughout this talk i'm going to
introduce you to this tool and
specifically how this tool
uh leverages ebpf and oppa in order
to achieve runtime security
okay so let's discuss random security
architectures in general even regardless
of
tracy pretty much every random
security solution will have the
following um
architecture where there is there are
two components basically at play here
one is the monitoring part this is the
part
that uh deals with uh monitoring
everything that happens
on the operating system right we are
trying to protect our servers our
production probably
um so we will install some components
onto that servers that will have
visibility into every single thing that
happens we want to capture
as much information in as much detail as
possible
in order for us to make the detections
later on so that
part basically just produces raw data
a lot of events and then we take those
events we take this raw data and we fit
it into
the other component which is the
detection engine this
is a separate component that uh is
looking
into that stream of events and it is
trying to find
uh patterns suspicious patterns based on
predefined rules that we will give it so
um there are rules that we ship with
tracy you can
write your own rules as well but
basically you
you give it something to look for you
you kind of teach it
what a suspicious pattern might look
like and then it
looks for that for those patterns within
the stream of incoming events
this is a very very very very very high
level overview
of tracy or random security solution
and you know the title of the talk so
you know there are
two core technologies that play here
one ebpf for monitoring
uh the operating system so
ebpf is a very exciting
linux technology it's part of linux part
of the linux kernel
and in a nutshell it allows us to
instrument the operating system and
attach
to very interesting
points in the kernel workflow
and actually executes our own code in
there so this is the
this is the actually the the uniqueness
about ebpf
that it allows us to run our own code
there
so that we can collect whatever
information we might need
and we can do it in a very safe and
reliable and performant way
so that you will you will not be
affected by this
overhead i'll talk a little bit more
about ebtf
soon and the other technology that is
helping us
build tracy is the open policy agent
for short opa oppa is a
graduated cncf project that deals with
policies
and policy enforcement it was meant for
scenarios like
uh authentication uh authorizations so
you can define
the uh the rules the policies
that you want um that you want to
enforce and and hope
and oppa gives you the language first of
all to describe
those policies and then the tool to
enforce them
another popular uh scenario that we see
oppa at play is with kubernetes for
example
it is an admission controller so it will
uh
receive all of the user requests to
create resources in kubernetes and you
can define policies of
what kind of things you want to allow or
to deny
and oppa can help you enforce that
we use oppa slightly
in a slight creative way because
we think that the incoming events we see
them
as input documents and we express
open policies to help us
look for the specific patterns that we
want to look within those events
and we will also see talk more about
oppo and see an example
for that later in the talk
all right so what we're going to do next
is to
zoom into each one of those components
and see see them at play
let's start with the first one about uh
monitoring the monitoring component
and to discuss that we first need to
understand this um
mental model of how the operating system
works and
what it means basically operating system
tracing
so this is a very common uh
[Music]
common diagram where you have your
application
it's running on the computer uh there is
hardware to the computer right and your
application is trying to make use of it
let's say it's trying to create a file
or it's trying to
communicate over the network or whatever
it needs to do with the computer
actually the hardware itself is
inaccessible to the application directly
in every modern operating system
including linux
the kernel which is the component of the
operating system
that is in charge of managing the
hardware is the only
component that can actually touch the
the hardware
so the kernel is the only way that we
can touch the hardware
how can we do something simple like open
a file
because the file exists on disk we need
to interact with the disk somehow
so uh the way the the mechanism
that operating systems lets us
communicate
with the hardware is via system calls
system call
is a common interface where
the kernel exposes these system calls
basically think of them like functions
that you can call from the outside
and by calling the system call let's say
the open system call which is a real
system call in linux
you can ask the kernel to open a file
for you
so let's go through uh
this uh these layers from the top to the
bottom
you the application developer or someone
who uses an off-the-shelf
application the application is trying to
open a file
probably the coder whether it's written
in any language
node.js python c it doesn't really
matter
it's going to use some library that will
call into another library that is called
into a lower level library which will
eventually
call a system call and that system call
will be handled by the kernel the kernel
has access to the hardware
and via probably some device driver will
actually move the needle read the bytes
and return the result
to eu and the reason that i'm um
sharing this this at this moment is to
show you exactly where ebpf
fits in ebpf lets us plug right
there between the system code and the
kernel
and this is the perfect place for us to
be
if we want to if we want visibility into
everything that happens
on the computer because it doesn't
really matter whether the application
is written in whatever language whether
it's running in a container
or in a vm or whether it's privileged or
not
none of it matters all of the code that
is being
executed on the computer and is trying
to access the hardware
is going to eventually go through us
thanks to ebpf and this is where we have
the opportunity
to examine what's going on but more than
that
unlike other instrumentation
technologies that lets you just
log the calls in this case
we can actually run our own code
at that point and we can and our code by
the way runs in the kernel so we have
a lot of visibility into everything that
happens at that point
we can collect additional information
sorry collect additional information
and provide a lot of contextual
information around the the raw event
and this is what helps us create very
high quality
uh events uh with accuracy and
reliability and the result of this is
that
the ebpf probe this thing that we send
into the kernel to help us
collect the data will tell us yeah
an open system call was detected here
and this is
all of the information that i can
extract at this point
all right so this is operating system
tracing that we can
achieve using ebpf we discussed
system calls there are a lot of system
calls in linux
and the good news is that tracy allows
you to trace pretty much all of them
out of the box today i counted it just
before this calls
just before this uh talk it was a 353
system calls that we support in tracy
it's a lot it's it gives you everything
all of the information that you may need
in order to make quality detections
later on
but the interesting part is that
on top of those system calls
tracy also gives you access to other
kernel events
these are specific uh
points within the kernel that we chose
to instrument
manually in order to give you
more information that is more meaningful
in a security context because
because this is where we are at we're
trying to detect suspicious behavior
so those other uh kernel events which i
will demonstrate
in a second will give you access to
more reliable information more accurate
information and more secure information
and we keep adding more events to tracy
every day um probably by the next time
you'll see this uh recording uh
the numbers will be different uh but
what i want to do next is
to demonstrate what tracy ebpf looks
like
by the way in the tracy code base we
actually
uh keep it that way that the the
monitoring part is separate from the
detection part
so we call the monitoring part tracy
ebpf
and yeah and now we can
see it in action
all right so i moved over to my terminal
here
and uh tracy abpf is now uh an
executable
is a command that you can run and i can
tell it first of all to just list
all of the events that it can trace
so what you see here is a huge list of
all of the system calls and other um
other kernel events that we can trace in
tracy and for each one of them you can
see
what kind of information you can expect
to receive
from this event let's start tracy
with no arguments which will start a
general purpose trace
it will just try to trace everything
that happens
and you can see already that things are
happening here maybe try to open
a file here and you can see more things
that are happening let's stop the trace
and just in a couple of seconds we
captured
almost 150 events and uh
this is because you know it's a it's a
linux
machine it's alive it's doing things all
the time
and uh we can see a glimpse into what we
were able to capture here
at what time what user what was the
command
process ids what is the exact event
and the arguments of that system
for example we can see an open system
call
open add is a variant of open and you
can see
all of the arguments that were given to
this
system call and you can use this
information to do very
uh very interesting investigations
let's do something else let's ask tracy
to trace just the opennet system call
if we do that um sorry i forgot
to add it event uh i want
to ask tracy to trace events of type
opennet
and now we see
slightly reduced output still quite
verbose but
slightly reduced uh actually let's add
another filter here
let's ask tracy to only show us the
output of the
cat command right
and i'm doing a cat down here
for a file and you can see now a more
digestible
output these are all the open
at events that happened from this
cat command you can see it trying to
open some files
eventually also opening the test file
that i asked it to open um
and this is a good opportunity to also
mention the other
events that we add on top of system
calls open edit is a system code
and you can see here that um
you get it access to the the real
information that
was given to the system called in this
case test
just the name of the file but uh there
are many different ways to access a file
in linux
to reference a file so for example you
can say
the relative path the full path you can
give it a drfd
uh that changes the way that the path
name is handled
you can give it a file descriptor that
is already opened
this is linux so there's a lot of
flexibility
but what i can do here to make the
output more usable
is to add the security
file open event
this is an event that tracy is
introducing on top of the open
system code and i want to show you the
differences this is the opennet system
called same one that we've seen earlier
that shows us the output of the tests
the opening of the test file
and this is the security file open that
gives us
the resolved file path
to the real path to the real file that
was
that was opened so this is much more
usable for
us if we want to make some kind of
assertions
on this output in order to make
detections
moreover this event the reason it's
called security is that it
is more secure um i won't go into that
we've written a very detailed blog post
about that in the
blog but system calls because they sit
in the
in the border between the user and the
operating system the user has some
influence on what they pass to this
cause what kind of arguments and when
and
it is vulnerable to some kind of attacks
while the
security events
which generally called in linux lsm um
functions are not so it's also it's not
only more usable
it's also more secure to use this kind
of events
um i could also ask tracy to output
the to format the output as a json
and i could pipe this
pipe this json stream into
other tool that will you know look into
for example the args you see here the
arks property
and we can look at the
second argument here
and you can further play with it and
create your own kind of detection uh
logic but we'll see that there's a much
better way to do that
soon all right so
that was a quick uh segue just to show
you
what the raw data looks like the
monitoring part of the random security
solution of tracy let's move
on to discuss the second component the
detection component the detection engine
like we call it so we're now zoomed in
to the detection part we have
on the left events flowing in
from tracy ebpn this is raw data
as we've seen and on the right we will
produce detections these are
alerts actionable alerts that the user
can process
so we've seen an example of how an event
looks like
i'm just formatting it here as json
documents so it's easier easier to
reason about
and we have access to all of this
information we just need to know
what to look for um
so this is where we are using the open
policy
engine more precisely more accurately uh
the open policy agent uh
the language that you write policies in
is called regular
so technically uh our our
rule engine is able to process regal
signatures this is how we call them
regular signatures and it looks
something like this
so we ship tracy with a bunch of
regular signatures for you you can also
write your own you just create a new
text file it looks something like this
and uh
let me just bring the pointer back
um and you create a text file
you you can declare some metadata for a
prettier output but the interesting part
is this block here
uh you create a rule that is called
tracey underscore match
and within this rule you just give us a
list of conditions
that needs to be matched in order for
this uh signature to
detect so think of it like a big
if else statement where you are only
required to provide
what's inside of the if what are the
conditions that you are interested in
and you have access to the input here so
you can say things like
input dot event name this is the name
of the event so input.event name
let's see if it equals to opennet this
is the system call that we're interested
in
and then let's see if the
input has an args field which it does
and it's an array so let's just run
through all of the
elements in this array and look at the
one called value look at the field
called value
of every one of those elements
and let's call this file path because we
know this is what it represents
and then let's see if this file path
equals to atc shadow which is a very
uh well-known um
file that uh that you don't want
to manipulate with too much if if you do
see
uh this file being manipulated and
without your knowledge then it's
probably malicious so this is a very
simple detection that will detect
that but what i want to show you
here is the really the simplicity
of writing a new rule or a new signature
for
um for tracy and it all really
thanks to opa thanks to rego writing
something like this in code would
probably
result in um i don't know 50 lines of
code
that uh with a lot of loops and a lot of
checks and a lot of
a lot of stuff there here it's just
three lines
you know we just assert that the event
name is opennet we just
implicitly iterate and
look into the elements and then do
another assertion and that's it
pretty neat i think um
yeah and what i want to show you now is
uh
example for signatures that we have in
tracy
so i'm going to move over to my browser
here
and this is tracy on github aqua
security
tracy all the code for the ebpf part the
monitoring part and the rules part
is here i'm going to click into the
rules part
and signatures rego
and you can see a few regular signatures
here we keep adding more and more
and let's look into for example this
signature i chose this one because this
one
is maybe the most complicated one that
we have
but it's still pretty simple so it's
really demonstrate
the readability and expressiveness of
this signatures language
so it's a text file you declare some
metadata here
just so that the ui can show you
something helpful
you tell us what kind of events you are
interested
in subscribing to and that's this is
the boilerplate and then you can see
these tracing match
blocks there are three here
because this is a coding injection
signature as you can see
here and what it is looking for is
indications that
someone or something try to manipulate a
running process
at runtime and there are
different ways different techniques to
do
that in linux right our research team
has researched and investigated the
different
ways that someone might be able to
manipulate
a running processes image at runtime and
it came up with these three
ways so they just wrote them down
codified them as rego
code the first one is using the ptrace
system call
so we see if the event name is ptraced
uh
we look at the argument called request
and you can see here a slightly
different way to do that
uh we also provide helper functions uh
regular
helper functions so you can ask
something like
give me just the value of the request
argument without
writing that more various code that
you've seen earlier
you get the result and you see whether
the
ptrace a request
is p trace poke text poke text means
that
someone tried to manipulate the code
of that of the program if it did
then it's clearly a code injection
behavior and there are other behaviors
here let's see
a more complicated one in this case
we're interested in the security file
open event
and we want to see if the opened file
looks something like this this is a
regular expression so if
if the file being opened is uh slash
proc
slash slash mem which is a special file
handle that linux offers to manipulate
the memory
image and we also check whether it was
open
for write and not for read and if
if so it's a detection uh here we can
see another uh cool thing
not only other helpful functions and so
on uh we also see that we
can you can also return a result from
the detection it's not just a
true false yes there was a detection you
can also give us some
evidence of uh give the user some
evidence into what really happened
and you know there are many different
ways so we're not going to cover all the
signatures just wanted to
show you uh a real world
signature that is one of the more
complicated ones
but i think it's actually pretty
readable and approachable
okay moving back to the slides we have
covered
the monitoring part we have covered
the detection part and now let's zoom
out and review the solution end to end
we have the operating system which we
now
instrument using tracy's ebpf probe this
is
the the probe that we send into the
kernel
to report back to us about everything
that happens
it report it it reports it back to tracy
ebpf
which is the component that is in charge
of monitoring
tracy ebpf is then
generating continuously generating an
endless
stream of events that represents
everything that happens
on the operating system and this
uh this raw data is being uh fed into
the tracy rules engine this is the rule
engine
which is loaded with um rego policies
regular
signatures each one of those signatures
is always looking for a suspicious
pattern
and if it finds if one of the signature
has found that pattern it will
create an alert the alert that
the detection itself is human readable
is actionable unlike
the the very verbose raw data this is
something that you should
understand and you should be able to
respond to
and you can also ask tracy to
send this event to you in whatever
preferred way you have for communication
so you can ask tracy to send
a message over a slack channel send you
an email
um open a jira ticket whatever
using a very flexible webhook
interface and this is how the runtime
security
looks like end to end in tracy
and just to
finish that demonstration i wanted to
show you that in action
actually i'm going to move over to our
documentation
very quickly um which
is linked to from the github repository
and i'm just going to copy this line
over here
this is the quick start example of how
to run
a tracy all together
so
this docker container aquasex
tracy includes
tracy ebpf and tracy rules and all of
the signatures that we ship with tracy
and it is set up so that it uh you know
it sets everything up so that
you immediately start monitoring and uh
detecting
things let's just run it like this and
you can see that it has loaded
some signatures and actually what i want
to do now
is to execute this test
file and you can see that tracy has
detected something
this is a standard input output over
socket
which means that um
tracy has detected that some
someone has redirected the input or
output
of some process into a remote endpoint
and it even gives you the remote
endpoint
that we detected and what was the
command what was the container name
and so on so this is something that you
can actually
understand and react to and uh hopefully
mitigate
all right great um
so uh i hope that you learned uh about
uh random security today uh
i invite you to go over to github.com
aqua security slash tracy
we have uh discussions over at github
so if you are trying out tracy you have
a question
you have a suggestion you just want to
reach out and say something
please go to our discussions area and
start the discussion we'll be happy to
talk with you
and uh try out tracy give us a star and
uh tell us what you think if you want to
get in touch with me personally you can
find me over twitter
at itaisk ita ysk and uh with that
i wanna thank you i hope you enjoyed
this talk and i hope you enjoyed the
rest of the conference
thank you