good afternoon and welcome to natick 54
this is our member meeting so we will go
very quickly because we all know that we
are between you and the Super Bowl so
we'll make this brief animals I'm sorry
let's go yes 1712 mats they just punted
to the Giants and we will don't get
retrospective of some kind okay so thank
you everyone we liked I'd like to thank
all the directors on the board we're all
sitting here and the program committee
was sixteen members of the program
committee the development committee five
or six members communications committee
three members and all our nanog staff it
takes all these people to put up a nanog
event membership information we have
three hundred and three members and you
are most likely one of them and we have
94 members that have registered for nigh
on 54 we would like to thank our hosts
talax our connectivity sponsored cox the
diamond sponsor is NT t google and
verisign or silver sponsor
alcatel-lucent or annual partnership
sponsors things is going to go too fast
arbor errands in there we go bearing
gear sponsors and are various break
sponsors in our newcomers breakfast and
breakfast enhancement sponsor thank you
everyone all these sponsors are required
to keep our registration fee at the low
level that it is and we also have social
sponsors that have put up we have
socials every night and we also have a
this is Wow alright I want to control
this all right Development Committee the
recent activities we have a new
sponsorship model that is in place which
will drive the activities for 55 56 and
57 the objective is to ensure
sustainability as you know we were this
is our first year of operation we did a
lot of trials and we learn from these
trials so now we have a new model in
place and we think it will ensure that
we are financially stable it will be
posted on an anode website very shortly
and you can always make inquiries by
sending an email to marketing at not org
financial information ultimate financial
information is reported to the members
at every fall meeting so our next
sequence will be at man of 56 you can
also consult quarterly information when
you log in through the arrow tools so
that information is public and also an a
dog as just good business practice
decided to undergo a voluntary financial
audit at the end of this week just to
give us a an appraisal if we were doing
things in the right way for our
not-for-profit status
we decided it was better to do that at
the very beginning rather than having to
correct things and now I will pass it on
to Betty who will explain the next month
what we're doing in what's our strategic
plan and we've had a session in August
for a three year plan and we are
actively implemented this plan so Betty
will explain to you thank you welcome
everyone I'll be brief there's a few
slides here so I won't read them all to
you I'm just going to highlight through
and give you some highlights my goal is
to share with all of you the commitment
that the board has to developing a
forward-looking plan for sustaining
nanog and growing nanog so all the
things that we talked about in terms of
wanting to be able to create a a set of
new set of tools or new set of offerings
we throw all of those ideas out on the
table as part of our retreat discussions
and then we come up with a plan and my
job is to help us keep on track and to
report to all of you how we're doing and
to bring that information back to you as
members so you're aware what we're
planning three years out you know right
now we're dealing with 18 months but
we'd like to be really thinking you had
three years as we think about
implementing these new ideas and bring
them back to you and so we can have a
dialogue here at our member meetings we
really want to make sure that it's a
long term investment we can maintain all
of the offerings so we think through the
process of what we're wanting to do what
other nods are doing what we should be
doing and how they line up with
priorities and the important element of
what we think about when we're doing a
strategic plan is the members you know
we have members we have all of you who
are making a core investment into
nanigen we
we want to respect that and honor that
and that's one of our drivers as with
any company we want to achieve financial
stability we weave physical stability we
want predictability we don't want to be
just thinking about is nana I'm making
money meeting to meeting but do we have
a reserve to sustain us annually and
into the next year so we talk about a
lot of those things we want to broaden
the scope in size of our sponsor
contribution while maintaining the look
and feel of Nana's principles so you
know what nanog to become trade show
we're committed to the vendor neutral
environment that you all enjoy and we
want to protect that for you in our
sponsorship model so that's a big driver
that we talked about we want to be able
to create exceptional support for our
vendors and operational efficiency we
don't want to have a lot of overhead for
our sponsors to be able to be here
either for us or for them so we always
think about ways in which we can make it
easy for sponsors to participate and we
talk a lot now these days about making
sure that we can honor the deliverables
that we've committed to giving you it's
an important business element and so
we're paying attention we want to build
the unified branding message about what
why is nanog unique and we all have an
opinion in a view and we're sharing that
in our collateral and in our message
with all of you so that we're all three
hundred and what I'm sorry Sylvie 303 of
you who are members are sharing the same
vision as the board that we're speaking
the same language that we all know what
we want this organization to become
together we are developing mutually
rewarding agreements because we can
believe that a sponsorship model is very
rewarding for nanog but we have to make
sure that it's a rewarding experience
for the
sponsors for them to come back it still
be indicated with the goal of
maintaining the registration fee so
financial stability means registration
and sponsorship and those are moving
targets and they come into play when
having a plan so you can you can address
them if there are changes we can talk
about them with you and you can check on
us by looking in arrow at the financial
information all available for members we
need to think about how we increase the
numbers of members in the number of
folks that are meeting so there are
things that we talk about NAT anew
they're all subjects that we've talked
about at nana for a long time we have
450 people on average what would it mean
if we had 650 people and what would it
mean if we have 303 members today and we
had 600 tomorrow and if we want 600
tomorrow how are we going to get there
what's our value proposition so those
are some of the subjects that are
drivers in our strategic plan objectives
that we talked about my job is to report
how are we doing on achieving the
objectives that we committed to do in
the strategic plan and we will be
publishing in a prettier format what the
strategic plan actually is after we meet
on in a second retreat because this
Wednesday so the retreat information
will be out there for you in a prettier
format we're using it as an internal
tool in my job is to keep us all honest
and keep us on track and it's sometimes
hard because we get busy the board gets
busy all of you are folks who have very
busy day jobs in the board is no
different and so they're very committed
in
job is to sort of be that sideline voice
reminding them we have to come back and
we have to deal with some of these
things because it's important for Nana
and thus far as you can see by the goals
when we started this in September
through the summer we're doing pretty
doggone good in making our commitments
that we we made in our plan plan is only
so good unless you actually have some
metrics for success how do you know if
you plan in what you're doing is going
to be successful and so we set some
again metrics for whether we're
successful some of that is of the
membership do that we have are you all
renewing so we can grow the membership
but a metric for success is that all of
you are still committed and so you're
renewing and I'm pleased very very
pleased so far in the first renewal
cycle which is January we have received
ninety-eight percent return rate so of
the folks who signed up last January 98%
have renewed again so that's a pretty
good metric for success and we're
growing the number of members meeting to
meeting when we look at the number of
members that we have that's that's
pretty good you know that that's another
metrics that we're doing the right thing
a lot of time Mike Smith and I and
members of the board have been dealing
with budget modelling right we no longer
have someone else telling us what the
budget is we own the budget and we have
to make sure that we have a model that's
real and that we can share with you and
that we are on target through our
attendance our fees or sponsorship and
cost containment of expenses that we're
achieving our goals no different than
any other business enterprise it's just
that we own it now now we're paying
attention to those things we want to
spend some time over the coming months
thinking about
our communications and image what does
that mean what does communications an
image mean to all of you into the rest
of the world and so we think about that
in terms of what we're saying on the
website what we're doing in the way of
printed collateral and signage and we
have made a commitment as part of our
budget to make a major investment in
overhauling our website and in improving
our image another part of our strategic
goal we want to grow the number of
sponsors we're making continuous
progress when we look back for meetings
ago to the number of sponsors that were
present here at nan on to the number of
sponsors that you'll see here today it's
more than doubled its more than doubled
and we need to keep that path going and
we need to manage it the other piece of
our strategic plan is program content
relevancy we have a program clearly in
order to keep it relevant it needs to be
dynamic and it needs to be it needs to
change stay you know active and that's
not just something the program committee
alone has to shoulder the board and all
the committee's talk about program
relevancy and we're talking about
developing new ideas new content that we
may be able to bring to the forefront
just these are things that we're talking
about I can't tell you that we have
actual plans to do anything but they're
on the table for discussion and they're
part of our planning that will bring
back to you in and talk with the
membership about well anytime you have a
plan and you're doing a lot of dreaming
and we own it there's some risk right
you had to talk about your risk and the
risk is when we increase our sponsorship
or we increase our content or our
programming there's cost associated with
that right there's people behind
the scenes making things happen so we're
constantly also dealing with oh this
would be great we want to do this buddy
says reality check it's great but let's
talk about what the impact of supporting
it is so that we're not ignoring the
risk of putting something in place
that's going to be very expensive for us
to support we also recognize we're not
the only network operators group in the
world right there's global competition
not only in other operator groups but in
other professional organizations and we
can't be unaware of what they're all
doing and where we're at in terms of our
positioning and drawing your attention
to come to our meetings we have to as a
board in asset organization make a
strong commitment to these strategy
goals so we've spent a lot of time the
board has and we spent some of your
money paying for a facilitator to come
in and help us put these plans together
and we need to be prudent and make a
commitment to stay the course and not
just plan meeting to meeting we can't
revert to the old ways and we're
committed to doing that what what will
help to ensure our success is your
engagement your willingness to tear
yourselves away from the super bowl to
come here to a brief member meeting but
nanog is only as good of an activity as
you're willing to be engaged with us
it's not a one-way conversation looking
forward I think we've said this many
many times and I believe that everyone
here and the board and everyone on our
committees believe that we have a very
bright future that what we've done in
the past year in terms of terms in terms
of the transition has been the right
things to do that making a change has
been good
and it's been tough a lot of work for a
lot of folks but when we look at the
financials when you look at the
financials that are available for you to
look at an arrow and when we as
committee members talk about some of
these new ideas and relationships that
we're building it's really exciting it's
a really exciting stuff instead of just
the same old same old same old kind of
nanog we're really talking about
changing in creating a new future for us
and I think that there are rewards that
we're starting to see in that we we have
the usual discussion we're six weeks out
from a meeting and we've spent a lot of
money on this hotel and the registration
number is up like it 185 or 200 and
we're going on my goodness but you know
what there's over 480 three of you here
today so we must be doing something
right our our membership numbers are
growing our attendance numbers are
growing and our sponsorship engagement
is growing in your registration fee has
not increased so I think the kind of
attention that we're paying is paying
off and what we are also seeing is that
nanog has grown up in that there's not
as much negativity being discussed in
the mail list about Nana but you're
talking about operator issues in the in
the mail list so that's also another
sign that the list that we have that is
critical to the operations of the
internet is working and it's working to
talk about real business of the Internet
as opposed to just business of some of
the political isms of running Nana so I
think that's also a bright future that's
the strategic plan that's where we're at
as i said i know this is was very brief
and there are a lot of details that i
threw out there things that we're
thinking about as soon as it becomes
more concrete
and we can share it with you we'll put
it up on the website and we'll have both
electronic and more conversation in June
with you at the next member meeting
questions hello hmm well uh just 20 to
introduce myself when I think yes all
right I'm my name is Dorian Kim from NTT
America and I got a diamond sponsor yes
but I'm actually speaking as just a
member not as a sponsor in this case you
know all this growth numbers that you
talk about is great but I have specific
question about the sponsorship Jim you
said that you know we've been even
growing the number of sponsors is that
specifically because you're looking for
diversity in sponsorships and you know
for sustainability or is it because that
original set of responses were not
meeting the financial requirements of
nanog it's because when we set the model
in place Dorian we didn't a year ago we
didn't know with certainty how much
money we needed to support Nana that's
the reality of the situation we had an
idea of what we needed and we needed to
put a model in place that would help get
an infusion of dollars quick because we
didn't have any money to start with and
so the investment from the diamond
sponsors was huge it was so critical to
be able to know that out of the gate
three meetings ago we had vendors who
are willing to support that kind of
money in investment nanog now what we've
done is spent serious time looking at
what does that sponsorship model really
need to be going forward not based on
diversity you know in any of that but
really from a financial model point of
view what's the what's the targeted doll
that we need to try to achieve then let
me ask a question with this time with
the sponsor hat on does that mean that
you should be repricing or reclassifying
the different levels tears of
sponsorship as in up the dollar
requirements there is a redefinition of
the model yes and what you will see in
the coming days and on the website
through the development committee is
more details on what that new model for
Nana 56 and Beyond will be our first
cycle ended with this meeting and we
spent a lot of time right sizing that
model and putting together a new model
that will take us through the next year
and I really think that it is good for
nanog and it is not painful for sponsors
the benefit of what we've done is well
Dorian is we've spent time making sure
that we know what our commitment to you
is and how we're going to deliver it so
it's not as much of a gray area a trust
in gray area we actually know what we
need to do to honor that commitment that
you're making for us go to us I think I
can take the rest of the sponsorship
stuff pop you're offline okay thanks and
income and see myself for Misaka Misaka
where are you Masako is right there
she'll be happy to talk to you about it
okay thank you you're welcome hi Dan
Goulding with a rage of our data centers
first I want to say I'm personally very
happy with the fact that sponsorships
have been been broadened because I got
to sponsor it's I don't think we've
looking at the sponsor signs you know
some people are going wow that's a lot
of sponsors and I think some people may
be concerned that we
we've got nuts and you know certainly
you have to look at how many there are
but you know I I don't think it's it's
becoming reasonable I do think you can
charge a little bit more I wouldn't
charge I wouldn't double it but I think
there is still some distance you can go
on increasing the charger sponsors the
thing that I would ask in return is a
sponsor is continuing to professionalize
the sponsorship process so if you know I
pay 30 grand or something right time to
kill me to be 50 only if the sponsorship
process becomes you know much more
seamless painless and
and look this looks much more like a
professional organization and much less
like a network engineer striking through
conference which is which is not a slap
at any of us it's just one of the things
you have to do it sort of the quid pro
quo absolutely the other comment I want
to make is I I think we're doing great I
think you guys have done a wonderful job
I think the fact that you don't have 100
people in this room have we're going
here to to scream and yell and freak out
is the ultimate vote of confidence and
so the only question I would ask is are
we to say we're still getting the
volunteers we need to even process and
police to develop those volunteers are
we getting the community participation
we need your peopie are we putting the
right cogs and the right holes you know
it's we've gone past the stage where the
early pioneers are you know something
many of them were on the stage but at
some point the early pioneers are stuff
wait we've other folks ready to step in
and do
somebody want to answer I mean I i can
give you my dan you're absolutely right
let me answer in two ways we recognize
that we have to behave more inner is a
professional organization when it comes
to our sponsors there's processes in
operational activities that we need to
change so that it's it is professional
that it's more streamlined than what
it's been we acknowledge that and we
thank everyone who's been willing to
stay the course with us and we know it's
been bumpy as a board as as your ed we
make a commitment that it is getting
better and we spent a lot a lot of time
talking about how to make that better in
fact so much so that's why I can't say
oh here's the new model we I wished I
had that for you we're not quite there
yet because we want to make sure that it
is professional that we understand it
and that we can honor the commitment
that you're going to make to us so we're
first and foremost it's right in front
of us the second part do we have enough
volunteers and and do can we sustain the
volunteer structure that we have we
talked about it a lot and we talk about
what the balance between volunteers and
paid contractors ought to be how much do
we go to a model where we pay
contractors to do everything for us just
because that's easier than trying to
deal with the balance of some
contractors and some sponsors or
volunteers doing bits and pieces of it
we had a very long day today talking
about just those issues we have it lost
track of it and i should say we don't
have any problem finding volunteers from
the community to do things for us the
nice thing about nana is that you're all
committed and so when Betty says hey
something happened I need somebody to
help me I do not have a problem finding
somebody out here to find a way to get
help for Nana
and I think the board is an excellent
resource in giving me direction on who
to call so we have never found a prop
you know having a problem getting
somebody to step up and do something for
us it's more an issue of us deciding do
we want to pay pay for that so we have a
paid service level agreement and it's a
little bit more ironclad than the work
that it takes to find volunteer
so Dan's asking if we have enough
volunteers on the pc and stuff for the
rest of you aren't being directed at his
very quiet voice Dave points out the Dan
is now chairman of the mailing list
committee thanks Arkham our committees
or staff but I think that we'll all get
a better handle on that commitment level
dan when we do elections again when we
get folks who are willing to step
forward and and take on the work that
your board has been taking on the past
18 months are they willing to be equally
committed in the same thing with program
committee members we won't know that for
sure until we do elections again in the
fall but but I can't say that everyone
who's there now is fully engaged Jolie
giggly quick comment well former and
probably future sponsor but I actually
don't think there's too many logos out
there I think that's actually just fine
as long as they stay out there when
they're on the podium that'll be like I
think probably a bridge too far so you
know we just have to keep things in you
know keep our roots in mind and I think
that that that guidance will probably
hold us in good stead it has so far
you're absolutely right part of the
value set that we hold and share with
you is to create a vendor neutral
environment inside this room so we love
sponsors it's great to have them here
it's wonderful to have socials but by
doing that does not give you the right
to be here at the microphone or two to
have control over the program and so
that again is part of the dialogue that
we have with the sponsors but it's
absolutely a commitment that we have
that's one of our goals and
and founding elements I'm sorry I'm here
again but I like to also echo a Joel
said I'm definitely concerned that if we
were to ever see like sponsorship logos
as responsive by the way in the meetings
and such BB which to fall but in
responding me a little bit to what Dan
said I want to caution one thing you
know certainly you know if you guys need
to increase the dollar amount for
sponsor to it and so on and so forth
I'll be fine but in terms of the Prophet
you know becoming more professional yes
for the first year as we're doing this
for the first time the things in the
process that obviously could have been
done better but I also wouldn't go so
far down that process to essentially
create the processes and procedures and
so on and so forth that takes you know
people's times that is not necessary I
think that you know we need to know what
the best solution is and what the
easiest way to have no not be a you know
an organization for sponsors to deal
with and then just stop there and no
further yeah and we need to be very
cognizant of the fact that you know as a
member-driven organization like this
there's no reason for us to be more than
what we are thank you
anybody have a
mentioned a lot about the sponsors and
obviously there's been an increase in
the number of sponsors over the last few
who are easy I'm vishal sharma met
annoying and my question is what is what
is the value that na nóg is planning to
provide to the sponsors i mean you know
they obviously do not influence the
program that's like sacrosanct and nanog
and that should stand but in addition to
that where is the value for the sponsors
as the number of sponsors increases and
the sponsorships shifts labs increase
what is the promise to the sponsors I'm
just wondering sure we make a commitment
to our sponsors that we will help
promote their visibility through our
signage through these slides that you
see it breaks you know recognizing their
contribution we do a lot of web page
presentation again recognizing the
sponsorship the nice thing about nanos
website is that we value our archive so
if you respond sir that's archived and
it lives as long as nan organs around
and there's information about your
engagement and that's that's pretty
valuable not you don't get that with a
lot of investments in organizations like
Nana the other thing that we promise in
the value returned is that we provide a
set up inside the exhibit I don't want
to call exhibit excuse me wrong word
because we don't do exhibit halls but we
provide and pay attention to the setup
of where the break food is the breakfast
food and we make sure that there's a
traffic pattern so that if you're a
vendor at break or a vendor who is
participants or that's participating at
breakfast that you have an area that's
assigned to you where you can put up
your display and you can have access and
be available to all of the attendees
that are here doesn't it doesn't mean
that everyone has to come by you but it
gives you the opportunity to have access
to them outside of this room and we have
a variety of ways in which we can do
that through beer and gear through
breaks through all sorts of things and
we've we've priced our sponsorship model
accordingly to deal with that return on
investment so there's you know really
large investments in their smaller ones
and it's up to the sponsor with the
development team to right-size which one
works best for you ok I think that's
that's good the day slabs and then you
have opportunities for visibility and I
and I guess one way for nanog to also do
to kind of capitalize on the base that
nanog has is that just and then require
some thought process probably but just
being I mean if it can be so constructed
that just being a sponsor of an event
that is vendor-neutral is in itself
something of value then you know there
are sponsors that will come forward to
do just that absolutely and in this
venue isn't the right one for other
sponsors so we acknowledge that too so
we're very open and we don't try to
mislead anyone as to what this venue is
and what the value asset of this venue
is and of access to all the operators
and it works perfectly well for some
sponsors and it doesn't work well for
others and that's fine thanks
we're done unless you have any questions
I I think we're done Sylvia are we done
scores still 1715 Patriots they second
down on the 8 yard line 2nd intent on
their own 8 yard line thank you again to
there's there's three wheel it in bmore
near the beginning of the fourth floor
any time any of you as members nine
minutes or the community in general all
of us our members of board at nana org
and i can assure you that we pay
attention to everything that comes in
nana support if you don't know you have
a comment operationally things aren't
working right for you give me some help
and then marketing at nana org helps you
get the information on sponsorship one
last reminder you'll hear this many
times tomorrow please please do take the
survey we have a number of different
types of surveys because we have a very
diverse population and we want to to ask
certain questions of you know our
speakers and our sponsors and so forth
but it's really important for you to
provide me and the board feedback on
your experience here and the only way
we're going to get that is by you taking
the survey and we hope we've made it
easier for you takes just a couple
seconds so so please do the other part
and give us your feedback thanks
you