alright welcome back and break everyone
thanks to subspace communications and
Tori point for putting out a great
spread there thank you if you haven't
had a chance yet please fill out surveys
we value that information very much as
we planned future nanos coming up next
we have Craig labovitz with deep field
Network sees going to talk to us about
how the other half of the internet lives
Craig welcome okay what am i doing wrong
person
well as I wait for the slides to come up
today I'm going to tell you about a
mystery a mystery that's plagued me for
the last several years two years ago I
did a bunch of work looking at how the
internet was evolving how the major
hyper Giants the major traffic players
were consolidating internet traffic was
changing build-out of CDNs and exchange
points and when I was doing that work it
was pretty clear what the top fifty
percent of internet traffic was there
was a hyper Giants there was all the
properties my mother and my wife knew
about the facebooks the Google's of the
world but as I was doing that work there
was always a strange element very large
traffic volumes that weren't part of the
hyper Giants in fact as I look for them
they weren't part of any well-publicized
websites or properties rather big
mysteries so this work is really looking
at the other fifty percent of internet
traffic so as I said it became clear as
I was doing something earlier work about
2010 that the same asn same site or
block same data centers kept showing up
again and again and again in the data
and it's never quite clear to me who
these folks were what they did why they
actually some of these folks had like
one or two percent of all internet
traffic it was going to some of these
ASNs on these data centers but if you
went to the web page they had these
small little European companies as
customers that I never heard of it
clearly wasn't these little companies
selling tires and widgets and umbrellas
that were generating one to two percent
of all internet traffic so spent a lot
of time asking around I asked all the
major operators I asked lots of folks in
the NAND out community you know I'm
seeing these asn do you know why they
have this number of terabits per second
of traffic and you know the nice thing
about the Nanta community is asking
around everyone had theories and you
know the other nice thing that the Nana
community
is that not only do their theories but
they're pretty sure of their theories
but when you actually ask them great so
leaseweb is doing this how do you know
that generally it was a shrug but they
would insist even more strenuously than
fact their theory was was accurate as
I'm sure many of you know arguing with
your colleagues so the mystery was where
is all this traffic coming from if you
actually look at net flow you generally
come up empty these are you know
millions and hundreds of thousands of
different IP addresses typically all
behind URL our application level load
balancers tools come up empty who is
doesn't tell you much DNS doesn't tell
you much some of the sites actually go
out of their way to obfuscate their
business or obfuscated their ownership
structure some using short-lived DNS if
you go to the websites often you'll get
in the load balancer or more frequently
than not you'll get insulted this is you
know you're you're too stupid this site
is not for you other sites salted my my
mother and my family and my heritage so
today all will be revealed I will tell
you what is the other fifty percent of
the traffic where it's going and in fact
as my colleague likes to joke it turns
out i have an exhaustive list of many of
these sites now it took a bunch of work
it actually took us a few months we
actually did a lot of stuff it turns out
it's not one thing to actually identify
all of these major sites you have to use
a variety of techniques techniques
combined them together there's math
involved and this is not a methodology
talk i'll do a paper and those more
academic bent can attend those types of
conferences but we spend a while
collecting data doing a lot of work
spinning up VMs around the world and we
found out who those fifty percent of
internet traffic work this is really a
best effort we believe it's
representative and before I go forward I
want to make explicit that will be
talking about sites that have varying
degrees of morality
legality I have no well I do have
opinions on these but the talk isn't
about those opinions and we're not
getting into any of the copyright or
other issues we do have a blog post
today that's out with a little more
detail and we will have a paper coming
out shortly so now I know the suspense
is building what is this fifty percent
of internet traffic who is it where is
it coming from well the conventional
wisdom I'll give you the answer now it
is file-sharing p2p in adult video is a
massive volume of internet traffic
shocking I know to all of you in the
audience but what's really interesting I
think about this massive traffic volume
is that the conventional wisdom at least
you know as you talk to folks or hacker
news or slashdot is that you know adult
video is everywhere every nook and
cranny of the Internet same with
file-sharing in p2p it's just all over
the place completely distributed and it
turns out as you look at the data what
really is the most striking thing as you
look through these you know terabytes
and terabytes of data is that no in fact
far from being spread out you have in
all of these industries all these more
or less niche industries you have
incredible consolidation of supply chain
of hosting providers Colo providers and
providers they all use more or less the
same folks and you see similar things in
other industries because many of these
have specialized needs you know it's
interesting the adult video is a very
specialized industry with the payments
file sharing is fascinating business
model but again very very I think
centralized infrastructure so this talk
this talk is a brief tour of a very
large volume of internet traffic that is
actually supported by a surprisingly at
least to me very small number of
companies particularly we're going to
focus on file-sharing p2p an adult
traffic today yeah and with a focus on
the infrastructure that supports it
so first file sharing is a bit hard to
define at least you know the New York
Times had kind of an interesting piece
around the megaupload the piece was all
about how do you know all the sites look
alike you know if they're going after
megaupload Dropbox is next box net is
next no one can really tell you know it
turns out that I think at least it
superficially that's true if you go to
any of the file sharing websites they
all look identical layout similar
graphics even similar fonts and some I
mean they're all playing by the same
playbook somewhat ironically even some
of the known file sharing ones have very
strict prep cynically dmca takedown
notices and staunch warnings against
file sharing is not allowed here even
though that's 99% of other business and
but rather than get into the business of
what is file showing or not I think what
we decide to do in this talk is allow
the industry to self classify so if you
go to one of the hundred of file-sharing
search sites you can right now all of
you have your laptops going to Google
try to download type in download man on
a ledge you'll come up with many of
these search sites and in turn these
search sites point to the file sharing
hosting sites there's a couple hundred
of them generally though I've yet to
find and looking at 50 or 60 of these we
surveyed none of them actually point
shockingly to Dropbox or two box net
they all actually point to the same set
of other hosting providers so if you
have any mystery or you know in your
York Times reporter that's confused you
can point them to any of these websites
and it should help with some of the
confusion the only other note I'd have
is please don't actually download man on
a ledge if for no other reason it's an
awful movie
I should also point out the file sharing
sites have a very different notion of
verified than I have some of these
actually go to files but they're not man
on a ledge movie there I in please don't
go to them because they're not
appropriate some of the things behind
these links for a mixed professional
audience so file-sharing I don't have
enough time to get into it but it's a
fascinating business model and as with
other industries you very specialized
partners very specialized ecosystem as
the money flows through it but generally
breaks down into a couple of categories
of advertisement supported you've the
folks that are actually paid for search
you actually have to pay them ten
dollars before they'll actually give you
the hidden URL in rapidshare or
previously megaupload or filesonic
there's others that you just pay to
actually access the file or for the
storage so really kind of an interesting
business model and we spent uh this
isn't part of the talk but spend a bunch
of time looking who are the different
partners how they interacted and what's
the money flow through this particular
industry so final shooting overall huge
part of internet traffic it depends
where you measure but broadly in North
America up to ten percent at any given
time of all consumer traffic generally
though from a fairly small percentage of
consumers about one to two percent of
actual and and some consumer subscribers
and you know had some very similar
patterns in terms of diurnal nature and
some other sort of stationary properties
to peer-to-peer but the most interesting
slide is this one or this in the next
one so the real question is you know
file-sharing it's all over the Internet
there's hundreds of different file
sharing sites but what's amazing is
these hundreds of file sharing sites all
use the same colos and it's not
particular it's that this is how these
industries evolve and there's a variety
of reasons why this happens but I can't
actually read my slide in front of me
nor can I read that but I'll do this
from memory this is the slide from
18 2012 in the hours just before the
coordinated global raid on megaupload
and dot get his name Kim calm which I
always thought was a fantastic name
you'll see that Jerry teeth megaupload
was the giant megaupload owned about
thirty forty percent of all file-sharing
traffic using Carpathia in the US
leaseweb and a few other providers and
you'll see that everyone else was pretty
far behind you had you know putlocker a
bunch of other folks and I didn't have
enough room in the slide to list
everyone but they're generally in the
other bucket but when you look at where
they're all going again it's the same
data centers the same hosting providers
not a whole lot of a variety or Hetrick
you know it's pretty homogeneous set
though as I said it actually takes quite
a bit of effort to identify not only
what's a file-sharing site but the the
infrastructure they're using so this is
January 18 2012 and then in a matter of
hours the global file sharing world
changed one to two percent of all
internet traffic dropped overnight at
least for an hour or two and for some of
the other file sharing sites this was a
gold mine so who won who are the winners
or losers if there's winners or losers
in this well putlocker really came out
ahead I don't really have a lot of
insight into why they've been reading a
lot of the discussion you know if you
actually search for this stuff you can
you know there's a lot a lot of traffic
from the different file sharing focus on
why they prefer one site over another
but putlocker came out ahead the
industry kind of rejiggered and today
we're basically back up the same traffic
level though you know we're not using
Carpathia anymore and said it's leaseweb
and a few other providers enter the top
10 or so of the global file sharing
traffic sources so you know the
interesting about file sharing is
there's hundreds of distinct domain
names out there if you actually spend
some time you
find out that many of these domain names
and what looks like separate companies
are actually all the same company
generally it's pretty hard to tell with
adult video and file sharing what the
corporate structure is generally I only
get a really good idea when they sue
each other because the court documents
the ownership structure comes out a bit
but really you've got ten of these sites
contribute seventy percent and you just
add four kolos you know leaseweb troopa
a few others basically owned eighty-five
percent of the file-sharing market so
not very distributed highly highly
localized and putlocker the new winner
so that's a segue I don't know how it's
a segue but I'll move into adult video
now and again I'm not making any moral
judgment these are just very large
traffic sources that often aren't
documented aren't discussed and
certainly if you go to a LeaseWeb
homepage you know they're not really
advertising who their major file-sharing
customers are but the adult video world
also is really really interesting
economy how they do the link sharing and
the file sharing what's interesting to
me is most of the traffic is CDN based
all the drm all the billing and all the
other stuff comes from a very very small
number of specialized players again very
specialized ecosystem most of the actual
traffic volume which again is video
comes from the CD ends and what's kind
of cute is the CD ends make an effort to
generally segment all of the red light
traffic is in its own little cider
blocks own little dns hierarchy you know
whenever you reach any of these you
might not recognize the site name but
you know that anything in these blocks
is adult video most of the CD ends are
involved at least to some degree in
adult video and again you know no crime
not making any judgment though it is
interesting folks like Akamai have
clearly decided it's just not part of
their business model which you know may
be a luxury of the market leader perhaps
but as with the the file-sharing again
there's specialized market and even you
know what you notice as you look through
the different websites the file sharing
the pwc box folks are
all trying to sell they all have
messaging but they don't want to they're
not very direct none of the file-sharing
large kolos come out and say you know
we're supportive of this industry this
is what we do similarly with adult you
have a fit if this I think this is like
in force you have things like you know
we don't ask what you stream when you
stream how you stream you can stream
with us just please don't Blake break
any international laws and again
specialized payment hosting providers as
well this is what adult video looks like
today as you look at the underlying
infrastructure there are thousands and
thousands of different domain names in
URLs it turns out every fetish gets its
own URL and own domain name and by the
way there are a lot of fetishes but the
major players our xvideo tends to be one
of the largest ones followed by free
cams and again fairly well distributed
but what's interesting if you look at
the red lines that's the drm the payment
the control traffic all going to the
same specialized providers typically
I'll you know most of their year a lot
of them are European and then we have
got the global cdns number one two three
and four anonymized I know not we're not
naming names at least of folks that
might be in this audience so that's
adult traffic and I'll finish off the
talk with the rise and fall and rise of
p2p so p2p used to be massive p2p back
you know seven years ago was going to be
the end of the internet circuits were
filling up the world was ending folk
stars are deployed DPI you know it was a
huge huge problem and then for a variety
of reasons including carriers throttling
raa notices that p2p just was awful you
know the performance and you know they
declined overall globally I found that
in some of the research work I did
and a number of other commercial
companies and researchers all documented
the rather steep decline and that's the
kind of graph on the right there left
depending so p2p was declining
disappearing as a major source still
sizable and some networks twenty percent
but overall the trend was clear file
sharing was being replaced by zooming
p2p was being replaced by file-sharing
but then the world changed again what
changed the cloud and HD and blu-ray
movies changed as well forcing the video
requirements so p2p was awful I know
none of you you know use p2p to download
movies but if you had tried you could
spend hours to find out you didn't get
the movie you expected it was so much
easier to go to megaupload and just
click on the link and download or pays
pay your five dollars but what really
changed is p2p is really starting to
adopt the cloud before p2p was dorm
rooms talking to consumers over
throttled you know and megabit links
today from maybe 60 or 70 different
providers of any size you can buy for
twenty five dollars a month unlimited
bandwidth 250 gig storage pre-configured
the latest torrent code and maintained
for you and you can host it conveniently
in Europe which not coincidentally is
outside the jurisdiction perhaps the US
movie and record industry and you can
now get streaming you know the other
thing is that p2p market at least the
high end is really competitive right you
you're judged or the software
automatically calculate your download
based on your upload and it's all about
the ratios so you know it's incredible
change to go from you know a DSL to a
giggi in a data center so we've seen the
emergence of extreme seed a seed box
just hundreds of these guys still a
small percentage of the PDP market but
growing fairly rapidly and being
marketed fairly half rapidly and we're
you know especially starting to see an
uptake I think
post some of the megaupload changes but
again with with file sharing and adult
video it's kind of interesting if you
actually look at where the major
trackers live where the major seedboxes
live it is really fairly highly
centralized ovh LeaseWeb again shows up
softlayer singlehop and a few others and
you know I think this happens in all
different segments of the economy or
different markets with a case of like
OVH if you have a seedbox you know obh
does a little bit of active marketing
but you also want to be closest to the
other seat box seat boxes so this a
little bit of a network effect Metcalf
effect whatever you want to call it
where you know I expect a huge portion
going across OVH data centers is just
seedboxes sharing the same files to each
other again and again as well as by the
way quite a bit of the p2p traffic is
now your customers getting traffic
incredibly and efficiently from the seed
boxes in Europe and you'll see if you do
some Google searches you'll see the
community of file-sharing argue over
who's the best if you're curious OVH is
not the best though they are the
cheapest so they have first place right
now globally so a very brief tour to
finish off the talk if you want to know
where the largest Russian p2p seed was
it is satisfyingly in an old bunker
which if you read the google translate
text they got cheap due to the radiation
but it again I I'm sure I could get a
better translation i'm sure i could get
a more accurate translation it would not
be better somewhat depressing I mean
this isn't nearly as cold lot of this is
a file-sharing in the UK brand new data
center the most efficient in Europe
which I'm struggling with all the glass
windows exactly how that is going to
work whether they're cooling and their
energy but if you want to see where the
the file sharing is actually coming from
small number of data centers and here's
a picture of another so my final slide
before questions file-sharing p2p adult
video are huge thirty percent maybe a
bit more depending where you are what
your audience base is what's really
interesting particularly i used to be a
academic long ago but i'm fascinated by
the consolidation of the shared
infrastructure and the ecosystem
economic ecosystem the head has
developed around these companies that
really leads to very specialized needs
targeted sales strategies by the
different vendors in the cyber supply
chain and as I blog this morning I think
the biggest observation i have is about
the megaupload takedown did not end
file-sharing didn't even interrupt it it
did however make it staggeringly
inefficient as most us file-sharing now
is going to centers in Europe and so
perhaps the biggest change and you know
it's a very dynamic market that we're
watching as we see in the in the market
is such a huge volume of traffic it
really can have significant impact on
carrier iix decisions peering decisions
and the like with that I've got six
minutes and this is an awesome countdown
clock for questions
so especially in abuse yourself j j qi p
infusion so especially in a PTP case as
you know a lot of software distribution
models increasingly relying on p2p
distribution probably some file sharing
as well but have you started drilling
down into the origins of the supply
chain for some it's traffic yeah we can
track the Akamai stuff I figure out what
the company the bog is called now it's
escaping me but we can track the
different types i mean there's lots of
different types skype and you know the
Akamai commercial stuff and this bunch
of the games all are types of PDP but we
can track them individually and have you
noticed any kind of new trend or any at
some point there was a quantum change in
the type of traffic or as in the
industry move to this sort of newer
model for distributing bits and bytes
yeah i mean this data set is a fairly
short one so i really don't have
longitudinal you know going over time in
longitudinal that logic to terminal date
on that i was only really been tracking
you know just fairly recently thanks
Dave temkin Netflix so I noticed that
you mentioned a bunch of hosters in
there but you anonymized the CD ends so
what was what was the reasoning behind
that uh you know I I think that's a fair
question I think
there's a lot of those hosters in this
room there's only some of those CD ads
in this room so it's kind of interesting
direction to go with that yeah you know
I think it's a fair question initially
we had had no names and then it looked a
little silly so but I think I think it's
a fair question but no answer you know I
I could I could just leave you too Randy
because I'm sure he'll have something
pedantic Randy Bush i J um I hope you're
going to do the longitudinal because
there are some interesting aspects what
will be the reaction to the megaupload
takedown and how will the market and the
technology they use respond to that will
they distribute more will they go to
bittorrent more what's going to happen I
presume megaupload got taken down
because you or somebody like you with
connections to Leo looked and said
there's the biggest one let's go shoot
it the other side is have you looked at
the payment flow and how that's done
because it's pretty amazing i learned a
little about it by accident by picking a
random partner dinner and they happened
to be in the payment industry for the
adult market and that's very
concentrated and it's very it's pretty
different it's pretty different and I
once had lunch with up again I can I you
know it's all about meals for me um it's
um had lunch with a an adult content
provider and I found out that in America
most of the adult content providers
ownership lives in Florida because
Florida
state law says that you cannot
confiscate somebody's primary residence
so they all have enormous assets
involved in their primary residence in
Florida I mean this is all weird stuff
yeah you know I knew it was mostly
busines Florida but I thought it was the
weather I hadn't heard that no it's not
it's because they can't take your
primary residence you build a
ten-million-dollar primary residence and
their assets yeah so just to answer the
questions I only remember one of them
now I I was not involved the record I
had nothing to do with the megaupload
takedown we were looking at this this
before but that's nothing at all to do
with us and then yeah I have no idea
what your second question wasn't anymore
does anyone the audience remember since
he's walk away ah yeah I remember now
he's people aren't stupid then there's a
lot of money involved um so the they're
going to react and there I don't know if
they were going to change business model
but they're going to change technology
model I presume yeah and will it spread
to more differs of distributed hosting
well it spread to more P&P will the
payment channels change etc yeah you
know I think it's interesting to watch
you know i will say I'm not a lawyer but
you know that's really I think
megaupload really was different in the
degree they didn't make as much an
effort to I think obscure what really
was a core business proposition you know
all the others really do I believe have
legitimate you know some legitimate
business and there's safe harbor and you
know just looking at the website it's
very hard to tell you know what business
there they're in so you know I think you
will see the file linking and how those
things interact with each other change
you know I don't think you'll see as
much that's immediately available on a
google search bringing up the latest
Hollywood movies may it much more of it
may be behind a paywall or other things
like that 13 seconds left if there's
anyone quick they can ask a question
okay thank you