alright hello everyone this is some
James Califa renesis and the topic today
is this curious incident that some of
you probably remember from 7 November I
worked on the analysis for this with
Andrew Hobgood from renesis I should
also mention that this is based on a
huge pile of data as you'll see much
which was collected by Clint Abner who's
at home in New Hampshire and Alex Colvin
who's actually here today so cheers to
them just quickly for a level sitting
how many of you remember exactly where
you were at 9:09 and 30 seconds Eastern
Time on 7 November 2011 Johansson Wow
nonzero ok for context who remembers the
big event was blamed in the popular
press a June us bug that caused the
internet basically to fail rather widely
for about 20 minutes on this particular
day does it ring some bells okay this is
good I'd like to see that you remember
this because otherwise I'm talking about
something you don't remember what we're
gonna go through today is the first
chance that renesis has had to talk
about this event which was certainly a
unique event it's odd for us to take so
long to address an event like this
usually we come out with a blog you'll
notice we never blogged on this and part
of the reason is that well lets you'll
see it was a really strange event it
took a lot of analysis and a lot of the
time we spent going through this was
deciphering what it had not been and we
actually ended up inventing some new
tools to figure out what it was what it
probably was so just to take you through
to a day in the life at renesis you can
imagine what this is like in the old
days we used to have a lot more big
events internet-wide events where the
internet would sag and everybody would
have a bad day and largely through your
efforts the operator community those
days are now few and far between but on
this particular day something really
bad happened to the internet and in the
first few minutes of incident response
that's kind of what you start hearing
right you're out there on IRC start to
see traffic on the Nanog list you see
outages pop up people are tweeting
something really bad has happened to I
think they said level three and
everything's going wrong nobody knows
what's going on it's bad for me because
that renesis I know exactly what's going
to happen next and the fact that I know
what's coming
makes it worse so somebody out there is
gonna write in and say does what renesis
have a report ready for this yet this is
15 minutes later Dave okay is incident
15 minutes right the the instability is
still raging everything's going wrong so
actually we did have a report I had a
small wooden ball that it arrived in my
office with the identifying prefix
engraved on it as courtesy to the
renesis pre routing team they knew about
this we had the report already written
no that's not how it happens um
seriously we all started the same point
of confusion we start at 14 o 9:30 UTC
people are saying it's level three wait
it's not just level three its tada wait
it's everybody okay everybody's losing
transatlantic traffic people are losing
traffic all over the world türk Telekom
is having problems everybody's having
problems we lose about seven percent of
all of our BGP peers in the first 10
minutes and we have hundreds of bgp
peers as many of you do so here's the
the first symptom right if you've
watched a renesis presentation before
you've seen this curve this used to
happen in 2001 and 2003 and it used to
be worms right we'd have sequel slammer
that would cause so much traffic that
BGP would get crowded out and and we'd
lose keeper lives and then sessions
would crash and you'd see something look
just like that this huge surge of BGP
prefix updates advertisements from
everything all over the world coming in
is a 30 second rate so recently the way
that this happens is not a one
it's probably a router bug and so we
started digging into the huge pile of
updates trying to figure out what were
the common things we could find and
we've seen lots of these especially in
you know the 2009/2010 there seemed to
be a rash of them and you'll probably
remember a lot of these as having ruined
your day long a s pads long a s past
full of 4-byte asn t attributes weird
compliant but ugly things that get sent
out and somebody doesn't like them and
it tickles a bug and they reset their
sessions we didn't find it that we
looked at all the appearances of
attributes we looked at statistical
distributions of all the features that
all these updates have there was just no
pattern and so we said ah must be a new
kind of cyber nuke I did not invent this
phrase I merely exploited cyber nuke is
when one major vendor has done something
wrong they failed to recognize a corner
case right and the other vendors didn't
and so what happens is it's kind of like
epidemiology you have a problem starts
somewhere in the world it doesn't matter
where and everybody who doesn't have
that bug propagates it gloriously to
everybody who does have that bug and so
within about 30 seconds everybody on
earth who's vulnerable is going to
suffer whatever effects this causes and
bgp goes to hell it looks like that so
we dug in as we are want to do we took a
look at the distribution of newly
unstable prefixes so here are individual
prefixes in the table which we're stable
up until the last minute or so and
suddenly they're unstable we look at
this onset and we break it out by
geo-located country and what you
basically see is a cross-section of the
Internet so the u.s. is the biggest part
of that but there's a lot of networks in
the u.s. it's not really something
obvious that's you know geographically
local so we take a look at the up
streams we take a look at all the a s
paths try to figure out if there's any
particular a s we were hoping to find
somebody simple like level 3 oh it's a
level 3 problem no broad spectrum
instability almost every provider has
some instability in their customer cone
there's no smoking gun
okay at this point I'm realizing that we
may not be able to write the blog the
same day so what did we do we actually
had to go out as we looked at this and
four days failed to find what it was
that was the problem we were hearing
from the popular press what people
thought it was but we had to tie it back
to data so we ended up actually
inventing some tools to figure out what
this might be so we have a distributed
traceroute dataset I think this is the
first time we're talking about its use
it for events like this but this was the
idea of having a distributed traceroute
dataset we have some number of dozens of
collection points here there and
everywhere around the world we are trace
routing to as many IPs as we can find
that will respond so nearly a million of
them every day we do I think it was
about 8 billion in the last year and you
know traceroute is a pretty coarse tool
for doing Network measurement but in the
aggregate it tells you pretty
interesting things so here's a metric
that you can use non completion rate
let's measure how often that guy were
traced routing to fails to respond if
that changes
somebody is impaired and we can figure
out through careful analysis who that
might be
so of course trace route analysis many
of you have done it it's difficult you
have to be lucky enough to have the
right kinds of traces in flight at the
time of the event because we can't
predict that these things happen unless
we have the pre routing team in the tank
you have a big diversity problem right
you really have to have a lot of trace
route collectors in order to factor out
all of the collector side problems that
might be affecting one or more of my
trace route collectors in various data
centers and perhaps for this event it's
important to note this event is only
about twenty minutes long boom it goes
it rockets to a high level of
instability it exponentially repairs
itself in about 20 minutes it's kind of
over and so there's not a huge baseline
here but you can see the signal hey it
looks kind of like the BGP update curve
same timestamp simultaneous worldwide
increase in rate of failure
it's about double in 30 seconds and each
individual line you can see there is one
of our traceroute collectors reporting
it's non completion rate off of a
baseline there is a global baseline you
don't expect all targets to respond to a
trace but the rate of failure here just
goes off the charts and then comes right
back and it decays and pretty soon it's
kind of back to its long-term baseline
so we dug into this here's where you
realize why it took a long time for us
to talk about this we took 34 million
trace routes that we happen to have had
in flight during those first 15 hours
leading up to the event we identified in
each trace route pairs of router
interfaces in the paths that we're both
reliably crossed by our traces for the
event and then not reliably crossed in
the first 10 minutes after so that gives
you a nice subset to take a look at
there's about 28,000 of these edges
where we had really good coverage
viewing their availability and then we
take the intersection we look at who is
highly traversed and who was highly
impaired and when this was accepted one
of the conditions was that there not be
any math so I'm gonna violate that but
only very slightly here's what we did we
took we made a matrix in which the rows
are individual guesses that we are
tracing across right people who appear
in a s paths of the prefixes that hold
the IPS that we were tracing to the
columns are common 30-second time steps
forming a basis so this is a signal
matrix and we did an SVD to identify the
primary sources of variance you can see
them there in the left and the
colorfulness the top lines there are
illustrating the primary ways that all
of these a s's trace counts are varying
together as we walk through these 15
hours and fortunately for the analysis
you can see that the event that takes
place is very prominently visible it is
the primary thing happening on the
internet in these 15 hours you can see
that trace counts basically drop and
struggle back to the
you know that we got it all because you
can look at the next few great singular
vectors and you can see that there are
periodic noise there it's probably some
things that came out of our traceroute
collection little spiky periodic things
but basically we got the entire signal
in the first three or four we take on
the right a scatter plot we take all the
a s's and we find out how well they
correlate with the first ones right so
you're trying to figure out which a s
has had trace count signals that look
pretty much like the clear signal of the
event and again thank goodness we found
that providers like Tata and level three
and Comcast and Roadrunner and AT&T were
the ones that actually had reach ability
impairment in the data that looks a lot
like the story that was then going
around in in the chat rooms so we can
dig in again we can do the same trick
pull out a single provider take all of
the edges in the traceroute graph that
is all the router interface pairs of
which at least one is a level three
router and let's do the matrix thing
again let's normalize it let's do the
SVD and find out which ones of the level
three edges in their network correlated
strongly with these strongest signals of
impairment and you get a nice subset so
out of the heavily traversed 3,100
router edges that we took a look at
there about 650 in this first 10 minutes
and if you dig into those you find about
85 84 percent of those are just internal
edges they're on level threes Network
it's between a level 3 router and a
level 3 router as you might expect the
rest are out on the edge facing peers
and customers we're feeling a little bit
of whatever this was and because we know
where the routers are to some extent we
can make a breakdown of where the
heaviest impacts were being felt and
again it sort of jives with the stories
we were hearing what Los Angeles San
Jose Frankfurt London so you get unusual
people like türk Telekom having
significant problems ostensibly because
they are connecting to level 3 in
Frankfurt let's say and at that point
there is some transient it's called an
impairment
of course comes back very quickly you're
the same analysis I won't go into the
details again but with Tata
so provider by provider we're working
through finding the sets of interfaces
that we think were really hurt by this
70% of these 300 edges are about or
internal Tata the rest are spread over
peers and customers again New York Los
Angeles u.s. East and West Coast also
London right
Tata's Network as you would expect
there's some impact in Singapore and
Hong Kong and Mumbai and the people that
are impaired are impaired as you'd
expect if you take a look at this we're
going back now to the original data
we're saying how many traces had a
responding destination this is that
response metric again that's nice and
simple and you see as I pull out these
six providers you see the signal others
don't look like this you can see that
some of them are very direct and they
have the same shape of outage and
recovery like level 3 Tata Roadrunner
and then you see others like türk
Telekom who have a recognizable
modification of that signal but it's not
as sharp because they're downstream of
the presumed problem all right
a lot of traceroute lining back to bgp
which is my comfort zone
let's go looking for the root cause no
I'm gonna be the first to tell you that
there is no final root cause to be had
in this deck because this is about
correlation and observation here's my
favorite metaphor for this technique how
many of you as a kid really liked
thermonuclear weapons design yes I'm not
surprised Patrick yeah everybody this is
a beautiful device I think this is the
Castle Bravo test you can see the the
the primary the fission primaries on the
right and there's the lithium deuteride
secondary on the left okay there are
light pipes coming off of this thing the
way that they study these explosions was
that in the very first microseconds
there are pipes literally to carry the
light away from the detonation so you
can study it down at the end of the
bunker before your equipment gets
vaporized this is my metaphor this is
what
did we dug into this signal you can see
it go boom we wanted to dig into the
first seconds of this thing and figure
out exactly what was going on here okay
first thing everybody always tells you
when you're starting to do bgp research
at the university is don't mistake
session resets for signal yeah that's
true you know every time a bgp session
resets you get the full table and it
looks like a big signal but it's not
just a reset so here you can see
actually that the light blue is our
peers who are not resetting this is all
collateral damage this is stuff has gone
away somewhere else and we're seeing the
reconvergence noise of people trying to
find the best routes that don't exist
anymore
and then only a couple minutes later do
we start to see a rumble like a
secondary wave of resets from our peers
and we've ruled them out of this
analysis so let's take a look here's a
technique that we've used in two
presentations before each black square
here is the entire Internet okay we've
this is the measurement factory xkcd
kind of a modeling tool where you use a
Hilbert curved the space-filling curve
to map out the entire ipv4 address space
in a rectangle and so if you could see
this at full resolution each pixel is a
slash 24 belonging to somebody and here
we are looking at 30-second snapshots in
the first seven minutes and you can see
the first light coming out of the light
pipe right as this thing goes off and
it's at 1409 30 we can do a 10x zoom
okay now this is the first 30 seconds
that rectangle from the previous slide
now we're looking at it in three seconds
slices so each one of these is a three
second picture of the entire Internet
and again you can see it lighting up the
red box contains nine seconds of data
and we're gonna go diving in there to
try to figure out where this came from
this is a log scale plot of three
candidates that kind of fell out of the
analysis as possible places this might
have come from we're looking at the
advertisement rate per second in BGP
from all of our peers log scale they're
basically three here we thought it might
be so to tell
in Beirut or tikona in Mumbai or
possibly the Ukrainian academic research
net in Kiev you can see they're all
plotted there in my best Canoe plot and
the box there the rectangle is that
first nine seconds so the thing you note
about this is that the wave the the
leading edge of the signal is not
horizontal it's not vertical meaning
it's not simultaneous there is a leading
edge and the earliest light here comes
from tikona in Mumbai a large access
network I think they're a WiMAX provider
very large network and as you'll see
very a lot of a lot of prefixes in the
table it's so bright at this point that
in the first two seconds we see 28,000
advertisements just for tikona okay in
fact at that rate for just the two
seconds first two seconds of the event
they're brighter than the rest of the
Internet
the brown here is everybody else except
tikona the bluest okona one provider
such a couple samples there where they
are brighter than everybody else now
notice that after this initial flash
they fade and the rest of the internet
comes up as being unstable if you zoom
right in and it's very clear that
something extraordinary has happened and
they were the first on the scene again
we're sort of accumulating
circumstantial evidence so what's so
neat about tikona
is that basically they have two big
blocks that they allocate out of one is
this one 13 190 3/16 which they've had
for quite a while the more interesting
one that's in blue the more interesting
one is in red which is this slice the
slash 15 out of one dot a few of you are
nodding because you know that
interesting things happen in one dot
this is this is their recent acquisition
and you can see that over time as they
build out presumably their their
wireless infrastructure all over India
they're using pieces of this they're
putting slash 24s into the table and you
can see that in recent history it gets
pretty darn spiky meaning that they are
periodically D aggregating and re a
granade D aggregating and reallocating
and creating this routing instability so
why does that matter
there was this okay so months before
this happened there was this quiet
little announcement that there was a
vulnerability in Juno's that the router
could actually crash if it received very
specific very unlikely install and
delete actions the set of route prefix
updates is non-deterministic and
exceedingly unlikely to occur complex
sequence of preconditions has respond is
required to trigger this crash I'm not
saying that to make fun of them I just
love the sound of it there's no harm in
that right we're all friends
so it's interesting because what might
have happened here and I'm gonna kind of
leave you with this hypothesis because
since this is the first time we've shown
this in public I'm also looking for the
operator feedback to tell me if I'm
wildly wrong is that the bursty D
aggregation of that one dot space may
have accidentally recreated the trigger
conditions for that bug which as I
understand it it was very similar to the
bug that any of you will have seen if
you've written code to analyze large
numbers of BGP updates where you're
using something like a Patricia try and
you're trying to put things in and take
them out and keep track of them as they
nest there are corner cases that are
really easy to write in code like that
that can cause terrible problems I don't
know that that's the case but it's just
it looks like something I could
empathize with if in fact this was the
trigger it would make sense because
they're tired they're transit providers
were Vodafone India and Bharti which
were largely unaffected and Tata and
eventually as you go through the graph
of how they're connected this would have
hit level three and and everything would
have would have gone off the rails so I
present this without direct evidence it
is still hypothesis but it's my best
working theory at the moment so if I
summarize this
I think the summary here is it really
could have been worse I'm glad we don't
see these internet wide sags anymore
except on very rare events
I think what smells like what happened
here is that that vulnerability
description as you read it was was very
clear about the remoteness of the
probability of tickling that bug and I
think what may have happened is that
many of you took a look at that and
rationally said well I'm not going to
schedule a special maintenance to take
care of that I'll just wait and pick it
up the next time it comes around but
there is this law of large numbers
anything that can't happen on the
internet eventually will happen on the
internet and it took several months to
recreate the situation but I think it
happened and then you were all forced
with the necessity of doing this again
under pressure during eastcoast business
hours and the whole deal and so you know
you pay now or you pay later the
critical thing I think to realize to
remember here is if this was in fact the
bug where you have to apply route
updates in a particular order and then
pull them off again and then apply some
more and pull them off and then you get
the corner case is good because what it
means is when these things rebooted they
didn't just come up get the same update
the Poisson update back in there in
there in in their input and then die
because if that had happened this could
have lasted for four hours instead
basically we got one rebooted everybody
took a reboot went down came back load
it up all good keep going and so the
duration was mercifully limited to about
this 20-minute period so I think we got
lucky that's it I'll take your questions
West Georgia Time Warner Cable um I
think one of the takeaways that we got
from this was that there's sort of a
hole right now in the way that we find
these these bugs you know when we do our
certification testings either in the
vendor testing and their unit testing
and things like that in any more
specific testing that they do to try and
replicate one of their carrier customer
networks or the testing that we do
internally to certify things before they
go out in the wild I'm not saying that
we could have done some tests that would
have found this bug right or any such
thing but what I what it's kind of
getting towards for me is I'm wondering
if maybe we need to be as a community
focusing a little harder on sort of a
protocol fuzzing kind of thing within
bgp to try and poke at it a little more
and find some of these things in a
slightly more controlled environment I
don't know whether you know how we would
go about that whether it's you know
throw throw weird-ass things at it and
see when it's oils bed or whether
there's something else we need to do but
I've you know wanted to kind of bring
that up for if other folks have ideas or
if you do it's a good point I think that
this yeah I give if in fact it was
Jennifer's issue I give them credit you
know that that it was not it was really
a very remote possibility that this
would be triggered and so in some sense
it's at some point you have to change
over your strategy from zero defect to
resilience and recovery and whatever you
are doing presumably work pretty well
because after that one reboot cycle
everything converged then we went on our
way no it's not like the old days where
we could have been down for days if
somebody did the wrong thing so I I
agree with the sentiment that at some
point the discussion becomes about
resilience Brian Dierdorf level three I
just want to say that you're correct
about the address space
that it was out of so sweet that's good
the other thing is we did try to I had
the sequence from you know a couple
minutes before and we tried to replay it
in our lab and we were unsuccessful in
recreating it and that's really lucky
because you know my fear was oh it's a
nun it's the equivalent of a zero day
right it's this will be weaponized
tomorrow and then everybody who didn't
do the upgrade is going to get taken
behind the barn but that's cool that you
couldn't make it happen again
yeah that was my concern is that it and
well I didn't want to distribute the TCB
don't that I had and I had a concern
that it could be weaponized I guess but
it was I was happy that we were not able
to reproduce it me too
Jolie eglee I think one of the things
that I get from this and a lot of other
events that we've sort of experienced in
the real world is it calls into question
for me our ability to properly put error
bars on unprofitable events particularly
in this case the event itself may be
really in problem improbable but the
transitive nature of the impact of it
means that it only has to happen once
and so you know it could be a six or a
seven or an eight or nine sigma event
and it could still actually happen once
and that would be all that it takes so I
think that places us an interesting
place as far as risk goes I would like
to think that the system that we have is
robust because it's loosely coupled and
that it's behavior as you say you know
should be such that it's
a rare event is not immediately
repeatable but I don't think we've
arrived at something that would be the
opposite of fragile for example so great
I think it's good I mean you have to
come up with a rational response to how
you're going to spend on stuff like this
again it's a question of how much you're
prepared to spend to reach zero defect
and you know the five minute maintenance
window discover the fault let's fix it
well and I don't think zero defect is
actually likely doesn't sense any
universe that we live in so not in the
system unfortunately I think the mass
media and the culture at large is
catching up to us
because now they have also experienced
some three four five six Sigma events in
the markets and so forth and they are no
longer doubters you know the risk is
important and it's difficult to deal
with and you know they don't put blind
faith in the fact that we can just keep
the Internet up 24/7 for the rest of
time so good for us
the photo Tilikum I wonder whether
you're reading of the global system did
show to you a couple of other events
around say just two months around that
given the timing of the previous
advisory I did go looking and I did not
find okay
so let me let me let me tell me tell you
what saved us from actually
participating in the flaps we see
something like three distinct bucks that
were remotely trigger about just at the
end of September and dealing with that
stuff and actually we know we know that
a couple of other networks have been
flapping sessions around the same events
obviously not as bad not as bad as this
and well okay in the in the in the path
of dealing with the bugs that we
encountered while okay we did some
emergency upgrades back then which
included fixing this leak but kind of
kind of interesting thing is there are
actually so many events that show that
the BGP system has vulnerabilities that
can be triggered that well okay we can
be lucky that the public press isn't
really taking note of it
I'll leave that there because we're out
of time it's a great point thank you