I want to talk about changing the
economics of the network she talked
about culture I'm talking about money so
I want to talk about the control plane
the control plane is what connects the
Internet it is the internet is a network
of networks oh you've heard that a
thousand times how do these networks
connect well they connect through the
control plane which is defined by the
border gateway protocol why does it call
that because if you have a network of
networks when those networks touch
that's a border it does not refer
initially to international borders BGP
directs traffic step-by-step hop-by-hop
so that it arrives now why is BGP
interesting in terms of attacks and
vulnerabilities well BGP is not that
easy to map you can't draw a map like
this necessarily even though routers
have placed so suppose you wanted to
send something from FedEx from Tullahoma
to Memphis it may go to Madison if FedEx
has a center there and if it does it
goes to Madison every single time just
like your postal realms BGP routes are
not like that
well for one reason because in BGP it
might make sense to go I don't know
across town in Denver by driving to
Kansas and why would that make sense
well because the fibers and the networks
are owned by different people
if you PS you've owned all the roads
across town in Denver it would make
sense for FedEx to drive to meet Kansas
so why does it matter because if there's
no control plane there's no internet and
if there's no secure control plane none
of our goals can be met if I can
interrupt and reroute all your
transmissions remember the very first
opening set
when they were saying oh yes back when
we had these tiny tiny little key sizes
and we see everyday innovations in
cryptography we have a better
understanding of selecting keys so your
session keys cannot always save you and
if they can't save you then you're not
going to have an integrity in your data
and even if your crypto was perfect and
secure you it is possible to just a
black hole data so basically what
happens is internet pass changed very
rapidly
some of them changed back and forth all
the time they just flap back and forth
like Oh
Kansas not Kansas you know Internet they
can change very rapidly and once you
hand that packet over to BGP that's it
right so take these super secret
incredibly important intellectual
property nuclear code memos across the
country okay that's fine but you know
maybe I'll sell them first so one of the
things I've liked about this conference
is the introduction slide so why do I
care about something like BGP and why am
i making an argument that it is
legitimate to take a political and
economic perspective on something this
fundamental that is because I am a fish
who swims in two waters I have spoken at
the White House in the National Press
Club and RSA and black cat I changed in
four thermocouples at Catawba Nuclear
Station and I was I think the only
person at Catawba South Carolina nuclear
station who thinks that it is awesome
that I was in the house gallery you know
around the edge when Obamacare was
finally passed into law so just like I'm
an intersection so is BGP it's a
fundamental problem so one of the the
very first hearing on Capitol Hill about
computer security they brought up the
fact that BGP could be hacked I wanted
that I hung it
one of the then young men from loft he
became a DARPA program officer said I
can bring down the entire Internet in 15
minutes and we've seen that happen in
other countries if you look at some of
the internet takedowns the in Egypt and
Syria in India they've gone much farther
than this
it's basically a BGP attack it's a
fundamental problem it's foundational
technology and we've made very little
progress why is that well I believe that
I have an answer to why that is and it's
the economics so I'm going to argue not
just about BGP but more largely than if
we think about security as a thing if we
bring in economics and think about how
to only make it so that everybody wants
this by aligning investment in benefit
by design we could have a more secure
internet I mean in terms of the privacy
I will come back to that panel and say
it's a lemons problem it's a market
problem so what is this hijacking I keep
talking about it is not like carjacking
so I picked this equine attack because
bitcoin heist so as you know we all know
bitcoin is a distributed ledger
cryptographically signed technology
that's implemented where you gain value
by coming by calculating the correct
matching hash right so that's computer
intensive so people get together they
form a big club they call it a pool they
search collectively
and then they get the rewards and they
share them so there was a large mining
pool and they used Amazon servers Amazon
Cloud Servers to coordinate not to do
the mining ain't go Amazon it turns out
they set it up with no passwords or
security so if anybody wants to talk to
me about the brilliance of Bitcoin
miners I have the whole reception um so
what the attacker did was said hmm maybe
I'll just tell
the world that this tiny little slice of
the IP space that the miners are using
that's in Canada I get to say evil
Canadians which you never get to say so
this evil Canadian and there is only one
was able to get tens of thousands of
dollars with super quick bursts of
incorrect control plane information so
why do people commit crime is this a
criminal problem
there are basically three arguments that
are popular in crime science today one
is routine activity if you are walking
down the street and you saw a lot of
cash on the sidewalk you pick it up and
say you know rejoice I must purchase
better wine for Jeanne because actually
legally what you should do is you should
pick it up and you should take it to the
cops and you should describe when you
picked it up and they'll hold on to it
for X days and then if nobody comes and
explains they left this amount of money
you know a very fuel very few of us are
that good I mean it would take you hours
and also it's cash right but that's
literally a literally a crime right to
take it unsecured wealth the lack of
social support I'm sure you've heard
about the broken window theory that says
if there's no social support they'll be
more crime and relative economic
deprivation I mean here we have a
picture of a wonderful young man who
spent all morning stealing a loaf of
bread and then gave it to orphans if you
remember your Disney but relative
economic deprivation is particularly
strong on the Internet
because we have people as you noted from
all over the globe with tremendously
different standards of wealth where what
I would be annoyed by and write off as
my credit card would change would you
know cover their rent for a month so if
you look at these crime theories and you
think how can we measure this well was
routine activity theory you can say all
right their economic rationale
we're gonna look at available targets
and lack of oversight because frankly if
you pick up $200 off the ground you're
never going to get busted for it that's
part of it part of it is culture lack of
social support endemic practice lack of
oversight if there's no deterrence and
relative economic deprivation which is
just GDP per person I mean so we like to
DDP per person and secure Internet
servers and relative exports and we took
a lot of variables and we found that
there were some significant hotspots
that crime theory could absolutely
identify this is this is what is
happening this is a crime that is
happening just like smuggling we have
hot spots for hijacking there were also
some other places that stood out and if
you recall a map of underground fibers
the reason for some of these is obvious
right it's just where the fibers are it
makes it easier if you have a lot of
routers but there are some countries
that kind of stood out and they stood
out consistently across all Donita in
2014 cisco bought bgp mon and so the
data sharing is not the data sharing
changed and we so what we did is we we
clustered them we said all right we did
our multivariate regression to look at
crime and some of these things just did
not make sense so basically we looked at
secure internet servers which is
availability and access and how much
internet there is and mold governance
indicators which is how much crime there
is and you can see how you could draw a
line through that which is part of what
we got from our multi variant analysis
but there was a part of it that really
just did not make sense there are some
real outliers in this and when we looked
at those outliers we found something
kind of interesting which is that
excluding Comoros which is the little
tiny island with all the fibers coming
into it and all
the other drivers going out of it these
are places with either active conflict
or long-standing civil strife so there
was a good argument that something else
is happening besides crime so we have a
very serious problem and we all have to
work together to secure BGP because it's
not like your browser I can choose to
secure my own browser I cannot choose to
secure my own BGP so how do we make that
work
well it's a coordination problem I could
spend the rest of the talk trying to get
everybody who is in this room and
similarly aligned and completely
gracious and willing to help to move one
seat to the left just think about how
difficult that is in this kind of
coordination in this little space so how
do we do that how do we increase the
investment and uptake of secure routing
we redefine the problem as economic and
change the nature of the good so the
idea is if we look at the economic
threat we can change the economics of
BGP to beat that threat and if you want
to use the market you have to have a
market that functions the goods have to
have some basic characteristics or the
market doesn't work right the guys have
to be rival risk which means if I eat a
cupcake that cupcake is gone that
consumption is rival risk you cannot
have my cupcake it needs to be
exploitable which means I can protect my
cupcake from other hungry people and it
needs to be transparent which is like
this is definitely a cupcake
it is not a lemon and when you have
these kind of failures you get different
kinds of goods and the problem with
public goods is we don't have a way to
invest in global public goods
now goods that are non-excludable but
rival risks you're going to invest much
more than you would in a public good and
similarly for glumph goods that are
excludable and nonrival risks to give
you examples and
just names obviously cupcakes ready for
lunch
fisheries are non-excludable I cannot
keep you off the ocean but if you catch
a fish I cannot catch it and that was a
non-excludable and nonrival risk
experience of sound all right so it's
gluten ball and nonrival it's like a gym
membership we can all hug go to the gym
I did not pay them to do that so we can
change these weight the way we do
security we can change it like IP
addresses are non-excludable but rival
risk so if I claim an IP address and
your traffic is there that is I and
email I can I can keep you out of my
email right but I can't prevent someone
else from reading from copying the email
so other kinds of goods can be changed
by design so phishing detection we see a
lot of sharing clothes sharing
information groups incident data and I
believe that we can change bgp updates
of course most goods are not pure goods
they're mixed they're a cupcake in the
gym so traditionally my work has tried
to change the nature of goods here we go
by for example when I owner abilities we
all know about bug bounty programs and
the market for vulnerabilities before
bug bounty programs there was a young
man er people were arrested on the stage
and DEF CON for exposing of
vulnerability because not only could you
not you can only sell it to criminals
that was a problem so what are hijacks
are they a crime it's linked to spam
it's linked to malware and deep packet
inspection is linked to both so I wanna
make an argument that in addition to
machine learning and clustering there is
a real reason to believe there are
nation-state actors so beautiful Denver
people go there for this ski
there was a month-long hijack of the
traffic in Denver why is that well
because Denver outside of Denver is
actually the concentration of America's
surveillance infrastructure NORAD the us
NORTHCOM Cheyenne Mountain the recently
named space force and there's also a
building that everybody claims isn't
there but is there because I've seen it
and so if it existed it would probably
be associated with surveillance also
Peterson Air Force Base the Air Force
Academy and bike the Air Force Base so
all that's in a tiny little area and
interestingly enough as you saw in my
example it might make sense to go
through Kansas because FedEx owns the
roads
so sometimes Denver to Denver
Communications goes from Denver to
Dallas to canvas to Denver for months it
went from let me see let me see if I can
do this Denver to Chicago
yikes Denver to Ashburn to London to
Iceland which was a hacked IASP that was
generally generally reported that it was
owned by the Russians at the time that
this attack was happening and then it
went back from Montreal this was not
detected at the end point because the
delays were so so insignificant so how
can we solve this well the first panel
would tell you we need better crypto we
always need better crypto I mean crypto
is the oxygen of security if we don't
have it we can't do much so there's been
two proposals on the table for a very
long time which is resource public key
infrastructure basically says this is my
IP address you can't have it and BGP SEC
which says this is my IP address and
this is where it should go
so PKI origin value validation it just
says I'm going to associate the network
with the origin and that can stop
both IP address hacking and black and
black holing which means that you send
your data to an IP address and BGP takes
it to you no dev null it deletes it but
it can't do anything about BGP hijacking
and as long as BGP hijacking is a
problem we're going to be systematically
structurally fundamentally vulnerable so
BGP SEC offers full pass validation not
only is this my IP address but this is
my IP address and this is the correct
top and then this is the correct next
step and this is the correct next step
and we are all exactly where we should
be right of course
BGP it would be more like but it only
identifies trusted connections if we
trust everyone with a public key so and
it the wall it's only as high as its
shortest point so if there's a part
where it just kind of Peters out and you
can walk around it you can hijack it it
also requires that we trust the public
key of every participant so if we're
willing to trust I don't know Putin's
public key then sure we can roll this
out and then we would know things were
being hijacked as soon as we looked just
like they are now only with more crypto
so one of the ways I want to encourage
people to invest in things that help to
generate technologies that help the
person who invest in it so mismatches
between the autonomous system where
something connects to and it's the
jurisdiction are uncommon traffic
leaving San Francisco to go to San Jose
typically does not go through China it
did for a while when the US had a bunch
of soldiers in Afghanistan so Facebook
traffic actually went through China for
a while so traffic starting in one place
ending in the other place doesn't need
to go through any of these places but it
has gone through all of those places I
am in my research arguing for individual
autonomy the thing about I don't think
we will ever come to a time when we all
have shared values but we should be able
to express our own risk perceptions and
values on the internet without impinging
others I think we should be able to
choose one select a path and then say I
only want this data to go out if it goes
through this path I want it to go
directly there I don't want it to go
there there there there there there
there and there
and to do this to show you that this is
possible we created a route reflector we
named it Bongo because zebra is a famous
open-source product and quagga is but
Bongo is the ungulate with horns it's
the one that can fight so this is just
basically a picture that says we use
Bongo we put it between and it can work
with different architectures including
architectures for you know cloud data
clusters it works with Sdn and so
basically how can an organization
mitigate data exfiltration it can choose
to use there we go so much for animation
it can choose not to send the content
that is all you can really do today but
you can do that on the other hand if it
was widely adopted by individual
organizations hijacks would be
identified much more quickly so we
tested this on 50 financial ISPs well
the only one that dropped off and our
theoretical run is if we all had bongo
was the main bank and Iran and for some
reason it has very bizarre routing
patterns sometimes against Russia
sometimes it gets to Germany sometimes
it goes through a Mon
so if we understand hijacks is criminal
and economic as well as nation-state
that uses routers and wires that are in
specific very real countries with very
different priorities and cultures we can
do politically and economically inform
design to solve those different kinds of
problems thank you for your attention