so yes Brenda Baker tech lead for cloud
security Google today I want to talk
about our philosophy our approach to
internal production security at Google
this is really the first time we're
talking about this we recently put out a
white paper on this topic in December
and this is going to be an approach and
a walk through some of the history the
rationale the problems and how we've
addressed these problems for security at
Google so talk about the background the
problems history I'm gonna go through
and talk about some differences between
traditional infrastructure and sort of
this modern sort of cloud native
security infrastructure that we've
implemented in production at Google walk
through some of the details on how those
systems work and then sort of wrap up on
you know how this is applicable outside
of a place like Google so to start
thinking about the problem space that we
have to work with the Google or to think
about how we can manage security when we
have thousands tens of thousands of
developers deploying several billion
containerized workloads every week with
many products that have a billion users
and how can we manage security for these
at scale repeatedly and consistently
even in light of problems like this
heartbleed a flaw and open SSL that
allowed somebody to extract data if they
could connect to any server that did TLS
termination running open SSL or things
like this shell-shocked remember this
one this was a remote command execution
through bash shell escape it was
actually fairly prevalent a lot of
software included this included
libraries that allowed somebody access
this vulnerability or things like this
little more recently tcp sac that was a
panic and potential do s and maybe even
exploitation in the linux tcp/ip
networking stack or things like this
meltdown inspector and foreshadow and so
on right cpu side-channel
vulnerabilities
if you think about what these things
look like you know we're in a space that
has really moved way past concerns of
viruses and worms and phishing to an
environment where we have to be
concerned about vulnerabilities in
common software common infrastructure
the supply chain for how software finds
its way into production and
fundamentally even be concerned with
flaws in how CPU and CPU isolation was
supposed to work so given those concerns
again how do we do this in a way that's
consistent and can deal with patching
and scale that we have to operate oh
yeah and there's one other problem too
we have to do this without actually
having there be noticeable user impact
right so to get there first we have to
agree on a few things
servers are cattle not pets the whole
idea for this and to make this really
work at scale is that no one server no
one machine is special and you don't
have a different type of machine for
different types of workloads they're all
interchangeable there's just one sort of
compute fabric and things can move
around things do move around all the
time we also have to agree that security
doesn't end at the network edge just
because something's past an edge Akal a
firewall checksum IP check or connect it
in through the VPN doesn't mean that
it's trusted okay so this is getting to
this idea of a zero trust environment
where just because somebody is present
on the network we don't trust them
in fact if they're just on the network
we really don't want to trust them we
also have to agree that developers
shouldn't have to be security experts
and what that really means is that we
don't want developers to have to be
concerning themselves with all of those
vulnerabilities and patches and security
issues I just mentioned we don't want
developers to have to be concerning
themselves with what's the right
certificate policy that I should be
setting and enforcing that needs to be
part of the infrastructure needs to be
outside of what developers have to be
concerning themselves with because we
want them to be productive and efficient
and not all have to be security experts
we also have to agree that workloads
shouldn't be the place where we enforce
security policy every time I want to
update
going back to that ssl policy i
shouldn't have to push out new versions
of my workload to change that i want to
start enforcing perfect forward secrecy
on certificate checks for example and
the last thing is to make this kind of
work can work at the scale that we
operate we need all workloads to be run
as containers really without exception
and I'll get into account a little bit
more what that means a minute and why
that's so important for security
it obviously has huge benefits just for
deployment and workload management but
there's there's a security angle here
too and so if we step back for a minute
back in 2014 we published this idea in
this white paper called beyond Corp
which at the time really looked at the
changing environment for how people were
and where people were doing work for any
sort of an enterprise Google included
and on beyond Corp the key assertion for
beyond Corp is that the traditional
network model no longer applies the
perimeters not just the physical
location of where people are or where
the enterprise network is and just
because something's inside the perimeter
doesn't mean that it's blaster safe
place to be or to host computing devices
so really the idea would be on corporate
is let's move past the network and let's
think about not identity as where
somebody is or what network ports are
plugged into or what their IP address is
but think about who the end user is and
what's the security state and add a
station of the device that they're using
to access the network and so if you
think about taking that model and kind
of thinking about these problems and our
dressing them for production it's really
a very similar idea and if we just
simply replace the enterprise with the
data center replace personal computing
devices with you know workloads and
servers right this is kind of informing
kind of where we're getting this idea
for beyond prod so now let's get into
some of those details I mentioned
containers are really important to the
model you know the quick idea for a
containers
workload is deployed with all of its
dependencies packaged together all the
libraries and other things that's going
to include and the intent is that that
container workload itself is immutable
you don't hatch the container once it's
been deployed you build a new one and
you push that out in its replacement
another key important aspect of how
we've developed and structured services
at Google is the idea around micro
services this is taking a larger Sony
traditional or more monolithic
application and breaking it down into
smaller pieces and deploying and
managing those things independently but
building up trust and policy that
describes which micro services are make
up a larger identity and which ones are
allowed to talk to each other and which
ones aren't and so we found that when
you combine these two things together
because we can break things into smaller
pieces we can also patch and deploy much
more frequently much more easily and we
also can understand what we have and
what it depends on and when somebody's
using OpenSSL where that exists and so
the idea of kind of these things all
combined is often referred to as going
cloud native really what it is it's
informed by our history and developing
and running cloud services but I think
it's really applicable to any
environment whether you're deploying 100
containers or billion containers so we
think about the migration and sort of
what a traditional security
infrastructure looks like and kind of
what this cloud native infrastructure
model looks like along a couple
dimensions if we think about it along
the network dimension the traditional
model might look something like you've
got from it our base security it's about
firewalls it's about IP whitelists and
blacklists but communication once
somebody's passed that firewall might be
regarded as trusted called data model it
really is this idea of zero trust where
when we talk about zero trust we mean
that because you're present on the
network you're sending packets around
that that isn't good enough that isn't
actually anything that will confer you
any sort of trust and if we think about
identity and the idea of like service or
workload identity a traditional model
might tie identity to
where something's running right so oh
it's the database server and it has this
IP address or oh it's the you know CRM
application and it runs on these
machines that have these IP addresses or
these names in cloud native model
because we're containerize using
resources much more efficiently moving
things around
you can't tie any notion of identity or
policy back to the mission right it has
to come from somewhere else has to come
from some other inherent idea of
workload identity and not server
identity I think about kind of where
these security policy and security
requirements get baked in a traditional
model might say I mentioned before like
that the policy that the application is
required to enforce has to be compiled
in or built in included with the
application the cloud native model says
look we've got this shared
infrastructure and so we can have
requirements that live outside of your
workload your component that are
enforced by other things you have
dependencies on I'll walk through a more
detailed example of that in just a
minute what that looks like in practice
rollouts patching obviously is an
important element of security
traditional model might be because
you've got a larger monolithic
application made up of a lot of
components and a lot of dependencies
included in and because you me ramps
have fewer instances of that thing
running it can be a lot more difficult
to patch or patching happens less lit
often less often a cloud native model
because we've got these standardized
small things we are in essentially
continuously patching we also can do
sort of a blue-green deployment model
where you've patched some things and
check to make sure they still work right
before you actually do a wider rollout
rather than bring the whole application
down bring the new one up we're doing
this sort of constant update and patch
cycle a traditional infrastructure
security model might look at the unit of
isolation rights for separation as
strictly around the physical machine or
maybe the virtual machine cloud native
model because we are been packing and
we're using things more efficiently and
workloads are moving
and because we often will see workloads
from different services that end up
co-locating together in the same
physical machine and because we're
concerned about problems like where did
the code come from
what if it's compromised what if there's
a cpu side channel and we can't
necessarily guarantee or rely on
physical emissions operation we've
really had to invest in stronger
sandboxing isolation technology there's
something called Jeevitha that we've
developed that's been reasonably
effective against some categories of
side channels and generally as a
mechanism for sandboxing workloads as
something we found really helpful to
take us away from having to rely solely
on OS process isolation we were sort of
deem is not sufficient on its own and
give us several additional layers of
security between workloads so I'm going
to take those principles as properties
kind of walk through a life of a request
for user data as it goes through
production services at Google and talk
about some of the technology that we've
developed to impose or sort of implement
the different security principles behind
beyond prod at each step this is the
first time we've talked about some of
these things externally some of the
names may have been changed for the
white paper for the Googlers next
Googlers in the room but I think you all
understand some the concepts do as we go
along so if we start at the left step
one there's a request you end users
requesting data for something Gmail or
search or maps or whatever right and
that request comes in and hits a Google
front-end and the Google fronting is
responsible for TLS termination she's
much more TLS termination for all
services at Google different services
that Google don't run their own front
ends the front ends aren't part of the
services these exist as a layer as a
service layer and what that also means
is that when it comes time to do things
like change that certificate policy or
push that update for something like
heartbleed or change from open SSL to
boring SSL we have one place one place
that we need to do that and that all the
rest
of the applications and services and
backends downstream don't have to be
updated to get that security benefit so
the request is there but now the request
needs to be forwarded on to the specific
application that's responsible for
whatever the Senate request is going to
be to protect those communications
internally we re encrypt using something
that we're calling here
application layer transport security and
this allows us to do mutual
authentication and protect the contents
of the request and also to identify the
both source and destination of the
request with that being protected we can
send this now on to the appropriate
application fronting right the the part
of the application is actually going to
service this request one of the other
things that we've done in order to
essentially protect thee and reduce the
data access behind a request is a
requirement to take a live request and
generate an end user context ticket and
EUC ticket and this is something is
implemented by again a different service
this is a place where now we can enforce
separate security policy around user and
user access so when the application
front end then can request it over to
the end user authentication service and
prove that there is a live end user
request and get that validated it gets
back this EUC ticket and why that's
important is we only want these
application front ends to be able to
then go on and request data for users
who are actively using the service in
the moment at that time so now the
fronting at step four will now place the
request back into the service back-end
for the storage system that's
implementing whatever back-end for
storage that this service this fronting
decided to rely on again microservice is
an decoupling of things these are all
the same thing the application doesn't
have its own storage it uses other
storage services and so that requests in
addition to being protected with alts
will also be 40 along the end-user
credential ticket
to show that there's proof of live user
requests here and the storage service
now will in addition to validate and the
request is coming from an application of
front-end that it knows and is trusted
and it's been validated that it also is
passing an end-user credential for a
live user request for the valid for the
service and only when these policies are
checked and validated by that storage
back-end will it actually pull the data
and send the data back into the
front-end that's necessary for the
request so the beyond product model
though is not just about controlling
access to data it's also about
controlling access to the binaries that
then can access data so really what's a
year it's not just about infrastructure
it's also about a development process
and the artifacts of this process make
up something we call binary
authorization a a binary authorization
for board Borg being the job management
and scheduling system here and this is
another piece of the policy enforcement
of not how and what's applications can
talk to which other applications but who
and how a developer at Google can induce
a change or update a container or update
an application in production so to walk
through what that workload workflow
looks like starting here at step one
where we have a Google developer who
wants to submit a code change well the
first gate is code review there's a
requirement that at least one of the
developer and usually more based on you
know having somebody who is a specialist
in the language and somebody who owns
the codebase so one or more additional
people need to review and approve that
code change and once it's approved it
moves into a code repository that's you
know a central service that's run as a
distributed code system but it's not on
their workstation right they're not
going to be doing this build locally
they're going to be doing us build on a
system that is itself another secure
micro service set up and this secure
see I CDs so this build and deploy
pipeline will go through and build the
binary run validation tests and then
ultimately sign the result with this
binary Rother ization information about
how and where this was built and so the
resulting binary there's a resulting
container that comes along with it also
is bundled with this binary
authorization information such that when
we go to push this into production the
production services then that are going
to be accepting the update or the new
build or the new service will check and
enforce policy around where and how this
was built to ensure that it actually
came through that secure system that I
mentioned in step one and step two we
also further can isolate the workload
using G Weiser sandbox technology so
that the workload now if it happens to
be running some other workloads on the
same service are protected from each
other with additional layers of
protection none of your workload
necessarily runs with G visor it depends
a lot sometimes to on how and where the
source code is originated or on how much
exposure or how much data processing
risk it has so if it came from upstream
and we don't necessarily know where the
code came from or if it's doing a lot of
you know in peg encoding maybe that's
something that we're more likely don't
want to have to sandbox so overall those
are the steps and the pieces that make
up this beyond prod model you know miss
I mentioned it's about protection at the
network edge but beyond zero trust is a
really important element here it's about
knowing here trust between services it's
about having trusted machines but we're
running code with known provenance that
came from somewhere that we have some
identity information about it it's about
choke points places outside the work
load places where we can enforce
consistent policy and do that so across
all services that are running within
Google not one by one it's about simple
automated change
rollout patch management and it's about
isolation isolation between workloads
that are running side by side on the
same machine doing things beyond just OS
isolation and for us yet making this
change required substantial changes over
time across two major dimensions both
infrastructure and our development
process we approach these simultaneously
and incrementally but I think that the
model overall that's described and
beyond prod allows for opportunities for
taking pieces right doing things in
phases
doing things where you could start from
where you are with today pick one area
and build from there well I think the
full realization of the model and having
all these pieces come together is the
most powerful place to be I think each
one of the things and topics i've talked
about are on their own effective at
mitigating different categories of risk
so for us you know the benefits that
we've seen in sort of making this change
and and taking this philosophy and doing
this beyond prod model have been around
strengthening the security of our
workload deployments and communication
isolation about enforcing policy as
chokepoints about decoupling policy from
workloads you know this is really a lot
about with just the bottom line of this
is just making security something that's
done everywhere it's done upfront and
it's not something that our developers
have to be considering themselves with
day-in day-out let them focus on
building services what's the security
people focus on with the security
concerns as I mentioned we developed a
lot of systems and services and tools to
make this model or reality we've open
sourced many of these so I mentioned
about having application layer transport
security and mutual TLS I mentioned
about TLS termination and having that
reside outside of a workload you'll find
some of that in the Envoy open source
project you'll find the idea around
having policy for which
parts of a micro service are allowed to
talk to each other and which our pcs are
allowed which one should be blocked that
idea's cord is something called sto
having this idea of buying your
authorization having code provenance
where something was built from having
these checks as they go into production
is part of the kubernetes and mission
controller you'll see it showing up in
things like kritis OPA gatekeeper and we
do have binary authorization for
kubernetes as well and that isolation
piece that strong sandbox is something
that we've open-sourced a large portion
of something called G Weiser
there's only cured of that repet source
project um
this is a large undertaking there's a
lot of concepts there's a lot of
material here so we've been publishing
white papers about beyond prod about a
lot of the topics that are related to
beyond prog binary authorization alts
secure designed for infrastructure from
hardware and bootstrapping all the way
up we're also taking this opportunity
with something called anthos which is
really about taking us beyond prog model
both for workloads and for security a
lot of people to modernize both on-prem
and cloud and hybrid cloud and a lot of
these concepts and ideas were also
building into anthos to make it easier
for people to adopt this kind of cloud
native type architecture in their own
environments wherever they may be and
with that gonna wrap I'd like to think
enigma again for giving us an
opportunity to start to talk more about
what Google's security looks like from
the inside I hope you found that
informative and look 40 questions thank
you
[Applause]