okay it's sad welcome to Kota blue
welcome to Blue Book and welcome to my
talk I'm not a commentary I introduce my
marvelous to pirate Expo dreams
according to the box for Mary ownership
advanced let me introduce myself
I'm I work for national poison agency of
Japan I'm a manager of a small it's a
talent development team and I was a
Maria analyst and teacher French
Connery's in the past and I'm also happy
programmer interning programming on
weekends I being a rainbow previously
project since 2001 for 18 years and I
love the thought software
participant means it's a friction of
provides for mock references effects
editor it has 16 stable probably ravines
many problems all programs I developed
and it's useful for various kinds of
decoding in mario energy development
started in 2012 seven years ago it is
our private project and developed at
home so it's not a product of Japanese
government it is the important point and
it's ravines it's available at my kid
huh bleep you Tori
I'm directly explained background
attackers obfuscated but is data in
barrier to hamper ownership and fight
their Indian such as imitating
executable file decoy documents see the
host names file path and code it server
all itself and Mario analysts have to do
the open state attempt of other nurses
[Music]
and motivation of development at the
beginning in 2012 I was a warrior
analyst in in the government security
operation coordination team called T
sock at the time vulnerabilities of
Microsoft Office sometimes we are people
Albatros prayin and other media were
frequently used for malaria infection
I can such kind of vices document
sometimes it is quite cold did not work
in dynamic analysis did you target
bathroom it's much I had to find the
correct buzzer
make exploit old work but it is very
time-consuming task oh I wanted to
manual extraction obfuscated tomaría if
the Kilda profiles from Martius document
the points see the host names and
proclaim earlier but correct motivator a
big change in the dead
I just want more more MORE
papa free exceeded pretty important and
I'll try to explain fire inside well
what will not for we are with it funny
that is a free hex editor developed by
Murphy it was useful meeting functions
to take orders xat T disassembler
remarks structure we're and scripting it
also have unique feature that is
extendable with final problems but it
has being no update since 2009 about 10
years
I'm 43 it has been disappeared from the
McAfee return website oh my goodness
however historian of fine insight is
thin available at this location
I'm not a share of the future on 5 5
isn't now let's see the details of
appearances Perrine's
so there are many proteins these
proteins categorized into eight
operation categories such as basic
compression crypto encoding meat passing
Asajj Amex or visa added support over
algorithms and formats many many
algorithms and formats supported by my
proteins and all data added functions by
my province such as hospital calculation
fire type detection finding if it advice
starting with regular expressions
opening theater with the Castella tools
elitist customizable and find competence
caring with generals and war many
functions regarding East region by
region from means requires x86 version
of Python tool and it is not compatible
with executive x64 version of Python 2
and PI 2 3 but vitamin Python 3 can
co-exist read for other instruction
written in read meaning of very sad
proteins and it also requires some
Python modules and so on step 2 is
treasure it very simple please copy the
problem folder into final set of order
under the document folder
how do you use
please click per category from the
plugins tab immediate which will be
appeared take stricter provi you can
also use praveen's
from from the right-click menu
I've tried to mention finally fessed
ravines a good friend
cyber share any user profiles fellowship
yeah thank you
yes I have a shape it is super powerful
decoding it works
oh brother we brothers and inductively
developed by British government TCH here
are the many developers involved it is
very good that much processing of the
coding but not good that the modified 18
so fine in tightened by inside problem
here the authorities on cyber sharing
and thus able to probe in job can turn
up straight into theta to cyber shape
job title you get up to take it apart
I've installed the demo our beta yeah
it's Tim time I prepared five devil the
first demo is a versus Microsoft Excel
file my buried into the mobile give him
a minute and confiscated with XOR and
bit rotate under this from is exotic is
such fine to be unified and seemed to
Praveen to equal the merrier
yeah and it is a container excel file
now let's see that the end of file yeah
did it feel suspicious barrier and i-89
a try a try a try sometimes if
executable files is encoded with XOR
it's g8o files it's filled with extra
key so it seems to be our X okey now
let's use the brute-force attack to take
over dinner repeat such operations
exotic search and I enter that vicious
dream physique to indicate applying G's
each program
yeah without admission yeah
theta ik sake under our feet to rotate
and such kids eat a biscuit this program
cannot be run in DOS mode it was basic
to be a photographer so not now let the
because of with is key funny that has be
doing feature X for about another X 48
line because then bit rotate with
by weeks and such it God
look marked here now you can see the PE
header you can see the string this
program cannot be run in DOS mode then
my extract is probably the executable
file with punching operations find
people to be executable file found at
this top teeth of same content over the
original files bookmarks so you can
select eject the fire I use I strike two
other aspiring either so are you to beat
corporations tend to think I'd agree
I can derive this clarify with either
the past past devil
the second demo
secondary there are rich merchants of
mystics fire
[Music]
miss Maria its Maria executable file is
emitted and obfuscated with X or Y
incrementing X Hakeem is called rolling
X or they call this sample I use the
propane for the guest 2010 256-byte EXO
keys I use this Praveen because if you
use drawing XOR sometimes a cyclic 202
sick stick 56 bite patterns are you
disturbing
[Music]
yeah this is the content of all the rich
text file here
there are even suspicious fiery data
attached in heck view the content
derived right did now let's see the day
the end of the fire
you can see the white butter
[Music]
you can see the bottom there are 1 2 3 4
5 6 7 like this so X of G value is
incremented
now let's start a indicative of our I
use X operations gets to 256 by ticks
Aki's yeah the candidate of extra keys
has been shown and wincenty to the
unifier found out this offset and a
little compartment hater found us this
off-trail saved for the morning
Geoffrey's just copy like XO key then
select all the content then paste the
code XO key then the goal
yeah you can see the B hitter so you can
extract this Mario 5 it is the second
demo
okay saturdaya start level either PHP
will share the code really obfuscated
with base 64 L'Occitane defrayed and so
on and these protein project ravines we
use low 30s order custom based 64 the
board growing plain and simple
[Music]
yeah it is the content of the PHP code
the code is obfuscated with the PHP
functions like this now I'm going to
because this for this code wipe one by
one now and select the encoded string
execute not something rubbings and
coding operations not studying the Greek
okay decode it then
give us the order based on this function
basic operations be bisoder
and base64 big conflict encoding
operations custom page 64 the code if
you don't modify each table it works a
normal basic base 64 taken now they call
it then each data too compressed to
accomplish I'm going to compress this
data with compressed operations low in
fridge yeah you can see another take it
encoded data
and I opened this data in Newton basic
operations open a new file and it is
encoded in base64 then seeded inference
now I copy the data selected the data
encoding operations at a basic three
ball decode and this is the compressed
data then compressed operations no wait
yes it is decoded PHP code now it's
aligned with this bitch pre-code with
external tools takes the data bits
corporations tend to be as tall so you
can see it PHP code with be just as you
call so you can do further analysis or
is PHP for ya that's our table
yeah next for stable the embassy Mar
where it is used by a psychotic group
evidene 28 also known as fancy beer it
uses some tickets of dreams
they are encoded as a ecstasy I extract
and take out in extremes under based on
these extremes I scan with general based
on its train so in this demo I use
strain scrubbing and the a scam Praveen
yeah it is not content all of the
verified I use the propane passing
operations strength strength shows with
this sitting dialogue dog I increase the
minimum language duty I select the post
process to remove duplicates unable this
checkbox they called hex encoded
extremes they click OK so these are
extracted piece of string and decoded
string will be shown like this decoded
and original so I will search I'm going
to search the cottage string yeah
these are decoded extremes a visa some
entities swing dot top cakes question ID
name enter password to open file
Microsoft Word
these specific strings and can be used
to create
yaarun now
I already prepared the general based on
these strings this is Yahoo watching
this picks X ticket then
let's scan with this Yahoo
such operations Ellis can then dialogue
shall be shown so you you should direct
fire to be scanned the general fire for
effect
de Rossi totally take Rick okay yeah
scanning without admission it's so hot
strings have been matched in in under
Angela offset the match
much the strings will be highlighted as
a bookmark so you can see photo stream
you have been matched with your general
so file inside can use the are you
testing to and general editor it is very
useful a digital force demo
the last day this demo it did not Mario
file but it is a binary file that
contains the hidden method it is a it is
like a very easy City shift like
challenge I'm going to solve the
combination with cyber safe and I am
going to use this Praveen file type XV
decompress something to
yeah and it is magnified
I used passing operations file type
yeah file type is actually compressed
data now I use compressed operations
Exley's able to compress the file has
been they compressed and I use file type
driving again it is pink image data it's
this image tend to mspaint yeah it is
- Nicole now let you the cyber safe to
take all disk your goal miss cooperation
send to cyber chef automatically the
reporter brother have been executed and
the data will be imported
it is a very important data select the
recipe data image
they also have to be shown then passed
to alcohol yeah
it is the secret message thank you for
eating my toad
I'm ready to enjoy convert 2009 learn
about wine it has proteins make fire
effects in hex editor more perform like
animal suits and it is very useful for
various kind of decoding task a task in
mario energy it is available after this
by github repository please download and
try it and I am waiting for your
feedbacks
pluralist bug report and feature
requests thank you so much it's a
straddle take will be available at my
github repository
I will upload on this ride immediate
immediate immediately after this talk
thank you very much