good morning and thank you very much for
the opportunity to be here today it's
it's a great honor I'm delighted to be
able to come and visit Japan I've never
been to Japan or Tokyo before and as
soon as my body is caught up with the
jetlag I intend to explore this
wonderful city and country as well I
will try and speak as slowly as I can
I'm afraid my Japanese isn't very good
it's in fact almost non-existent but I
will do my best to help the translators
today I've come here today to talk about
a book which I published about 18 months
ago which you can see on the slides
there called hacking the bomb and this
was my attempt to wrestle with what I
thought or I believed to be an
absolutely central problem in our world
the intersection of the ultimate weapon
and I don't need to tell people in in
this room and from this country of the
significance of nuclear weapons with the
whole suite of new and emerging
technologies under this label of cyber
and this struck me is one a fascinating
academic project but also hopefully
something that had considerable
implications for how we maintain and
secure a peaceful and stable world so
what I intend to do with the time
allocated to me today is to give you 11
takeaways from the book I really had
hoped this would be 10 because it sounds
better but it is 11 I couldn't squeeze
them together and hopefully this will
give you an idea of how I've tried to
map out this challenge and thought about
it I should also confess at the start
that I'm not a techie I'm a political
scientist or perhaps more correctly an
international relations scholar so
please forgive me for that to start with
but I'm also us I think it's fantastic
that in a forum such as this we can
combine people from different
backgrounds and I think many of the
issues that we look at today require
that cross discipline and people from
different backgrounds and to address
them so when I study looking at this
cyber nuclear challenge five or six
years ago and I was very lucky to have
some funding from the UK government to
do this a lot of questions seem to
abound
so could hackers break into nuclear
systems cause a launch or prevent these
systems from working
could they be spoofed electronically or
could operators and decision-makers be
tricked into making wrong and
potentially fatal decisions could
nuclear secrets be vulnerable to cyber
spies and perhaps even would-be
proliferators and in what ways might
certain attackers do this what exactly
does the threat look like and what is
vulnerable to in what ways and to whom
how much of the hype should we believe
how series should we be about this
challenge and of course finally what are
the best ways to manage their mitigate
some of the worst possible scenarios
that we could foresee and interestingly
it seemed to me that some 35 years after
this film that you can see on my slide
was came out in Hollywood wargames
starring a very young Matthew Broderick
and back in 1983 it seemed that perhaps
we had reached an era where hackers
perhaps not necessarily a teenager in
their bedroom in Seattle but hackers
could get into nuclear weapons and we
had to take this challenge seriously so
it seemed that as is often the case what
was happening in sci-fi generation ago
had almost become reality
today the first thing that really struck
me about as a political scientist
looking at this question was that the
word cyber is fundamentally contested it
is nebulous it is used by different
people organizations and countries to
mean very very different things this
often means that analysts or even policy
makers talk past each other when we use
this word for some cyber is actions and
I'm guessing this is a lot of people in
this room purely through the internet or
through networks for others it's bound
up with this comp for this concept of
information warfare for others still
it's something about the whole broader
age or period or epoch that we are
living in and this of course makes
understanding the challenge at its most
basic level let alone responding really
difficult also I think has and continues
to lead to hype and worst case scenario
thinking a good example of this and I
apologize for for picking on Donald
Trump it seems to be a a regular theme
of people these days but it's a good
example in 2016 in the presidential
election
debates with Hillary Clinton then
candidate Donald Trump kept referring to
doing this cyber better we have to we
have to do many things better cyber is
one of them and I think as I say Donald
Trump is by no means the only person to
do this but gives a good example of how
this word is being used in an
essentially meaningless way whether this
refers to cyber attack capabilities
Network defense information security or
something completely different really
isn't very clear and this is comes
across a lot in the debate from a
political science perspective so the way
that I tried to address this issue is
thinking of cyber or computer network
operations as two different things so
first of all comprising a particular set
of tools or capabilities or operations
many of which are new and as well as a
broader context within which these
operations capabilities and tools are
being used or are carried out so the
question then becomes not so much which
cyber technologies or what the cyber
technologies can do but rather how the
context alters the way that we
understand and interact with the world
and in this case how we think about and
understand nuclear weapons and the
politics that surround them and I think
because of this it often makes sense to
work backwards from a problem as a
scholar particularly as I say in the
social scientists rather than going in
straight away with a framework and this
actually was one of the things perhaps
not the most exciting bit of the
research that I did that was probably
the most fundamental to get my head
around this definition and conceptual
problem there is even a case although I
found this increasingly difficult when
cyber is in the title of a lot of my
presentations to get rid of the word
altogether and go back to some of that
language that many in this room will be
familiar with from the 1990s information
security information warfare network
security computer security etc etc often
much more precise and how it's being
used second key thing to point out from
the work cyber however we define it and
nuclear are different it's been quite
common I think over the past decade or
so to compare the two to try and
superimpose lessons or frameworks from
the nuclear arm and nuclear era on to
cyber that somehow this is the latest
technology that can summative
supplanted and therefore many of the
rules will remain the same but I think
this analogy while the questions that we
ask may be correct
the answers are often very different and
therefore the analogy is quite often
flawed again the major difference here
is clear the amount of damage you canyou
can cause and again I don't need to tell
people in this room how much damage
nuclear weapons can do but modern
nuclear weapons even a small nuclear
exchange would have vast with a
considerable and significant
consequences probably for everybody on
the planet in reality where we are now
and there may be others in this room
better in a better position to comment
than I but so far as I'm aware no one
has died of a cyber attack and the
impact would likely to be much more
temporary and perhaps and almost
certainly not as devastating so we're
often better thinking or a good way of
thinking about this is a difference
between weapons of mass destruction as
in nuclear and weapons of mass
disruption something that is far more
temporary often much more specialized
secret and often happening at the lower
end of the threat spectrum targets are
often likely to be different
sophisticated cyber attacks often have
to be very specialized whereas nuclear
weapons are broadly seen as being
largely indiscriminate transparency is
clearly important here nuclear weapons
are displayed you can count them they
are quantifiable you use them for
signaling and posturing in a whole host
of other things is much more difficult
in the cyber realm to demonstrate
capability or to show off what you have
moreover if you do show off what you
have those weapons or capabilities may
lose any value that they had to begin
with the other key point with this is
that the vast majority of what we think
of as cyber threats or cyber operations
actually happen right at the bottom end
of this spectrum and really have nothing
to do with nuclear weapons at all but
there is a tendency I think to conflate
these two and that often leads to hype
and bad policy third point cyber threats
are very diverse
there is no single cyber threat despite
the fact that the way the word is used
often seems to imply that might be the
case and we're far better thinking of a
cyber threats spectrum something that
ranges as you can see on the bottom of
the slide there over quite a wide range
of different activities at the bottom we
have general hacking nuisance cry
espionage denial-of-service and then
just at the top in a very small
component of this would be physical
attacks all those attacks or operations
seeking to cause damage or destruction
as far as I'm concerned warfare is quite
a problematic concept in term in the
cyber realm and will refer back to that
later and I don't think we've had and I
don't think we're likely to have cyber
warfare in the way that we've thought
about it in the past but a lot of these
different threats are often lumped
together and so when we're talking about
a certain type of threat it can often be
misinterpreted or seen through a
different lens and again this leads to
hype misunderstanding and perhaps
complicates responses such as in terms
of whether deterrence can work in this
realm which will come on to you a bit
later we can think of attackers in the
nuclear arm specifically it's trying to
do two things and this goes back to a
classic strategic studies way of looking
at problems as looking between
intentions and capabilities so various
actors in the Nick terrarium met may
seek to enable something so that is
causal launched exacerbate a crisis
cause problems that lead to need for use
in some way they may do this indirectly
or directly and I think it's most likely
that this is what this is something that
a non-state actor would seek to do I
can't see many reasons why a state actor
would want to exacerbate a crisis at
least it doesn't immediately come to
mind a state actor is probably much more
likely to seek to disable a system to
stop it from working whether it be an
air defense radar whether it be a
particular weapon system at command and
control node or something else States
again I think a more capable of
attacking systems directly they have the
time resources capability to do this
whereas non-state actors or cyber
terrorists leave if there really is such
a thing out there and more likely I
think to seek indirect measures of doing
this manipulating the information space
and finding other way other ways in I
think one of the reasons for this is
quite simply that for a terrorist group
there are often much easier ways of
causing they're causing damage or
achieving their objectives it's thinking
about cyber tools and capabilities as
just one part of a toolkit not
necessarily the only one that will
always be used
so there's a common perception I think
across the broader cyber community both
social science and hard sciences the air
gapping or network separation is it is a
way of defending things if you don't
connect if you don't connect systems to
the Internet if they are not linked into
broader unsecured networks than they are
if not invulnerable and then certainly
safe but I think this is slightly
misguided and in the nuclear-armed
wicked weekly I think there's a very
good example of how this might work
another good example of course is that
Stuxnet which was discovered in into in
2010 entered an air-gap system in the
tans in Iran but another good example of
the problem of the idea of air gapping
or network gapping or separation at the
UK Trident submarines these are the
submarines the UK uses to house its
nuclear deterrent the Trident missile
inside the Vanguard submarine which
comprises the whole nuclear deterrent
for the UK so when I was doing research
for this book officials in the UK
Ministry of Defence and across
government constantly told me that this
system was absolutely fine it was
invulnerable hackers could not break
into these submarines they could not do
anything to the UK deterrent because of
course the submarines are on patrol
summer in the North Atlantic sitting in
a deep trench silent and no one knows
where they are well that's certainly
true but it forgets the fact that
somebody has to write the coding for
each part of that submarine all the
different systems on it whether it be
for the natural maintenance of the
submarine and its lifespan clean water
supplies somebody writes coding for the
missiles in this case that's somebody in
the United States probably at Lockheed
Martin not in the UK and of course the
warhead also relies on coding as well
these submarines go in to base to be
patched the operating system is upgraded
it is often plugged in potentially to
unsecured networks and it gives access
to many people while it's in port they
also receive a very small amount of
communications via via radio waves while
there while they're at sea and this is
potentially another way that you could
compromise submarines to the other
aspects of this of course is that you
don't necessarily in the UK case need
- cause the warhead aboard to explode to
achieve your aims it may simply be doing
something to the submarine that makes it
have to come back into port in the UK
case there are four identical submarines
if one fault or problem is caused on
that submarine it will raise questions
across the entire force of submarines
the UK will deploy and this would be a
massive problem for the United Kingdom
given that it relies on a policy of
continuous Patsy deterrence whereby one
of these submarines is always on patrol
again it's not it's not the easiest
thing to do to hack into these
submarines but I think getting away from
this idea that they are invulnerable is
really really important more broadly and
I've seen this from research they've
done in other parts of the world
including in Asia there's an increased
dependency across all parts of the
military establishment on commercial
off-the-shelf technology quite often
simply for reasons of economics and a
lot of software that is not built
in-house or is further and further away
from the actual user and more research
even suggests and I won't say which
country it is but that at least two
countries where I've spoken to people
rely on software and components not
built in that country for their nuclear
weapon systems and I think that's quite
an interesting and quite worrying
development so going back to the cyber
definitional challenge if we take it as
being a contextual thing and about this
latest information age and about the
system's upon which we rely then we also
have to accept that some cyber
challenges in the nuclear-armed and more
broadly are inherent so it's not
necessarily that a hacker will break
into a particular weapons system but
that those weapon systems and the
systems we rely upon more broadly are
vulnerable simply because they contain
bugs various software errors and a whole
host of other things and this means that
in the nuclear arm the more complex
things get the more we rely on
complicated codes systems that interact
in ways that we sometimes can't foresee
that things could go wrong this is an
idea borrowed from sociology from
Charles Perrault called normal accidents
and we can perhaps expand this to think
about normal nuclear accidents theory
that is that in a cybereye x'd or
highly complex more digitized realm
things just may go wrong
without hackers being involved at all
and part of the reason part of the
problem here is that for many countries
there is a tension between keeping
nuclear weapons ready to go the
credibility of being able to use them so
that you can deter you can show your
adversary you are willing and able to
use nuclear weapons but at the same time
making sure that they are safe secure
and can never go off by accident
unfortunately for many states it's
towards the always side of this dilemma
they're always there being able to use
them and this I think exacerbates some
of the problems I've discussed another
way of looking at this and this came up
in the executive meeting yesterday that
I attended is 40 years ago we have
evidence of a number of problems that
happened at NORAD the North American
Aerospace Defense Command which monitors
potential incoming missile threats the
United States a whole host of problems
with their computers whereby a training
tape was loaded into the system a
circuit chip caught fire and this caused
all sorts of false alarms and problems
of the possibility of a massive Soviet
incoming attack now these were old
computers they were the big sort of like
cabinet computers it was the 8-inch
floppy disk it was this area it was old
stuff and actually that was a blessing
in disguise because that meant many
people could figure out what happened
what had gone wrong and diagnose the
problem quite quickly the worry today is
that we've moved from that those big
computers that where we can see the
physical components and what's gone
wrong to something that is far smaller
and is often far less easy to diagnose
and understand the problems that have
occurred and this I think I think that
the lessons from the 1980s are to be
careful how we go about this today I've
put up there Eric Schlosser's book
command and control which is about a
nuclear accident in the 1980 so I won't
give away the plot but it but it is an
excellent book if some of you haven't
read it so far the other aspect of this
of course is the more tightly you keep
nuclear systems coupled with warning
sensors so launch on alert launching
soon and quickly to ensure that they're
not you're not destroyed in a
pre-emptive attack exacerbates this
problem even more if you've got systems
that may interact in complex ways and
that you don't understand problems and
accidents
happen and in the nuclear rome of course
the nuclear weapons realm the
implications of this are enormous the
cause of this I think this is an
interesting one for many people in this
room who may be involved in developing
systems for companies and perhaps even
militaries it's worth thinking about
whether modernization and complexity and
further digitization of the systems used
for nuclear weapons and the sort of
broader nuclear enterprise should be
modernized and should become more
complex or whether we're better keeping
them simple such as those that were used
in the 1980s the other thing that struck
me with the whole cyber challenge is
that it's a fundamentally human thing
while we often focus on high
technologies hacking sophisticated
methods of gaining access to
informational systems much of this can
actually be traced back to us as humans
many humans or humans design and build
computer systems they write the coding
create the software enter data operate
the machines and make decisions based on
the information that they provide this
is as true for me sitting here with this
computer as it is for somebody who works
in a nuclear command and control center
humans are knowingly give away personal
information click on infected emails
download malware insert infected drives
into systems and are therefore often a
key way of bridging the air gap of
getting across sophisticated defenses
and even that separation between systems
as well humans are clearly a very
obvious target for would-be attacks it's
much easier to dupe a human or perhaps
even find a way of social engineering
than it is to get past or utilized
zero-day exploits or other ways of
getting in this whole idea of cyber
social engineering it is a really
interesting one I remember giving a
similar talk to this several years ago
in Canberra in Australia and as I was
doing it somebody in the audience said
they'd looked up nuclear nuclear missile
is on Facebook and found a group and it
was a group of US Minuteman missile is
the people in charge of the u.s. nuclear
weapons in in the Midwest had a Facebook
group to tell people what was going on
so I think it's just an example of how
information can be shared and
information can sometimes very easily be
given
this of course could be used by a
would-be attacker or somebody seeking to
compromise and those systems we are of
course potentially getting into an era
where computers might be able to begin
to think and with integration of
artificial intelligence we might see if
we see more and more automation in the
nuclear realm but ultimately at the
moment computers do what we tell them to
do so it may not be as sexy as Stuxnet
or causing a missile to launch or or
whatever else but the biggest challenge
in the cyber nuclear realm is is
espionage now this is not new any anyone
that seen a James Bond film will know
that nuclear espionage has been
something that in the plotlines of
Hollywood for years and even before 1945
as well but this challenge is clearly
changing in the digital era in the cyber
era in different ways so we have to
think about the security of both
operational secrets so how things will
be done the policies the doctrine the
things that you want to keep secret but
also the design of things as well it may
potentially be becoming easier to steal
blueprints and various intellectual
property of weapons to share this
quicker no longer do you have to sneak
in a camera or take out large amounts of
documents or copy by hand this can now
be done in different ways and indeed I
remember going to the United Kingdom
atomic weapons establishment many years
ago and to give a talk going in with a
USB Drive and they said there's
absolutely no way you can bring that in
you can't do this quite simply because
it would be so easy in theory to
download information onto that drive and
take it away the challenge is kind of
bifurcated between both hacking into
these systems and the information
security more broadly and again this
idea of an air gap or Network gap or
separation is not a panacea purely
because of the human aspect that comes
in to this whole idea of cyber nuclear
espionage is not new and go back to the
1980s and the Cuckoo's egg where a guy
called Clifford Stoll traced a an East
German hacker through the computers of
various laboratories in California and
across the United States but it's
expanded pretty exponentially since even
to the point where we're worried
or there is a concern about sort of
digital illicit nuclear trading within
this realm as well some people may be
familiar or be aware of the Pakistani
scientist AQ Khan who established a
nuclear smuggling network in the 1980s
and 1990s the worry here is that a cyber
AQ Khan will be far worse and far more
far more worrying this idea of
proliferation is merely only one of the
implications are of cyber nuclear
espionage and the importance of
protecting nuclear secrets and it could
be a precursor to sabotage I'll explain
about the Syrian nuclear program in a
minute Operation Olympic Games was
clearly falls onto this the the broader
program that led to Stuxnet but it but
again it can be it can be different
there are different implications for for
what you might do but that protection of
sensitive information whether it be
operational or design has become more
and more important I think in this
particular age so one of the major ID or
one of the big sort of ideas within
within the cyber nuclear challenges well
we can't deter it cyber accompli can't
deter hackers because we don't know who
they are we can't attribute etc etc
therefore ideas of deterrence that we
had in the past whether it be through
air power in the 1920s and 30s or
nuclear weapons in the 40s and 50s can't
work well I don't think that's quite
right I think deterrence can potentially
play a role in this before this
challenge but with the proviso that an
enormous amount of the response will not
be deterrence by denial it will be
things happening much more basic so
linked in with the idea that humans are
one of the key aspects of this challenge
is the fact that many attacks many
security breaches and many other things
probably could have been prevented or at
least mitigated through better cyber
hygiene and better practice training
enhanced defence and security and where
necessary law enforcement as well and so
again it's thinking about where the
problem is and the particular aspects to
it however if we look at this from a
strategic perspective it is at least
possible that some cyber operations
could be considered as acts of war maybe
not now but certainly in the future or
military operations and that deterrence
by punishment
could have a role to play but I think
the thing to remember here is that cyber
deterrence only may only apply in
certain circumstances and it's not
either/or or something that can be
graduated in 20 2013 the u.s. defense
Science Board published this very
influential report January 2013 the
influential report resilient military
systems and this talked a bit about the
nature of the cyber threat and also how
it could be deterred and it quite
explicitly linked a nuclear response to
a cyber attack so the idea that not just
a conventional but even a nuclear
response could be possible or or indeed
credible in this realm is not far away
from the policy debate and we saw that
kind of reflected again although not
explicitly in the Trump administration's
Nuclear Posture review last year I think
it's worth saying a quick thing about
attribution in this room again many
people will know more about attribution
and probably are involved in it at the
moment but it seems to me again this is
not a either/or but something that
depends on a number of different
variables notably the amount of time you
have the forensic capability you have
and perhaps also the political context
within which any attack takes place
although that has to be treated with
some caution deterrence can become
complicated when considering a
proportional response in this realm so
it's not necessarily that you would
respond in kind one particular cyber
attack being met by another type of
cyber attack they're probably much
better off thinking about the impact of
these attacks rather than the method
through which they were carried out
there's also some problematic idea of
probably some problems here about if you
were to try and respond whether you have
to have already breached certain systems
and therefore have essentially preempted
any attack that you may face
so this broadly sort of comes back to
the idea that threatening nuclear
retaliation to a cyberattack might seem
pretty overblown it is there in policy
documents but it's something that isn't
going to go away none of the
nuclear-armed state certainly the US
Russia China or the UK has explicitly
ruled out responding to a major cyber
attack or as we'll see in a minute
attack involving cyber with nuclear
weapons and ultimately any country that
is attacked in this way or the
or the attacker has to run the risk and
those nuclear capabilities may come into
play but the whole point about
deterrence here I think is that it's not
just one type it's deterrence by denial
those things at the top and it's
possibly deterrence by punishment in
certain circumstances so I think well I
wouldn't want to be too sanguine about
this most cyber operations or attacks or
hacking it's probably manner in the
nuclear arm it's probably fairly
manageable during times of peace
notwithstanding those points I mentioned
about weapons that can be used very
quickly but are probably a lot more
risky and worrying during any sort of
crisis because of time pressures
perceive vulnerabilities and certainties
and a whole host of other things as well
and this could happen in a couple of
different ways so state actors I think
would seek to disable an opponent's key
systems before military operations can
begin seeking to prepare the battlefield
this is fairly explicit in both US and
Chinese policy for any hostilities in
this particular region this leads to
greater uncertainty pressures for
pre-emptive attack they'll preemptive
strikes and this fears of
use-it-or-lose-it if you don't order
firing you may not be able to because it
could be compromised because of the
uncertainty there's also the problem
that terrorists or other non-state
actors or third parties might seek to
interfere in various ways spoofing
systems conducting false flag attacks
flooding the battlefield with
misinformation intending to cause the
crisis to escalate and the two quite
good examples of this so at the top
there this is a picture of a tweet after
the Israeli Defense Forces Twitter
account was hacked and this was back in
July 2014 the hackers here simply posted
possible nuclear leak in the region
after two rockets hit Dimona nuclear
facility now it's fairly easy for
Israeli policymakers and military
officials to see that this was a hoax
that they had been hacked and could be
fairly quickly rectified but imagine if
this had happened in the middle of a
crisis or a middle of a beginning of
warfare or something else when time
pressures are there when communications
are down it's more difficult to gain
full situational awareness something as
simple as it as hacking into Twitter and
or even stealing a password can be very
influential and the second example and I
mentioned it slightly
that in 2007 it's believed that Israel
managed to hack into Syrian air defense
systems to essentially turn off the
sensors and fly over and bomb a
suspected nuclear facility
al Cuba you could liken this to in
Hollywood films where burglars
enter a building and find some way of
making the cameras go blank so they can
can walk straight through it's
essentially an same concept we don't
know exactly how the Israelis got into
this system but it's likely that it was
hacked in in some way before and it
gives you an idea here of how you may
compromise early warning and again sort
of if we expand upon that how that may
work in a crisis and again just to
reiterate the reliance of modern
militaries on increasingly complex and
computerized communications not least
between space and and command nodes on
the ground is creating I think more
problems and more dangers and more
potential things to go wrong it suggests
to me not least in this region but also
in other parts of the world that what we
think we know about nuclear crises and
escalation signaling may need to be
reassessed in light of this new context
and some of the new problems and that we
may face point 10 viewing cyber in this
nuclear world I think is quite unhelpful
I don't think we are at we will ever see
a pure cyber war whereas if you'll
forgive the terminology James Lewis says
a geek versus geek on a digital
battlefield and I think this temptation
to view or cyber threats or cyber in
isolation as a separate domain it is
quite problematic it may make sense for
administrative purposes and in reality
becomes much more blurred well clearly
cyber operations may be used on their
own for low-level low-level gains or
low-level policy or or even by non-state
actors it seems more likely to me that
they'll be used in conjunction with
other forms of military force in warfare
why would you simply use a cyber
capability when you could use that
alongside your kinetic capabilities it's
thinking about this again as just one
tool in a toolbox rather than the only
tool just because it's new
but it also means again that we need to
rethink how these how the integration
between these different forces are if it
is that cyber will be used to go after
communication links early warning
command and control assets then we need
to think about how that is going to
impact future warfare as well at the
strategic nuclear level I think we need
to think more broadly as well and
perhaps see this cyber challenge as one
component of a new suite of advanced
non-nuclear or strategic weaponry a new
suite of capabilities that are different
I think from traditional military force
tanks aircraft and getting closer and
closer to nuclear weapons both in terms
of capability destruction but
particularly in terms of the roles and
they can carry out and what we've
essentially seen is a percolation of the
technologies of the revolution in
military affairs from the 1990s have now
come up to this strategic nuclear level
so we see ever and then again something
that's that it shouldn't be lost on
people in this country increasingly
capable and increasing reliance on
ballistic missile defenses as a means of
protection various precision strike
weapons whether it be anti space under
the sea or against against targets on
land a greater incorporation of
artificial intelligence which is helping
with sensing monitoring and targeting
and a whole host of other things and
other exotic capabilities that we can
think of so if we put cyber into this
broader group we can begin to see a
whole suite of technologies that
challenge the way that we think about
nuclear weapons again it's not thinking
of cyber as one thing alone but it's
part perhaps of a broader suite of
things that are changing the way we do
warfare and in this case nuclear
strategy as well final point the what I
think we are beginning to see and I
think is increasingly worrying and this
is perhaps only after over the last
decade it's an emerging norm of using
cyber computer network operations to
target nuclear and missile forces this
is primarily happening it's something
primarily being done by the United
States but I think we'll also begin to
spread to others as well so the obvious
example of this is Stuxnet back in 2010
but it also seems fairly likely that I
think it was about two years ago
an example of this that the United
States is also perhaps with allies
alongside is also utilizing this
approach against other targets - namely
North Korea a couple of years ago there
were lots of reports of a failed North
Korean missile test and this very
quickly things in the New York Times
were very quickly linked to whoa hang on
has it been hacked has is this a
deliberate sabotage by the United States
and its allies the truth is we don't
know missiles go wrong they are
complicated to build you have to test
them but it plants the idea that this
may be happening and it's almost
certainly something I believe that
certain states are trying to do this is
actually starting to come out in US
policy documents and this was general
james Cartwright former former US
government official said this I think
this was five or six years ago and what
we're beginning to see is cyber attack
capabilities becoming part of both a
full spectrum missile defense mission
and also the Global Strike mission as
well the Global Strike mission was the
ability to hit anywhere in the world
inside an hour with conventionally armed
missiles well this is now not just with
inside an hour but also inside 300
milliseconds that cyber is part of it
but it's also part of the idea of of
left of launch so kinetic missile
defenses such as that are deployed in
this country and in this region would be
right of launch that you're utilized
after a missile has been fired or after
a threat materializes left of launch is
the idea that you stop that threat
materializing before through new ways
such as cyber so this is becoming
gradually more explicit in US policy
documents that there is a move towards
pre-emptive use of cyber and other
capabilities against nuclear and missile
systems why is this a problem because it
creates a precedent there's a real
considerable worry in both Russia and
China about what this might mean in
terms of their own forces it's much
harder to see these capabilities of
course they aren't tangible in the way
that a kinetic missile defense system is
and this creates uncertainty it also
creates a norm and the possibility that
other states will follow suit something
that I believe would make us all rather
less secure rather than more and there's
an idea going around that all of these
technologies but particularly the idea
of using cyber print
against an adversary systems is moving
us away from mutually assured
destruction to mutually unassured
destruction may not be there yet but we
certainly may be going towards it so
conclusion recommendations I think the
place to start here is with the quote on
the right hand side and this is from
eminent scientist Carl Sagan and I think
this really captures and probably where
we are today perhaps not so much in this
room but certainly within society that
it and he said it's suicidal to create a
society dependent on science and
technology and which hardly anybody
knows anything about the science and
technology I think that's increasingly
true a generation ago people could
understand most of the things they
engage with whether it's your car or
whether it's various other aspects of
your life today as sociologists or even
Marxist would say we're getting further
and further away from technology and
understanding it and that relationship
is very important not least I would
argue in this nuclear realm go back to
that analogy of NORAD in the 1980s and
the big computers and the 8-inch floppy
disks and where we are today with much
more networked complex and systems but a
few ideas of where we go in the future
so probably the most important thing
from a political scientist perspective
it's some sort of agreement on the
language that we use the semantics of
cyber and the nature of the threat of
being clear what we mean when we're
talking about these issues we also need
to be clear again and I'm sure I'm
preaching to the converted to many in
this room that a considerable amount of
cyber threats or cyber challenges could
be ameliorated through better cyber
hygiene and good practice this would
probably prevent many things happening
in the first place and maybe dissuade
attackers from even getting involved but
this reckless has to recognize the
central role played by humans I believe
there's a strong need for different
communities to speak to each other on
this issue which is why I'm one of the
reasons I'm delighted to be here today
to speak to people from a slightly
different background to my own these
problems that we're facing whether it
being cyber threats to particular
companies or looking at it in a more
conceptual lens or three or more
conceptual lens like I am requires
people with different viewpoints
different
skill sets and different understandings
of the problem that's the only way that
we get roundness and I think it may mean
we need different views different people
and different groups of people to
address this I think it's probably a
good idea to train and deploy
specialists computer of security
specialists cyber specialists at nuclear
facilities and conduct regular outside
red teaming I know that's I think that's
something there's actually probably
going on on here in terms of red teaming
this is something the military does a
bit I don't know how much it happens in
the nuclear realm but it strikes me as
being a very obvious and good thing to
do there's ideas about establishing
early warning centers and and and links
between countries so we can share threat
data particularly if we believe that the
greatest threat is non-state actors and
the exacerbation of a crisis or causing
a launch
well let's share data let's share
insights that share best practice
between ourselves the idea that we could
establish certain norms or moratorium I
said in the previous slide we have the
establishment of this idea of hacking
the bomb of using cyber capabilities
preemptively well if we all believe this
is a bad thing then we should get
together and make sure it doesn't happen
can we find something to agree on that
would benefit all of us that would make
us all more safe and it may be that in
this there is a role for non-nuclear
States and allies as well such as such
as Japan in pushing this agenda in
trying to frame it and making the
nuclear-armed States look at this in a
different way and finally I think we
need to think about whether these
emerging technologies and cyber
including as part of this need to be
looked at in a different way this may
mean including it in current
international agreements and
international frameworks but perhaps
more likely it means building new
frameworks much in the way the
scientists and scholars in the 1940s and
50s thought about the nuclear revolution
and how we manage nuclear weapons
perhaps we need this again to bring
together an epistemic community of some
social scientists but computer
scientists and everybody else to think
about what the rules of the road and
what arms control and other measures
might look like in this new world and
finally and this is a bit of a bit of a
sound buy unfortunately but I think it
does capture things quite well in this
new world in this new environment as we
go further into a more complex cyber
nuclear future we should really think
about keeping nuclear weapons as simple
as possible not making them complex for
the sake of it
keeping them separate from other other
systems other military capabilities
including perhaps warning systems as
well and as secure as possible of not
being tempted towards wanting to push
towards the being able to use at the
expense of security and safety that's
that's me done thank you very much for
listening and I look forward to any
questions you may have thank you