hi everyone welcome to my talk
leveraging Yahoo's to hunt for abuse
telegram accounts I want to start by
asking you all how many of you are
members of illegal groups all channels
on telegram okay I understand why nobody
raises their hands let's begin in my
research I found that almost 50% of the
telegram accounts that I checked abuse
the Platt phone in one way or the other
let's start by telling you the six
takeaways for my talk the first thing is
that I will show you how you can use IOT
global search engine for your own
purpose in my case I use it to hunt for
abuse telegram accounts the second thing
is that you will understand how to
leverage our rules to hunt anything you
want and not only malware for the ones
of you that work is Redeemers I will
show you how to use telegram to create a
community control server and for those
that are on the blue side I will show
you how to protect yourself from such
kind of threat and what nesting I hope
you'll get ideas for next talk just like
happened to me I'm opposed by the head
of research of repose of I reported an
IOT global search engine which protects
company's assets by scanning all of the
global internet on a daily base to
perform that research I had to take
advantage of raposa feist data I am
passionate about helping the community
especially with Charles you can find
some of my created rules on the fish of
github of URLs I'm the creator of the
known tool coffee shot which I was
presented at blackhat us 8 2018 and
lastly I'm excited to be here for my
first time at code blue Japan
what is cybercrime cybercrime is
criminal in a chronica a cyber crime and
criminal activity that involves a
computer or other networking device
there is a long list of cyber crimes
such as fraud money laundering identity
theft as well as many others
in the past if you wanted to get into
the cybercrime districts you'll have to
be in hacker or colder over the years it
has become easier to enter the darknet
and it's come to the point of using
Google to find darknets darknets markets
or website that publishes the latest
darknet market links on the darknet
however the darknet is a difficult place
to navigate it is complex and risky it
is correct that anyone with the tor
browser can get in the dark net but it
will take them some time to find the
phones with the close chat rooms where
people are selling the most evilest
items the dark that is the hive of
illegal activities start starting from
drug dealing selling of guns stolen
credit cards ransomware service and
illegal pornography buyers and sellers
use this medium to trade and exchange
both knowledge and products this is of
course and killed the wrong game of the
law comes in and shut them down the
takedown of such darkness marketplaces
hence a market alpha bay a dream market
by the law across the world made Halen
news from time to time and served as the
latest example of how this cat-and-mouse
game works while there are still
numerous websites operating under the
same premises in both clear net and dark
net the previous examples just indicate
how vulnerable these sites can be for
mahaki will be into a capitalist market
as long as there are illegal products
and money to be made there will always
be criminal invaders developing new ways
to trade the darknet users customers
seem safe rich to the same conclusion -
as well as migrating to more secure and
easily accessible platform from the
criminal perspective it wasn't long
before the shifted to new channels on
the surface to evade the law and
continue their cybercrime an example of
such a channel is the increased lip
popular mobile and messaging app
telegram to continue their cybercrime in
my research I found
Telecom has become a popular tool for
delivering cybercrime so let's dive in
into the presentation and understand why
telecom becomes so popular for
cybercrime Telecom itself launched in
2013 and it's encrypted instant
messaging application with 200 million
active users monthly however what sets
telecom apart
among other features is the pride place
on their approved security capabilities
included prevent end-to-end encrypted
chats the telegram app allows you to
create groups with up to 30,000 members
goofs can be best described as close
chat rooms in which all members can read
comment and post in Marisa found is the
place where cyber criminals advertise
connect and share knowledge and
compromised information just like what
happens in the close dark web phones
telecom also is a nice feature called
channels that can be used to broadcast
messages to an unlimited number of
subscribers and their aunt an amazing
history can be viewed atticus many news
telecom channels to advertise fraud
services and products another thing is
that the implementation sorry another
thing is that by using telegram you have
the option to share files of nearly any
type in my research I found malicious
use of that feature by telegram command
control servers that contain zip files
with the stolen data from the victim
computer another benefit of using
telegram from cybercrime is that anyone
with a shady offer can enjoy encrypted
chats and hidden identity instead of the
exposed threat that are seen in all in
the online web forms if in the past
several steps were required to ensure
anonymous connection to all today
any telegram user can easily and quickly
join channels with a single tap on their
phone and start to receive notifications
of secret conversations and shady offers
directly to their smartphone all while
keeping their identity completely hidden
so I already told you about the telegram
channels
groups but the most known telegram
feature for cybercrime in the telecom
bots
telecom bots are a couple of feature
allowing third-party apps to run within
the platform they have a rich set of
features and quick adoption BOTS can be
set up for specific tasks and legitimate
uses our automatic file converters daily
weather as well as many other legitimate
services the telecom bots are cyber
criminals next step because they include
several significant benefits such as
automatic cybercrime and remain
invisible no need to register a host and
a domain which eliminates all of the
typical security challenges that might
impact a website DDoS style attacks
become irrelevant what someone will try
to ddos telecom web servers in order to
take down some telegram user using
telecom bots also eliminates the need of
cyber criminals to protect and hide
their website from law enforcement
anyway it is also what I thought before
my research another thing is the
implementation of telecom bots in the
fraud contest is relatively new which
makes the law enforcement unaware for
that as a result telegram has become a
valuable alternative to the darknet in
my research I found that malware that
uses telegram is a command control civil
uses the telegram bot API for sending
commands and communication the phone
link is an example of the bot API
request that used by malware in the wild
as you can see the request contains the
bot API token which is built from the
API key an API hash and there is also
the Gately function which coloured in
blue I will explain the purpose of the
get me function in the next few slides
the latest malware which uses telecom
bots as a command control server called
Mossad stealer the Mossad stealer is all
this off-the-shelf malware and
advertised in other ground hacking
phones and dedicated telegram groups it
is still a meme malware
capable of stealing browser data
including safe credentials Lauren Logan
forums and
card information they even have support
groups on telegram in English and
Russian the Mossad still sends all the
information it collects and also
receives comments from a telegram bot
that controlled by the attacker
this is screenshot of the malicious
pickup that I captured using burp as you
can see the request contains the bot API
token and they get me function as I
explained you before in that case the
get me function is used to verify that
the command and control server is up and
ready to get the stolen data from the
victim computer if it will be up the
response from the command control server
will contain the board details which
looks like that and contains the bot I D
first name and username
once the mossad still made sure the
command control server is up it will
send it will use the same document
telegram API function to send a zip file
with the stolen data from the victim
computer as you can see there is the zip
file with the file name
there are also at the frameworks to
create telegram comment control channel
for malware and can be found on github
and Google this one is called brain
damage and it's written in Python you
can scan the barcode if you want for the
links for the framework for direct link
for the framework this is another
frameworks for telegram common control
channel and as you can understand by its
name it's written in C sharp you can
also scan the barcode if you want for
the link
those are screenshots of the comments
the telecom bots command control several
supports as you can see the c2 comments
are very similar to regular c2 server
that we all know such as this info who
in my reverse shell this one is another
example of how looks telecom boats c2
from the attackers perspective on the
right side is the seat to lock terminal
and on the left side is the c2 bot
executing commands on the victim
computer like get a CR so leveraging
yowls to hunt for abuse telegram
accounts on the Internet
let's talk about the research itself how
did it start
before a couple of months ago I attended
the talk at the besides TLV conference
the talk presented a fish eat kid
campaign the twos telecom bots as a CNC
server during the talk I had a spark and
wondered to myself is it possible to
hunt for telegrams c2 severals using IOT
global search engine so I started my
research and my first obstacle was the
need to hunt for a specific string in a
large number of web pages as we all know
the using of Python operators or reg X
on such a large amount means slow
performance which take us a long time to
get some relevant results because of
that I decided to use the are rules my
affair with Charles started a couple of
years ago when I started to walk for a
large AV company since then I published
a couple of sophisticated Yahoo's to
hunt malware and I thought it can be a
great idea to use it for my research
also using yarra compared to other
metals has proven to be more effective
with high performance when dealing with
mass amount of data to scan including
options to create unique combinations
and involve heavy reg X to hunt for
specific data just for you understand
the size of difference I tested the
performance between Java and Python
operators and the result where that with
the Python operators it took me about 22
seconds
32 seconds sorry with 150 function calls
compared to using owls where it took me
only 0.008 seconds with only 10 function
calls I tried to create a graph to show
you that but because the difference in
the performance in difference in the
numbers of the performance was too big
you will not see any colors in the our
rules column my next step in my research
was to write sophisticated ER rules
which involve heavier eggox for
capturing telegram join links telegram
account web pages and exposed telegram
API tokens on the global Internet
although in my research I created three
our rules for the first year will I
analyzed the source code of the telegram
web pages accounts which looks like that
then I use the source code of the send
message button to capture the telegram
user name this is the HTML source code
of that button as you can see it
contains the name of the boat of the
telegram account in that case the
telling the name of the boat was a
repulsive fight bot this is screenshot
for the of the folder created to hunt
for telegram account web pages on the
Internet you can as you can see it
contains some heavy relics for the
second Yahoo I wanted to expand my
research by capturing telegram links
that were published on the Internet
some of the most malicious ones that I
found were posted on comments for
YouTube videos that people that people
can easily and quickly join this is an
example in the green text is an example
for the link structure for joining a
telegram account and this is a
screenshot of the second Yahoo that I
created to hunt for telegram links on
the Internet
as I explained a few slides ago Mel watt
that uses telegram is c2 common control
server uses the telegram Telecom API
function for communication the following
link is an example for that HTTP API
requests I was very curious if I could
capture such as exposed
Telecom API on the global Internet so
for that purpose I created my third and
last yahoo and here is it my turtle
to hunt for exposed telegram api's on
the Internet don't worry in the end of
my talk I will present a link to my
github well where those are wolves will
be published so once I had my our rules
written I combined it with repulsive I
ret Scannell to hunt for exposed
telegram stuff on all over the internet
I stopped the scanner after a couple of
minutes because the list was big enough
for my research you can also scan the
internet yourself and combine through
Charles if it is by using the API of one
of the non global IOT search engines or
using open source tools like that Matt I
commend you to do that you will be
surprised by the things you will find
using yowls and exposed to the Internet
following getting an output list of a
long list that contains telegram
accounts I started my next step in my
research by utilizing peloton telethon
is Python 3 library to interact with
telegram API as a user or through both
account and publicly available on github
you can scan the barcode if you want for
the link so let's stop for a minute and
take a look at the steps that involved
in my research until now and how it
worked the first step was to create an
leveraged Yahoo to hunt for telegram web
pages links na P is that exposed to the
Internet
step 2 scan the internet with miles
step 3 gain an output list of telegram
usernames step 4 using teletón to divide
those usernames into groups channels
bots and users at this point I ran into
another obstacle that I was blocked by
telegram because of API limit at this
point I ran into I ran into another
obstacle that I was blocked by telegram
because of API limits
I tried to manipulate telecom API and
founded telecom block you for 24 hours
after doing about 200 API requests
meaning checking only 200 telecom
accounts daily it that wasn't enough for
me so I overcome the ape the telecom API
limit by purchasing a large amount of
SIM cards I found that once you created
an API for a SIM card
you don't need an active telecom session
later meaning that you can create a
config file with telecom api's and when
it will get an API in limit exception
the script will continue by using the
next API from the config file that you
created after overcoming the API limit I
insert to my POC code some suspicious
identifier based on the telecom
command-and-control open source
frameworks and from malware in the in
the wild the tie found which uses
telegram as command control server the
following screenshot is the result it
contains multiple languages such as
Arabic Persian English and Russian at
that point I started hunting for abuse
telegram accounts by the following
diagram using one of the many features
the telethon has I was able to discover
whether some telegram account is a bot
channel group or regular user in tech
action currently in one case where
identified a group or a channel I use
telethon again to iterate on all over
the history messages and captured those
who have matched to one of the
suspicious and deadly fires that I
insert earlier in another case where I
identified the account as a bot I
utilized telephone
to send message comments such a start
and help to the bot analyze the output
and capture those who matched one of the
suspicious identifiers that I insert
earlier at the end of my talk if you
will have time I will show you what
happened when at the beginning of my
research I accidently detected regular
users as a bot it will be funny this is
a screenshot of my PLC tool in action as
you can see I started by connected with
some sim card then it tested the first
telecom account in the list send him
message comments and waited 30 seconds
before it analyzed it response in that
case it discovered a malicious boot in
testing number 2 the tool detected a
malicious channel or group by searching
for one of the malicious intent Affairs
that I insert earlier in its history
messages in my research I found telecom
bots that leveraged the app to perform
malicious functions starting from human
control servers in polkas to create a
bot that helped use of stay low and
order the perfect woman for a night
based on the options we chose like hell
weight and area I also found black
market channels and some closed hacking
groups here you can see a screenshot of
the mossad stellar that uses telegram as
a c2 server and got haunted by my script
is another malicious telecom both see to
channel of the Mossad stiller that also
got hunted my my script you can see all
the stolen data
did the victim stole that the attacker
stole from the victim computer and here
is another man well we choose Telecom is
command control server and looks like
another variant of the Mossad still in
the Forex screenshot i hunted a persian
darknet channel which publishes a rat
for Windows the rat as you can see
called spy note this one is an automatic
bot for buying stolen credit cards and
has already been deleted here you can
see the bots with by pressing any one of
the buttons you can order a woman
foreign Knight based on the age hair
color and weight this is a bot folder in
drugs to your home just like what
happens in the darknet so we already
talked about how I used my two Yahoo's
to capture telegram links and accounts
on the internet however I didn't talk
yet about the money about the results
for my third year all that I created
hunt for exposed telegram api's on the
Internet
once I hunted the telegram API tokens
that belong to a malicious to attacked
oh if it was on virustotal
or hybrid analysis or other threat
intelligence websites I was able to
access to all of its history messages by
abusing the forward message API to
forward all the body story messages to
my account the forward message API
structure looks like that it is built
from the chat ID that you want to
forward them
- in that case my jet ID was in the
green and the chat ID of the malicious
BOTS itself in orange but as you can see
there is also the message ID which in
red and contains the number of the
message to forward in my research I used
that I used that to write a simple
Python script that will iterate on all
of all the numbers starting from not one
and in until it will get an exception
and by that I got all of the bots
history messages from the first one
until the last one so when I forward the
fourth myth the first message from the
command control server the boat I got
the start command that the attacker
executed to start the sea to the next
messages contained details of the
victims with their stolen data in order
to protect your organization from
malware that uses telegram is a command
control server and find its way out for
out from out of your network
I'll community to block the domain
address API dot telegram dot o on your
firewall or in your other networking
security systems so the stolen data will
not reach to the command control server
so as I said for a couple of slides in a
case that I detected an account as a
real users I skipped it and move to the
next username but at the beginning of my
research I made a small mistake when I
sent message command to real users and
as you will see the result was funny
here you see someone that certainly did
that he isn't a bot
and he is a programmer and wanted that I
will hire him in the end
it tried to stop me by sending me a stop
command in that screenshot you can see
that someone got enough for me and sent
for my message comment send me funny
gifts to show me that
and here you can see that someone went
crazy for not understanding what I want
from him in the end he tried also to
call me I didn't answer him so taking
out the trash
cybercriminals that leverage telegram
for conducting cybercrime is not as it's
not necessarily new as I speak my script
is Lanting for more varieties of
cybercrime on different types of
telegram accounts it doesn't matter if
it's a bot channel or group everything
is taken into account through my
research and the tool that I created I
reported to abuse at telecom not all on
such abused accounts to help to help to
shut them down so what's next
improving my script you can also have
helped me by sending me pull requests I
will continue hunting for telecom
accounts that abusing the platform for
my stuff and trying to make it a better
place and the last thing I want to focus
on hunting for expose telecom API is on
specific threat intelligence websites
such as virustotal
and hybrid analysis and also other
sandbox websites because I found in my
research that this way hiding I had more
chances to hunt for telecom c2 servers
thank you anyone everyone the POC code
for my Anne Meyer rules can be found at
the following link you can also scan the
barcode for the link or take a picture
of it if you want so thanks to everyone
[Applause]