[Music]
now what we want to talk about and
that's what we're doing today instead of
the other one but I will eventually do
the other one because there's definitely
some funny positive another but who we
are we both work for Black Hills
information security I am a dusty red
teamer and I host the show called
tradecraft cool I was my felch you stay
ready on Twitter so like bo said with
Black Hills and then I also work with
helping organize besides Orlando and I'm
part of I'm the chief breaker for a wasp
Orlando so real quick disclaimer we
actually really do love Google we love
their security we love the emphasis that
they put on really trying to secure
their products and and it would be a
discredit to them to not say that so
even though we're going through this
presentation about Google and in red
teaming them the reality is they
actually do a really good job at what
they do and so I just wanted to put a
kind of preface on that and one other
thing to add to that is it's not
necessarily where it's hacking Google as
a company per se it's it's things that
we can attack for organizations who are
utilizing and also this isn't like an
attack against like Google as a single
entity we a lot of these techniques
you're gonna see that could be
translated across other environments as
well but you know it's Google so good
stuff so here's a brief overview of kind
of what we're covering we're gonna give
you a brief juicy the security overview
we're gonna talk about a real world
offensive attack path against sort of
to utilize Google products we're gonna
demo some new functionality that we've
added into mail sniper and current site
this new think red sniper which you will
thoroughly enjoy I guarantee it talk
about the G suite security alright cool
so this is not an exhaustive list this
is basically just a few of the cool
things that Google does for suspicious
activity basically it will send you an
alert on your device it will email you
some of the stuff you probably already
seen the other thing that's interesting
is that on some of the two-factor what
they'll do is they'll have an additional
security dialogues and so they'll ask
you to kind of interact with it and
they'll show you some information and
then the other cool thing that chrome
does if you're using Chrome is that
it'll actually identify phishing sites
so if you have a gmail phishing site
setup they chrome will alert the the
user that hey this is a malicious site
you even want to be careful here and
then the way that we get around that is
just use SSL it seems like if you just
you know set up a let's encrypt SSL cert
and they'll be fine
and then the other thing that they
really provide that's super critical for
any of the admins on Google is the admin
console you have really powerful tools
that they give you to kind of drill in
and and and and focus on where you need
to focus so but from that I want to
speak a little bit about the two-factor
options that Gmail or let G suite
actually provides you so there's a lot
of different options that they gave you
one of the things that I really want to
put emphasis on none of them are
bulletproof and and so there's a
difference between convenient two-factor
options Oh convenient two-factor yeah
it's not gonna work options and then
being a little bit safer and so the
problem is not a Google problem like we
were saying earlier this is kind of
affecting all products that are using
two-factor across the board it's you
know this in the back of everybody's
mind will just use two-factor but it's
not as simple as that and then the other
thing that Google does provide you with
this new thing that they came out with
earlier this year a couple months ago
actually two months ago three months ago
was the advanced protection program and
it's basically using two UTF devices in
order to
to lock down your accountant with some
really cool other things but I wanted to
put some other emphasis on each of them
so SMS so getting a text message
basically when you log in to your
account you're going to notice that it's
going to send them back to text message
there so it's your username plus your
password plus your SMS token that comes
to your text messages it's super easy to
enroll if your Google admin and so
usually that's what they do right they
just they enforce two-factor across the
domain and then they just enable SMS
because SMS is just really easy
everybody has a phone doesn't have to be
a smartphone really convenient and then
the other thing is it's a backup option
so in case you have some of the more
sophisticated ones like a UTF device
which we'll talk about a little bit
later it's the default it's one of the
backup options for recovering access to
your account and the thing to note here
is Google really wants to move away from
this so I've seen it kind of across the
board they don't want to use SMS anymore
they're pushing for new alternatives and
then this is actually deprecating it as
well and so but they're defecating it
for different reasons they're talking
about a mobile carrier redirection like
these really advanced attacks on on
people and then maybe like a malicious
app on the phone so they don't want you
to use SMS for whatever reason I want to
say if you have to factor turned on and
you have SMS you got to change it like
this is absolutely the worst option I
would say for Google and then so next is
is kind of a time-based one-time pass so
this is like the Google Authenticator
app so you get a token expires every 30
seconds it's a little bit more difficult
to enroll for if you're not
non-technical if you're not technical
but there's lots of different apps of a
bill there's duo security there's the
Google Authenticator app there's other
ones this is also a backup option for
Google so I'm bringing up the backup
option for a reason because we'll talk
about that a little bit later but if you
switch devices and you have to resync
again and it gets kind of hairy if you
don't have the Google Authenticator app
available so it's a pretty bad idea as
well and we'll see why a little bit but
basically it's it's fairly
straightforward the user loves into the
site it's already in sync with Google
server so there's a secret that's sent
it's signed
there's some time on it it gets back to
the server according to how you signed
it with what crypto it knows whether or
not you're the original owner of that
and then it just passes you through and
so the next one is this phone
this is really cool this is um so with
with G's with the G sweet now they have
if you have an Android or an iOS like
they'll have this phone prompt and the
phone prompt you just have to say yes
that's really me that's logging into the
session the interesting thing is if it's
if it seems like the the authentication
is a little bit suspicious it'll
actually put a number on the webpage and
say hey touch this number on your phone
and it'll give you three different
options it's seamless for verification
so if you have a Google account inside
onto your Android phone or an iOS with
the app that they have I guess it's a
pretty good alternative for obvious
reasons and so next is the kind of UTF
so this is a universal two-factor it's a
hardware device it could be USB or
Bluetooth this is probably the best
option the problem is that has such a
slow adoption rate so chrome uses it for
Google accounts so it does require
Chrome so if you're using like Microsoft
edge which I don't think anybody is
using edge and if you are you probably
you want to switch anyway but the UTF
device uses it requires Chrome and so it
also requires a backup option well you
have to think like okay so I got a
hardware device so I really want a
backup option I mean if I'm using a
device that's secure and then it's the
strongest verification process it's
definitely the strongest option and it's
fairly straightforward I mean it's just
using PKI it's doing some funds you know
certification you enroll a device into
Google and then it knows you know if
this challenge is sent to the device it
uses the JavaScript API and then it
interacts with the hardware device it
sends the challenge response back and
then you're good to go
so that's kind of the UTF so that's kind
of where we're at you want to start this
one but that's basically the the what
we're going to be kind of looking at so
let's talk about attacking organizations
use Google so you can look at an
enterprise uses Google the same way you
look at any other enterprise you're
gonna do recon you ever heard me talk
about the mail sniper I mean I go
through the entire attack path of how to
break into most organizations just
through email and that kind of ties this
whole thing around to Google now too and
basically it's um so what we what we
typically would do is one of the things
that we typically grab like contacts
from
like LinkedIn or something develop a
nice list of that created like a
doppelgänger gmail account of somebody
who works in that environment and we
were discussing this last night we're
talking about whether or not it's it's
better just to go with like the at
gmail.com domain or go by like a type of
squad a domain and then you know have
like the the employees name hat type of
smart domain and you know honestly like
so this we did a red team and had what
like was 25% yeah 24 I think on on one
of those using Gmail calm as the domain
so you know go create a gmail account
have the guy's name and then import
contact so you can create a CSV that you
you import them to Google and it will
grab all the profile images and the
names of everyone who whose email
address you have which is pretty cool
set up your server environment this is
something that we're going to talk about
more detail here but then we have a
slide port we'll talk about we have a
slide for it no we don't we don't no no
and then so one of the cooler things is
creating like a fake agenda and the G
doc environment and then pointing the
user that which we'll talk about that
whole piece here in a moment but this is
basically like the the setting up of
getting ready for an attack so set up a
fake G doc haven't redirect to like an
authentication page that you control F
creds and with cred sniper you will see
that this is gonna be a lot easier than
you would think
so talking about exporting trust let's
talk about phishing for a moment because
phishing and users everyone's been on
you know they've been trained right like
that's the thing that every organization
trains our place on don't click on this
link
don't you know now begin to this page
that was sent to you that you know looks
like came from like a Nigerian prince or
whatever so one thing that is kind of
new that we thought would be fun is what
about calendar invites how many people
actually look at the content of a
calendar environment so we actually
ended up doing this research along this
line of what we call the event injection
so event injection what is that
storytime well not yet so sign of what
like this whole event ejection thing is
basically we have the capability with
Google to inject events and do to
anyone's calendar we want and this is
something we report it to Google and
they haven't responded yet
so this is one of those things this
probably one of the most important
pieces of this entire talk is one of the
soul of interjection thing about to talk
about because this is crazy all right so
basically what you can do is you can you
can do you think think about the
possibilities of having an event show up
in a an employee's calendar that they
feel the urgency to go to right so like
how would like be a meeting that happens
at 10 minutes like an all-hands meeting
and now they get an alert saying oh I
had this meeting and in the content of
that say you know review this agenda
prior to this meeting and make it like a
malicious G dot so story time how we
even got here one day I was I was just
looking through my calendar and I saw
that I had like travel plans like the
next day and I was like where'd that
come from I'm not going anywhere
I mean John hasn't sent me there yet and
so I started looking through the email
and what it turned out it was a cowork
it sent his travel plans in the body of
an email and Google thought that was my
travel plan so it added it to my
calendar automatically and so we started
looking at that as like being a like
that was the starting point this whole
thing like we decided okay so if I can
if I can send travel plans or send an
email how does that work like how does
how does Google look at that email and
decide whether or not it's gonna add us
your calendar so there's a metadata
attached to that email which we thought
was cool that was the start of it right
like if I just send you an email it's
gonna add it to your calendar that's
kind of neat but then an email wasn't
actually even necessary so Mike he
started just you know looking through
the calendar and literally all you have
to do is create an event invite somebody
to that event and click don't send the
invite like you know pops up a little
box says do you want to send the invite
to to the attendee all you do is click
don't send and it doesn't send them an
invitation but it will add it to their
calendar automatically so yeah if
they're in
they're a gmail user you don't have to
send them anybody they will be on their
calendar so prevents or presents a
really unique fishing situation right so
here's a few ideas
let's include a conference call linked
to a conference we control and you know
how people call in and record the call
you know that can get really interesting
haven't point to like a credential or
missing page have haven't point to a
malicious attachment so it's like you
know with with creating event you can
create you can add attachments that's
you know and then one of the things that
Mike's gonna elaborate on quite a bit
here in a minute is sending them to a
fake Google auth page that collects
creds
so this this gets even more fun when you
hit Google's API because Google has an
API that is is really awesome and once
so one of the things that we're gonna
demo later is basically there are there
are a couple settings that would
eliminate the ability availability of me
adding a calendar invite to your to your
check calendar or an event to your
calendar but it's prefaced with the fact
that you improved it so there's there's
not for the says don't automatically add
events to my calendar if I haven't
approved it with the API I can make it
look like you approved the event that I
made on your calendar which bypasses
that completely so yeah looks like the
accepted it bypasses the the auto adding
and now let's talk about some
personalized fishing okay cool so real
quick before we get into this we'll talk
about credit sniper real quick so with
cred sniper everything that we're going
to be doing and going through here it's
just a new tool that we kind of put
together it's modulized so in the module
that we're using is is the Gmail module
but it's basically similar to all the
other like set and those guys but it
makes it so that you could really spin
up new SSL based phishing pages on the
fly and then also includes two-factor so
what we're going to walk through here is
kind of a multi-stage process this is
specifically for Google so we're gonna
look at you know capturing the email
obviously capturing the password
we found out that they have to factor
which one do they have are there
additional dialogues and so on and so on
and then we're going to retrieve the to
factor our tokens straight from the user
and then we're going to redirect the
user and then we're gonna vanish we're
gonna just we could just erase the event
out of the calendar and there's no
history there's no nothing they're going
on and so this is basically the typical
workflows you would normally see but
with Google so on the fate on phase one
what we're gonna do is we're going to
inject the event into the calendar the
calendar is gonna trigger a reminder
alert on stage two on step two so that's
gonna remind the user that they have a
meeting that they forgot about that's
gonna redirect them they're gonna click
the link they're gonna go to the
phishing page now the thing with Google
is if you ever logged into Google which
probably everybody has they ask you for
your email address first and then they
what they do is they actually send you
to the password page but that password
page has has your email address but it
also has your profile image so the way
that we do that is on in the background
we actually go to the Picasa profile
page pulled the JSON object extract the
profile image for that users email that
they submitted and then we just render
that image on the profile page that way
it's more personalized and then from
there so from there we're gonna fish
their password because now they're
seeing the password page they see their
profile pages they feel confident that
it's Google bear in mind the urgency
right so that notification that told
them that they had a meeting that they
forgot about their they're worried now
they're not even paying attention to
what they're clicking on or where they
put it they're logging into what they're
gonna do they're gonna give us our
password so that what we do here and
this is what Christopher does all
automatically for you is it will go
behind-the-scenes authenticate with
Google learn what two-factor option that
they have available and then personalize
the phishing page for the two-factor
token but all behind the scenes if it's
enabled so if it is enabled then what
it's going to do is it's going to
redirect a user to that phishing page so
if it's an SMS we're going to look at
SMS phishing pages we're going to look
at all the different phishing pages if
it doesn't we're just gonna pilfer the
data
Alessa meal sniper comes in male snipers
are gonna run in the background it's
going to wait for the credentials and
the two-factor tokens to come in if it
needs to and then we have some modules
that but we'll get into a little bit
later on new mail cipher features so
this kind of the workflow that we're
gonna step through real quick so real
quick hands which ones real which ones
fake
so it's it's impossible right you can't
I mean it looks exactly the same and we
in bear in mind we can control the URI
in the in the browser anything past the
domain we have what we own right so we
can make it look exactly so obviously
that one left was fake you can't tell on
this one so let's look at the
personalized password so this is what we
just talked about we're gonna use the
Picasa API we're gonna make an XML HTTP
request we're gonna grab it and we're
just going to ask nicely for the
password
behind the scenes were checking
two-factor we already seen it so which
ones real which ones fake this is the
personalized page same thing you can't
really tell it's exactly the same so the
one on the left is fake so stepping
through the personal Authenticator this
is a little bit more interesting because
now it's the profile image plus the
email plus google tells hey this is a
two-factor application so go to Google
Authenticator or go to duo security and
get the token this is a little bit more
interesting because these tokens expire
in 30 seconds so you really have to
automate the process because they're
gonna put that token in your two-factor
page but what we've done is behind the
scenes when we've authenticated and we
found that they're using the Google
Authenticator for their two-factor we're
also extracting it says login to Google
Authenticator we're taking that Google
Authenticator app name and then feeding
it back to the user as well so just the
same way that we did with the profile
image more Nall also personalizing it
for Google Authenticator and then you
have to log in within 30 seconds or you
know relatively up to 30 seconds
depending on when they actually
generated a token that they're giving to
you and so that looks like this if you
notice which one's left which one's
right we don't really know but if you
see you see where says Google
Authenticator we just extracted that and
then rendered it in the page and so cred
sniper is basically just templating so
you could add whatever you need to there
this one it looks like the one on the
left is the fake one because of the
profile image but real quick disclaimer
so Google is not very consistent with
rendering the profile image on their
login process so sometimes it's there
sometimes it's not we do it all the time
so ours looks more legit than theirs
yeah so and then the personalized SMS
this is this is the reason why I really
think this is about
idea it's the image in the email
obviously but it's gonna ask for the
last two digits of the phone number well
bear in mind we've authenticated for
that user they've shown us the last two
digits we extract that and data out of
the page we render it on the phishing
page for the user so now it says oh wow
you know what it has my last two digits
it must be Google and then the
interesting thing about this one is as
comparison to the last one you have
plenty of time this is an actual these
are actual tokens that were sent to me
and look at the time stamp it's the same
token hours later and some of them I had
I didn't even show on here but it was
like three hours later or something
crazy but it's the same token and the
reason for this is because way Google
does is when it generates the token and
it sends it to the SMS if it doesn't get
used which it's not right because we're
triggering it on the backend we log in
the backend
it triggers the two-factor token to get
sent to their text message we redirect
them to our phishing page but we never
actually use that token until we need it
so that you have plenty of time
basically that that token is not tied to
a session the SMS token on a repeat SMS
token is not tied to a specific session
and you could you can see I could fish
it and then use it two hours later when
they're home at home and they're not
even at work anymore and so they just
resend that use token until it gets used
and so personalized SMS so the last two
digits you see there it looks legit
obviously it's the fake ones on the left
again because it didn't for some dumb
reason load my profile image on the
right but you can see these are very
exact pages this is super dangerous it's
super automated I would say that two
factors is definitely broken at least in
this use so the phone prompt this is the
new one contains the profile image the
email and then it has this will you
please touch this number and then on the
screen we'll see a little bit later but
it prompts on the phone so the first one
is is this you yes or no they click yes
so they click no if they click yes then
if it's suspicious and for some reason
I'm not really sure but it's always
suspicious with the credit sniper I
think it's because of my user agent but
it's prompting you for the number you
click that number and then but remember
it's showing you the number on the page
that we've authenticated against so we
know what number to feed to them again
so we just tell them hey will you please
click this number 46 and they're like
okay yeah for sure and so
the cool thing with this is the phone
prompt is a little bit more tricky
because when they're authenticating yeah
we could just take that 46 they could
authenticate it we could take those
session like the session cookies and all
the headers and then feed them through
we're not doing that yet with cred
sniper so what's what's ended up
happening is I'm going to come back here
we have two different triggers that we
need to do first is when we're
identifying that they are enrolled on
behind the scenes the second one is our
authentication so we're gonna log in
again and then these screens are going
to prop back up on their phone the cool
thing is if we do it quick enough the
new image that loads on their phone
prompt will actually override so our
real authentication where we're logging
into their account will make their old
screen go away and it'll be our screen
that they're actually clicking so it
doesn't matter anyway it's just gonna
work and so the real versus fake same
thing pass the name through this one
I've screwed up it says check your phone
I it's so inconsistent on the background
- you have to have like four different
regular regular expressions to make sure
that you get all the different variants
that they do because they do a lot they
like unlock your phone or you know check
your phone and they change the verbage
and if you don't have all the rights for
all of them you'll miss it and so then
the dreaded UTF this is the interesting
one so contains the image and the email
obviously we can capture signed messages
because whenever you put a UTF into the
into the USB and you actually submit the
credentials it's really just passing
that signed message and with two new in
line returns and so line feeds get sent
it gets posted at the server we can
capture the token the problem is we
can't really replay it and there's
reasons for that the first thing is I
tried replaying it with send keys but
send keys doesn't actually pass the key
code because the key code with key event
keyboard events in JavaScript basically
is how it determines whether it's a
virtual keyboard or real keyboard so
that didn't work so I was like okay I
got another idea what about the rubber
ducky will yield hak5 ducky it's
actually a USB composite device I'll
change the vid the pig to make it look
like in my yubikey I'll change I'll
modify the firmware so that it looks
like it's actually Yubikey it doesn't
obviously conform to the the final UTF
spec because we don't have any
functionality into the Dougy
we'll say that one for later I think
there's some cool stuff here that we
could do with like using a ducky to
clone a UTF
we capture the message as long as we
replayed that message from a legit one
I'm not sure yet I don't I don't know we
I'm prove that yet but so instead of
trying to like do anything with UTF
licious bypass it right so you have UTF
the only thing is um UTF only works with
chrome and it requires the backup as
semester the one-time pass right so what
we do is we could downgrade to the
backup options and so what we do is we
changed our back-end user agent I was
going through some of their JavaScript
and looking at things the way that I was
working and I noticed that if you it was
checking for this cry OS user agent so I
tried with my pythons I'm just using
requests with credits typer and so I
just used it and with the interesting
thing is whenever you're using a user
agent that's not Chrome it doesn't even
bother with the UTF all it does is it
reverts back to the Recovery Options
which is SMS or the the Authenticator
app and then it triggers that SMS token
and from there what I'm doing is I'm
that identifying its UTF and so I just
immediately just I fished their SMS I
trigger the SMS on the background and so
we don't even have to use UTF we just
send them to the phishing page for the
SMS and life is good so we just continue
as normal so UTF UTF with backup options
is dead we cannot have UTF with backup
options and expect UTF to be the device
that's being used because i mean you're
gonna go to a page you're not gonna know
whether you've enrolled in UTF on that
page or not or might be SMS you're gonna
forget I mean nobody really knows
because the adoption rate is so low on
this or maybe I'm in Firefox and I'm
used to seeing it I'm used to seeing
that anyway I don't know it's just it's
silly to have UTF with backup options
that you can't turn off and so from
there I want to add a couple different
things I did notice that there was when
during suspicious activity with Google
sometimes it'll ask you the last
location that you've logged in from this
is really simple I just take the geoip
of the request on the phishing page I do
a geoip
I grab the location the city state zip
or whatever and then I feed it back into
mail sniper so that whoever's using it
knows where they're actually at so they
can just type it in there and it's good
the other thing is there's a new there's
some new alerts that they do in Google
wearing Gmail whenever you log in to be
a big red bar at the top that bar it's
like hey I've seen some unknown activity
or some weird malicious activity if you
clear it clears it for everybody and
it's only showing it to new sessions
that sign in ceiling I was really
worried about it it should show it to
everybody but it doesn't
and then the other thing is so multiple
failed phone prompts so if you're using
the phone prompt and you're testing this
you're you could lock your phone prompt
out for a couple hours so just be aware
I don't know how many times it takes it
takes I think three or four maybe and
then the other thing that we were
talking about doing that we haven't done
yet is we could just complete this
session on the back end and then pass
that session information to mail sniper
we're not doing that currently because
we just ran out of time this is all like
within the last couple weeks we've got
the code going but that's something that
we're going to do kind of in the future
and so from there we'll just go on to
more of the persisting access to delete
that from let's automate creating in
habitat password to work we're go grab
all the back end codes and then you know
we have another way which is fun add a
new 2fa device so that we now control
for the two factor and then maybe change
the recovery email and create create a
forwarder for three emails
so yeah just real quick I just do this
in this morning so basically you could
add full scope access to the account you
could generate an API key on the backend
he'll get into that a little bit but if
you just add some scopes and you see
over here it you can read send delete
manage your email bear in mind you
already have this session so you don't
have to trick the user into authorizing
this you are the user so you just
authorize it for them and then it adds
it as an authorized app it gives them
full access backdoor to pretty much
everything their calendars their Google
Groups their Drive or sending an email
data with mail sniper that's one main
things that I do with it as search email
find sensitive data that's kind of what
similar similar idea to what me know
something was doing with exchange we're
now searching Gmail same exact thing so
we have
now the searches you know since if data
the cool thing about searching Gmail
through
we're with with male sniper is that it
doesn't actually show like any of the
emails is being read so you can you can
search it like let's say password or
something get you know 70 emails that
have the word password in it and you get
the full contents of it not if it looks
like it was ever read which is kind of
neat
and then a bonus is that you got the
Google search operators right so you can
there like file type : give you up in
there you can throw you know various
like search operators like or you know
like that's sort or credentials that
kind of thing which is nice you know
soon include drive groups and contacts
as well and let's talk about the data
export for google for me because this is
pretty pretty crazy how much data you
can get so there's a there's a my
activity google comm site that allows
you to basically export all of your
google data that they know about you and
it includes literally everything like
every every piece of searches history
you've ever had all your location is
straight so if you've ever used the
navigation on your phone with google it
has all the places you've ever been all
the cheap every single g drive file
you've ever uploaded all your emails are
contacts i mean we're talking about like
nightmare scenarios for you know any of
anyone really but like you know think
about like a politician or celebrity
that you get access their genome just go
export everything up
well let's search history that beep that
day so yeah and then pivoting systems we
just try to skip yeah let's sound let's
get to the demo because we only have I
think like so what we're gonna demo is
basically the event injection from mail
cipher using the API and so Mike's gonna
show basically the settings in Google
like how like what I was mentioning
earlier where you can disable the
adding to your calendar cool so okay so
this is a brand new account so if you
guys screw with me I'm okay with that
it's a it's Wyatt Earp and so we created
a new email real quick and what I want
to show here is this new setting this is
so we notify Google a couple of weeks
ago that we can inject calendar invites
there were no features we step through
together at Black Hills trying to see if
we could turn it off on the Google admin
side or we could turn it off on the
user's calendar side we couldn't do this
at all the only thing that they did have
is this events from Gmail so I'm going
to turn that off real quick notice that
if you turn this if you turn this
security feature on or if you turn this
normal feature off it prompts you and it
says hey you'll no longer see any events
automatically added the other thing is
if you've previously added events they
go away so you can't really turn this
off not without really greatly impacting
your calendar and that's just from the
Gmail this new feature so after we
notified them they didn't really say
anything to us but they added this new
feature about a week later automatically
add invitations to my calendar so we're
gonna say no only show invitations to
which I've responded we're gonna save it
here and then I'm going to just take
this so in mail sniper I already have a
session here and what we're going to do
is we're going to just use mail sniper
to invoke it we're gonna add it to the
calendar and we got an error of course
it's not authorized that's because it's
the access token is expired which that
piece is going to be automated and next
week
so any any questions so far while he's
doing this for Blake let's say like a
mill or something no idea because it's
different completely different right so
you know I have no idea like how that's
probably I would say depends on the
service right it depends on what the guy
looks like depends on what's that
so middle sniper kind of does officer
sees I've already not with two-factor
now I did well depends on the two-factor
right so we've tested a couple different
two factors and some of them don't cover
you know all the services like uws
if that's the case okay
yeah
so we're get into in the background and
Google admin side there's some really
cool stuff they even have an SDK so you
could run like the CLI inside of it
let's see if this one works real quick I
don't know if the same token but yeah
they got some cool stuff some really
good back-end tools to kind of aid that
process here you won't take this real
quick one of the things I was mentioning
is like so there's a few four flags that
you're not saying here you're seeing
like even title then we're gonna specify
you're seeing the description you're
seeing the location but there's a lot of
other things you can basically tell it
how it should work the city there does
service hey we're running short on time
I'm gonna screw over the other presenter
keep going up until the line Michael's
gonna cut us off but there will be a
video released and there will be another
step-by-step tutorial blog post released
so everybody can actually go through and
do this as well okay cuz there's a lot
to cover in a very quick period of time
yeah we're doing a series of tradecraft
security weekly shows
so real quick fighting back so this is
cool so that was basically what we were
doing and this is this is interesting
because this is going to your question
about the logs right so this is a Google
admin console log the way that we're
currently doing it this is clearly
identifying right so you see the first
one the very very bottom you'll see that
it was presented with a login challenge
this is what we're triggering it on the
back end the second one is when we've
actually captured it and we're actually
logging in ourselves so you see like one
two and then they logged in one two
logged in this is so these they're all
available and you could search by IP
address so if you found somebody this
account was compromised straight to
Google admin take the IP address that
was logged into that account search
Google you'll find all the other creds
behind the scenes but it's pretty pretty
good for like removing backdoors and and
kind of looking to see who's set up
other stuff the other thing is so if you
didn't expect it question it right this
is it's typical the problem is we we
don't change where we don't train for
for behavior we train for like
technology like don't if don't click it
if it's from this person so this just
look for weird activity they got some
really cool stuff with security checkup
that you can kind of go do so let's just
recap real quick so SMS one-time pass
for two-factor is completely dead if the
tokens are not tied to sessions it's
dead don't do it don't use it you TF is
completely useless if there's a backup
option that's default that it goes back
to fishing training should be on
behavior not specific red flags and
there's you know and obviously there's
for the company having Google suite is
super convenient but just because it's
convenient for you doesn't mean it's not
convenient for attackers and then if you
use G suite literally at this moment
anybody can inject an event into your
calendar and there's nothing you could
do about it there's nothing that you're
gonna be able to do about until Google
fixes this and so I knows when they're
gonna do that hopefully it'll be soon
because I think you know they're really
good with catching up on stuff but so
that's pretty much it
[Applause]