[Music]
this is authenticated code execution by
design or making zen and the art of how
I learned to stop worrying and love the
password for fun and profit great again
so I think the Who am I slide really is
best used as a way of telling you why I
think you should care about my opinion
on things I am a penetration tester now
I was the Metasploit community manager
for several years I worked for rapid7
writing Metasploit for several years
before that before that I was a security
researcher so I've been on some networks
and I have some I've seen some the
question is what's Metasploit and it's
it's this Python tool that sorry it was
a reasonable Perl yes so what is a sub
first it's authenticated so that means
that there's some sort of login involved
and that doesn't have to be a password
most of the time it will be a password
but there are other kinds of
authentication too there's certificate
off there's key off like SSH as ed was
talking about just a moment ago so
there's lots of things that allow you to
log into stuff they're not always the
same they often have different
properties sometimes you have to if a to
deal with but I'm not really super
concerned about how the authentication
happens what we're talking about is what
you can do with it once you've
authenticated when you have a session
like what happens so first it's
authenticated then there's code
execution and I'm gonna be a little bit
fuzzy on this sometimes I'll mean code
execution in the terms of like shell
code sometimes it's you get to run an
executable sometimes it's operating
system commands sometimes it's none of
those things and it it lets you like
manipulate stuff in a weird way so I'll
be a little bit fuzzy on this and we get
to that eventually anyway
and it's by design so that means that
we're using the service in the way that
it was intended to be used it is the
design goal of this thing to allow you
to run code and we'll talk about a lot
of different things that allow you to do
that this is sort of a grab-bag of all
of the the things that I think are most
fun and the things that I've run into
that allow you to log in and then do
something stupid so first before we're
to get into any of that none of this is
meant to disparage the tools we're
talking about everything I'm going to
talk about today is something that
solves a problem a piece of software
that serves some purpose that people use
to do their work that doesn't mean that
they're bad things because I can log
into them and do something stupid
there's nothing wrong with them there
are still good tools and they do good
things so I don't want you to think that
I'm hating on these things I love these
things
because they give me shells so why why
do we want a Simmons intrusion
prevention systems can't block passwords
they can't block logins or otherwise why
do you have the thing to log into in the
first place if intrusion prevention
prevented users from being able to log
into the system then there's no point in
having the system right so IPS can't
block regular users from being able to
log in legitimately if you can log in as
that user then IPS can't block you
either passwords will always work and I
mean this more broadly I say passwords
but I mean it as authentication
passwords are somewhat less useful today
than they were 10 years ago because of
the rise of 2fa because of certificate
authentication because of other kinds of
things that people are doing to secure
logins but I don't care about any of
that because as
as a bow and mic demonstrated yesterday
in their talk about Google suite 2fa is
just more work stealing a certificate is
just more work stealing a key is just
more work it's still logging in I can
still log in as that user and I don't
care how the authentication happened so
authentication is always going to be a
thing there will as you know I am NOT a
miner I'm not a person who can read the
future but I don't see a way in which
the world can exist without
authentication you have to be able to
say this person has authenticated and
proven that they are who they say they
are and they are authorized to log into
this thing those two aspects of
computers will always exist this won't
go away and passwords are the best form
of persistence I stole this from Rubik I
get all my best ideas by stealing them
from mobic
if you have to use an exploit to get
into something you're setting off all
kinds of alarms there's things that see
you on the network there's there's risk
there's lots of risk involved with that
running a payload has lots of risks to
your there's potential for triggering
IDs there's potential for triggering a V
if you just log in as the regular user
much in the same way that IPS can't
block regular users logging in they
can't get pissed off at you for doing
the same thing that regular users do so
now I'm going to talk about some of the
individual things that I think are
useful in this domain so first we'll
talk about login services the obvious
things that that everyone thinks of when
you when you think of the idea of being
able to log in and run stuff things like
telnet telnet is according to the man
page a direct network interface to login
it's a very simple protocol developed
originally in 1975 with RFC 15 so it's
been around for a minute
it's one of the oldest protocols it
preceeds IP by eight years telling
that's been around for a minute
so it's it's pretty old and as InfoSec
people we've been telling everyone to
stop using telnet because it's not
encrypted but the concept of telnet
haven't lived forever and will continue
to live forever
we don't have encryption and therefore
we tell people to stop using it but it
still exists you still find telnet on
real networks you still find telnet on
all kinds of embedded devices it exists
all over the place and what you get to
do when you log into something over
telnet depends on the thing because the
protocol is is very simple it's stupid
it just lets you talk to the device and
sometimes that means you get like a raw
bash shell sometimes it means you get a
Cisco shell or all the various kinds of
things that that telnet gives you but
because there's no encryption we yell at
people for using it and it's super old
and it's like this old guy you tell him
that he needs to quit smoking but he's
been smoking for 80 years and like why
should I encrypt my lungs now so then we
get the new kid on the block and this is
this is the the older new kids after
Marky Mark left with OpenSSH and we add
encryption on top of that now you can't
just watch it on the wire and steal
passwords and see everything that's
happening encryption gives you some
privacy some confidentiality some
integrity you can't inject stuff into it
but more than that it's a more feature
full protocol with telnet you log in you
get whatever the shell is with OpenSSH
you also get port forwarding that's one
of my favorite things about it
open SSH gives you the ability to tunnel
TCP traffic from your local machine to
wherever that endpoint is that your SSH
to and now you can create new packets
from the inside of the network on the
other side
and expand your influence that way so
this is not just code execution you can
you can run commands you can upload
files you can execute those files but
you also get network access from OpenSSH
so I love SSH it's it's one of my
favorite things in the whole world but
OpenSSH is not the only SSH there are
multiple implementations of SSH there's
a sitcom which you don't see a whole lot
anymore but it does exist and there are
numerous windows implementations of SSH
and each of them has the same issues so
you can log into it then you can do
anything that the user would be able to
do then in the windows world we have
remote desktop and also known as
Terminal Services it's a graphical
interface that lets you connect to a
Windows machine and pull up a full
desktop and interact with it in the same
way that you would with a console it
also gives you access to Network shares
on that device so you can connect
network shares on your local machine to
network shares on the remote machine
that you're logged into with remote
desktop so in a way it acts similarly to
SSH in that you get network access to
the environment where the target is is
logged into and in Windows 8.1 and newer
you can even use pass the hash against
RDP in certain scenarios the restricted
admin feature was added so that you
could prevent your login to a remote
desktop machine from being used on the
other side of that network the idea of
it is that normally when you log into
Windows your your credentials are cached
and you can use those credentials to log
in to anything else it's the single
sign-on idea that allows you to traverse
a Windows network in without having to
give your password for everything that
you touch so that is kind of a problem
sometimes when you're for example a
helpdesk person and you're logging into
a system
and you don't want the person you're
logging the the machine that you're
logging into to be able to reuse those
credentials and log into more stuff as
you so they added this thing called
restricted admin that prevents that but
in doing so they allowed you to now pass
the hash to anything that has restricted
admin enabled and x3 RDP implements this
so it's just it's a Linux tool that you
can use and you just give it a hash
instead of a password and it works super
awesome VNC is basically the same idea
but implemented in the dumbest way
possible it's just it's just pixels
that's all it is it's a frame buffer and
sometimes it can be password lists VNC
can let you login with no password and
then it's an authentic ated remote code
execution by design I love it and it's
also often unrelated to system login so
whereas SSH relies on either Pam or
radius or whatever and remote desktop
relies on windows authentication VNC
can do windows authentication but most
of the time it has its own little thing
has its own authentication that has
nothing to do with your windows password
you can set it to something else and
people are terrible at using passwords
you can't do two if a with V and C as
far as I'm aware I've never seen a VNC
server that required two FA and that
lets you bypass any two FA on the system
that you're logging into with then
there's helpdesk things things that sort
of replace the the simplicity of remote
desktop with different kinds of
backdoors ami admin is is particularly
fun
this one was brought to my attention
because a whole bunch of scammer
assholes we're using it as a means of of
stealing money from old biddies where
they'd they'd call up just random phone
numbers and be like hey I'm from
Microsoft and your shits owned and I
need to log into it
so I can help you I can I can I'm here
I'm gonna be your your support so log
into it and download this tool and then
I'll help you and help means I'm going
to encrypt your thing and ransom your
ship back to you so that's not a me
admins fault but a me admin absolutely
enables it all of the other remote
desktop is sort of things work very
similarly basically you install this
server the client can connect to it and
control the desktop in any way that they
want sometimes this is even
unauthenticated - if you're lucky or
unlucky I guess depending on depending
in your perspective so then we get to
file system access all of these have
been things that you log in and directly
do stuff while system access is more
like I just get access to the files
maybe I can only read sometimes I can
write and these are the standards the
the big one of course is FTP FTP is all
over the place
NFS is still around in in UNIX shops
although there are fewer UNIX shops then
then Windows in the world for sure and
WebDAV now getting code execution from
file system access relies on a lot of
circumstances so you have to be able to
write to certain directories or in some
cases you can read and turn that into
code execution so for example if you can
read associate private keys then that
converts to code execution in another
way you can transfer that to a different
protocol and get code execution that way
in the windows world if you can write to
system 32 you win if you can write to
anything if you can if you can write to
see directly the see dollar share then
you win if you can write to any place
that an executable loads a DLL from then
you win and all of those things are very
dependent on what the share is giving
you access to so
these are the most unreliable things
that I'm going to talk about in this
presentation everything else is you log
in and you win
these are you log in and maybe you win
maybe you don't WebDAV is a lot less
common than it used to be it was around
it was really prevalent back in the like
early Audis with a Microsoft front-page
and the rise of subversion the fall of
CVS and now the subversion is falling by
the wayside in favor of git and
mercurial and all the new more useful
tools WebDAV is sort of dropped off a
bit but it still exists you still find
it and
WebDAV in particular is useful because
most of the time when it's available
it's intended directly to be able to
upload system shells but that's sort of
sports the whole point of it so you can
upload new code to the server then we've
got out some B and I didn't put it on
the previous slide because SMB is a
special case does anybody know who Ned
pile is there's ants
Ned pile he's the he's the program
manager for the SMB protocol at
Microsoft he's a cool guy very punny and
I love this quote it's fantastic so SMB
one is the older version of the protocol
he's been trying to push for everyone to
get off of SMB one and on to SMB two
which is a much faster less stupid
protocol and running SMB one is like
taking your grandmother to the prom she
means well but she can't really move
anymore and it's sort of creepy and
gross but it doesn't really matter that
much which version of the protocol
you're logging into if you've got access
to SMB one it's the same as having
access to SMB to in that I can still
write files wherever I'm allowed to
write files and Windows has all of those
places I mentioned before but there's
more to SMB there's more than just file
system access so
we'll come back to that in a minute now
I want to talk about some more servery
type things administration things is
anybody familiar with Tomcat I love this
thing Tomcat is an application server
and it has a manager application whose
whole purpose in life is to allow you to
upload new code that's what it's for
it's it's for you to deploy new
applications on your web server by
default it uses HTTP basic auth over
HTTP
so it's unencrypted base64 passwords
sweet
by default it has a user named tomcat
with the password of Tomcat and in later
versions that removed the defaults
Tomcat the the Tomcat user is no longer
allowed to log in by default but this
was just shells for days and it it's not
the only thing like this so we'll talk
about some more of those the next one is
websphere does anybody know what
WebSphere is it's like Tomcat on
steroids the whole point of Tomcat is to
deploy on the application server where
Tomcat is deployed the purpose of
WebSphere is to deploy to a whole
cluster of application servers so when
you own Tomcat you own the Tomcat server
when you own WebSphere you own the whole
data center and my favorite part about
IBM WebSphere ok first can anybody guess
what the default authentication
mechanism is not you anybody guess what
the default authentication mechanism is
for IBM WebSphere none you're right
so the the application supports ntlm off
it supports LDAP it supports radius it
supports all kinds of stuff but by to
fall logging into WebSphere is clicking
a button it's just it's a button on a
webpage you have to give it a user name
you have to give it a username but it
doesn't matter what the username is you
can give it anything and even better if
someone else is already using that webs
that that username it kicks them off
first it's awesome then we get to the
same idea so websphere deals with
application servers and then we get
things like virtualization servers that
let you control entire data centers full
of VMs getting access to vSphere is
amazing it's so much fun
once you've got access to this thing
you've got full concept console access
to everything that it controls and these
Center is intended to be able to log
into multiple ESXi servers so that could
be this could be dozens of machines by
accessing this one service so if you see
these fear log into it procs box is an
open source thing that works very
similarly to vSphere the whole point of
it is that you can log into all of the
virtual machines that it can talk to
proxmox can also connect up to I believe
it does Xen and it does then it does
ESXi it does KVM and so this is more
likely to get you a bunch of Linux VMs
which is interesting in its own right
but absolutely worth your time if you
can log into this thing I recommend
doing so and you have all the various
cloud things
[Laughter]
so I'm just gonna let that run for a
minute that's mmm yeah so if you get
access to Amazon keys you can login into
their AWS and and see all the VMS you
can download more secrets from those
things often gaining access to Amazon
keys gives you access to SSH keys gives
you access to more machines so steal all
the things and if you're working in the
cloud it's okay to be sad the next
server administration thingamajig is 1rm
and I love when are in it's not enabled
by default on Windows but it's enabled a
lot a lot of people turn it on and
inside any powershell session you can
type enter PS session def computer name
and then whatever you want to talk to if
if if the target machine is running win
on RM and you have a valid login for
that machine then you can run PowerShell
on that machine it's fantastic there's
also the winner s command which will let
you run a command directly so this will
be like a CMD command and both of these
things are fantastic lots of people have
done a bunch of cool work with this so
I'm not gonna repeat it too much but
definitely winner M is one of my
favorites and that leads directly into
what I said we were going to talk about
more later
now it's later and SMB like I said it's
not just SMB it's a full ecosystem of
all kinds of crap the RPC interface in
SMB
gives you access to a bunch of weird
stuff the one that everybody knows is
the service Control Manager so the way
PS exec works is it uploads a file it
creates a new service it points the
services bin path at that new file that
it just created it starts the service it
stops the service it deletes the file it
deletes the service
and you get shells for days now almost
all of the things that I'm going to talk
about you have to have a local
administrator access to the victim
machine but you can do everything that
PS exec does manually you don't have to
use the system turtle stool you don't
have to use the the Metasploit module
for it you can do everything it does
manually directly from the CMD shell if
you want and a lot of places don't like
seeing PS exact Exe on their network so
it's something to keep in mind that you
don't have to do that with PS exec you
can do it with the underlying mechanisms
that it uses SCO exe is the service
control executable that lets you create
services and stuff and if you give it a
computer name it will operate remotely
exactly like pass exec does then there's
the task scheduler app dot exe is the
way you interact with this you can use
at to point at a target server and I'm
going to steal Rob's story about this if
you use at make sure you check the local
time of the target system first they
might not be in the same time zone as
you and it really sucks if you tell it
to run ten minutes from now and it
actually meant ten hours from now so
watch out for that and the task
scheduler on older Windows used to go
directly over SMB and the same is true
of PS exec you used to go directly over
SMB and it would talk to the named pipe
for the at service 80s VC same with PS
exactly used to talk to the served
service SRV SVC over a named pipe now on
modern Windows instead it talks to first
the port mapper on 135 and then some
ephemeral port on a high number but it
works exactly the same way and it's all
completely transparent to you if you use
the executables so you just use that dot
exe or you use sco exe and it
exactly the same way too regardless of
what you're talking to if you have
access to SMB as a local administrator
on the target machine you also have
access to the remote registry changing
stuff on the registry is code execution
every time there's the the run key the
run once key which are just things where
you put an executable name and it'll
just run that when the system boots and
that gives you the late execution you
don't get your shell right away you get
it when the system boots but it's still
a valid way of getting a show
there's the debugger keys which allow
you to set a debugger for any executable
and I stole this from Moo bik's to you
you can set a debugger for the
stickykeys executable and then when you
use remote desktop you hit shift 5 times
and it gives you a shell or runs our
executable whatever you told it to but
it doesn't have to be sticky keys it
could be anything you could set it on
Explorer dot exe and then the next time
someone logs in you get a shell as them
you can also modify the path by
modifying the registry there's many many
ways of gaining execution by controlling
the registry these are just some of my
favorites by changing the path you can
tell Windows to look for my executables
first you can put a UNC share as the
first thing in path and then it will
always go and look at my box for your
executables anytime anything runs a pin
it DL else does anybody know what that
is show of hands
what does happen it deal well okay a few
people basically if you've ever heard of
LD preload in the Linux world it works
exactly the same way it's a bunch of
dll's that anytime any process starts
that uses user 32 it'll load up those
dll's as well so you get direct code
execution in every gam process it's
awesome
then you get decom objects these are fun
this is a relatively new means of code
execution through SMB where I believe
this was Matt Nilsson enigma enigma' x3
so MMC 2-0 dot a plane is the the decom
object that controls MMC so the the the
machine configuration doohickey one with
all the snap ins you can add snap ins
through this through this D comma object
but if there's also just an execute
shell command method on that thing so
you create the decomp object then you
call the execute shell command method on
it and it runs whatever you want on the
victim machine
similarly Excel that application is
Microsoft Office Excel and that lets you
run macros so anything that you would
would normally use in a phishing attempt
you can run it directly through this
interface and the best part about both
of these is that the services run a
system so it's just shells for days yes
Excel does have to be installed but how
many shops have you been on where Excel
wasn't on anything so then some that are
not quite so obvious I love these things
WordPress is my favorite web shell it's
it's a content management system that
I'm sure most of you are familiar with
but that's not it's only only
functionality and this is the market
share according to ww3 text comm anyway
59% of websites on the internet that
have a CMS have WordPress 28% of the
entire damn Internet has WordPress if
you can log into WordPress as an
administrator you have access to all
kinds of fun things like themes and
themes sounds like it's like style
sheets and templates and stuff no no
it's PHP code because why not and you
can upload themes directly from the
admin interface and it's basically just
a zip file containing PHP code in a
certain directory structure and it's
super easy to write them there you can
get all kinds of examples on the
internet super easy to use
there's also plugins so WordPress and
plug-in sounds more like a thing that
executes code right and turns out yes it
does you can install plugins directly
through this interface as well it works
exactly the same way it's just a zip
file containing PHP code there's also
like marketplace thing where you can go
and download other people's themes and
plugins and there's a bunch of them out
there some of them are really useful for
attackers there's one called shell PHP
which I bet you can guess what it does
then we get Joomla and Joomla is not as
widely deployed but you still see it
it's still so if we go back to this
slide
3.2 percent of the Internet is running
Joomla that's still pretty significant
and Joomla has this extension system
where you can upload a file directly but
they also have a market thinger similar
to work press and that uses the the
marketplace where if you want to create
a package you you need a Joomla account
joomla.org account
you need a git repository somewhere on
the internet that it can talk to you
need a key that will allow you to upload
your code to the marketplace and so
there's some hoops you gotta jump
through it's all free and there's no
humans involved in the process so you
can sign up and you can do all this
yourself pretty quickly but you don't
really need to because other people have
uploaded other things there's also a
shell for Joomla it's right there in the
marketplace then we get to Drupal and
you may have detected a pattern here
there's a plug-in system for Drupal and
you can upload plugins it works exactly
the same way it's a zip file full of
code you upload the file it puts it on
the file system it opens it up and runs
all the code for you
Drupal before Drupal 8 also had this
awesome thing called PHP filter and the
people who smiled I know how old you are
PHP filter is an awesome feature is kind
of a kind of unique to Drupal no one
else really did this where if you if you
have access to create content in Drupal
not just as an administrator but anyone
who can create a post you can filter
your your post through various things
that that make changes to it one of
those things is the PHP filter that
allows you to run PHP code in your post
so the way that works is it puts the PHP
code from your your post in the database
and then evals it out back later now
that's really cool but it gets better
because that leaves the forensics
evidence of your code living on the
database there's also a preview feature
which allows you to just email it
directly and it never hits the database
so then it's not even on the disk and
good luck with the logs on that but
again this is kind of a unique thing for
Drupal and they got rid of it in in
Drupal 8
but then they brought it back and and I
lied it's not really unique WordPress
and Joomla both have the same sort of
thing and an extension so you can
install them all you can it's all of
these things directly from their
marketplace interface and these do
exactly the same thing so in WordPress
that's called insert PHP and it lets you
put code in posts and in Joomla it's
called direct PHP but they do exactly
the same thing they let you execute code
if you have any permissions at all on
the the CMS interface so thanks guys so
then I want to talk about some stuff
that didn't really fit elsewhere how are
we doing on time oh I gotta go faster
smart just fun it's got a plugin system
the plugin system is just Python code
it's Python code and a zip file you win
then they also have external plugins
that you can basically give it an
elephant it'll do whatever anything you
can run on Linux
it supports Pam radius and LDAP for
authentication but if you get the trial
version or like the free community
version or whatever no off at all it
does not allow you to do any kind of
authentication like that's that's a paid
feature yeah good times I mean the
Nagios I don't actually know what Nagios
does other than give me shows
Microsoft sequel server is fantastic it
used to be back in the old days that if
you have an essay account any any assist
system in or DBA account you could have
access to the XP command shell stored
procedure and you run commands directly
through that and that's cool that's all
well and good but it's getting a lot
more lockdown these days sa blank isn't
the default anymore and you can't you
can't rely on command dot exe always
being there or being allowed by
whitelisting etc etc but you don't need
any of that because sequel server allows
you to load assemblies directly so you
can upload c-sharp assemblies and it
will load them in its own process and
all of that is completely a memory
awesome and my homie whitey did some
stuff with with my famous sequel a
couple of years ago where he's looking
at the external scripting interface that
allows you to run anything that the
scripting interface is set up to do and
by default it's not installed but it's
starting to be a lot more common
especially in like the data science
world they're starting to use R for this
and if the our services thing is
connected to MS sequel if you're a
system in on sequel you can run any kind
of art you want which R is a full
program programming language with access
to the windows API with access to socket
libraries everything you need then pete
PHP myadmin PHP PG admin they're not
they're not exactly code execution this
is the fuzzy part I was talking about
earlier they're not exactly code
execution but they get you sequel
execution and sometimes that's just as
good or better because being able to
read the database is really powerful
sometimes sometimes you find some really
stupid in databases I'm gonna get
emotional if I get into that does
anybody remember dis EC never heard of
dis see seen it was a build tool
intended to allow people to
compiled Gentoo because Jen she was
trash and sorry shots fired
so Jenkins is sort of the evolution of
that idea we have a build server that
allows you to compile stuff and do all
of your like continuous integration
testing all of that in one server and of
course there's a plugin system and
there's a scripting system and the bad
side of the scripting system in jianxing
jenkins is you have to use groovy which
is kind of a terrible language it's like
a dynamically typed Java which is just
the worst of all worlds so that's okay
that's totally fine because Jenkins is a
build server you can just upload make
files and run commands and then I
debated about putting this one in the
slides just just a little just a little
now getting access to Metasploit Pro is
not code execution directly on
Metasploit Pro necessarily but anything
that you've compromised if you've got
meterpreter session sitting in your
medicine pro instance and i can log into
it i can get those two so it's code
execution through authentication to a
thing that does code execution which is
kind of fun so now how screwed am i how
do we defend against this how do we stop
this as defenders the best defense don't
be there don't run services you don't
need turn stuff off if you can keep in
mind that anything that allows a user to
log in and run code is something that
could allow someone else to run code to
and we've been telling the industry this
exact thing for decades still doesn't
happen so I'm not really sure where to
go with that tell it more I guess say it
again
restrict access by putting cats on
keyboards
if you can't if you can't log into it
then you can't run code that's that's
the whole point of that if if the thing
allows you to run code by logging into
it don't let people log into it
and watch pay attention to the logins no
it's fine okay so pay attention to where
people are logging in and not just where
people are failing to log in but where
authentication happens successfully
audit all the logins not just the failed
ones but also the successful ones
because Bob in finance should never be
logging into production servers and
there's two ways you can stop that one
Bob should not have access to the
servers and two Bob shouldn't even
really be able to talk to those servers
you need some segmentation between those
two things Sally and engineering
shouldn't be logging into Finance
systems that she's an engineer she
doesn't need access to payroll seems
like a no-brainer but we have to say it
and no one should ever be logging into a
hundred systems in five seconds if that
happens some shits wrong so conclusions
exploits convert illegitimate access to
legitimate access once you've
compromised something now you're that
user whoever you compromised now you're
that user you can use their
authentication to talk to anything that
they can talk to and now your legitimate
incidentally if you google image search
illegitimate you get a gallery of
bastards through the ages
[Laughter]
and logging in is better than exploiting
bones if you if you compromise something
with an exploit there's all sorts of
ways that you could get caught as a
result of that if you just log in
there's much less risk passwords will
always work I want to reiterate that
being able to log into stuff is never
going away and you don't always need a
show so we talked about getting shells
and popping boxes and compromising
things with passwords but you don't
always need a shell sometimes just
logging in and stealing the data is good
enough PHP myadmin is a perfect example
of that you don't need to be able to
compromise the operating system on which
the database runs if you can read all
the data in the database and that gives
you all the credit cards think about
where you can find this stuff so I give
you a whole bunch of examples these are
some of my favorites
but this is everywhere this is not just
the things I talked about being able to
log in and run code is a standard thing
for many many services and many many
protocols so think about where you can
find this stuff and share with the world
what are your favorites you can find me
on Twitter oh and yeah and this is a
this is Lou Ferrigno throwing a bear it
has nothing to do with my presentation I
just think it's hilarious
because well what I he's throwing a bear
okay thanks to the whole throwing a bear
because we're not so you can plug me on
Twitter I'm at you jump with a seven I
have a new email address you just rip
Black Hills InfoSec comm are there any
questions
oh okay
okay so the question is you've got creds
to a database how do you log into it
what do you use to talk to it so there's
a couple of things I really like Heidi
sequel Rob is a big fan of Nabi cat
there there are both standalone
executables that let you talk to a bunch
of different kinds of databases and the
best part is they tunnel great over SSH
or interpreter port forward anybody else
no more questions well I think we're
just about out of time anyway so thank
you for coming
[Applause]