I am Doug white from Roger Williams
University and security weekly so Paul
asked me to come and talk to you about
some things Roger Williams were the
sponsors of the conference because we
know that everybody's out there
interested I like to talk to people
about how to get into the field because
that's kind of one of my sort of
missions in life because we have forever
been short-handed we need all of you we
actually need you right now if you're
not already in the field I'm presuming
some of you are not already in the field
or you wouldn't you'd be listening to Bo
or whatever but I wanted to try to talk
to you a little bit about how to get
into the field in some of the different
paths people choose because there are
different paths to get there and many of
us have taken weird gnarly paths and
other people have taken very
straightforward paths and some of us are
still trying to figure out what the path
actually is and there's no right answer
I always wish I had a perfect answer for
you and said well you just get this cert
you know it's and you're done and you
can quit and and you'll get to make a
lot of money and you get promoted and
everything will be great and 30 years
later you'll like retire excellent but
that's not how it works and most of us
know that so I thought I would talk a
little bit about this this originally
had some bad language in it so I took it
out and I thought you know let me get
like if this is gonna work yeah there we
go so one of the things I always talk to
people about is skills I mean that's
really the essence of all they're right
I mean it's really about what can you do
because if I'm an employer I don't care
how many letters you put after your name
I don't care how you dress I don't care
what you do I just really care can you
code C can you code Python can you pin
test a bank and if you can do those
things
hell yes you're hired take a badge and
go to the back but unfortunately that's
not as simple as that
because if I ask you right now and I say
can you code C and you want the job what
are you gonna tell me hell yeah
and you hope there's a book about it and
that
you can pick that up because I've been a
consultant for 30 years and consultants
never say no they're just like other sex
worker types we need the money so we
don't say no when you call me and you
say Doug
do you know Python I go yeah absolutely
and then hopefully I can learn it before
I need to start the job and I usually do
we had a few real bad disasters where it
was like oh I said I could do this and
it wasn't or I already know it but you
have to be able to do that too and saws
are able to go out in the marketplace
like like Larry I put a picture Larry up
there and everybody knows Larry and if
Larry shows up at your job interview go
yes you're hired Larry there's no
interview just go ahead we need you
other people like ash maybe you're not
so sure about I mean when ash shows up
with a chainsaw for a hand I might still
hire them because maybe I need a
programmer with a chainsaw for a hand
because that could come in really handy
but at the same time I might not hire
them and the other piece of this is that
good job markets make companies get more
interested in you regardless of how you
look or behave because there's been a
time when I had a consulting client on
so long ago who called me any city's
wanted to talk to me about we can't seem
to hire anyone and it would bring all
these people in for interviews and sack
and an hour InfoSec cybersex stuff and
it was a big company and the guy said
and we offer them jobs and they say
thank you and they leave and they don't
take the jobs and he's like why would
why would that happen and I'm like well
have you ever heard of the fact that
other people are hiring too and I so I
said we'll interview me they said that's
just how we'll do this I said I'm gonna
interview me and I'm gonna come in and
I'm gonna do your whole interview
process and so I did it I was there five
minutes if I wouldn't work here if you
paid me a million dollar million dollars
I wouldn't work here for what are you
guys paying and the guy said well we
have an awesome benefits package which
is usually a bad thing when they start
with that when they lead with the
awesome benefits package they using me
the salary really really sucks because
they're trying to say like we have a
really awesome benefits package and
everyone just loves working here really
but what do you pay like what am I going
to put
pocket and the guy said well we have
really kicked those salaries up into the
45k range at entry level yeah I was like
you understand most these entry though
if you were getting like 70 and the guys
like really Savin me that's outrageous
you know and you get that that sort of
disdain that you get from like corporate
executives you make you know six hundred
thousand dollars a year with a million
dollar bonus and they're going nuts just
an outrage and you know yeah and then
there's that whole dress code thing so
the other thing they had was a dress
code so I was looking at my evaluations
because I was pretending to be an
entry-level point I was looking at my
valuation of the interviewers and the
very first thing they wrote was not
dressed properly I'm not kidding you
that's what this person wrote he didn't
write pretty good C programmer awesome
Network guy you know they wrote not
dressed properly and they might say
beard oh and I was just like really like
you cared how I was dressed well like
but I'm not gonna deal with customers
I'm gonna be back here in this pit and
they're like well yes a customer sought
you where would the customer see me I'm
back there in the pit
you could put chicken wire around my
desk oh but don't ever get near me you
can tell them I'm rabid it's fine
I'll be like the network the crew
working at Network Korea chicken wire
enclosure in the basement they're like
okay don't do it too close we just throw
some beanie weenies in there every now
and then it seems to keep them contained
so you have to be careful and all those
things become problematic I can go
forward there we go
the good thing about all this is right
now the job market is such that you can
kind of pick and choose and even
companies like that that these stodgy
financial type companies are starting to
realize if they want you they're gonna
have to change their game somewhat
government's realizing that there was
this whole big thing recently where you
know the FBI was having trouble hiring
because they have all these different
standards we had a state police problem
because the state police want to hire
you to work in computer crimes
because you know the people they had in
computer crimes originally were like
police officers you want a bar fight
broken up we're there but when somebody
goes well this guy like you know he like
broken through like port 60p they're
going what wait what he broke in you got
a film of that you know they don't know
what they're talking about and it became
a problem so today all those people are
trying to change those rules because
they want to be able to hire you so we
still have to get back to the sort of
purpose of this what do you do how do
you get into the field and it can be
tricky depending on where you sit and
some of us are fortunate and we have
letters after our name that people
recognize not just letters we made up
although there's probably some of those
too and that might work I'm just gonna
put some stuff there and see if they
check
I actually fired two people in the world
by audit that I caught with fake fake
credentials I will tiger straws it's a
side story I caught this guy
okay I see if you catch it this is sort
of those little audit things pen test
things I caught this guy because he had
a diploma from Harvard on his wall like
Wow diploma from Harvard that's cool and
I thought that diploma is written in
what language it's from Harvard
his diplomas written in English but a
diploma from Harvard is written in Latin
and I said it's unusual that you have a
Harvard diploma written in English and
he said oh yeah
see they had an option and he said you
know you could get it in lynnie language
you want and I said oh do they do them
in French and German and things now -
and he's like yeah I'm sure you could
get them in any language you want it was
like interesting so then we immediately
back him background check the guy and
guess what we found out I called Harvard
they never heard of him so here's his
Harvard degree that said Master of
Science in marketing Harvard University
when I call Harvard they said yeah he
did take a three-day course here called
leadership in the world and I went back
and asked the guy and he's like oh well
yeah I mean that's kind of like a
master's degree it was like I'm dancing
as fast as I can
you know it's like come on so there's
three places you can go or all three or
none of the three or whatever to get
into the field skills training education
so let's talk a little bit about skills
are great I love them I love you to have
skills and I want you to prove them to
me and therein lies the problem you went
out you spent years coding in the
basement you have coded thousands of
apps you've done this you've done that
you've defaced this you've defaced that
you're nothing illegal of course and
what happens is you come to the
interview and you can't prove it and I
want to talk a little bit about how to
prove it but here's some of the skills
that you ought to really have coding I
love to see coding skills so I do a lot
of interviews for companies they hire me
because they don't have anybody they
feel like can actually talk to you guys
and they want somebody that can ask you
the right question like one of the
questions I ask in every interview I do
is what's your favorite programming
language and you'd be surprised how many
people that are interviewing for SEC
jobs say hello yeah um not really much
of a programmer like well yeah I didn't
ask you what your best language was is
it what's your favorite like you know
pick one and I've had people go well you
know you don't you don't have a favorite
programming language like damn
and then I asked him what's your
favorite port a tcp/ip that's the sex
the second question asking the interview
and again I have people that go port a
you mean like the Port of New Jersey the
Port Authority well I don't understand
I'm like oh you're gonna do so well but
then I get somebody that goes well I
like you know port 23 right we all like
torque 23 port 25
all those good ports that we can take
advantage of 443 139 and stuff that I
like to see and when I hear those kind
of answers I don't really care what the
answer is it sticks at what flavor of
ice cream question they used to ask at
Google you know and my answer was always
I'm lactose intolerant why do you ask
I'm not really but it's just fun to turn
it around I didn't get the job either
they sent me straight down to the smart
ass Department for I got I've shown the
exit door but I like Python see that's
my thing you may like Java JavaScript
but you need something you know you got
ahead of it kind in your toolkit you
have to be expert at it but if you want
to work in an InfoSec you really have to
have you've been here you've been seeing
that right you're seeing people that are
coding and decoding in different
languages and doesn't mean you have to
have any given one but you've got to
have something and you have to be able
to sit down and say yes I can code
something I'm not a master of it but I
can code something so you need that and
pick one I don't care
pick two and learn it how you learn it
go to some free resource and learn it be
that person that's who I want to hire to
I want to hire the person when I say how
did you learn see they they go well you
know I picked the project and I wrote it
then I sold it to Microsoft and you know
I'm well okay you're hired you know I
don't want the person that says well you
know I'm hoping that the company will
send me to some training yeah we're not
gonna do that thank you
networking obviously I'm not even going
to mention that it'd be beneath you but
you need to know it right
I built a program at Roger Williams we
built it around networking because we
felt that was a more critical aspect of
cybersecurity because it's what our
employers told us it was because I went
on and talked to the employers and they
said they got to know networking and
again though
the questions you can ask you want to
add all these cybersex skills awesome
the more of them you have in your
backpack the better you are the broader
you are then I'm talking about
entry-level I know some of your like
specialists and if you want to be a
specialist than be a specialist but at
the entry level that broader bag of
tricks means you are much more capable
of getting a variety of jobs and then
pushing into that depth later as you get
started so you say I wanna get in the
field I really want to be a pen tester
because I heard that with the coolest
thing out there even if you do get
tasered sometimes and only twice it does
suck worse than it actually looks but
you know get that broad bag of tricks
because it gives you that it gives you
that appeal to that employer and we'll
talk in a minute about how to dot
document and you can get all this just
by doing it it's how most of us got it I
mean when I went to school know this
stuff existed literally I had a student
not so long ago said we're a dog where
did where did you learn Ruby because I
was - I was teaching Ruby on Rails to
some people and I was like oh yeah all
right I learned it cuz I did it I didn't
get that in PhD school and my
undergraduate program they taught Pascal
and Fortran so none of which exists
anymore really but yeah I see people
going yeah those are great languages but
they're gone sorry I mean yeah I know
they're still out there and you can beat
that dead horse if you really really
want to but you're gonna have to figure
out how you can do this stuff legally
and how you can prove it to me or then
you end up being a free employee and
like I said musicians do that was a
musician and and you know I I donated a
lot of blood because you know you need
gas money so you can either get enough
at the show or you can head down to the
plasma Center and sit there for three
hours and they such the father of you
and yeah it's not good here's some free
stuff if you just wanted to be skills
you to me they have free classes are
they the best class in the whole world
no probably not
but are they free yes and free is good
because as you'll see we get in these
other things
it all starts costing money so we're
still at a free point now podcast
self-serving plugs watch podcast see
what their talk
a ballot I mean I love to watch security
weekly because I hear people talking
about stuff and I go ha I don't know
that and I go try to figure it out or I
go wow that's I don't want to know that
but I can go try to learn and watching
things and getting in the community like
you're doing something very proud of you
because you're here you're meeting
people it's always great to meet people
that are better I love it because I'm
the weakest person there and that's
awesome you got to get over yourself
sometimes but it's much better to be
surrounded with really smart people that
know more than you do
because one they'll make you look good
and two you can learn all kinds of
things instead of being like yeah I know
everything dude
and we interview people like that too
I've interviewed fueling I'm just like
so one of my other interview questions
tell me something you don't know and I
feel good go ahead I don't know what
that would be like really let me get you
this calculus problem here bring that
back in a few minutes
a lot of different a lot of different
pucks some of the like IT Pro TVs cheap
one it's not free but it's it's it's
definitely a bargain if you in fact if
you go on security we can get a discount
code don't tell me I told you that but
you can't gns3 as a network tool that's
free you can simulate massive crazy
networks and learn networking skills and
practice just your basic skills this is
like working out right you want to be a
boxer you have to train you can't just
say gee yeah okay whatever you got to
practice and you got to be good and that
way when people talk to you you can talk
to them and that's what will give you
that job
cyber re obviously a great thing to be
involved with is that dot-com or Jeff
dot IT I apologize I put on there wrong
so Jeff Beck there so cyber is an
awesome resource if you've not checked
come by our booth that I'll give you a
sticker so and you can check out cyber
and you can you can start picking these
up curious stuff radar page another
thing you can throw up on your screen if
you don't already put you know put it on
your spare screen it's just what I said
on my upper right monitors radar page it
runs all day long and I just glanced at
it sometimes you know I'm like I look up
and I go oh wow what's that then I get
distracted Oh hon can I forget what I
was doing but that's okay I learned
something at the same time or you can
get trained
yeah training is the great greedy I know
there's some training people here so
training is the great greedy thing you
love it oh it's so good
it's quick it's a little painful but
it's like oh it's done I should do in
ten I was a instructor for intense
school I taught CISSP s he's back there
is B squared haunting me keep an eye on
me make sure I was saying them in the
IFC squared is great I use teach cissp
GCC an ACC training all this thing one
week five days you're gonna suffer the
torment of the Damned but by God at the
end it had five days they'll give you a
little set of letters you can put after
your name and you can go home and go yes
and does it work it does and I know some
people here especially this contra
contemptuous of some of that stuff they
say oh you got some letters in a week
you don't know a damn thing and they may
you may be right
but at the same time you can put these
letters after your name without spending
all that money because you can just go
take the test I mean you don't have to
come pay me at intense school a whole
pile of money I don't work for them
anymore but you could just take the test
I don't know of any certs some of them
do require you to demonstrate some kind
of training but you can say you self
studied you know take the CC you can
just write it down and why so studied
okay take the test if you pass your CCE
you can do digital forensics and that
literally is all it takes sometimes it
can get you the job and I will tell you
another thing about training you may
have to do it because now when you look
because the industry started to mature
you look at the entry-level and guess
what you're gonna see this required that
required this required that required and
that gets trickier because now you say I
have to have this I have to have an A+
and you may sit there go A+ come on
seriously Doug I don't think that much
of it either but guests hope they're not
here but guess what if that job says you
have to have it what's going to happen
when you try to apply for and you don't
it's not to be me looking at your resume
it's going
be some drone who goes down a little
checklist and goes a plus No okay um SS
plus no they don't have any of the
requirements projected no matter how
good you are so sometime you're gonna
have to figure out a way to prove to me
that you can do it we'll talk a little
bit about that too
and then there's college I mean college
is cool right and everybody likes
college I was like I liked it it was fun
I loved computer science I wasn't so
keen on Greek yeah that's the first line
of a Iliad if you didn't if you don't
just happen to read Greek but I mean
college is a blast and it's fun and you
get to go party and have a good time and
you might meet somebody and you might
even learn something but then there's
that college isn't cheap I mean you can
do there's cheap pads like you know it's
talked a little bit about the end but
college is expensive and it's expensive
and more ways than just cash right
it takes time because one of the big
problems a lot of people and InfoSec
have is they don't have bachelor's
degrees and I meet more and more people
like that and bachelor's degrees are
murderous how many credits you have to
have to get a bachelor's degree 120 120
credits so with three credit courses
that's forty courses most people you
guys are smarter than most people so you
might get take six courses a semester
welcome to the rest of your life I mean
if you're a part-time student that takes
a long long time there's a thirst ways
around it but it still takes a lot of
time but college is an awfully cool
option if you can do it and it ends up
being a stumbling block at the end I'm
going to talk about some perils of all
this when one of the perils of all this
is that you don't go to college and I
get that a lot I get a lot I work with
CyberPatriot so I get a lot high school
students go man I'm good at this and I
go get a job I'm like yeah you can but
get a job they pay your tuition and then
you can go to college while you're
working and yet it'll take you eight
years but you're working and instead of
you paying all that money you're getting
paid and you're you know and they're
paying your tuition so that's one of
those things you can't do I mean if some
of us are older and it may not be that
big of an option
for you but at the same time there are
solutions you can pursue and if you
don't do it it's a and we can argue all
day long about whether it's worthwhile
or not and you see everybody argues all
the time and there's wall street journal
articles and there's there's Washington
Post articles about his college worth it
but the truth is in most professions
professionally I don't know what history
majors do all my friends who were
history majors and I'm not making this
up all my friends who are history majors
went to federal prison for selling drugs
now they were damn good at selling drugs
until they get caught they made millions
and millions and millions of dollars
until my old roommate ratted out
everybody he got caught with eight
hundred thousand dollars as a speeding
trap yeah was ridiculous I would have
told him never to trust him with money
but they did anyway and they all went to
prison but professionals like you guys
at some point in your career you stopped
wanting to be in the chicken wire cage
maybe some people don't some people are
cooler than chicken or our cage forever
I'm actually pretty good with it
personally I'm not that big of a people
person I can't like you know the chicken
wire cage
no customers don't come down here we
don't let them in the basement good when
I ran the programming shop at the bank
we could see people but it was through
eight glass walls so we could see them
off in the distance kind of moving you
know like hurting and flocking or
whatever they do look see there's
somebody moving away over there but they
couldn't get to us and when I was a sis
op undergrad oh it was awesome because
the mainframe is that almost awesomest
amount of power you'll ever have in your
life cuz I completely controlled it I
don't like you your note is dead you
couldn't use that local crap your note
came up and it was like the and I had
this little frosted glass window and
people would foolishly not gonna despite
the fact there was a science that do not
knock on window you know you just
knocked on my window come back in three
hours it was great cut me off in the
parking lot yeah the windows never
opening for you again have a nice day
but College I don't know when we have to
talk about a little bit
I have to wake up my mouse come on wake
up I'm not gonna wake up now okay we'll
do this the old-fashioned way
or maybe we're locked up so there's
really three things you can do then what
I call the Barenaked path go crazy hack
naked I don't got nothing I'm gonna come
to the interview and I'm gonna sell it
to you cool if you can do it
you know I sit down and then I came and
I've seen this done I sat down and I
brought you know my credentials my
portfolio and if you can do that that's
cool I hear stuff I wrote she was apps I
sold here's things I did for people and
I somehow documented that it's tough to
do especially the further up corporate
you go you get startup she got a little
more opportunity because they're kind of
desperate you get into corporate it's
tough because they got their rules and
their regs and and some HR purses look
anyway he brought a whole bunch of paper
and some like tapes and things in this
life uh-huh yeah the other one clothing
optional that's not a bad path really
clothing optional means you know put a
few letters after your name
and I'll tell you how which ones to put
in a minute I really will or I'll at
least tell you how to figure out which
was to put so put a few letters after
your name and you can do it you don't
have to invest thousands and thousands
of dollars and years and years and of
your life you can go out and you can
identify these things you can use free
resources you can self-study and you can
pass that thing and put a couple of
letters after your name you can do it I
promise you if you're here you're smart
enough to do it I mean if you're out you
know laying in the alley or something it
might be a little more challenging but
you're here so you took time out of your
day or whatever to come to these
presentations and then the last one well
I mean obviously the last one's pretty
good I mean you know you the more
letters you know you put letters after
your name it's a good thing and you put
all kinds of stuff you put Bachelor of
Science in computer science Bachelor of
Science and cybersecurity
Bachelor of Science and networking
electrical engineering even business it
doesn't matter
you put that after your name if you'll
go okay you have a bachelor's degree
checkmark or maybe you actually learn
something double check
mark you know history well I'm least I
know where to buy weed but at least you
could put those check marks on there and
it's gonna work I think my mouse must
have run out of juice so what should you
do this is my plan go job words go to
monster go to dice whatever you like I
don't care
find the job that you want maybe now
you're not necessarily qualified but
find the one that you want now play it's
like a game find something cool Wow look
at that
that's awesome and look at what it tells
you you must have well whatever level
you're on this is how I strategize this
what do I have to have to get that job
so that's sort of my first step if the
job says you must have royal blood from
the Vlad the Impaler family to apply for
this job
you probably don't qualify and you go
but could i I don't know you have to ask
yourself that because then people do
kind of shoot a high sometimes you know
they start saying well yeah I could get
the OS CP in the CCNA and and a PhD in
at what year too and that's kind of
stupid because you just waste a bunch of
time that way look at stuff that's
realistic that's just a little above
your level and say can I get that job
and say like six months to a year and
what would I need to do to do that what
certain do I need because it says you
must have an A+ like oh god a plus
really go get it then because when my
students tell me oh it's so lame like
then it should be easy just go get it
it'll take you what no study time to
pass then just go pass it yeah it's late
I don't care or maybe it's not so lame
maybe it says you have to vote CP unless
he pees hard down tough maybe it says I
said my favorite OS CP or C eh we did a
show about that and voice if you all got
really upset with me because I said
get the one that works and like see eh
yeah okay that's what grab a book we'll
be ready to go
Oh SCP not so easy I'm like and then
they tweak this whole argument erupted
about which one's better and I was like
I'm not arguing about which one's better
I'm like I'm talking about which one do
you need worry about the cool stuff when
somebody else is paying the bills that's
been my like life philosophy you know as
if somebody else is paying great go get
a no SCP let the company shell out for
training and you can go to training you
go to sand
I mean Sands is cool everybody been to
sands or in the sands class yes this
bunch of people is cool right I used to
go to Sands and then you know my company
is like oh wow that was expensive it's
awesome no I mean I get somebody sends
me to Sands I'm always like I'll go yeah
I'll take that and cycle send that class
it'd be awesome
they get great instructors and all that
kind of stuff so Sands is really really
cool but it costs money so if you just
need a ceh and it says ceh or OS CP
don't get carried away oh if you could
do the osep cool do it but if you can't
are you gonna have to go spend 10 grand
to get it maybe just get to see Aichi
then there's a check mark and you can
apply for that job it says a plus and
see eh got it now if it says bachelor's
degree
well what try to talk about the moment
but you've got to figure out a way to do
that if you have to get to degree then I
don't know I mean that's a tougher
question to answer because it may take
you some time but I will talk a little
bit about that and apply for the job you
know don't don't don't not do that that
would be kind of silly how do you get in
the door well hey take some social
engineering that's that's one way no
don't I'm gonna talk about illegal stuff
HR can be restrictive if you don't have
a degree they say you don't have it you
don't have it and this is where I want
to talk a minute about portfolios so the
idea that you try to put this stuff
together document what you do in your
life this is one of the great
shortcomings in InfoSec people don't
document what they do they're proud of
it but they don't document it you need
to think about all this cool stuff
you're doing you're here this car
Fritzing you're break-in that c-3po Wow
it's cool you're breaking an IOT thing
you're breaking the SDR thing you're
breaking that thing in this thing over
there document that stuff it doesn't
have to be some kind of fancy piece of
parchment document it put in a file
somehow video yourself talking about it
and telling what you did and collect all
that stuff and you can take that to
these people and find it but you're not
going to take it to HR because guess
what HR is going to do with it I'm sorry
we don't accept it like what is this a
lot of application form please so how do
you get it to people you're already
doing it you're here you go to these
cons and guess what happens you know
people you keep going if you go to this
you go to this con you go to Vegas to go
to Def Con you go to Connecticut and go
to b-sides you can see some sense so
other people sitting here I've seen you
know not just in the Dakotas and you
start meeting so you need to meet people
and have them meet you talk to these
vendors because all those vendors out
there are people that are in in this
industry I was just really I was having
such a good time I was talking to is
c-squared earlier and they said do you
know we were just talking the other day
to Congressman Jim Langevin he's the
chair of the cyber caucus and I said oh
yeah he did my thing on Saturday last
week small community so get to know
people and impress them and that way
when you're applying for the job you may
walk in and the person sitting there is
him he's the guy interviewing here it's
me and you already know what I'm gonna
ask you right what's the first question
giving me my mouth what's your favorite
programming language and you'll be ready
you guys talk hey you were that guy that
barked on me right that's okay you're a
really good coder but document that
stuff find a way even if you've got all
these other things after your name find
a way to contain that and put it
somewhere that you can reproduce it when
somebody wants to see it because that
can sell me on it if you could get past
HR and there's a way around it that
doesn't involve any kind of elaborate
social engineering and wearing disguises
it's just simply going I know somebody
who works at that company I met them at
a con I've got them in my list of names
I'm gonna call him up or I'm gonna hit
them up on Instagram or on Twitter and
say hey Doug I saw you work for Paul's
security weekly - I was hoping to get
this programming job remember me I'm the
guy that barked on you at Def Con oh
yeah you owe me a shirt but that just
got you past those guys every single
time I guarantee it will work because
that kind of networking will sell
everybody on you and it works so well
because in these kind of small
communities of experts
everybody knows everybody pretty much
and if nobody knows you because you've
never been out of the dark and you never
went to a con and met people or you
didn't do slide roulette
then nobody knows you and that that's
cool too that will work oops advanced
you can you can go back to HR and come
in that door - nothing wrong with that
you just now you got to have all your
check boxes so I don't change I guess it
knew I was talking about this so try to
go I know these things cost money and
they take time but go to you can go to
cheap ones like this you don't have to
go to Def Con I mean Def Con is cool but
it's expensive but look at this this
thing's cheap right it's a cheap place
cheap registration and they had all the
bigshot people here anyway I mean Dave
Kennedy was over there it wasn't like
you were having to listen to me oh wait
see you messed up but you're meeting
people you're making friends and that
gonna pay off big now what is it doing
you really need to work a little bit on
this I interview a lot of people yeah
and one of the problems I see a lie and
it will get you cut fast is lack of
attention to detail I promise if you
can't spell things I literally
interviewed someone once who had
misspelled their name repeatedly on
their resume I was like your name you
put on this form is different than your
resume and if it's like oh yeah how
about that I was like yeah thanks for
thanks for coming in yes sir oh you wave
it okay he's waving me down that's good
that's good so think about to get cards
this is another thing I would teach my
daughter might get cards maybe they
don't have same fancy on them get cards
may say Doug white C programmer
interested in a job here's a nice car
I'm gonna hand you cuz then you got my
stuff and I know it's old-fashioned my
daughter's like it's old-fashioned I was
like it's it is but it works that's why
it keeps happening cuz get collect cards
you can scan them in and make getting
the elaborate databases out of them you
just show me that in the interview look
what I built you can have a copy cool
certs I put them on the screen these are
mostly entry-level certs none of these
shirts are going to steer you wrong if
you go to monster.com or dice comm and
look at all these search you will see
them and I'm not gonna argue about their
quality or their lack thereof I'm gonna
say that these are certs that are common
they are out there and you need to look
at and I didn't mention cissp because
that's a little more advanced than
entry-level that's a great cert - I have
one I keep it I keep it up because it's
valuable it's it requires some work
experience so it's trying to talk to
entry-level but find the search you need
don't get searched you don't need does
that cost money and you got to maintain
them so get the ones you want look at
monster calm or diced up or whatever you
like make a list and then check the
prices what will this cost me to get and
you can price it not just in dollars but
in time you say I can get this eight
plus certain a week self-study cost me
whatever to cost 300 bucks good
it's gonna take me six months of study
to get this master's degree heard a year
and it's gonna cost $40,000 it might not
be my best option so maybe I need to
revise what I'm looking for or maybe I
need to go get the master's degree you
pick or find a company to work for that
will pay for your master's degree that's
a good idea I like it I hate paying for
stuff college there's all kinds of
options one option so shits degrees a
lot of states now have Community College
degree plan in cyber they often have
very good ones but research and see if
they're teaching what you need to know
don't just sign up look at that course
catalog and say am i learning Cisco and
I'm learning cyber security I'm learning
stuff they say I'm learning or I might
just really take it a bunch of computer
science courses in Fortran programming
that have been renamed cyber security
through Fortran programming because they
do that so look carefully but
associate's degrees a lot of states
that's free so you can go to your school
for free and get an associate's degree
that will set you up so when you get a
job they can pay your tuition you can
finish that to a four years degree a lot
of schools will do that for you they
have articulation agreements between
those schools so you can transfer your
credits all that kind of stuff but just
just study you guys are smart so you
could study this stuff and figure out
what you need to do and you have friends
in the industry so you can ask questions
I have people literally write me
questions that watch secure digital life
and say Doug can you explain one
associate's degree as I had that a
couple weeks ago I didn't put it on the
show but I answered your question so
when you have this kind of questions you
got friends that you know from these
shows and people answer bachelor's
degrees 120 credits master's degrees
usually one or two years 30 60 credits
dot PhD yeah good luck and not that you
can't do it but it takes a lot of time
all you can do it it's just another game
it's just like hacking it's just like
figure out what the rules are
break them as much as you can without
getting in trouble and then achieve the
goal same problem different outcomes all
works online degrees be careful because
there are disreputable ones and there's
good ones call me we have a good one
you'll be fine
I keep opening that perils real quickly
cuz on around at a time lack of
credentials that's one of your big
perils can't prove it nobody knows what
you got nobody knows you okay good luck
you're gonna be tough too many
credentials that can hurt you you have
too much stuff people are looking at you
as an employee they go wow this guy he's
like either a cert collector dilettante
or somebody's gonna cost us a fortune to
maintain or they're overqualified for
the job and they're gonna stay here for
three months and quit so be careful now
that I mean you don't have to put
everything on your resume either you can
leave certs out I do it all the time
like when I apply for consulting jobs I
don't put PhD on my name because PhDs
are a bunch of idiots I put CISSP or
CCNA I put those things on my resume so
think about it a little bit
don't don't oversell yourself either get
the search you need to keep them if you
need two degrees you're just gonna have
to get them folks suck it up and do it
I'm sorry that's the but find the best
path you're hackers not only I'm not
saying to cheat I'm saying find the best
path that's what hacking really is it's
not about being illegal or doing bad
things it's about finding the best path
to the goal so figure that one out and
you'll do well they're gonna come kick
me out and say I have even more perils
and even more perils after that so but
check this out we already talked about
it I'm gonna skip that finally you gotta
like it okay so that's the last one and
I'll shut up because these people are
gonna come in and they're there as soon
as they overwhelm us by force will be
reversed to be taken out look if you
don't like this move on I hate to tell
you if you're here going I hope owe me
big money I really hate it and that's
why I asked that question so I'm gonna
come back to that my last thing and I'll
shut up what's your favorite programming
language when you say well I hope I
don't have to take too much of that then
I'm going you don't like this you just
here for some other reason it doesn't it
be programming he's now working or
whatever it is you like but you gotta
like something if you're just doing it
for the money it's gonna suck and you'll
be miserable go be a history major and
sell drugs I mean you know I could work
out for you well I don't do that really
thank you so much for coming if you have
questions just hit me up I'm gonna be in
the ballroom all day at down on the end
so if you want come ask me
question about this I'll do that then
because I know we're gonna run a time
and I think they've reached an
overwhelming number now unless anybody
has like a Taser then we can fight our
way yeah
I'm just kidding thank you so much
[Applause]