[Music]
so we're doing this thing who has had a
good time so far wild les a confessed
who's had trouble with the Wi-Fi who's a
t-mobile customers you have for
service energy yes enjoy it it's my it's
my thought that John's actual plan was
just to bring us all here the most elite
friends who travel the world and have no
service in a place like this so we have
to use an open Wi-Fi network just ponen
us all as we speak so yeah many of us
have fun gigs though many of us have
really fun jobs people come up to me a
lot and they say oh my gosh deviant you
know physical security and breaking it
and that's your job is so cool I like it
and yes I get it right like being the
break-in guy is fun if you've never met
me that I run a covert entry team Robert
Babak and our crew hooligans in places
we shouldn't be but the funny thing
people kind of romanticize this notion
like yes our ops division does very
dynamic door kicker stuff but for this
one scene here this was a photo shoot
when an article came out about what we
do they were like oh yeah get some pics
and get some pics in your hands right
and so like I'm here picking a door now
everyone has said to me I'm known as
this lock picker and like maybe I've
taught some of you about lock picking if
you've ever seen like any of these
animations that tool has on all of our
slides like you've ever learned how a
lock works you saw their little pins and
they they bind but they push up with a
key and if I don't have a key like how
do I get in the lock like I've taught
about lock picking forever
and everyone thinks of me is this lock
picker and they say oh yes so like I'd
love to have that job man
like that's you know you at a door at
2:00 in the morning with those picks out
I wish I could do that and get paid
which again like sure that's fun and I
have picked locks to get into secured
spaces but this here manipulating
the pin is with like pick tools it's
something like the ninth thing on the
list of stuff we try to get into
buildings and this whole talk is not
this is like the last lock picking slide
in the talk because this is not a lock
picking talk
I am I know hurry is what I say cuz I'm
so tired
hey you ready I'm so tired of talking
about lock-picking I look like I love
when someone new is learning it right
and if someone's never done this and
they get it and it's this wow moment
that's fun but I gotta stop this
illusion that we are picking a lot like
how many times do you pick a door you
don't daddy like yeah Vince and you
like you don't really pick doors this
this is great that's not what we do
so let's talk about how physical pen
testers actually get into buildings how
real covert entry tends to work and how
you fix almost all of it dumb right
like right off the bat I have not dive
legit knocked hinge pins out of doors
you just bang the hinge pin out walk the
door I don't care how many locks are on
the door if you can walk that door away
from the frame walk in this is a thing
that you can do with like a nail or a
nice little orange tool so you don't
bust up your fingers but again like all
these locks on the door what you don't
see your hinges hinges are on the
outside of this door this is an absolute
method that gets you into places and
stupid easy to fix I'm giving you like
easy ones off the bat here this is a
security hinge the door swings shut
little peg goes in a little hole it
doesn't matter if you bang the hinge
pins out you can trench that away from
the door frame because the peg is in the
hole like literally it puts it puts a
block from that attack if you don't want
to buy new hinges and rehang all your
doors I'm huge into recommending what
are called jamb pins I don't sell any of
this stuff like I know some of the firms
that make it but like brilliant idea
what are Jam pins you have a
conventional hinge take out these two
screws replace them with jam pins take
out these two screws replace them with
fuck-all you just made a security hinge
and you didn't rehang your door like two
dollars I think brilliant kind of
solutions
easy easy stuff slipping latches and
such like people see me like oh he's
taking a tool out of his pocket he's
gonna open that door what's he doing I'm
not taking pics out of my pocket most of
the time I am too if sound by the way oh
no sound we're gonna need sound who's my
sound guy back there
let's see anybody you here all right oh
well I don't know why we're not getting
sound but yelled the guy in the back
he's not doing anything so yeah like
this is a completely locked door this is
a water treatment facility this is the
room where they chlorinate and prep the
water for the supply and I'm not picking
the lock I'm just attacking it with a
little latch slipping tool you should
not be able to do this on most systems
right here's the door there we go is
there some sound can anyone in the back
turn the sound the up please
there's a remote oh wow this is like
dad's living room but way too many
buttons is that a thing is that
happening I don't know whatever all
right I don't care I'm gonna keep going
but yeah like this little tool this
little stupid hook that we've been
selling in our student kits we give them
to you you give them to students it's
like a $5 part and it gets through so
many doors what we're doing here it's
not that you can like reach the latch
here's a latch you can't reach with a
hook because it's got that big plate
over it right get yourself a big piece
of wire oops the problem is not that you
can touch or can't touch the latch the
problem in all these bits of footage
here is that the latch is not installed
properly latches in a modern environment
should be what are called dead latches
in fact this is a picture of a dead
latch well let's talk about what is it
dead latch what is not well this is the
latch right this is what goes into the
strike plate holds the door shut if you
lean on the door the door does not pop
open
you might remember doors that only ever
have this this is what a door used to
look like long time ago and then all of
a sudden you started getting this extra
little button sometimes called a guard
bolt sometimes called the dead latch
plunger has a lot of names but that
extra button that I will highlight in
red here that indicates that you have a
dead latch mechanism the dead latch
plunger or the guard bolt many people
only see it when the door is open and
that you know it's not always in this
configuration sometimes it's next to the
latch it's there's a lot of styles no
matter what style you have you might not
know when the door shuts
that's supposed to be held back it's
supposed to be pressed back into the
door by the strength plate it's not
supposed to pop out into the hole if
that is pressed back that latch is now
dead
you can't hook it slip it shim it
anything like that that's how this is
supposed to work but the problem is door
fitment if you don't have the right
hardware mounting you don't have the
door hung properly we see this all the
time on doors man this we've got a nice
door properly locked okay that's a piece
of trash literally a piece of plastic
garbage shoved in boom server room look
at the size of that strike plate hole
you could drive a truck into that why is
it so huge is this the strike plate that
came with this handle set what do you
think this is yes I heard it say it
louder
electronic strike play this is a card
reader access door so they retrofit the
additional like the original plate of
strike plate they put like a separate
units a solenoid powered strike and
there's all different configurations of
this kind of hardware we literally know
integrators and installers who are like
Oh make sure you always get like the JP
41 that's the one with a big hole it
always works no matter what door the
client has it's no problem
no that is not how this is supposed to
work you are really undermining your
security another door another water
facility right nice lock I mean I'm I'm
a decent-enough picker I'm not gonna try
to pick this why not because boom bad
door fitment over and over and over and
like you know you don't want me in there
I don't belong in this room $5.00 hook
gets me in when a nice lock could have
prevented me if they had properly set
the door up let's talk about this kind
of door fitment problem you got crash
bars let's just reach through you've
told stories like this forever what
happened there I was like talking to
point at Johnny right let's watch that
again crash bar let's get a bent rod and
just slip it through and bam hit the
door right absolutely works the why
because weather stripping is not a
security device weather stripping is not
the same thing as a plate or even a
movable astragal of metal if that is
just rubber or that
brush material if I can slip something
through and smack on that crash bar they
make specially designed tools just for
this here's Robert when our guys on our
team reaching through with a reinforced
tool hitting the crash bar BAM
exit paddles smaller target how many
times like you see glass door glass
doors are wonderful because you can see
exactly what you're hitting or not
hitting but going back you can barely
see it's a really dark photo you can't
see it here easily you can't see it in
the video though sometimes is this
daytime or nighttime this what is it
it's not it's like 3:00 in the morning I
know it's a little bit white out here
but it's it's very dark out this is a
low occupancy structure at night what
could they have done and not violated
code they could have set the deadbolt
it's right there right well this
tool there's a tool it exists for this
the idea of a deadbolt again for code
many of these attacks as you all know
like fire code and actually egress like
restrictions and allowances you have to
set up doors certain ways if you have a
deadbolt it probably has a thumb turn on
the inside this tool exists I have it in
my room this is a phone turn flipper you
stick it through the door and you go
broop absolutely that like these tools
are out there man they are not expensive
and again like here we have a nice this
is a classic California office building
why because it has frameless glass doors
oh my god California where the weather
is so nice you don't care about
insulation frameless glass doors
everywhere so yes
reach through with the tool the hardest
part was just getting it to stop
slipping off the knob was so tiny but
eventually sure enough you get it on
there you twit it's just like a braided
cable attached to it's not a
sophisticated tool right
but eventually BAM that's open post
office near where I live you can see
like right on the other side of the door
I'm not gonna go steal a bunch of mail
or anything but the gap is huge you
could get through there Tesla dealership
of course it's California why because
frameless glass doors that's why middle
of the night no one around I'm not
saying I wanted to duplicate Tiger team
and like steal a car but absolutely like
frameless glass
stores boom thumb turns that's the only
thing preventing anyone from getting in
here and the gap is like a half inch
wide talk about another gap problem
here's a lock door there's some noise
and then dr. Tran comes through like
ninja and a cloud of smoke what happened
there many of you know this one already
I hope this is a lab where we do a lot
of prototyping and we just show it like
Babak and the Hat just showed Ross and
Ross is like hey building owner Evan
come here I want to show you this thing
I just learned so you'll see he's trying
to do something with a tool up in the
time Babak says no reposition it a
little bit out here and look through the
glass you'll see the same thing you'll
see this sort of cloud of vapor and all
of a sudden this lock door is no longer
locked yay well who knows what
government there's a very restricted
government tool that they're using I
don't know if you can get it like talk
to someone you know who's kind of spooky
you can find out how to order this it
comes with a one-page idiot-proof
government instruction manual that says
hold tool like this so all you're doing
if you invert one of these spray dusters
you're boiling off that r134a
essentially is what's in there and
you're creating this cold gas cloud
what's actually tripping many doors have
sensors on the inside especially
electronic lock doors they are called
requests to exit sensor if you have a
system where you badge in but you don't
have to badge out you just walk to the
door and just open it
you might not realize you have a request
to exit sensor you have most of the time
a simple passive thermal sensor it's not
the only technology out there it's far
and away the most common one and if you
can get that sensor to trip in this case
just by blowing a cloud of gas through
the door the door unlocks these are old
tricks you should know them Dave if you
saw his keynote this morning dave did
he's a big you know vape guy is a big
ecig guy oh yes so he and Ben Tenn
recorded this is one of the best videos
ever of it so like I don't know if you
sub ohm your coils or something because
he makes this amazing cloud through
there but he's just listening to hear
that solenoid he's listening to hear it
trigger and when he knows that
electromagnet is done BAM door's
unlocked
boom now unlocked yeah Chris up here I
think it was like hey Dave you should
try this on that door this is totally at
we don't we don't where we eat
right yeah this is this this was the
dirty Derby class yeah yeah and like I
think eventually people other people
kept trying it until the point where
there was staff in that because like a
staff area and staff was like what's the
smoke coming through the door they went
freaking out I don't smoke I do drink
too much my wife caught this video once
we're walking home from like a bar this
was late at night this is a bank the
bank is closed but I'm like well there
is a rec center up there and I had just
kind of walked out of a bar with a drink
so I just spit that through the door and
like that works so yeah man passive
infrared doesn't understand hot cold
it just says different Oh different must
be a human this one up top here the
Honeywell passive infrared sensor I
guarantee you've seen it or you've seen
it rebranded and rebadged as somebody
else's almost always white sometimes you
see them in black our page you will see
that everywhere all over the place and
why are they calibrated this way well
you don't want someone with a bunch of
boxes to like banging into the door and
fall over these are tuned and the
installers mount them in a way to get
the most wide spectrum hit because they
don't want to be called out repeatedly
hey the wreck sensor is not working it's
not picking us up it's causing you know
Mary just fell down with her cane and
her Walker the Installer doesn't want
that installers and integrators want to
always have these things trip so you're
gonna see that on a lot of doors because
it's got a really good coverage and
you're gonna always see it open the door
what is this on the bottom though that's
your solution ge is the only one I've
ever seen that reasonably brings to
market a dual technology wreck sensor
yes it does passive infrared it also
does microwave radar so it has to see
some temperature change and it also has
to see something vaguely human-sized
coming vaguely toward the door we knew
like a hacked wrist actor so nine
val/val actually she'll put balloons
through doors and blow them up and let
them go because the old trick with the
PIR is you usually just put them further
away from the door you just put them
down the hall and you
if I'm trying to gas the doll like I'm
not hitting it so her solution for that
was like like send balloons like blowing
down the hall to try to trip them
GES product will stop that I don't work
for GE I'm not here shilling for like
muack sand his buddy's moving so much ee
I don't know no all right but yeah it's
the only like dual technology sensor
that's I've ever seen that's good for
this also code let's talk about door
handles what is the last time you've
seen a doorknob like in an office you
don't because if someone like has
reduced grip and tactile function or
what if someone doesn't have a hand they
need to be able to get in and out of the
building especially in emergencies lever
style door handles are the norm now well
inside I mean you see the front one
facing me that's locked and has a you
know shitty little hidden procs reader
on the inside there's also a lever
handle which many times that's going to
be the case there are tools like this
that exist this is an under door tool
I'm doing a little show with a guy named
Tyler gray he's like will show me this
tool and his cameraman is like how would
you get in here and they expected me to
do something at the door they didn't
realize I just knelt down and kind of
bang the door open and actually it's one
of the cameramen was like can you do
that like again like slower that was way
too fast I didn't understand what's
happening well these are actual tools
that we use on jobs what we're doing
with this tool it's called an under door
tool we're reaching a rod under the door
and because modern doors have those
lever style handles they're really
really trivial to grab that handle and
hit it on the inside I'll show you a
picture from flipped around in a second
this is Robert middle of the night
getting into a server room you know
people see this video and they thought
they'd see him crouched down like how
he's gonna unscrew like with a
multi-tool to get through that crawl
through the grate no he's not he's gonna
lean his head into the door and just
push it open because of the inside we're
just swinging a rod pulling down on a
line and yanking this handle absolutely
works because when's the last time
you've been in the server room and had
to badge out some six of real secure
facilities maybe most of the time you
hit the handle and you leave there are
solutions for this there are what are
called dynamic door bottoms this little
animation shows you a black
if this black plunger gets pushed in
what happens you'll see this bottom bar
drops down so when the door shuts that
bar drop stay now this is not a security
product this is like a heating and
cooling insulation product but the same
principle applies to much more robust
models so a company called pemko PE mko
pemko makes the door bottom now they're
sold by ASSA ABLOY big contoured floor
plate interlocks in this metal bar and
unless that plunger is relieved of its
pressure that door bottom is dropped
down you're not getting a tool
underneath the door now you might get
something over the door this is a video
from Utah a buddy of ours named the
InfoSec Pope he loves demoing this all
he uses is 35 millimeter film for the
young kids of the room film is what we
used to take photographs with but he
literally just feeds a bow of film over
the door walks it over to the handle and
then pulls and you might not do this as
a user but if you pull up on a handle
it's usually gonna open the door so pull
BAM that doors open and I mean pemko
makes the door bottom I've never seen
anyone sell the door topper so like what
do you actually do to prevent this
problem well consider a shroud I was one
time working an under door tool in this
one job I'm like got damaged
yet I've like radio - Robert and like
Robert get in here can you and Roberts
trying he's like son of a bitch
bobak comes around from another building
and he throws a borescope unto the door
and we're like oh crap what is that and
eventually like with the borescope we
can kind of see and shove the wiggle the
tool we got it open and I asked the
client I was like man that one door gave
us freakin hell where did you get these
things that you installed in the server
room and they're like odd they were like
on the building when we got here I don't
know what that this one used to be like
a storeroom or something these are like
in Grainger catalogs these are so carts
don't crash into door handles when you
they're just shrouds for like protecting
the door handle not for like security
they're just so you don't bang into it
with stuff brilliant no money solution
if you've ever been in a hotel and
you've seen the door handle mounted like
down who's seen this before
hotels know about this man
tell us about break-ins with on their
door tools they mount these handles down
for reason this is one of my favorite
pictures renderman sent me this and I've
started to see hotels and other doors
with these like little clips I was like
I stayed in a hotel once for like a week
in San Francisco on this job and you
know it's talking to the staff late at
night hanging out and I'm like
hey so I got it I got to ask you the
freaking clip thing that looks very out
of place on the doors
is that like under door tools and the
guy was like oh yeah we have people
breaking into rooms and stuff we I was
like I gotta know where you get these my
clients could rip because I couldn't
that would be a nightmare trying
to get an under door over door attack
he's like well you know the closet in
your bedroom with the the sliding doors
yeah these are just those little feet
that like you put in the carpet on slide
like literally a Home Depot for dollars
if you don't care that it looks a little
weird
put these on your server room door man
it will completely frustrate the hell
out of me so I love this kind of
thinking I love wierd and hilarious ways
of getting in and I've got just I just
guess it's this crowd I added some funny
right like stealing keys you think
we're above steal it just outright
stealing stuff this was the security
cart on a facility once we just found it
and I was on a job with a guy I was
actually subbed in on a job had
everything key like everything all over
the building and of course like yes we
stole it I'm not gonna I guess we're
allowed to say J wouldn't mind I'm not
gonna say who it was but like eventually
we just stole the car and just drove it
around because if you get to that point
I mean you don't want jobs where you're
like you've gotten everything and
there's still time and you call the
client and you're like so we're in every
they haven't stopped us do you wanna
start doing stupid and the clients
like yeah just push it so yeah we
literally took this little golf cardi
thing and drove it around the parking
lot until it ran out of juice and we're
like puttering back it like no miles per
hour just to try to get it back to where
we left it so it looked really and we're
not in uniform no one stopped us but I
loved it like all the keys were there
lock boxes oh my god talk about stealing
keys stealing keys from a lockbox these
show up on a ton of buildings possibly
your buildings if you have con if you
have infrastruc
like cell towers and stuff on high
buildings and other contractors are
coming in to service that gear I bet you
there's a lock boxes somewhere that you
might not even know about tunt there's
one two three four five six seven
different people have to get into this
building I can't even think of that many
cable & wireless providers I don't know
what's going on here these kind of boxes
oh my god telephony boxes right this I
just throw in because mostly you know
Chris knows this guy in the slide yes
Dennis like Dennis is a good cat right
Dennis is standing next to a linear
access control box I am standing next to
another brand called door king let's
talk about these two big players in the
industry just because this is stuff
that's not usually in my slide deck I
just had to throw you some fun
right most of the stuff that cracks me
up when it comes to stealing the key
like I don't even think it counts as
stealing in the instance of like linear
you got this nice lit up keypad you got
the little W grill linear boxes all have
the same key it used to be called the a
126 key it's not really it's the 2 2 2 3
4 3 key but if you google like linear
key or linear 2 2 2 3 4 3 or linear a
126 you'll get this key it's the same
key on all the freaking panels it's not
a restricted key or an expensive key but
it lets you do crap like this so here we
have a locked door now my wife is going
to enter through a different technique
beep whoops this is actually the
apartment where we've stuck Marcus
Hutchins while he was waiting for trial
so we only got one key fob we cloned it
to her hand so she could come and go and
have an extra a key but now I don't have
a you know the key fob the door is
locked so what can I do well when your
boxes are all key to like 8 126 key
there's a little momentary switch and
just boom flip the relay so that works
same key on all these boxes man
absolutely
so yeah door King the one I'm standing
next to here I personally think door
King has even more market penetration do
they have the same key yes they do the
16 120 key it's been the door kinky I
think since 1992 and it's never tried go
to trade shows I go to like the trade
shows with all this gear and the door
King
huge and I take I just walk around like
he's my king just open stuff and just
walk away every few hours just walk by
the boot this was like a giant parking
gate arm like a huge crash barrier thing
and it's again 16 1 20 keen they're all
the same key door king systems let's
let's dive into this for a moment here
we got a lot going on here alright you
can always always always tell a door
King system boom boom boom a Z call
those three huge buttons you'll spot
them a mile away now there's not just
that we have a we clearly have hid procs
going on here we'll talk about
electronic credentials but let's get
right into it alright let's use our 16
or 20 key look at all these electronical
x' well there's a lot of stuff going on
in there we've got a big bank of
connections here what's going on in this
terminal block well
punch in door king manuel da pete file
type PDF in google you get a big manual
with this on one of the pages what's the
most giant writing you see on this page
real a1 relay - those are the door
relays right there they're just dry
contacts on the frickin panel so if you
have like door relay one either normally
open or normally closed you can just
bridge that circuit and like oh boom
fire the relay open the door fire relay
to open that door so in this case do you
see how this is wired by the way you can
see one common and you can see what
normally open so that tells you this is
probably a solenoid powered door lock so
normally there's no power put power just
literally by bridging that with a piece
of wire the door suddenly is open
there's another useful feature however
if you don't want to like carry your own
wire and I'll show you what I carry
around way up top let's look at this PSW
function what is p SW it's postal switch
a closure between these terminals in the
common will cause whatever relays are
set up however they're set up to fire
how is this normally work in fact is the
postal switch wired up yes it is it's
right there a little white in the little
blue a little white and blue that come
down you got these two beam connectors
and they come somewhere else let's look
all the way down in the front
amazingly low tech this is the postal
switch right here it's literally just a
momentary and on the front of the panel
you'll see they have these
doubts that you can just bang out a
piece of metal and install your own lock
and the tailpiece of that lock just
comes around and hits the momentary
switch many many door kings are
installed this way so we got a lock door
now of course you know we could clone
the hip rocks we could install a sniffer
or whatever we want we don't really care
what lock they're using for the postal
switch because it could be a good luck
it could be a bad luck I don't give a
damn because I have the 16 120 key Oh No
Oh laptop don't do things that laptop
sometimes do you're killing me whose
pony my laptop so ultimately here
hopefully we can get it to play because
it's really hilarious this is outside of
like roamers apartment I think we're in
town for band practice and you know we
called him up he wasn't answering like
try shaggy he wasn't answering and I was
like you want me to just let us in so
you know we walked inside so you know we
have this postal switch let's see if my
16 120 key works if I'm our if our video
plays nice here we go momentary switch
fires door's unlocked how many buildings
have these on them and people don't
realize many times it's not like your
office right it might just be the front
vestibule but if I can get in if I can
leverage this access in and find a way
then I get the next step I get the next
step I ride the elevator etc if you're
keeping keys like on you oh my god
there's a whole talk I did with Howard
Payne the CH 751 is like the everything
key it's the most common key in this
country for all kind of dumb dumb stuff
every little wafer lock everything like
steel toilet paper I don't know what
you're doing if you're you know you live
in a trailer you need toilet paper I'll
steal it from this hotel whatever like
the CH 75 one my favorite story was we
were on a job we got into an office like
a broom in this office building and
there were all these filing cabinets on
the wall and we're like oh I don't want
to pick every one of these open to see
which one has the valuable
but let's try a CH 75 one totally worked
and it turns out every one of them had
valuable it was like their HR
archives going back years the great part
and I just added this story because K
Joe gave his talk and he talked about
finding the exploit from the last job
you were on like still on the server
we found this we showed the client we're
like boy these are really terrible
filing cabinets and you're leaving this
around in a room that we just waltzed in
so the client was like oh my god we'll
get on that
we were hired seven months later to a
different office and we got into like
another room and we're like wow look at
all these filing cabinets and we opened
them were like are these the same
wow these are the same filing cabinets
they had moved them from one office to
another office but didn't actually
change him so we had the same finding
just in a different state ch seven five
one all day long for maximum Lowell
arity in the key to like space stick
1284 ex into your google engine right
looks a look at some image searches
you've seen a lot of the same vehicle
here the 1284 ex is the ford motor
company's fleet key the number of crown
vics and excursions and explorers in
this country that are key to like to
1284 x tons of police departments in
this country will all and not even
knowing it that all of their cruisers
are the same key and what's the most
common use of a Crown Vic after it's got
enough use hours and have to kick it out
of the force taxis they auction them off
and money to become taxis there are
cities in this country where the entire
taxi fleet is key to like and it's key
to like to the entire police fleet 1284
X is not a restricted key it's not a
special like this is the paper still
attached to it from Home Depot you get a
twelve eighty four X ticket Home Depot
cut as many as you like yes it will open
the doors yes it will open the glove box
yes it will open the trunk
nothing interesting in a cop's trunk
right and it's not a chipped key it's
not a key lock it's nothing like that
yes it'll start the freaking car so if
you have cop friends and we have plenty
show them the 1284 X if you get your
hands on one it might pop their eyes out
if you're curious my like everyday key
ring that sometimes people will see me
with they say what are you actually have
in your pocket all the time well I have
an elevator key the most common elevator
key on me at all times I have the two
most common filing cabinet keys the c-47
C for one C four and five a CH seven
five one I definitely carry that 1284 X
cuz it's funny right I have a couple
jigglers because why not
little tiny jigglers that we make if I
can't get through
simple Chitti lock this is my wire
bridge when I'm attacking door King
another box this is just a paper clip
that I burned the insulation off the
tips and looped it around door kinky if
you didn't get it earlier as the 16 120
linear the 2 2 2 3 4 3 which is
sometimes called a 126 and a cuff key
that is that that's my smash right there
that's like deviants devious keyring
giving you pearls here I don't think
I've ever shown the slide before outside
of our training so there you go
because I love you John strand and
everyone else who invited me here if you
are not an electronic person in fact you
know we were talking about this earlier
but we're at hire people from our team
we either have people that came from the
electronic digital world and we sort of
train them up on physical or we've
pulled people who are door kickers
they're just cops and other people that
were like hey want to make a better
salary and not be evil come come work
for us and like we have to train those
people on electronic learn some things
about electronic access controls learn a
little bit about badge systems it's not
that hard to get you spun up we can get
you spun up in a day or two on basic
cloning and sniffing and a lot of
credential stuff but the fact that we
take long-range readers and weaponize
them babacar electronics dude changes
the guts packages up a self-contained
power supply power on this reader let it
sit in a bag
you know the idea look very mr. robotic
kind of stuff right if you've seen that
credential grabbing scene this is real
this is about 18 inches away credential
grab out of someone's pocket biggest
with a nice antenna and a good power
supply inside that backpack that readers
gonna grab that card and it's gonna work
we can talk about that later if you want
we can talk about how if you get the
reader off the wall you can install a
sniffer on the back side of the reader
and you can sniff replay get credentials
that way there's a whole world out there
and it's not hard if you've never done
any kind of digital electronic work like
this if you are just a door buster this
is within your grasp and I encourage you
to get kind of cross-trained like that
little story time for you now new stuff
I promised as I tweeted earlier it's not
I've given versions of this talk in the
past this is all this is all new because
war stories are great and we've heard
about them from
speakers so let me give you a few good
ones most of which if you had to distill
this down the lesson is just be
confident and look like you belong if
you've never seen this footage here this
is a robbery of a Walmart where a guy
came in and said oh I'm here from Loomis
I'm here for the the pickup you know I'm
the armed guard he's not he's not the
armed car guy he's wearing of runners
vest with like you know weights and the
tactical pants and his hats down I think
they found out later at an airsoft
pistol and he took $75,000 he's not I'm
here from Loomis no he got in a chevy
lumina and drove away
this dude another guy keep your hat down
and don't bother anybody
look I'm just here from you know your
beverage services I'm stocking your
shelves no you're not this guy hits
seven stores in one weekend in Alabama
he's just stealing beer he just went in
with a cart loaded this thing up and
just freakin left look like you know
what you're doing and people will tend
to believe that so the elevator
repair story all right we got into a
building it was an interconnect we
gassed off you know a wreck sensor
because again you could see it on the
ceiling
Honeywell PIR boom gasps the wreck
sensor get through okay we're in the
building now we've got a go whew like
we're come in weird the first time you
get any get that like adrenaline rush
and I'm with somebody on this other job
just another company we're partnered
with and this guy's like man what are we
where do we go what do we do it was like
calm down I got an idea let's come walk
it find the nearest elevator we just got
in an elevator okay
why because I mocked myself up I'm here
from I've got my little Otis badge I've
got my clipboard I'm an elevator repair
technician why not you want another like
great tip from me to you this is your
cover story for being any elevator
repair guy ever have a stupid clipboard
and learn these three steps you press
that ephone somebody picks up it's many
times as a computer if it's a human
hello this is a test of the emergency
phone in this elevator step 2 can you
hear me clearly right now step 3 where
am i calling from and that last one
flummox is the hell out of people a lot
of the time because they should be able
to know where you are in event of
emergency you will sound like a
jedd elevator tech if you do that you're
not really breaking any laws you're not
causing any harm to the elevator you can
just sit there and just try elevator
you know like trial evader phones and
just to get this dude to calm down I was
like hey just relax let's try some
iPhones man so we're just being the
elevator tax and it turns out the third
question really flummoxed somebody
because it wasn't like a service that
went out to Otis line it was the the
front desk and we wound up consistently
hitting the front desk and like oh it's
just another one of those elevator tests
yeah I don't know where you are though
it just says extension 39 and like so
you can't tell me where I'm calling from
like I mean you're in an elevator I'm
like okay sir I'm gonna have to write
down that you don't know where I'm
calling from
and it gets them all panicked right
turns out the security guard was so
flummoxed by not knowing where the
elevator emergency well I'm like don't
worry so there's just a test you're not
at fault here we just we just have to
put this in the notes that came into
play later so while we're in the
elevator the guy says to me it's like
okay so all we got to do is get the poem
plug and deploy it and oh oh man I
didn't grab it I'm like oh you didn't
grab the pole plug well you know the
hotel is like 10 minutes away just drive
back and get it
I'll stay in the building and I'll let
you back in he's like okay that sounds
good you're gonna look okay I'm like
dude I got my metal clipboard like come
on who's gonna mess metal clipboards
great because you can hide a bunch of
tool and gear in it and like all your
stuffs in there but the better thing
about the elevator story is if you
actually watch the elevator hacking talk
we have a lot of keys that do things
well my partner is back at the hotel
which was not going well he was like hey
man I got some delays here I'll just
hang out in an elevator so I just
disabled an elevator with my keys I'm
just in the elevator just hanging out
nothing I'm like reading Twitter and
stuff occasionally asking like hey how's
that going at the hotel turns out what
happened is his USB keyboard wasn't
playing nice with the palm plug he was
hooked up to the hotel TV and he
couldn't get the key so we had to use
on-screen keyboard to like set up all
the scripts and it was taking forever
and I'm like dude that's fine I got
Twitter I'm fine I'm just sitting in an
elevator until I almost had a heart
attack cuz I thought I heard someone
banging
on the elevator door because it's like
you're camping in the woods like
everything sounds loud in the woods when
you're asleep in the I thought someone
was pounding on the elevators like oh my
god there's like a camera I didn't see
is that security trying to kick their
way in and like no calm down calm it's
it's 5:00 5:15 the cleaners are here
they're probably like Windex seeing the
fingerprints off of the hoistway doors
like alright calm down eventually the
guy comes back and he's like alright let
me okay I go to let it turns out it
wasn't the cleaners turns out security
had come by the elevator not because
they thought I was in there I had been
in there so long that they had stuck a
sign on the elevator
that said elevator out of order do not
use this elevator use other side of
building which was great because when we
came back in my buddy and I now were the
only people in the damn building
security came down a hall the sauce saw
my Otis badge and went wow you got here
fast and it was like oh yeah I got that
Oh des you got that Otis elite care
service so like they dispatch this out
here I'm you know doing things with keys
that because clearly the elevators
working now that I turned it back on but
he was so thrilled he's like we guys
doing that elevator test earlier I was
like no that was the other team but I
heard you had some problems but you know
what the elevator dispatcher is in this
room can you let me in this room and
sure sure enough the guard just like let
us everywhere we wanted to go because
you know who wouldn't want their
elevators to run right right on the I'm
the helpful elevator guy I'm getting the
light on time I'll give you I'll give
you one more story I got a couple more
stories here but how much time we
actually have five or ten minutes five
we can do another story and a half in
five so the armed guard story is a good
story
most guards it craps you a lot of guards
are under trained a lot of guards are
third party this was a guard desk that
literally had no one at it and one time
I just sat there
I actually took the binder of keys and
key cards and just kind of like spun
around in the chair just waiting for a
guard to come up to see I wanted like
know what the hell they would say and it
took so long that I just got up and left
like the guard literally never showed
armed guards are a different story
they're a little more mastered they're a
little better with interaction and
they're gonna be more cautious now this
was an instance where we needed
electronic credentials we really wanted
to get in using a badge
and all the employees like we couldn't
get close to the employees at all they
were using a separate entrance like the
vestibule is the only place we could get
in and during the day the only people of
the vestibule were the armed guards this
was a private development space well we
know how to do a credential cloning
right we have our gear we have our long
range reader that you saw earlier right
shove that in a backpack once you power
it on shove that oh we already saw this
video shove that in a backpack get
somebody to go in just try to get close
enough
you saw 18 inches or so so when we said
who's gonna go in right well what is
every guard especially armed guards kind
of wish they want to be or maybe they're
trying to be the trying to be cops right
send it a cop like Rob's on our team rob
used to be a cop or like get in there
and cop it up man just talk about cop
stuff
so he goes in Bob Beck is in the
backseat of a rental car in the parking
lot like remote on to the reader he's
like trying to check the status of it
and goes out of range
his Robert goes in all the way to the
vestibule so babak's like man I really
hope I really hope that readers getting
some credentials and Roberts trying
everything Roberts like getting close
but they're armed guards so they keep
bleeding off every time you get too near
them at one point he put it like his bag
on a counter and he was like asking the
guard he's like hey is this a good
restaurant is no Donyell trying to get
the guard to like lean over the counter
wouldn't do it so he keeps trying it
keeps trying to keep strand getting
nothing finally at the end of the inner
ace telling cop stories right so he's
friendly with him he's like all right
well I gotta if he stays any longer he's
like this is just weird it's like all
right fellas I gotta I gotta go all
right take it easy man it's nice meeting
you and the last guard he just
surprised hugs him and like very very
Kennedy he was like make it a little
weird make a little weird all right
brother all right and gets out of there
in the car
bobak is in the backseat like what did
you do I was dying back here it's like
well here check check the logs man bobak
check dumps the courage he's like you
were in there 47 minutes and you got one
read
and that was it but then who are we
we're the armed guard at that point so
getting that you never know exactly
what's gonna work out for you in terms
of getting in I had one other story
about you know find me in the bar will
tell you about about some other stuff
what I really wanted to get to I'm gonna
quiz you at the end here we got a little
we got a little Q&A and I promise I'm
wrapping it up right so this is I hope
you're paying attention right what kind
of unit is this here door king wide you
know that three huge buttons who
remembers the door kinky 16 one twenty
key buy it buy it online what kind of
unit is this it's one of the ones we
talked about has a little recessed lit
keypad linear linear absolutely what's
the linear key a 126 or technically two
two two three four three blurry dark
picture but who is it door King exactly
three buttons you can do this on
Google Street new we got a building here
let's zoom on in you can't see it
clearly but you see a recessed lit
keypad what do you got you got a linear
a 126 key absolutely let's look at this
John over here all right can't see it
from here but let's zoom in and Google
what do you see three giant freaking
buttons door king absolutely door king
we got a lot going on here let's let's
talk about this all right first of all
we clearly got a door King system we're
using what key is the door kinky 16 1 20
go buy one they're also using hid
old-school prehistoric hid procs
soap rocks card - you know they're using
cloneable credentials you know you could
sniff the back end of this because you
could pop that circuit board open easily
they've got a ton of key boxes this was
for deliveries I don't know if that was
a CH 75 one but I'm sure I tried it in
their little freaking you know kidde
accesspoint in here what is what is this
one turns out it's also a key box it's
just a different key box so we have
multiple key boxes we have a lock that
we know the key for we have a clone a
cloneable cred there's one more thing
that you can also see in this picture
can anyone tell what I would I would
look for through the windows maybe you
can tell what elevator fixtures they
have so I know what elevator Keys I'm
going to need so I can prep my story and
I can bomb in there all equipped and
ready to rock so keep these kind of
attacks
mind keep physical side in mind try it
out if you think it's all about
lock-picking you're not exactly right
most of the time we're just doing dumb
stuff to bypass our way in but I love
sharing this and I love trying to give a
little hope you got a couple of pearls
in this one to make your jobs easier and
your life better and my job harder
because that's in the end that's a win
for me like I like being the guy in the
server room
but I also like telling people what they
did right and a lot of it's not hard to
do so thank you very much for listening
and I hope you enjoy this
[Applause]
you