[Music]
well first of all why do we give a round
of applause for everybody that made this
possible so we would not be
it's really awesome really awesome to
get folks out here and see so many
people out here for a very first time so
many familiar faces but thank you all
for coming out to hear me talk on my
aquino front today I'm talking about
more get to the gym attack patterns and
this is something that is near and dear
to me because I feel like in this
industry we're getting better at some
the stuff that we do and that's a good
thing and so today's talk is will gonna
be talking about what we're doing good
what we've been doing better at
ultimately let's blow it up a little bit
more so we have to get harder to detect
things again so I'm releasing a new tool
today I'm calling Trevor c2 but I'm
talking about that here just a little
bit I'm Tim Kennedy you know whatever I
remember Mikey was a manager again
everything but isn't enough people fun
facts I was in a rap video recently that
was really weird you know I'm not a rep
person in any way shape or form or like
a heavy metal on the run person and if
you were to ask young knave would he
ever be in a rap video I'd be like no
there would be no chance of that but
what was interesting about it is I was
literally hacking away on a computer
they built this whole like 1980s hacking
I think there's old screen TVs and
everything else there's like dancers all
around me in this rap artists rapping
behind me and I'm just hacking into a
computer there's one of the most awkward
things I've ever done in my entire life
like
I guess they was so uncomfortable that I
can't even explain hand out was funny
because I started to Gotham hacking you
know like their damn the songs put in
the background they're kind of lip
singing to the songs and I'm like
bobbing my head like yeah please stop
Bobby door and they go oh sorry sorry
you know and they're hacking again you
know but hackers are cool right that's
the fun part about everything that we're
seeing out here and that's that's a neat
thing and seeing represented in railways
who's kind of needs and all that good
stuff but I'm sure events a lot of talks
lately
and over the past probably ten years
that the world's birding hackers are
winning there's nothing that we can do
to defend against the attackers that are
out there they're always going to be one
step ahead of us they're always going to
have you know awesome zero days they're
always going to be compromising
everything we're doing and that's the
tonality that we've said you know look
at what we used to do in the pen testing
industry we just to walk into come
corporations or organizations we break
into them steal all their data and then
high-five each other and walk out give
them a line on 50 page report then next
year we go to the same thing and it was
just cyclical effect of breaking in and
not really sharing with what we're doing
you look at today it's changing a lot
you know the blue team is understanding
a lot of the methods that we're using
they're the techniques that we're using
a lot of folks in here are good reason
because of that happening you know
sharing the knowledge of what they're
doing things that stopped them as
attackers and it's interesting because
the the tonality is changing around
attackers being able to get into now our
attackers have to get better and better
to not get tripped up when it comes to
what we're seeing out there and some say
this is false or getting a better at
defense defense is something where you
know it just takes one specific thing to
trip us up they get detected now we have
to shift our tactics into a different
way to hopefully not get the get
detected so it's becoming harder for us
as attackers it's noticeable there's
noticeable for us when we go on
assessments we've gone red teams it's a
little slow me go into organizations
it's noticeable we're doing social
engineering and fishing now it's not for
everybody right and not everybody's
doing
we have a lot of people that still need
a lot of help and a lot of people I
still have a lot of my work to do but
across the board
we're starting to get a lot better out
there and that's a great thing to see
who's actually I don't understand read
tactics and their techniques of
procedures we heard the TTP's a lot it
was a it's a big word
but it's interesting because you look at
the whole purple TV concept that John
and Mick and everybody else and you know
Rob and a lot of other folks in industry
I've talked about for years and years
and years around how we needed to share
what we're doing on red and how blue
really had to have a good understanding
of what red was doing the order for us
to get better if that's actually
happening now like we actually are
starting to understand why should
looking at sub T's Twitter account is
breaking things every single day you
know we're looking at things like that
and understanding what you know
attackers day we're understanding
different groups and remotes and how
they office Kate code and and the
methods that they're leveraging and
we're starting to build those detection
criteria in and it's getting a lot
better as we're going along we have a
long long ways to go there's was a lot
of things out there that we're not doing
though there's a lot of things that we
can't do a good example is protection
protection is one of those things that
is very difficult for us in
organizations to actually roll out
because it impacts the business right
anybody you're using the state version a
job across the board no right you know
protection becomes very difficult for us
to have to go do it and I can actually
solve the security problem right now I
can solve it all right here I actually
have an idea that would literally fix
everything that we do with security
everything everything yeah one person
dedicated one security person dedicated
to every single employee in the
organization
you can sit over the shoulder like no no
no don't like that don't click all you
clicked it on I get use your computer
hang on I've got a computer come on
where you look past the next person pass
the next person you every six or seven
people a very mature you go back to the
first he gets to the back minimum hit it
intrinsic performance that would
actually work we actually have a
reduction of breaches we have somebody
before shattering somebody else making
sure we do anything but we have that
luxury right we have to really focus on
understanding those in minimizing what
we can ability detection off of that
when we can and everything else I really
love this to me they have used it before
in the past but it's probably what my
favorite sweets out there every Slayer
me some excellent alright baby
this is one my favorite ones out there
and and the fact that I came from Egypt
who was predominantly red you know when
it comes to building exploits and
running awesome code and breaking into
systems know Jeremiah from Whitehead
sometimes said it said that never Sarah
just needs to find one vulnerability to
win just do that they need to just find
one system to target that no they don't
yeah that's true so you know we're
always gonna have a vulnerability or an
exposure or a way for us to break into a
computer system that we didn't
anticipate right that's how this works
we're not gonna be a hundred percent
secure if you all know that but what
each encounter with and I love I love
this quote was Connor quote once you're
in the system atmosphere role reverses
blue only needs to find one indicator of
compromise to catch right and that's
where we're currently at so you know you
compromised a box you get around all the
protection mechanisms
you know you get around there artificial
intelligence machine learning and
everything else that's out there today
to be no does a great job and everything
right um yeah we look at that we say
okay
you know what we need to do next now
we're going to start looking at
extracting cash that's what do we get
you know caught there or looking at
clear text passes in memory or grab
assess cans and curb roasting or moving
laterally to a different system you know
there's a lot of different parts of the
phases of the attack we start moving to
other components that we can get
potentially caught on and so I really
like this because if we're looking at a
bettin log 46:24 we're looking for
network login type 3 we're seeing if one
machine from one source IP address is
moving to another workstation and that's
something that we're looking for we
could snag that right and that's a
detection pattern that can trip us up as
attackers and it takes a lot of effort
for us to get that initial access to
that computer so now we have to burn a
whole infrastructure down or go build
another one go attack again and go
different I'm hoping that get detected
that way so it's a lot of effort now
that's going into what we have to do
from the attack cipher and so obviously
it's interesting because if you look at
a lot of what we're seeing out there and
a lot of what's coming out in the
research industry what's going on from
groups like fin 7 and others is that we
have a lot of obvious gated code
occurring to get around detection
criteria a good example says does this
look legit and a little bit baby so
gonna get downloaded an executable and
starting that process and you know I'm
telling you from the internet if my PHP
sites were to legit as you know using
exec bypass no profile and so you know
if you look at what we do is it's as
defenders
should look at this information it's
easy to spot stuff like this right you
see that command being murdered like hey
that's not good right so we know that
that's wrong just recently just a couple
days ago
Daniel dbo silver at fire I posted this
one this one's legit it's using Casey's
metaphor Cerrito to go and download
something from the internet what's nice
about it is it doesn't actually
PowerShell to go it down there from
there he's asserting something going
down the internet and execute power
shell again it's just look legit you
should you ever see certain cell be
getting out to the Internet the first
legit right that's good we're gonna day
so looking for things that are abnormal
is starting to be a thing that we can
identify pretty quickly so obfuscation
now is becoming a problem for us as a
temper this is the easiest if down now
we're just relying off our automated
tools we're probably not gonna pick
stuff up like this right if we're
looking for patterns of behavior they
cave PowerShell is not baking out there
I would want to know every single time
power slot republic's the internet back
to my company I don't care what it is
just PowerShell cause internet period I
can baseline my environment say okay
that's an exchange server and this
specific script calls out and it's going
to be specific IP addresses I can
baseline that right I can spend my week
or my month baselining powershot my
environment then looking for deviations
of patterns behavior
why is register 32 urban hands Internet
why stemis code going onto a file share
like those are all things that we should
be looking at from a behavior standpoint
to say hey these are normal environment
of the look at these doesn't mean that
it's malicious it just means I should
look at these so you know and then you
tell you take my mutation on top of it
you can use
within a couple of seconds determine
whether or not this is Bana like it
takes me a second to look at this and
say hey that's not legit right it's not
downloading something from a Microsoft
site or you know somewhere else another
good one probably not legit right using
MSHDA in the about parameter to run an
ActiveX opponent probably not legit
right this look legit technically here
you saw that registry actually getting
man into your environment on the in the
current version run that little shits
here probably not right so things that
we can look for they're suspicious in
nature that have specific items we need
to talk done so it's not legit right
it's not legit so being able to find
these specific things is this is
different now if you look at current
ways that we get code execution of
systems typically still predominant
excusable like okay we enable a macro or
using dde auto but what is it typically
doing wet as it executes go to download
to binary
alright you look at trick bot that's
using the DD auto stuff or a lock
hearing those ones are going in
downloading binaries afterwards the fact
that we're still appealing with onset
code binaries running in our app records
and user profiles is a mystery to me
right so if you look at that to shrink
that down you look at a lot of the
points we're still meeting execution
powershots the possibility other ways
we're still predominantly FCS like a
powershell power structure a patient is
dying you don't know that or not i mean
we're getting better at the texture
becomes the powershell i'm not good news
no one's moving to our supper club yet
these not a lot of folks we're not using
constrain thing we're not using script
lock logging all the features that
Microsoft has built into it
Microsoft has a lot of great stuff
inside of it that becomes much more
difficult for us to get around a lot of
techniques there's a lot of companies
out there doing some substantial work
around pop so detection
okay good indication why is the link of
PowerShell command greater than 100 or
500 or a thousand or 2,000 that's
probably a good indication that
something's amiss heywhy system time
management automation that dll being
loaded as a memory when it's not a
commercial process like those are good
things that we can determine and detect
very quickly when something's amiss so
Power Cells becoming one of the most
secure program in the images that we
actually see out there people laugh at
that but from where it came from power
sovereign Zoo to where we're at today is
completely different it's a completely
different ballgame we're going to be
dealing with that down the future so
using powerful exploitation your window
of time for exploitation right now as
drastic and being reduced and you're
already getting caught in a lot of cases
you're using a VOC expression or encoded
command or other things like that you're
going to get busted they get just the
way that it works now if your detection
cards here is just looking for a code
command you saw unfortunately right
that's not what you want to be working
on you notice like 16 different
variations of Nakota command yeah - de
you know - in the CFD FCN you know th
you know def nco all these different
variations do you have to ever call a
coder command using the answer I recall
an Evoque expression you can do all of
that directly from you know I'm using
different methods so PowerShell is
becoming a lot more difficult for us to
actively gonna use because of the things
that they build into it and that's a
great thing you know it's interesting to
see the whole research community around
PowerShell focus on for the past several
years and see what Microsoft actually
did to make it better I mean powerful
over two
you know I remember giving so my claim
to fame and I still have that which is
great is I gave the very first ever
PowerShell security club so a PowerShell
MFG at that time and I remember when I
was on Microsoft site and Parks was
branded owners I knew about it by the
way is I was at Depot at the time and
one of my guys on my team came by music
hey Microsoft's coming in they have this
new beta that they're looking at
introducing into our environment it's a
whole programming they were 12 power
shelves invader and I'm going to looking
at embedding it into their entire
infrastructure I think what hasn't sound
good I started take a look at that very
meeting exposing event into our
environment in the future so I wouldn't
actually staff to this this Microsoft
tutorial on the ropes came in and demoed
with PowerShell was so I started looking
at it like oh this could be really cool
to run like a whole bunch of tools in it
and that year we released the tool
called powered up I thought was kind of
funny up in the Sam database in
PowerShell and no but other things are
on that but what's interesting if you
look once at Microsoft's website it said
I'm at the time you know execution
restriction policies are way to prevent
unsigned code from executing on the
operating system right then after our
talk they fixed it by changing it to
execution researcher policies are not a
method for stopping unsigned code in
your environment so you look at where
car-show burning Tuesday that's where
we're at today
extreme language mode everything else
it's a lot different in becoming a lot
harder for us to actually go attack and
for me do regular users ever ever ever
regular users ever need these marks no
god no
yeah
so in our environments we have users and
we have this this awesome thing called
app Locker we have this awesome thing up
half block or a group policy that you
literally restrict commercial execution
to all ranges right now like right now
it wouldn't impact anything doesn't mean
administrators or developers or you know
your council running it just means
regular users do any of your regular
users need to access the powers over
know the regular users believe any Java
really or in macros for mega so that's
why probably that's why macros are still
a great exploitation Avenue versus DDR
everybody is like looking for didi on
him now like the whole thing they all
focus not off of macros and it's been
great like I ran into six customers and
they were like hey there's macros like
everyone looking for Dede OTO right now
okay cool um we look at this and this is
just like something we can do right now
to reduce our tax service that we're not
doing the basic stuff right so here's
some examples of good progression
regular users blocker power show or
heavy logging on it right so for did
some heavy logging on PowerShell we can
use script lock logging which is
fantastic some great stuff there
interesting enough if you still look at
how like Windows Defender anything else
is working you know there's a lot of
talk about how the new offenders come a
long way and how it's done a lot of
great stuff the integration it's a the
anti-malware scan interface for MSI
what's funny is recently update to
Windows Defender started snagging
uniform which is a power saw injections
will there
oh my god weird like maybe I would have
to spend a lot of time going to rewrite
it you know you get around it again
figure out why it's getting detected I
figured hey maybe it's turning off like
Colonel Kurtz you being loaded with that
power shell or something else right so I
start looking at it and I found that I
had one damn variable at I forgot to
randomize so what happened when I can
randomize that variable no problem right
that's still worth today in those
products it's crazy right so that's one
piece walking outside executables Artois
spiders at least and user profiles like
your users really need to be running
emcs and our code sign in the user
profile directories all your active
directories to make any sense
no I got alone is like a huge reduction
of attack service disallowing
workstation workstation traffic that's
the biggest one that I can't recommend
enough yes yes they're getting ride bus
- that is workstation workstation
traffic why it does Bob and sales need
to talk to Mary and IT s computer / SME
RPC why does it make any sense
whatsoever so block 135 405 like Donal
up to anybody
the longeth anybody get from workstation
worst days ever seen your servers may
need to do SCCM updates or using shad
liquor so they needs remote it from your
server infrastructure but where station
Park station and communications should
not be happening ever Rubin capabilities
your DSL inappropriate SSL termination
is anybody doing that so termination
you're like one ish one entry that kind
of dish that's some termination to get
visibility Ness is that like we're not
looking at that application control I'm
a huge advocate of application control
so why would you ever wants when work
work so for Outlook to never call
command of exe or power sub idfc or
anything like that in the first place
right should you shoot people on that as
well
probably not right so looking at what
normal behaviors for applications and
facing those in blocking any known
execution types that side he comes out
with every single week
or day for our probably right now I'm
talking but walking specific ways that
we're using for for a code execution um
some example skin detection
I love ECW was dis mine since mod you're
not familiar it's a free Microsoft tool
I'm going down that it's persistent her
goals mark russinovich this team runs it
exposes have met lunch racing with that
you can do some substantial detection
around me because injection you see if
well Claire that DLL being loaded for
non specific processes I think there's
ways of to pay that but we see ball play
the DL being loaded from non system
specific processes you get actually to
technique as it's coming in I'm same
thing for your process injection you can
see across the deduction occurring
through through system on you can do a
lot of other things to a glad remove and
I'm great thing about this is most folks
that have things like carbon black
already get this like with like you know
check parent-child processes and you
know they're never communications but
with system on you can actually monitor
specific SD cables and pioneers and see
what network connections that they're
actually having along with its you can
pull all that back what happens is with
system on is it exposes a Evette viewer
on my deep and it's just in your bed
viewer so you grab those logs send them
back to your no instance or your Splunk
instance or whatever you do block
centralization then you can see those
start to build the texture criterion so
it's this month's awesome
deviations to protect your controls they
provides register if they choose bonding
network connections lateral movement you
can do that through a bet lock 4624 now
what's the problem with that specific
event on you actually have to pull up
all from longer ten points right which
means that our EPS comma not goes up
with the pace walking another million
dollars for all report 624 amenities
right
the gorilla hand length of data specs
being said Dina's log analysis on East
the West traffic not just north and
south so some stuff that we can do very
quickly to get some idea what's
happening out there so it's actually get
better easier for us to trip up and
easier for these anatec attackers again
for some not everybody out there so if
the tensions getting better
what do we need to do as attackers to
start to get better at that and so you
know look at what we're talking about
this is what we start talking about
legitimate patterns behavior and we need
to get better at what we're doing if you
look back at how we used to hack
probably back in 2005-2006 social
engineering wasn't a major aspect of our
day to day life ahead a little bit but
wasn't every day actually hacks your web
sites we actually found an explosion of
vulnerabilities we got a little lazy
when it came to end users because it was
so easy
he would click a link you get access and
it was like literally oK we've moved in
different systems and then we started
building on our capabilities and getting
better with C to insert a RC traffic you
know insert to do you know specific
things there so we got lazy and SC miss
you know still pretty easy it's so easy
to get people to click stuff but it's
getting a lot harder right so one thing
we gonna do is continue to be amazing
and what we do and start moving more
towards legitimate act backers and
that's really where when you start
focusing on the different tack
definition and rasps been talking about
this for a long time I her rat tail
mushroom from coal strike he was talking
a presentation of sands it was probably
like five or six years ago and he was at
the time talking about how we needed to
go more towards emissary simulation and
focusing on emulating attackers and
focusing on patterns of behavior and
time I was like man wrap people like
still got like a fashion
I'm Kent on the external perimeter they
should be focusing on this yet but he
was right none of the steps that we
needed this start getting better or
we're doing it companies are starting to
get better he just posted this this
yesterday a huge fan of this this cord
air defenses are evolving and that's a
good thing
as blue TTP's gain ground it's on us to
adjust our operations and find ways to
challenge ECP's and this is how both
sides get better and so again this is
just a natural evolution where we're
starting to get better detection and
we've never really had this point in
time where defenders have gotten better
and attackers are certainly having a
tough time getting in infrastructure
it's literally been in like it will fish
somebody will go and grab mess pans or
will extract the hashes all the hash
values on the local operating system is
the same on every other system everybody
has an RPC NSN be an admin sheriff open
so we can just move from one system
until we find a domain a server admin
you go to the server admin there's a
domain admin log into that server box
you go to that domain names domain admin
rights let me go to everything else
right au revoir responder they have a
separate character pass where you go
over and that crack that password we go
into that box has admin rights you know
I'm getting that box with other systems
it's not like that anymore it's getting
harder for us they go on to do those so
our focus I love this video
I'm not gonna lie it's not really weird
but like when I'm coding for a long
period of time every once in a while
I'll just like stop and just watch
it's therapy for your mind so what works
double dance is still good but our
single phylogenic protocols and using
the chip in applications so this one
we're starting into emulating user
behavior so so a good example of this is
if I compromised the machine am I gonna
have it start working on 250 different
ports no but can I make myself look like
I'm browsing a website yes can I do
things that don't exhibit patterns of
behavior that be sure to buy a
individually hey if my process is gonna
be going out I should probably be using
like Internet Explorer or whatever there
there are no browser choices leverage
and then as a method to piggyback so
using that for initial foothold in the
start to move and start to exhibit
illegitimate behavior another good
example is look at the actual system
you're going on - most of the time we
first get into a box we drop in a shell
we start pillaging when I grab a process
list and see what's actually running on
that box first and figuring out what
they have as far as defenses and
building our attacks off of that we're
seeing what systems are connecting to
start going after those systems versus
going till our removing our systems out
there in it as well
so login and this one too is another big
one where see chakras or the becoming
and done that is really where a lot of
focus is becoming on because there's
literally no visibility into that
whatsoever you can run msbuild without
getting the tech that you can run you
know c-sharp code with getting one
detect that's another big feat here you
like it to my face amazing things in
this face you know Matthew graver is one
of those in KC's another one you're not
following them I recommend putting them
down right now and following them and
checking it like once a week because you
probably have a new indicator that
Russia's using now because of them it's
good thing it's a good thing to do good
stuff and a good example of taking them
and leveraging something nemesis build
is so if we release released a tool
called MPs payload and there's two
payloads in there one's a c-sharp a lot
the other ones are powershell payload
and what you can do with msbuild is you
can call remote file shares and have it
go and pull down specific code or next
to you drink into memory which is great
specifically with this one
you're not from with MPs what we call
non powershell been about seven came up
with a technique where you can call the
assistant of management automation at
the eleven letters powershell full
without ever calling Powershot idfc or a
partial underscore i CWC and so with
this you can actually leverage the full
functionality of power show without ever
calling PowerShell so converse if you
want to get around things like sign
lands you just renamed power so that a
exceeds and move wxe and you're all set
so you know there's a lot of different
ways of skinning the cat when it comes
to this but calling an assistant manager
not
DLL without their burning power so that
exe and not getting detect it typically
trips up a lot of the ers and things
like that out there so a good way of
getting around Adams but again why is
Miss Bill Dunn exe be getting out the
internet probably not a good thing right
so all about magic unicorn so much show
you that demo real quick and this is a
new one of the new versions of of
unicorn and for those new record it's
just a position tool or power so and
actually if they get started with gates
so attest me get something to work so
it's unicorn you a few different options
you can do HD 80s you can do DVDs you
can use that use the circuit so method
to convert a payload back you can import
your own PowerShell files you can do
macros and there's a lot of other
capability to it but it's nice about
this is for an occupation standpoint
you're looking for patterns like encode
a command invoke expression you're
probably not going to have good
detection
so I'm just a generator code over here
usually insulted a parent there we go
let me just copy it over here so you can
see it easier
totally legit right see that in your
environment it looks normal
insurance exchange notice what we're
doing here do we ever call in co2
commands no right we are calling the co2
commander we use set favorable and gift
variable to piece together a bunch of
strings we chunk up things like PVC you
can't live for you know get variable so
it's a G you know ticket it could be
things like that that cause a lot of
obfuscation in there right so from a
PowerShell perspective this is loading
up Shoko drove into memory now a good
example of an indication on this is sis
well 64 okay so it's gonna be calling
the sequel backslash Windows backslash
this well 64 backslash
what does PowerShell backslash first 100
version backslash power so you see
they're gonna present so it's calling
that specifically so VC sis while 64
hitting in your environments probably a
good indication something's amiss but
still I would just use that as a good
indication the link that this command is
a good one right this also has network
connections what's going on to the
internet with the show so our show
beginning on there you should see
multiple things on this specific one but
not based off of the hey I'm gonna look
for you know G back back B it's not a
good detection criteria that you're just
kind of you're focusing a lot of the
specific areas around that cat mouse
game interesting enough it's a lot of
lead into like a lot of tools would look
for base64 encoded strings so what you
can do is just chuck those up so it
doesn't actually create a full basically
for ghost drinks when you see those that
messes the whole decode function of it
up cuz you don't join those together so
again just ways it messing
with the tools another good one
whose macros
so most people will look for deputy
Rochelle PowerShell command WC things
like that that would be embedded that's
on the macro right so why not never
reason he lives
so as you can see here
break those up a little bit now when
you're writing off is gauged by the way
the worst part is it having to go back
and change your code it sucks
like what the hell did I write in it
intrigued me at that time so you look at
the code you're like wow that's amazing
I don't even know what what's happening
at this point it takes a lot longer but
if you look over here total is it right
looks legit I got but not gonna call the
Hong Kong and go to command so this one
coded thing actually spawned because
they've got some kids in there some
might not show this but I went on a long
rant on kaspersky
and so there's still one lawman of
frustration there so just different ways
of obfuscation right but those things
are easy to spot
so that about Trevor see to Trevor
now interesting about some folks you
know this reacts so well to the whole
trucker thing but to me you know you
have a dead cockroach that that
generates five thousand dollars reporter
before we can release one from the
hacking community like we can use our
platforms and do hidden jokes as anybody
does so here's the CNN one year I just
wanted to show it
the news conference by the Senate
Intelligence Committee was designed to
do three things set pretty massive is
number one we're not done yet
number two we're still searching number
three the Russians are still coming
the Russians view I mean they understand
our political system they understand
hot-button topics and I was actually
discussing this whole thing
[Music]
take these sucks we're stronger to the
terrible incident then you turn it into
hurricane relief funds and you know
costumes and then it gets a part of the
industry and just having fun with it and
laughing in it so you know get on that
and everybody else does her making it's
absolutely racing so maybe I understand
it's a little over some folks you know
but I'm still a kid and I think it's
four layers every time when I go home I
also start giggling single driver it's I
mean it's it's awesome
so what's Trevor situ
[Applause]
so I'm a lot of open source projects I'm
currently working on but not to say I
probably will making a framer guy that I
think I will figure it out but we're
listing this today up on get help Soviet
rustic that gave up that calm so I
stress its neck / Trevor c2 and what it
is is it emulates a regular user trying
to browse a website just as we would so
what ends up happening is the Trevor
server portion of it on the server
infrastructure well go and clone any
website you want to or import in any
website that you want to so there are
similar to that features like the social
engineer it's okay right you go and you
own a website and embeds all the stuff
into there and it goes into tax so what
happened is when it goes to clone the
website no you go your register your DNS
names and everything else as usual want
this site but when you go to browse the
site that's a legitimate site the site
has all the images anime that you need
for it the site is browsable by a
regular user regular user so as an IR
person I'm going to this site and look
at and look at the code is gonna look
good if I'm gonna look crazy not form to
look like a legitimate site goats into
the site I'm into the sources sites for
us to the whole site itself is c2 stuff
and so it's going to be leveraging that
and so the c2 stuff is actually embedded
into the site itself throughout the
whole of the whole source of the HTML
and it uses a way for humana controls
all get requests there's no post or nice
feeling a bunch of data out of posts and
the way that it works the way that it
uses it is that when you go to the site
and the client goes to execute
go in that the client needs is the query
parameter and then it's all random I'm
sorry it's all configurable in the C to
the query parameter the the path you
wanted to go to and the extension x1 so
what it doesn't it makes it look like a
floating when you have refresh the site
and make it look like it's loading other
files in the site like images and in
those images the filenames themselves
are actually the data that's being sent
back and piecing it back together so
it's T to the c2 is actually a based off
of it looking like it's a legitimate
site being loaded every soft they're
random beacon intervals so it goes
between certain times you control that
you can have it done for every 30
seconds to five hours for what you want
to before it checks in and it's it up
but basically it makes it look like a
user is browsing a website in a
legitimate fashion and it's in user
agent strings everything that what's
great about this is it's so simple to go
and build a c2 platform for then
building it and c-sharp is easy building
in a car shows yeah I just did a proof
of concept of Python but all you really
need is is simply the ability to to go
to a website via a browser and have it
go to a specific origin forever and then
system commands then in a while
statements that's basically it so I have
all the examples in there I'll be
releasing a c-sharp and PowerShell
module hopefully within the next speaker
so I started working on it last night
and then I decided that get into the
trucker costume again once there's a
drink so but so I'll hopefully have that
done next week with the C sharp ones in
the partial right now on there's a good
proof concept example there from the
class set so let's take a look at all
this way
crappity dinner
I need to get adapted to actually fly
all friendly here
was I
okay
so let's take a second pop up let me get
Trevor seats ready
now if you go to the code all these
things are configurable so the user
agent strings you know the past you can
use queries you want to use you can
customize all of those all configure
boxes I have a recommend config Ram now
one thing that I'm not doing currently
that I will incorporate is the way that
they're chunked up is your command and
they on the data gets sent into base 64
encoded strings so I'll put a es in
there before I committed I just had a
chance to do so AES and then basically
spread codes and chunks up randomly
throughout the images themselves so it
was still make it look like a floating
there but I'll chalk it up to a way that
doesn't get detectors and you know
there's a stuff here if you want to use
like specific paths that actually parse
the data it's it's all really easy that
really um walks through pretty much
everything it goes through all that
stuff so what's nice though is in Python
you have what's called simple HTTP
server and base DCP server and you have
the ability to hijack they do get to do
post commands for everything so what
ends up happening is when you get
interceptive des to get if it identifies
it as a client they can put back
different data back to that client to do
the command control piece of it so
that's kind of how we handle the
instruction sets when it comes to that
so
all right
all right so everyone Trevor and it's
just a two clones rustic calm as an
example
right it's not a hacker so unless you
got a scare all right it's pretty simple
it's know what I'm gonna do here the
girl hi you dress right away
it's those two two four
I'm going to do is this is just a
perfect concept than the Python side I'm
gonna double click that and now we have
our shot running now if we want to
execute any commands we just type in a
command
don't ask
JMO it'll be fine I'll be fine
did you know didn't like that coding
change this can probably attest
well they will work I promise there goes
all right so that's a local one
community we receive response back from
the client now let me try the other side
we cancel this one
again
in his desk see if it comes back up now
I could be the random intervals I up the
timeframes for as well so city comes
back in a second
what's great about that is the random
intervals can go from low to high so it
worked up here and maybe my Windows
machines having issues communicating but
nobody knew Liscombe and she's a very
quick
[Applause]
so that's it closing I will have it
fixed before I put potion up but nice
job defenders for some of you this means
that you know probably the type of time
that I've been in MO SEC we have a
minute position like this before where
he actually at the contingency reserve
bar it's not as easy as it was before
that's a great thing that's great things
were making a difference it means we're
doing things great and we're getting
better now we have a long long long ways
to go and we're never perfect for but
we're doing awesome so thank you
[Applause]