thank you very much
this talk is a hacker's view two eyes
OSA e21 four three four and even though
the title is rather complex and sounds
like organizational security I'm trying
to get the picture on where we are
regarding automotive security and what
will happen in the next few years so I'm
Martin I'm on Twitter during the day I
work for the automotive industry but
from the supplier point of view by night
I do digital forensics and work on
applied privacy schemes so privacy is
kind of my thing in between I have a
very old car so this car is my
experience and automotive hacking mostly
but it's built in the 80s so all the
fancy parts which we have now in modern
cars are not included
not even closely so everything here
which is electric is basically electric
there's no buses to communicate there's
no e call no airbags not even seat belts
so usual disclaimer this is me not my
employer also I have the bird's eye view
on the documents but not the process so
I'm not actively involved in the process
to this standardization there are plenty
of people in the standardization process
involved so they might have a different
take on why specific elements are part
of the standard and some are not however
I think the the current draft of this
standard is in a state which is somewhat
presentable and this is why I'm here
because I think it's kind of an
important topic and I'd like to
encourage everyone to actually look into
automotive security because it's
actually fascinating itself
so all started for me at least back in
2015 when Charlie Miller and Chris
valasek they hacked the Jeep they hacked
the entertainment system remotely over
the Internet
and were able to send Khan messages this
was kind of like the super gal for the
automotive industry in the fall out they
had to recall 1.4 million cars into the
workshops which is among the most
expensive things you can have as a car
manufacturer and of course people lose
trust into your brand of cars and the
implications are numerous and that did a
pretty damaging impact an interesting
thing about the fixes so once they had
the black hat talk and this video came
online they they showed how they hacked
those jeeps and one of the things which
let them to connect these cars over the
Internet
were open ports which are reachable over
the mobile network so the car had a SIM
card in it it was used for connectivity
features pretty usual but the network
was not separated from the regular
network so everyone within the mobile a
mobile provider could find these devices
and basically this is what exactly what
they did yeah and also interesting the
quickest fix for these issues were that
the service provider they dropped
forwarding those packets and this is
like one I pee table role this was
conducted within hours so the ISP the
network operator cooperated in a way
that this issue was fixed within hours
and just in the fallout afterwards
these devices were called into the
workshops they have been patched some of
them were patched remotely and yeah it's
an interesting story how this all turns
out so this is second quite popular hack
it's a so-called relay
attack against keyless entry system so
usually when you have a keyless entry
system and I have one myself it's really
convenient when you come home you drop
the key next to the entrance and this
was caught on video how the thieves in
that particular case stole the car they
had two devices they extended the range
of the overall keyless system got into
the car drove away and we're out of the
country probably within hours
interesting thing here is that if the
key is no longer present in the car the
user gets an indication saying hey you
maybe forgot your key if you turn off
the engine you will not be able to start
it again but the engine is allowed to
run and it runs and runs it runs as long
as you do not turn it off last year
there was another black hat talk and was
by Keane Labs again they do amazing
research in vulnerability identification
and they hacked BMWs expensive ones they
do pretty pretty good stuff on the Left
there's the list of the C V's and so
forth but yeah hacking cars is common
and yeah it actually works remotely over
Wi-Fi or over wireless networks which is
kind of scary
so the overall motivation for this talk
is that vehicles are complex if you buy
a modern car you have about 100
microcontrollers in there they control
and configure everything that you move
in the car or that can be moved from
lights to airbags to brakes to the
engine everything is tightly coupled
they're highly intervened they need to
communicate with each other using
various protocols and often they have
real-time requirements meaning that if
some sensor detects a crash you really
want the airbag to detonate within
milliseconds or microseconds even to
prevent the passengers from actually
hitting the car
however security not a priority - so far
so history
bound to repeat itself we had same
issues for I don't know 30 40 years ago
when the public internet was invented
security hasn't been an issue look where
we are now it would be great if we
wouldn't have to repeat all the errors
with it back then but we're on the best
way to actually do that so this is the
the network map of a modern car it's
from a paper which took a Skoda some car
modern car 2017 model and they mapped
all the different ECU's and components
which are part of the actual car so
usually at top you have the OBD port
this is mandated by California and
us-based laws that you have to have this
diagnostic port you have then the
Gateway module which more or less
separates the different networks this
separation is not due to security
reasons would be great but actually it's
for bandwidth reasons so you couldn't
put every ECU on the same bus simply
because the bandwidth is much too small
and you can see you have different buses
you have chassis cars chassis bus you
have a comfort bus somewhere is the
infotainment system and they can
communicate with all the other buses
happily Everafter
over the Gateway and if the Gateway is
not built to actually fill the frames
and messages sent between those
different buses then this is just one
gigantic possible Broadcasting Network
another problem is that software updates
for cars are not a thing yet so we have
software updates for plenty of devices
ranging from our smartphones to
operating systems whatever you name it
and updating software and cars is still
stigmatized so every car vendor would
love to have the capability to actually
push updates over the Internet no works
have involved having them signed and
have them
transported securely but this is not yet
happening weakest part are often the
customer so I as a customer buy a brand
new car I have no say in the
architecture or the software update
policy I have no idea how long I will
receive software updates if there are
software updates planned so I'm the one
left in the dark more or less
interestingly for car manufacturers
money is a great incentive so they do
build the cars as secure as they need to
be and as they some even go further and
they derive fascinating architectures on
how to secure communication common fear
however is for wonder on the liability
in the US law meaning that if you toast
your hamster you can be liable as a
manufacturer of a toaster and insurance
cost so if there is a specific car which
is particularly easy to steal then the
insurance prices for that car will go up
and the car manufacturer will sell
actually less cars of that model so this
is kind of the the balancing act between
a car manufacturer the customer and the
rest of the world trying to be safe from
that actual threat so some background in
a car we have the so called can bus it's
a rather robust communication channel
which works very well has been invented
other than I don't know 30 years ago and
is a real-time protocol allowing
communication between different
components bandwidth is low you have
about a megabit tops usually you have
250 or 500 kilobit the payload is very
small you have 64 bits of payload per
frame meaning that if you want to add
encryption or authentication to that
this is really really challenging
because you have 64 bits of data
and you have to actually split the this
area one part for the data you want to
send a data part for a signature and I
don't know that many signature themes
schemes but 64 bit tops capacities
sounds like a real challenge to me and
of course no security built in there so
the only security in there is that you
have arbitration so if two different
components are talking at the same time
the one with the higher priority
assigned will win so you have
prioritized signals that can go back and
forth and yeah in essence this is the
holy grail for automotive hacking if you
can send raw conference it's just the
same as if you got rude on the Box it's
basically that put everything everyone
is trying to achieve the attack surface
arranged from top to bottom is also
quite large you have physical attack
surface meaning that people will try to
take out the chips and the control units
try to reflash it with different
firmware and most commonly this is used
for chip tuning so you have the car you
flash the different software and all of
a sudden you get 20 horsepower more of
course this is not allowed and shouldn't
be done but this is the the most basic
physical attack against the car there is
then you have the wireless protocols
every modern car is equipped with a
multitude of wireless communication
capabilities you have wireless key fobs
which allow you to approach the car and
enter it without actually doing anything
you just have the key in the pocket and
it works
tire pressure sensors so back in 2010
there was a neat attack against the tire
pressure sensor because they were not
communicated communicating securely and
using a radio which you could program
you could send more or less con frames
by manipulating the tire pressure values
you have the infotainment
system so all the big breaches not the
breaches but the big hacks in recent
years where cars have been hacked most
of them used the infotainment system
there was a poem to own last this year
and they Tesla participated and they
whoever hacked the car did it via the
unpatched browser and the infant nment
system yeah if you're getting physical
there's always an obd2 port in the car
it's a standardized connector you can
connect to it and then talk directly
with the car this is what every workshop
tool does to actually read out the error
messages to get an information on the
state of the car and so forth and
increasingly their back ends so every
car is connected it talks via public
network private network whatever to some
back-end it sends some data there are
API is available to act
I don't know start the heater in your
car remotely and this is also part of
the attack surface of course some
interfaces it's not only limited to con
you have a multitude of wired and
wireless protocols that the car is able
to speak you have flex rate most Lin
those are bus based systems to exchange
data at a higher data rate you have
automotive Ethernet which is not the
standard Ethernet that we put into our
walls to connect our devices but it's a
twisted pair Gigabit Ethernet still its
Ethernet so all the tools and the
different parts of the available
literature should work you have wireless
in the different spectrums which are
openly available used for key fobs or
whatever and of course convenience you
have NFC Wi-Fi Bluetooth if you have a
phone book which will be synchronized
with the car
of course that's a an attack vector as
well most of these things have no
security specified they're just built to
work with Anik
and in the challenging environment of a
modern vehicle most of them have no
security or it's optional so Bluetooth
we should all know can be made secure
but it has to be configured properly and
to actually be encrypted and
authenticated and without anyone being
able to do a man-in-the-middle attack
for example then we have gsm LTE this is
in europe mandatory so if you buy a new
car today this is mandatory to have the
e call feature if the airbag detonates
into your face it will automatically do
the call for help
usually this interface is only activated
when the airbag detonates so you don't
have the always-on connection which is
trackable body service provider but
still it's men that they mandated by law
that you have to have a SIM card in your
car which is able to actually do the e
call and you not only have one you have
multiple SIM cards so these things are
connected some of them are able to speak
GSM so you could do MC capture deployed
with a u.s. RP next to the car and try
to actually communicate with the car
over this communication channel and of
course there's vehicle to a vehicle to
vehicle communication vehicle to
infrastructure vehicle to whatever this
is currently being developed these are
protocols which we'll see in the next
five years they have security to some
extent built in there we will see which
of those protocols will prevail but
currently there are two protocols which
are discussed one is based on LTE
technology the other one is based on
Wi-Fi so they are built to communicate
the information that there is a car the
direction the speed anything you can
imagine could be transported to nearby
receivers in the future
but best security measures so far and
this is the the one of the things which
actually makes automotive hacking very
expensive if you want to hack an
expensive car you have to have access to
an expensive car and if you look at how
you have to dismantle all the different
body components to get access to the
different issues this is nothing which
will happen over the not over the night
or at the weekend so you cannot do it
with a rental car but you have to have
access to that and most people don't do
that for money but for fun so you need
to have access to a car which you can
then actually do your hacking on so this
is pretty dark pictures so we have
plenty of proprietary technology
protocols we have low accessibility for
people to actually look into these
things which doesn't look so good from a
hacker's point of view so we have
challenges in getting access to those
things we have the problem of getting
the information that would be needed
from a public point point of view to
actually look into the things and have
been implemented this is not a good
thing this is but this is the the way it
is right now there's not much we can do
so this brings me to the ISO part of the
talk there is currently a ISO standard
being drafted to actually improve the
security of cars and entire cars as well
as components so currently this is a
committee draft I don't know when it
started it's already probably three
years back when standardisation of this
process began but right now the draft is
about 120 pages some of them are only
informative so they have annexes they
have examples describing the different
steps on how to actually secure a car
it's internationally collaborated so
manufacturers are included as well as
suppliers
the general public is missing I will
come to that in the second and sometime
next year it's expected to be released
so the ISO standard procedure says that
right now we're in the community draft
phase and once there is a more or less
public draft available then the members
will vote on accepting or not accepting
this as an international standard and
this is going to happen sometime in 2020
so some fun facts when my background is
in IT so I studied computer science in
the automotive world the v-model
development process is still a thing
which is a good thing because you have
complex things and agile is not built to
suit for any case however when I first
discovered this I was like what is this
so the model development still works in
the entire draft you have 822
occurrences of the word cybersecurity so
cyber is king you have one time cyber
security with a - so they're
inconsistent and you have plenty of
risks agile only ones so what is the
draft all about
in essence it's risk management so it
takes the entire picture of how a
component or how a vehicle will be used
and tries to identify and then mitigate
the risks that can be applied against
this component or car so beat a
component or be the entire car the the
goal is to identify the risks and make
this thing secure with everything that
comes with it so not just the
development process but also the
operations and decommissioning which is
a pretty good thing it also can include
vulnerability management meaning that
any manufacturer any OEM which is
actually
committing themselves to this ISO
standard to be they have to have a
process in place to if there is a
vulnerability identified then they need
to be able to actually work on that they
need to process it they need to provide
updates and and this is a core component
of the entire standard it is based on
two things one is the functional safety
stand standard which is a big thing in
the automotive industry so there's
always the confusion between safety and
security safety is built around that the
thing you're looking at is not able to
kill you and security is always about
that someone else could use this thing
against you to kill you so well
safety is four things against humans and
Security's
four things against different set of
humans there's also a internet the sa
sae standard the security guidebook for
cyber physical vehicle systems this has
been published beginning of 2016 and
this was interesting because this came
out shortly after the like half a year
after the cheap hacks and it already
includes a multitude of steps to
actually secure things during
development it doesn't speak much about
the usage of the product and how it can
be made secure during runtime but it
includes a lot of steps during the
development process which is kind of
impressive also relevant easel 31,000
ish that's the standard risk management
thing without reading the draft this is
just common sense if you have a risk you
can identify the severity of manifesting
that risk with the likelihood of this
thing to happen so this is what we do
every time we cross the street or we
browse a website or we click an
attachment on an email that's always how
likely is it that this is
going to be bad versus what's the impact
and what will happen if I do also in
2016 d8 nhtsa the national highway
Transplant Security Agency in the u.s.
they published a best practice booklet
on cyber cyber security in cars also
shortly after the hacks this is also
pretty complete in a sense that it came
at the right time and did good however
it wasn't mandatory it can be audited
and so forth automotive industry is a
bit slow so everyone knew that it was
there
but many didn't simply care also quite
recently the UN body for economic they
drafted a standard for security in cars
as well as over-the-air updates this is
impressive because usually if the UN
comes in and draft something like this
it means that all the others are late
for the party and in 2018 there was a
California IOT security law published
which is basically for everything which
has an internet connection and is small
enough to steal it more or less which
could also mean that this applies to
cars because they have an internet
connection and they use it for all kinds
of different things one of the early
documents was kind of interesting
because it recommended using an
intrusion detection system in a car and
imagine you have this complex Beast of
networks distributed systems and then
someone tries hey wouldn't it be great
idea to actually do intrusion detection
on those signals and everybody's like
yes it could work we don't even get it
right on the internet not sure what to
look for how do you do the baselines and
so forth so this made quite some
confusing looks from my side as least
yes you have a
physically bounded thing that moves but
just doing intrusion detection on the
signals that are transmitted seemed a
bit far-fetched to me so what's in the
standard itself this is standard risk
management this is happening both for IT
systems as well as humans every day of
their lives you identify the assets what
is important to you you identify
possible vulnerabilities and then you
get resulting threats the risk value is
impact of the threat to manifest itself
times the feasibility and around these
list of risks you can then sort this
list and then start mitigating them
accordingly to the risk value also
security goals you want confidentiality
integrity availability was also for
vehicles interest is freshness and
authenticity of course you do not want
the wiper control to actually ignite the
air packs so you have authenticity in
there as well some basic examples you
have the acid the acid for example could
be the engine control unit which
actually controls the engine every part
about it for against and protected
against chip tuning goal is to preserve
the integrity of the software in their
impact could be severe so if anybody
modifies the software of the engine
control unit this could have severe
consequences while you're driving for
example engine shutting down to to a
narrow state this is not something you
would like to have and feasibility is
high because chip tuning is a thing and
you can buy tools of available online
outcome of this risk estimation is a
better do something about it protect the
integrity of the software running in
there and this is actually happening so
you have integrity protecting mechanisms
like secure boot authenticated boot
signed software updates
to actually prevent someone from
modifying the software of that
particular component if you take another
example you have the infotainment system
the thing which actually plays the
sounds of the radio or whatever it is
you're listening to goal is availability
so customers will be rather fed up if
the radio is not working or if they
cannot couple their smartphone with the
car to listen to their music so goal is
availability impact if that doesn't work
is rather low it's frustrating for
customers but at least you can die of
that and feasibility is high outcome
could be okay but it's probably not
depending on the particular
circumstances so this is happening for
every component for every vehicle
according to the draft prior to
development so before you actually start
implementing stuff you identify okay
what are the risks what are the threats
and how can I mitigate them to prevent
those threats to manifest themselves
next step then is to develop a security
concept to actually mitigate those risks
so you specifying that okay to prevent
modification of software or inspection
of communication channels you actually
encrypt them you put these things into
the requirements and they will then be
implemented these can be requirements
saying you need to encrypt every
communication with the public internet
end-to-end and you have to authenticate
it and so forth can be also not strict
could be organizational measures so
proper training of developers for
example could be a requirement to be
fulfilled that people should know okay
you're using C C is a known language to
be not memory
not good regarding security with memory
management so you would like to have
your developers trained trained the
standard then describes you develop your
software you verify that actually the
thing you built is according to the
expectation you have and then you
validate the entire concept for example
using a penetration test this is
interesting because if you apply or if
you want to follow this standard
eventually this will mean you have to
have someone externally of the
development process to actually verify
that the things you did are sane and the
product is not able to be in the
headlines this could be for one a
penetration test this could be also an
audit to check the security organization
on and so forth the good thing is it
doesn't end here because once the car is
in the field it is still a valid attack
it still has a valid attack surface so
the good thing about this particular iso
standard is that it doesn't take the
development process into scope but the
entire lifetime of that thing which is
great because usually it was you sell it
it's out there you're done as a
manufacturer but now the responsibility
lies even further until the end of life
of that particular car or component
meaning that once development is
complete you should have a list of the
residual risks specifying okay this
could happen but it's too funky to
actually mitigate it or impact is too
low to actually do something about this
these residual risks are not static so
every time a new attack arrives by some
conference presentation the first thing
you can do is take the list of residual
risk
you ate them if one of those risks gets
more likely or impact gets more severe
to redo the analysis step and then again
triage figure out what is it and how
does it work it also includes aspects
for production security some aspects of
production are rather interesting to say
it like that
having key management is useful if you
have individual cryptographic keys in
different components you really would
like to have some key management you
would like to track the serial number
with the key you need to know who is in
possession of the key and so forth and
also production is usually another one
shot so once a car is made it's made for
five six ten years then it's refurbished
or upgraded but the entire process is
not done by simply say great we're going
to production thanks for everything
it then goes even further
once the thing is in the field you have
the operations and the maintenance phase
where actually incidents can happen so
you as the producer have to monitor you
have to triage for incidents and then to
proper Incident Response so figuring out
okay how did this attack okay did you
can you verify that it actually is valid
and then to incident response in the end
of the day it boils down to update so
once some issue is identified that needs
an update there has to be a process in
place to actually to updates
it also trickles down the supply chain
so if you're just as a manufacturer
getting components you will likely need
your supplier to be able to ship updates
and so forth so this is our current
position at least my that we are part of
the supply chain we have suppliers
ourselves and now the responsibilities
trickle down to two
the last end of the supply chain like
the chip makers or the manufacturers
which are contracted this will be
interesting and in the end you have at
the Commission phase so once this thing
is no longer expected to be alive it can
be killed and then responsibilities
regarding security ends that's it so
what's my take on this basically I think
it's a great approach it to make this an
international standard cars are rolling
distributed system with attack surface
as large as the butt of an elephant
more or less so cars are currently a
challenge to secure them properly one
thing on the standardization process ISO
has a business model of actually selling
those standards so they are not keen on
open development of these standards
which is in my particular view not a
great thing to have so standard this
asian process is closed and E's have to
be signed every time I talk to someone
if I can get a copy of the current draft
for example then I have you signed the
NDA yes of course of scientist
however it's 2019 soon to 2020
I really thought we are over this the
quote Kenny Patterson Kenny Patterson is
my hero in back in the standardization
of TLS 1.3 there was a discussion about
RSA's RSA key transport someone from the
banking industry came and said hey we
thought we could keep RSA key exchange
alive because we needed were need to
comply with the laws and Kenny Patterson
then responded you're a bit late to the
party
further down he said I know the banking
industry is usually a bit slow but this
takes the biscuit with the
UK dryness of humor
so I would really like to see more
openness in developing such standards
because it could make sense to include a
broader range and in the end someone
will complain they have not been
involved they didn't participate in the
standardization process or they are not
keen on actually following it as usual
with everything that is technical
related with risk and the devil is in
the details so if one of the good things
that comes out of this standard is that
the awareness is made that okay you need
entick ation you need to encrypt your
communication and so forth but the devil
is always in the details so there is
likely to be a project or a vendor or I
don't know sure where you take your
privacy series but sure we use secure
boot but we store the key in unprotected
memory these are likely phrases that
might or might not actually happen but
if they eventually happen I call dibs on
them yeah sure we use TLS but we don't
pin has happened for smartphone apps has
happened for everything on the Internet
I find it unlikely to that the
automotive industry is not repeating
this sure we have individual keys but no
true random number generator so this is
the Sony flaw which may or may not
actually manifest itself in actually
weakening encryption than increasing it
so don't wanna jinx it but I think the
this standard will be good mostly
because people will at least
manufacturer suppliers and customers
have something to talk about so they
have a specific set of recommendations
and requirements that they can walk
along
however cars are really really complex
they
have again an attack surface as large as
a tent and it's all in the details we'll
see how that works out so I'm optimistic
but I'm rather optimistic person however
feel that we as a community and in
particular as technicians who actually
tinker with our physical things can work
on improving that thank you very much
[Applause]
is there a microphone angel running
around you have a microphone I'll repeat
the question for the stream so the
question was if there's anything
regarding autonomous driving in there
not specifically no this is a distinct
topic there are there's a different SAE
a standard which defines different
levels of autonomous driving that I'm
aware of but that doesn't doesn't
include security so they are kind of
distinct and of course if you want to
have autonomous driving it's a good
thing to actually include security so
the awareness is is there in that regard
but it's not included in this standard
any other questions
great so I'll be around I think next
item on the timetable is lunch thank you
very much
[Music]
[Applause]