hello so yeah the speech will be about
the operationalization of attack
framework for security operation centers
and today I will present to you the
atomic fred coverage project which is
free open source available on the github
and i'm working on it with few of my
friends so who am i who we are
my name is mateo I'm working as incident
responder in theater important
originally this presentation supposed to
be conducted together with Daniel Lucas
Lasky who work as threat detection head
of fraud detection in syndicator in
Russia unfortunately he was not able to
to get here so I will present along and
presentation will be a bit shorter and
we also have two other colleagues Jakob
Benson who works as Fred detection
specialist in theatre Poland and Mikhail
axon of working as automation team lead
in business Russia
okay so first question please raise your
hand if you are familiar with
intelligent driven defense okay I can
see some hands so
basically it has really straightforward
assumptions know your enemy if you want
to be able to defend yourself you have
to know how adversary operates what are
their strengths and what are their
weaknesses it is very popular in
military I'll taught in cybersecurity it
wasn't that popular a few a few years
back from now but it changed when in my
2000 in May 2015
my true corporate corporation released
the attack framework which operates
based on on this approach and is the
threat model so I'm pretty sure that
most of you guys are familiar with this
one but just to be sure that we are on
the same page more or less that's how it
looks like this is the enterprise matrix
from from this framework and we have the
twelve columns which represent the
tactical objective and inside desserts
we have the technical implementation to
achieve the tactical goals so quite
simple columns are the tactics in sauce
we have the techniques that's how simple
technique looks like this is
exfiltration over alternative protocol
we have the description some of the
example of usage and high level
description of mitigation and and
detection for this specific technique
however there are some problems mostly
opera and nationalization problems so
description from my terror attack is to
high level it's not actionable so you
cannot simply take this page pass it to
to your team and ask for these guys
could you detect these activities or
could you mitigate it
the second thing is kind of consequence
of the first problem which is lack of
ability to explain requirements so it
does not provide us the information what
exactly we have to configure how to
configure it and where to configure it
another problem is reporting to the
leadership so what is the current
coverage
what is the progression when when when
you decide to work with the might of
attack framework so the problem of
coverage is currently in the community
there is no like common definition of
what the coverage really is when you can
say that you already covered the
technique and you can go to the next one
so our view on this looks like this so
basically there are four pillars which
have to be fulfilled to be able to say
that yes we are covering the technique
those are the simulation detection
response and mitigation and only if you
have the entities related to to those
pr's you can say that yes I am
conferring the the technique or at least
the known usage of of the technique so
we implemented this kind of the approach
but we want to build a tool which will
allow us to do do more things in an
automatical way so less less manual job
more automation and we set a few
requirements for ourselves
first of all plain text files this has
some historical reasons when we
initially implemented this approach we
were using the confluence for storing
the
knowledgebase and it's required from us
a lot of manual job when we when we are
editing something or when we were adding
the new entities so we wanted to make it
simple and as I said we wanted to make
it as automatic as automated as as
possible so automate almost everything
so yeah regarding those four pillars we
have the entities which are related to
2000 and I would like to quickly show
you what we choose or what we've built
that for those purposes so when when it
comes to the simulation we decided to
use atomic reading project this project
was already mentioned yesterday so this
is the tool for emulation of of the
adversary what's cool is that it also
has the execution frameworks so you can
define the list of the tests which you
would like to execute and quickly
execute all of them on the test system
to check how to check what you are able
to detect or what you can mitigate
that's how simple trigger looks like so
we have the mapping to miter attack
which is really important for us and we
have the test which consists basically
of the commands which will be executed
on the test systems so once we are able
to emulate the adversary we would like
to detect it and for this we decided to
use the Sigma format Sigma is a generic
signature format for DCM systems and
it's getting really popular right now
and the concept is quite simple so there
is the Sigma format in which you are
serving the rows and there is the Sigma
converter which can convert those rules
into the queries for multiple search
systems like elastic search Splunk
karada arcsight basically many of them
and that's how it looks like we have the
roll with with the simple description we
have D tagging for the Matic attack
matrix and we have the conditions which
are necessarily to match for the rule to
trigger on some specific event so now we
need a data which could be analyzed by
by this rule and for to store
information about about the data we
decided to create the date and
identities again simple Yamla format we
have here the example of of the log the
fields which are inside where it comes
from so what is the source and there is
another problem because a lot of logs
are not are not produced by default so
you have to configure something and to
track this information you also have the
reference to logging policy here and
that's how logging policy looks like so
a sample step by step configuration what
has to be to be what has to be
configured and where to to be able to
collect the the data point in terms to
security operations center especially if
in the managed service providers you may
want to track what is what you are what
we are collecting and what is
implemented per customers so another
simple entity when which you can use for
tracking and when it comes to the
internal security teams this might be
not external customer but some group of
the hosts or even some specific some
specific server if you want to go
further you may want to enrich the data
and to store information how to do this
we also have the enrichment and it is so
again simple description requirements
for the enrichment if it adds new new
fields they are also listed here and the
config which is needed for the
enrichment will be also presented inside
such entity
when it comes to the response part we
are using the small response actions
with the workflow what to do in case of
of the response and response plates are
built with with those response actions
so they are just small building blocks
which are used here so you can reuse
same response action in multiple play
books and if you will update one of your
response actions all of the play books
will be also updated and also some other
information here like tax information
about the severity PLP PAP and so on
okay so know as that's how our tool
looks like under the hood so the
entities in the young format which I
just showed you are ingested into the
Python script there with some black
magic everything is mapped to each other
and calculated and the dependent
dependencies between the entities are
calculated and then this data is
exported to multiple format which can be
analyzed or ingested into other
platforms and following our make it
simple principle we decide to use simple
Linux make utility for orchestrating the
the usage of our tour so we found simple
command most of the things will be
generated so the underlying sub modules
like Sigma or atomic read team will be
updated and since those are added as
these sub modules if you have your own
locale fork of those projects we've some
built in house rules or all the triggers
you can attach your own fork of those
project it will set up the confluence
and the markdown repository and push
data there as for the knowledge
and the confluence is not the
requirement exactly the same data will
be presented in both of those formats it
will create the attack navigator
profiles which can be further analyzed
the playbooks will be exported to d hive
templates and i will show to you how it
looks like in the moment and the data
will be also exported to elasticsearch
index so you can do further analysis
inside the Cabana ok and time for small
demo
okay so yeah once you will upload all of
the data to the confluence and as I
mentioned same data can be reviewed in
the markdown files you will get the tree
with folders for all of the entities and
their human readable in the human
readable format so let's take a look at
sample detection rule how it looks like
here this one okay so we have the table
with the metadata and all the links here
are let's say clickable so they will
take you straight to 2d related entities
so this can be easily used as the
knowledge base and in the bottom you
will find the original unmodified Sigma
rule and generate that queries and this
part is configurable so if you are if
you are using one system but not another
and you want to save some resources in
the configuration you can choose in
which queries you you are interested
okay so just for demo purposes here we
can go to the page with with the date I
need that again nicely rendered role
example here so you can pass this page
to see empty more data engineers to show
them what exactly they should expect and
link to the login policy so with one
click you have exact configuration what
to do to collect such data okay and
let's go back to 2d
the detection rule for a moment here it
will also automatically create the link
to the atomic red team test for for this
technique and in current version it's
it's only matched based on the technique
so it might appear that inside the
trigger there will be no actual trigger
for for this rule but since my two
recently announced the sub modules but
not sub modules but sub techniques we
believe that with these sub techniques
it will be much easier to to assign the
correct triggers so here is the human
readable with some HTML tags here's the
human readable version of the trigger so
you can you have the quick access to
document if you would like to perform
some kind of of the testing okay and
let's take a look how sample response
playbook looks like so again similar
fashion nicely rendered table or of the
links are clickable here here but the
response actions will be also rendered
in the bottom so it's a good for the
knowledge base but such playbooks are
not really actionable so we are also
exporting them in the format which might
be imported to the hive platform if this
is the case management platform it was
built by incident responders for
incident responders and it's pretty
awesome it has a lot of possibilities
for the automation and integration with
another projects like cortex or or Mis
so if you are out and it's free and open
source so if you are looking for a good
internet management platform you may
want to take a look at this one okay so
here we can import
the template which was created by ADC
okay and all of the response actions now
will be just a tasks here and
additionally the information about
severity and so on will be pre-populated
here so if we will create the sample
case based on this template just test
case yeah so that's how guys now looks
like we have the description and in the
tasks all of the response actions are
are the tasks so you can assign it to
yourself or assigned to someone from
from your team and start working on case
having the pre build that template for
it okay and when it comes to the
measuring the coverage I've mentioned
that we are exporting data to the attack
navigator profile so little is available
on the internet but the code is also
published on the github so you can spin
up the your own instance of this insider
inside your environment so you can
import existing template and yet for now
as you can see we are exporting we are
creating the profiles per customers and
one general with with all of the data
from from the project so let's import
this one and here we go we have we have
highlighted all of the techniques for
which we already have some kind of
DeRose this is really good for the gap
analysis if you want to measure your
coverage from detection point of view or
when you have to present your
progression to the higher management
okay and the last demo I also mentioned
that we are exporting data to elastic
search index which can be then ingested
to
instance and this one also might be used
for this one also might be used for
reporting to higher management or
measuring your current progression so
this is the sample dashboard it was
built based on all available all
publicly available Sigma rules for the
Windows systems we've created this one
on 24th of this September so it's quite
up to date so some of the sample
analysis which which might be showed
here ok so first of all we see how much
rules we have per different tactics
another thing is just sample analysis is
the distribution of detection rules
implemented per customer so we can
easily track how many of rules which
we've developed are already implemented
in some environments and which are just
inside inside your organization and you
are not detecting anything with them
another thing is the distribution of
data in these providers so which data
sources provides your ability to
implement more rules and you can easily
see that almost half of the publicly
available C models currently are based
on the assessment data once almost 44
percent is based on the Microsoft
Windows security auditing box
another thing is distribution of
detection rules the distribution of the
detection was summary deeper than ended
providers so here you can also easily
see that this one is not only that's not
only allows you to implement more of the
rules but it will allows you to detect
more critical stuff so if you have this
conversation with higher management to
install system system on or not to
install sis
on this might be used as as a good point
in in such argument ok another
distribution is the detection rules
development status so it's easy to track
which rules are still in experimental
phase and you have to test them which
are ready for production and might be
implemented ok and in the in the bottom
just a list of the detection routers top
10 of them and stopped and that I needed
so here you can easily see that system
on process creation is in the first
place the second one is the Windows
process creation with the command line
ok and let's go to the presentation so
some of the conclusions what we what we
achieved currently we have the mitre
attack detailed enough for the
operationalization so we can take the
technique and you can easily find which
data we need to detect it how to him how
to collect the this data what has to be
configured to be able to detect it and
so what are the mitigation systems which
we would like to which we might want to
use for for the mitigation we are using
analytics as a code so because we are
working only with plain text diamo files
we can use version tracking systems like
github or gitlab to track our
progression and see what was changed in
in the rules or in other entities we
have total automation so all of the
exports mapping uploads and updates now
are made with one simple command and as
i mentioned before that a lot of the
stuff we were doing manually and it was
taking a lot of time so now we have more
time to focus on more important things
we are able to visualize
existing analytics for analysis so as I
showed you with sample dashboard in
inside Cabana we can easily represent
what is what is our progression and show
it to our higher management we also have
automated coverage representation so
those my trip Navigator profiles
currently we are generating them only
for the from the detection point of view
but soon we will also generate the
profiles for mitigation and mitigation
response and simulation point of view
and actually that's the first thing on
our list of ongoing works another the
second thing is the full Sigma support
so currently we have all of the data
which is needed for covering all of the
windows-based rows but we are also
working on the Linux part and network so
probably soon it will be we will be able
to say that we are fully covering the
current rule set from from the Sigma we
also initiated the open security
collaborative development sprint and if
you are interested in that one there is
a link pointing to the page with more
information so basically this will be
activity on the hacker conference in
looks and work in ten days if I remember
correctly and it will focus on improving
the existing Sigma rules and creating
new new detection rules based on
existing and new result early and new
research we are also
discussing the collaboration with the
awesome project awesome project is the
project from Roberto Rodriguez which
deals with data dictionary so it's kinda
similar to what we have in our data
needed so to not duplicate the work we
are looking for some kind of D
collaboration on on this part we would
also like to speed projects into modules
because if you will go to our github
page right now the readme is like
extremely long it has detailed
information about everything and we
would like to split it and for now
mitigation systems are just the sub
modules so all information is in sub
modules so it will also allow some kind
of the integration if someone would like
to use only part of of the project we
also have the ongoing conversation with
miss regarding integration with with the
Miss galaxy project and we are working
on the web application with API so our
project could be queried by my different
projects or individuals for some of our
entities or our analytics so we are
warmly welcome any kind of the feedback
or suggestions so if you if you have any
you can contact us if you would like to
contribute we also have the list of the
open issues and the github Timo page of
the confluence which I showed you is
available on the internet so you can
find it under the first link if you
would like to see how how it looks like
same goes for Dima of of the dull parts
in Cabana this is also available in the
in the Internet this is the second link
and you have to authenticate there and
we also have Twitter so if you want to
follow the project from time to time we
are publishing there are some some
information so yeah if anyone has any
question I am ready to answer ok since
that there are no questions so thank you
very much for your attention
[Applause]