good morning hello and welcome the 11th
edition we are so glad to be here right
now because we have to be honest it has
been a very difficult year for us as an
organization last year we had the 10th
edition we really hyped up to the 10th
edition we put a lot of efforts in there
and it's not like we didn't want to put
a lot of efforts in the 11th edition but
it was just a difficult year for us as a
coup so some people got married some
people took all the jobs which made them
obviously I have other priorities in
life and that's not always easy but I'm
not here to share only negative news so
but I just wanted to tell you guys this
that we're so glad we're here I was so
glad to see that we've kicked it off so
second of all again this year we sold
out much quicker than last year so it
took us about three weeks little over
three weeks and we were sold out last
year it was about a month month and a
half before we completely sold out and
we actually sell out
alright Achatz again before we publish
any schedule this is to us a very
positive thing because we know that you
guys trust in the schedule we're gonna
build later on and you buy tickets
anyway or you just buy it because we
have beer that could be also a reason
alright so it's hard to judge but then
again thank you again for being in such
great numbers thank you again for all
the support I mean we really love doing
this we're all volunteers but we always
so happy whenever we started we come to
see this in the morning seeing the
amount of people coming up to us and
saying hey guys we love doing this and
thank you again so and on that note you
have people in red and orange shirt so
the people in the red shirts or more the
crew the orange are people who are
volunteering it's thanks to all of them
all of their time all their if they put
tune into this that we can arrange a
broken like this so please give them a
round of applause
[Applause]
okay then a few practical things so
tonight we have our mentor-mentee night
this year will be in the Novotel again
but in the basement the idea is a bit
that you subscribe you can do it there
on the spot or beforehand via the
website and then we have a nice
interconnecting where you can talk to
other peers really to look for mentor
mentees see if you can help them out you
can help each other out where to go in
the IT security career field then all of
you got this fancy badge you heard there
is a temporary firmware on this so our
bad guy jean-georges who worked the
trudy entire nights to get this working
he is working through the entire day to
get a more version of the frame already
with more features we will announce it
on Twitter and say it here when it's
ready in the ICS first you'll be able to
go to flash your badge with the
up-to-date firmware and everything but
for now it's already working partially
you can see the map now you can see the
schedule so that's the basic
functionality if anyone of you want to
help out we will open the gate
repository as well you can push code if
you would be up for helping next year
also let us know the night the United
also will be a party it'll be in the
same location as last year its Lobato
all information is in the booklet so you
can find there and we hope to see you
all tonight ok I think that's that's
about it
yeah speaking of okay enjoy the
conference have fun
these are questions come and find us
enjoy buchamma thank you
[Applause]