all right thank you thank you for the
invitation everyone had a good lunch now
hopefully I've got to try keep you awake
for the next few hours but I do I am
told there are bears later on and if all
else fails I got an extra beer at the
front here free run so my name is
Controlman chief security officer for
the cloud nai groups with inside
Microsoft
yeah Microsoft's a very big company
basically what the areas that I'm
responsible for are looking at the next
year plus of security technologies that
we're going to build and apply and the
longer term vision for Microsoft on the
security front and so to talk about well
topics and I thought most have probably
for the intro for the team here or for
the group here it was really about
looking at how seam has changed so
security incident response incident and
event management how it's changed and
where it's going next the reason for the
change is that well I think you if you
be watching the news fairly recently you
would have seen an awful lot about cloud
seam and a cloud native seen both in
particular from Microsoft with Azure
Sentinel and Google with their Chronicle
solutions and so these are all cloud
based but more poorly AI based so when I
started looking at doing Incident
Response in event management a long time
ago how many of you you know had have
begun their sort of security security
careers about 20 years 20 years ago
looking at things like does anyone
remember site protector Internet
Security site protector none okay well
that's right so over the years the
technology required to analyze threats
to
to investigate compromises and perform
response has changed fundamentally
during that time so 20 years ago if
you're appalled analysts effectively you
had tree type dialogues to start
navigating and trying to find out what
was a big red light and what it actually
meant that's already well and so a
couple of years later the first
generation of scene technologies came
out we're effectively take all of those
logs from all of your typically your
network defenses load means one place
and then scroll through those logs right
that didn't really work too well
you know and so if you're a good analyst
you would have just furtively if you
know give me the command line and write
scripts to investigate and hunt through
your scene technology to find those
particular threats that was okay until
the volume of data started increasing
dramatically right and then we started
to move on so if I start think in my
career about 2006 throughout 2012 watch
its technology then switched from seam
and command line to Hadoop clusters you
know so using Hadoop and and no sequel
type engines to be able to group and
cluster types of events together and
then start analyzing and looking for
threats and that was good except that
you know you have to be a bit of a data
scientist and more importantly you
probably had to have you know if you've
ever built Hadoop clusters and try to
manage them you've probably spent about
90% your time just trying to you know
manage the Hadoop cluster is about Tim
and 10 % neat i'm actually trying to get
data out of their systems and so
technology changed move on the server
and so really today much of the
technology you'll find for looking at
security events and security logs is
really graph based technologies so in
particular AI based graphing and log
analytics time systems so that's been
the 20-year journey I think that the
part where we are today is this thing
called cloud seam yeah and you know
wherever you pick up the press today you
will
and lots and lots of notations about
this whole thing about cloud seam I
wanna step back a little bit on that and
and that is there was a different type
of seam on what that actually said
already means right so if you like today
there are three classes of seam and they
get cold cloud in various ways so you've
got your on-premises seam
okay so effectively this is my wrecked
hardware
it's basically sliced by the largest
load I think I'm going to analyze and it
will have local salt connector so local
controls and connectors for sending new
commands to say BitDefender or to your
Cisco reality Cisco routers or firewalls
the bottleneck for that type of seam has
always been data retention so many of
the co-operators took their yeah over
the last three or four years took their
on premises you know ten wraps solutions
and we effectively put them onto virtual
machines and then loaded them up into
the clouds okay so at that point you
have infrastructure as a service type
hosting of seam with a pairs interface
so you know a nice little web interface
for controlling that is that's right you
get a little bit of cloud scaling
effects normally from rapid scaling
across horizontally from a data
structure side but many ways you can
sort of think of you know that first
generation or that that stepping stone
of generation of trailed seam was really
sort of a managed type of service the
biggest bottleneck with that type of
approach has really been the I as
pricing so by moving from on premises of
the cloud you're not really making use
of anything that anything from the cloud
side you were favorably using the cloud
is you know a next to no external
hosting provider cloud seemed
particularly becomes cloud native it
starts changing the way that we look at
these things so we moved to a layered
SAS model and more often to a service
like of architecture so hyper scalable
and or no dimensions
importantly when you look at the you
know the solutions in this area is now
AI enables and it's AI by defaults
and more importantly I think here when
we look at the seams technologies are
changing especially now
DevOps compliant is mandatory right and
so the DevOps cycle is now built into
the cloud seem the bottleneck
interesting and I'll cover this in
question so detail really is the
bottleneck lies and the labeling process
so what that really means is that I've
got all this data I'll always have all
this data I'm very good at hunting
through the data the machines are even
better at finding things through the
data it's just that the machines find
things that have no labels and requires
an expert to understand and then decide
on how to respond to things that the the
cloud throws up one of the big trends
right my season one I think for most
people understand when it comes to
security information technology's really
is the state of trend of this for like
this hockey stick approach to data and
data volume so today if you look at that
volume of data I sort of break it down
into a number of areas so if it's
visible is this the volume of data is
increasing doubling tripling you know
every week in some instances so what
constitutes that security data so we're
talking about alerts events and logs
also engage us with the telemetry right
flows from the network devices threat
intelligence TTP's and detonations their
Nations is not familiar with that or is
effectively you know a lot a lot more
work has gone on taking a malicious link
malicious URL or a suspicious file and
then opening it and in a controlled
environments watching what happens in
extracting those behaviors and so over
that time while those sort of
technologies have changed and we've it
add more technologies to their space the
role and the use of steam has changed so
you know if your organization really
started with a steam technology and
you're a large organization you probably
walked up to the stage you have the seam
of seams because an individual seam
couldn't handle this type of data going
forward now the rest of the cloud native
seam is the only ready area that we can
start dealing with the true huge volumes
of data that we have to deal with
under the cover and so you know this one
here is a you know the background and
like as your Sentinel from a cloud seam
but it'll be the same type of approach
for anyone that sort of close goes well
native so fending me from left and right
you have the data collection so that
they logs the custom maps and the
information that's being passed through
there right so go through a passing
engine and at an ingestion stage
there'll be a number of connectors so
for example where the syslog and other
types of connectors the vendors
themselves of those devices will make
their own connectors there'll be network
connectors and there will be custom data
connectors for your own organizations
and your own applications that you sort
of built the next stage if I have those
connectors is effectively normalization
so how do I convert all these different
let's say I have three different vendors
for vulnerability scanning right and
they all call us you know they all call
and I cross-site scripting vulnerability
have slightly different names and
different sort of descriptions I need to
normalize those to bring them down into
one description and to be able
understand and track that from a mapping
perspective if I had to look at all the
areas of security and where we are today
and particularly from a sim technology I
think that that normalization phase is
one of the areas that all probably would
I would like to get rid of as fast as
possible you know the normalization
phase loses a lot of data and a lot of
new intelligence their way so once it
belies that data we then move on to so
if you like the storage and so today's
storage really can break them down to
three classes of storage so log
analytics so effectively have I tackle
those logs and story in this searchable
database blob storage so all the f of
mation that can't be you know stored in
individual logs or individual analytics
and then a graph DB so taking some of
these the metadata some of the
highlights and being able to use that as
a mapping between intelligent clusters
after that yeah the next area of cloud
native AI really is about how to build
and train the models for detection and
classification
and we'll cover that in normal detail
after I've got these sort of you know
machine learning models or AI models
then I can move on to enrichments okay
so they'll be taking and threat
intelligence living analyst blow up
their own bookmarks and building up
their own data sets and query science
and security graphing okay so be able to
take that threat hunting experience
through graph and convert that back into
a replayable playbook for example and
then the last stage really serve and
visualize so the UX which is always
great fun to sort of play around with
better though on the day-to-day side and
from the sock operations really moving
into the search and sort of detection
type technologies so if that's the sort
of if you like the core chunks of steam
technology how do these think will play
out okay so when I look at where is the
cutting edge today for seem in
particular the threat hunting experience
and if you like how these things aren't
going to evolve I think it's a good idea
to take a snapshot of where they're you
know if we're the state of the artist
today so first of all should be without
any argument the state of the art is
cloud native okay the big thing here is
all the data all the time okay and it's
really hard to understand or to stress
how important that is and how we go
change that is so traditionally if you
want by the number of hard drives they
had and at the speed of access then
maybe I could you know analyze their
threat hunts and retrospectively threat
hunt through say ninety days 180 days
okay if you've been following things
like the Verizon reports threat reports
or the IBM reports or I don't know you
name the next 53 reports that sort of
come out every month or every quarter or
every half year what you'll find is that
probably the average time to detection
of a compromised is somewhere between
about 190 to 200 days so that's the
average right
that means said of your seemed really
needs to have probably about three years
maybe five years of data stored in it
for you to be able to sue look for
threats hunt for threats investigate
threats and draw out some instant
response plans against and to manage
against them Devaki piece about being
cloud native obviously being hyper
scalable but also the cloud automation
okay so when when I look at cloud seam
what I also focus on what my mind on is
all of the workloads that are also in
the clouds okay and this is a new area
really of as organizations move from
on-premise and have a mix of different
you know I think the on-premise security
environment has about a hundred and
seventy different types one hundred and
seventy classes of technology and about
seventy different vendors on average
okay what time you move to the clouds
and running advanced workloads you down
to about ten to twelve vendors and about
seventy technologies but those
technologies can be heavily weighted
towards the cloud provider as part of
that package though the cloud providers
also providing all the automation that
surrounds them the next big piece really
is visual investigation ok so moving on
from simple queries and entity matching
to now be able to traverse between
entities such as users assets apps and
URLs but also now between activities
okay so logins transfers usage or the
telemetry all these statistics about
connections and work places they go
forward and more importantly what we're
now thunderously is the growth of new
AIS that actually automate that visual
integration visual investigation process
of being able to predict what you're
going to be able to click on and provide
the best answer going forward the next
part of cutting-edge is really the use
of machine learning notebooks so the
ability to be able to create your own
machine learning classifiers train your
own data sets be able to
provide a almost an advanced scripting
approach to automate a hunting going
forward more importantly be able to take
these take these notebooks and be able
to pass them on to other teams inside
your organization or be able to share
them as playbooks externally and once
the third slot there I could create many
many slides on this year but if it delay
AI right so at the at the large public
cloud sites at cloud service providers
side AI is pretty much everything that
goes on behind the scenes here so for
example a key things that I'm most
interested from the AI side kill chain
and attack or reassembly should we clear
here does everyone raise your hand if
you don't know anything about school
chains raise your hand if you don't know
that mitre attack framework okay a few
unfortunately there's only a few of you
here are you happy to talk about a
little bit later but the attack
framework is really where a lot of the
technologies are now changing and moving
to so you know upgrading from cool
trainer type approaches into the attack
framework and attack reassembly also
moving onto nominated based detection
auto training of classifiers so the
ability to train up an AI to solve a
particular class of threats or to
identify a kill chain and be able to
then take that model and deploy
somewhere else and to relearn a new
environment so for example for me to be
able to take a create a machine learning
algorithm for spotting impossible travel
type scenarios for email brute-forcing
or email access train that up inside the
nsrc socket and then be able to deploy
that into on-premise seemed forever
customers and for it to relearn and to
be able to stop detecting new that class
of threat almost immediately
give you an idea of scale and why this
is important okay
so one of the things that as a cloud
provider perhaps one of the most common
scary attacks that I see is this
particular event so what happens is that
some bad guys guessed the password or
the login credentials for a customer's
workspace so for their subscription so
they compromised the identity of the
subscription owner they then log in they
create a service principle so if Italy a
new account for being able to manage the
the workloads or manage the subscription
they then add that newly created
principle to the admin for that
subscription and then they start doing
bad things
so extricated data locking out systems
spitting up Bitcoin mining all these
sort of things so that first thing you
know looking for these types of things
you know how do I go about this so today
you know using the from the azure
customer's perspective I see about 300
billion identity logins right per month
4.1 billion active directory admin
actions in about 3.2 billion as your
admin actions okay so you can mention if
you had your seam store on-premise I've
probably filled up your seam already
just with the data that you know that's
required for looking at there's one
class of threats now as I started using
user behaviors and start looking at
anomalous behaviour for those detections
that can start shrinking these things
down right so if I'm looking for if I
can start identifying behaviors say that
these actions happen ants weakens our
happen in sequence and they were
happening at a time that is you know
outside the normal business hours of
that organization and things like this
right I can start shrinking that down to
about 28 million so great for billions
down to millions of identity detections
you know 20 million anomalous active
directory actions and two million
anomalous as your Azure actions
now if I'm smart I start converting into
graph type relationships okay
and so the graph taught relationships I
then start applying probabilistic kill
chain model to this okay and so I start
bringing all that all that data down to
a 50 320 graphs or sub graphs which you
know it's a big month at the moment
rates at about 18 cases okay so if you
sort of think from from an analyst
perspective without that the use of
artificial intelligence but more
particularly the use of graft it might
graphic technologies I was still be
trying to sift through those three
hundred plus billion events to find out
some you know which ones are actually
resulted in something we're bout to
result something bad okay so so from my
perspective and as we as we go forward
from as a cloud provider I have to
approach everything from this type of
scale okay
anything that I start looking at that
requires those starts or requires a
human to be involved in is going to be a
failure from the first start right so I
have to look at a different different
way so what we've also had over the time
is that there's been changes in the way
that hunters think okay so was all about
alerts yeah
let's go you know we'll stack these
alerts from green through to reds or
into brown depending on your car theme
yeah and you start with a bound and work
down okay then we start moving on to
event correlations so just instead of
looking for individual alert sort of
bring these alerts together as clusters
and be able to say this these number
alerts represented a kill an attack
pattern right and that have had and then
develops into timelines and kill chain
reassembly for the last couple of years
there's mode you know that's changed
into the mitre attack framework yeah and
being able to build up the Year the
attack attribution that goes behind
there and we're today from for a
machine-learning site particular is that
of a labeling and the training of
response systems interesting one here
what he is from a threat hunter
perspective you know for for many
organizations almost the
the role as a security professional the
role that many people aspire to today is
the threat hunter right and particularly
to be that the top the best threat
hunters there are inside an organization
the question of god though is that with
all the data that's coming in into your
organization how many of you here do
three hunting of some degree ok so most
of the hands here how many of you you
know raise your hand if you you if you
spend more of your day proactively
hunting as opposed to having to just
clean up and investigate stuff that
someone else pointed out ok three or
four hands ok so the interesting thing
is that despite all these types of
technologies that are out there and they
the growth of tray hunting threat
hunting is still largely about instant
response and retroactive looking at
threats investigation of threats ok
what we're also finding though is that
we're getting more data so our ability
to acquire and process data and so the
cloud has resulted in customers and
organizations turning on more logging
richer logging more events and passing
more data through and so we're into this
sort of you know hamster wheel of more
data creating more work providing more
visibility into the threats however we
have less time to investigate them from
a human perspective and from you know
from a human perspective were also it's
getting further away from when the event
actually happens so we're doing
retractors retroactive hunting now an
interesting part of that really
translates into it used to be from a
funding perspective it was hunting for
needles in the haystack ok now if the
types of systems that we have what we
end up is that we end up with a haystack
of needles instead more often than not
we've now moved on from a haystack of
needles into haystacks labeled haystacks
with needles right and so we have to
figure out ways to prioritize the way
that we investigate going forward so
that privatization comes in minis or
reforms and so you know a large part of
today really focuses on
how do we train AI systems to understand
to replicate what the human beings doing
how do we you know engage the human and
the labeling process but how do we
actually score these types of events and
so that we can really you know we can
reprioritize those what so what we're
seeing is a lot of integration of
combining internal intelligence and
third-party intelligence together yeah
and in the case of the attack framework
also the TTP's you know tools tectus and
processes of the bad guys to be able to
provide attribution but as haystacks
themselves keep on growing okay and so
despite for many organizations they may
break their hunting teams into malware
teams apt teams and other specialized
threats those hey states just keep on
growing so move you know so for many
organizations what we're finding is that
there still swamps no matter how many
more people that come on what we also
find is that the more security
acknowledges that deployed the more
haystacks wind up creating needle stack
should we same so that sort of moves
really on to cloud native threat hunting
okay so we have to relook at all the
tooling and all the process that we've
used in the past and Nunley reinvent
them that's fundamentally changed the
way we do these things so first of all
all the data all the time okay so let me
evaluate data is no longer a bubble next
a retention period is important ideally
as a threat hunter you want to get as
much as that data and stored it for as
long as possible however if you ask your
CFO you know your chief legal officer
they'll probably say no more than seven
years or no more than three years
because of the legal constraints that
are on this on these things it also
means that you can hunt across larger
periods of time with new TI okay so if
you're about seven years you may get the
latest batch of threat intelligence from
Verizon report or whatever you can go
back through those seven years and find
out when you were there may have been
potentially compromised through that the
other part is actually learning from
every single successful hunt so from the
good guys side you know as you find
and stuff through this type of data find
these particular threats being able to
describe that threat and labeling its
machine then learns from that and so
that you don't need to repeat that
process going forward ok and there's of
course to assemble and collate all that
data together so what are these things
that look like you know here's just a
snapshot of as your Sentinel from two
weeks ago before I was traveling here
what you see is a difference of approach
to from the threat analyst perspective
so here what I've just grabbed is the
different way of looking at the hunting
procedure so you sort of see in this top
right-hand corner the mitre attack
framework so being able to take instead
of having a look at an entire kill chain
and try to piece together a kill chain
from a graphical pace a graphical
perspective start breaking the down
breaking that down to individual
components so for example long genus URI
queries for example which is part of you
know it was a row so she netted with a
number of TTP's for bad actors and start
managing and hunting on that and that
aspect what you see is this gage of
providing the attack framework the
ability to search and hunt on these
individual things or collectively and
ability to modify create your own
queries and then build compound queries
going forward if that's one way of sort
of viewing how other technologies that
are changing I think the next part
really is understanding what the clouds
and cloudy I actually brings the table
from a security experience so here made
up some graph here say if you like a
two-dimensional layout of all the
different threats and alerts over time
that are happening inside your
organization you know in traditional way
what would happen is that we would look
at these particular events build up a
timeline and call that near attack
timeline and you know this would be
perhaps our kill chain that would be
studying
how we got there was in one of two ways
right at some point something was
flashing loud enough red inner flashing
the most or law enforcement knocked on
their door and said is this your set of
data you associate that one particular
event and you start mapping everything
that was associated event back in time
to eventually get to that the starts and
say let's say the start was a little bit
brute-forcing for example right the
other way is that I have all this data
and I am now giving a little piece of
threat intelligence of a second of a
command and control server and I look
through my logs and I find that that
command and crawl server was used at
this particular time and I start booking
on my kill chain in both directions okay
when I walk out of the combination of
cloud and AI I work the other direction
and that is I start from the very first
events and I start you know for every
one of those events that I see I start
mapping up probability is that this this
event is going to go and is going to be
connected to another event and whether
that probability of that neck and second
event is going to lead to a type of
threat type of TTP or an aspect of
maliciousness and so what happens that
over time as I see these events
cascading I'm eventually I'm able to
alert and provide insight saying that
you know I'm starting to build up a cool
chamber arrived in a earlier description
of that this is hitting towards
something bad okay so while that's
happening the other parts that are
fundamentally changing is the way that's
user and event behavior and elixirs
coming into play so today much of the
you know on-premise Yui be a type
technologies are focused on the network
layer right or you know within slides
mmm say the top protection Suites
installed on the actual host okay so
what's happening there is that I'm
looking in real-time at the raw data and
I am creating new you EBA alerts on the
fly from the
when I'm looking at from the same
perspective I'm working in a different
way right from the same perspective
you've got to assume that I don't have
you know the seam doesn't have presence
on the endpoint and doesn't have
presence at the network instead that's
reliant on all those other security
technologies that are really there that
are creating new alerts new events new
incidents are just raw telemetry so the
traditional way from a 3ua you EBA
perspective was assume the attacker only
takes one path to attain their goal it
assumes the attacker follows the static
kill chain and that they attack path is
fully executed and also assumes the
information is present in all the logs
okay that breaks most the time right and
so from a cloud state perspective I'm
applying AI we do it in two different
ways so first of all the derivative
iterative attack simulation so as I
receive new logs new events I'm trying
to predict where it's actually going to
go and I'm going to assign probabilities
for these predictions and so I'm going
to fuse these different events that I'm
seeing in collating and be able to map
those against certain scenarios or text
simulations that I care about the motion
the organization what I'm also doing is
I'm going to provide a problem list at
kill chain right so as these events are
happening in these fusion of the
different events are coming together I'm
going to try to predict which way this
event is actually going and what servers
and what's the risk and priority and
also the overall impact organization as
it goes forward and then also using
advances and graphical methods I'm also
basically putting in random stuff into
those predictions just in case I might
have missed an event or a class of
technology wasn't deployed or something
happens to that I'm going to assume
they're going to miss out certain types
of data and so I can project an advanced
going forward
what else is happening in this space I
think one of the newer interesting areas
is AI powered for intelligence in
particular forecasting so I started
before I got into security my background
as an atmospheric physics and
meteorology if you like that the first
you know bigger uses of supercomputing
before everyone got into the nuclear
trade should we're saying but the
forecasting is an important part and so
where we are now seeing we're now seeing
the first generation of AI based threat
intelligent systems commercial threat
intelligence systems so for example you
know being able to take all that cloud
information the last 30 years of
Internet traffic domain used domain
abuse malware malware analytics bring
them all together and then be able to
fuse and project with these things are
going so for example one company based
in san diego's ecliptics provides an
average of 51 days in advance
notification that an IP or domain name
is going to be used for badness and what
that badness is going to be with things
secondly 97% probability right
everyone's like notice technologies are
we looking at the threat actor answers
the threat actor you know you choose
your list of threats actor that you care
about and you're notified in real time
we know what's new infrastructure the
bad guys are set up but it also provides
near prediction of what their what the
infrastructure is probably going to be
used for and what campaigns it's going
to be used for today so these are cool
types of technologies but you know if
you sort of think of how would I apply
these from you know from my existing
types of security technologies and this
is where it gets interesting of being up
reply prediction systems into cloud seam
so that you know you can pull one you
can watch the Internet as a whole as a
cloud provider and then predict how
those changes that you're observing in
the cloud are going to affect that and
potentially result in the techs against
your customers and against their
workloads so from a 300 perspective we
mapped out you know though those
particular events in a bit of a kill
chain or if you also do as you're using
graft technologies you can build out all
those other associations so while if I
was looking through events I was just
tracking back from you know from the the
most evil back to the original start
there are not a lot of other activities
that the bad guys we're doing at the
same time right and the types of tools
the types of systems they they touched
and things like that
this becomes a mix of TTP's and provides
a little bit of a fingerprint for either
a bad gal operator a type of tool that
they're using for automation or a class
of attacks and so effectively by
combining those together if I see these
types of you know shapes in the data I
can start building and training
classifiers for this right so today you
can do yourself or just part of a cloud
seam you just say you know here are
these three attacks I think they're all
roughly the same click a button go build
a classifier check that classifier
against your data and see if you've seen
other threats that are very much like
this right and labeled a classifier
that's great for a you know which were
active hunting perspective paths that
are much more interested though are how
do I get ahead of the threats and start
proactive hunting for these things and
so if I still look at that type of you
know shape that that cluster that's the
machine learning instance we're along
this process am i comfortable with a
probability that is going to lead to
badness right completely artificial made
up in here right at some point I say I'm
98% and my student five percent twenty
percent you know at what point am I
comfortable with this and so what's
happening and this is why the attack
like the mitre attack framework is so
important if I can take these smaller
chunks here these TTP's or phases of an
attack
I can raise my confidence of being able
to detect these things but I can also
overlay those with a framework off the
threats that I really care about these
bigger these bigger trains and labelled
threats and I can start doing things a
little bit differently in particular I
think one of the biggest things for one
of the newest things from attack
mitigation for a cloud it really has now
become conditional access controls so
what conditional access controls allow
me to do is that it is now possible to
for the systems to for the cloud to
identify who the user is who the victim
is who the attacker is and we're in the
attack process they actually are so for
example Microsoft cloud knows that
Controlman is currently logged in here
myself and when I last authenticated was
here roughly the same location
I used the pin number two on Windows
hello to open this machine
so for example and because their
PowerPoint open and we connect on the
Internet probably the last time I made a
change to the PowerPoint was
automatically backed up so the word
knows all this types information already
now the bad guys that say that someone
over in Singapore has a brute-force
existing brute force you know after you
know tried five times against the big
adramal accounts or password and the
sixth time those successful okay so
first of all the cloud knows that that's
is a different instance I've got Drammen
here at leonarda's over the end the
first part right through the machine
learning side it could also say well
actually I did see this brute force in
which i think is suspicious and the
probability that this could be a start
of a ransomware attack is 16% for
example so because it's so high then
what I will do as a conditional access
is take what I will just turn goodness
permissions on these servers to be
read-only okay and at the same time
maybe it's not Ventura or maybe it is
gun sure and so they used the password
and so I'm going to ask for a different
biometric for that particular instance
right
and what that biometric is being
calculated so for example prompt the MFA
I've also disabled admin permissions
that are going on and so what happens is
that the the systems are able to
uniquely identify but take actions
against the bad guys without
interrupting me while I'm doing this
okay you know traditionally what
happened is that's you know a detection
of that my counter being brute force and
compromised which will then happen
that's the result would be my account
would be locked out my machine would
then prompt me up now here since I've
now been locked out close all the
applications and changed my password so
the ability to separate these functions
is highly important going forward
warrant without interrupting users and
also for mitigating the threat before it
actually evolves into something bad
so cloud affects their number of key
things is that first let's step back
here if you imagine that yeah you're
running your organization you have your
workloads in the clouds you see this
amount of the clouds from a cloud
operators perspective I see across all
those clouds right not looking into your
data but looking at all the events that
happen around those data on that so for
example you know I can tell you and tell
the entire cloud to win a certain IP
address that is never ever touched
there's a cloud and has never or may
never have touched port 22 now suddenly
starts doing their I know that and then
I can apply that knowledge across the
entire organization rights and so I can
start labeling so this is such a normal
appeal ittle bit careful about this the
so call so you know there's models for
detecting threats inside your
organization I can take those threat
those models and apply to large data
sense refine those and be kind of
hanging them spot different classes of
threats and learn against those threats
and then try to smaller models that can
be deployed inside your own
organizations what it means is the other
way around
and that is essays somewhere else in the
clouds a new attack is detected fix
someone else you know I can see in this
example as a watering a hall and there's
a tech command and control and from
there I could deduce the threat
intelligence or CIA and the TTP's and so
from the clouds perspective is that if a
threat or
successful or a type of compromise that
gets labeled from from anywhere inside
the cloud I can then apply that
knowledge preemptively to everywhere
else inside the clouds okay
and so the bigger the cloud becomes the
more the the faster the rest of the
cloud becomes immune to these attacks
now from operating that slide
unfortunate one of the key things is I
end up ditching a lot of human
constraints okay so I need to start
thinking about you know these logs and
things that were human readable yeah do
they need to be human readable insects
one of the biggest constraints they have
today is I received
52:24 basically syslog okay here is
something that is over 20 years old and
defined for allowing humans to read what
the machines are basically spewing out I
also need to move to real time not quite
real time or real time TM type responses
right so I need to be able to respond
observe these events as fast as possible
and take actions as these events are
being created and also need to propose
mitigations and responses to those
threats so what does that mean from a
thrill hunter perspective okay so today
if I look at a typical threat hunter
role you know stay for the bottom tier 1
tier 2 tier 3 so effectively tier 1
you know false positives false was the
removal you know type of things tier 2
there's a script for that there is a
procedure there is a methodology for
that go deal with it and tier 3
basically anything that skips those two
paces right but of proactive hunting and
certain response being a bit of a
security architect also a risk
commentator from a cloud perspective
today if you're in a cloud what's the
role of the threat hunter effectively
tier 3 analysts but a proactive hunting
and the role of the security architects
become much more important the risk
commentator so instead of being able to
say the sky is falling this
vulnerability you should be scared about
to now be able to say that vulnerability
is there but here are the things they
can do to protect against this and train
the machine to remediate that you also
need to become a little bit of be a bit
of a data scientist and you also have
what a larger role becoming a
machine-learning trainer where this is
really going away if I have to lay bits
on the next three to five years then I
think that hunting role becomes quite
different again I think the proactive
hunting goes away many because the
machines you have to operate at real
time and so the pro active hunting
becomes entirely machine based what also
sort of see is that Security Act to
becoming a cloud security architect and
the data scientist piece is only
temporary part of time because we're
still evolving those types of the
analogies and I think data scientist
role goes away as part of the security
agreement and we've gone from an email
training to Al trainer AR trainer and so
the two big things that are pulled out
so one is you know how these roles are
changing and that is from a you know
chicken little disguise falling type of
commentary to being able to be that
business risk explain what that means is
that as an organization moves to the
clouds all of that infrastructure the
pen testing the red teaming all of that
managing clusters managing containers
managing civilus types functions than
that you don't need to do anymore
because it's the responsibility the
cloud provider but what it means is that
the biggest weakness and anything you've
ever pushed to the cloud will be the
code that you push as an organization
and so it becomes more important
understanding what the business logic is
and be able to protect that and we also
see is that you know what today is
you know sixty plus percent of most
threat hunters role and federally
disappearing down to just the Tier three
type analyst type of role okay
so running up on time here and I'm
thinking few nursing pictures here to
see if he ones awake what do you think
ties all of these pictures together if
you're sort of thinking of technology
transportation yes a little bit more
precise
okay roads a little bit true true but
what brings all these things together
how we've designed our latest cars there
are trained buses roads infrastructure
is that everything's down yeah even the
containers that we ship things down is
designed by the width of two horses
asses okay
so entire so four and a half thousand
years of evolution of transport is down
to the width of two horses okay so when
I think of what AI and how we're playing
AI to security today on try rethinking
this you know so today you've you know
we talked about supervised and
unsupervised learning a large part right
so we're aligned on the human and we so
we have our aspects of how we've
traditionally approached these types of
roles before we've also had the same
data sets you know a million should melt
syslog so these are things that were
designed to be human readable okay what
if I move away from these things that we
human readable let the machines actually
enrich the data in ways that's we have
we we humans can't no longer deal with
all right and yeah what about when I
start focusing on yeah faster do I want
to go too fast for a bit of human to
solve these types of problems were solve
a different way okay and so it's a
question about you know what am I trying
to do am I trying to you know build the
superhuman AI threat hunter or am I
trying to solve the individual pieces to
that so if you like the you know the
first world's that the first robot
citizen versus the the Roomba or the you
know you know lawn mower or the
driverless cars and things like that
well though I just sort of see this you
know this fully automated lawn mower and
I I didn't see any stickers about it
being pit friendly so
yeah and from my perspective we're not
we look at the clouds and that's and
where we are today I much prefer to go
on the second route of you know get a
new machine to specialize and solve
these particular problems at this point
in time it also means if I change the
medium if I change the way that I look
at this particular problem I can in
start changing the way that I handle the
threats so if I moved away from yes it's
a mid-air travel or the sea travel I'm
no longer bound by the roads or that you
know the width of two horses and so if I
start changing the medium start looking
at different ways of approaching AI and
different ways of approaching deadest
origins with and within the clouds then
perhaps I'm going to open up new ways of
thinking about and solving these
problems going forward so the evolution
of machine learning I think is a key
part here and that is what I'm what I'm
guessing is you know as the cloud has
become more centralized and has more
data or what we're also seeing is the
growth of the intelligent edge okay so
what we're seeing there is that we
require more compute to also happen on
the edge points of the cloud and also
the edge point of those touching of
those technologies and so I think what
we're at the cusp of doing today is
moving away in parallel of instead of
having just the AI central in saying
bring me all the data in one place and
I'm gonna analyze a little bit of a
superhuman type aspect is that I need to
also have AI systems that are on the
very edge of my network you know on the
very edge of the clouds and make those
first pass decisions all right and one
way of sort of thinking of this is you
know as data volumes increase as speed
of connections increase as the speed of
the threat comes yeah I've got to Bethel
you know I'm as Microsoft I'm already
battling machine learning and I power to
tax systems are against me already so I
have to operate at those speeds if not
faster right and so it's that sort of
thinking about if you like from a
military side I want those smart
lieutenants at the edge facing the rule
part of the battle dealing with the
attacks as they come in making those
decisions but it also wants to
grow and groom those generals from an AI
perspective centrally taking up the next
four or five steps in advance of how am
I going to not only mitigate this
particular threat but how am I going to
remove the attacker from the system or
from the internet at the same time so
things do i Minar the beverages with
friends or beers tonight I think from 8
o'clock tonight I think it was four
beers tonight so speed of response the
human is the bottleneck you know if
you're doing things in the cloud and
thinking about 12 security and that and
you rely on humans that and humans are
part of that process step back look at
other ways approaching this so threat
hunting will change but for the bitter
all the time from everywhere so the
machines do this thing a lot better than
we can right at this stage they're still
learning from us we're still training
these types of systems but even then we
give them the data volumes and types of
things they can find it's you know it's
clear the machines winning in the space
on their behalf okay so what used to be
you know if the Nemesis for a threat
hunter or a security person was there's
really events there's anomalies machine
learning systems excel at finding
anomalies that's the easiest thing they
can possibly find find those anomalies
the hard part is you know giving those
anomalies labels and describe and then
classified as some type of risk and as
we probe this part conditional response
systems so being able to use threat
prediction being able to use AI to map
activities as they're occurring and then
to take small steps injected
intelligently into those processes to
deflect or mitigate a threat without
compromising the current user or the
environments that needs to run and keep
on running a business systems going
forward and the last part is yeah if you
set your goal to be a threat threat
analysts today that's not saying that
yeah in two years time three years time
you're gonna be at a job
what's really happening though from a
cloud perspective and for organizations
that move to the cloud that threat
analysts that threat hunting world is
turning into a business security analyst
role right and so the roles becoming
both once be one space both more
technical and understanding the class of
threats and how the operators the bad
guys operate but also becoming much more
in tuned about it precisely what those
what those threats mean and impacts your
organization as a whole and being able
to that translation from what is the
threat and what are the AI classes is a
threat and to mitigate into business
systems so with that or less then I've
been talking for quite some time so I'd
like to open the floor to let you guys
talk and maybe there's any sort
questions out there if I stunned
everyone to silence or as everyone it's
like a lunch coma so do we share threat
hunting notebooks Jupiter notebooks and
things to that so yes you may have seen
the bigness here at a small acquisition
that Microsoft did called github and
it's part of that so we've made all of
the azure sentinel type of threat
hunting notebooks or the machine
learning or jupiter notebooks and things
like that are all available there and
we're trying to build up that community
I think there are lastly who was about
8,000 different notebooks for different
classes of threats there today you have
a questions going once going twice
done the back there
yeah so the question do I see big risk
in poisoning of data behind so the
models yes for some types of things so
for machine learning you know and
supervised unsupervised learning and
some data like type problems yes
that said I'm approaching for two
different ways so one is if you were
today for data scientist the third
hunting part of if you like is if you're
a security person and the threat hunting
being three hunters that let's the apex
if you like of your career in many ways
for a data scientist you're your apex
today is to be a adversarial AI you know
analysts type of thing and so we're
spending a lot on and figuring out new
ways of how to poison knowin systems and
to to figure out how new ways these
tanks can sort of mitigate how these
types of attacks and go but we are this
is a little bit different is that many
of the the techniques that have been
used today that you'll be published like
you know a stop sign and someone puts a
few pieces of tape on and becomes a
rhinoceros or whatever or turtles or
another
those are traditionally they're things
like cognitive AI type systems and
things like that and so we're looking at
different approaches and so if you use
multiple classes or models together and
AI systems and then ready to look at how
those things work together as opposed to
solving for each one individually so
that that's one aspect the other aspect
is we're also looking at new ways of you
know if I train the new model with a
jupiter notebook or some other
deliverable can I reverse engineer that
model to be able to figure out what the
raw data was and still work back from
that's right depending on how that was
generated things are changing very fast
what we've also found was interesting
once I was advised by the Microsoft
lawyers and a few other places was that
today if you want to protect your you
know your classifier your intellectual
property inside from a machine learning
side
the traditional way is to use patents so
44 the US Patent Office has said that
you can only patent so your patent has
to has to list the inventor the inventor
has to be human so if an AI invent
something you can actually use paint and
law to protect it apparently so far
today so there's a lot going on in the
adversarial AI site today you know
primary approaches from a security
perspective are we're using multiple
different classes of models and breaking
those models into smaller chunks for and
then really looking at conditional
accesses our control for you know for
actually mitigating the threat in real
time still got two minutes any last
questions if that's it then thank you
very much your time Cheers
[Applause]