so I'm Lauren thanks you run for having
me here today it's a really big honor to
be at this conference and talking on
people who are really industry leaders
in this area so I haven't committed my
speech to memory so just be with me as I
read my notes today I'm presenting a
very short summary of my honours
research that I've just finished so I'm
currently doing my master's degree and
information systems I'm here at Vic and
I also work with a great group of people
at PwC and the cyber team just in
advance I apologize for the use of the
word cyber especially given the previous
talk but I do agree with that talk as
well so yeah so I'm Peter we see is a
graduate security analyst now and I've
been there since seize out of the year
so thankfully the phenomena that I set
out to prove and my research actually
exists or at least albeit with a small
sample that I took so are we taking my
findings to a larger scale over summer
for completion of my master's degree
yeah so I apologize for the use of the
word cyber my research has a few
purposes so the overarching purpose
being to prove what I was observing was
actually taking place so I've noticed
people and you guys for the hem as well
typically non security specialists or
non techies in general like in a broader
sense they tend to hold some really
specific thoughts and opinions of who or
what a heck it might be I cringed at the
use of the word hacker
so I didn't attempt to define the word
but I just let it be so I feel like pop
culture news media and generally
speaking the sensitive nature of
security or factorization would
contribute to those perceptions so a way
that I like to explain this explain this
in short to people it's by asking the
simple questions so oh sorry oh my
goodness sorry just be with me okay so
by asking a simple question so how do
you picture what do you picture when you
might when someone sees hacker generally
this explains the existence of the
phenomena that I set out to prove but if
I were to ask this audience right here
I'd probably get a totally different
response or at least I hope I'd get a
really different response so nonetheless
if you picture a teenager in a dark room
awake all night hacking whatever that
might be then you're not alone so my
research sample
thanks the same with some interesting
findings so to investigate this
phenomena I crafted two research
questions as a starting point
what stereotypes if any does the general
public associate with terms including
hacker hacking cybercrime or computer
computer hacker and what are the
characteristics of these perceptions so
be honest what are the social
governmental and business implications
for how these perceived hackers are
portrayed and public discourse so the
problems caused by these perceptions
developed as I conducted the research
yes it's bad that people assume hackers
to fit a certain mold but what's worse
than this is the disconnect and lack of
fear or awareness a lot of people have
this reflex and their own security
behaviors the lack of awareness was
extremely apparent and what's worse is
the company lack of care so to quote one
of my interviewees my if postponed is
the same as my phone pin haha actually
probably change that which yeah you can
make of that what you will so then I
wondered what are the implications of
this beside really for security what
does this mean for wider society let
alone the security industry but also
like why have I opened this can of worms
so like most research I spend a lot of
my time performing my literature review
and at the side of my university career
I never imagined I'd have to analyze
Angelina Jolie's 90s classic hackers but
here we are and as expected it didn't
help me to define hacking but it did act
as an integral influencer to society's
perceptions of hacking so I mean about
proving this problem through a
qualitative assessment of my findings
which were gathered through a series of
ten interviews of teen people or
confidential in nature these 10 people
were intended to represent society and
to address the elephant in the room I
realized that teen is a really small
sample to conduct from but I wanted to
use qualitative methods at least to
begin with so I could gather data that I
couldn't really measure with numbers
however I plan to move to a quantitative
for my next stage so I can like really
have a broader scale for my research so
the individuals who participated were
from a range of professions some of
which include a hairdresser a wine
grower and electrician carpenters and
importantly one security professional
and other professions including some
students so 19
questions were developed and of these
questions were five topics and including
attitudes to attacking personal security
behaviors
hacktivism piracy and legal matters so
now to get to the surprising and the
unsurprising findings starting with
awareness so important to note here as
the asterisk which means that whatever
is stated as excluding the security
specialist who I interviewed thank god
so he essentially ended up being a
control of sorts so that was good so all
interviewees excluding the specialist
expressed confusion towards a topic of
cyber crime a lot of arms and as we said
as well as a lot of I don't knows
relating to all five question topic
areas again none of the interviewees
apart from the security specialist knew
what the suit was or what the function
may include people did make some
reasonable assumptions though including
cert being a fire brigade for computers
and just important to note here when I
was a sitting cert I wasn't assessing so
indeed specifically but rather suits as
a I guess global industrial construct so
the next section being understanding
nine out of ten interviewees were
accepting or not concerned about piracy
despite admitting to protecting in it
and while I hold no no opinion about
piracy I found it alarming that none of
these individuals had heard of VPN so it
appeared that a major disconnect existed
with individual understandings of
cybercrime and the lack of security
measures that people had in place so if
you were aware that cybercrime is a
problem but don't seem to really relate
it to their lives it's like a dissonant
message that they just don't act upon
apart from the security specialist
possibly the most important topic was
influence which drew forth some alarming
but not really surprising results so
seven out of ten individuals solely
reference external means for their
reasoning such as online sources and
news media and only three drew from
internal reasoning such as comparison to
other crimes or experience be it
personal or otherwise so of the sample
of ten nine people worst confusion
frustration or general concern for the
poor media portrayal of cyber security
related events so I say cyber security
really broadly because to some people
that means to come calm but to some
people what it means like completely
different things altogether but I
deliberately didn't
to define that sort of realm so I found
it really concerning which raises
another problem that people are
consuming media from sources they
consider unreliable but they're not
really bothering to get to the truth so
I don't know about you guys but I find
that quite worrisome so I found some
unexpected findings about perceived
characteristics of hackers I'm sorry for
the boring table but I think it's pretty
good so sex people feel that heck is
illogical technically smart or something
along the lines of intelligent
this was an unexpected finding as for
the previous literature that Odysseus so
an odd utilization or assumption
appeared so here we are and it's not
targeted at anyone so four out of ten
individuals mentioned participation and
World of Warcraft to be an attribute of
a hacker make of it what you will and I
didn't remotely prompt people to mention
World of Warcraft
it was rather from participant made
comments alone so I figured this might
be a reference to like gaming and gaming
culture in general and this was just how
people kind of explained it because it
might have stood out as like a prolific
example but nonetheless that forms a
notable trend so general nerdiness was
mentioned as well as being awake all
night I feel like my participants might
know some pretty committed gamers or
what they deem to possibly be hackers so
another boring table I'm sorry but I
also measured the frequency and nature
have sent out cyber related events their
participants mentioned so broadly and
the realm of cyber so the chemcam saga
was mentioned by nine out of ten
interviewees and I'll get to why shortly
but you can probably imagine why so
monochrome was mentioned either directly
or indirectly three times as was snowed
Edward or should I say it would Snowden
and the American elections mentioned in
a very broad sense so important to note
here there were more characteristics
that were mentioned but I'm just
including the ones that had really high
frequencies so people reiterated across
the interviews their confusion about
these about these in other events
so two admitted they tried to follow
news headlines about these particular
incidents but found it too difficult to
follow and otherwise didn't know really
like where to find out more
so the coats the quite sunscreen
demonstrate this but there are certainly
more throughout my transcripts of the
similar sorts of comments alluding to
the same things all right so to long
didn't read or what academics refer to
is the conclusion what does this all
mean so a high level of participation oh
sorry a high level of intelligence
participation in Wow and general
nerdiness are characteristics of a
hacker at least for the sample that I
get it it seems a few of my friends
might be hackers after all based on this
logic furthermore the chemcam saga for
which I hold a neutral stance was a
standout event related to cyber metas
generally at least to non-specialists so
most importantly and unexpectedly
interviewees were mostly dissatisfied
with media reporting on the topic of
chem comm and wider security security
and cyber crime related events so what
do these mean for the widest cyber
security industry I can assume from my
findings that sorry that the perceptions
were taken generally they may cause
social government to and business
implications whether we realize it or
not importantly I think my findings are
significant to policy development going
forward and IT and security areas
because individuals and organizations
may act according to these perceptions
or at least their preconceived ideas or
lack of care and awareness so distrust
for news media has major repercussions
what sources will people turn to if they
don't know who to trust and of course
security behaviors so if people think
that hackers are just well players who
have too much time they may be a little
bit less inclined to improve their
security practices and this definitely
relates to an organizational level as
well
so just because the crime may be less
tangible than a physical crime it
doesn't really make it any less damaging
and hopefully we're all aware of that so
that pretty much wraps up my talk and
thank you all for listening to my first
ever talk so if you want to find out
more I definitely want to hear people's
critiques constructive criticisms and
this sort of thing along these lines so
hit me up at my Twitter will talk to me
after this
you