hello I'm gonna make a quick demo this
was not supposed to be a talk but it's
kind of an extension of the previous
talk from our two children it is
basically to show the new features in
panels mode also integration with
procedure or the compilers by itself I
confer two children or two that have it
now if it's not in here but basically
when you load the binary right now we
had the visual mode which is a uppercase
B but if you use the lowercase B you
will get into the panel's mode you can
use the exclamation mark to toggle
between the visual mode and panels mode
and when you're in panels mode well you
can precise the thing and you can
actually use the mouse I'm clicking
in different panels you can see we can
also click in the menus so we can pick
different the compilers it's detecting
all other compilers that are supported
or install it as plug-ins in here we can
change the settings also for example for
the disassembly we want to change for
example and toggle the bytes we can also
close the panels by pressing the X and
if we present click in the title we can
actually change the contents of the type
of the panel so for example we can use
the D compiler in here so as long as the
function is not analyzed the compiler is
not working so I will just click in here
and then analyze function
so now we have the the compilation and
the right side but as you can see this
is the compiler of PDC which is the
internal local pilot comes inside -
which is not really a compiler just a
cellulose assembler with some nice
output but the output is not correct at
all I mean it can be useful for having
like an idea of what's going on here but
it's not real compiler so as we can see
we check into the we shall have now the
PD D which is our - deck so we have PDC
which is the phone that comes with our -
you can see there are some reference to
strings resistors names and a variable
names function calls etc but you can see
that this is not real something that you
will expect to rely on so until now we
had P D D which was the our to deck the
compiler which is written in JavaScript
and the output is quite nice but it's
not removing the trash code or making
many optimizations and on the output
there is also support for red deck and
there will be a talk later today about
that but in order to show the different
options that we have into the compiler
and the waiting to create that into our
- we'll see that there are some output
some sub comments of the pd d and also
it's also available in PDD which is for
example the pd d o which shows the
output of the fan of the the compiler
next to the offset you can see the
offset next to this assignment right and
it will use PD G which is the leader of
the compiler we can actually use the
same thing
was removed
[Music]
loop's was working in Bastion from
joseline's
so yeah let's pick the compiler and if
we choose for example a pity speed he
was working fine but we can change the
contents with the output after the
compiler we're going to enable the catch
so the output of the so the contents of
this panel will not be updated every
time that we scroll or do whatever
otherwise we'll be quite slow so we can
resize the window and in here you can
see the more effects
you can actually click on things so you
can for example highlight the register
values which their names or instructions
which is kind of handy if you want to
analyze like different some pieces of
assembly code so we know it's a code and
here we can for example pick the
different functions by just clicking at
them in the offset we can use the mouse
wheel to scroll around the panel and
same goes for the author's the compiler
so if I change the output of this panel
to contain that PDD oh we will see that
you get the output in there and we can
actually change the view to the
disassembly and we can scroll around you
can see that the output is updated this
function are kinds small and the auto to
sketch so we can for example click in
here close this panel and we can scroll
around and you can see always the the
output of the compiler so we can click
in in the other panel and scoring there
and you can actually highlight the
different offsets and actually highlight
the the same offset in the other side
it's what's supposed to be working so
yeah so that's more or less the new
features that are coming in in too and
also a no wait integrator the compiler
output inside r2 is that even Eliza
function and we integrate the output of
the compiler of the function inside as
inside the r2 with comments we can go
into this whole mode for example and in
the disassembly we like we can we can
see that the right side the auto the
compiler is that as common as comments
so we can press a hash and then it
basically removes although it's assembly
on offsets and we see that the compiler
output in the disassembled you so you
have like all the gen lines and all the
control flow graph and so on also
working with the output of the compiler
so you
use the output of the compiler with with
the output of the in the graph B or into
this assembly view and you can just
basically toggle that we're using the
hash key okay so that's a quick overview
on how to use at least today I cannot
reach it inside there - and what are the
new features of panels mode in the last
version for Alfred - so no let's start
with the next talk which were starting
it's in two minutes
thank you