can everyone hear me okay yep
so hey everyone thanks for inviting me
to be here first time at Arctic on first
time speaking so thank you to everyone
organizing the conference already even
with the trainings this has been awesome
so yeah this was gonna be like a 20
minute presentation and with all of the
movement and stuff we're gonna try and
speak a little bit slower I was trying
desperately to get as much information
in and speak really fast so I could tell
you a lot of stuff but and now I can
slow down and speak slowly so yeah today
we're gonna look at using r2 and r2
frida to analyze some protected iOS apps
and I'm kind of speaking about a really
narrow concept not everything to do with
protected iOS apps I'm not really
delving into obfuscation and things like
that but at least showing you something
that is not new but isn't really that
well documented and some people ask me
this question a lot and when they're
looking at apps so I figured it would be
nice to share it with you so the idea is
basically like me a few years ago I
don't know how to drink from the glass
and use r2 and r2 frida or hookah
Cisco's or anything like that so I
figured rather than just figure it out
and keep it to myself now maybe I can
share some information and help you so
this is kind of like a little bit of a
journey so I'm just gonna talk a little
bit about how this was happening before
with substrate and you know arm 32 and
how we were doing things in the past and
you know writing things down on pencil
and paper and you know making mistakes
with addresses and messing the the
application up so yeah basically like a
journey from being a total idiot to
slightly less of an idiot
so that's the idea right so yeah mainly
we're going to talk about 64-bit iOS but
as I said there is a little bit towards
the beginning where we talk about arm 32
and predominantly other than maybe like
two slides I'm going to talk about
Cisco's
so is everyone aware of how Cisco's work
anyone who's not familiar okay good so
yeah I mean on iOS they're no different
than other platforms but what's
happening is of applications will use
inline assembly to invoke system calls
to circumvent the standard library so
that when we're using
to try and intercept various library
calls then we we don't get to see what
the apps doing so furthermore we're
gonna talk a little bit about automation
right so using our two pipe and maybe
even some octave 3d plugins towards the
end so that you can do this stuff faster
without actually having to spend a lot
of time manually the other thing is
probably most of this applies to Android
but the caveat is I don't do anything
with Android so the native layer like
there's a lot of similarities but yeah I
mean geo speaking later he does way more
Android than I am so go see him he's
more of an expert so some of the reason
why we're doing this stuff obviously
like all of you we do this for fun or
sometimes we're paid or sometimes you
read you of Annie's blog and get jealous
and want to learn like him so go see his
talk and yeah basically just finding
this stuff takes way too long and
bypassing it can take even longer and
it's just a pain in the ass so if we can
use some automation then we can we can
actually get to the more interesting
stuff quicker so yeah other than Cisco's
some examples of things that are
typically happening in apps usually they
try and stop us from instrument in the
app in a number of different ways so
looking for things on the filesystem is
the obvious one so on jailbroken devices
or devices where we have things like
Freda president or substrate present
there is you know residual artifacts
that are there on the filesystem that
they can pick up and obviously they're
doing this with common API is like stat
open and access and so on you can also
look for these things in memory so
really common again like loop over all
of the libraries that are loaded in the
process space look for the name Freda
really basic check but many people do it
and then you know depending on which
platform and how you're using Freda and
it's not always going to appear there so
that there are some tricks to identify
the the Freda pass in the memory regions
without actually using the D while the
image iterations so the other thing you
can do is you can be looking for
artifacts or evidence of Frida across
memory so strings or some kind of
fingerprinting of Frida our substrate
that you might be looking for so again
this is really common in in various
applications and then there's this thing
which some many people in the room
probably are familiar
and many people might not be so on Mac
OS and I actually have this flag in the
or environment variable where you can
use it to preload libraries so it's
called D while the insert libraries and
in the linker they have some code that
says if you have a segment and section
with the name underscore underscore
restrict then you ignore the environment
variable so I'll show you an example of
this on Mac in a second but yeah the
first time I was looking at this was
even pre Frieda and even in my
constructor of my hoots the basic log
statements weren't even there and you
know I was pulling my hair out like I
mean this should work if that's nothing
complicated but my libraries weren't
even being injected so yeah I lost way
too much time on that one but it's
really simple now that you read about it
so if you want to do it you can compile
with clang or GCC or whatever and add
the sections they don't need to contain
anything they can be empty but in this
case using our two we just print the
bicep in the section and you can see
says hello article 2019 and then the
last thing is which again is very common
many of the the products that the Ross
products and stuff they're looking for
identification of tampering to memory so
looking for any kind of alterations to
the code so check something of the code
sometimes running in other threads they
look for evidence of repackaging in case
maybe we're not even using jailbroken
devices and then looking for certain
trampolines inside target functions so
they can be in the standard library or
even in in their own functions as well
so as an example of the restrict section
you know if you look at various
applications on both iOS and Mac you'll
find this so here we have iTunes on the
Mac and if we print out with our tooth
with Robin to get the all of the
sections we can see here we have
restrict and if we try and use Frieda
with the process it tells us that we can
and if you go ahead and remove that
section then you can attach and so on
yeah really basic ones you know about it
but yeah if you don't know about it can
cause a lot of pain so I'm gonna try not
to offend although here I'm gonna try
and talk a little bit about how this
works but not specific to freedom but
also with substrate so the basic idea
again
many people in the room will be familiar
but under regular circumstances your
application calls functional in in the
standard library let's say access the
function runs does a wiggle and then
execution comes back for answers fairly
fairly simple so if we use some kind of
hooking tool that uses trampolines then
what happens is the diagram might look a
little bit weird but we have some kind
of replacement of some instructions in
the target function which is going to
hijack execution and run some
replacement code so when we when the
application now calls the the function
in the standard library executions pass
to us and then optionally we can either
we can replace the functionality and
never call the original or we might you
know call the original if we don't want
to try and re-implement whatever it was
that they did and then funfun finally a
execution goes back to the app so really
like hand-wavy sort a basic example of
how this stuff works but why is that
interesting well because many
applications actually detect this so as
an example with RT Freda you can ignore
the first command now you don't actually
need to import the information anymore I
think pancake last week made some
changes to automatically do this which
is awesome so if we print out two
instructions at the address of open you
can see we have some arm 64 store a pair
of registers and some move instruction
and if you use the backslash di one
command in R two frite you replace the
return value of the of the function so
in this case we've we want to alter the
the function to return one and it uses
Interceptor underneath and now if we
print out the first two instructions we
can see these have changed right so in
in the red circle you can see some up
codes and if this has been detected even
substrate and for a while and as I say
many products do this and here from even
from a white paper in 2016 from Vincent
tan he shows like a really basic example
of identification of these up codes so
you pass a function pointer and check
for the up codes and if you find them
then you know someone's tampering with
it so again very common practice now
so much of Lib system is exposed file
system calls obviously so typical
interaction as a developer you make a
function call under standard library and
standard library invokes a system call
and on iOS there is in excess of 400 I
think I'm not a Windows guy but I was
reading there's like in excess of a
thousand so different platforms
obviously operate in different ways but
you know here the numbers exceed I think
even 500 but they're around
I think 400 unique but you can print
these pretty easily so there's tools out
there like Joker which is another open
source where you can print out the
system call table if you pass it in iOS
firmware and thanks to mr. machete who's
somewhere here I think r2 can also do
this so now if you if you give are to a
decompressed kernel image you can go
ahead and analyze it as well and do many
more things but you can get the system
called a table or the trap table as well
so r2 also has some of this built-in via
some internal commands so you can use
like the a s commands for accessing
information about the system calls so
you can do like both lookups by name and
the inverse by by number so you can for
example like a P trace or read or socket
or whatever is that you're looking for
or if you want you know a list of these
you can use ASL as well so how this
works on iOS on iOS the instruction for
supervisor calls is as we see oh it's 84
system calls and on Android you think
SBC 0 and it falls likes that follows
the standard like calling convention for
functions so X 0 through X 7 is gonna
hold your first arguments and then
thereafter the arguments will be on the
stack but what we really care about is
that the system call number that's being
used there's gonna be in X 16 register
and again I'm not an Android guy so it
could be wrong but I think it's X 12 or
something like that so basically if we
have this call here to socket what would
happen you know if we wanted to call
this we would have our constants they
can go in the registers and we can look
up with our to the system call number
for socket which in this case in
hexadecimal is 6 1 and then if we go
and called the instruction then we can
you know we can make that happen so this
is the way it works and knowing that we
can start to build some tooling to to
find out what's happening and identify
what the applications are checking for
and the trouble was in the beginning the
way I was doing this was analyzing the
application and like hopper and you know
going through finding these things by
searching for the mnemonics one by one
and writing down the address and I'm 32
and putting on some paper and then
putting into some substrate code and you
had to compile it and then the
application crashed because you made an
error with one of the addresses or one
of the addresses that was actually
Petrus he put it in the socket
you know array so you hooked it like a
socket call so this was a real nightmare
but it was all I knew and I was still
learning this stuff so it was really
painful so back in the beginning had
some really basic hopper scripts to just
go through and find the SVC oxa T's
print out the addresses but this was
like five years ago and even Freda has
been around longer but I wasn't really
aware or using it but the trouble is
this is just I have no patience for this
now that I know like the better way of
doing I'm like I don't even like to
admit I was doing it this way so the
trouble is like in that context I was
printing out like a list of addresses
with no information I have no idea what
the system calls were it was just a nar
betray list of offsets so I was going
again by each one and tools like hopper
or I done just looking for move
instructions to see the value going in
and then obviously as apps are
obfuscated you can't really see that too
easily so you know this was a bit of a
problem but then we figured like yeah we
could use substrate to hook these right
so anyone who's written substrate hooks
I figured like yeah we can just go ahead
and do this but it doesn't really
support out of the box
hooking of like just an off set or an
instruction you have to have a valid
function at that address
so some people I was working with they
came up with a sort of hacky well a very
happy workaround but basically just
using the MS fook function of substrate
but then changing some instructions to
make it work and so
again I'm 32 but not armed 64 so this
was again allowed us to now hook all of
those and replace the functionality so
we could now see everything they were
doing with access and socket and so on
and then we ended up having like huge
sets of hooks for all of the standard
library all of the things that we know
from do break detections or Annie
tampering and then we had like these
arrays again which I was popular in
manually for Pete Ray's clothes reads
and then we were looping over those and
calling the patching all of them one by
one so this was fine like when
applications had like you know 10 to 50
Cisco's like going through manually
doing it one by one it's like only a
small small effort but still too much
effort but apps now have like thousands
like so many have like several hundred
or even in excess of 2,000 there
depending on what kind of product is in
use or how paranoid they are and so I
figured like okay if I could do this at
runtime
even in substrate if I could figure out
the system call number at runtime that I
don't need to manually figure out which
ones which I don't need to put them into
different arrays and do all this clumsy
stuff I could get it at runtime trouble
is if you remember what happens when we
replace a function with interceptor the
the register that holds the system call
number is used during that process so
the the system call number is actually
no longer there so we have to do it in a
couple of different ways so there's a
number of ways you can get around this
and it's the same for substrate and
freida and on iOS I think on Android
it's actually okay so I started getting
all crazy again late at night thinking
yeah I'll write some hopper script that
generates a debugger script that you
know breakpoints and prints out the
value at runtime and then I can put it
into Frida script and eventually I ended
up just changing some Frida source so
don't use this because it broke a bunch
of stuff it was accepted and then
immediately discarded because my ideas
are crazy so basically I just changed
all of the usage of X 16 to X 18 since
it's meant to be like an unused register
but me is used it turns out
so we have some other ideas we were
speaking just a second ago there and mr.
mr. machete about other ideas we could
maybe do that which will I guess talk
about after the conference but yeah
there there are other ways of doing it
you can use soccer for example as we'll
see but then the other problem is like I
don't have time for all of this like I
don't I don't want to install an app run
a tracer at runtime and even some of the
system girls might not even run so I
figured like okay let's go back to the
drawing board do this statically and
colleague at the time I do he was our to
Khan and he came back and he was doing
the CTF internally and I never use our -
up until just after last hour - Khan so
I was like okay this looks like way more
extensible and and pluggable for what I
want to do so I figured that if I can
scan the app statically and find out
most of the stuff then that would be
ideal
so yeah I'm still learning so again many
people in the room use r2 a lot more
than I do but yeah you can find the
system calls in a binary with /a s it
will tell you which system call it is
which is handy and we can also use the
slash eighty command to give some
instruction types and get information
there as well but if you look at the
count there is some variance right so we
can see there's a little bit of context
when we use slash yes but when we use
slash eighty we get more but we don't
obviously know which system call it is
the other thing is I don't really want
to analyze the whole binary because
since in large obfuscated binaries it
takes too long so and the last thing is
towards the end when we do this at
runtime and we don't really need to look
by mnemonics we can look for the op
codes which as you can see with the
timing is significantly faster right so
this was just in a small application but
in bigger applications it can take like
15-20 minutes when it's searching so
obviously doing it in you know a smaller
factor of rounds is much much more
appealing so I started to build this
tooling based on our to pipe which
hasn't seen the light of day yet because
it's really messy and has missing
features but basically you can give it
an iOS app it will go through look at
the main binary figure out all of the
linked libraries and basically
recursively scan them all identify where
all these things are used and for some
stupid reason I decided would be a great
idea to
create an XML output and surf Jason so
I'll show you a quick example I have a
crack mean we scan it with the tool very
fast we're also doing some signature
matching for various products and then
we get like some information so here we
can see there's retrace X access and I
the tool even you can feed that back in
and it automatically hooks them all and
freida all the system calls get hooked
and it traces everything that's
happening so that was like the first
approach that I went down works fine but
again it could be better in obfuscated
apps sometimes I wasn't able to see the
the system call number especially
because I hadn't done the analysis
because again I want to do as fast as
possible so I figured like maybe I'll
use Eisel and Kandra was saying already
don't use IO cash equals true so I'm
gonna have to change this so yeah I'm
still learning but yeah basically we can
use e so we jump back probably more than
is necessary but just seek back and then
set up the emulation and go ahead and
emulate until that point and you can see
here before when we get the system call
number it's nothing and then afterwards
we can see it's SS CTL which is for anti
debug or for many things but probably
front et buggin so we built this in and
looks something like this really bad
Python code as a trend when you look at
my code and basically it works it runs
everything all of my hockey print
statements are now commented out so nice
and the result is we get something like
this so different applets the CTL but we
can now see there was a call to the
system call forget pit and we annotated
to say that we emigrated with ezel so if
we wanted to extend this and use unicorn
or something different then we can do
that as well so yeah moving one step
better we can do this with our T Frieda
and we can also use our T pipe with our
T Frieda which if you were in the
training the other day you would find
out from the last part of the
presentation so again you can ignore the
backslash I asterisk it's no longer
needed
but here we basically want to search for
the main binary because it's a correct
me that I wrote for the training so I
know it's not in any other libraries so
with back
diem we can get the the maps for the
current loaded process and I just want
to filter by an executable region and
then we can seek to that location and
use dot backslash f4 slash which will
set all of the search parameters in the
environment variables of r2 to the
current image that we're currently seek
to so here when we do back slash forward
slash you can see all of the search
parameters are the same boundaries of
the code block and now if we if we want
we can go ahead and use a back slash
four slash X to search for taxpayers and
we can use the assembler functionalities
of r2 to actually even get us the up
codes for the SVC instructions so I mean
not that it's hard to remember the the
up codes but you know if you if like me
you're doing a lot of stuff and you want
to search for different things you can
just chain the commands really nice and
we search only in that region and we
find 63 hits so in challenge one of the
crack knee spoilers in case you want to
do it at home but challenge one is using
the standard library and challenge two
is similar but with system calls so here
we have 63 matches so with that we can
use other commands so for example in our
two frite you can use backslash DTR
which will trace registers a particular
given address so like other
functionality bar two you can use the
erase so we can say let's trace the the
current address with x0 register to
print out all of the hits right so for
each of those we want to find out what's
the next 0 and the reason we chose x0 in
this case is because those system calls
are accessed and I think else that which
the x0 is the file path so when we do
that what happens in our two frite is we
can see the the the path that's being
searched for so they're looking for
Cydia and in the correct me I say they
me I'm looking for Cydia and I find it
so you know if this was a real app we
could see the paths that they're being
searched for although searching like
this with tracing on all the hits isn't
really gonna work because they're gonna
be different system call
but we can again we'll get to be more
creative than that so the other thing is
you can do this with stalker so without
having to make changes to Frida you can
use stalker because stalker is less
invasive so here what I did was I dumped
all the system calls into a dictionary
in the JavaScript for I think iOS 12 but
they don't really change all that often
but once I have them there I can trace
functionality and it's very slow but it
works so I'm tracing all instructions
and if if I see
SVC then and it's also part of the the
main app so you might want to do it for
other libraries as well but for here I'm
just living it to the main app if I see
an SVC instruction then I call out to
some other functionality so over on the
right hand side you can see what I'm
doing my my code basically gets the the
value of the program counter just in
case I want to print that out to see
where it is you could also work out the
address static the static address if you
want to feed this into our to scripts
offline to add comments or annotations
or anything like that as well which I'm
currently adding now and but also we can
parse the the register value of X 16 and
we can look it up in the dictionary so
now we can create some switch cases or
anything to handle access pete-r a
socket or anything else right so now we
can be more Krave so in frida itself not
an hour to freedom in frida here's an
example of that working so on the cracka
me if you use the stalker based approach
we can see all of the access calls and
we can see all of the file paths that
are being searched for and furthermore
if we want to bypass those checks we can
just use the Frida api's to replace the
string with a file path that doesn't
exist with the caveat that obviously you
could have red herrings and stuff so if
you replace everything then again they
might still pick you up but you can see
here we have the flag for the second
part of the correct name so
so basically the next steps were okay we
can do this in stalker we can script
this stuff but you know I was looking in
the last few weeks to see that you can
actually write plug-ins for our two
frite so I figured okay like if I can
write a plugin that will do this easily
I don't have to worry about chaining the
different commands or if I want to
replace certain system calls I can put
that all into a plug-in and make it like
really easy to use so commands will
probably change again it's really messed
up code right now but you can use like
backslash st F to find them all you can
stock all of them with s to print out
what all the system calls are and with T
that's where I'm starting to build a
logic in to allow you to put like
blacklist of files that you want to
replace so we can actually start to do
more so again like just like in the
previous example we're now calling it
from within the plug-in in our to Frieda
with backslash STS and you know you see
the output from the from the script so
it's really easy actually um I don't
really like JavaScript sorry
so I even I have a buddy who's like
really hardcore JavaScript I'm like dude
what the is a promise so I'm trying
to call to to our to Freder host
commands and it was just hanging and
he's like yeah did you have to chain the
promises okay sorry
so basically you can register command
handlers for different commands in this
case I just have one and I have
arguments that I passed to it and the
code looked way nicer than this but
stalker relies on duct tape or at least
currently there's some problems with VA
in our to Frieda and our VA is the
default and Artefill
so if we want to use talker we need to
turn that off and then I had to like
find some website that was gonna convert
my syntax to something old-school so
it's still not too bad but yeah it was
looking there so yeah here we can use
the commands that we know from our -
like PA that we're using the previous
example so we can say PA with the
mnemonics and we can get the the opcodes
and then we can go through look for
executable code regions we can go ahead
and search for the system calls and
populate them in some JavaScript objects
and the result of that is
now like we did before we have a plug in
where we can find the bypass all of
these again really basic functionality
for now but maybe we can we can make it
better going forward the other thing
that I said I would
I mentioned pancake worked on this I
think a month ago or something but
there's also the option to inject as
code using a free day as well so you can
use this code here to inject system
calls and and invoke the functionality
if you want to so you can you can also
do that so what's next
keep writing bad code and hope it works
but yeah we can get very far using our
two pipe one of the limitations I've
found so far with writing our to Frieda
plugin is I wanted to just use the
commands that I was using before like
the you know backslash 4 /x to search
for the the bytes and you can do it with
the the Frieda you know I could do it
with Frieda but you know I figured if
that if that logics already built in I
can just reuse it so you know I had to
use both Frieda code as well as running
our two commands which is probably the
neat way of doing it but with our two
pipe you can obviously make use of the
arterial commands as well so it's quite
quite a bit more extensible for me and
also I don't have to worry too much
about the JavaScript side because I can
use Python so the next steps for me is
to try and identify different detections
different products there's a tool out
there I do and some others work on it
called apk ID so I figured like there's
no iOS equivalent maybe it'd be good to
work on something like that but then
also for these things to create some
kind of mappings to help you work out
offline so as I say maybe adding some
comments and our two offline to show you
what the system called number was what
the arguments were maybe if you can't
find it through them easily and also
creating some graphs that will help you
figure out where things are so when
you're looking at really complicated
apps often you're working through the
back faces and then you hook those
things and then you see what they call
and again we can automate a lot of this
stuff so that's that's the plan
so yeah ideally I want to have two
options either
scan and get as much information offline
as I can but if I have to run the app
which is becoming more common then I can
run the app and I can trace everything
at runtime the other thing is to show
the example of how this will work at
some point as I say I need to make it
neater and there's a few things missing
but also I think geo is going to talk a
lot about dwarf which is a like a
debugger built on top of Frieda with
many many other capabilities and he's
also now making it extensible to write
agents and again it should be pretty
easy to add something like this across
platform for for dwarf although he might
even have that already so yeah that's
that's it for what's next
I have screenshots I can show you a demo
if if we have time I guess we definitely
have time so let me go ahead and do that
so how do I do this without taking a
video of myself okay
so
let's go here and yeah let's go shall we
just make sure I have the thing
okay so yeah basically I can show you
the the plugin we can go here yeah so if
we take a look at the code let's look at
the the new code I guess so again we
have dictionary the plan is we can use
that from the a s command so we don't
actually need to do that but again I'm
lazy I haven't got around to it so yeah
we have some commands here to handle the
different arguments that the the we as
users are going to want to use whether
we're finding them tracing them or doing
other things we are trying to add some
support for Android but as I say I'm not
an Android person so I'm not a cyborg so
here we have the code which calls the
are two commands to to get the the op
codes like we showed and down here if we
want this talk we call the stalks this
calls function and if I jump to this I
can show you what that looks like okay
here so again right now we I'm just
creating a PLC so it's limited to the
app region but super simple to to fix
and when you're finding them it it
creates a mapping for all of the
libraries in memory and shows you which
ones belong to which so we can easily
leverage that going forward and yeah if
we if we find one then we're just going
to go ahead and print it out but as I
say maybe we can import that information
into our to offline so we can create
some scripts to create comments and
flags and other things that will help us
when we're analyzing this statically so
really basic stuff but let's go ahead
and run it
let's just make sure that lets go strong
I guess be okay so I think I remember
correctly so what happens in the crack
me if you want to play along at home if
you have an iPhone device when we spawn
with Freda or two Freda obviously the
application is running but in like 15
seconds the OS is gonna kill us because
yeah the application hasn't been resumed
and it says yeah times I so we can
resume it and what's gonna happen is the
application is gonna detect us and
self-destruct again fairly common when
you're analyzing apps like this but what
we can do we can import challenge one
and we can go ahead and resume so now we
see some cold wait now the application
opposite doesn't rise so challenge one
is fairly fairly easy nice trying to use
a laptop when it's slanted away from you
so yeah basic example we have a
blacklist based on the tracing that we
did of some files and we with Frida
we're hooking access and we're also
hooking else that it's not really that
horrible because instead of using args
I'm using x0 just yeah because I'm lazy
or because I want to look cool I don't
know
so yeah challenge one is really easy and
now obviously if we go to challenge two
is gonna crash again right so we go to
challenge two it gives us like a two
second timer and yeah applications dead
right so let's go ahead and restart and
let's go for challenge one again and
let's resume so we be challenge one and
now if we want to what we can do I've
put together some commands already
so if we want if we wanted to automate
this we can either batch ups of commands
and pass them in with - I and it will
run all of those are two commands or we
could put it into our two pipe or we
could put into a plugin so here all of
the commands I showed earlier we have
them batched up to automatically bypass
challenge - so I'll show you this one
first so let's go ahead and actually let
me change something real quick pancakes
gonna hate me I'm gonna use now so let's
go ahead and do find the RT so I just
want to import a challenge one okay so
let's go ahead and run that and we can
say - I and do find or - so let's go
ahead and run the app spawn it again now
we can see we have the blessing of
Clippy right it doesn't work if you
don't use Clippy so here we bypass
challenge 1 and then we need to resume
the app and now obviously we can see
some other stuff okay and what's gonna
happen is if we go to challenge two we
should be the challenge so here you can
see it says it's going to self-destruct
but it doesn't and if if I search for X
0 : we can see the flag but also we can
tap through there's freedich detection
there's jailbreak detection there's
various other stuff so we can do all of
this I'm from within within the the
batch script but also if we want to if I
tap back out to let me let me restart
just for cleanliness so let's say
challenge 1 again and let's resume and
then if we want we can go yes 5
so let's go ahead and import the plugin
and now we can go ahead and use the
command and so we can do like back slash
SDF it will go through and as I say
recursively look for everything but you
don't really want everything necessarily
and again it's hacky so there's some
JavaScript objects because I don't know
what I'm doing
so here if we want to go ahead and for
example trace we can run stalker now and
we'll go ahead and run the challenge you
see it's a little bit slower with soccer
but let's give it a try and again this
is just a crack me so you know using
this in relapse it's gonna take take
some time to get it working but let's go
ahead and give this some seconds yeah I
know why it's not working so again I was
saying stalker has some issues right now
with VA and if we if we load up with r2
and yeah I'm gonna have to kill this
somewhere okay looks like it's fine okay
so if if you want you can do like this
and you can see the run time is VA in
free debt defaults to duct-tape so we
have some problems here so yeah we'll
let it do its thing it's going to
destroy itself so if we want to to go
ahead and do that then I think I
remember the command
[Music]
yeah so let's go ahead and do this and
yeah we can just go here so if we set
this environment variable now to let's
see
disable v8 2-1 and we're gonna go ahead
and spawn the application again we still
have the the commands being passed in
but we could go ahead and take the mouse
since we're going to do it with the
plugin so here we need to go ahead and
import challenge 1 again we can resume
click OK now if we if we want to we can
import the plug-in and we have the
commands again so just same as before we
can still search that's not the problem
it's one we want to go ahead and run
stalker so now you see doesn't hang on
the first threat we have some more
information so let's go ahead and go to
challenge two okay so now we can see
that some access calls were called and
let's go try one more time and let's do
challenge one again so this is just to
trace the system calls that are running
but if we want to implement the bypasses
we did a second ago we can use the final
command so let's go ahead and run this
is gold tracer so in this case I think
we run STS right otherwise my god Brooke
yeah okay it's fine so this time we run
as st with t to say we actually want to
trace and to do more stuff than just
trace as you can see the syntax doesn't
really make sense yeah but we'll figure
out so yeah ok still died bad demo but
yeah basically um the idea is we can go
ahead and build in black lists and for
common things these exists on many
platforms so if you go looking around
white papers and get happy you'll find
lots of examples of you know Annie Jo
breaking Annie tampering and we can go
ahead and start populating some kind of
knowledge base of this stuff and then
pass it in here so yeah I mean it's demo
is not exactly working I mean I was
working on this stuff right up until the
end of last week so
but yeah you get the idea so the idea is
we need a little bit of time to make
this work better on iOS and then we need
some Android people to to come help so
yeah I guess that's that's everything
yeah
any questions well thank you for your
presentation and I want to tell you that
I will be doing the Android part so I
already tested and it was more or less
working but I think I bought it in one
week or so so no worries nice thank you
thank you thank you yeah it's an
interesting journey thank you for
sharing only one question during your
journey why you did not considered al LD
be scripting yeah I mean I did I was
doing a lot of stuff in our DB and even
as you say it like halfway through I
figured like let's just create some l DB
scripts to do this and even some
colleagues working with where I show
them this stuff they are doing the same
stuff in ello to be just preference I'm
not I'm not opposed to using a debugger
but yeah I mean I'd rather do stuff
which is more extensible and I can
change things on the fly and yeah for me
I prefer it but ya know no real reason I
guess you could do all of this the same
way but for me just prefer using tools
like Frida and Artie Frida so yeah thank
you for questions okay thanks