[Music]
tin
a european regulation claimed to
guarantee net neutrality
and the right for users to choose their
own routers
but is the battle for net neutrality
over yet
no it is not in this next talk lucas
lazotta
who works for the fsfe will explain
how these new national implementations
of the regulation
will put these rights at risk i'm
looking forward to its overview over
recent successes for router freedom
in the eu and what challenges are coming
in the future
lucas we're really happy to have you
okay thank you very much hello victor
and hello everybody i'm very pleased to
be here today
and i would like to thank the organizers
very much for the opportunity
uh to talk about a very interesting
topic not just a legal board topic but
certainly something that concerns all of
us
so thanks victor for the nice
introduction uh today my talk
will be about net neutrality in europe
and the continuation of the struggle
continuation of the debates uh that
we are having right now my name is lucas
losota i'm deputy legal coordinator of
the free software foundation europe
and also i'm fellow research researcher
at
the humboldt university where i'm
working also
in the field of i.t law uh feel free to
reach out
uh there is my link uh about me
and so let's get started today
uh i want to talk about router freedom
an activity that we conducted uh when
the
in the free software foundation europe
for already uh several
internet this topic has grown more
traction
and become very important in the last
years
and we'll talk about what is router
freedom what is
opennet internet and device neutrality
and of course why router freedom today
is in danger
in in europe and what you can do to help
so how you can join our
advocate so how you can join us in our
activity
so everybody in europe every citizen has
his or her rights guaranteed to use
their own equipment to connect to the
internet
first i would like to
say that well internet
oh i'm sorry internet access
is a human right so we do everything
today
in the internet and this year has shown
that not only our normal interactions
but our
not our personal interactions but also
our
work interactions everything that we do
are connected the internet so
we must guarantee or empower
users to have access to the internet
through their
own means through their own equipment so
guaranteeing their the right to use
their own equipment
in order to connect to the internet is a
must and
since 2015 this right is guaranteed by
european
regulation so um
through uh the net neutrality regulation
although
the official name is called open
internet regulation
guarantees end users consumer citizens
for the far freedoms of net neutrality
the freedom of content
freedom of application they want to use
freedom of services
and freedom of devices well we use
different devices to connect to the
internet when we are at home we use
home home routers when we are in the
street we
use our own smartphone for an example
and uh although
uh it's quite intuitive that nobody
today tells that the isp owns your own
telephone
and you can use your own telephone your
own smartphone to connect to the to
the internet it's not like that when
it comes to the router the home router
that you use
so in fact we have seen
that uh users are although it is
guaranteed by law
users have a lot of problems to uh
use their own router to connect to the
internet and
of course if you have your own router if
you have the
the free choice of your own equipment
um not only is compliant with the law
but there is a lot of benefits and here
i would just like to say some of them
if we if we protect router freedom
so the type of equipment that we use to
connect to the internet of course
then we are protecting freedom of choice
we are protecting privacy data
protection of the users
competition in compatibility in the
equipment market and of course
security because users can update their
own software
and to make their equipment more secure
yes but therefore
the the legislation protects that but as
we're gonna see it it's not so
uh straightforward uh to comprehend
but uh net neutrality
uh elders for freedoms is just the
beginning
of a broader debate uh that is going on
right now
in europe net neutrality guarantees that
every user can access any online content
or service using the device of their
choice
the focus of net neutrality debate is
concerned with the various network
management practices that
internet service providers the network
operators
should be allowed to pursue being the
central gatekeepers between consumers
and content providers
there is a difference between however
between open internet and net neutrality
the european net neutrality regulation
from 2015
we're going to talk about that in a
minute and try and uh enshrines user
rights to access and distribute
information and content online
but it applies only to the internet
service providers which are
all only one link in the internet access
chain
the ability to access the internet and
provide content to relies
on a much larger chain in which other
stakeholders also play an important role
well open internet is a broader concept
it involves regulation against
discriminatory practices involving
software and hydro which could impact
any
end users reads of choice for an example
operating system neutrality devices
manufacturers
with select and operating system and a
small number of popular apps that cannot
be uninstalled
the same is true for app stores in the
mobile
market search neutrality search engines
like
google or bing may have no neutral
conduct by ranking
search results that relates to its own
or affiliated
services high in the organic and paid
search results
and of course browser web browser
neutrality
can because web browsers can also be a
vehicle that allows vertical integrated
companies in favor their own services at
the expense of consumers
freedom of choice well uh
so we think that uh the the debate of
net neutrality uh
is much broader when we consider
disorder kind
of neutrality in this
in these other elements in the chain and
in this
in this picture we can see that the
router uh
stands in the end of
the the the network between the end
users domain
and the public uh
network isp domain
and that's exactly the point
where router freedom stays in danger
and why router freedom a concept a very
clear concept
uh in law is being danger right now
well we're going to see that there are
vague rules
on the european level uh national
authorities
are responsible for monitoring the
activities of the internet services
providers they are doing the bad
monetary
and the network uh operators they are
imposing barriers on
users so let's see uh the first one
so i said the net neutrality regulation
from 2015
the uh provides users the the
the right of to choice to choose and to
use the routers and equipment they want
to connect to the internet
um but in 2020 uh there is
a new set of rules technical rules
regarding the network termination point
a definition
that the terms if the router and the
modem should pertain
should pertain to the user or to
internet service providers and barrack
has
uh put some uh criteria to determine
if the router should uh who should have
the property of
the router the the user or the isp
the most controversial topic in that
is that they say if there is a
technological necessity
if the isp can determine a technological
necessity
the router can can go
directly to the infrastructure of the
isp
and right now the
eu member states they will implement
these rules the network
the natural regulation the uh
doesn't need to to be implemented
because of regulation but the guidelines
on ntp will have to be implemented uh
on eu member states and here lies the
problems because it
will be easier for isp to prove
technological necessity and they can
keep uh our routers in their own
infrastructure
so uh besides that
this national regulatory aid authorities
who
okay so uh right now the national
regulatory
uh authorities they are responsible for
monitoring the activity of
isp they are doing very bad and they are
not
imposing any type of
fines or penalties
on those who do not comply with the
regulation
allowing users to use their own routers
and of course uh
[Music]
isp they are imposing different kind of
barriers
uh in uh for consumers
to use their own routers and we at the
fsfe we divided
these barriers in two types the software
barriers and the hard
barriers of course the hard ones are
much serious because for an example
cause
customers are forbidden to use another
router by contract
isp do not provide users they login data
to the public network
they use known standard plugs or
proprietary protocols
and of course they don't they don't
offer technical support
uh for internet access but there are
other types of barriers software
barriers for example when they don't
inform
the users that they have the right to
use their own routers or
they manipulate users through customer
support in favor
of their own routers and of course there
are other
types of barriers that isp are very
creative
in order to impose their own equipment
on users
so uh what you can do to help
um as we said uh there
there is very clear rules defending our
rights but
right now we are suffering a lot of
people are suffering
with their network operators the
internet service provides because they
don't they cannot use
um their routers and we are we want to
change this scenario
we want to
demonstrate that in fact our rights
should be
respected and we can do that because
there are very clear rules
so what you can do to help three
three steps uh contact your isp ask if
you can use your router
and send me an email tell me the results
lucas.lasota
fsf.org and
let me know uh what are the kind of
problems you are having
and we are working there to
raise awareness in europe around router
freedom
and fighting for our rights
so i i think uh we are done
my presentations uh um
is quite short and i would just i would
be
very happy to hear if there is some
questions
thank you very much thanks and what
people can do i really like the strong
call for action ask your isp so far
there have been no questions from the
internet
but i thought that maybe so
when when i was thinking about what you
just told us i was really interested
if you could tell us so imagine a legal
situation where the route of freedom in
the u
is absolutely guaranteed what's
beautiful
nice things would happen for the user so
what what is the vision
we're working towards here what are the
the really good things
that would happen for users if we if we
won this fight yes uh
absolutely uh again just i wanted to
show
that the benefits for that because
first freedom of choice users will be
completely free to choose the equipment
they want
today an isp for an isp is very
easy to impose their own router and if
we are
obliged to use their router we have
problems with security because
we don't know uh which kind of software
if it's preparatory structure running
in their equipment um we don't know if
this software uh
has some bugs and therefore we don't
know which kind of software is running
on the equipment
so our privacy and that protection is
all compromised
and of course when we have the
possibility to choose our own equipment
it's it's uh we can uh
it's very nice for the market because we
can then
provide free competition and
compatibility so we are
fighting this kind of fight for router
freedom so
users can enjoy this kind of benefits
okay thank you there just
a question came in
um so it's and the question is asking
about the possible examples of these
technological measures
i think the rest is missing do you
already understand what the question
means
so i think there's technical measures
the isps
are implementing or the requirements um
right and i think the question is asking
for example for that
do you have any maybe
oh yes for an example uh
well a very very true example because
happened
to to me and to other staffers in the
fsfe the
isp they don't want to provide use the
loading data to the public network so we
tell them
look i have my router here and i need
the looking data to access
your network so we i can have access to
the internet here at my home
and they say i'm sorry uh the the
looking data is provided
only inside the our own equipment so we
cannot provide you that
you must use our own equipment so this
is one of
one of types of barriers one type of
technical measures that isb imposed on
users
and uh and we talked like here but it's
happening all
over europe okay
thanks a lot thanks a lot for the talk
thanks a lot for answering answering the
questions
as always we have the after talk
discussion
board where you can you guys can discuss
something with lucas and ask him
additional questions it's at all as
always
on discussion dot rc3
um and there's nothing more to say
for me thanks for listening thanks lucas
for being here today
and the program will continue
shortly thanks a lot and thank you again
the organizators for this beautiful very
nice opportunity to be together
thanks a lot pleasure
[Music]
you