[Music]
the future laws
on ii in the eu are being shaped right
now
and while many voices from the police to
governments call for widespread video
surveillance
broad coalition of 14 european
organizations calls for the opposite
a ban of facial and other biometric
recommend
recognition systems in public spaces
the next talk is about these efforts and
will be given by five people
andrea who is organizing campaigns at
adrien
elif therius co-founder of greek civil
civil society organization homo
digitalis
ella who is policy and campaigns officer
at edry
phillip who is an engineer artist and
activist
and ricardo who is a journalist and
researcher for the italian hermes center
for transparency
in their talk they will present the
campaign their goals
and explain what you can do to support
it we're really happy to have you here
so good morning good evening or good day
everyone we don't know when this is
being broadcasted
yet but this is the reclaim your face
talk
for this year's congress
and we wanted to start with an
imagination exercise
imagine you're in a public space uh what
do you do in this public space
you're probably walking you're on your
way to work or to your house to grab a
beer
or you're just walking for the sake of
it you might be meeting a friend to hang
around in the park or
some people for a demo um maybe you're
in a public square and you just decided
to join some folks for a random concert
that spontaneously just
started because some folks had their
guitars around
the point is that public spaces are
spaces for communities
their platform for group dialogue and
civic action
there's spaces where we can really
exercise our freedoms
be it our freedom to gather in an
assembly to speak out against injustices
or the freedom to document and record
abuses
public spaces are the areas where we
want to be treated
fairly and not discriminated against
because of how
we look how we walk what we wear or who
we kiss
public spaces allow us to decide
ourselves
how we want to be seen by others and
have the autonomy
over what actions we take
however the introduction of biometric
mass surveillance into our public spaces
is threatening our communities our
freedoms
our autonomy and the very expectation
one has to be treated fairly
when we say biometrics we mean any type
of data that relates to your body or
your behavior
biometric data is sensitive data under
eu law
what better idea than to combine this
sensitive data
with an unlawful practice mass
surveillance
mass surveillance is any monitoring
tracking
and otherwise processing of data of
individuals or groups in an
indiscriminate
or a randomly targeted manner
our qualities behaviors emotions
characteristics are used against us our
dignity is
under threat people are objectified
commodified dehumanized
the use of these technologies like
facial recognition
are manipulative for example coercing
people into avoiding certain places or
events
the problems with biometric mass
surveillance are many from being
constantly monitored to being treated by
your government like a potential suspect
being discriminated against because you
have a certain color
religious accessory or because you're
holding the hand of the
wrong partner biometric mass
surveillance technology such as live
facial recognition
is being deployed in european public
spaces every day
in secret with no evidence behind the
need
of such deployment with no respect for
our right or for our dignity
in the public space this is why
the reclaim your face movement is
calling for
a ban on biometric surveillance in
european public spaces
we are a coalition of organizations
across europe as well as organizations
with international reach such as article
privacy international access now and
european rich such as italy
my name is andrea and i come from
european digital rights the umbrella 44
digital rights organizations
today i'm joined by my colleagues ella
also from edri
el esterios from homo digitalis in
greece
phillip from share foundation in serbia
and ricardo from hermes center in italy
in the next hour or so we will give you
an update on how the eu legal
landscape is looking like we will zoom
in
on the mobilization in greece serbia and
italy
and we will discuss how you can help out
if you're as concerned as we are
i'll hand it in now to ella my colleague
will give a
intro into how the eu law landscape is
looking like
thanks andrea so what are things looking
like for
biometrics in europe well the eu
has actually been developing rules on
biometrics since
as early as 2004 and parts of the edgery
network have been advocating for
just as long to make sure that this is
done in a way that's lawful
and that respects people's rights so
probably most notably
in 2018 the now world famous
general data protection regulation or
gdpr
as well as its lesser known counterpart
for police purposes
called the data protection law
enforcement directive
both came into force and these rules
explained for
really the first time in european law
what biometric data actually
are and they also established the
principle of a ban
on their youth so specifically this
meant that the
processing of sensitive biometric data
was now
forbidden in eu law but
there are a number of really broad
exceptions
and loopholes to this ban which has
opened the door to deployments which
have really clearly
violated people's rights and freedoms
and it's been a really similar story
in non-eu european countries like serbia
too
so in february or march of 2021
we're expecting that the european
commission will propose a new
and potentially quite groundbreaking law
for how the eu
will regulate artificial intelligence
this law will likely have ramifications
on
other european countries and probably
the rest of the world
in terms of the standards that it sets
and it's likely to include rules on the
use of what the commission calls
remote facial recognition but we call
that
a form of biometric mass surveillance
and there are many other forms of
biometric mass surveillance out there
too
over a year ago there was actually a
leaked draft of a paper
on artificial intelligence which
revealed that at one point
the european commission had actually
considered a
three to five year ban on some uses of
biometric surveillance in
public spaces but ultimately
and very unfortunately they made a
political decision that
so-called innovation and profitability
were more important so we're really
hoping that this time round
when we get this new proposal for a law
early next year
they'll be more aware of their
obligations under fundamental rights law
so to quickly give an overview of what's
happening in europe in response and and
what we're doing about this
uh well because our lawmakers and our
politicians
are not yet taking decisive action to
protect
european public spaces democracies
and essential rights and freedoms from
biometric mass surveillance
our coalition is stepping up to demand
that they do so
we've been raising the alarm about the
fact that any use of biometric
surveillance technologies to scan
everyone in public spaces inherently
constitutes a form of mass surveillance
and as a network we've been following
the deployment of these systems in
almost every european country and
after investigating the high levels of
abuse
the harms posed to individuals
communities and society
the resistance to this biometric
surveillance from people across europe
and the emerging global examples of
people's rights and freedoms being
really severely violated as a result
of the use of these technologies we have
decided that
enough is enough over
20 organizations in the reclaim your
face coalition
have been exposing why biometric mass
surveillance is so harmful
and they've been providing strong
evidence for why we need to ban it
we focused on the lack of transparency
and justifications for
existing systems with for example
members of ccc in germany
raising freedom of information and data
subject access requests
for information from authorities and
companies
we've focused on the need for clear
legal limits with
la quadrature dunet in france
successfully litigating against
unlawful uses of facial recognition by
authorities
and across europe we've focused on the
shocking
absence of respect for human dignity
human autonomy and human rights
um so i'm gonna pass over now to three
of the brilliant organizations in the
editorial network
that have been resisting biometric mass
surveillance in their cities and
countries
so that they can share more about what's
been happening specifically in greece
serbia and italy so without further ado
i would like to introduce elepharius
from homo digitalis
in greece i think ricardo is the first
one to go
but i'm sure
reshuffling is not an issue ricardo will
basically detail
the black hole italy is when it comes to
details on the facial recognition used
by police and how local municipalities
are trying to catch up with the latest
innovative
technologies completely disregarding
fundamental human rights
ricardo you've got the floor thank you
in the past three four years italy has
seen a slowly but constant introduction
of these
biometric surveillance technologies
ranging from face recognition to
other kind of metadata analysis of
video cameras in this map you can see
three main points of entrance in the
city of cuomo
a festive recognition system was
introduced but later
thanks to the intervention of data
protection authority the system was
stopped
because was deemed illegal the city of
turin and the city of udine they're both
trying to introduce
barometric surveillance systems in the
case of wooden they are specifically
talking about face recognition systems
while in the case of turin they are
talking about a kind of metadata
analysis of the video
that would allow the the police forces
to
monitor the movements of citizens across
the city
and to distinguish if someone is a man
or a woman
and to check and detect what kind of
clothes or objects they are carrying on
these are examples of what's going on at
a
local city level when we look instead to
the italian police so
at the national level the scientific
police has bought in 2017
a fist recognition system that can be
used during investigations
just to give some examples of what's
going on what we've done and what the
protection authority has said
in the case of the city of como this is
a summary of an article you can find on
previous international
we wrote in english so we can spread it
around
basically the seed of comma was
approached by huawei in order to
acquire a new innovative system
for uh ensure that the city was more
safe so basically surveillance as a
safety measures but also seen a
solidarity between the citizens
from our investigation from finding
funeral information requests we obtained
documents that
clearly show how the data protection
impact assessment carried out by the
city of cuomo
was basically a field of a seal of
approval uh
meaningless because was done after the
system was acquired
it was basically claiming that face
recognition
equals video surveillance which is not
and for this
for this reason the data protection
authority uh stopped the city of como
from using
this kind of surveillance system video
of face recognition system
and also from the from the documents
we've seen that the huawei the company
involved in this kind of
activity was basically uh pushing for
the introduction of these innovative
technologies
and in the end again the city of como
wasted public money on a system the data
protection authority
say it's lacking a legal basis to be
used
from the from the documents that we
obtained
thanks to the freedom information
request we can see the
other kind of abilities of the
technology that it's being solved by
workbay in this case it's a soft or sort
of metadata analysis so we can see that
the the system in addition to physical
recognition can also
uh track abandoned objects loitering
crowd density
face detection head counting abnormal
speed detection
these are all kind of metadata analysis
that criminalize behavior so basically
there is a if there is a suspicious
behavior
which is like not clearly defined this
system can send an alert this kind of
message analysis
falls within the barometric surveillance
the biometric processing of our data
and it's also something that yeah it's
been installed in the city of turin as i
mentioned before
if we move forward and at the national
level
talking about the system acquired by
italian police this is a screenshot from
the
system being used showed on national
television you can even see the address
of the website
of course this is called and
it consists of two different um aspects
there's a sorry enterprise
which is basically an upgrade to the
manual search that they used to do
in the database of mac shots uh
previously they did this
writing down the details of the suspect
in this case the police can use
a fish recognition system to automate
the process make it more
fast a kind of optimization
and can search images during
investigations
given an image from a cctv camera during
an investigation they can
match this image to see if in the
database
there's someone they know and that
there's a match
as andrea was mentioning in italy the
black hole regarding this information
this is the fact that when we ask
questions regarding this database
we don't know uh how many people are in
there
the overall number is two million images
of italian citizens and seven million
images on foreigners
but when it comes to these foreign
citizens it's not clear if they are
citizens from other european countries
or migrants and assignment seekers we
know for sure
they're in there because the office
database this is the name of
the database used from for this space
recognition system
is a database that includes also
fingerprints
of people so if you are required to
give your fingerprint to the italian
police you are included in this database
also there are lacking evaluation of the
algorithm used by the police every time
you ask
information they basically refrain from
giving you
any kind of details in 2018 the italian
distribution authority opened an
investigation on the second
aspect of the saudi phase recognition
system which
is the real-time one so after two years
the investigation is still ongoing and
we don't have any
kind of details regarding the legality
and possibility
for the police to use the real-time
system that was
acquired in order to monitor
public manifestations public events
which falls within a kind of biometric
mass surveillance
but we're still waiting
i now leave the floor to philip to
introduce
what's happening in serbia
thanks ricardo hope everyone can hear me
so
as ella said serbia is a non-eu country
we are in kind of hybrid regime at the
moment media is controlled
freedom is of speech is suppressed so
officially we are leaning towards west
and european union but we have also
strong influence from
east and china on i would say mutual
interests
we are part of the china's belt and road
project among
other 70 countries mostly third world
countries and
we are being probably victims of that
trapped and soft power influence
so uh huawei managed to sell us
a huge infrastructure with around 8 000
facial recognition cameras being
deployed
either on poles in the streets of police
cars as
since few days ago and
also there will be body cams on
our police officers so since we are not
into geopolitics we don't care if this
is like huawei of or siemens
or some us companies cameras we're just
scared that
this is completely unlawful
so two years ago our
ministry minister of police said that
there will be no significant street
entrances or
passages between buildings that will not
be covered by cameras
we will know from which entrance and
building the perpetrator came from which
car
so this was kind of shocking to us we
started doing research on this we
were sending a lot a lot of
freedom of information access requests
we were being denied
mostly because they're confidential
so we did some uh
awesome or open source intelligence
research we found a nice case study
about belgrade on huawei's website which
was kind of weird because we didn't get
any information from our government
but we got it from from
chinese website and as soon as we
we published it it was removed from
their website
which was kind of interesting so
we analyzed the laws and we were pretty
sure that
that this is unlawful we also found some
other ways to
to obtain some information like this one
while the the the cameras were deployed
on the streets
and uh finally we we
we realized that we have to to reach out
to the community because
we we know that the whole system
uh is really bad for the society and
it's also awful so basically in serbia
we have this
uh data protection law which is kind of
translated gdpr so
so actual purpose was not defined for
this system
and the the necessity was not confirmed
so basically belgrade is not
unsafe city we don't have terrorist
attacks we
don't have much of this low-level crime
so why do we need this kind of system
also data protection impact assessment
was not approved yet but we still
have this whole system being installed
in in belgrade so what do we do next we
start reaching out to
to community this is a a small
exhibition at the art festival we we put
one bench under surveillance and and the
qr codes to our
cute little small website which was
just uh means to to to leave some
contact information for everyone that
was interested in joining this fight
so we we basically were promoting it
on on music festivals we
we on hacker events we
printed a lot of these speakers to
promote the website at one point and
went it went wide
viral so actually
a lot of people reached back offering
help in many ways
so this was a good sign for us
we gathered them in a nice event
we them to do collaborative work in
several domains so basically what we
wanted to do
we had a group for called.txt where
journalists were speedwriting
everything that our citizens needs to
know
we had the pdf group which were legal
guys
who were analyzing laws and making some
strategies for this we had the
html group which were web developers and
designers creating this website
we also had tech guides that were
analyzing
patents and other resources this was
one of the blueprints that came to be
something like this so we actually
did a really nice map called the
architecture of the face recognition
system this is
yet about to go out but we used
understanding of this system to to
and some of its details to to help our
co-citizens understand the issues so
this is
part from our website which actually
explains how this whole system works and
why is it so bad for for the whole
society
so uh finally we had the the
the guys from the local hack club in
belgrade that
helped us deploy the surveillance under
surveillance it's
it's a german um free and open source
application for mapping
cameras so we deployed this and then we
started
the hunt for the cameras as we call it
with with the
with our community in in belgrade in
serbia
we invited people to recognize the
cameras that
recognize themselves so these are the
three most common cameras used in this
system
we set up the twitter profile which
became uh instantly popular people were
sending us photos from the
from the streets with gts coordinates
and
and we actually were able to
fill in gradually the whole
map of belgrade which counts more than 1
cameras at the moment
so we launched this crowdsourcing
campaign which was really nice
and and this this is kind of success
that
because we have now a strong community
supporting us we did
a nice campaign a few weeks ago
asking the petition campaign asking
the government to ban biometric mass
surveillance
and of course finally
we managed to to start a crowdfunding
campaign because as
you can see on this internal uh
meme we did one of the main components
in
our starter pack for anti biometric mass
surveillance factories
is resilience we mostly do this pro bono
so we started
this crowdfunding campaign and it's
going really well so we are
hoping to ban uh biometrics in belgrade
and remove all the cameras
so thank you very much i will leave it
now to asterisk
thank you philip ellis
if you would like to turn on your camera
and
hello yes thank you i'm sorry i had a
small
issue with my camera before also i still
hope that now you can see me well
uh thank you felip thank you andrea
greetings from athens greece
uh in the next few minutes i will
present to you
my slides about the the actions you have
taken
in greece i will speak about the central
database of biometric info
about the use of drones at cameras by
hellenic police during demonstrations
and about an important contract of smart
gases
that will enable the hellenic police to
use facial recognition technology during
stops
and controls in our streets so
without further undo to begin with
the hellenic police and the private
vendor called intracon telecom
signed last year a 4 million euro
contract
the company will develop and deliver the
hellenic police
smart devices with integrated software
enable
facing facial recognition and automated
fingerprint identification technologies
among other functionalities the devices
will be very small in the size of the
smartphone
and police officers would be able to
carry them with
to carry these devices with them and use
them during massive police stops
in order to take a close-up photograph
of an individual
as well as to collect their fingerprints
then the fingerprints and photographs
collected will be immediately compared
with
data already stored in eu databases for
identification purposes
so we decided to take some related
actions and to file some extra
information requests
to the hellenic police the replies we
got were very unsatisfying
so we decided to proceed with a
complaint before the hellenic data
protection authority in march 2020
it is important to remember that no
related legal bases exist
for the use of such technologies in
greece
as well as no data protection impact
assessments were conducted by the
hellenic police
prior to the signature of this smart
policing contract of 4 million euros
we were very satisfied to see that the
hellenic data protection authority
follow up
and in august 2020 they started an
official investigation against this
contract
now moving on to uh the next action i
will briefly speak to you about a
central biometric database of the
hellenic police
our police collects all fingerprints of
greek passport holders
in this central database it is again
important to underline that based on the
eu laws on passports as well as
the set case law of the european court
of the court of justice of the european
union
fingerprints shall be stored in the past
from themselves in the very documents we
carry in our
bags and in our pockets so the eu law
neither
prohibits nor allows for national
central databases of biometric
info to exist if member states want to
proceed with the creation of such
databases they have to create their own
laws
but also we need to remember that based
on european data protection laws
processing of biometric information such
as fingerprints
is allowed where it is strictly
necessary subject to appropriate
safeguards
and authorized by a national law
so we had to take action again and in
june 2020 we decided to file two
strategic complaints before the hellenic
data protection authorities
using data subjects um two months later
the
taxation authority replied to our
complaint and they started again an
official investigation
now in addition to these two uh
actions i would like to briefly speak to
you
about the use of drones and other type
of civilian mechanisms by the hellenic
police
back in april 2020
we filed one friend of information
access request
before the hellenic ministry of citizens
protection
because the hellenic police used drones
in order to monitor
people's movement uh during the coving
19 lockdown measures last easter
also a few days ago we filed other two
freedom of information access requests
before the chief of the hellenic police
regarding the use of drones and cameras
on sticks
in public demonstrations it is important
to mention that back in
april 2020 the hellenic police didn't
have
a legal basis to use drones or other
types of cameras and
surveillance in order to monitor
individual movements
the adoption of a related presidential
degree of the legal base
happened a few months ago in september
so with our first friend of information
access request
to the hellenic ministry of citizen
protection we demanded to know what was
the legal basis
for using these drones in our city
centers baking back in april
while with our second round of friend of
information access requests
we ask the hellenic police uh to give us
access to the related data protection
impact assessment
that sees obli that it is obliged to
carry as well as
to the administrative decisions that the
hellenic police
is obliged again to publish based on the
applicable laws
and i will now give the floor back
to ella and adria to continue their
presentation
thank you alesterios um ella
i think now you will uh give us some
tips on the next steps for our campaign
absolutely thank you andrea and uh
thanks
to uh the real ella serious this time
sorry for my mix-up earlier i hope i
didn't confuse anyone
so yeah next steps uh how are we
continuing
to resist biometric mass surveillance in
europe
well we're continuing to reveal abusive
uses and to contest
the implementation of biometric mass
surveillance across our public spaces
in europe because we're just not seeing
enough action from regulators or data
protection authorities
instead we're seeing law enforcement
governments and private companies
really taking advantage of the
democratic and
legal vacuum that we're in right now
so in 2021 we plan to do
even more to engage people across europe
to help us challenge those in power and
to seek answers about what's really
going on
this is going to include everything from
formal challenges
and requests to information from
authorities like with freedom of
information requests
uh also through to public workshops and
even partnerships with artists our
big ticket item for 2021 is going to be
a european citizens initiative calling
to ban
biometric mass surveillance practices in
the eu
this initiative which is also known as
an eci
is a form of legally recognized petition
which will call on the european
commission to take concrete legislative
action we have very clearly told them
that right now
the lack of specific eu laws to limit
uses of biometrics
and the problems of enforcing the
existing
general principles have meant that they
are in violation of their obligations
under the eu charter of fundamental
rights and
that causes so many harms in the ways
that my colleagues have just
explained in just three of the countries
whereas this is happening systematically
across
europe and so soon we are going to need
over 1 million european nationals to
sign our eci to say that they agree with
our call to ban
biometric mass surveillance practices so
we really hope that we can count on you
for this uh the eci is also going to
give us a platform
to extend the coalition that we've been
building
bridging across issues of labor rights
media freedoms
social and racial justice women's rights
lgbtq eye rights
environment and more because
after all biometric mass surveillance is
an issue that can cause
very serious harm to certain groups
but of course it can also have a
chilling effect
on absolutely everyone because it really
goes against that fundamental right that
we all have
to respect for our private life
andrea i'd like to uh invite you to let
everyone know how
they can join us and be a part of the
reclaim your face movement
thank you anna so biometric data
includes data about our body and
behavior and that means
everything from fingerprint palm print
palm
veins face recognition of course dna
hand geometry iris recognition
retina recognition typing rhythm walking
manner
voice and much more companies
and governments in europe are
innovating and trying to find new ways
to capture your identity
um yet under eu
data protection law this data is
especially sensitive
they're linked to our identities and can
be used
to infer protected and intimate
information about who we are
our health and more if you think this is
problematic
and if you're worried about all the
information
my colleagues have mentioned so far well
get involved over 11 000 people
have already wrote to their governments
you can go on the reclaimyourface.eu
website
and sign a petition to address your
government
from february though we're mobilizing to
address the eu
so two things what can you do
now and what can you do in february 2021
as you've just heard we're focusing on
gathering evidence
and um gathering support
so right now for starters you can write
an email to your mayor or to a city
councilor
in your own city ask them to promise
that will
they will not deploy biometric mass
surveillance in your city's public
spaces
do they reply they're positive about it
get in touch with us and let us know
we'll celebrate together in february
we will launch the european citizen
initiative that my colleague ella
mentioned
in order for this to be really powerful
we need to reach
1 million signatures then the european
commission will be obliged to respond to
us
this means we'll need a lot of help do
you want to get involved in gathering
these signatures
again get in touch finally
what if you're an organization what if
you know an organization
that might be interested in joining our
coalition
we're looking in particular like ella
mentioned
for organizations that cover a broad
range of areas from media freedom
freedom of assembly
disability rights sex workers rights
labor unions and more let us know
put us in touch and let us build
together a
civil society movement that will make
your grandchildren
pretty proud of you thank you i would
like to invite my colleagues
to turn on their cameras you can get in
touch with us
um through our twitter handles of course
um
or to writing directly at info
at reclaimerface.eu
i'm seeing them pointing in all
directions
um we're looking forward to your
questions
and see you around
so thanks a lot for the overview over
everything that's happening in
in europe right now i was really
interested at what made you start the
campaign or what was the the point where
you thought
now now this has to change we have to do
this campaign and bring organizations
together
and stop this
question yeah so thanks rick and uh hi
everyone
and on the uh point about experimenting
with the q a
we are very happy and comfortable
experimenting with q and a's um
we are not happy with experimenting with
people's faces and bodies
and public spaces so that's kind of
what's driven us
to to launch this this campaign um
from a policy and legal point of view
we've been following developments across
europe
uh for many many years across the edry
network
and we were noticing a trend in
the number of really harmful uses
just going up and up we were seeing
every
or pretty much every police force in
europe starting to trial
these technologies in a really uh
sketchy way and we were seeing private
companies
rolling them out in supermarkets concert
stadiums
football stadiums without any public
debate
on what this means without properly
considering the risk
without knowing what it means for eu law
and then when there were the rumors that
the european commission was considering
some sort of ban on you know five year
three to five year moratorium on on some
of these technologies
in public spaces that have gave us a lot
of hope
as civil society and as activists and
it never materialized and we realized
that
civil society aren't really being
listened to and
the public aren't really being listened
to when it comes to these
biometric technologies but as i've
noticed when i've spoken on panels
alongside ceos from
surveillance tech companies they are the
ones
that are being listened to by the eu
they're the ones that are getting
millions of euros to essentially
experiment with with our faces and
bodies with our public spaces
uh so we decided enough is enough and we
need to do
something about this um and we needed to
make sure that our our european values
our democratic principles are actually
adhered to you it's really really
important to us that this is something
that is considered
um and not something that's just done
and
a few years down the line we hear well
it's everywhere it's
it's too late um because it's not too
late this is really
the time for us to take decisive action
but yeah andrea am i am i missing no i
think that was a great
overview um and
if i if i may um chip in some thoughts
we started working on this already
i think more than a year ago right so
when the corona crisis
and all the measures um to
stop the spread of it were not even in
our
worst dreams um but i feel like in the
past
months the general public has
grown more and more aware of where
can surveillance measures
lead to and how do they look like and
see them above their heads when they go
out in their cities and i feel like
this this awareness um
is also a very very kind of
big push for this campaign to move
forward
and like ella mentioned when you see
that people are outraged about this
and when you know that the eu is making
new laws
on the topic there is no way we can stay
quiet
so i feel like um yeah i'm
sure and i i hope not but
i have a presupposition but more and
more reasons
we carry this fight for world war ii
appear
so we better start mobilizing
ella you mentioned that in many many um
cases there's no real debate and people
just start implementing systems and are
listening to the
company bosses of big companies instead
of the general public
what do you think is the reason for that
so why are we missing out on these
really important debates
what what do we need to do to have these
debates before systems are introduced
there are so many reasons really why why
it's happened this way
um a lot of the pushback shall we say
that we hear from
the european commission for example are
things that just aren't true so there's
a lot of
myths out there and people say oh well
you can unlock your
phone with your fingerprint um so it's
too late
and actually that's that's really not
the same thing as
suddenly every time you leave your house
to go
to a protest uh to walk in a park to
to do nothing as is your right um
suddenly you're being tracked
and not only trapped but that's etched
into your identity um in a really
immutable way that's going to follow you
around and connect you to lots of people
is absolutely not the same thing as
unlocking
a phone so we hear these kind of
arguments that
that aren't really uh aren't really true
um and we face the kind of security
argument
um a lot and we have uh
governments in particular using that to
justify doing
uh unlawful activities and actually uh
if you
look at the eu law that we have there
are of course
provisions that allow governments and
police forces
to protect their citizens um that's a
legitimate
policy goal to keep people safe um
it's just that there are controls on the
way that they're allowed to do this
so that we can have those checks and
balances that also protect us from
abuses of power um from arbitrary
surveillance
um so actually these excuses about oh we
need to do this and it's justified
i'm not true there's a very clear legal
threshold and
what we're seeing is pretty much every
single european country
is is not meeting these legal thresholds
that are designed
actually to keep us safe and when we
think actually about what it
what it means to feel safe and to feel
secure
to know that you can express yourself
uh whether that's your gender identity
your religious beliefs um whatever it
might be
you should be free to to be yourself
um and secure knowing that you can vote
you can attend a community event you can
participate
in the things that make it
worth living the public activities that
make us feel a part of something
bigger than ourselves and i've said this
before you you only have to look at
every dystopian science fiction
film and book ever to know that the
thought of society where there's someone
breathing down our neck and capturing
every bit of us to put in the database
and turning us into walking barcodes um
it's not a society where everyone feels
safe and secure it's
it's actually one where we're treated as
if we're a criminal suspect
all the time and we know that once
people
understand it in those terms and and see
the fact that this doesn't
contribute to the sort of free and
vibrant and open society that
i think the vast majority of us want i
think then it's a lot easier to
understand
um the nuance of this debate
and to not necessarily pay attention to
a lot of the either political statements
that we hear
or often the marketing you hear tech
companies spout
all sorts of glossy things and often
they can't do what they say
we've found many that are not lawful if
they do what they claim they can do
um but that's a lot of of what we hear
in civil society
our budgets are not as large as the the
tech giants
um which is why it's really important
that we
find creative ways to raise our voices
yeah yeah just to add to that i think
biometric data is really
a gold mine
for government surveillance but also for
surveillance capitalism so when we're
talking about this
we're talking about private companies of
course on the other side
but we're also talking about government
so there is here common interest
um that i feel it's not made
clear for obvious reasons to the public
and i feel like there's also
a misunderstanding when we're
discussing what is the real public
interest at stake
because of course governments and
companies can
shop can shape the discussion around
public interest and what does that mean
when it comes to biometric data and
biometric mass surveillance
face recognition but is that really
the public's interest is it really in
public's interest
to feel like you're a suspect whenever
you go out of your house
in a public space is it in your public
interest
to fear that you know whatever database
that has your face stored on will
leak tomorrow and you will never be able
to change your face again
or is this in our public interest i
don't i doubt so so i think
perhaps we can also you know do better
across civil society to
have a common narrative about what is it
that we want
this public interest to mean
explanations to me
it seems like you're implying that
many of these misunderstandings or that
people um
see these technologies in different
lights actually comes
from not being informed enough and not
being informed enough how these
technologies work
and what implications they have and it
it kind of like
what i got from your answer is that the
the difference of a utopia and a
dystopia
is like the nuances what you think might
happen
as soon as these systems are installed
and
what do you think what do we need we as
a movement as a
um as people as civil societies what do
we need to do
to get that knowledge to these people
who are making these decisions
that they kind of like can come to our
side and see that it's actually a step
towards a technological dystopia and not
a
safe and nice future for everybody
yeah well if i may i think
i'm thinking translation into ability
we often talk about uh you know human
rights but
these are such theoretical non-tangible
concepts that
very few of us actually envision
something when they spell them out and i
feel like we need to make
these concepts much more clear
and much more close to the everyday
reality
of people um i feel like
this is something we can definitely
work more on and also personally i think
the role of
art is so important at
inferring the impact of biometric mass
surveillance
on our freedoms without mentioning the
human right that is at stake but rather
the experience
that europe have if you don't take
an action and finally i think you know
we spoke
a lot about dystopias and utopias but i
feel like
we're um and i feel like we're doing
that already
we really need to envision what do we
want
this um future to look like in order for
us
to have a common vision and make it
clear
that our values are common we're all
working towards the same
goal here ella
please add please add
thanks andrea thanks andre
that sounds perfect and yet just to to
wrap off what andrea said absolutely we
need
to work towards the positive vision of
the kind of world that we're trying to
protect
and create where everyone is free and
not
put in a box and not judged and labeled
and controlled based on
who they are but actually one where a
world where we encourage that
beautiful full spectrum of human
difference human diversity human ability
um so trying to build that world and as
andrea said
translate it not just in terms of the
concepts but uh in terms of languages
making sure that this is a
multi-lingual accessible broad
movement that whatever language you
speak wherever you live
wherever you come from you have a place
in the movement
so
um thanks for for being here today
although remotely thanks for recording
their talking their talk
um yeah and i think there's not much
more to add
please um now everybody who's watching
this and is interested in a further
discussion go over to the discussion
room
please you too i don't know if you
already are or please move over to the
discussion room and then we can
start the discussion there and um
thanks a lot and yeah
yeah thanks to you
looking forward to seeing you in real
life next year hopefully
at some point everything will happen in
real life again
bye bye bye
[Music]
you