[Music]
you have a disability
and assistive tech solutions for that
are either
unavailable in your country or extremely
expensive
or they come in a terrible hospital
light green
the team of caribbels.org has been
tackling this problem since three years
and today they will present an insight
into their journey
we're really happy to have aprica here
today who will give you an overview over
their journey
their actions their key moments and how
they were able to help people
we're really glad to have you here today
thank you so much
and it's so exciting to be here on the
stage
and i'm presenting today caribou's
open source hardware for care we
went on a journey three years ago to
explore how to co-create
open hardware for care to create an open
hardware platform
and to bring different people together
to create
these solutions together
and first i want to say quickly what a
caribbean is
and thankfully most has already been
said so it's co-created
with those people who need it so if
you're a person with disability
or with a person with a temporary or
chronic illness
you have specific needs and you are the
expert about your
needs so makers designers
people in healthcare create together
then
it's replicable and adaptable for the
individual need
in the local hackerspace or in a local
makerspace of hablab
and lastly and most importantly i think
as well
it's open and documented so we have an
open platform
where you can upload and download open
hardware designs
get inspired and where you can see
which solutions there are that might fit
your needs
and why do we need this because the
solutions
sometimes don't exist because they're
very often super expensive and
often also unfortunately stigmatizing or
just wrongly designed and not so
beautiful like we would want
them to be
i'm standing here on the stage but i'm
representing a global community of
people who are creating these caribous
um here you see the members of the
global innovation gathering
an association registered in berlin but
spread across the whole world a little
bit maybe
comparable to a chaos computer club
airfares
like a knowledge exchange group that
comes together
and where you see people who are in
basra
in iraq have very similar problems to
people who are in south sudan for
example and creating a hackerspace there
or if you are in nairobi you have um
yeah things to discuss with people who
are in brazil in olinda for example so
that's
how we come together and
that's also a tiny map of where
caribou's activities already started to
be
taking shape and we are like now in the
stage of opening up to everybody
who wants to become part of that
and i want to give you a little bit of
an insight into
into the different projects
we are creating and in the different
in the different um yeah products
created and the different events
created and because i'm only standing
here for such a huge
number of amazing people and their
communities
i bring mostly videos they send to us
from their events and i'm starting with
a very inspiring video
from berlin that had world premiere
last year at the congress so i'm happy
to now show it in an
even better version and i will start
now so
you see the open health academy
and what happens there
is
[Music]
um
foreign
[Music]
so you see all the solutions created
here had the beginning
and the need of the person who wanted to
have it like sven who wanted to ride a
bicycle but couldn't
so that's at core of everything we tried
to do
and as everybody knows during coveted
pandemic
we had lots of people all over the world
creating protective equipment
personal protective equipment also here
in berlin
but also all around the world and here i
bring an example from kumasi hive in
ghana
where the makers and the makerspace also
created
lots of face shields for example
and we still were thinking that face
shields were super important
for protection and also
of course for medical field so in komasi
hive
they were already connecting to local
hospital for people with disability and
also with
engineering students and worked with
lots of people in these regards
but also had to see that they can't
access the makerspace
so there were only always a few people
allowed
to enter the makerspace
but still they created lots and lots of
these ppes
and these face shields and other helpful
equipment and they also were part of the
caribbean
seeks to empower people living with
disability
by removing the barrier of the lack of
assistive devices
the project is in two phases training
and co-creation which culminates in a
hackathon and kitchen summit
manufacturing and incubation
trainees for the program have been
selected they have been taken through
intensive and interactive training
sessions on product
design 3d modeling and fabrication
and material selection this training is
done in person and veterans
a virtual challenge to engage and
evaluate the skills of trainees in 3d
remodeling and fabrication
and material selection has been launched
and trainees are working on many
projects in teams
teams will develop a investor door knob
lever that easily converts a standard
door knob into a liver handle
people with difficulty gripping a
standard doorknob should find this
adapted liver handle
an easy way to open a door the handle
should be ideal for anyone who has
weak hands osteoporosis or arthritis
designed by a team will be shared on all
our social media platforms
for our online community booth for the
best
not in nepal
[Music]
together with students mostly to
work on these kinds of new designs but
also reproducing
designs that were already published on
the platform and on the internet
generally
and they have opening
they are opening very soon the very
first fab lab in nepal
so for them it was also a really good
case to show the community around their
region
that a fab lab and the tools and the
machines
and just creating things personally
can help a lot in the local community
and it's not only about
[Music]
learning but also creating something in
the end
there were lots of iterations of course
and in the end they published this
as open knowledge again for everybody
and also for example work together with
a local
hospital for people with disabilities
where pallab from nepal community
could help the local engineers
to work together in the hospital to fix
their 3d printers for example and this
is polyp
to fix 3d printers and to work together
to
create designs they needed in this
hospital
now we also see what they did during the
humanitarian design challenge
[Music]
and we will also of course publish the
videos so you can revisit them
and see what you can take from it for
example
[Music]
some of you also might have heard about
um
which is an organization that creates
this kind of capacity building
workshops but also was known like from
the beginning on for 3d printing and
humanitarian aid
so creating
[Music]
and also to collaborate
a lot with ngos on the ground in a
certain humanitarian situation
so that yeah the capacity
to build nowadays they are
mainly also creating
for example makerspaces in different
areas of the world
like in iraq
and if you're interested to create such
a
design sprint or other co-creation
events yourself
we also publish the the blueprints for
that
so that you can say the ideation the
empathy
the prototyping i don't have so much
ideas about that
can you help me and you can read these
introductions and then also try it out
yourself in your hackerspace
oh this was nepal which was very
exciting
next is casa cliatura lab in olinda in
brazil
and they they've also been working a lot
in the
comfort response
foreign
[Music]
so this is the last one and it's
something for
all the 3d printing nerds among us
[Music]
and also in milan as you know
in the beginning of the pandemic there
was yeah
a huge hit
yeah very struck and so
they were mass producing
also
[Music]
such a nice idea
so this was our very small world tour
of places that contributed
a lot to carables there's
many many more to show of course but we
tried to limit ourselves a little bit we
created an exhibition
that you can exhibit in your makerspace
so in your hackerspace
we created much more material of course
that you can use
and it's just so nice again
yeah so they also mass produced so much
what you see now in the box
and also work together of course with
hospitals and with other people who
really used
and needed these materials like
many others did
so if you want you can become part of
the caribbean's community you can send
us an email
connect on twitter connect
on the website of course check out the
resources we publish
and also just yeah explore
what's on there and if you have any
questions
or any comments please let us know
and if you want to join please also let
us know
thanks a lot
thank you so much for the talks of
course
we're supported gladly by the european
union
if anybody wants to have um
yeah the european union is supporting
lots of different innovation programs
and also this one
so thanks a lot for that
cool so far we haven't gotten any
questions from the internet if you are
watching this and
right now you think of a question please
ask it um over the usual channels
um and in the meantime i thought of
maybe maybe it's interesting for for
more people
how did that get started so is it
traceable
to to a circle of people who sat around
the table and were like
yes this is what we need to do there's
this problem and it needs to be tackled
yeah there's assistive tech communities
all around the world
working for example in humanitarian aid
or in humanitarian collaboration
where you see field ready is working for
a long time already cardos is working
for a long time already
in this field of creating your own
solutions for medical purposes for
example
then there's assistive tech communities
from people with disabilities
for example just creating their own
tools that they need for example i don't
know
enhancements for your wheelchair or
other things
and then there was a group
from the um
society in amsterdam meeting
geraldine one of the founders of the
global innovation gathering
in brazil in olenna i think or in rio
at a really amazing event and they spoke
about
what can you do and there's this grand
opening
um from the european union where you can
apply for with like
50 pages or 70 pages of proposal
and we were always in contact also with
the public in berlin and with lots of
people
from the hacker community of course and
found
people in milan who were closely related
with a center for the rehabilitation for
children with disability
mainly neurological diseases and they
had
such yeah beautiful products as well
that you could just reproduce for other
children and so they all
came together and thought yeah we can
create that proposal we can create that
platform
because back four or five years ago
there wasn't so many
open hardware platforms yet where you
could really dedicate it
find assistive tech solutions but you
would have
all these general platforms you all know
where you
find door handles but also small ships
and anything else that you could
possibly
3d print and so um the idea to have this
platform
dedicated for medical and for
assistive tech use was born
to have a place to collect this all and
to
have a place that is maybe also more
accessible for people that is more
accessible for example also for people
in the medical field who maybe don't
want to
scroll through all the ships and all the
other
tiny gadgets you can print so that was
the idea and then
we won the grand and we could start it
and now
the grand period is over and now we um
expand it to um yeah whoever wants to
contribute
cool yeah thank you for the insight for
the explanations
um maybe as a last thing i think
no question so far um could you give us
some
outlook so something if everything goes
great
what has happened in five years or what
where do you aim to get
um everybody knows how to create their
own
assistive tech and it's empowered to do
so for example through
online course and how to create designs
in cid programs for example
people in the medical field are
knowledgeable about what is possible
and for example people in the um
physical therapy or
like in this in these areas know about
what's possible technically
and are connected and of course
everybody is just putting everything on
the caribbean's platform but i mean
there are more open hardware platforms
out there now which is great
and so we're more collecting also and
yeah open open source hardware is
advanced
so like right to repair super important
aspect that you're the owner
of your own devices i don't know if
many people know it but if you're a
person with in a wheelchair for example
you're not the owner of your wheelchair
but
your health insurance is and so all
these
there's so many problems in this field
we're trying to tackle a tiny bit of it
and we hope that more people feel
inspired and
empowered to um work in the field
and we're also having a talk tomorrow
in the main program which is super
exciting
as well to reflect a bit on the last
three years
as well and to give an outlook of what's
coming
in the next next step okay
thank you for all the explanations that
sounds like a very good future
we will continue at seven o'clock with
the next talk
until we had then we have a dinner break
thank you so much for being here today
thank you so much for having me bye
[Music]
you