yet yet here's a mock wrap
come through them doing it
I I use
I don't even know memorable lyrics
champion yeah means i win
I comes along with us at the PM's clock
ticks down on lost in trans people total
is making dance
mention like a butterfly topic he went
high and dry
when you read my pics to meet with
little warning was moving through
also just give me time late notice not
be just fine
Hobbs Pennisetum year before me I'm
bound by his run away to glory
this block is mad at me I'm a room with
doping largess that
Bush Bush open year ago
yeah
home and
are all you do and when
okay so we're in a period from
I O is that I
your country's do people allowed
Rd the head I yupp
yep
need yeah I'm to lose money
okay so
you I will not only introduce the top
unit so cohort
yes I am wearing a slight one all happen
you doing he have fun
here you to you you do you
you
his PDP
do who
okay we figure out how to use were
ok
up I'll said thank you
little its fully owned my own Lexmark's
are
okay so I I would normally gives an
introduction
but a datagram this is Skyler I'm if
you'd like to know where u Pixar
I talk I we're going to
this detail which are a very particular
type a block I'm they were gonna talk
about how the different how the better
how they're worse
arm and the reason I think both of us
wanted to do this talk is cuz
we focus a lot on the pin number seven
years
and and you know when when we go to
other countries we go anyway
can really use the same stuff we do and
just to dinners are slowly in
getting more and more popular around the
world I'm because
a lot of the companies that make them
make specifically high-security just two
teams
I'm and in Asia the companies that make
this detainers make
the worst of his ever but they also
question that we are
be the least expensive locks ever and in
places where nobody wants to
afford a walk that's more than one euro
this is what they buy
Andrew we're seeing a time have the
we're seeing it on the yeah can emit 0
Lake
not very good but passable locks pouring
into the country right now
we'll talk a little bit of bike locks
later on rye well and we're
I don't know I'd say we're on the verge
of another Big Ten
situation with my kryptonite as other
brands because
nobody's actually moving to a new
generation I love they're not very
good walks right get so
up the main thing is is only one way yes
okay I water just it we just kept
getting close hand
water just interlock so the channel
locks are a specific type a lock
mechanism so a lot you have on your
doors are probably pin tumbler locks
which means these pains
to prevent you from rotating the plug
before you have
the cranky inserted or obviously
lockpicking all that other stuff combo
lawsuit with the crack key
and so distant is a very visually
distinct just from looking at your tech
crazy lock
and so the majority a bomb are mishap
circle thing like in the center
but there's also the more exotic
varieties such as on the left
actually if you look and the game room
the game room has nothing but
I just a tener padlocks and if you look
at the vending machines further down the
hall they have nothing but just in a
padlock swell
excuse me a cylinders built into the
machine so
to blame the way this started was
actually very also a lot of people
assume that anything that's not a pin to
lock
I must be new right that's not true so
these
a are pretty close to about 1 pin number
started become popular which is late
eighteen hundreds so the first person to
I invented just a tener as we know it
today
is this a.m your hendrickson and he
founded a company called ABLOY
which is now 1 I've I the biggest la
companies in the world beyond
everybody yeah happen
and so here's some examples the early
Apple iPad locks they look very
different than the padlocks we use
army as well obviously the keys in cuba
is a very different and so here's
example some keys and so the general
concept behind this to 10 or locks is
that instead of raising components
like mostar are common American locks we
wrote a components
and when all the components rotated in
the proper
position then the walk now open
and so here you can see the way they
accomplish this is by putting
angled cuts on the key and when you turn
it obviously
the components will stop a specific
position depending on
the angle so here's an example
a all the disks and components inside
NAIA a distant a lock here's an example
have all the discs inside
and CC each desk has
or keyhole cutout some them have the
support have
and all of them have the sole cut over
on the side in a car is what tells us
tells the lock when it's properly routed
I
to prevent picking all of these locks
will have all skates so
you know obviously if they're if they're
nothing but correct Gates who would be
considerably easier to just
try everything at the Philip click into
place and then you know that discuss
entrance by so
most if not all a serious distant and
manufactures will include some form a
false case to
deter this custom and one other things
that is the the main reason that's I am
just locks are becoming more popular is
because they don't use a pin mechanism
and as as a result tonight using a pen
mechanism that can be bumped
and everybody you know in our way of
looking at things
we go low bumping was a big problems I
wanna lock can be bumped
so this will not be bombs but that
doesn't necessarily mean that you're
buying the block
so I think of it in terms I love in all
our computer security stuff we all look
in just one specific attack and then say
well as long as I'm
protected from that I'm fine you have to
look I was in the big picture
I O is sOooo have is actually function
so
I this is an Eveleigh classic style disc
you have your open half moon which is
your key hole this shameful correspond
to the
shape on the awsome
was gonna pass many thanks mediums ago
I am so yeah we've even happen kilo
which corresponds to the shape of the
key
I you have your true gate the gate being
what a sidebar which you'll see a second
going to drop into you and your Tabares
stopper
I'm which is going to an online thing
newsletter rotation and there's a
your zero discharge will see in a couple
seconds here have a specific purpose but
okay Paso you your sidebar the sidebar
the locks is between the plug in the
lock in my house on the block
this is what's preventing the plug from
turning this is what's preventing
anything from turning at all
now the sidebar wants to go into the
gate let others do it so
when you are misaligned here
the cyber can't wait go in as a result
the plug & roti
blah blah here with the proper p.m.
and rotated to the proper angle was a
market dropping a place in the whole
season concerned really
okay words hope their play in
do dude been
Mac again you do whatever cut
I am difficult decisions then
you know I never open that on this
laptop
in I mean I feel like
we couldn have given a better talk to
them
still Walker talk anyway now so good
okay so here it is so this is the name
is plus or looking at the concept is
exactly the same
I was recently learning how to use
Blender I'd really like it I recommended
I'm anyway see your Kia Motors the
different angles came to the key
the angle cut into the key corresponds
directly in with the
number of degrees out from center BD is
was just double ball mechanism inside
the padlock
the law mechanisms are awesome they're
perfectly should improve
but nothing to do with this team's right
here comes the important part
let's look inside so the reason
that've I'm yeah awesome were eight
there
alright so the reason that the sidebar
pushes itself into the discs whatsoever
is if you look rate here
this large piece of metal is actually
protruding from the plug
when this 0 desk in this case the disk
back here and there's another discredit
the front
when these are fully rotated by the key
they actually collide with that tab
beginning to put a turning pressure on
the plug itself
by putting a turning pressure on the
plug that then transfers that pressure
to the sidebar
and as you'll see you right now the
sidebar is mounted in an angled
chamber and soul wants to slide out in
that chamber
into the gates if they're available to
it
in
yes done there's chaim their
science their gun II passed around a
couple different as two tenors they're
all made by Apple I am now basically
work
on be at the same principle there's a
minor differences
in the that the way that each at the
things I passed around works
but they're basically the same
to make sense you are welcome to tell us
if it doesn't
okay straight through just let it go
no problem
it is yes you that resource will be at
the end of this
metzger's pretty directional microphone
there's min man im good im good
but
to at least train coming 10 been in
there they're watching there much in a
good
you guys good pppppp shop
who'd
mmm
so feel free to ask us questions we're
very open to
what
wallets told mechanical means moving
every this has nothing to do with it
doesn't drop in its four-step
correcting the sidebar
the sidebars force10 every time we try
and turn it together it tries to push it
just like when you try and turn the key
on a pin number lock it tries to move
but if there's anything blocking can
going in the right position
where'd where'd okay
so here's some examples a different
sidebars for different models and
they're all pretty much the same thing
is just
a barber that interfaces with the gate
on each dis
I'm and the only real reason for variety
is I'm one is sort of security so for
example you can see the difference
between the one on
the laptop and what bonham I'm so the
reason they change this and the reason
it has a hook
in future designs this is the applicant
Pasig on the top left and this is I
believe the appli-
just talk which is the later model are
the reason they did this was because
if you don't have that little hook you
can just drill a small hole in the face
block
and take the sidebar out and then
there's nothing preventing you from
Rokan
the the cylinder and %uh I'm walking the
walk
so adding subtle hook you have to draw
all the way through
and and that could be harder depending
on you know
up a steal steel desks to make a
hardened real and so on
I so here's an example of a
Ablett profile this is it with the
sidebar in the sauntered
this is the sidebar removed and all the
disks are misaligned
so you can see there some fall skate
summer and the true gates
but obviously the side was not gonna be
able to attract with all these mixed up
like that
and hears them all correctly aligned so
they they try that nice little pocket
for the sidebar to fall into
I'm
so 10 questions is okay well that's
really cool I get home works
I'm I get wires kids I
you can bump it and I can see how it
might be
different a pic on behalf what if I have
like a large
institution I wanna master kisses
several approaches I'm in the photo the
main thing they do is they just add
extra cuts
so this would be you know I don't know
the actual numbers but say this is a two
guy and a three-time
and so either those would work depending
on the rotation
on what they can also do which is
slightly worse just make a really long
day
and the reason that slightly worse is
because this little did break here will
actually prevent the side marker
tracking fully
if there's another them because it's
slightly higher so it
you know it is different but it's just
an example
I'm this cut out here if you're
wondering what that is and on the fourth
one as well
that little extra shape is so that
trying to move this with
manipulation tools will be more
difficult because you have less room to
grab onto
and there's actually a funny story I
I didn't bring the tool because it
shames me to look at it but that there's
a company that makes
a pic for the ABLOY classic
and it's it's the and bronze padlock
being passed around
I'm and these are desks from that and so
the reason it sucks is because they
didn't account for these desks which
very much every
block ever I'm and so the tools like one
millimeter half a millimeter too short
10 pick up these discs that have the
anti manipulation feature
which I find hilarious because it's one
of the basic fundamental features a lock
and you know for some reason they just
didn't account for that
we have some photos up picking tools and
whatnot once included later so you can
see what it looks like
I'm and then there there's other
variations so that was the basic and now
they
they add more to it so I was next idea
it was to add warning
to the keys so if you if you remember
the previous lot just had the half
circle
and so they give you a pretty good range
movement with
manipulation tools to try and pick the
lock and so they started adding profiles
in
a anything past the classic model and
they can do pretty extensive warning so
not only can they do you
morning that's the full-length the
Keyblade but they don't make also new
warning that's just in the back
or in the middle of the lock and the way
that they do that is that as you're
inserting the Kia passing through
each of these these cute key holes on
each day s
and somewhere further in the back the
keyhole will have
I reduced area so your key has to match
the whole
farther back in as you can see some
examples here like such as this third
one
has a partial aback Q-eight cuts aims
here
tim is here and so there's a lot of
variation even though it's such a simple
concept and here's some better pictures
so this is a falling for
here's just in the back and this on the
bottom has no warning
on this site at least
the next talk to blame a tan and really
like it it might sound funny that we
just talk about however an hour but
they're really the company that may be
lost popular
and remain that have the keep yeah an
end really the only reason other
companies make these is because I was so
successful
so it was kinda funny zappa lawyers you
know a hundred years ahead of everybody
right now everybody else is making disc
just blocks are kinda
catching up and all this although they
start to resemble the more modern
tabloid
yeah it's painful how many of them just
resemble that same exact 1907 model
without any invaded very very competent
iterations the tablet made over the
years
William but this is the dislike pro I I
believe the one main feature of this
was that this was the first tabloid that
you can turn both ways to unlock so you
can have a lock and unlock feature
the early ones don't do that because
that you know if you TriMet it the other
way
then that the gates on each disc or not
the right position CFD account for both
rotations
still very few are able to do that damn
and so here's an example and here's the
dis- they look pretty much the same with
a slightly different
on to talk about washers I've Nadia
so there's these are the desks and then
these are the washers and the reason
there's washers
is because you have this big stack up
discs and when you put your key and try
and turn you don't want
discs to be stuck together and then your
key cut picks up two discs and pushes it
too far too short so there's washers in
between every desk
in a disc lock to ensure that each key
cut only picks up
a single this so here's an example again
upon
discs aligned I this is actually one
locksets getting passed around
similar again what this added this the
Amway
exact I am they added this dimple
and so what they found was what you can
do an earlier models is
you can insert the key partially and
then try and turn all the way
and that's obviously not much want for
normal use and it also
slightly helps against manipulation
because you don't want them to be able
to test discs
without having whatever it is although
inserted as well as accommodating for
this
so it's not a big security features more
reusability feature but it does have
implications for later models
so here's an example though this those
discs and again
they're they're all very similar these
can also turn both ways to person
I am and the way that be key retention
mechanism works is that it's just these
little pieces
and wage rancher Nikki it tries to push
and and it
there's you know and he's partially
inserted there should be material there
which will not allow this to retract
which will in turn not allowing the
soldier turned
so Boozer those are going straight into
that dimple
allowing them to retract im I'm so
passive element if you've just remove
that section from a key that you made
it would still fall into place it is
just looking for a lack of material at
that point mickey
I and the other thing is that he's up
from the just talk on
that what he's also reversible see you
can insert it in either orientation was
obviously not the case
nap circle the not actually not no
longer the newest but they're they're
most well-known currently
is the Ablett protec and this is what's
used on vending machines
over in the hallway and yes
it's a very strange looking at why
particular event it is a project
I'm and these are pretty interesting how
they work
so they look very similar to all the
other stuff we looked at me say they
have two temples
I am and the me dis themself looks much
more intimidating but they're
essentially the same thing
I am out what really is interesting as
they also have this
this dis iraqi retaining mechanism
I these ball bearings in this i think is
it takes a little bit less space
it's probably cheaper nom same idea as
the exact
but what's very special is that they
have what's called the disc
locking systems and talk about or
home have a car like this is not like me
this is the part that you should talk
about them
when %uh up but leave a VM
you want to talk about it first go ahead
so the weather just walkin system works
is that and
in an ideal lock you're not allowed to
test discs individually when I sit asses
you're not allowed to
manipulated just individually to find
where the correct position it's
you guys out obviously know how any keys
work and when you pick up into lock
that's what you do is your testing each
can stack individually and setting them
individually and then you open a walk
you know how many view have ever used up
into virtual were you
you raise everything at once it's called
the key
so you've all used it but it's not the
same thing the
I'm so the way that the protect works
that has these serrations on the bottoms
up the desks
booty over here I as well as these to
return mars
and so what happens is you insert your
key and you turn in as you start turning
at a certain point
these bars will lock up into these
serrations on the bottom each desk
which will in turn keep them in place
King and so at that point then they can
touch the sidebar and see if they're in
the correct position
so it's its the idea that it makes it
considerably harder to manipulate
because now you have to move everything
together and that makes it much more
time consuming to try and pick the lock
is you know when we pick a locking okay
in a move this year filled with this
year feels consider you enact
you have to move everything at once the
correct position that's considerably
more difficult
separating tension from manipulation of
the time where is the holy grail of
making a mechanical lock
what we've been doing sense the eighteen
thirties
is called the tentative method replied
tension to the tumblers a plate direct
forced to those
and then we manipulate each one of them
individually to feel how they react
what ABLOY have succeeded in doing is
make sure that we cannot
applied tension to then test what we
feel from the cylinder
as the moment the you apply that force
you can no longer manipulate the
the individual tumblers and you can
manipulate individual time where as bad
as you manipulate them
you can feel nothing because you can
apply any forced to the sidebar
I'm so the big maybe hit this holy grail
moment
yeah and and even know that desk house
as a holy grail
its in the ideal it's it's the future is
what we want to have is this sort of
thing because it makes so many things
more difficult
I it's not perfect there's been problems
with it not
in the past few years for example
there's a specific model
love the padlock with Ablett protects
where the
desk in the front would have enough for
the whole the you could put a wire and
indirectly tension the actual sidebar
overcoming this I'm so there's no
problem with that
and you know it's not perfect but its so
far its exceptional
considering all the other just block dis
locks on the market
thus a bbm a
on them yeah
to yep
okay this is going to get there from
some my
protect marketing for injection I see
this is just the lock
in its assembly
ok been technically advanced
construction
possible return writer that locking bars
here actually made his locks
a lot easier to assemble their
predecessors to you
big not only dramatically advance the
security blocked me tomorrow I'm is
really mean to you
and don't forget there's some discs and
in and gave us earlier
news is that the model you
okay this next bit is actually kinda
cool because the yeah
interior the radiative the
have the key because I'm a key actually
manipulate to different sections
I'll the desks so the number one cuts my
number two cats
operate on this exterior service
who whereas 336
X has been a little bit further and
you're gonna see six in a second year
six actually just avoiding any
interaction whatsoever
down the lower right corner
because the sex is directly aligned to
decide where to begin
oh and lastly is just an animation those
walking by as you can see them in action
yep thank you
if you guys wanna see a I slightly
better representation on this
9 gonna delays amazing King dot com
on A's a friend of ours who has made
very very nice
three models at this you can see all the
different parts working together
and they're all about Iran's website so
the amazing teen
dot com book that's gone her
are there any questions about the
project employed Center in
if you're about to dive into attacks on
other stuff
yeah ok are except the a first-class his
class and some other just to relax where
been a pet project mind most don't last
year
I'm some
nothing too crazy about them we look at
the model the earlier
I'm the word that says housing is
because the safe love you for giving
back
on as I was saying earlier the angles
Kentucky correspond directly to the nth
degree
have the gate along the exterior of the
desk I am so you have your 0 just in
your profile desk
will be at opposite ends of the a
plug I both of which are going to put
pressure directly on the sidebar being
termed by the
uncut portion above the key this was the
video you watched earlier down this
putting in slightly different territory
okay I am 0 up but between them
besides Deepika God om so
most loss we talk about my column up
they're very specific to you
door hardware or padlocks I
there's one walk in particular that's
very interesting pastor yep
Jim yeah he called me a his
I'm 1 lakh that's very interesting is
the love our 2200
and it's made specifically for safes and
vaults I'm
we're passing on around now it's kinda
funny is that this key
is actually the small ski you can buy
and and
this is I believe the 8-inch and it goes
up to something ridiculous like two feet
and so the reason for that is good
obviously have the law inside the the
ball
and you put your janky through and then
eventually the typically gets the lock
and then you can actually turn and I'm
we had one
we have one of picking a village but the
giant he's having a removable Ted
so that when you the final minute
drinking
obviously you don't care I'm to fuck in
your pocket might be slightly
primitive I'm so what they have is it
tip that you can remove you keep the tip
in your pocket because thats
the important part and you just keep the
long Kieron
you know in the storage closet next to
the water or whatever
I'm funny story about that there was a a
a story that's very famous now that the
book flawless is written about this big
diamond heist and for and the cards were
super lazy and left the two for key
just in the closet with the tape
attached
same I don't know that it was this
particular lock but there there's
you know variations on a theme in that
was fun part sacred
so this is actually very similar it's
sorta a hybrid love the distillers we've
been talking about
and standard combination safe box and
again we have
standard commission say blocks in
lockpicking village like to learn more
about them
they're made explicitly to fit into that
footprint
7 so it slightly different we have all
our desks
and me this portion here and then we
have this big arm
that goes in Germany feels the same role
as a cyber there's also some additional
security mechanisms such as this
PC rosary locker but if the back is
knocked off then don't the Loch Shin
lockup here's a picture out the key and
it's essentially the same thing
we just have a slightly different like
cuts and that translates to
different positioning of the desks when
you rotate the key
here the dis- themselves as well as the
washers between each other
you see their little bit different they
also have this cut out here as well as
some polls
so there's two reasons for this: the
cut-out down at the bottom is for
reaching
the cut outs in the top part to
distribute weight evenly along the desk
so problem with traditional safe locks
is I'm in like pre-world War to date
find
like I if you're on a a big boat for the
navy
locks which is kinda open with and they
couldn't figure out why for a long time
what happened was just the National
vibration the ship
would slowly rotate all these discs in
the
the combination lock and it would
eventually hope Inc they'd eventually
all go to the right position which is
putting all the gates up yes the Middle
East material was facing up and if
you're locking bar was directly
vertically above it
yeah so now all modern I say Fox do this
to distribute weight evenly on which
disc the rekeying is very cool all
you're actually doing is slightly
polling that arm back
which allows the inner wheel to rotate
around the outer disk
changing the position at that gate
relative to how the key interacts with
them
this fall also uses false case of course
they go unlike that other distant as
these go around the entire
diameter there that whatever
the caller on the desk I'm and then
there's obviously a single
since that's how one single issue
conference come
said I'm and so beside that
there's a million shitty ribs now
pass around a city rebuff yeah and
they're mostly they're mostly asian maid
I'm again I said this because of what
they and their shelves
I gave each row one so
okay so there's a lot of these and
pretty much if they're not
these couple grams we talked about
they're probably really really bad
and so the reason I really bad out
without pictures eyes because typically
they don't use false case
they don't use any sorta key retention
a any of the features we talked about
except having the Esks
they probably don't use which makes them
very bad music very bad tolerances Welsh
like about him
I'm so I what's up next doing
the broken picture the Birkenstock so
there's a funny story we had friends in
Malaysia and ask our friends
and they this the Solex lock here
and and variants have it are just
everywhere
and they went to a locksmith task you
know hey how would you how would you
open one in these
because you know they're their lockers
in 10 it up and they wanna me local
locksmiths
I and a locksmith just kinda laughed and
pulled out an Allen wrench
and he says well you just put it in and
then he turned really hard
and they sent me some movies that that
had been open this way essentially they
just
force the sidebar into the brass and the
desks and make a gate
what and it looks really funny if you
look on my website there's there's some
photos at this this defense sidebar with
all these all matches:
forced into it I'm and that's apparently
considered legitimate
attacking in Asia's care and allen
wrench in open when everyone
higher security locks in fall into the
same problems yeah
it's considerably harder with some the
other stuff we've talked about but
because these obviously a slightly
better material slightly better
tolerance is something fishy in
particular
yes yet I'm so now let's talk about ways
that we can open these law word and has
a slight
process I don't do these a lot you don't
know or have permission to pick
not so mmm the first question is what do
you use
because you know you gonna walk ignored
you see the the strips a metal that uses
pics
to open the paint on the locks in wafer
locks and warlocks are all fairly
similar
but these watches very specific tools
and the reason for that is because
there's a DS in a lock that provides
tension
as well as the discs you want to move
into position to open it
so you need to be doing two things at
once and in
interlocking lockpicking we accomplish
this with a a separate tension tool
but because the way the key works for
can't really do that
and because retention against a
component we have to have this kind of
2011 school
it's very similar to lever locks which
are in order to block
thats are popular in certain parts to
europe and so essentially
what it is is just the pic is a
combination I have a tensioner
and something to manipulate each each
Jess
and Dave very quite a bit because the
the positioning of where you have to
tensions on some watching a detention
that the disc right at the front and
some locking in detention the desk all
the way in the back
and some somewhere in the middle yeah as
those in a real dick locks
yeah that and so here is
a photo of a pin a pic for the Avis bus
which she had if so
which we'll be picking a belief I'm
and scalable time or cost I
okay so again in his place as one might
have projects a lot last year
I yeah go figure lean good friend of
hers Finnish guy
I as they say in rally car racing if you
want to win higher if im
hmm good for is OK address the nation
version Medicine do and actually there's
even next version is angel sitting at
that table
I'm not gonna ask you has ran because
it's the only 1i know the country them
I home buy it is I I father is the
ugliest thing I've ever seen him but it
feels amazing like acne
okay so the really important thing about
he goes to is that it isn't just the two
in one picture doesn't just apply
tension
and then manipulated to the individual
tumblers
those markings also let you know
exactly at it let's you did hold block
as you're picking at
so by aligning be long straight line on
the barrel there to be individual marks
hashed around the
the section on the left the online that
they
the one who when they lie and you know
that you are on the in this case third
position you've turned this to what
would correspond to a number three cut
on the key and bats reveal its at all
you jot that down so by the end when you
open up a lot not only if you open the
lock
but you also have the code to reproduce
a key
an Avis doesn't include their keys
whatsoever see you can request a key cut
just by giving them the direct billing
email mail it to you I am
which I did with many local seems names
and I usually called
I I'm additional aim the
castration is running I around the man
don't let you know what disc you are
working on any given time
and I'll I think almost most importantly
in order to help you differentiate
between the fall skates and the true
gates
using the amount of movement that you
get
this piece year with the hash marks is
the part that's turning when you're
manipulating the wafers
watching the amount of movement that you
get when you are locked into in GATE
will tell you if you are in a false gate
because you will not be able to move
very far
already trying gate where you'll get a
significant amount of freedom and
movement inside and out lock
because the tolerance in the travelgate
is much more open and tolerant
the fall skates and it's one of the
easiest ways to tell if you're caught up
in a mosque a tertiary gate
which can be a real bastard otherwise
I'm so you can use those marks to
indicate yourself
you know where you were here and we're
working on
I'm additionally you can now if you're
if you're getting kind of not being able
to figure out what do you not know
whether you're in a fall skater a true
gay we know a lot about locks when we
approached them you know what
lot about individual brands like to be
bitten tumblers be the distillers
whatever the case may be
we know about amos's van the
true gates are mirrored by false gates
to and three positions away from
themselves
now that may not seem amazing yet but
when you take that information
across Egypt the discs that you're going
to be working on you can dramatically
reduce the total key space
as you're creating a church for yourself
that describes the code block as you're
picking
on these are all the small tools that we
can use to accurately and quickly open
this lock
and determine the key codes we can
produce a key in open it for
I'm Geico me to really nice too old for
this
really specific
okay and I really importantly when it
comes to being distant unlocks
I am what I wouldn't I was saying
earlier about be on
about though washers is incredibly
important
in the ABS plastic and several others as
one apply to every lock the work on
but that hit this tool is very very thin
and that's because when you overlay one
way for
her sorry one disc over another you can
just proceed
into the next desk they're blocking each
other now
however by their very nature the spacers
in purple there have to be completely
open
they have to be completely open
completely stationary so if we build the
Temple Bar pick to be is been
as the one as the washer as that spacer
were able to push just into the spacer
and then rotate freely in that space
aligning ourselves to the opening up the
next desk within push
into that mess next disc said it and so
on and so forth
I believe this will yen
so
the you think your portion is turning
just a friend 0 disc which will start
applying pressure to sidebar
now watch the been tipped as it moves
forward
yeah sets and desk
moves forward into the spacer turns
freely to align the next is
use forward sense that desk
terms in a spacer et cetera et cetera so
the spacers have to be there to allow
the discs not to interact with one
another will
during normal use the lock but that is
the feature that we use
to allow us to move through manipulate
aged the individual disks
in the lock and
there's it opens along
misspent I am Marion
okay I'll the
yea cuz story with a bus actually
started with a really cool attack for
the Avis plus
he eventually built this tool the eva's
pick and decoder jewel
as a response to Gerhard Mack back to
present the 80 S corporation
the reason he has been named the No and
then hit the reason the news in contact
with Paul Gerhardt to begin with was
because a mess
now it's a little breaks you can't quite
see what's going on I'm even larger
vendors yell at you action
okay so when he got discovered poland
are
year
weird
we corresponding he
now they were peacing out where they
were
facing toward BM toward the user you can
just program and look at it
but if you apply a tacky substance
push past the disc you wanted to
impression
turn 90 degrees in poll backward when
one this was overlaid over another 90
degrees you can still get just enough so
that number
the when you hold your tacky abusive
whatever out
you would see clearly the impression
that number and be able to decode the
lock just by
looking behind the desks it was awesome
yes
yeah I'm sowwy a co I with myself and
the guy named Michel Euler was able to
get in touch with the
it is corporation I'm you human meeh
Michel Euler was the
the main point of contact I met a lot of
work to make that happen I'm gerhardt
said good work very good that we will
get rid of the stamp desks
I'm so on their own factory line now you
get mixed cylinders were some dust will
be stamped some discs won't because they
probably had them
you know millions of the stamp this they
were just going to ask them I'm but you
can only earn
use this attack to fully open or Dakota
lock however
he also sent me a Kobe meets maritime
the nobody's clapping with you give it a
lot
all I'm dicks I
I'm using a coastal I but I'll should
you ever have a working this 10 good
actually use other 3d animation you can
see the live video Jim
yet 3d animations helped okay I am
so I so get hurt actually sent Diego a
lot without a key
up the new mix Ellender and said if you
can send me back
the bidding which is the combination of
cuts you can send me back to the
building I will send you the key is in
this will be your trophy
and so Geico invented this tool
and decoded the lock wrote the whole
thing down. send it back to me received
the keys
is one of my favorite stories from 2009
only I was
in okay so
I'm I'd ever has but the company name I
don't have them but this is the
have a classic pic I think stocks
because I'm they also make a neighbor's
plus tool which is
fairly similar to yeah it was too
although in the photo this is a back
tension lock
as you can see by the the tension is
very large that wouldn't be able to fit
between our desks
as missus you know it's weird %um you
can tension on the profile if you want
to but thats
yeah this is different yet I'm says the
opposite wave tension in from
from a coastal by the public very
similar they also have the scales for
for decoding and knowing which disc
you're working with this is
a talk about Fisher of 42 pics on my
favorite I am sOooo
reported to be herbal paste when okay
I'm sued to block a leg
just a lock for automobiles who've seen
very little innovation appears to be
very easy to open
I'm but with this does what I love about
this tool
is that each the heads are connected
directly to each of those
I little from a thingies
all words I don't take exams Minister
basically you can manipulate every disk
unlocker once
without having to move anything you push
on one of those you manipulate the desk
associated with that it runs through the
whole thing
and it's very cool to watch people use
because they kinda like slap it on one
side slab to the other side window
around a little bit and loving opens up
and it's amazing and they may have the
mckeon can reproduce and everything is
very cool tool I love it a lot
and I like most about it is that I think
that it could lead to brute forcing to
all the way up in most american bike
locks
im probably under three minutes lot more
about that Sep
that's you I I'm
so when we get locked talks I hope you
realize that
despite are international fame and
acclaim and all that that were mostly
just two assholes
on stage there and I'm was rapping for
that six
are I there are
ate lots government level 20 stopping
these locks and the reason for that is
because they are government level locks
a lotta governments use these locks for
very important stuff
arm and so obviously there's Associated
market
for making tools that will open them I
these are some very cryptic photos
I'm difference I opening and decoding
tools made by
a company called false its securities
from the UK they make
a lot of tools not just just tools but
I'm
a lot of different tools for a lot of
different amazing locks
I'm and you say seemed mostly they're
very similar
I'm mostly is also come out come with
what's called a makeup key
which will talk about in a in a moment I
believe bill clinton's
to stop okay that's why I'm and wanna
make a key is that
if you pick the lock that's great but
what if you want a pic again
and it took an hour and a half the first
time or you don't wanna said they're
picking again for an hour nap
so you use these tools to code lock and
then instead have
making a real key you might not have the
time to go back to do that
his keys are taking the time to water
them or whatever your so what you have
is a
a tool that has all the different key
cut possibilities and you
basically assemble a key your sample the
key to whatever beating you want
and then you can use that as a a a fakey
but it also solves like essentially you
know obviously keys are just pieces of
metal that move other pieces metal
in the in the right places test old open
in Iraq is the key we love making keys
the Lagarde that we passed around also
has a commercially made
tool made by Lotfi technology I may see
its very fancy but essentially the same
thing
where it's just the picking and as well
as a tensioner
I'm and they also have the scale to
decode
like if I was in Dec and had shipped
datagram
cutaway a month ago when I told him I
would he was gonna build tools
I'm batsman 2013 baby yeah
yeah cool okay so I'm last layer 1 this
actually this
this photo is from companies Angeles
there one
very brief story about last year when I
should've meyers was we staying with a
friend in a way for three days to catch
up an old friend from school
heey when I arrived said although I'm
not in the state sorry I totally forgot
I am a ride to the rental car company
they gave me a convertible for no extra
money because I was really late May
didn't have my car and they're very nice
and so will read after layer 1 at the
gate Instagram for any legs and it was
there is anything
I got Matt convertible and I drove the
circumference California
and it was the best road trip ever taken
away yeah
will sell yeah but the plan the whole
time some guy in the mirror of Patel
really cool guy was hanging out in some
higher see channel talking to people
about the fact that he started
Rep wrapped introducing he is virtually
complex at
box somebody in this random IRC channels
is all you need to tell scale a town
about that
so he sends me an email to use icy moon
waco fantastic he's in the Bay Area as
in LA at the time is like ok cool I'm
gonna drive up to your house
news lake that sorry and like day to
likely driven through the desert now
making the in the woods a mic I'm gonna
be in your house today
is like home just in reply to my email
some six hours from his house in wakey
bro I can really use an address common
to your house and values like Harry fine
okay
I'm you like ordered some wings you
watching Despicable Me which turns out
to be a really cute movie actually
recommend is really good
like orphans and interested in getting
these anyway I'm
set up a few I also sorry there's
nothing to live I had when I should
do drinking buddies my my local bar in
Boston happen to live with them
ten-year-old okay so we II should I say
hey this is fantastic i love you I love
you
wonderful non-locking herds that say hey
twenty-something blocks
every damn wanna be u solves for quick
set in slaying
we don't need you to solve for quick
said usually quintessential Ingersoll
were if you look at it he but I can say
treated could sentence leaky use
this would be a good call me every day
care community beautiful photographs
that he's on the Internet
and all I wanna do is mail their keys to
them and say oh you've got some beauty
anyway on I have a folder on my laptop
just called Crydom
where I is sushi people's key is with
their Google Maps lighthouse
on anyway I hung you know those being
recorded
hi no i'm just talking and talking
missus million
I'm my minutes and then
okay so I'm as showbiz house
and I say you know this isn't as we
don't need people to solve a quicksand
late really boring in the mid-late you
guys are doing amazing stuff
applied something cool I happen to have
a high love the it was is because again
was may have specialist aaron
eyes and you know do you think you can
make with these do you think you can
make a key for
this lock and we sat down I was your
measurements are trying to actually get
on the horn Geico in Finland million we
covered several more hours after it left
I'm and just being guess work in him
working in the open Skadden
something like that anyway he was taping
like crazy was making
amazing he seems on the commuters
incredible I'm it looks like actually
real physical world hacking women
okay I we know we're doing we didn't
have the specs we had no idea but just
being
guesswork after five hours back key
this key open the lock that I had left
it was 1am
I left after thinking that we were
failures and I got an email from the
have nearly the same you know I went
back to the lot
and I played around a little bit I put
the key back in I just tweaked it a
little bit and a
top trade open for me and so this is
very cool because he's no threat
rap printing keys to moderate security
locks compared
remarks you want to this country on but
the really crazy think I'm crazy
implication is the fact
the soft plastic allowed for a
miscarriage
key to function in the lock here's why
it's awesome
okay let's see that we wanted had locks
that have slightly open tolerances would
have cuts
so this is a 3.5 comic he it turns the
foreign desk
to hear interns are three desk to hear
but if we are using a malleable enough
material
because as you saw on the video has been
repeated several times that Sabres being
forced
into the gates the cyber wants to go
into the gains
it for material is a all malleable the
sidebar will force its way in
and will open up the lock on the half
capped and services
exponentially should leave how often do
you really can see exponential
exponentially reducing the key space
on the locks or attacking okay so take
bad idea
and now apply it to the four-team idea
where you're manipulating each disc once
okay so you have six cut cs6
typical cuts in a key for most Americans
to tear locks
fun you bring that down to three cuts
were using have cuts
Brite now you may cancel even brute
force your way through those three cuts
and thereby clocks out there that only
the i've seen by
likes that only have three in actual
coded desks
and the two on the energy 0 dis we
always know how to send a certified just
walk with only three discs that we need
to figure out
3 desks in three positions
81 somehow I got 281 a difference like
that but if you want
you can dial your way through any way
possible combinations in a
battling it probably as you please 1433
walk the fine
additionally I'm the real the real fears
that we're going to find ourselves
another pic pens actuation
were for using malleable enough
materials just bashing around facing our
way inside locks
is not to work on every bidding is not
going to work never really did cut
against a really shallow tech is your
valuable
services are gonna be able to make that
transition clear enough but any building
that is close enough to one another
you're gonna be able if I was opened in
10-15 seconds
just like the Big Ten's used him this is
a very exciting moment and I'll because
I insisted on being a total creeper
engine at a guys house
he did most work bomb you
ok adults I I one other
Monday as thats I like we talked about
replicating the skis
you getting a real key for if you know
the code can be challenging
ass that's my set of keys exist that's
why scholar on
this on if you have physical access to
it he is something we talked about
to use going to I you can actually just
cast one
you can take the key may come on with it
and cast it with whatever material you
wanna
so in this photo is an app where protect
he on the bottom
is a casting virginity key and so it's
obviously not
wanna percent perfect by it opens the
lock which the only important part
and as intimidating as the keys look for
these types of locks
be cast beautifully and the reason for
that is because they have such a solid
core
so there's no heavy undercutting and
there's no
real weak points you know if you think a
ver a traditional pin
tumbler key they can have very deep cuts
which makes it
conserving more fragile but all the disc
locks have a very sturdy keys
I'm which lends itself to making very
sturdy cast includes
ok well sorry we talk about this yep
I am and that is basically it where we
flogged and put a slightly older version
of the slideshow do much to
I see ap but that is it a scholar wanted
to show you some other tools
yeah just for those up americans are you
yet to skim through them out what was
going on
okay so I'm this is a guy who made his
own decoder for
because the game is on the counter for
Mabley classic locks
I'm almost certain I found these in the
men's section blog 21:01 bat comment
found my computer in all resources
I feel terrible that I can I give this
person the credit they argue
but they're part of the OP 11 community
that much of Europe a battle to prepare
is going ahead
is going to actually slide along the
exterior all
up in through the desks you'll see a
picture in a second or two
discover the gate good ongoing
okay so although it's kinda hard to see
you see where the
discs are separated from one another
bastard timber that after the best team
that actually erupting
up through separate in the nest and then
it rhymes along the outstanding grades
on the essay that is until it feels the
gate
and uses the guy has a gauge good
I'm speaking discover where that gate
has appeared
men's all yeah yeah and that's the marks
in best gauge
obvious to its Annie gauge gauge phone
here we go
okay so he didn't have like traditional
materials to make him a curfew from 6
just took a bunch
other key is for have the classic rock
since lace them into pieces
and you can't little live capitol a
openings into them so that he can stack
them
go ahead so here's a piece on the end
this
this piece is permanently attached to
his makeup key
because there's gonna be turning the
disc in the back to block and every
other one
gets stacked along and using using that
method
it is a completely functional key and so
he is not only the currency to make you
pee in a more permanent session later
but right now he can pop it open again
as often as he needs to do with his made
a key
yeah and this is just homers that is
some dude plan around his locks
wanna one other thing that I just
realized that include was that
is so we talked about walking we talked
about one thing I we talked about
various forms coding
one thing we haven't talked about his
impressions mom and so the
if for those you don't know you come to
the village a later on or tomorrow
to learn more about impressions a
technique where you start with the
blankie
and by forcibly trying to turn the
components
in this case obviously discs you leave
marks on a key
and then you file those down and then
as the component start to go in the
crack positions
the mark stop appearing and eventually
you have a working key
this work something tom was as works on
on dis parks pretty much
every kind the block that we have I'm
basically anything that tentative
methanol worked on will be impression
I'm and so
I our friend you go also was working on
impression the oblique classic
comment again it's kinda funny cuz the
law community
I'm as far as the public eye goes with
you we seem to keep focusing on the
older versions aboitiz the new ones
just hard it so it might not be true
other not public community
bites out of my eye I found it very
interesting so what he did was
he took a blankie and he cut a little
slices in between each Kiki cat so that
the material would deform easier
as a solid piece it's hard to harder to
make a mark
so you can always all slots I and then
they would
more usually to form and then he had to
figure out a way of making the angled
cuts I believe he ended up using
Sam LaHood yessir something like water
plus be the lasting solution
because he wanted perfect i cant
is often disguised I'm and I think was
that stuff is up online on his blog
unfortunately the name isn't finished so
I don't remember it
can I am unplug this just to come to
rely slide yes cool
I we'd have to skip a slide that is
sadly in this presentation shouldn't be
sorry secrets and we'll bring you to our
last labor resources he did concede that
uncovered ask whatever questions you
have
believe that the I oh here we have his
blog
awesome yeah that's why I want that
met do it Columbus right now
ok
K
are okay so I if you'd like to learn
more about
box or just box or a walking or any
other fun stuff we
usually in talks about I'll first and
foremost got a lockpicking village
I heard they have lost their arm you can
also visit
my website luck with the dot-com its
awesome and I never go
and every time like arm and check out
this awesome thing I learned about this
lock is like it's an article on lock
rekey
Dec every time happened earlier today
yep I you can also visit to La Salle
a lot of the protec- and other Apple
iPhone does I used were from Hong vay
tablet articles Witcher
excellence amazing I am and I believe
they're linked to the front page it'll
Diane Allen not search for Hyundai avoid
I'm
and some you write that down your right
down the 80 s blog because I don't know
what I mean I think the name actually
translates to disk lockpicking in
finish heavily I am but I'm not sure but
he has a lot of stuff
he post some stuff in English some stuff
II in Finnish I'm but I believe there's
a lot of information on his work with
with Avis tabloids is dis locks in
general is very very informative
I'm and and ask either has a number
love tutorials on how to pick this
particular a bus lock on YouTube as well
as his website
I'm then you can use this link to jump
to it its
yeah it is my entirely mainly personal
URL shortener pronounced lock God
on I like to party
yeah I'm do you guys have any questions
done anything yeah in
the was the casting question is what is
the casting material
armed you can buy it's a kid from a
company called the lunar light
I believe I'm and I believe it's just
silicon molding and
urethane casting a believes the post
they have some different stuff
I'm you could buy like a a party that
you just used to take a quick
impression I've keys I i mean i think
this stop
that they sell all in terms of box but
they're me for all sorts of
kasinga brushing Sat and then they sell
like a beginner
casting and moulding kid that is perfect
for on for a walk related stuff
on and again you know you have to
consider if what you wanna make
the cast though is a two-part if you
need a two-part maldita loca undercut
sir or whatever but
you know I leave that in your cable
plans but the company's call the lumen
light
that I buy most lhasa from I had a an
awesome time for the mine's a food
scientist
I'm read a book while back in we wanted
to collaborate
and see said why don't we impression
he's in food safe mouldings we can make
any keys
dominant the the only might stop is
offered safe
and I we don't like in case you need to
eat your mold in the key as you're
running away
p.m. I am yeah became very very close to
opening at three Ks appear sugar we just
had a little too much flashing on me a
on the side and by locking tuning
distilled sugar your questions
some even here yes
yeah I know if indeed this is like first
week with wonder
I yeah I've played around with textures
two-degree I need to spend real time
with it
yeah any other questions no
okay well thank you all for coming well
good
the him also player one
later on tonight we will have a very
special re:
non-traditional you net I he will be
here in the room
up I think we will hear about 9:30 a.m.
him around 10 only I'm
where one members whose I'm
anytime enjoy the game Martinez hermanos
area home the house and I'm
California has offered have fun
co-founders 9am me
of yes I will you be my
has gone up I could
pretty called awesome thanks very much
funds called for the promised
here okay when you got better leary's
really invest in a big game
his summer is coming in: DST village and
also %um
peddling and eventually cock RT
assumes I mean there's a limited number
racism how this would be a smart
but numbers just like his moms just like
us but numbers on
only an email know there's he said
too thick to called yet is everything
i win