alright
welcome everyone to wear wanna know he
has a public man doctor
lunchtime food comas but some my name is
not John or a lot you know me as our
plate
I know I decide to be old news my real
name here you know this presentation
said kinda scandalous she thing to do so
hot today we're going to talk about
access control systems and by access
controls
I mean physical security controls that
like these of ID cards were relevant
issue in dorm rooms
possibly a poor choice in the merits
part Donald
so I what we're gonna do you desire to
go through this
a we had the surname we do this exercise
ever appeared about
18 months we're on the 23 be shop
Packers Basit surah
while y'all are gonna come down there
tomorrow maybe for a party but we got
tired of dealing with metal keys
in which are looking into you're
researching
an electronic access system and realize
that they were
have a lot of things wrong with that
from hackers purple perspective
sell for starters you know why are we
doing this so
security now access control systems the
mostly closed-door us
and very proprietary I we really had a
hard time getting much useful
information for me the vendors
very little information about the inner
workings is published
a some unpublished little bit about
their actual protocols
there are so many men as my Tripoli
standards in a alarm manufacturers
standard for
a woman in false alarms the few things
Nancy stuff
but that's really about at noon some
even other chip number: scrubbed off and
you know they're
ones with the fuse is blown you can't
really think album
on when you can access control system we
basically got tired of dealing with he
is and how it doesn't look like I'm
learnin
you not be over vote he's a big enough
for somebody so
you we decide we won like drug after its
controls we want something that we own
the
you we could prove how secure in secure
was and
we would be able to modify it so in
order to
to really get there I think it helps to
start by defining what we mean by
security in this case
so this is the classic I personally or
or Ross Anderson security engineering
triangle mean security defined in terms
thereof
assets in our case we're not talking
necessarily tronic assets
data but we're talking about people were
talking about our facility our stuff
maybe our information inside there maybe
our server room we'll talk about threats
those assets threat actors
actual people who intentionally want to
get you harm their stuff
I vandalism fee and all those sorts of
things
and recycle countermeasures you things
we can wrap around those assets to
provide some sorta
mitigation the stress and important
differentiation
I safety and security are related
but they're not the same thing security
is typically a counter measures you
install to mitigate intentionally
and harmful threats were safety
that more incomes is things like a Eunos
human error and and natural disasters
but they effect each other and sometimes
and doing things like getting safety
systems increased security
and vice versa one other thing to
consider
on all these things have trade-offs I
worked we talk cost convenience
and we have things like creation new
vulnerabilities well from where thought
maybe from doing your web security and
network security
but when you're talking about things
like a making sure you can
X your building in case of a fire it
kinda acquires new dimension
so we have to you know we have to look
at that
things that are open the doors it's an
emergency you know shouldn't be able to
be
easily subverted to open it for a Unit
actor
so this man kinda interesting
a been Ross Anderson security
engineering to great book
he has a a good section about physical
security and he really
kinda formless it there's a come before
cited square for seven-figure
other four things you can basically do
with physical security
devices and and countermeasures you
can't stop anyone from getting into your
stuff for your facility that's just not
going to happen
before things you can do that or deter
them you can delay your attacker
you can detect an attack and after is
already in progress sir
been attempted and you can mount some
sort of response to it
and that response could be anything from
communicating with your chapter is an
intercom
setting off a siren calling the police
page in the guard desk anything like
that
so fundamentally these are all there
to enforce a security policy
in and that security policy is something
that you have to decide for yourself
whether it's your partner hackerspace
your corporate high-rise
are you know what are the priorities in
water you really trying to get out at us
just like an enterprise IT security
policy is necessary before we start by
firewalls
are you need to figure out what
procedures you want to be enforced by
your
your access controls and %uh some pretty
easy for little ones
may come up over and over security and
see if you the personnel
any kinda have security measure you put
and if it does not protect the people
who actually work in the building
you give them something they're not
going to follow their to prop the door
opener there are gonna care
because you know it it's apparent that
their safety isn't
first and foremost mine prevention if
after damage your assets
that's a big one and auditing about
access and security events
that's our stuff falls back into
deterrence as well as response it lets
you mount
response after the fact maybe prosecute
someone
maybe find a vulnerability that you
would have some logs
and you know we talk about threats
something that's kind of interesting a
there is a model developed at San
some security text books it came from an
army officer they don't cite the name
but the basic up with four model
attackers
and this is something I haven't seen a I
mean obviously
we have models actors in the room but
you know they all fit same old black
shirts
and she looking this is the more formal
what they did is a cup this for
arbitrary guys and
I see guys but so that's what they did
we have Derek Charlie Bruno and
abdurahman
and these guys sorta represents a
spectrum love
have different threats your physical
threats to
facility or some assets and %uh the
first one
this is probably the biggest one we had
in mind with our
you know hackerspace security system der
at Derek is a nineteen year old adage
he's looking for low risk opportunity to
steal something he can sell for his next
fix
rather fitting because we're also one
walkway from methadone clinic him
akers be israel's day is noise most
prime
hey so next one we have Charlie
charlie is a forty-year-old inadequate
with seven convictions for burglary
he spent seventeen at last 25 years in
prison
is like a classic career con although
not very intelligent
he's coming experienced he's picked up a
lot of war
during his balls inside he steals in
small shops in suburban houses
taking what he can to solve a local
fences and this is a guy who
new made you a smashing grab or maybe
someone who has access is more
sophisticated things and tools
maybe he can use lock picking a lock
bumping
you know aid some other things that we
might see in a residential or commercial
burglary
you repeated over and over and we have
this one at this is kind of interesting
a bruno a bruno is a gentleman criminal
his business is mostly stealing our as a
cover
he runs a small art gallery he has a
Ford university degree in art history
and one conviction for robbery eighteen
years ago after two years in jail
she changes name and move to a different
part of the country his own occasional
black bag jobs for intelligence agencies
who knows past
he like to get into cyber crime but most
he's done so far stripping $200k worth a
memory chips from the university's PCs
in the mid nineties when there's mary
Fallin
and then our last one this is something
you know the kinda
you lose some threat that's always in
the news but never seem to see
a berman in a German had to sell
overdoes Norton's most military training
they have infantry weapons explosives
with PhD grade technicals were paraded
by disrupt your country
a German himself came out to third in a
class a 280 at the Monterey County that
country was not promoted because he's
from the wrong ethnic group
he thinks himself as a good manner that
bad man in his mission is this your
plutonium
so clearly we have different kinds and
Fred actors
we don't really worry about the last one
that's the military's problem
I really it's sophisticated controls
wrapped around
lots of mass you know things like
concrete barriers that stop trucks in
explosives and you know the tapas greens
with guns you come and kill those people
and the first one a in a second one
those are the problems love
criminologist and sociologists and so
forth so we really
you're kinda worried about Sabrina he
sort of it's in the air
at and the upper and love off-the-shelf
criminals
that's what we design things like data
centers and higher security
installations around
but we probably not design every
business round that so
I'm I traveled a lot of businesses and
you know we talked enterprise security
and things like that
and come its monster visions your
typical
business promoter is protected by our
standard 5 to 7 p.m. and mortise lock
from
chalet Gill sergeant Center at tempered
glass windows
an alarm system civil kinda stuff we see
a larger sites have electronic burner
access controls often
and their many cases tied into building
systems like
each back in lighting and and maybe an
on-site security does the monitors all
and the physical or account lots they
have
are usually higher grade like passed in
you medico and some others Browns
and we'll see for key control and in the
village master key a little bit
were safely this kind of thing it
represents good basic protection from
burglary meet insurance requirements
and Derek and Charlie threat models are
probably covered fairly well here
data centers a high-value I've
merchandise is handling facilities those
are geared more towards the bruno
attacker
where you have things like defense in
depth in a layered security not just a
promoter
a more robust detection response maybe
with the
no armed security from a security
company that
you has very rigid protocols for you're
not taking no for
an answer for a call back in things like
that
us in a typical features these me look
into these we
I took apart alarm systems and access
controls and media
you looked at existing installations
where people gives permission
and we simply have a modules control
under four doors
a little black boxes mall here and there
we have a centralized usually Windows
platform computer
up stories the access token information
and keep logs
they typically push up all sees the
usually you can access the the doors and
so forth without that system being on
you know its stores locally case
something goes down
I usually have some sort of access
device
a you're talking you know where the
rubber meets the road
a electrical signal between five and 40
balls
is what's going to open your door it's
typically electromechanical Tobias
in by things like electric mortise lock
which we have one here all show you
door magnets will have some pictures
those say you've probably seen those lot
of places there
big heavy-duty electromagnet the whole
the door shut
electric strikes your get byes into a
pawn shop or something like that on your
horrible sound that season easy operated
electric strike
all the stuff is me we're doing is
basically
in being in closing some kinda relay
and energizing a a device that wasn't
mad about 1910
gotta love it up the access and so can
readers
utterly systems use things like plant in
pads in the used a
in physical keys the trying to switch
and you now we're looking at more things
like a cards say could be mag stripe
contact cards smart cards
a contactless RFID cards that sort of
thing
I am 4100 those are cheap open standards
are pretty cards are used in
less expensive systems I the hit systems
are basically a
a slightly extended protocol with a few
more bits
released on the lower end my fair and
Allah
some others Browns are able to do things
like read and write
data and you know do a little bit more
stuff
up some important things almost every
facility
has some sort device that gives anyone a
free exit
there might be a press to exit in the
appropriate local language
me and maybe it's lit up the often have
motion detectors actually usually both
I in fact is that the Bush tax it
physically applies under its power
so that if all that electrons is not
working you're still able to get out
are sometimes they have a button that
you push it and
a leg timer goes off for you know counts
down thirty seconds and lets you out to
make it
in communion so that you don't use that
as a your main means opinion now
they may have integration with some
centralized console application where
security cameras can follow up the
events you know
the camera comes up immediately in
loading dock if
motion detector goes off saying that
there's a truck there or someone pushed
a button
to the intercom a most facilities have
the capability of doing a remote
lock/unlock
it could be something dumb like go to my
PC imagine a Windows PC
that's kinda scary but that does control
physical access
sometimes you have things like
a I could guard console that you know
they can verify that you're at the right
door
with the camera and then let you into
the loading dock without having to know
leavin
you go track the guy down and open the
door
and then integration the alarms anything
from I just
you know triggering a a contact you no
fall
it. level integration isolate
I went ahead and made a little diagram
kinda shows how those work
and a bigger facility its ok we have the
access servers
in some sort of database Sun in the
server room
and that's they're basically just
answering your sequel requested some
kinda a friend and software
I could be clustered or not but simply
management PC
and smaller systems and Andrew PC is
also the database in the policy pusher
we have things like a each back alarm
systems
a lot of the the newer ones have
Ethernet built and the ability to
communicate with these things
sometimes there are integration saw for
companies that title together at the PC
application I N we look at the lower
left hand corner others all panels
sometimes it comes bare boards the
cheaper ones do
lot times their little sheet metal box
the village church in screws the wall in
a closet somewhere
flew in the locks they have a UPS
because you don't want to get denied
access your space if the powers out
basically have a a simple
microcontroller could be a
no doubt man all or a pic or you know
the summer travel Cebu
and some kinda network capability the
older ones are RS 422
basie fancy serial port that goes over
long ranges
a newer ones are altering to be
internet-based
and those doors they have a few almonds
I'm
they have things like access reader you
could be a pimp out a scramble pad wear
pants a fancy pen how that's harder to
shoulder surf
I you know some type of talking reader
something you have
could be a biometric which is basically
taking your fingerprint and
something that it thinks is your
fingerprint and give you some numbers
that compares into database
possibly local copy about cash there and
then you know
requests to further can go back the
actual server
and then they have up with the car
wrecks answer its request to exit
basically a a button worsens or both to
let you out
regardless 'em you know what state the
doors and so forth
on the meantime we have a sensor need
side to see if someone's actually there
and sometimes out those decisions are
have a locally and sometimes they go
back the panel
been any case is almost always
mechanical writer some sort of way of
getting people
a accessed through the door least in the
exit direction
up the systems that do you block your
physical power after accident don't have
an easy mechanical wave opening
I usually have to have something like a
a and integration with the alarm system
fire controls things like that so that
they can
get a signal to release all the exterior
doors that say in the event of an
emergency
I'm something that you need for safety
codes enough PA has ended the call
depart 101
that governs out but also something that
he supported by an attacker
I can or near systems they're gonna have
your network
preferably a good secure one but if it's
installed by a
in electrical lender may just be you
know some some done that your hubs and
and that sort of thing so
we can talk with a truck model love it
when we talk about some attackers
I you know what ur advantage in this
match is électronique locks
up the first and foremost one the
business problem they release all
it's easy to revoke the keys the keys
are cheap
the are disposable usually and you can
given
you know give them and you can
electronically revoke them
without any real financial penalty
obviously argued metal keys
but you can have very flexible security
policies
I you can make a your your front door
any Dorner facility ernie space
accessible
only in the context of a certain time a
day or week a month
your physical location in the facility
security level
that he was assigned to you security
policy
you can have public and private areas
with different
policies wrapped around them are you can
have princess alarm sensors everywhere
but you can
shoes to not alarm but only log if it's
a a a lobby during business hours
you can maybe that have to make a
decision just like you to analyze logs
and you
intrusion detection a system for for IT
security
you kids determine if someone's there
and a certain hours that they are
supposed to be there are you can you
know
raised alarm do things like that up
public spaces often become private
spaces you know on the weekends are
after-hours that sort of thing one nice
thing
it'd Cana can be a good hedge against
carelessness
so we can do things like up you know
allow over the the front door is always
be locked I even if
Munim people are there and so forth
because you can make it very convenient
to swipe in and out and unlock it
whereas in the system he might have had
before the cat with mechanical locks in
in middle keys those are going to be. do
something that always gets left propped
open
you know left unlocked and you can also
use a alarms and things discourage that
and the blasting it's really important
that you don't have with mechanical
devices
are you can audit you can know none is
really who released
know what token was presented or what
alleged user
access what and where and what path they
took through it if you come through the
logs
and finally I love your stuff you
anything from lighting to
alarms to air conditioners they can all
be tied into this
you should add and dry contacts readers
have an on/off every layer
you know sensor you can do things like
turn your commission on or
trim that lights on have someone come
into the facility so that
go there securities actually improved by
having the other path lead in
you know through the parking lot or
through the space and you're also saving
energy in
im making things more convenient
in so let's talk about the disadvantages
what Ron o'clock sir
you know we're kind of here too to think
about you know security measures in
terms of
you know how can I break this rate for
all hackers
so our fight he right that's been the
you know big in the news and take
everywhere
I love you people have seen the audience
probable the pox mark
it's like a Swiss Army knife that can
decode even emulate these cards
you know what what are these cards the
right if we you know
fun when we look at it it's a little
radio antenna with a chip on it
and when you put up to reader you can be
interrogated
without having to necessarily touch it
and it can spit back an idea or can make
sense or transaction where data stored
and and rewritten or challenge response
is down or something like that
and they're designed to be basically
used like a credit card it
contact distances and it's assumed also
that
you know they are can be readily cloned
well turns out we know that's not
exactly case right
physical key can be cloned you know if
you get
physical access to it you're able to get
a key machine her access to a locksmith
I can even be done with a high res photo
but I was proven a paper in 2008 but
these are for any cards
you know they have some problems a.m.
you know up the technology is really
only meant to be read from a few
centimeters away
but depending on the system you can
build larger quayle's im
apartment but more power and you can the
do something like herein are for the
card from
a foot away or even five feet away
possibly
fever walk to shopping center that has
the on a shoplifting tax
that big plastic a stanchion in the
middle of the aisle
is a box for big coils
there may be 15 centimeters across the
might be 30 a.m.
and they will pick up and those low
frequency tags that are on your goods
and alarm if you bring one out all that
sort of thing can be adapted
to read are pretty cards and
unauthorized way
so we look to see if it can be red you
should just assume we can be cloned
%uh if we you accept the premise that
these are just chips
a they can be emulated with software
and we have some very fast
microprocessors and microcontrollers
that
can basically bit bang out meet up a
signal you want
here another disadvantage they require
electricity
and required electricity I you know we
we have some interesting problems the
command
for one thing Park me interrupted or can
be manipulated
like we can do things such as that
analyze the power
going to a device and maybe deduce
whether it's sending zeros and ones are
processing something here
possibly get to spit out its key we
might be able to you
shorted out and interrupt its power and
deny you so that reader and outdoor
we might be able to if this is poorly
designed get the door open
by a plan to high-voltage or a dry
normal low to make a brownout
different things like that unlike a
physical lock where
basically those time where is in and
metal bits moving around
are governed by physics this is
something that
if you can control the power going to it
you may be able to do an intentional
things that
and finally they might feel comfortable
way
your door lock is probably is going to
break but man lies reviews too hard
but you don't exactly know an electronic
device with a few thousand lines of code
you didn't write
is going to do when you possibly push it
to fail
and another thing if you want to try out
let's see every medical cuter is
it might take you a year sitting there a
tryout he's even if the tolerance is
little sloppy
but in a poorly designed system you
might be able to hook up a device for
widget
that can basically let you trial doesn't
you know seconds or minutes now strength
is also in that because its offer based
stuff
you can you have countermeasures
not shut up but it certainly Real Talk
that's possible
and finally you are depending on
security over everything in there from
the physical layer
through the network in order to get that
signal safely to
wherever the its authorized to you're
talking to me authorized
and back and out authorization signal
same way
can we get about so with all that in
mind
we had good set about designing at
and access system that we could use to
research these issues
and we could use for space so we can see
criteria
first without the relevance the Derek
and Charlie attackers made sense
and really our main goal was keeping the
junkies rally at a shop
a the original door control
was age like double with five kids
so we figure if we can beat that sizes
security target
for at least better of me started
a resistance to more service gets actor
was plus start
so we need to control two doors on
myspace is serving a smaller places have
a couple
%uh spaces may be a you know from back
door we thought that was a good starting
point
I'll only gets you something with lots
of doors and so forth
we're probably looking at some things
can be multi-tiered have possessed
remodels anyway
we like the idea of being compatible
with off-the-shelf readers
so we've seen a few are ready projects
the the adults labor space in
Germany believe budget some very
interesting
homemade readers and support a crypto
code in
you know hamlet on the quayles made some
really need devices
about the problem is though we thought
that would be a little too hard to
replicate
we prefer to get something with low-cost
off-the-shelf so that other people
kidney to pick us up and pack on it
and the other thing that kept coming up
other people we got some really fancy
interesting which it like a
her scramble pat or some type of retinal
scanner other biometric that was for
plus they got
and discarded from a renovation of some
high-security facility
and if you're how to make it work that's
great but if someone else were to try
and pick that up
maybe five thousand dollars each new you
know just for that
the system with no manual so before but
was it really is relevant
we presume he get either use on eBay as
commodity
or new firm you know pick your not
offender
we like it you have been able to run
independent of a PC or other
you know server anything with a real OS
has more ways to attack it
it has no ins lines of code you didn't
write and
if we divide it into what we call hard
and soft ass
hard task in things like opening closing
the doors
and soft ass mean things like connecting
to the internet which require a lot more
sophistication
a we'd rather the soft ass be allowed to
fail
and not affect the heart just like
leaving the front door open
kinda basic embedded systems a floss be
them
the dumb device is the master and the
smart devices
a peripheral and of course we want to do
logging auditing we know that was to be
able whether it could be internal or the
flash card or
pc-based turns out we can do both
I we want to have alarmed since our
capability you'll be able to detect
occupancies we know someone's there I
have
you may be four your alarm zones for
your alarm in occupancy detection and
request access
things like that and we also likely to
be able to integrate with
existing alarm system you know the
contacts 04 so we have some redundancy
in defense and up
so we can offer methodology apparent
we we had decided just her to start the
Arduino
microcontroller let me know kinda lost
common denominator
ground floor for embedded systems
and you appear to have enough I O ports
and
and processing power and storage do this
we want to have
a time and date security policies
possible to implement mobile security
levels
need to be very physically robust
battery backup
protection against reversed polarity and
high voltage is not all those sorts
nasty things that happen in the wild
as posting a breadboard we ought to be
low-cost
so open standards tokens leaders
adaptable to new stuff
something we can build for maybe a
hundred dollars or less a
commercial systems there are few you
know China knockoffs but
Muslim you're looking at a thousand
three thousand dollars per door to
electrify
so you know that's going out other the
budget have you're starving hacker
and watching that was our people I only
commodity components you can get through
digi-key Roman 14 in a row served god
forbid Radio Shack
itself in check yeah
so but no we we took all those those
constraints in mind
and missed our design something on we
put on a breadboard we started testing
some you know free code we found for
interfacing some other readers and and
that stuff
we had to do love debugging other
something called the wagon protocol
which is a we enter why can't I don't
know a sack frank and actually did a a
talk here in 2007 about how to intercept
boughton
replay that the tokens and so forth
other between not
manufacture date issues we figured out
how you know how that works in
we got some good together we built a 1.0
version
the circuit board we put some discomfort
in but protection and
UPS power supply on their we found
a smart ID cards that her used very a
successfully industry for you know
things like cattle tracking and
goods and you know things like that they
are available and keychain and
swipe card format called in 4100 summary
writeable summary domain
as we got some our hands most readers in
no tokens were less than a dollar so
affordable to play with him come up and
so forth and we estimate alt is a
plywood
called a version 1.0 so this is it
a there's a power supply that's not very
efficient on top with the UPS
big honkin battery there's a couple
pieces the door hardware there is a
adore magma bottom others are bored in
the middle
or just up from it and there's a couple
reader is a a million reader
which is bases I'm to go on a a busy the
the door jam edged extra front door and
then there's a a and
interior reared as a pin pat's we can
you know
use two factor authentication entered
arsons in command that sort of thing
and so we sorted treated this like it
was the front door several times or come
in here with swype in an hour
intestine try to break it find it all
its flaws
and we had use that with a homemade PCB
twins much money on
and Connor find it we found out some
things like that we know
u-turn at Marshall had takes a lot of
power can burn up the regulator on board
some of them
so I made a nice 1 I'm switching power
supply and put out on board
we decide to make it carry no 5 answer
continuous current for some other
heavy-duty
I security door hardware you can get put
in more protection the inputs made it
harder to reset brown Outen
holes for two things and we set of air
PECVD created
and I we went ahead and built-in
capability work in store 200 local users
I 255 security levels
I had a console you control the Ethernet
and a rather
via serial but can also be serial over
Ethernet
and win a great alarm access functions
and tested this not I'm
and of course insult us your jeans and
this is the result
so this is our first to create a
commercially produced
it said kinda bickford we know shields
about six certainly knows
worth and it's got some big relay is in
a switching power supply in the middle
that's not input protection with a surge
protectors and movies
it's got big screw terminals I it's got
some
Darlington transistor arrays love the
stuff we copied from a
1980s alarm panels we figure that
you know that's something that's been
use and abuse for twenty years
so there probably were doing something
right then we put a real time clock
important
something are doing doesn't have and we
up to isolate everything
so there's no direct connection to that
micro so it's a world is
you know hopefully sandwich the way
where
you know bad people can get to it is
easily
and you know we had we just without and
we are now at our
I guess we call our 2.11 and we have a
basic is a hardware that supports to
readers
supports a navy compatible or do we know
so we test the freedom you know on this
evening a lot of those
often are driven very responsive under
the reeds
Putin it does have
up no modern capability we're using just
cereal to a small NXP see you know we
look into using the are due to return it
has a lot of issues
single-threaded it doesn't respond very
well planned
what's your host hangs up in you need
the full 30 seconds time out
and during that time your front door is
open not so good
so the hard and soft ask if you're that
shit is be offloaded to you all were
you know when it's BC you're an embedded
devices some kind
and you know we had come to fine-tune
the a remote administration
happen any a consul password and here
three strikes you're out for an hour and
things like that
and we publish the evil cat files and
there'd be no coding
package show up and then we decided to
your own dog food
we have put in production and we
security
Joe a commercial door hardware which is
pretty expensive
turns out a few have a storefront type
building anywhere in the US
probably quit within Adams right
mortgage about
aluminum a mortise lock and they're the
only game in town
and they want three hundred dollars not
for their stuff
presidential towers are some some sheets
for that
you can act as a Walsh leg I keep adding
stuff to
just be a dumb solo it for the door
but we programmed it up and install it
in an old alarming closure regarded
and put a big honkin battery you know
the big talk about her from a foreigner
and will UPS circuit and ice five and
power supply that's
camel's back and we start putting in
hearing from me up all the stuff
and it's it's worked out pretty well we
found
a about a dozen major bugs the first
week we had it
in production clean one would let you
inner in the archery compound after a
successful swipe
even if you or not the right person
stuff like that you don't really find so
you live with it
and with all the size hardware put a
little bit higher security locked
a than that said much leg
you know 510 wasn't there before and
you know we have a a couple options are
some or doors this is
at another site this is a a magnet lock
with with two magnets in EverQuest X
reader
%uh this is what we installed another
door it says your door magnets that
but a twelve hundred-pound Paul magnet
only takes about two hundred million
skip shut
and then there is a posh exit reader you
see this thing over and over
of you do see rosa while by the way you
can pull that cover of you do things
like change the pattern that it's that
to picks up from making more permissive
you can set this is Jimmy to be higher
so that
things like we've issued a paper through
the door cracked let you in
thing to think about yeah so in doing
all this
mister find smaller villages really were
here at offers for the wiring
wiring is absolutely vulnerable in any
resistance a few them do you have full
challenge response
capability in encryption between the
you know they all the devices and and
the the brainer that inhibition occasion
panel
early access server the most window
so you can do things like man in the
middle that we can protocol you can have
a device that stores in replays
successful swipes
you can short out the low voltage wiring
it controls the soloists
I in some cases if it's not designed
well you might be able to blow a fuse
and have a feels us now to feel secure
bus feel safe door open
that's device right there the door
magnet when you enter a power to it it
opens no matter what
so if you can attack the wiring you can
you blow a fuse or you can cut a wire
somewhere
your N West found something else
interesting
I somebody's devices have a
a little one or two wires that are
grounded
to indicate a green LED is successful
Swire for little chirp the year you got
in
well some others are tied into the same
relays that control the doors
and if you can back she died you can
supply run 12 volts or you can
shorted to the power to the reader they
might actually that door hardware let
you in
so something interesting and we'll see
if you doubt that the alarm sensors
a if they'd most powerful alarm systems
a pretty good they have a usually a
resistor in there somewhere
you for it either short out the wires
were cut from both those will trigger an
alarm
but some cheaper system that uses
digital pens are you might be able to
short out the
alarm wiring and have improperly read
that the doors close was really open
that sort of thing and wheels appeared
out another nasty attack that's probably
feel on any these
is a plan hai bol said something like a
stunning underplaying and 110
probably will just blow up a you know
component and just disable that reader
but you don't know if they don't have
good surge protection like fast UPS
transient suppression diodes in movies
and stuff
affecting get on the power bus into the
microcontroller
you might build a cost something in
particular happen like that you know
a register to get so high that opens the
door it's not predictable
but it could happen now the talking
themselves
the readers we discovered that
I your course anything that you contact
physically
its moral to vandalism to being you know
inscription wall and manipulated
I you can obviously you know vandalized
or cut wire isn't
juvenile service course you can clone
RFID and other tokens amy biehl's do
replay attacks
and skimmers are are valid threat that's
something that actually could be totally
passive you could have a lil overlay
that's powered by the feel the power
Zafar Freddie cards from the president
and you can use that to you maybe powers
Cameron
and store this first organs and
community can use the reader's own feel
we also discovered that was his readers
have no collision protection
so mean if you have two or more tokens
physically within range
it can't read either them or me read the
first one
and then going to like a a lock state
where won't accept the second read
so you could glue down to also
conceivably and
to access a reader interesting things
like that
also you know we've live this before but
very skew systems have any kinda
protocol security
its clock and air weekend or serial data
you're really not anything that cannot
be trivially spoof replayed intercepted
you know passively or actively this is
is that you have this are usually is for
things like a
transit tokens security having a secure
payment systems
even one like the mobile speed past that
have encrypted in
have had papers published where their
alleged been broken so
I don't thing it relies on a master key
something like that should really be
you know concert secure awesome is
access tokens
they all come in different formats you
know they have key fobs they have
implantable ship's side of the lower
left hand corner
I wallet cards are typically the larger
that device
the longer arrangement or something out
so the small devices have actually some
additional security
in that the don't work very well long
distances harder to
to power them up and get them to read up
that the prosecutor government has this
is actually very similar to these
knock-off
are fighting ships are used for
industrial applications
but it has a and Sep 26 bits maybe
thirty four bits
in the key but they're very similar I'm
interceptions technique so the physical
hardware
we also found there's some things you
can do like the store magnets
typically they're stronger than door
frames themselves but
a turns out that putting a piece a paper
piece of tape
over thats a magnet produces a string to
radically
certain inverse square thing it's
actually possible to put like some heavy
clear packing tape for contact paper
over at the looks
your clear same texture as the the
magnet
and it reduces the door strength their
holdings think about 90 percent
so it looks like it's close we can kick
it over kinda interesting
there are some horse tracks maybe I'm
not very well made
non-ferrous materials in those are you
know possible to attack physically
destroyed
but some others may have the possibility
via
you put in a strong magnetic hard drive
backed up to it and subverted
I might also be possible that will
shielded
to induce a current in its magnetic
on solo it strong up to open
and then this is the classic one the US
me refuses to go into a data center
somewhere in the los turkey or whatever
but the exit readers are almost always
installed in securely
I there are some guidelines like keeping
that the push tax a button six feet away
from the
the door from the me a jam and things
like that they're never followed
most places BB they can be is a narrow
hallway whatever
but motion detectors me for a number of
ways into opening you can throw
something through the door
you can inflate a miler balloon under
the door cracked I heat up with a
hairdryer
I you can you access the buttons with a
special tool been outta some heavy wire
all those are possibilities and almost
always
security policies are implement such a
way
as you watch for and false alarms and
not sized
you know worry about absolute prevention
love someone getting through the exit
sensor
and so I thought it might be interesting
to bring some hardware
relax play show-and-tell and I and maybe
demo the system
good okay good okay
alright so what we have here
we have our person to allow domestic
partners in the access control
and this guy has a couple times
fashion here's a forest right
and we can do things like taken of race
car
you can swipe at he's gonna be we can
make unauthorized
car you can swipe arms
following trashed opens tells open
so there is a commercial Henry we can
you up slowly
good with singles tennis team
we have flown in here and we can clone
these shits this is a
fifty dollar a day fine you clearly have
oil wire
a couple passers me three ships on
workers believe you're hyper
and 32 card here with his mom was not
well
you put up to quell we redid
anonymity is rewriting attack this whole
issue 2
put that on there his longer than of
clone
okay you know doesn't listen
as one that uses knowledge you wish
because you don't listen
we can read up
takes just seconds included
an hour
though attackers really know
reasons can be in fall know it's an
apostate insurer
you know a day traders the you know like
to hang out or whatever
so you know if you can be really if we
read
II week-long you know we should offer is
not something
news wiring he's long way this is very
small
issue 22 gauge wires in like that is our
most popular current
it doesn't take a lot to yep you heard a
lot about protecting oneself
many up
we don't have all the alarm hopelessly
hooked up this but you can easily put
for
different zone alarm %uh sensors and and
you can experiment more with just
register as a resistor
ready for another way to do it we got
your own hands for you that were
for additional you know sensors to so
to live up to up
oilmen do not we also the log in this
so this is our server logging it's
really simple
you know it's just the 57 kill a bit a
serial over USB and we can turn into a
Linux Lagos that tales logs we have some
scripts the written up that are
published I'll let you do things like
pipe that's your learning system
our email or SMS you when someone comes
or goes
an alarm happens that really basic but
it's a gives you the capability irv
directly internet margarine ur
your cell phone or modem where you have
and we have those four relays
only to which are used for the door so
what others can easily go into our alarm
system as well
trigger the alarm monitoring company so
just the the last thing a.m. again we
have
are physical exploits we have the
capability have
you know initially met you in the wiring
doing horrible things with the data in
transit
I you intercepting every plane it we can
do and I'll service in a number of ways
these things up the contactless readers
in some ways
are better because we can put all her
reading behind the glass sir
insider perimeter but we have you know
obviously new
problems with me know what intercepted
out people's pockets lunch boxes
I so if you were
are curious about you know the the
engineering behind out and you know how
you can
projects how much range you can get how
much power way I actually was able to
find one
engineering textbook an RFID that's on
here knots or third entry down those are
pretty hamburgers translate from German
school but weird but I guess you are
interesting info
and I highly recommend this book
security engineering by Ross Anderson
this really has everything from physical
security to building secure embedded
systems
to secure networking pretty neat stuff
and last book in the bottom
I there's an interesting projects in
there that
you can implement as just a hobby hacker
type our fight each weighs
this guy I'm all graphs tra actually
implanted in the AM 1400 ship
in his hand and wired up everything from
his car to his house to open from that
so there soon as the Libyan it pretty
interesting and that we have a few good
links to their protocols for some stuff
for published
up the man the middle attack but I
mentioned
that sack franken Def Con 15 player 1
we have %uh some these documents from
the CSEA and that's basically Nancy
working group
and since other stuff about smart card
the your water bill is
and some other interesting stuff about
just
president general on last thing
you can download the code everything
evil files
the design there'd be no source code Sol
right there
up the Google could link and doesn't
have any questions
yes sir he s lockheed access
so that's not a problem at the best you
can do you
is logged out the door opened a certain
time some
the door hardware house a specific
sensor inside
that is tripped in the event of a key
physically turn it in
but that's not so that's something that
felt the mechanicals
a you know the really the only reliable
thing is determine the state at the door
for the state a motion detector outside
a bit we call that a request to exit if
it's on the inside
and that generally is logged in most
alarm systems where they
are are actually correlating is someone
tributes answer
with us a request to exit but the let
you out regardless of whether you trip
sensor
a anything else yessir
integrating with the you know the alarm
system have you found any lets in
residential commercial any
legal issues with that our insurance
issues are things with integrating with
here something I got his or her dream
Kate will be integrated with easily
to other yeah he's wage make that happen
is to basically asked for a dry contact
loop
most of the arm vendors are okay with
giving you an on/off contact that you
know trying out on our break in that
connection
will tripped the alarm people use out
for things like I let see
monitoring their freezer if you have a
grocery store you know you want the
alarm to go off if the freezer quit
working so they don't lose
ten thousand dollars worth of seafood on
you can get it for you like the
a sensor that you to text her basement
is flooded so generally they're friendly
without
I don't think they care so much what's
on the other end as long as it doesn't
put hibels a gender scripture system
that that's why I found common thing
yeah it's pretty columns
unusual request smaller cities may not
have enough zones are
you know the system that you for free I
wouldn't count on it but any
quality systems fall by pro should be
have able to do that
most them have a panic button control
alaska point you could you have to
stupidest kinda controlling time for
that
and I'm one more question yeah you talk
about you know how can somebody like
this
the keep them losses and I got its on
how how successful is up in second
you know had mister been repeated a few
times and
also the one working currently is the
Herschel électronique scramble powered
those are available all over EVA and
they're cheap because the only operate
with guess what
first electronic space station's so we
have to find a rebuilt
up their circuit board that's really the
only time you can have success
I think according to those that
particular I had a
up a one-time programmable Intel 8051
CPU that with all the fee to the fuse is
blown
you count them thrown out a bit and it's
dead silent until you hook up to this
device that
arsons 300 heard supple seeing square
wave along with some
white forces here and there for about
five seconds and will bring light comes
on telling you it's working
so not secure protocol but an obscure
protocol
and something like a logic analyzer like
the analogic project knows baseball
can help you to cut that that one also a
little bit unfortunate city code because
it's a 24 volt plus 12 months full
signal
so we'll see it's a build some notables
divider
or some protection so the to block logic
analyzer
but that one we think is doable a some
the other ones that have a real
you know security challenge response for
a call those may not be
so so easy but I think they're all
within range happily
the 11 put a you hit system in there and
their apart near the garage now I mean
Stoli tools is within range
INR toll
units LV or the min
good question yeah we actually up
ordered about a dozen boards
and we have a spares & kits available so
we've been signed those that the 23 be
shop I am will be there
you know Sunday a we will have some
so it's all over 100 bucks shipped and
will the
also was really busting on who attended
player on
anybody else and more I got it but no
that's the
working all at once the readers to you
know I love you
were altman's to use of the word on or
do we know
no I readers other readers are available
all over
YouTube a from water China vendors Hong
Kong Taiwan
they're gonna sell for between $20 and
$50 dollars each
there's a actually nice lawn I was in
the version 1.0
that one will will get you both the PIN
pad
and an indoor reader and it's like 16
bucks for shipping its
mister cheap
yes we do so there there's a wiki at the
Google Code link
and that will show you at every to rate
their it's like 16 bucks if you see it
is still a good for but the that the
wiki has a lot of stuff on wiring and
debugging and building a thing
and you we didn't find some other you
know
information was interesting I'll all the
import is your readers work fine in our
your voice heard deploying these couple
others pay some
but sum up the expensive commercial
brands like kid
didn't work reliably we discovered the
Sen faster pulses and
might be a little bit under spec for
what you know we had a
we thought we'd have that the standard
is in
is always published so if you doubt
there's more grounds you can put a
couple bounces on there and pretty much
any reader works is fine
really anything that speaks why can't 26
if you just you
you may search for white and or W 26
you'll find loads have compatible
readers intercoms
yes he demonstrated his %uh across one
from result that is not approx mark this
is a must dahmer
single-purpose devices and what this
does
is it lets you simply I
clone EM 4140 10 to tags:
they're one of the the cheaper
industrial tax that's available
me open standards in and cheap
but there's no reason that can be done
what other phone Peace Research
and affinities Hockaday I know 12 people
read
on if you saw the duct tape RFID tag but
the
someone sick a just small aid
pin at Mill CPU think it's the
AVR 85 and the attach a couple
capacitors a live wire
and made the busy and are ready to give
you later
we actually but when his last minute a
up the shop last night and will confront
or a bit every
clone another tag under so that one
will do both should cards and the in
1402 they're very similar this is all
the different coding
so there's no reason I think that can be
extended to other types the cards
that opinion as well exactly yeah can as
well as not about it it's a second
factor
authentication with Laura integration
alarm system it has nothing to do with
it is another option
I about sort of thing %uh surveillance
your cameras the lot of sight
all those you know represent defense in
depth
yes word your system every into
I know some a security camera DVR stuff
alarm
porcelain as well so could be integrated
into something like that so that
it would do the motion to table as well
so if it has
like a port for motion detector that
would be a dry eye contact and that
would be easy to generate
if it doesn't on it there might be other
residents for software
think which is about as I'm for anything
else its
and %uh decide should be available
online
up you know probably right after the
conference
with that
no reason you can't
I'm just lazy