ok I think we have a yes/no okay we're
good we're good
cool alright cool
can everyone hear me in the back their
thumbs up
yes don't worry about microphones I like
to walk around so i could use the
microphone but this seems like a small
enough room and I'm loud enough that I
don't necessarily need to so so welcome
to kick starting at are you good good
good
ok welcome to kick-start an application
can reprogram my name is Timothy D block
and this is not picking up why is that
because now I have problems
oh I general area
alright cool so why this talk well I so
I don't have a strong programmer
background and when i started building
an application program i didn't have a
strong abstract program back programming
background so I kind of had to start
from from scratch from from literally
zero to get a program off the ground and
I i want to put the talk together to
kind of help people who are in similar
situations are looking for ideas how to
get involved in development lifecycle a
little bit more
we're hearing you know a lot of people
think we've got to get the software
development lifecycle for a lot of this
stuff just look at IOT so this talk is
meant to do that to address that kind of
help people what I do have experience in
this building other programs i've built
into the response programs patch
management and those were very
successful in both my athletic programs
have been successful as well what I'm
finding is that other people already
doing this stuff and so this talk has
given them a little bit of confidence
and for people in the consulting realm
are you know they're looking to engage
with the development team a little bit
more this is I've talked to a couple
people who have found benefit this talk
so that's why this talk is so the
roadmap is understanding environment
security assessment inventory and then
there's two
others their feedback review and
improvements
this is a 30-minute talk I it is
originally a 50-minute talk I just
embellish a little bit but I don't have
time to really go into that stuff and
the title is kick-starting so this is
just getting a program off the ground so
my first journey started with we need a
nap site progress and we am i mentioning
this here because one of the first
things that you need a building an app
set program is leadership and management
support if you don't have that you're
probably dead in the water you can be
very difficult to get anything started
at anything done i have had to lean on
management sometimes to make sure that
the development life did that when new
applications coming through that they're
going through security so my first
journey started in columbia south
carolina the advantage I have is that
it's a known environment I've been there
for a year and a half the disadvantage
of had is that I was wearing multiple
hats
this is also a waterfall so it is from
it from a security perspective
waterfalls several months and has very
defined steps or the process for getting
security in there is a little bit easier
than some of the other methodologies
so what I did with my first but I
started my research and I used
everyone's favorite IT to google and I
literally put in how to build an app
select program in there again I'm
starting from zero don't know anything
don't want to go
Google's google my guiding my guidance
my guiding point but as you'll notice
they're the first three results are from
something called OS which is the open
web application security project this is
a massive nonprofit open-source
organization just focused on application
security you're going to get a lot of
value out of this it has knowledge base
that has frameworks and it also has
tools and this is where i started with
was a dynamic analyzer called that that
attack proxy and what we did was we we
set this up as new applications and new
features were going out we were doing
dynamic analysis on the new stuff and
this dynamic analyst is where you can
proxy all your traffic from from your
computer to the application and interact
with it and
and it's life-form I some longer talk to
do go into a little more the methodology
but what it was great about these tools
it's very well documented you can go to
youtube you can go you know read just
the documentation itself and really get
started with it
the alternative is that proxy is burp
suite that is the preferred application
or the preferred dynamic analyzer for
application security professionals it is
three hundred dollars a year for the pro
version there is a free version
the only difference between free and and
the paid version is that it's throttled
a little bit so that's best dynamic and
I just another tool is static analyzer
static analyzers allow you to scan code
in the transform you get some really
good code coverage the downside to that
there's a lot of false positives
you've got to opt two options that you
got your open source which typically
focuses on one language
you've also got some commercial options
and there's there's more than just
what's up on the board there for each
one of those there's a ton ton of static
analyzer is out there the commercial
versions will cover you cover multiple
languages so if you can afford it
commercial isn't a bad way to go again a
lot has a page that kind of talks about
what senokot static analyzers are and
some of the options that can be utilized
so vulnerability tracking and this is
where Iran it's my first problem I had
we had set up application any new
application that features going out to
be scan and what ended up happening is
is you know you you have the criticals
and heís address the medium and load
depending on factors you could
potentially it slide and have addressed
later on is still the release go through
we would get timeline for that stuff we
would come back a month after those
timelines we didn't think about it we're
tracking us by email or spreadsheet or
what have you and we realized that it
wasn't addressed so that was kind of the
we need something to really start
tracking all the findings were having
internal options are great if you can
use what the development team is using
that that's that's probably where you
should be because ultimately security
findings are bugs so they should be
addressed
and prioritized in the same way if
you're looking for some security tools
this is where i started with dradis I
didn't have much success with this it
wasn't very well-documented and we just
had problems getting it installed on a
server that we wanted to run it from
this is in a lot of like Metasploit
framework and samurai web testing
framework i have heard other people have
success with this and they really love
the tulle we moved onto the right fix
and thread fix had a free community
version that has since confirmed by a
couple people has stopped
they've stopped supporting the free
version so this is pretty much turned
into like a paid product i haven't used
it since they gon pay but it is
essentially allowed us to import the xml
files that were generated by the by the
that tool to kind of start tracking and
checking and and getting some metrics on
security vulnerabilities more recently i
have found OS defect dojo and I had Greg
Anderson on my podcast exploring
information security to talk about the
tool and it sounds like a fantastic tool
it will accept a reports vulnerable
reports from multiple tools and then
what it does is it will be duped those
down to one security finding if there's
multiple across tools that sounds like
fantastic in itself it's got integration
with JIRA so if you want to automate
ticket creation you can do that it's
also really easy to install like one
line of code and it's got some metrics
if you go to Los page there you can
click on the link and kind of go through
a demo version of it so you can kind of
poke around in there see other people
have been in there poking her out
so let's talk about handling
vulnerabilities and this is probably one
of the most important things so you're
you're pounding away finding all the
vulnerabilities you're generating report
what are you supposed to do next
well make sure you confirm your findings
do not take the developers false
positives if you take them false
positive is going to be very difficult
to work with them in the future you can
have nine security findings and you have
one false positive its they're going to
lose trust in you so you really want to
work with the developers to find a
solution and if you're like me where I
had you know I had a detriment and
application security and programming i
had to ask them a lot of questions
they're very much open to questions just
don't take them a report and walk away
for doing that it's going to be very
difficult to get things taken care of if
nothing else demonstrate the
vulnerability I found several times
where i just showed them the cross-site
scripting of the sequel injection they
thought it was cool then they ran off
the got to figure out what they needed
to do to get it fixed and if you if you
both don't know how to fix it you need
to hop on google and try to start
researching how to help them to fix it a
lot of times though in my experience the
developers already know how to fix it
that they they know what's wrong with it
or you know the best-case scenario
that's old code we can just delete it so
you know it you work with them to really
address these vulnerabilities so
training and something interesting
happen when i started showing them the
power of the dynamic analyzer they
wanted to start learning the tool they
wanted to start using using its app it's
free so they can just go download it and
start playing with it which is what I
had them do I started having one-on-one
and group training with them to show
them how to use the tools that they're
going to go use that tool before they
bring it to the security team that's
just going to make everything smoother
and and make the process move along a
lot better and something interesting
happened we had reports of a security
incident where a phishing email is being
generated by our application so someone
would register and then never get a
fishing about the end of registration
that doesn't sound good so we got
together made a plan of action the
development team was going to go create
a user see if phishing emails actually
generated I was going to go refer to
route research the phishing email and
see if you know we were seeing anywhere
else and then after that I was going to
go back to the registration process with
the dynamic analyzer and test and test
it
you know why we're looking at it we
might as well go ahead and take a look
to see if there are like a cross-site
scripting vulnerability or something
else that might need to be addressed so
we we go away
everyone gets back together developers
say no phishing email and here's a
purport this was kind of my response
this is what we want we want the
developers using this tool and this is
kind of where I had an epiphany and that
we want to improve the security mindset
of the development team there's this
concept of you know setting up an
application security assessment and then
working left of the process you want to
get into design and code review QA you
know just where ever you can get well
the furthest left of the development
lifecycle is the mindset of the
developer if they're already thinking
about security then you know there
hopefully coding it in a secure way you
know you can also think of this as a
defense-in-depth strategy where you have
certain checks throughout the process if
they're kind of getting it at the first
jet at the first check which is their
mind you know that's going to save
everyone a lot of time and money so that
was kind of my first journey my next
journey was a little bit different i
moved to Nashville Tennessee to accept
the role as I was sitting with the dev
team to build an application security
program from that was going to be my
soul so that's my advantage my
disadvantages I have to kind of have to
learn the environment so my first step
is to understand the environment and
building an application security program
the first journey has allowed to skip
backside been there for a year and a
half
it usually takes me three months to
start getting adjusted of an environment
six months I start to feel comfortable
year 22
I feel really confident and and knowing
where to go and one thing about these is
that they're not really steps for more
guidelines phases they can kind of all
merge you will still be doing understand
the environment while you move on i had
my first security finding and first
process established within the first two
months of being there so these aren't
really like you do this and then this
message they can all kind of merge
together so my first step is to build a
relationship and I build a relationship
because security can be very
intimidating and so I want to humanize
and get to know the developers
understand you know get to know them as
a person and kind of humanized security
as well and i did a date they respond a
lot better and mrs. so that you can have
the harder conversations because
security
we're just going to be bringing a lot of
bad news most of the time so having a
good relationship with the developers is
really really important if you can sit
with the development came great if not
you're going to kind of figure out how
you can do that because I've seen it
where you know our security team the
personnel there have a different
interaction developers and I have 101
sitting with and sometimes it can be a
little frustration there in the
communication lines if you're looking
for an area to start business analyst
scrum masters are typically the the area
pios product owners are typically the
good area to start because they have
their their their hands and a lot of the
different areas of the villain life
cycle which is where security is going
to be at as well
this picture is from Johnny Christmases
talk and be said national 2015 about how
to meet people at conferences a lot of
the same concept can be applied to
interacting with the development team
they tend to like a lot of the same
things that we do the other things I 10
meetings i try to get into daily weekly
you know whatever meeting i can and this
is solely for the purpose of observing
and watching I don't say a lot i want to
understand the goals the challenges the
frustrations and you know their security
acumen because security is so much in
the news now the developers are becoming
more aware of what's going on
I mean how can I not with with the
constant breeze
cheers and constant vulnerability of of
you know vulnerabilities being found in
software so I go in there and i have
seen where developers will start going
down the wrong path and security
perspective I haven't said anything and
it's it's it's amazing to see them self
correct they know you're in the room if
they do they know your role they know
you're in the room they will start
taking security from from a you know
they'll start being more aware of that
and you know that's great that's what we
want we want to be speaking we don't
want to be speaking up as much because
again we're bringing a lot of negativity
to their process and a lot more work so
if they can fix a lot of that stuff
themselves that's great and sometimes I
think developers spit out like a whole
thing on security and then right at the
end go but i'm not a security person you
know that we want to start building
their confidence and security because a
lot of them aren't doing it pretty
pretty well and if you have to speak up
dude in the form of a question what's
the problem we're trying to solve what
you know why are we doing it this way
try to understand it versus saying no we
can't do it this way I mean there might
be certain scenarios where that is but
try to do in the form of a question kind
of start guiding them that way they
respond a lot better that kind of stuff
the other thing is to inventory
everything i'm sure many of you can look
up here and see that there's been some
kind of security incident i think even
with them the last both the beginning of
this year or there's even like that with
the Amazon Web Services stuff two weeks
ago or you know within a relatively
short period of time
this is an online computer and network
asset management within with nit we need
to have an understanding of what's
needed
what's in the environment and this is
only logos from about a fifth of of
another graphic that someone had of all
the technologies that could be used in
the development lifecycle this this is
just scratching the surface on this
stuff and you need to have an
understanding of what's in your
environment so that is a big
vulnerability can be hit you can go
check to see if there's an issue
apache struts just came out last week
the issue with that they're so having a
good understanding of what's in there is
also there also be looking to you to
understand how to do best track
security with a lot of stuff again you
might have to go to Google or go to some
other resources to figure out how to
secure these applications and this will
take a lot of time I am I am still doing
this i started this six months ago and i
am still doing this so now we get to the
fun stuff we establish assessment and
processes and we want to start with all
new applications and features and the
reason why we start with all new
applications that features is because we
start the old stuff you're just going to
be costing costly beat playing catch-up
you're going to be looking at stuff and
addressing things that they are working
on right now so you want to kind of you
want to start at what what what they're
working on right now and when you have
an opportunity to go back to stuff
already production you do that you can
also this is also an opportune time to
do automation within the development
lifecycle so there's a project called a
las pipeline which deals with continuous
integration and continuous development
the next step is also you want to
implement processes that make sense a
lot of my processes have been
implemented because the developers have
asked the question how do we handle this
how we're supposed to be doing this one
of the first ones i setup was a
third-party assessment of vendors again
you know you need to have an
understanding what's being environment
who you're interacting with and some of
the time before i got there you know
development make a decision on something
and then go ahead with that and
securities going Lolo you didn't tell us
anything about it
Security's got a vet a lot of this stuff
is go you gotta go through compliance
you got to get all the legal document
sign for you know third-party stuff
especially if you're dealing with
sensitive information so they were the
process where I gave them a checklist
and you know to run through of what
would might bring them or get the vendor
you know disqualified by security
assessment the other one and I set these
up and within the first two months the
other one is security tickets so how do
we have a security finding how do we
address that within the development
lifecycle and so we set up away a
process for me
me to create a bug ticket and then send
it off to the right people for them to
be addressed and prioritize and I'm i'm
also there's a resource with that stuff
so training and I'm doing it again
because I feel like training is very
important time focusing a lot of
building relationships getting to
understand the developers because you
can create a lot of havoc otherwise and
so kind of advanced my training ideas
from from the first my first journey and
I brought bacon that is a picture of a
hundred and forty four pieces of bacon
for training for security training for
the development team that is 270 two
packs of a 272 pack of precooked bacon
and it was twenty bucks of my own money
i can get the cup she's healthy with
that they gave me some swag which we'll
talk about in a minute but i did that
and drop it on the table and the look on
the developer space when they walked
into security training was amazing is
that is that make it it is you know it's
so we want to make bacon here we want to
make bacon
we want to make training interesting we
want it you know we don't to death by
powerpoint slide we don't want to death
by put bullet points so a lot of this is
my presentation here i use a lot of the
same things i'm doing security training
we like to have fun watching youtube
videos
this allowed me to segue into
piggybacking and then we watched YouTube
videos on a guy trying to get through a
man trap with a server which was
hilarious because it took like five
minutes to do it so look for for look
for opportunity to make make make
training interesting doesn't have to be
you know they get a lot of the security
awareness which is a lot of compliance
stuff already so you kind of want to be
more interactive with them during the
training and I brought swag highlight
security wins again and security we're
gonna bring a lot of bad news and a lot
of things they're doing wrong so we want
to highlight security wins bigger small
look for opportunities are they using
the tool and the development life cycle
that has a security aspect of it I would
highlight them so yeah you're that's
awesome
or did someone find something code or
you know I had a developer who uses a
unique e that's awesome i want him to
use a 32 character password for his is
our password i think that's great and we
want to highlight these wins because
we're going to have a heart-to-heart
conversations with them things about you
know internal issues boring processes
lessons learned from our potential food
from a security incident you're gonna
have to have a lot of hard conversations
with these people they respond a lot
better if you're a positive influence
among them and that you're highlighting
a lot of the good things that they're
doing so they don't feel so bad when you
only focus on the bad it's gonna be
really hard to get them to respond the
other thing i like to put in there is
highlight current trends who's heard of
MongoDB and the issue there got a couple
hands and laughing I had a room full
developers who not it was blank blank
faces so we had a great conversation
around when ransomware miss
configuration I pulled up showed and
showed them the power of showed and they
were they were absolutely amazed by that
you know you can also talk about
strategies where yes it had mongodb not
met but now they're moving on to
elasticsearch and couchdb you know you
could cloud pets is recently hit the
news is something i actually had a
privacy talk one-on-one with one of the
developers about privacy so he was
taking privacy really seriously and so
we had a good conversation around that
kind of stuff so this is you know this
is also meant to highlight why
Security's important why we're doing
what we're doing so that's pretty much
it achievement unlocked you stood up an
absolute program now this is you know so
what's next and this is again we're
gonna have a future talk hopefully
feedback and review you want to
understand you want to make sure that
what you're doing is effective and
actually fit there's an issue or they
don't like something you should probably
adjust and look for opportunity to make
improvements as well you can also
improve your skills if you're like me
and didn't have a strong programming
background get on these sites there are
tons of free programming resources out
there there's one not up here that
haven't had had to check the ad yet
which is code fight cotto fight is a
puzzle based the meeting certain
criteria to be challenged for coding i
love codecademy
because they've got a terminal that I
have to code properly before I move on
to the next step and you kind of build
out an application over nine or ten
steps
pluralsight is another favorite of mine
it does it's got a lot of video training
on there it's anything anywhere from an
hour to nine hours so there's a lot of
great stuff on there and it's also a
great resource if you have to if you
have to research some follow people
within the application security field or
can get training do that
sans 542 with a course that really made
application security click for me I
really started getting feel feel more
confident with an application security
sorry hon is one of my favorite bloggers
you eat your blog he does a even
recently started doing a video blog
he also does a lot of floral flight
courses the web application hacker's
handbook is considered the Bible
application security if you're looking
to get better burp suite that's a good
one to go through with it as well
because it has burp suite screenshots in
there there are a ton of people this
this is only just a small sample of all
the people application security to
follow so final thought here I've kind
of focused on people skills a little bit
in this and and not as much technical
but that's what i found is that a lot of
developers already know how to do a lot
of that stuff
what they don't want you to come in and
do is tell them the code sucks and as I
was going through the interview process
that was a criteria they don't want to
bring in someone that was going to say
the code suck it was a you know it's a
relationship it's it's I'm considered my
role of the design of the liaison so i
have to have a lot of people person
skills and soft skills to interact with
them and very tactful when I'm when I'm
bringing security issues to the
forefront so my final point is you know
i I've stuck by the model of putting the
developers in a position position to
succeed and if i do that kind of helps
me with getting them to take security
more seriously
so that's pretty much it i run a podcast
exploring from a security is my contact
information if you need to contact me or
have questions my my place of employment
is looking for a senior Spock admin if
anyone's block and wants to move the
nashville and we're also hiring for june
pentester all so that's pretty much it
good ol time