ok we get this to go fullscreen talking
is poultry weird enterprises that size
and watching that is it good
can everybody tolerate this on this side
now is hope yet okay so can everyone
hear me okay alright awesome so i am joe
gray this is a cent for the win
basically i'm going to talk to you about
how to do better penetration testing
through your social engineering attacks
using open source intelligence so about
me I'm an enterprise security consultant
sword and shield I was in the Navy I
navigated submarines I didn't touch IT /
say a few certifications i write blogs
for anyone who's willing to listen as a
as noted in the introduction I do have a
blog and podcast at advanced persistent
security dotnet we'll talk about that a
little bit later before i moved to
tennessee from Georgia I taught
introduction to cybersecurity
information security and introduction to
computing in colleges so with this
presentation I want to talk to you about
what is open source intelligence ascent
social engineering in terms of what kind
of social engineering you can perform
such as pretexting the various types of
issuing as you can see up there wailing
baiting dumpster-diving we're not going
to get too much into those I just want
you to be aware of those as possible
vectors will do some applied social
engineering up then we'll talk about
enabling better social engineering
through open source intelligence
mitigation and we have time we'll talk
about training your team's up for
prevention so to talk about social
engineering
what is it in essence of human hacking
it is trying to get the target to either
give you information or performing an
action they wouldn't do so otherwise so
that typically bypasses your normal
security controls because in reality you
can spend half a million five million
five billion dollars on technology but
if you can get a user to click something
and actually let that perform an action
or change the firewall rule for you you
negated it so here's a few books i
recommend you definitely Christopher had
nagging social engineering
dr. Robert shielding is that influence
the psychology of persuasion and then we
can talk social engineering without
mentioning kevin Mitnick so the art of
deception is another good one
with that being said we have the
pioneers of the art I've mentioned three
of them already in the top left you have
kevin Mitnick on the top right you have
dr. qld the bottom right you have
Christopher had maggie and then you have
freaked Abigail on the bottom left of
catch me if you can
same here is who leonardo dicaprio
depicted so that was basically the story
of his life and since since he's done
his time he's now a consultant for the
FBI he designed secure check and does
other things on the on the white hat
side now so moving on into examples of
social engineering we always hear about
fishing but then there's also
spearfishing which that's what this
primarily going to address because
you're going to hone in on a specific
target wailing which is social
engineering the big fish your sea level
your senior management fishing which is
voice phishing mission which is text
message fishing baiting that could be
dropping USBs that's a bonus data or
layoffs or something like that to get
someone to get curious and plug it in
and then let it do your deed for you
free texting which is basically when you
take on a persona which is exactly why
we see Daniel day-lewis here he's a
method actor with him when he's
portraying a character he stays in
character
I didn't know until i was actually
researching for this talk about when he
filled the crucible he did not day 43
months because that was the norm in that
time frame while it's a good movie I'm
glad I didn't have to be around him
because if he ever went to DEFCON he
learned that the three two one rule
right so with that being said dumpster
diving and tailgating are also options
so with social engineering and how this
wraps into applied psychology we have
the six principles of persuasion and
this is the the main idea of dr. killed
in his book which has more since then
but this book in particular it is one of
the most typically cited books into
social engineering applied psychology
field so reciprocity commitment or
consistency social proof likability
authority urgency scarcity think of the
last time you bought a used car
the used car salesman might say
something like someone was just here to
look at this car they went to the bank
to try to get financing you must act now
principle number six or man imagine the
chips you would pick up in this car
social proof or the other day I was at
lunch and I overheard two gentlemen
having a business lunch and one of them
said oh let me pick up this this tab for
you and the the gentleman who I assume
was the one that was the prospective
buyer refused so the sales guy was like
I will come on I'll get the next one I
would really like you to come to this
event so basically he was trying to
perform reciprocity but he was getting
shut down so ultimately that there's
just various various ways that you could
look at this
that would actually appeal to the human
psyche right so as I stated before it's
all about influencing people there's a
difference between influence and
manipulation and I'll get into that a
little bit later but ultimately you're
trying to get users to give you some
sort of data
ideally you want sensitive data you want
the keys to the kingdom you want if
you're pretexting as a user of a bank
you want that person on the other end of
the phone to give you that person's bank
account number you want them to reset
their username and your password to
whatever you tell them to
so that you can login which that's
actually part of performing an action
but you know you you want to find out
something that's not online and readily
available sometimes you don't
necessarily get the information you're
looking for but I'm sorry you can't
provide me that can you tell me who
would be a better point of contact a
little bit more knowledgeable that can
give me more information a better target
hey that's just as good as the keys to
the kingdom and then as Jason mentioned
earlier you can find out about the
operating environment what problems are
you facing with your Active Directory no
use Active Directory users openldap
really or whatever what operating system
is what problems are you facing you can
easily go that route with performing an
action clicking a link making chase
firewalls open an email whatever so
talking about open source intelligence i
actually got this definition from the
CIA coincidentally this did not come
from WikiLeaks this was a done before uh
everything dropped on the WikiLeaks
about the CIA but basically the places
you can get open source intelligence
you've got the internet that's basically
the mother lode traditional mass media
some things might not be on the internet
it might be a an old obscure newspaper
from years ago that that's definitely an
option specialized journal conference
proceedings people always like to talk
about what's new and hit that
conferences
I mean we're at a conference so
conference proceeding sometimes have
very detailed information if nothing
else to give you some context to be able
to strike up a conversation with someone
and be able to appeal to those six
principles later photos of course anyone
who is at derby contest last year you
might remember Josh Hawks talk where he
extracted the metadata out of the
reflection from well at out of the
picture with the reflection of the gas
pump and he determines what kind of car
it was that that's exactly it i always
laugh because i don't have a good
relationship with my dad but he posted
to facebook a while back
uh using his android phone a picture off
its front porch bragging about he had
moved to the mountains and he was off
the grid
where's the logic in that so we're not
friends on facebook but I laughed about
it nonetheless and of course
geospatial-intelligence the geospatial
information google maps is an excellent
resource because sometimes you need to
know my target organization do they have
a sense where are their dumpsters where
are where the smoking area whether you
smoke or not whether you vapor not
that's a great place to collect
information when i was an auditor for
the Department of Defense i smoked very
heavily at the time but even if i didn't
i would probably still into the area
just to find out because I found out so
many things so many projects that were
underway that IP was not even aware of
like other business units were doing
things in Google's public cloud and not
telling us
so definitely definitely useful ocean
pioneers there's really only one and
with that you've got Michael battle so
he's written two books he's got his own
podcast with Justin Carol the complete
privacy and security podcast version 2
of that book is I'm sorry
volume 2 of that book is coming out i
believe this year open source
intelligence techniques of 5th edition
just came out i have heard that's the
final final rendition
so where can you get it aside from what
we've already mentioned how many times
if you've been sitting in a bar
I mean for for those in attendance today
that was at the hilton last night
think of the conversations we could have
overheard and what we could have done
with that I mean the couple that was
over in the corner smooch and all night
we could probably learn a lot about them
probably from the sweet nothings that he
was whispering I don't know
think of all the times that you've been
in the mall you hear someone just giving
their credit card number over the phone
because their accounts locked out or
something
restaurants of course it's just like the
story I told you earlier of certain
taste of thai knoxville tennessee
hearing people go on about their
business dealing how they're planning on
franchising something out making a
hundred thousand hundred fifty thousand
dollars a pop even if you don't have
social media
your family and friends do and for that
i can collect open source intelligence
about you through them again back to
jason's talk this morning
it's all about giving to those around
you it's your ecosystem if you don't
have social media or you have an ultra
log down you still have to worry about
your mom posting embarrassing pictures
it's a fact of life you have to worry
about people asking your friends and
family questions about you that they
could use against you later and they can
be absolutely benign harmless seeming
questions but nonetheless i like the
back windshield approach we're going to
talk about that on the next slide but
just know that I this one right here
puzzles me I really don't understand
what's going on with that family down
there it's in Baltimore
so you know the person that took it they
live in Baltimore but I don't know they
may have been driving back from maury
povich show Jerry Springer i'm not sure
but I'm really interested to find out
what's going on with that family with
this one you can tell he's a veteran
with this one traveling sports team they
all have websites those websites they
list the team's schedule you can take
the data which we'll talk about on the
next slide and determine the probability
of people being at home during that
traveling team sports schedule if you
wanted to break in
well there's your time what better time
then looking at a good example of open
source intelligence the number of times
of almost wrecked after doing this
analysis the first time from trying to
analyze the car in front of me and them
rapidly slowing down i think they're
onto me but either way with this you can
look at the family you can easily build
a profile on it right
so dad you dead he might be in shape or
he might just think he's in shape either
way you might find at the gym after work
or very early in the morning
mom's a teacher so you're going to if
you're going to try something with that
family you're not going to want to do it
this in the summer
she's probably home but you're gonna do
it monday through friday between the
hours of eight nine and to have a pretty
good chance of success
John play soccer John looks big enough
to possibly be older
for high school sports team they
practice three to five days a week
nobody's going to be home after school
because mom still grading papers
he'll probably at the skatepark so if
you go with a Thrasher shirt and some
vans you know you might be able to talk
to tony hawk with and get some
information out of him as well
the part that confuses me the most would
be Jessica I'm not sure if jessica is
old enough to babysit herself
I don't know about her extracurricular
activities I we don't know a lot about
her because of that and then with beaker
and Ruby we don't know what breed they
are rubies a hound so well looks to be a
hound so Ruby might be really loud if
you're trying to do something around the
house speaker who knows I mean speaker
could be a great dane or to allah we
don't know
so when you're dealing with attacks
dealing with the human element it's all
about timing
you can't talk time and without having
some flavor flav mr. Collinsworth and of
course father time because it's
applicable to both in the Navy we use
the term slow is fast and that didn't
mean that you needed to be ridiculously
slow to do anything because when there's
a fire you need to move quickly to
perform the actions that you're
responsible for performing to ensure
that everyone is able to live to make it
back to the next port but you don't do
it at such a pace that you become
reckless so we're doing this you might
have to do several rounds if you're
doing it fast you might miss a lot of
things that you might find if you're
going a little bit slower and more
methodical it's all about the
persistence in the details because
that's that's where the vitality life
you might need to do several rounds of
the same analysis on the same target
because you might get something to
refine that information each round you
might get a kid's name a phone number of
an employer a place of business
something to work off of further and
then faster you go you're going to flop
here so to talk about how they mesh
that they're similar in terms of human
psychology and you use your open source
intelligence to build the dossier that's
going to provide better context for you
talking to them if you're going to go to
the bar you know they hang out at if you
have some sort of context to talk to
them about that's going to be to your
advantage you can do better spearfishing
and then even better pass forgetting
there's a tool out of github called
pathology it's spelled pwdl ogy it
actually takes information that you
input about your target and create an
intelligent password list about them so
take that for what it so at this point
we're going to talk a little bit about
up Facebook and Facebook life because we
cannot talk social media without talking
without talking facebook we can talk
open source intelligence without talking
social media so we'll just look here
really quick this is a facebook live map
it's at facebook.com slash live states
are showing up for other here we go
oh here's something in indianapolis
let's a listener men and see what's
going on here we might be able to get
some data from it there's a few things
going on
so wait for it to load here in the
meantime i'll go ahead and prep the next
steps and the next steps
so
for whatever reason this could be the
two videos unsure and keeping keep in
mind i am up connected to the internet
through my phone so it might be a little
slow so for that I apologize
so with this
okay here we go ok so there live in
right
nothing nothing big no harm no foul
I mean people people are wife more
people are alive so
so here's what we're looking for we
don't care about what they're talking
about this point
here's what we care about this is called
the video ID and here is Michael battles
Intel techniques website to go right
here to the bottom and under video data
to take you to this PHP file he has
operating on a site and here we see all
of the data about people on facebook
live publicly well not everyone but
people within reason
it's like the most viewed land so this
may not work
it did look right here what we have here
is a latitude and longitude I don't mind
if I do so from there we go here
see where is ok to get a better look I'm
not familiar with Indianapolis so it
might be something really obvious but
you might not be I don't know which is
somewhere in this area so it could be
right here at the house so I did this on
a politically affiliated website a while
back
someone was the talk was just absolutely
hammering the snowflakes and berkeley
into the ground
there's a conservative-leaning website
so i did the same analysis on them and i
found that the lady was broadcasting
from her home in greenville south
carolina she lived in a cul-de-sac had a
white yukon and a black Mercedes SUV so
yeah and there's no there's no denying
that her house because she was the only
out of the cul-de-sac so be careful what
you publicly I've not tested this to
determine if you're using a proxy or a
VPN if that negates anything but it's
definitely certainly an option and just
starting something for the next part of
the demonstration
so moving on back to the to talk itself
so most of this starts with a single
piece of information you know you know
your target you know the business to the
organization's name you might know the
person's name when I have numbers that
call me that I don't recognize i try to
run the intelligence on them most of the
time they're spoof to it doesn't do any
good
are you might have an email address you
might have a physical address a user
name of some sort of metadata from like
if a photo i would like to talk about
the surveys think of when you're walking
around through the mall or through a
store and hey you have five minutes to
do a survey of we're going to randomly
select the 14 five-hundred-dollar amazon
gift card right
think of the information they are asking
for their asking for things that you can
use to reset passwords that could use to
be up to further events other attacks
you don't know what they're going to do
in terms of destroying the survey you
write the date on honestly I would be
surprised if anyone ever actually won
that five-hundred-dollar amazon giftcard
honestly but sorry Salesforce if you're
still in the room
I know there was a sales force employee
earlier but if the core of marketing
this is what Salesforce's about facebook
you are the product the same goes with
google I mean they're both excellent
products under but they're not products
we are the products the users of
Facebook the users of Google those are
the products retail stores think back to
the story about target there's a young
lady that had a rewards card through
target she started receiving coupon for
baby formula and diapers and she was 16
years old dad sees the coupons and
starts a poking around pradhan asking
questions
oh no dad I'm not bragging i'm not
pregnant too pregnant because yes she
was target realize before she knew or
her dad knew because her shopping habit
had changed and while that's not true
open source intelligence it's closed for
the most part it's still intelligence it
example of how it can be applied so
you've got to pull that yarn a little
bit more quote weezer just pull the
string as i walk away and with that
things could be linked you password
times have I been pwned it's a great
place before it went away leak source
for four dollars you had 24 hours of
access to leaked passwords like actual
password in some cases sometimes there's
only the hash nonetheless not hard to
not hard to crack a hash have a little
context around it
email account again public records court
records the news because i have appeared
on the local news in Tennessee I could
never hide from the internet again but
I'm speaking here today I can never hide
from the internet again it's okay
blogs well can't hide their either
websites same thing employer post data
press releases for publicly traded
companies sec filing form 10-k it's a
beautiful thing and then of course
friends on social media as i said before
this is not one and done you might need
several rounds you might find you might
be at the final stage of your
intelligence gathering you might find
something like you know what I need to
go back and apply this into my analysis
and use it together together more
information you might need to do that to
look at it from a different angle
you might not have thought about
something at this point we kind of
reiterate the six principles less prosti
commitment consistency social proof
likability authority urgency scarcity
think about malware you need to click
this and you need to pay us money
because the FBI says you need to or the
phone calls
this is the IRS you need to pay us in
apple gift cards calling from a Miami
phone number when did you move from DC
to Miami who ok but anyway so at this
point we apply those principles you know
enough about the person you're after
so when you when you're sending them the
phishing email you have the context you
know what they're going to click on its
like the example Jason provided earlier
with hey uh they uh
I had a really good time in my
going-away party my vacation was great
i'm settling into North Carolina
by the way this happened link out of
nowhere and then lot of all the bottle
on the ball you have enough context to
make them think that link is associated
with it you don't have to say you just
have to infer it and then of course
pretexting an impersonation in my
current role i actually do some
protecting an impersonation
I feel with some financial institutions
some manufacturing companies so on and
you just have to get into character the
the first client that we dealt with we
had this story we had a baby crying in
the background we were in walmart we
needed some account information we
really had to do this but it didn't work
so we called inaudible we spoke to the
internal number from legal and we call
their CFO and we said that hey so that
we go to church with he's trying to get
an internship with the FBI
you know we got robbed a few months ago
he needs some data about the financial
impact of a bank robbery
he's reached out to suntrust fifth third
and BB&T and they all shot him down
can you help oh yeah sure can i sure can
miss to miss such and such
okay excellent what email address do i
give it because this company was in
tennessee i actually had to use my
authentic Tennessee action because
that's where I'm from
it took a long time for me to actually
get away from it as this it took about
seven years of being in the Navy to do
that but anyway my email addresses such
as some wire okay about seven minutes
and 43 seconds later i pressed send from
a gmail account and it was nothing but a
link to the survey 15 clicks later on
his work computer five clicks on his
cell phone later he emailed back and
said hey buddy that link didn't work can
use it to me as a file
yes we can so there goes the macro
enabled word document
well email back it says that opened up
the first time it is really fuzzy star
clique that thing and it's still fuzzy
so I thought my computer is broke so I
close it and open it again now my virus
scanner won't let me open it
do you have another file yes we do so
next time here comes an executable
disguised as an excel spreadsheet
I think you know where that story's
going to what happened
yeah but then later on like a
manufacturing company i called them as
HR and we had sent him email from
internal revenue service dot-com I had a
bogus site for their HR company so it
works perfectly
but you know what we didn't get a lot of
people to take the bait on now and by
show of hands two years heard of this
the sinister website
quite possibly the most brutal attack
tool known to man called family tree now
ok so at this point to show you a little
bit of fun I've had with not with them
but at their expense so so by a show of
hands to who hears a familiar with like
our social interior toolkit
ok so there's this really awesome
function in it and i'm about to show you
just 44 the giggles
I try to stay a anti cliche but anyway
so right here where the SE toolkit you
know taking Adrian's parent company for
maintaining such a wonderful tool
nonetheless we look at social
engineering attacks specifically website
attack vectors credential harvesting and
the site cloner at this point I'm just
going to step through that i'm not
actually going to perform everything but
you have you just input the IP address
i'm just going to give it you know home
no big deal and then we'll do so we do
that
doing all that ok good well yeah I don't
have attached you running on this one so
you're not going to see anything here so
we'll just close that there i'll go
ahead and exit all that good stuff but
we do have the file hanging out here
actually not there so
we do have it here that's you've got you
know your your index data here so that
index one or index 2.html index dot HTML
that would be the data that's copied so
that's where family tree now would exist
so anyway in the other instance
basically i sent an email out from a
domain that I do I'm family tree now
taught online and basically it says that
someone input information about you on
family tree now and we would like you to
validate it
upon clicking it there's also an opt-out
option two because that's always good
but anyway it takes you here for
reference the website has changed since
I did this but this is the real website
this is not the real website but anyway
you can do all the stuff here
nothing big I've taken all the links
that would be for family tree now.com
out and basically there's nothing there
but if you want to validate the
information let's look at what kind of
information they want us to validate
let's see here there's firstname
lastname last four date of birth address
city state zip code mother's first name
mother's maiden name mother's last name
father's last name father's first name
imagine what you can do with this and
then if you click Submit don't know
there's a payload oh no oh no and this
was built specifically for awareness
type thing so I didn't want to get too
sinister with it but you know with Rick
athlete needs not to censor but
nonetheless that that is the point what
also occurs during this time is there's
a actually monitor the apache logs and
when you hit validate everything that
you can put in this field is input into
the get request so i capture it all in
the apache logs so there is you know I
just navigate to that and it's there or
if you want to opt out
that's you know you click here to opt
out and anybody want to guess what
happens when you opt out
oh no it's him again but nonetheless I
mean that took almost no time at all uh
realistically though the hardest part
really was uh just stopping the Apache
instance so they don't get detected but
anyway it didn't take long i just had to
go through and do like some edit all
nothing nothing hardcore to be able to
put that together and I've got to use it
in an engagement yet but I have a
feeling that whenever it goes it's gonna
be a pretty successful but nonetheless
never passed the technical piece of it
will hit a little bit of mitigation to
then start to finish up so can you
effectively mitigate social engineering
that's a double-edged sword and it's a
philosophical debate honestly some
people are going to say yes some people
are going to say no some people are
going to say maybe I come from the
school of for the most part maybe
because you can't have technical
mitigations like proofpoint that's going
to tell you this email was coming from
an external source even though it says
its internal it's coming from an
external source that still relies on
your users to actually not click it if
you make it juicy enough
I mean and in january if you offer them
a w-2 or in November you offer them a
free turkey they're going to click it
straight up malware protection if that's
what they're going for ideas signatures
to some degree user behavior analytics
can actually kind of do that but in all
caps having open source intelligence and
social engineering campaigns against
your employees that is the most ideal
mitigation and I'm not a sales guy for
sword and shield you don't have to do it
through swords shields you could do it
through trust effect Black Hills anybody
it doesn't matter who but it's usually
better to have someone from the outside
do it especially the open source
intelligence portion because
as a security professional within an
organization you do not want to betray
your employees trust let someone else be
the bad guy i mean i just want to see
things get better
the sword shield makes money off of it
great if if somebody else does
awesome no big deal but then you have
your administrative mitigations as well
having policy to place like your
acceptable use policy awareness dealing
with personal devices that's definitely
one as well standards of conduct again
awareness most importantly train your
people training is a low-cost solution
that really can
it's not gonna be a hundred percent
effective but it's going to bring up the
rear a little bit you make it relatable
to people i like to use what's called
the smart framework specific measurable
attainable realistic and timely you do
that and you maintain their interest and
show them how they do how their actions
impact the organization you'll have a
better outcome because realistically
insider thread social engineering plays
into that I call people who are
untrained the fall victim to social
engineering
I call that passive insider threat
active insider threat being someone's
malicious intent
nonetheless you have your training
recurring you don't do 217 good to check
the box with a year and move on now
because that's 364 days for them to
forget you do something weekly monthly
quarterly something you have to have
management commitment from the CEO to
the janitor you have management
commitment that actually plays into the
authority principle of persuasion it
will better persuade the people lower on
the totem pole to actually do things to
help your organization role based
training is also important as an IT
professional if I get an email with an
attachment
I'm probably not going to open it if I
worked in human resources and it said
resume
yeah i would if it were accounting if I
were in accounting and it said invoice
you guessed it contracting management
they kind of I'm not think they think
they're above the rules but management
kind of thinks that they're immune to
things that they're untouchable
especially those with assistance if you
can make it through them i mean it's
it's over and done with helpdesk mean
they're going to get calls and they're
gonna get solicited to reset passwords
create accounts whatever non technical
personnel and this is in addition to
general training across the board and
your sea level suite and your senior
management needs customized training as
well because they face different
problems than the technical team than HR
then everybody else really
and this is the final rant about
training you need to clearly define who
you want things to be reported to how
you want it to be reported what you want
people to do if they receive a fish if
they fall for the fish if they fall
victim because this actually falls into
your incident response plan and it's
going to make it a lot easier for you if
you know where patient zero is your
incident response process is going to
speed up tremendously with that being
said you need to let them know what to
do with your computer if they click a
fish do you want them to shut it down
pull the network cable step away lock
the screen do nothing what you want them
to contact you via email phone walkover
carrier pigeon
what you need to define that and most
importantly a non-punitive policy people
are not prone to report if they think
they're going to get in trouble you
reward those who do report and those who
report that they've done things don't
hold it against them
obviously if it becomes a trend and
they're reporting something every week
you might want to consider something
else but an honest mistake here and
there no problem but you need to be
cautious with gamification so if you
have users the report hey I got this
phishing email hey I got this hey I got
this
eventually they're going to start
signing up for fishing list so they can
get the prize whatever the price
especially if you give them time off so
just understand what happened with wells
fargo in the incentive
instead of program there with the fake
account before you start gaming find
something i recommend things like a
parking spot free lunch are stickers
yellow stickies of appreciation i'm a
huge fan of those challenge coins those
work as well i would appeal to a candy
bar diabetic and be like what are you
trying to kill me
so with that being said here's how you
contact me i'm on twitter at the
underscore 3p Joe and also at 80 persist
sec I'm on linkedin there's my email
address is my personal well Mike
quality personal and my work one a
boring the podcast is that advanced
persistent security dot net podcast is
basically everywhere you can find
podcast arm any questions in the
meantime questions comments complaints
grievances thoughts opinions other
statements
ok so I'm further obligated to show you
this slide of your tiny contact sword
and shield so there's the address social
media if you want a consultation secure
me a sword shield calm and here's my
further speaking engagements if anyone's
interested i will be back at Circle City
khan and i will be giving up open source
intelligence and social engineering for
our training in addition to talk so
again any questions anything of the sort
thank you very much
[Applause]