alright afternoon everyone rich
hopefully can hear me ok talking about
physical fishing USP drops i'm sure
everyone is familiar and seeing the
headlines where they drop USB keys and
parking lot and everyone in the company
picks them up and put them in
I didn't happen with my users still that
kind of made me mass when they were
turning them all and so I had to do
something bigger and better or something
alternative so i'm here to talk about
some of those alternatives and some of
the schemes that have worked in some of
the habit so station was supposed to be
here so i put in a little little extra i
love you to him so the essence of the
talk the TLDR is I'm gonna make
something nice and shiny that I want you
to plug in and I'm a Trojan eyes it so
you have to stick around if that's all
you want to get out of it
I don't know python programming but this
looks dangerous so on
I don't think I'll ever learn it and I'm
only putting in one mean not that clever
usually so this is as clever as it gets
so again we've made USB drops they
didn't quite work in the normal the mic
and r2d2 and I the yoda USB drops
weren't very effective
so you can't tell from the picture but
there's a tape dispenser up there by the
archer picture
and it has a USB hole in the back of it
and I just set that down in the
reception area to see if anybody would
pick it up
this is the for archer season six came
out and the mean says you want to season
six because this is how you get season
six implying that there was a season 6
on me
USB Drive it that was inside the tape
dispenser don't pick up the tape
dispenser but they did take the cord so
then i put another court back in there
that i had organized with cum what you
see there
below is a few different flash drives
you can find them small enough if you
look in the very center this little one
here on the on the right there
it's not very long and you can take out
what was in there before and put
something new and the actual
cord is the Trojan you don't have to
have it necessarily plugged into a
device the court won't work of course
but you cannot just stick that little
guy inside of a USB housing and you've
got the same same thing in essence
previous works that inspired that 1i
believe Adrian and even Dave Kennedy of
talked about these children eyes mice
will embed a little USB hub inside of a
mouse or a keyboard there's an actual
project out there called the glitch that
is designed for you didn't specifically
do this may have hardware diagrams out
there at the end of the talk there's
some links to the glitch
there's also yeah like I said keyboard
or this keyboard has the USB hub built
into it so you don't even need to solder
and USB hub and so very simple to
organize a keyboard and who would like a
nice new sexy wireless keyboard or well
in this case a wired keyboard that you
may be one of the sweepstakes or just
happen to show up on your desk one day
somebody dropped it off for you
previous works also in this area poison
tap from sammy kaye he took a raspberry
pi and I have quoted as Raspberry Pi
zero costing five dollars it cost nine
dollars to ship so i don't know i right
so that's five dollars but everywhere I
bought it from and it's very small very
sexually
yeah and yeah so very small very
powerful little raspberry pi device and
as it says here and although the bullet
points
it stimulates a USB ethernet device over
USB so when you plug it in your computer
automatically trust it
they did the same thing with the land
turtle musics I believe did that as well
so as soon as you plug it in your box
actually asked for out and you can have
it route all your internet traffic
through that little device its
persistence it creates a backdoor into
your machine and it is literally very
very small you would just have to put in
a nice pretty package that someone wanna
plug in and so further on the talk i'll
get into the pretty packaging that I've
been trying to shove that into recently
pack 5 has come out with the cash money
which I am I have not got my hands on
yet but I've read all the specs on it
looks like it's going to be mostly the
same thing as the the poison tap where
it simulates USB over ethernet also give
you dedicated shell access payloads so
not to better price this
yeah so essentially the raspberry PI's
also linux usually virgins own fourteen
dollars and ninety-nine dollars you
probably probably easier to use the $99
one actually if the rubber ducky is any
indication of how easy it is to use
their tools so some of the slides in a
bit of disarray but I'm also calling
physical fishing five fishing so that's
trademarked so I don't know
somebody's around but copyright
trademark five fishing you can add that
to your issues where to go
you forgot that one so Pony Express
makes this little a power strip down
there and anything you plug into a good
down now it's not how it works but it
does have a you can see i wish i had a
laser pointer or laser eyes maybe at
that would work but it has a essentially
a computer back there by the power
switch and listens for your Wi-Fi
listens for Bluetooth anything that's
coming by and it's a nice little hack in
a box that just about anybody's going to
plug in its pretty unassuming power
strip but it listens for all your
network traffic you can even plug
network into it i believe but it's a
nice little uh device that someone's
that the Pony Express people which Jason
Street earlier this morning he was from
them that's just one of their devices
they have several better really really
great only so i'm going to talk about
one of our most successful fishes and I
have a lot of profit like carrot top up
here so you guys are probably actually
gonna have to come up and check these
things out yourself or maybe after the
talk i'll just move over there
yeah sure thank you the others make it
explode
yeah alright and don't look at all right
so yes we created a doom 45 whatever
doom is now in September last year was
coming out and so I created these little
invitations to a beta that supposedly
the pretext was there is a little
envelope package that arrived at the
office and inside of it had letterhead
from festa that said your office was
selected to participate in this doom
pre-beta and here 25 free passes to
download the beta and lawyers had a
conniption over me using all the
branding and calling out doom and making
the test the letterhead so we didn't
officially use this at the company but
my boss is kind of cool and he just
dropped it off somewhere in a conference
room and so instead of sending it we
unofficially ran this this fish so
anyway someone opened in the conference
room and passed them all out and we had
28 people out of the 25 download this
Hardware profiler so 201 percent or 110
and a ten percent which is great effort
by my team they give a hundred percent
and yet nobody could wait for tech tech
savvy office so I I was pretty sure it
was gonna work but anyway the lawyers
did not did not like it so we weren't
going to send it in the mail and and
commit mail fraud or whatever else they
they thought we'd be
whatever toes would be stepping on
however it was a bit ly address on the
back of the the card not really a
because the domain registered was the 00
are in that tech because doomed at Tech
was taken and all the other domains were
taken so do orn looks just like the OM
in a browser so watch out if you have em
xin your domains you might want to
register the are in version of it and
i'll probably touch on that some more
throughout the talk because it's one of
my favorites so yes I do our end of tech
it's actually still up it think it's
going to expire this month so get your
hardware profile now
girl scouts of america came out with
girl scouts cookies last two months ago
I guess so that was going around so it's
a timely at time to send out a fish
around this so i actually have a city by
familiar with s3 from amazon Harris not
official website so if you look at the
URL it's girl scouts dot
s3.amazonaws.com us.com this is the
actual domain because s3 is the first
come first served basis on the name of
the buckets you choose
so if you go out to s3 and you register
or I'm sorry if you apply a name to your
bucket and this one girl scouts and fill
in the information do this
Adrian Crenshaw at the comment org or
com today
alright anyway did not work as far as
going to another page its users get
instead of post show up here in the top
you can see name equals Adrian email
equals Crenshaw there are other fields
that are off the screen such as phone
number organization address postal
city-country credit card number month
year blah blah blah
CCTV this is taking advantage of ya the
pre population of your form data that
Google often likes to do this is firefox
in this case but chrome would have
filled this out had I had a dream
contrast information the other
information would probably all have pre
populated in that form the the other
form elements are far to the left minus
500 pixels or so and there's a camera
who I lifted this from it is from this
github hear this guy and he was nice
enough to show everyone in the world
that this is a thing here's the doom
pre-release gotten invited a code enter
your email address so i got more email
addresses i got twenty-five codes they
all entered the same code however they
were in order it it turret so they get
they got together and one person did
figure out the next code that it would
have been and put it in and they were
able to
download just a hardware profiler
well-chronicled hardware profiler that
just ran a ping back to us and said hey
somebody on this machine this machine
name and solve this and that's all did
but it gave a message that it was
inconclusive that your network card or
your video card was up to snuff
so another s3 bucket here is 0 3 65 that
s 3 s website USA amazon.com and found
81 AWS com
so now Microsoft is given up on Azure
and switch to amazon which I think
that's fair
they did another beat as that's nice of
them to give it up but yeah this would
work just the same and yet as long as
you reserve the s3 bucket you can serve
a webpage from s3 which is just a data
storage on mom on amazon and here's
google giving it up to be on the on on
amazon now so amazon right for abuse and
who doesn't trust amazon right so back
to the slides real quick
so the Girl Scouts of America yeah that
was an entrance to when you know girl
scout cookies for a year if you want to
avoid lawyers and and things like that
you probably don't want to brand at girl
scouts of america you could say you know
who can use that green and maybe put a
cookie up there something and kind of
hint that it's Girl Scouts of America
but it's not actually Girl Scouts of
America all right where were we
yes so the search you get from amazon
totally legit who doesn't trust amazon
and i am going to go quick because i
know we we don't have a lot of lot of
time so I'm gonna hopefully have
questions at the end for you guys i'll
answer them so i have here again my
carrot top
these were seventeen dollars on amazon
it's just an empty shell you put your
cell phone in it and then it got the our
goggles so if you were to be sent this
at your office maybe you would be
interested in seeing what happens with
the our goggles you probably put some
crappy burner phone in here and then
maybe put in the poison tap Raspberry Pi
zero instead of or if you are smart
enough and I'm not so that's why I
didn't do it to get your payload into
the phone itself or maybe just use that
stupid cord i made earlier and you that
cord is the only one that makes this
work for some reason maybe your to use
that and they install drivers for it and
then you own their machine because they
wanted to plug in $17 headset when they
probably shouldn't have done that at
work so that's that's big the suggested
most of my my fishes trying to figure
out what I can cram a raspberry pi 0
into or a
flash drive into and get users to want
to install it
I have tons of ideas about that and
we've only done it once and the USB
drops were a failure but someone wanted
to plug in my tape dispenser or at least
the court from my tape dispenser which
was odd
so yeah the cell phone to be the the
payload more advanced maybe you send
them something that actually work so
maybe this maybe put a little crappy old
iphone 4 used to have and you load some
vr app on it and maybe that actually
works but maybe it still needs a driver
to install so you include a little flash
driver you include a seating by have
cd-roms anymore
no flash drive or maybe there's a driver
download from do our end up tech2 to
make the new doom be our work on it and
then maybe that cell phone has an open
Wi-Fi or Bluetooth to what to the
packaging itself so this this box
actually has a lot of open area and if i
was to put foam in the box or something
to conceal another way to exfiltrate
data so if I was to put a cell phone in
this box that was communicating to the
the driver was able to communicate to
the cell phone because you've installed
on your laptop and maybe I I can talk
bluetooth to you you can exfil without
going to their network you can have
their machine connect to maybe the
packaging instead of the actual VR
goggles themselves
show with all the ubiquity of all these
little devices and how easy it is to
program and how everybody as a developer
now the sky's the limit for your
imagination you can do the things that
were always depicted in you know spy
movies and see it in the CIA and you
know all the all the cool cool
who was at the q and some of those other
things
yeah and this is just a link to magnetic
closures which are a dollar-fifty to get
they are dirt cheap they look
professional enough that
they look professional enough that it
sells the fact that someone getting a
gift and it seems like it's not you know
the legitimate came in a magnetic box it
looks nice and shiny and so you can
print a logo on these little boxes they
don't cost that much but it's a very
professional package and they are very
cheap and anybody can put a photo here
you don't have to have them printed so
that's another idea
so some of the ideas I had some of the
things I've seen on the internet that
just I love them so much and if someone
sent me 1i am plugging it right in would
be I don't know if you see me 3d scanner
but there's a handheld 3d scanner scan
objects and you can have them ready for
your 3d printer and like no time
laser tag is anybody played laser tag
and while it's a lot of fun
somebody sent me a laser tag system and
I needed update drivers or something
like that i'm going to plug it in
something to file my neighbors ok maybe
maybe I want to that retro gaming system
again i have more props
I've got a little uh anybody heard of
the retro pie project now so it's
raspberry pie but it can play old names
are it plays mame roms your old video
games come back to life and you actually
play on you a controller that goes to
USB to your raspberry device so retro
gaming system if you had it all enclosed
in one little Nintendo or Genesis or I'm
sorry
sega playstation whatever whatever might
meet their fancy doing open source
intelligence on the maybe you know
they're safe and maybe another Nintendo
fan maybe there's a Microsoft fan so you
can send them a 360 controller and say
if you plug this into your computer and
run the drivers then
you can play all your old games again
right from this little controllers nice
and portable so you can own our
organization because we'll probably do
it work if you send it to him at work
again
preview of the long long delayed game
doom doom was way long delayed so I
wanted to play it so I came up with that
that fish and that was a hundred and ten
percent effective see other things
crowdfunded password manager at the idea
of working on just a little physical
device that the managers your passwords
but it doesn't you think it does i have
more again I have a lot of little props
and I want to be carrot top and just
show me everything but please come by
and see me later i have an RFID
wallplate skimmer just like an ATM
skimmer but if it's over the wall plate
of our ids we see all around buildings
and can state power for about a week
I don't remember what the light bulb was
this was is a if anybody is not familiar
with this work it's great
this is also physical penetration
testing in the literal sense where they
have a vampire tap you familiar with the
term so this little tiny tiny little
device right here
no bigger than whatever coin
denomination that is
very very small it gets put in behind
the shell you can see right here gets
put in behind the shell of the rfid
reader and it's it's physically on the
wires and listens to what happens as
people card in and card out and it saves
it all inside of itself and then you
walked by with your bluetooth on your
phone and you download all of them later
and then you make clones of the all the
ideas you've got so right here in this
video they're showing you and I think it
takes about a minute and a half for him
to punch down the wires into these two
little clips screw everything back
together and then start getting card
getting card data so we've got all back
together he put the car down there and
the door opens and his phone gets a
little little page because he's close
enough to it that here's a new rfid so
I'm working on something similar but
it's a clamshell that goes over the box
because on these boxes now they actually
have a little LED in the back that once
you take it off the back of the wall it
triggers an alarm
I don't know if everybody's configured
by default to to notice it but it does
trigger an alarm if you take those off
and I've got a bunch of credits here for
things that are better than when I have
again
adrian has done a programmable human
input device keyboard dongle and that
was great inspiration for me there's a
lot of stuff a black hat and that's
where i got some of the first slides i
want to give credit where credit is due
we do fishing campaigns at work but most
expensive
the email type we don't feel anybody to
quipped to deal with these kind of
attacks yet not many of them happening
other than the USB drops in parking lots
so I wanted to take it to the next level
and make make this a reality and so far
we've got sign off on on one project and
other customers are interested so we're
hoping the other people to think like
think evil but do positive things with
it so yeah I guess I'll open up the
question that's pretty much it it's not
a complex topic I don't think
going once going twice right well you
guys will please come over and see me