good morning how are you I'm like to
start off this is my legal disclaimer
and actually more than any time that
I've given talk this is probably more
relevant for this talk you can't sue me
for anything that I've done in this talk
period that legal disclaimer shows you
that ok I'm not a lawyer but I played
one on the internet before successfully
and basically what this says is that I'm
adorable
ok i will not try to steal from you kill
you or ruin you financially miss you pay
me first okay there's always a contract
so when I talk about some really
horrible evil despicable things that
I've done successfully
I got paid i was a good guy i did them
they're very bad and very evil but there
for good reasons the people that I'm
compromising in this talk allegedly I
didn't actually exploit I didn't
actually go all the way and actually for
them so therefore no harm no foul this
will all open open public research is
still available on the internet that's
not my fault it's theirs if educational
purposes only
so let's get into it the title this
talking strategy to secure your banks
and enterprises from someone who robs
banks enterprises for a living
that'd be mean and basically it this is
a wake-up call for this industry ok and
i'm not talking about like you know hey
it's time to wake up we got some
security problem i want you to be woke
like Jaden Smith realizing turtles come
from shells ok it's like seriously it's
like informatics there you go
so and this is one of the best examples
of that Super Bowl this reason superbowl
tier one level security event right over
5,000 police officers the Vice President
was there so you know Secret Service was
there you know it was a very secured
event right yeah three teenagers i'm
really not one of over twenty it's like
broken through the back of a gate at the
ass or the whatever the the new teeth
the stadium is called found a ladder
they didn't bring their own ladder they
just stole one from the venue
and they bypassed all the security
because they were carrying a ladder
because that's totally legit
I've got a ladder how can you question
my authority I've got a ladder here and
that's how they worked and that's what
I'm talking about it's like we want to
think and make assumptions that are
security is good we want to believe that
everything is well no one want any of
our data no one's going to try to steal
from us or try to compromise us because
we don't have anything worth actually
taking from from us where were we
secured people we have nothing important
and that's a lie
it's like that's not the way it works in
the real world it's like everybody a
target for somebody if I guess just the
way that it goes this is a feel-good
talk to I'm internet okay good so
release important slide that's just me
you want to get me on WeChat or Twitter
that's my Twitter handle and then this
is what I'm really mainly talking about
humans suck at risk management remember
when the bowl is without everybody
getting Ebola oh my gosh you're bolas
it's in dallas that means it's spreading
outward well my gosh we got worried
about the Ebola how many people died
from Ebola in America to people that
same year that it is unfortunate that
those two people unfortunately died from
a bowl of over 55,000 people died from
the flu and pneumonia but of all of it
sounds scary but we can't you know drink
orange juice and you know wrestle bitten
you know takes mastery risk management
we're not that great at it
one other example cool okay they're out
there
you never done 10 days gonna hit you you
know what you got watch out there's a
vendor who told us you can protect it
from the old days right and sequels
slammer sequel injection has surfaced as
the number one pak-rat 2015 sequel
injection let me get on a little bit of
a pedal here because i'm not usually on
pedestals writer ranting single
injection is not a security
vulnerability sequel injection is not a
security vulnerability it's crappy
coding you don't have a vulnerability
you have a bad coder who should feel
that ok that's what's equal injections
are stopped trying to give the
developers of acute by saying well that
was a vulnerability to have forgotten to
know you coded your stuff crappily and
they were able to get it sony sorry i
was are doing enough so tight you gotta
watch out for that stuff so that's what
you need to worry about and just a just
up ram that idea home
this was from this year sequel slammer
is coming back 2002 at DEFCON 2 sequel
injection that cause people clamor to
occur was released September of 2002
microsoft came out with a patch to patch
that sequel injection vulnerability
thing
februari 2003 sequel slammer hit I
thought about this tactical check your
firewall logs now and you will still see
someone running an outdated sequel
server that have not been packed that is
connected to the internet and that
doesn't make you want to cry you're not
human
okay seriously that's what's out there
right now but we're worried about
someone popping our toaster with a
zero-day that could turn on our
microphones on our TV and listen to us
argue with our to give another about why
you're trying to watch you know the
housewives of new york for the third
straight week in a row so it starts
getting too personal
so it's like so yeah like who wants that
who's worried about that stuff
so who's out you talk about risk
management is really coming after you
is it really the government you relating
the government come back to come after
me on my gosh that'd just be right but I
really coming after everybody
no not unless you're like you know you
run a nucleus of interviews or you're
building a communication gear or you're
the Pope come on seriously the Pope i
will say this okay
this Pope is pretty cool Pope I mean
he's like this guy literally dresses up
in a the lower priests like a missionary
priest garb and goes out at night and
feed the homeless vatican city is
literally the Batman of popes how
awesome is that
and a freaking NSA spying on him I mean
that other guide with the red shoes in
the funny hat and it's a little scary
about that guy was sketchy I'm sorry he
looks a little sketchy but this probably
get a good poke it's like I can't be
responding on so it's like it also led
the fact that make you feel that you are
being supplied by the government don't
worry because just like everybody else
including your your your parents and
relatives are still using really really
horrible bad passwords as you can tell
from the bolt 7 leak 123 ABC lowercase
des they got you on that one
that's the government dollars at work
right there people ok
security it's like so you have to worry
too much about that but have to worry
about anonymous 0 volts that coming for
me you know
well not really because i love the baby
if any reason if anything you have to
feel concerned about a don is coming
after you or to activist group coming
after you remember it's the same group
that bout to say that they were good the
hacker group Anonymous do any real
damage for Donald Trump campaign as it
is threatened and we know the answer for
that one so not as effective they like
to be but who really coming out to you
about criminals have a people who are
making money off of it
whoo how about people who actually
benefiting from the from the actual here
vulnerabilities your threat yeah I think
that's what you should be worrying about
because at the end of the day it's not
going to be the nation-state it's not
going to be the act of it it's going to
be the person who directly profits from
your failures and security that are
going to be going after you
so let's delve into a little bit deeper
to that and the best I mean literally I
mean to have the one of the worst
breaches in history
how unfortunate to actually have your
name target it's like I mean that's just
like that was like two on the notes like
I mean I mean home depot's was a really
bad thing but don't talk about know that
many jokes about you know owning a home
depot but literally don't become a
target
you're like it don't be target it's like
they have one of the biggest one they
spent billions
uh-oh over a billion it's like not
billions but like over a billion dollars
on this disaster still and how they how
did that happen
their HVAC company it's always hard
earlier point i literally just bought a
laser pointer just with this emergency
so they literally and it's only gonna be
effective on
sorry guys you're screwed so it's like a
butt over here I i would try but it's
just not gonna yeah it's gonna work
project so they had a malware lace email
phishing email phishing attack right now
we're late email phishing attack and
that's what got him
someone clicked on a link and I want to
correct one thing in this article they
just really gets me really bad
you cannot say that right here
badges it was the victim a sophisticated
cyber attack and the same paragraph when
you realize you've got popped by
phishing email that built they don't go
together ever
okay that does it that's not how this
works
that's not how any of this works ok so
that's what that is and also you gotta
understand they tried it the measure of
how common these crimes have been yes
you're still that crop common target was
prepared
quotes right there should be for this
kind of attack they installed a 1.6
million our detection tool made by fire
I and then they outsource it to security
specialist meglora to monitor the
computers around the clock and report if
anything happened uh spoiler alert they
didn't so that's how that occurred
it's like target with having defense
target was doing things that were
defending its stock company defending
its network target was doing some of the
things that were right but didn't matter
because the guys didn't go after target
they went after one of the the trust
relationships that target had
compromised them and that's all it took
because target trusted everything that
went inside network instead of being a
little distrust one that so now the next
part i want to talk about defense i want
to talk about things how you can defend
your network but there's a problem with
that people don't really take it to
heart when you talk about how you can
defend it because people are like why
don't have to worry about that we've got
a lot of different catching our company
we're very well-protected it's like that
that's good advice shapeable look but
we'll see about that
so I decided to do something different
on the stock i decided to show you how
arbitrarily and horrible things can get
so this next thing of my demo it is
random and arbitrary it is random as
your parents getting gunned down coming
out of a movie theater
it is as horrible as being your uncle
shot right out in front of a liquor
store
ok it is literally as random as a
astronomical event taking out your
planet yet those are all origin story
yet
that's how bad it's just going to be it
is not anything that I've done cookin
clue where I'm like oh I'm going to plan
this out I literally started with Google
like most people things usually start
out with
ok I good with it so what I googled was
biggest bank in Indiana and I got a list
and then I saw this lift
I thought name and this is all it took i
I'm not even joking i did not go
to any other bank i'm not trying to find
the easiest thing to go for I literally
pick one bank and I stuck with it
what's up is a fifth third I mean I'm a
high school dropout are arriving maybe
that's an algebra geometric equation
that really makes sense but what the
Fifth Third I have no clue but you know
what they're really good with fifth
third identity alert and fifth third i
do the alert premium I'm like that's
good enough reason to go after you
so get to i targeted bit third so here's
some information on Fifth Third's you go
to Earl scan dot IO you'll see all the
websites that are linked to him you see
the different countries that their
servers are residing in you see all the
different trackbacks you see all the
information look at all this information
that you're getting even outgoing links
from the web site
these are felled request from their
website and this right here is going to
be one that going into the details of
the Earl they're showing from the header
that are going to it and this is just
the more information you can get all the
different hits how long it takes what
the load is and how much data is coming
down all that I've not gone to the
website yet have the ideas alerts did I
trip to firewall blocked me to their apt
device come out and capture me
nope let's go to the website with a nice
website forfeit start everybody from
fifth third here
don't raise your hand because it just
makes me sad ok so it's like a so this
is I actually did this a demo sort of
like this in Germany with an insurance
company into the people from more like
was like the head-to-head so the guys
were there it was awkward
it's like a bit like throw up for this
is the website now this website tonight
let's light i'm not going to doggone it
looks like i'm looking at those couple
of you that guys ready for action Ryder
look at it like honey to the plane you
know what I got cool
ok that's awesome but that's not how a
bad guy sees your website that's how
good people to your website
ok this is how I see your website with
extensions like right there was an
extension that tells me right off the
bat that your IP addresses to 16 that 62
that 178 got 20 that your location at
Cincinnati Ohio that you're using akamai
as your dns service you're doing a
distributed internet service which is
awesome that's good good backup possibly
but the vaccination tell me my ascension
also tells me that you have nine other
domains hosted on this IP address
you've got an IP address subnet at 216
that a tooth at 178 that oh that's
really good list of targets right there
people and y'all go all the way out to
252 doubt once again so the whole range
and what else to show me it shows me
that the domains are 53 com RG crown
bank.com crown bank.com the curious
bank.com that is actually curious world
to have her bank but then again the
fifth third r dash C crown bank capital
bank in a 24 HR so they are also
probably others bank that they've
acquired another domain her but are all
those web pages coded properly do all
those pages made by the same team
maybe maybe not all I know is I've got
more targets to look at now I started
with one website now I've got a new list
of a whole bunch of others to go after
and see if I can do something and I have
a whole bunch of IP addresses to go
after
and what I'm going to hold onto IP
addresses quite a few of them because
look right there to 1628 to that 178 got
21 have got 99 domains on it
yay it's like you know it's like I'm not
going
I've gone from my doing oh I've got this
morning little window of opportunity
like a look at this huge barn door oh
there's an open letter jingle lock and
see that's where it goes from so i also
have right here their mail servers to
162 dot 180 dot 3631 4100 that's awesome
that's telling me that they're actually
doing in-house IT that those servers are
inside your network nothing bad could
happen with that I'm not the other one
is I see that they're not doing an adult
hosting which is good no hackers spyware
yet and they've got no open proxy also
there are using HTTP HTTPS because God
they want to be on the internet but
everything else is closed i also see
that this is I'm not making things that
are bad or good i'm just reporting
things so I'm reporting the good back is
that they've actually got a pretty good
who is information they made a generic
they put I tdot vns TxDOT bancorp at 53
calm for their contact and and that 5300
means it's probably to a generic line
that's a good way to do it
they actually did a good with contact
information we'll talk about that a
little bit later because when i'm doing
social engineering engagement i love the
who is contact information because
that's how i used to get up an
employee's name employees valid email
address and the police valid phone
number and fully valid address which is
a good place to start when you're trying
to compromise people so they actually
did really good on that one so so
there's it's not all bad
so now how many ideas alert to my trip
how many apt robots will be like you
know activating on the future retro
active energy of the internet device a
trip not
so now i'm actually googling my actual
target this third bank right there and i
love it i love with this pops up i'm
referring to the stuff over here trying
to get there that ok it's like oh yeah
talk about this because it shows me they
got all these profiles i love all those
profiles
BAM twitter we love to Twitter mean to
25 other personalities i actually have
running on Twitter currently right now
and what I like about these people
they're doing right is that they're
actually following a hundred and fifty
four people but they're only but only I
mean they're only following that many
people but they have over 30,000
followers
that's a good profile Rachel that means
they're not just accepting every person
that follows them or not they're just
doing their accepting what the one thing
i have a question about 15-30 people
just this one
what's up with Kentucky Fried Chicken
seriously i have no clue but someone in
their social media dept loves chicken
ok that's well it must be because it's
like it's also if you look at the
followers you look at cabin spicy Kevin
hochman hi Kevin Kevin hochman follows
296 people but only a hundred ninety
people follow him and he loves chicken
too
that's awesome it's like so what do i do
what's hard to compromise and get
someone to friend be that's like that
bank to friend him and get a DM psychics
Indian message that i could probably
compromise that with so what i do i
compromise one of their followers first
like Kevin because he's more willing to
probably accept the friend request if i
forgit properly and then so I didn't
compromise him and then Kevin since the
DM to the fifth third bank so there's
something wrong with your profile and
they have to click on this link to check
it out and then that person click it and
where they clicking it at inside the
corporate network because this is their
job
so remember the kittens I'm adorable
ok good so I hear linkedin linkedin is
like the facebook for corporations so
you know y'all got beyond your status
updates and your connections peppers
more spanish could believe that
so there's your LinkedIn connections i'm
not really going to go after Lincoln
right now this one it's like I want to
fuck about with something a little
different their YouTube channel was I do
want to notice and make dota is that
notice the common reoccurring picture so
if i create a phishing page i'm pretty
sure someone to buy if I just plastic
that picture on there right
I mean it's the lovely you know the nice
people just have a good conversation
someone just told a really awesome joke
it's not me obviously but still they're
there and they're having a good time up
and they are very social media savvy but
seriously google+ what and I like the
fact if you have not posted 2015 your
google+ to take it down it's just an
embarrassing amount
ok it's like come on that that it's like
you you're hurting google feelings as
well as people that are actually
refreshing looking for content onto ok
that's not a win-win situation for
anybody so let's not do that but we have
facebook
oh here we go now
anybody here you Facebook don't raise
your position of the olympics i use
facebook all time I all my stuff is
public
it's like I don't believe in like hide
things and make it easier for the
government agency to the following me
but I'm trying to be helpful though if I
got here is your facebook profile you
gotta love the praise favorite profile
not because of what they post because
you cared about the post but it's
because those who likes and share what
they post because we all know we all got
a barber right no Barbra got to do baby
she's posting every single freaking pig
eating the beach it's so adorable and
you've got like that picture because if
you don't like that picture she
contacted by just a baby picture he was
adorable pictures
you don't like my baby you think my baby
is that what you're trying to say you
your baby is better to my baby or
something I mean what is wrong with my
baby you know so you have to like those
pictures
it's like ok they're always oh no one's
ever walked like that but ok sure
so you got like those pictures or you're
inhuman monsters just a rule ok that's
facebook you signed up for it that's
what happened but do you share all those
baby pictures do you go and tell you
because when you share that picture
you're saying oh no this is the best
beautiful its way I've ever seen a
little baby beet I have to share this
with the world that's what your name to
it you now signed on to that beautiful
baby eating beets
it's like so when you see an employer or
a bank have opposed and people share it
it doesn't got to share offering the
fact that kind of practically schools
really fast about to post is how do you
really want it
I didn't delve into what does articles
about could I don't care and I was at a
time because I try to do under two hours
of this took less than 45 minutes
it's like why i always like to keep it
under two hours to compromise somebody
cool so I didn't really read the article
but it means somebody that it's like so
up but it had 18 shares there's 18
people that were going i'll i'm going to
share this with by fellow people and who
those people are usually sharing it
employs because for some reason to your
supervisor really cohesive team player
that he shared that link on facebook the
job you know it's like they don't care
it's like up here are the people that
share it see all these two right here
but i like the fact that Alex the net
shared it twice
ok I didn't go after him because he's
scared me because he shared it twice i'm
not really dealing with that kind of
person I don't want to come back to
haunt me
ok the very next person was Jeff Rogers
you know Jeff Rogers you know like Buck
Rogers and twenty you know I'm old so so
that was a great show so that's why
targeted there's there's Jeff Rogers
various facebook profile
this is a real employee this is not fake
this is not contrived this is remember
the kidding this is an actual guy to
work there and then I don't feel too bad
about these he's been in cancun okay I'm
Varrick including the guys in cancun
having a time of his life that offer is
like up you know what else he did have a
going-away party here at the beach grill
you had it there because he was moving
to North Carolina but still going to be
working at fifth third so that means you
know you still a target so that's
awesome for him but he's moved there and
he was there with six other people were
sitting with six other people so that's
also do with each other people these
people they were there at the party they
like them they thought it was cool
what's up Mandy I can't have the
potential to be your friend
I mean like you want to hear for me like
I don't even have the opportunity like
no Jason now you can you are which is
actually I can't blame her i I'm not
gonna like that's a good move i wouldn't
want me to print either it's like
especially in this context but uh but
still a little upset and will admit
maybe so we're going to target maybe two
there's there's I where's Mandy there's
jazz watching we do well we gotta send
an email now I gotta send email to man
be and i'm sending it as Jeff so i'm
going to send this email but what I'm
going to do if I for how do i how do I
don't even know what your email
addresses are how can i find out how
they even do their email addresses
because they may have a different name
and it's oh there's a after that website
you don't email dash format calm i just
type in 5273 five-thirds at 53 make up
your mind
okay so five 3.com
and look they tell you exactly how it's
done
that's how their email addresses are
they give you a list of people who have
used that email address formats that way
on the website which is another list of
targets so now we get into it
this is the bad part I'm a bad guy i
have broken into a building in a
wheelchair holding boxes and you're
saying Jason that horrible thing to do
I'm stealing from you like I care
I'm a bad guy that's what they do really
horrible crappy things ok we're not
talking about i think there's no bad
guys going like you know it's like all
I've gotta Robbie sir it's like uh I'm
sorry about the gun is not totally
overkill I mean nope sorry but I don't
think you mean it that way but I need
all your money right now it's a complete
disregard it except that I've kill you
if you don't give me your money
who does that you're getting mugged in
Canada ok it's like I mean come on it's
like they're bad guys are doing bad
things so I need them to click on the
link in my email
what do people click on an email
well actually a lot of crap as you see
the same rate stuff obviously but no
events that are horrible events that are
bad events that are newsworthy people
need information two days after the
Boston bombing I literally got an email
that said Boston news is the subject and
it said I always said was the subject of
the body the body the message was just
an IP address numbers is an IP address /
boston got hdmi male that was it
I'm like yes oh yes
you had a family member running a trace
you haven't heard from them yet phones
are still tied up it's like you don't
know where they're your friends at
Boston are doing right now are you
clicking that link we need information
you have terrible event happens you need
information
scammers create fake relief site on the
internet before Red Cross is even on the
ground that situation because it makes
money so it's not just me there's really
bad people out there
okay I'm just imitating one so i sent
this email I sent to Mandy Joe see this
red because if he's in the actual bc
field because I didn't send this email I
wasn't paid to do this i'm doing it for
the law sort of it's like but I'm like
this is a demonstration
no one was actually received this email
no one got sensitive is that shocking
news has me worried take care
those are three ! when you've got three
! an email that means business okay to
your really excited about it
30 my gosh at five I'm not even that's
just yeah that's gonna go there
ok so hello Mandy it was great seeing
you last month at the beach grill it was
great going away party that always
cherish still trying to get back in here
after the cancun trip and moving to
North Carolina I was mainly writing to
you after reading about the further
whore to the Delta murders and the ones
that just occurred just down the street
from you than bad link
I'm going to suggest that the bank takes
a proactive role in supporting people
who requested to their card at night
these events are so tragic and that it
seems that its continuing it's
frightening indeed
please state and we'll also be posting
some staying fit guidelines on my
facebook
take care jeff rogers in from a mobile
device that many times do I tell her to
click the link dietary that was the look
she links you to click how would they
not click the link
just to see what the news is just to get
more information on our rig event that
may impact them that how attackers
operate that's why bad guys are
successful because they know how to do
that because no matter how much your
defenses and your blinky boxes are
working there's always going to be a
human that can say yes or no
yeah but that's why you don't forget
about the kids I i keep saying the
kitchen okay there we go okay good
that's ok so and this is what's going to
happen
there's an update of social media-based
your employees are your greatest asset
but it comes to social media they can be
your greatest weakness they take
pictures they take selfies and instagram
and facebook at all the different
accounts that there on that they could
be leaking valuable information I've
literally sure i will get a construction
company in new york city and i showed
them because they had no data to lose i
showed them within like less than 15
minutes how I could take one employees
being from LinkedIn find out all the
information his home address find his
daughter's picture on Instagram that
license plate from his car the
construction site that he worked out and
show them how i could take his daughter
hostage and use him to a fire PF 98
shoulders surface-to-surface missile to
the Freedom Tower
I think certified to get unfettered
access to that went down that Street but
the demo was good i didn't really do
that that would be horrible and back
it's like I'm a good guy so I got to
keep reiterating that removes the first
time really giving a talk and like this
into the hanging out of realizing its
way scarier than I was intended to be so
so what do we do you know you ever see
those talks at it another pet peeve of
mine is public schools a lot of my pet
peeves
there's another one like that these you
get the people that get that Alright
yeah this is how I trashes and totally
broke that protocol on its done I've
done is like broken gone by
shoot how'd you fix it I don't know it's
just tore up but it's like I just
decided to destroy it like I don't think
about the password is just but look what
i did i made it work better they usually
leave no I'm not doing there so
hopefully now after that demo you
realize you need things to help defend
your network correct you need step to
defend what you're doing and what you're
protecting you don't have to be at the
attacker skill level to learn tools and
to use automated services that can help
you be like the attacker because you
have to stop building your defenses like
you're the one attacking you
you're a good guy good guys are building
defenses that will keep good guys out
that awesome
you can go to the next room and see that
lockpicks only keep honest people at or
about not locked it locked only keep
honest people out so we need to start
building our defenses like bad guys are
coming after us because news alert they
are that's not taking these people they
are ok so you can you tell us those this
one of those that framework enter your
name go to these forces and enter your
company's name start looking at your
company like you're trying to attack it
do certain searches do searches of the
framework see what kind of information
you come up with if you're working for a
bank fifth third this seriously
fifth third should be on IRC on the
other debt because that's where their
credit card information and they've been
numbers of their customers are being
traded they should do that on the
virtual machine on a network if not
attached to the corporate network and
they should expect to get toasted every
once in awhile okay i still get toasted
at least once or twice every 3-4 months
okay it's like you have to like start
back over so it's like the internet it's
a scary place so so they should have an
IRC channel running having someone
monitoring that
you should go into pastebin.com and just
doing a third for your bank or your
company and do searches that myth you
can do just the name of the company but
then also do like Carter's or card
information or banks or breach or
vulnerability do searches for things
like that to see if you're being
targeted
they even have news alerts that will
email you when a new pastebin comes up
that has your keywords in it like this
one right here where I did
indianapolis bank these are all results
like this person brown bag of
Indianapolis heard that code for 6290
phone number her card number for a
credit card or expiration date her TV
number and the remote IP addresses she
was that when she was compromised sound
nice i was this an expired credit card
so that was good
ok I didn't want to i want you want to
take a moment that I was being nice
ok i'm not being fully meet in this
thing ok I'm trying to be helpful if you
got professional people seriously
because sometimes a virtual machine
doesn't save you from this be careful
how you go to forums and like the dark
with have to take dark web
it's like everybody drink so you can go
there and you can search for of forum
that do credit card information credit
card trading offer your customers to
keep your customers are compromised or
may be compromised
another thing you can do is how many
devices that you have on your network
may be talking out to the internet and
properly
well there showed an yeah trust me the
only way this mask to be carrier the
difference from a zombie movie
ok because every one of those red dots
is actually a machine that is out on the
internet was a will be searchable
through show Dance all those dots
ok and that is actually a zombie
outbreak but you know more like a no
zombie robot army outbreak so scared
let's go a little bit more information
here's some people you've got 54 that
191 that I threw that one away setting
for too late i like 63 215 that thats if
you take that one
teen because there are 10 Bell actually
had like a few yards
they're like not only do we want to make
sure our stuff public on the internet
but we want to make sure that looks fast
plastic and they get people's attention
so they can see it so they're just a
bell oh my bad kitten
you can't sue me this is public
information alright let's drill down a
little bit more we're going to
Indianapolis here to level 3 55 hosting
LLC anybody from their pics you still
FYI just heads up you know just but also
look at this guy i like this one the
best because this was running 6969 that
175 228
no that's not the reason why I chose it
it's because of the fact it's running an
exchange server alligator that for 25
which is awesome
not too big everybody's got to have the
email right come on I'm not jerk you
have email but they're also has a
microsoft iis httpd running here
that's interesting if your eye is page
looks like that might be a warning sign
lobbying well okay part it might be a
beacon that people think hey happier
first that is true that recently just
haven't always think the positive side
it takes the mixture at least five
minutes
such a break-in it's like us so there
you go
it's like that you got that and once
again there's that thought in the back
of your head and this is the thought
that always irritates me
ok so we don't have to worry about that
who's actually going through and then
going searching showed in is that you
know find vulnerabilities and our
services that we may have misconfigured
they're walking out into the internet
this do take literally posted on sweater
if your platform research thingamajiggy
is on the internet and on his Twitter
feet you're having a bad day
that all there is to it so you don't
have the excuse to say it's not going to
be me but I want to leave with one more
thought there's the guy is a bike shop
in poughkeepsie there's a bike shop of
the kids in New York decided that he
wanted a website because you want
everybody to buy this bike because he
was the best bike shopping to kiss me I
like to keep it like taking too many
times so this bike shop in poughkeepsie
he decides to create his own website so
he got his own little desktop computer
and he put on his little web page i'm
sure it had animated gifts and
everything it was great geo city wonders
and you know what he did he had it
running on his on his server and a bike
shop it was beautiful looking for four
months so that's when the FBI SWAT team
broke into his a office and complicated
his server because that wonderful bike
shop and the kissing was a high-speed
internet line with a whole lot of hard
drive space and now serving out porn
illegal where's illegal movies all kinds
of really horrible horrible crap because
he was just a bike shop in the kitchen
who was going to attack him he's a
number on the internet you're an IP
address
you are a google search away from being
attacked
now not everybody can dedicate teen
people to do all these searches so if
you at the very least try to get a blue
team in a box try to find something that
can help you all to make the services of
looking like a bad guy and now I'm i
just didn't plug for mind it's like out
there are several other you can use that
can help you automate it searches that
can help you
I like burnt out of all these on the way
I like me threat the most because it
actually mimics an actual to exfiltrate
of data because we always talk about
worry about trying to protect themselves
trying to prove to build a wall like
it's gonna be huge would make you know
Russia pay for it it's like a like
firewall it's like so I rebuild that
it's like in there blocking and are
trying to make sure they're going to
keep everybody outside the walls aren't
working anymore it's because their
parents have been in so it's like are
you watching what's going out of your
network
are you monitoring who's coming in with
a valid permissions and what they're
doing once they're inside that's our
problem so you need to end what that
does is it mimics that kind of attack
someone exfiltrating data out of your
network and if all else fails at all
these things seem to be out of your
control and out of your means of being
able to get another google set up the
google news alerts to trust me Brian
Krebs to not be your intrusion detection
system okay that's a gift it's a it's
almost literally a 0 false positive but
it's a guaranteed that day so it's like
you do not want him to be your
internship negative great guy you
cheated full but built very cool person
it's like a Wookiee the push our
community I said that so another thing
you need to do is I start talking more
about defenses
these are some really awesome tips and
tricks and the birth to three I stole
straight from me bitch but when I feel
stuff at least I give you credit for it
so music has wouldn't want to talk wpad
who has a machine on their network under
domain called wpad hopefully the answers
know if you don't have a web proxy
server running that by that name but i
will tell you what every attackers names
of their machine is when they register
the domain their name is wpad because
when windows boxes cwp a baby on their
domain they go
automatic oh the WPA be here I have to
direct all my internet traffic through
this machine that's my web proxy now who
needs to happen they're giving it to you
so you need to make sure you do it no
route and stop wpad from being that kind
of thing every time someone does a
domain query is the wpad it all may
clear out to 127 00 at one unless you're
running ipv6 and we all know you're not
so it's like you do that
and also disable that vile seriously to
say what was running windows XP in here
don't don't raise your hand you will
make me cry okay you're not running
windows XP disabled netbios oh my gosh i
think the guys running that txt me fat
thanks it's like so--you got just the
neighborhood domain why it makes the
trap it makes internet run faster
trust me does that all the time someone
someday someone's gonna believe me
the next thing you can do in this one is
the most evil this cost zero dollars
zero dollars minimal effort and it is a
hundred percent 0 false positive to the
attacking someone has reached your
network it's amazing no blinky boxes are
involved in this create a domain admin
account called donate admin underscore
Kim put him put the password in the
description say password is password to
one of the extra secure here because you
know we're not gonna say or something
stupid
it's like a so password to disable
account November 2015 put that in the
description make sure that password that
you put in the description is the actual
password
seriously do that now this last this
next step
add some domain admins group seriously
added to the domain admins and you're
thinking Jason you are insane
it's like we're supposed to remember
kids but you're staring us right now
right right but guess what you get to do
right here
ask you that number four number four is
once again my you can't sue me Klaus
2-under login hours set to zero there
are three exclamation under behind that
for a reason
set it to zero login hours because you
know what that means the password the
user id never gets locked out the
attacker tries to log into the account
and it doesn't come back with a lockout
or password wrong or the account
disabled they just can't log into the
machine
but what does it do it sends you an
alert that someone just tried to use a
machine that account and there's a
demand curve right property manager and
what machine there on that will
compromise you just got an actual alert
that have reaches occurring in your
network with 0 false positives because
no one should be trying to be used that
account correct
so there you go zero dollars bureau
false positives
ah remember number for just you know
that again another thing is make a
public chair call it and we don't make
it a public share like in the root
directory
ok conceived after that's just human
nature okay Barry it down deep where
only like the fifth most evilest of apt
actors a nation-state hackers and delete
dark web criminals are going active or
bob from the county
it's like make sure it's not only one of
those folders okay that you have to
worry about and you type that folder and
you may get password audit 2015 and you
make some rights on that folder read
everyone right everyone that's totally a
rewritable share but then you create an
xml file make it at least four mags
looks legit because no one's going to
believe a password file 4 kilobyte sorry
just not going to happen and you make
about formats and you put everyone to
deny permissions on all of it as you
send an alert when I tried to open it
modify it copy it or do something with
it you get an alert and you now have a
zero loss positive alert that someone is
in places they're not supposed to be
because you have a policy that says you
should not be going through the network
unless you're going to authorize
resources
that's not an authorized resource so
once again you're finding a bad person
is doing from the batter you know just
Bob the county board going to network
shares he could be going to get your
pictures that he's trying to find on the
network shares that shouldn't be there
he should be looking ok sorry any Bob's
or people in accounting in the audience
so full credit for full credit
resistance from all from you explore
that was the talk on youtube I promise
didn't go to recast that's actually the
willing to his video so there's that but
i also created some other ones it's like
I could I didn't want to just go and do
the talking you go like me and Jason you
just gave with other people invite
awesome side it's more one that one that
I like to start off with and i did a
blog post somewhere that stupid you the
link or actually just didn't think about
it when I talk about the summary
mentality we like to make our network
very hard like the coconut right so I
guess I got hard drives and we're gonna
like no one's coming in but then once
you get inside it's all nice and mushy
it's like your networks would be like an
over should have layers
ok very hard steel you know very mean
layers to get through so either kids in
here could ever get this reference them
it's like though that's what you need to
create your network because you can't
have a network that is open
stop treating your internal network like
it's trusted it shouldn't be your
network interior should be segmented why
does your HR department need to
communicate via the network to your
developers why does your accounting
department need to compete communication
network to developers
why is your CEO and your CFO need to
communicate through the note you need to
talk to developers one thing but like
most excited over this is just getting
something like this people off on that
one
my bad so but he you know what I'm
saying you need two segments those
network there shouldn't be communication
between them they should be segmented a
submarine would it take the hit if it's
not immediately fatal like going
straight to the servers guess what you
can shut off that department
you can lock that compartment down and
the rest of the sub survive
I mean too bad about Bob in the
engineering but still I'm everybody else
goes everybody else is able to go
through and survived it
so it's like Bob's really 50 there Bob
the audiences like okay my bed so that
you can survive that and that's why your
network should be it should be
compartmentalised so if one gets hit
with ransomware it doesn't take out the
whole network it takes out that one
section because honestly the percentage
of unsegmented corporate network is too
darn high
you need to fix that I've really gotten
an engagement to do a pinch test to
accompany million-dollar company i walk
in the very first day and I tell them I
can't take your money
it's like you're not paying me for this
and you need to use the money we're
going to pay for me to pay for a network
guy to come in and create you a network
so i could try to contest it because
this is not I can't do anything because
you've already done all the damage to
yourself
literally the network with the 10 dot
000 and the web servers the email
servers on the same team that network as
a CEO at the production company as web
developers all this stuff all antenna if
you're here here's the fun part
ok here's this is what makes you cry
tonight up be guest Wi-Fi access that
network that had the name of the company
in the name of it
guest unencrypted same network
oh my gosh Nick start till just before
flipping off little material i really
had to stop and I was like I can't do
this it's like they're you you've
already done all the damage to yourself
you need to get a professional to come
in here who have never been accused of
being a professional so that you have
someone rework your network
those are still out there also code
names on your who his contact
information because some people do it
right like pizza hut com not trying to
play favorites or anything but peaceful
calm they do it properly they show you
what their proper who was information
making a generic like this third
seriously bank did up but also look over
here love people.com well i got the guys
name
I've got his email address and I've got
a dress so I mean I love peaches i'm
probably not going to classroom but
people can go after him because he's got
his name out there and maybe they don't
like PETA you know there's some Kentucky
Fried Chicken people around here that
seems to be like a little upset so it's
like you know it's like especially after
this talk right now they may be going
after that guy I'm you know they're not
because this Pizza Pizza Hut is but not
just I love pizza dot-com will be missed
so the next thing I merely and for the
record and I mean you can test this i'll
have another i did download + 1 x 1
pixel gift and put it in the middle
there before i put the arrows over it
okay
it's there put a 1 by 1 point pixel gift
on your front homepage have that gift
link to a page that does nothing but
send alerts it's been click and when it
sends the alert it gives you the user
agent string it gives you the operating
system to get you the IP address of the
other person or the unit or whatever
click on it because how many people are
actually going on a page and going by
what is the hidden link here maybe
something special i mean i did that was
on a job that was like I was bored okay
tonight but most are scanners like open
that and misto and like somebody with
are downloading the whole webpage
through w get so they can create a
phishing page for it and what does that
give you that gives you an alert that
something shady is going on that someone
is trying to do something especially
when you when you see open bags on your
website of lost trust me you're not
having a good day
it's like mr. was never there to serve
to see if you've got a deal that they're
looking for on groupon ok that's not
happening
it's like which leads us you know right
there shortly to use that number 3 user
agent string should also alert you and
you can stop them you have the means
your wedding / have the means to block
user agents from actually even
downloading the web content if they see
a user agent string name isto or open
bass denied not allowed on the site and
you're telling me like locating someone
could just rename disco and rename open
bass because you can modify the user
registry if you want to do
yes you could ok how many's doing that
how many criminals I'm gonna talk about
hacker not criminals
how many criminals are actually going
through and actually reading the man
pages to figure out how to do that i had
a friend of mine go to a CTF but he
destroyed half the network you know how
the invitations everybody's machine and
use root toor as user ID and password in
RM the mall because everyone in calculus
and no one case you
ID password no one changes default
because they're all to leave i guess
it's like a truffle your password has
1337 I've already owns you
okay cause that's just the way it
happens so if I changed and denied as
user agent strings
another thing is if you do business in
Paraguay then by all means you know let
paraguay traffic coming to your network
but if you don't do business in Paraguay
why are you long and connect your
network what you know is there anybody
here doing go the traffic or network
related activities with you
botswana you don't mind if I do a lot of
energy on any day now it's like I just
got like another eighty three dollars
but it's like up but yeah so if you're
not doing dude if you're not doing
traffic with those countries block the
country's at your firewall seriously
that actually stopped a lot of your spam
because a lot of these outside to send
you spam that that kept us that we can
tell management is gonna help with being
management but it also keeps the
attackers from even seeing your site
block them down by the ASM numbers a lot
of people started Apollo checkpoint all
the big hitters probably not cisco but
all the big hitters and firewall
technology and stuff you know actually
uses that if I can you can block by the
anything you can block the country sorry
thats good people here i'll bet i'd like
to send everybody if you haven't noticed
that it's like I'm very effective
evidence things so the next thing is a
trigger leads to your job listings go
from Canada should be familiar with this
guy and a firewall collect like taking
cisco something more like this
vintage also be familiar with technique
while also and very well-versed is going
to a firewall I literally compromise the
whole company because i was a defense
contractor people they wanted to give a
talk but for some reason they seem I
thought they would let me bring anything
in and I was actually really like you
get one whiskey drive that we've got the
sheet that we've just got and we're
going to why this you leave
you can plug into that machine not going
to help you don't need Wi-Fi is not
connected nothing would shut everything
down at the bios ok you can plug it in
we're gonna I mean lucky there was
though you know body scanning if you
don't mean it's like it and play was
just maybe just my word but I mean I've
waited like nervous and I proceeded to
show them the power points like this is
your idea systems you're using here's
your antivirus we're using here's your
office parks are using this is what you
code in this is the programs that you're
using and by the way this is where your
employees go to lunch probably and this
is where they go to the market after
giving a home and probably the laptop in
the car that I would steal their laptops
from any questions and I got mostly all
that information from their job at
applications they gave me the whole
outline of their network but the
equipment that I need to make sure my
antivirus antivirus this anti virus
virus virus and type r you know you are
paying us like that you have the the
thing that goes around the entire saying
you know it's like I know exactly which
one to work on because they tell me
which one they're using so you gotta be
careful about that
seriously people watch your feet that's
where the vision coming from buy up as
many as the domains that you can and I
did this in the 2012 tall so hopefully
this is actually a five-month will talk
about and I promise you those aren't
available anymore i don't know if
there's backe own but i know they're not
available anymore so even watch out for
that it's like you need to make sure you
own some of those domains and one of the
things you need to understand your
employees are going to click length
they're going to download attachment but
they do it before they do at least tell
them to do one more step of at least
going to buyers told if it's not
containing customer identifiable
internet information you can't sue me
for this
ok it's like if it doesn't have privacy
sensitive information they can upload
that on google because I mean let's make
the google probably has it right come on
ok they owned by shuttle they've already
got the day that you're trying to
so let them uploaded or it also has a
link girl Carla scanner on there too so
you can actually put the earlier in
there and have it scanned the Earl two
feet so there you go you can have their
just another little bit of defense that
you can put in there and and last but
certainly not least stop the bad coding
sequence sections are not security
vulnerabilities the flick of then the
last the last you know not leave going
to create teachable moments to your
employees and when I talk about
teachable moments you can do things in
your network by walking through the
thing looking at people keyboard for
passwords just letting the people
employees know that something's going on
I did it a couple years ago by taking my
Wi-Fi pineapple which I can manually
have here we're going to assume that
it's not on uh it's like and I would go
to these packing security conferences
and I would you know totally owned
everybody they're not up the kitchen
it's like all I do is just jacket there
that made them jacket my access point
and they showed a message saying this is
not the Wi-Fi access point you're
looking for and put that on there and
just a bring home because you know our
state's never been invited back anyway
this was at RFA 30,000 people the
biggest security conference where all
the people know that all the attackers
are at all the nature to all the all the
bigwigs are going there to get seven
minutes 42 people seven minutes 42
people i mean i could have done
wait longer to come on numbers lucky
number seven and the answer for
everything i had to use that one
so that's why you the screenshot that it
could've been worse but we're talking
about teachable moment and I need to
create a teachable moment for you so
that everybody gone to the websites you
have this wonderful website
the answer is no the answer is no you
have not gone to this website and I
don't blame you because that's not their
website this is their website can tell
the difference between of obvious ohon I
actually changed it to make it a little
more obvious that
next one should clear it up there 0 a
little bit clearer everybody been there
this match dot net cgi has been done
email / besides indeed great website
ever notice the problem with everybody
with everybody that you work with notice
the problem especially on a mobile
device or in the email by the way it's
the dot I actually own cgi dash been got
email because who knew email is a domain
name people read left to right mostly
Western countries but they even on the
internet they read that way computers
read right from left so I just create
something of any IP address or
conference or whether or bank that I
want to and then just put cgi dash
pindot email and I'm golden there and
indeed gluing that there is nothing
malicious not like i said distance I
asked that's a clickable link you can
actually go that high right now all
you'll see is that llama this in all its
glory
it's like because that's all I put on
there is no matter where anything on it
but don't have much like to that being
said so now we leave on a happy note and
basically these are all people that I
did the right thing your employees are
not your liability there your assets if
you train them properly and give them
the understanding that their part of
your security team
it's not stupid user click on the link
it's not stupid user went to a website
it was stupid information security
didn't properly train your employees
when all your employees realize that
part of the job responsibility for them
to have a job to pay check is to also be
security conscious guess what will be
security conscious because it's part of
their paycheck and how they became close
their children teach them that and they
will be good employees as well
do that don't like I'm done
thank you any questions
yes like that business was an act
provided i will you show them that it's
productive that you show them responding
to a breach cost more money than them
just calling an extension and saying hey
I saw something suspicious
it's like it takes a very little effort
for an employee to call an extension
that you've set out to say hey this is
suspicious i need someone to act on it
it's like do a lot of your companies do
they have an extension that they're all
the employees know about they can call
if they see someone to catch you in the
building like me or they see us get
emails investment if they don't then
you're not empowering your employees to
be part of the security thing but if you
teach them on day one that part of the
responsibility for them to do the job
security will be security minded because
they want to do what are the job and if
you do like little exercises if you do
things that make them involved in it
they'll be part of it and that's more
cost effective because they're more
attention to their work for more
attention to what they're doing and that
makes better employees and that's how
you fell to your upper management
yes
Bobby right and they care about
information but that's hard
it's like what you do is it starts with
the generic IT support services they do
have you helped you hope they get that
and you make sure they get trained is
that you make sure you ask the right
questions and what basically it started
out with you start getting attention
target was one of the best things to
happen to everybody but target because
it helps making it public
it showed other corporations that they
have to start taking security seriously
it's like it does i call it creating
situational awareness
it's like you got to create situational
awareness with these CEOs with these
executives of these businesses and one
of the things that I'm doing and this is
only a small part is not a big part but
it's a small part is I've been doing a
lot more conferences at the US Chamber
of Commerce it's like I've done a beer
Association i'm doing next week I'm
going to a medical conference and I'm
scaring the bejesus out of them and i'm
talking about them i did a conference in
vegas the hotel bar association and the
guy came up to me afterwards I dude i
was sitting next to my video lifetime
you're halfway finished he was calling
the the head of IT and asking them
questions about our security posture so
it's like you educate we have to stop
speaking
here it's like this is that i love
talking at the site it's like I love
going to the security conferences and
come and when he said it's like besides
is a place for that didn't go together
that's not actually true i don't want to
correct them with that but that's not
really true besides our amazing places
for you to get information and connect
with the talkers are secondary
it's like this is a place where you are
knowing that the people that you're
seeing and sitting next to our most
likely from the spain count that you're
in or the same field or the thing
company you have the associated work
with it's a perfect opportunity than
that
work it's a perfectly timed for people
that are trying and wondering about
security that aren't insecurity to come
here and go and say well I need to start
worrying about security about know where
to start
maybe I should go to this without
security conference and find out about
it it's like that's what the b-side
before that's why they're so vital
it's like I'll never speaking to be side
san francisco or Las Vegas I never will
it's like but i will go to as many local
beat of the camp because that's where
the messages because getting out to it's
like and that's why I'm here today so
it's like you need to do that you need
to connect with your local businesses
there's InfraGard there's a god that
Congress you know plug it's like there's
a 2600 meeting if you're desperate
it's like you're all these uh sergeant
like dunkin donuts and other it's like
I'm having issues at home with 24 people
so it's like so so you've got these
other groups that you could meet locally
and talk to help educate them so it's
like and the only thing that's going to
help the small businesses that don't
have a security department is seeing
bigger people have problems with
security
it's like them to start thinking about
it yes the imagio show comes out May
second or maybe I didn't say that guy
doll by the way not done his life but I
will hug you later
it's called it's called breakthrough
it's the series breakthrough Ron Howard
series of breakthrough on that geo it's
the episode i think to called fiber
terror because that sounds scary and uh
which is really hilarious so it didn't
reach its effect but uh yeah it's called
our job actually I'm actually flying out
i will be here till 1230 or one and then
I'm playing at the top like that's
what's actually do a panel on it
tomorrow and I'm an awkward hug no
deGrasse Tyson never directly use mine
so but yeah so that's their thank you
yeah that's what it is basically and
what I hope it comes out is once again
it's something to educate people that
aren't into information security about
some of the dangers it's like so
hopefully that they get that that point
yes any other questions
[Applause]