and we're so thankful to have you here
with the United sold man effects
weaponizing nanotech so can we find
Carrie now I will have to talk with a
scary
yes sorry i'm a fatty you get over there
are many of you hug me up a good con
well because ok so I'll apologize
upfront for this one
why isn't working what do they do you
need for out did I break it so good on
ya just gone the so I did and then I
take one of the Gurkha and I've got a
whole bunch of research instrument but
unfortunately the powers-that-be I
lawyers figured out what I was about to
talk about and as of what they are today
saturday as of Tuesday some of the new
stuff I've done not allowed to talk
about but the old stuff because agent
bank we recorded it last year and put up
with me into that there's nothing there
but it apart from yell at me which is
what we normally do anyway so all the
new shit that I can't talk about which
involves hacking even more human even
more stuff and being able to take over
some of the blood various stuff I
definitely can't say anything about the
fact that we've done blood barrier work
but also no let's talk about all the
cardiovascular system you can now hack
that so I definitely didn't say that
allegedly we recorded excellent evidence
item number church now you get I don't
care really
all right how's everybody doing alright
so we have all the fun
I'm so possibly the upside things that i
did i'm allowed to do with the Calvillo
guys is I get to throw the crystal ball
out I'm gonna walk in this is going to
rattle I'll apologize now I get to throw
the crystal ball that a little bit
further so I'm not necessarily looking
at exploits I'm not necessarily looking
at the stuff is coming down the line in
the next couple years I will be
perfectly honest for the most part I've
kind of given up with mainstream
humanity cuz i got asked about passwords
the other day and I said I've given up
with everybody skynet was right and this
will explain some of this
so before we start there's always be met
there's no they're both doing it
who do you can't blame the match-up
unplugged the third go here if all those
failed the sisters hang up
yes the mandatory FBI's like needless to
say we are going to talk about bodies
therefore taking notes and off the
record and bugger up nice and simple
standard housekeeping slides obviously
huge shout-out to our to host the very
front here please
very much at the end of that make sure
you give them hugs and thanks for all of
us being here if you were at the IOT
cookie we had cookies kindness and you
could have sold on us
Chester and a couple other guys for
helping our fates are helping out set it
up
ask questions we're going to go through
some fun stuff here we're definitely
going through some stuff that is not of
the normal in the hacking their side of
things and you can see the last 100 that
so I'm gonna talk we're gonna have a
little bit of fun with this one we are
going to talk about millions eyelids are
going to talk about millions of several
years ago we stood up into the whole
bunch of other talks and we want to
really talk about those kind of millions
for the backstory of several years ago
to the whole bunch of torture series of
folks in like by land by sea by air and
as well pointed out we hacked airplanes
we had cars we have to pretty much
anything that didn't move much faster
than us we had the Mars rover got yelled
at for that one
we managed to get it to play freddie
mercury plays god save the queen for
about 30 seconds until they figure out
what the hell we were doing we go yelled
out on that one
iot all sorts of interesting fun stuff
we got the village going off on that one
so now we decided to go after millions
and have some fun with this one cause
obviously when you decide you want to go
after millions and you decide you want
to hack humans
there's a little bit of trial and error
that involved if Hollywood has anything
to be believed by this is where trial
and never really ends up this is the
whole Skynet side the things which quite
honestly if you look at where technology
is taking us there's an interesting
barrier that I think we've actually not
just approach but we've hit pretty well
so head on a full steam when we are
starting to blur the lines between what
we consider reality and when the
machines consider reality that is not a
topic today but it is actually
interesting topic with anybody really
really want to have to go down that
route and obviously we've chosen our
friendly cyborg friends with us in which
it always brings up the same question
for those of you who watched that movie
which bloody timeline that we actually
now on in that movie
for those of you remember the old stuff
yeah we have made a lot of mistakes in
some cases but we come down to a couple
of simple things when we're looking at
hacking humans
there's a few different ways we can do
we can take the mainstream roof which is
endoskeleton and exoskeleton suits
we take our friend mr. Wolverine as a
wonderful idea
looks cool when the claws come out and
to some degree you pretty well
bulletproof but I'd hate to be trying to
do it my damn flies when those cores are
out as well it ain't gonna be pretty
if you take the excess go on that stuff
nice fun and actually from a military
standpoint they're actually doing some
pretty amazing development on those
things but downside is that cumbersome
of the moment they're a pain in the ass
to get on and when they go rank all the
batteries run out or hell breaks loose
so what other options do we have when we
talk about when we talk about hacking
humans slot
obviously he could reanimate the dead if
we go back to our friends at hollywood
and we go back to some of the other
stuff in history and it's great gets a
little bit messy and involves driving
not much but you can still body parts
are you get yelled at for doing that
kind of stuff is this endoskeleton stuff
obviously superpowers exoskeleton stuff
bit of a challenge on that one as well
any time soon as I feel like I'm going
to fall through this is the second
department of human and tech we
obviously now have and have been for a
few years of the stage where we've been
looking at the wearable technology you
guys have heard about hacking incident
pops you guys have heard about the
capability to stop and mess around with
heart rate monitors for those of you
haven't do a whole bunch of research on
healthcare facilities and have their
actually having to deal with near field
communications wireless communication
the various other things that are out
there there's so many interesting stuff
that's getting built in one of the
things we were talking about in the
village earlier on is the caps that
they've now built that are able to
actually do analysis on external brain
wave so now talk about for reading and
talking about the ability to read
thoughts it's coming at the moment it's
still millimetric away from the actual
head but it's getting to a stage where
the further and further we go we're
actually able to measure more
effectively and interpret that into
something useful some interesting stuff
on that one
so we started taking a look at what we
could do to hack the humans and
thankfully we took a good look at
wikipedia and figured out what the hell
the human body was made off we noticed
heart way down here the second one down
we've got carbon carbon is a very very
very useful elements when it comes to
building technology we don't know it
because we use them to carry around in
our pockets but if you start breaking it
down to the molecular level you can do
some interesting stuff with it and then
if we take the logic flow about what
we've done with building exoskeletons
endoskeleton to reanimating humans all
that kind of stuff we really want to say
okay how do we actually improve the
human that we are we talked about
putting tacky inside of us will why not
actually build that text as part of us
just what we looked at human rating
percent carbon carbon nanotubes
transistors have been around about 98 in
essence if you can control or manage or
inject or influence those we are nothing
more than a walking computer and then if
we actually turn around and look at
human nature itself we get hacked on a
daily basis think about germs think
about catching a cult think about
getting something worse than cold it's
nothing more than the body basically
being attacked
Justin and I were talking about a way to
discuss about breaking the human body
down to a network yourself your blood to
flow the network architecture the fact
that really we have three firewalls in
the body the barrier between the brain
and the blood system the barrier between
our breathing and the blood system the
barrier between our stomachs and those
systems those are nothing more than
firewalls if you really think about it
but we all managed to get jobs we
managed to get snuffly notice so how the
hell did those get in and how can we use
that to the best of our ability
we started taking a look at virus that's
fairly effectively the ribonuclease
asset the ones that are actually sat
those are the really cool ones they get
used very effectively when we talk about
vaccines you look at antivirus for all
its ineffectiveness it is nothing more
in some ways of accessing you take a
look at humans and the arguably
effectiveness or lack thereof actions
occasionally and they all they've done
is they've taken something nasty
they made it relatively tame and then
they injected back in simplified down a
bit so can we do the same thing and if
we do all your books belong to us
so how do we do this let's use
nanotechnology let's take a look at the
industry that's been at this for the
last 10 15 almost 20 years and then
we'll break it down in this one what is
a nano architecture how do you build
these down things is this science
fiction is this reality how do we
deployed them it's all real building
this damn stuff but how do we actually
get to do something and then how the
hell do we communicate with its at the
molecular level
you can't exactly jacket into an rj45 as
much as we'd like to be able to try to
sometimes
alright you gotta have this is my 10
seconds actually have a drink of water
for those of you by the way they want to
take pictures or want to copy the slides
hit me up afterwards I'll make sure what
Adrian video in the damn thing for
crying out loud so you can always get it
from him but if you want a copy of the
slides to me up afterwards i'm pretty
sure i can get a civilized version of
these so what's up with a simple
questions what is it have held you build
it how do you program the body things
and you control them and then obviously
how the hell'd you deploy them so
nanotechnology how do you have any of
you guys are familiar with nanotech and
nano architecture
alright so we'll have a quick way and
beyond this gun thing I'm keeping it
high level so one nanometer in diameter
by the size of a couple of atoms give or
take a little bit of strength really
strong bloody things hardness
ridiculously hard thermal properties
pretty amazing make it hot does one
thing make it gold can do something
completely different influence it with
other kinds of electromagnetic fields
and you can get it to do some pretty
amazing things which will go through
which is why we're looking at using them
the nice thing about them at this day
and age is we can make them into complex
systems often my screenshots of it
yes I got some slides in the second
thinking common energy growing carbon
nanotubes so the nice thing about these
days is that you Frank's pointed isn't
just a single molecule of a carbon you
know a nano 10 basically a carbon
molecules you can grow them into tubes
which if you look at this top left-hand
side is a carbon nanotube farm now back
in 98 all the way to the early 2000
building these things with a very
complex and pretty bloody expensive and
as you can imagine their pain in the ass
to try and managing to deal with well
for the last 15 plus years of making it
easier cheaper and simpler if you look
at the size and the scale of those damn
things
they're pretty smart and if you look at
the architecture is that what you can
build with them you can do some pretty
interesting things
let's separate fact from fiction on this
one which is kind of a fun thing to do
the nanobots in this realm but not the
realm of science fiction and what was
that GI joe whether know but I'm in the
eighth paris which is never a bad thing
to do
yeah will mail a few of these big hero
five and the carbon-based nanotech here
we're not quite there yet had the same
thing with honey i shrunk the bloody
kids yeah well that doesn't happen quite
the same way either transcendence was an
interesting one
we're actually what 5-10 years away from
being out the upload consciousness i
think last I saw it was 20 years because
of the advances and technet were about
five to 10 years away from being out
there potentially upload consciousness
that really makes life interesting and
I'm looking forward to that would be
perfect on this number 1 i'm getting old
and gray and number two I am so looking
forward to screwing around with people
and we talked about ghosts in the
machine at that point in time so how do
we build it modified DNA structures on
this one's for the whole concept here is
you can build a carbon nanotube farm
then you've got to actually implement
them then you've got to actually
architect and build them onto something
with a couple of structures and a few
more slides type what you can do and
what they're actually doing now is
they're adhering are adhesively adhering
whichever you want to look at making the
two molecules attract of carbon an
attaching carbon nano architecture and
those nasty things like avian bird flu
so now I'm able to actually have a
transport mechanism avian bird flu is
can break the blood barrier and I've
also got carbon architecture which can
do similar things on the certain
circumstances
the bacterial base so i can basically
use the microorganisms that we allow
into our body now as nothing more than
my platform to move my architecture in a
nap same thing we do on a network when
we piggyback off of something we're
doing nothing more than using its
transport and it's authentication into a
computer or a server to bring our
payload exactly the same concept and
then we have the Assembly's so you can't
exactly as I said jacket rj45 into one
of these things to actually program and
tell you what to do but you can do some
other fun things you can actually embed
programming in to the carbon machines
we've got some interesting program
interesting slides in the next couple of
slides on this one
how far along are we this was actually
taken under a basically set epfl
laboratory took of these images from
carbon machines carbon nanotubes
machines so now you're teaching the
machines have to do basic math had to do
basic english had to do basic I don't
know
assembler language you're also teaching
the machines from our standpoint to take
what we consider a language and accepted
in an electromagnetic frequency so how
do i go from our world into the
molecular world I embed it in a wave it
gets absorbed it gets accepted and now
he's managed to program something
depending upon how you build your carbon
nanotubes machines depends upon what you
can do with them they can be metallic
they can be attractive they can be
semiconductors if you do a narrowband in
other words a long thin tube of
architecture and you apply a single
layer behind it you can actually have it
swim with the bloodstream so now i have
a transport mechanism
and the other thing that's useful if
you're talking about the back in the
year two thousand give or take a bed
that $1,500 a gram for these things they
were both expensive and a royal pain in
the ass to manufacture he files forward
to now you're looking at a couple of
dollars per gram part of the reason for
this has got nothing to do with the
healthcare medical side of the world
it's the fact that they're bonding this
stuff into all sorts of other
applications will cover those are the
end one of the biggest ones that we tend
to find more in the commercial world is
in jet engines the reason we have much
more effective and much more efficient
yet engines are those blades can be made
lighter thinner smaller and much more
efficient by the application of carbon
nanotubes at a molecular level you can
now smooth out the metallurgy to make it
more efficient so we're making more of
these things and now we started put them
into the healthcare field already took
my drink was talking so we'll move on
so what do we do about them how do we
encode them how do we actually do
something on these ones world you do you
research no different than we do when we
look at hacking anything else the IOT
village the hardware hacking side of
things all of the lock picking guys and
everything else we do our research we
did our schooling and we figure out how
to get in this case we pick on either
geez nanotechnologies or some of the DNA
computing companies the nice thing about
DNA as it says on that it has an amazing
storage capacity and you can do both
molecular level and component level so
you can blend the human stuff that we
need to get through those blood barriers
and the electronics that we want to
deliver our payloads
but we want to be able to do is taking
the easy route to be perfectly honest
rather than actually having to build an
application will wait for the healthcare
mentality to build it for us and then
we'll just piggyback off of into what we
can do which is where we look at hacking
the code and there's a couple of
different capable logs on and you guys
can do the research on this what there's
a language very long would actually goes
through and describes the circuit
function so we are down at circuit level
with memory level and below because
these things are still relatively simple
you can't exactly drop some c code into
and go but let's see what it can do that
shit ain't gonna work or you can do is
add a component level instruct each one
of the nanotubes to be what you needed
to be
are you a capacitor are you a tractor
are you the swimmer are you the guy with
the payload I you the guy that's
actually going to destroy all sorts of
other things
another nice thing about it we have a
couple of screenshots and that's what is
it that we can actually put a
constraining file in place that we can
do all the coding in the program that we
need in a language in the way that we
understand some screenshots on it
cello actually has a really really nice
way of laying this at again you are
interested let's do a little research on
its kind of fun
set of algorithms verilog text color
designs or circuit rows of the circuit
and then go figure out how to actually
get it into something i love this one
so here it is this is where we take
standard code but on the left-hand side
we've built specific code that says hi
it parses it it synthesizes it it
assigns the gate flow and the gate logic
and then it basically dropped it into
the inputs in a frequency range that the
carbon nanotubes can understand so we've
taken a program on the left-hand side
that says high carbon nano architecture
attach yourself to eco lights pretty
much a simple piece of code is that you
deploy the code you have cello and a
couple of other programs encoded do it
as a frequency range and then you're
able to actually replay that against in
this case was an inside of body but it
was against basically a test subjects i
will call it for that one now mostly
built the code deployed it into my test
you but my petri dish but actually go to
deploy the stupid thing this would be
the nice way to do it if it was that
simple
unfortunately it isn't
however that is relatively simple those
a nanobot top left-hand screen those are
actual carbon nanotubes architectures
swimming
they've been given a set of instructions
to swim up the bloodstream and that's
exactly what they're doing as you can
tell the tale that little flappy thing
at the end of it is acting as we do in
the natural world as basically an
oscillation machine so you've given it a
set of frequencies to oscillate at and
it moves up the tunnel kind of fun
the bottom right-hand side we gave it a
set of instructions as well
simple instructions simple basically
encoding the difference between certain
chemicals so if you look at what they're
doing in the nice side of the world they
are sending certain nano in certain
instances actually sending these after
cancer cells which is freaking amazing
as far as I'm concerned the ability to
actually pinpoint so no longer do you
have to basically dose yourself up like
an atomic bomb every five minutes you
can send these little critters in and
you can do a much more pinpoint type of
attack against individual self now
that's great if you leave the
programming that way but then you bring
somebody like me and it goes to our
let's go to something other than cancer
cells will have that conversation in a
minute
let's get rid of some of the myths
although some of these of no change
courtesy of some more research I've done
you're in King tainted water won't
actually make you infected with nanobots
just yet which is a good thing because
they've got nanotechnology in to the
food system these days in a lot of the
packaging and a lot of aligning not
necessarily these gonna bottles but the
types of bottles that we use when we
drink when asked wonderful that in it
can't yet get through the guts and the
amazing amount of weird and wonderful
things that we have in our stomachs
thankfully that's acting the store
fairly decent barrier breathing
impregnated air supply at the time of
writing that was fairly true now as you
breathe in
obviously overnight broccoli looking
things inside the lungs at some really
really nice filtration systems
unfortunately the moment it's looking
like we can bring some of that
we're not shrinking shit down we're
actually building it up that's a huge
difference on this one the whole you
know Hollywood honey i shrunk the kids
unable to basically shrink a computer
down you know we're going back to the
very very basics and we're building
systems up and we're building them up a
little differently and then from a
timeline standpoint we're a long way to
go absolutely but the fact that we've
got swimming things the fact that we can
bind them to all sorts of interesting
technology and the fact that we can
actually give them some fairly basic
instructions
we're actually getting that some funny
cool stuff that's coming in the next
five to ten years so when we actually
gonna go after well and take on
healthcare because they're always fun to
break you look at the positive side the
ability to deliver targeted drugs
efficiently and effectively focused
therapies the ability to actually do
much more effective diagnostics the
ability to ask you all of basically and
combined 19 microbial techniques there's
some pretty awesome stuff and now the
dental boys have gotten hold of it as
well to look at any kind of
reconstructive any kind of preventive
that's some pretty awesome stuff looking
you're doing on this one all right pause
for a second I get to drink and get
spanked Adrian actually for recording
all of us
Thank You mr. Adrian
okay sometimes quick but so now we get
nasty
because the catch the airplane mode
enabled I have no girl time at least now
we get nasty
this is a hexene metric ring as it says
it has six stations so for those of you
that are used how many of you guys are
used to riding viruses and trojans and
that want to admit it in public for hold
on to that for a second
typically when you have that you have a
set of building blocks no different than
if you're going to run a payload you
have a payload that goes in and says am
I breaking windows or linux you have a
payload that says how am I getting in
you have a piece of code that says who
the hell am i talking to when I got to
something interesting and you have a
piece of it going how the hell am I
going to communicate when I find what I
want no different than when you're
building this we have our keys the
receptacle binders in other words when I
inject this into a human is he going to
accept it or is it going to reject it
those are nothing more than my crypt
okies that's basically my certificate
does the body allow it or not in this
case it does we have our transport and
RNA bacteria in this case I'm tournament
for the heavy work and it was something
that you like avian bird flu that we
took we have our bypass tools so the
body is actually pretty effective
sometimes the immune system goes moon am
I going to allow you in
in this case the right design in there
goes oh absolutely i'm perfectly nice i
am i'm wonder fault no different than if
you're doing an attack against the
company you use port 80 to go in band
and outbound nobody filters on port a
because everybody's to get to the
internet from the office
this is exactly the same concept we have
the reporting tool it's no good dropping
something molecular in if you don't know
what the hell's going on when you drop
the stupid thing in so it has the
ability to communicate externally again
in this case using frequency modulation
we have our payload which is the drugs
and then we basically have the decoys
which is the end of Muslim disruptors so
again the body even though the bodies
allowed you in past the firewall in the
ideas in the IPS to some degree the body
still keeping track of you you are a
foreign object inside the body so
occasionally you have to have decoys in
the world I work too
we call it deception in the world of
this work that we call it to its a nice
end of some disrupter so are they goes
both ways so if i put this all in
English we took bird flu we banded to
matter we banded to multiple magnitude
we told the body that don't worry it's
perfectly acceptable no problem just let
it it will be perfectly happy in this
case was injected we obviously have the
propulsion systems we have the ability
to track where it's going
we've also got the decoys so that they
can escape where the hell needs to go
and then the case of being something
nice
we have a drug to deliver to a cancer
cell kind of nice kind of altruistic
kind of a wonderful thing to do but if
you're somebody like us occasionally go
hey if i change the frequency and I
change the frequency modulation which
means i can adjust the programming i can
send it to basically go off the red
blood cells instead so I kill all of
your red blood cells in your body nice
little things this way outside of that
it's just so hard to do it
the downside of it is the technology to
do this cost about a hundred dollars and
most of it was sitting on that table and
the IOT space that's all it takes to
encode the body
this is a set that was put together back
in 2013 we actually replicated need some
other stuff this is molecular level
communication so this isn't wireless
isn't there feel this isn't anything
else
this is basically communicating in this
case using smell molecules
so the molecular level you're able to in
code if you really want to be blunt
about you can cook whatever the hell you
want to smell your encoding molecules
that can be ingested we can be put into
the system for about a hundred bucks
plus the two pieces of software and a
nice frequency modulator what do we do
about it
well do some research if you guys are
interested in this stuff again this is
kind of crystal bullish because with 5
10 years that for some of this stuff but
some of it as you can see we've got some
fun we're doing already researched the
Institute's your home to looking on this
one
take a look at the communication forms
you know these days we're still focused
on what 802 11 ABC N&P now is not i
think i was there any other letters of
the alphabet of mist geo god help us
figure out your an end
did I say in all right do you write look
at the industries that we've done and
then start taking a look at the
molecular level there's some interesting
discussions going on about you know
where I tea and we're IT security is
going and there's always the spaces and
there's always the take that we do this
still requires that nice rack of
equipment but at some point I'm that
nice track of equipment is going to
change and we're getting down to the
molecular level which is where we start
to see changes as humans do some
research on that's a fun little field to
mess with obviously have some fun of
Jesus expensive i do on a regular basis
i have a nice little stack of season two
sisters from the nanotech and food and
agriculture so this is the list of where
agriculture food and supplements are
going or have gone so again this is not
the stuff of science fiction
this is the stuff of science fact the
ability to basically in agriculture
instead of spring the living heck out of
the land to deploy at a molecular level
to adjust
the code inside the plant so this is no
different than our wonderful friends of
Monsanto and others do at that level now
we don't know how wonderfully we feel
towards those guys you think of the shit
they're going to do with this
not that I'm advocating to burn the
building down but I'm about one step
away from it the food-processing milk in
its normal natural form should not be
able to sit in the fridge for several
weeks vegetables should not be able to
sit out there for several weeks without
rocking we're going to the stage now we
start adjusting this is the molecular
level the most colossal bloody 12 months
for trying out let alone the fact that
the packaging that has it has this
molecular architecture and so is also
have interesting stuff here not sure I
like much of it and then the supplements
there's some positive stuff to that the
ability to actually ingest something
that is much more targeted honestly
research most of the stuff that was done
here was done independently i have
worked with a number of the Institute's
and a number of the basically facilities
as we've gone through this to go hey
have you thought about this and they
went oh shit we didn't think about that
help more and more of these guys
actually figure out what the hell we're
doing easy enough to do it
how we doing timewise couple minutes
oh awesome cook gate so from the
standpoint of what can we do
obviously if you guys are interested in
this start communicating start
researching start putting your own
papers together and start getting up on
stage and saying here's what i'm working
on at the moment take a different tact
go mess around with the AG industry go
mr. and the food industry and you're not
fine with that police driving me nuts
thank you what does it mean from a human
standpoint
well if those goes well it's great
there's a whole bunch of research into
Alzheimer's there's a whole bunch of
research into all sorts of other
biomechanical issues that we as humans
managed to suffer and this should help
it doesn't go quite so well it's gonna
be a bit of a mess technology lets face
it hasn't exactly had an easy start in
many different disciplines IOT being the
latest victim shall we say what I like
about it very much so is that IT itself
has definitely managing to trust the
domains
I mean it started off as it was just the
computer guys and then we started
building it into all sorts of other man
has been built into science is very very
effectively it's been used by chemistry
and the biologist but now we're building
the architecture directly into their
sciences confirm stuff that what we do
communicate effective communication
collaborate is also another good thing
i'll be honest i'm not the best of
collaborating as some people are very
happy to attest it i am the person that
will regularly throw the Molotov
cocktail or somebody's are not overly
happy with rather than sit down in the
border
sometimes it works sometimes it doesn't
but i would actively tell you to
communicate on this stuff and then look
at any alternatives you know all I've
done here really is basically sit down
and say hey this is where some of the
challenges are some great stuff coming
up with some challenges great find a fix
for it do you build some kind of
vaccination architecture do you think
some kind of deceptive taken it and then
how do we address it how do we actually
communicate with more and more the
research facilities again get engaged
how do we educate them how do we work
with them
what do we detect the human see what
happens because obviously that is always
the fun part so this is actually a
construct that somebody is putting
together
so how to actually build the nanotube
architectures one of the interesting
stuff there looking doing is gallstones
and various other things so you build
these things into a swarm technology you
have ones which guide you have 12 which
manipulate and then there are ones that
building that have frequency generators
so as it gets closer to its target is
able to generate the frequency to break
up the damn course done some pretty cool
stuff but again if it can break a girl
standing and all sorts of other nasty
nefarious things in the body if somebody
like me gets all the goat om in its
crate I mean the outside of this stuff
is phenomenal but my biggest challenge
is like a lot of other stuff that we
seem to have done in the last what 20 30
years we've been messing extensively
with computers is we tend it feels again
like with charging in blindly we're
looking at the positive stuff which
isn't a problem at all but were tending
to forget all the negative side not
necessarily negative side of it all of
the yes there we go perfect we're
putting all the unintended yeah which is
no different we've done with so much
other stuff i mean the ability for
insulin pumps to be carried around by
people is amazing but then the fact that
we leave the bloody things wide-ass open
to attack is a huge unintended
consequence until somebody goes hey look
what I can do something to get drunk not
pretty and it'd be nice not to have that
happen in this instance because the best
case is pretty freaking awesome the
ability to target the ability to measure
of blood clots I mean you look at how
many patients come out of surgery will
then suffer or have stuff of blocks that
were so that I took a nasty for was in
Barcelona up last week didn't ask me for
the last loner managed to knock myself
out for about 30 seconds it was quite
fun came to know some nice men in orange
poking and prodding me to make sure I
still focusing around I'm not been told
I'm not advance the runners and which
are going on up here so it'll be nice as
we get what with one of these things and
no good level good but at the same time
knowing me i'd be sitting there going
hey what can I do with my son will
yeah it ain't pretty legislated it's me
power sight removal you're learning all
sorts of crazy shit that's positive and
then you also take another step further
you know how many of us think in 10 or
15 years time when your telephone rings
that you will actually pick it up with a
hand answer it or what stage are we
going to be at where it's either
embedded tech all the tech has got to
search a stage where it's on the lens
inside our I or it's a direct neural
feet amazing capabilities especially if
we start looking at the ability to build
it out this way but the consequences of
a room full of us going hey look at what
we can do this shit is slightly
terrifying
so how do we get ahead of this game how
do we educate and how do we get people
to communicate effectively honest work
because the worst-case scenario gets
really freaking nasty now there are some
arguments as to our current state of
government as to whether something like
this would be an effective change in
policy shall we say and the fact that we
all be here we all sit behind skips I
mean those of us that have worked in
those kind of facilities like our nice
big not necessarily metal box what we
use some nice big metal box all the
sugar left outside the human walks
inside for now the human is nothing more
than a walking USB stick at the end of
the day we've done research with
cockroaches we can actually store 50 gig
on a cockroach freaking amazing and you
build me a little communication into a
cockroach and deployed into a data
center
good luck securing that ship last time
we tried that we walked out with 450
gigs worth of data so this is no longer
science fiction
yeah we did we actually dropped 20 and
we got 450 gigs with the data items like
whoa
the biggest challenge for me and this is
not a us-centric thing this is a very
much a global centric thing is we will
weaponize this we are amazingly good at
shooting ourselves in the foot as modest
as society but as a human race which is
why part of me is given up on humans to
be perfectly honest because we're going
to look at what we can do with this and
then we'll lose control of it because
it's not like a nuclear weapon which we
also lose those things this shit small
you know there's lots of them fired and
Harold headless there's lots of them
that feed on human hair
we can't find nuclear weapons had the
hell are we going to keep control of
this ship now the interesting is this
technology games and upper hand
there's an interesting argument to say
it's not about think I'd love to have
those debates those are fun debates to
have and then we start taking a look at
how r evolution goes where do we go do
we now go more to a carbon-based
architecture interesting stuff on that
one and then we start taking a look at
okay how do we influence these things
these days we influence those
temperature we influence through
electromagnetic pulse we influence to
near field communication so the next
time you walk through a tsa bloody rate
of not made us at TSA flip in there nice
little um detector you screw yourself
over because you've got carbon
architectures and so you not a pretty
sight to be yeah no shit i love my
little pat down just so cute i still
have my TSA pre but every single time
almost every single time i go through
this together like I you've been
randomly selected are ya see them for
who they are fun and kills I've done
that a few times there are some very
confused looks on their faces lesson
shark concluding thoughts there is this
unfortunately potential is is really you
know III my frustration is we sat down
Jesse and I sat down I had no early
mid-2001 hey you can hack agriculture
and by the way here's what we can do
with cars
ten years later hacking causes a thing
I'm like great one voice we already did
the same thing with planes is that
spread all over the google for crying
out loud but before we got spread over
google we spent five to six years trying
to talk to the industry like many of us
in the industry how frustrated we get
that our own sphere of influence doesn't
necessarily always listen to what we're
trying to do them until the last moment
or until she's gone too late
that's fine when a firewall fails but
when you've got shit like this embedded
inside of us
I'm not sure I want to get to a point of
failure before we actually decided to do
something about it because quite
honestly I'd rather avoid this
I don't mind if this happens among the
record for this one so we do have the
opportunity to influence change as they
race and as a society we have the
capability to change we've done some
amazing freaking things we also have
done some dumb as a box of rocks shit
too
we as the guy standing up on stage also
have the ability to teach and to help
educate them to help get people to think
better than we can afford a better way
of putting it
my job is nothing more to make sure that
the people the rugrats of the younger
than me come up better faster and
smarter than i do and the rest of us
should feel the same way
this isn't protecting the fucking
information is giving it to somebody
else so that when I troch somebody else
can carry on the fight it's as simple as
that
or as it says on the last point we do
have the ability in the time to prepare
for this
shop closing it's like we do have a hell
of a community can be a little
disjointed at times a little challenging
but you use it and the reason I say that
is I run into so many individuals ago
well my boss doesn't listen on my CEO
doesn't listen on my cxo doesn't listen
reach out to the community and help and
have them help you understand how to
talk to people or worst case scenario we
dr. CEO he realizes how bad it is and
then he'll listen to you always
different ways to do it
obviously a wonderful host
thank you very very much for having me
here despite the craziness in the fun
stuff policy the caveat let me stand up
on stage and closed case from an ESF for
always putting up with me Eddie for
everything and then obviously as the
last thing said get out
go have fun and make it down difference
guys last night thank you very very very
much
any questions from you yeah alright i'm
good for questions ask the questions
while we line up the next lesson couple
minutes cover good question
all I know exactly what you know exactly
where you're going on that 1i haven't
done the studies on it i have done
enough research to say that they are
working towards being able to influence
that yet but at the moment mind sending
is no manufactured on the outside at the
moment from a self-replication
standpoint you actually can build a nano
so there is the ability to build what's
known as a banana factory inside so no
factory takes natural carbon also takes
the carbon that you can inject into all
take raw material basically and it will
actually build the nanotubes they're
getting into a state that building the
technology to get to the stage where you
can literally be a self-replicating
systems program there's two different
ways you put carbon in but they're also
looking at single thing get carbon out
yes there's some really freaky stuff
going on and there's still a long way
doing it did then throwing a crystal
ball down the line to see where they can
take it
yeah but that's not there yet to make
that very very clear but the discussions
of obviously been had because it's ok if
i can get something into you
not only can i how can I get it to
replicate but also happen to get
longevity out of it
I don't just want to inject you now and
have something that works for a little
bit how do I have it so you literally
have a continual health monitor inside
of you that does nothing more than some
level of self repair there's a lot of
discussions around as a shitty little
really cool white papers about it but
it's still very much on the theoretical
side of the world course
oh yeah yeah there's yeah there's also
the shit that's going to be a figured
out go from talking about you guys had a
chance without the affected my recent
improvements printer right now based
Christian community for really no
attraction
yes yeah that has been I haven't done
much on that one to be perfectly honest
I kind of all be focusing on the side of
things because it's fun and it's
interested i'm going to be honest but I
know again there's some people out there
again do the research as much as some
amazing research papers out there on the
stuff
that is everything that you find
yourself 273 discoloration of that
content on the Peter discreet of that
interfaces Saturday you know one sec
yeah it's really tight so you know i
will build a set of carbon architectures
and i will basically inject into doing
that into a local architecture or a bird
or a vision or anything only those lines
and then from that point I didn't have a
in the process I can see how much
advantage at fifty percent 60-percent
eighty percent ninety percent and other
percentage threshold I know just inject
to islamic center