so this plant I'm like you guys you know
I think that this is important and it
applies to me it applies to people I
care about the legal landscape for info
SEC and I'm really I appreciate you
being here because I think this is such
an important conversation so I'm really
glad that you know we can do this and I
think you might not be surprised and
some of the stuff that I'm going to talk
about today it's not surprising but it's
important so this just came out this
quote was just in the Washington Post
the other day the assistant director for
the FBI's counterterrorism division told
Homeland Security that's the challenge
working with those companies to build
technical solutions to prevent
encryption above all of this is the
ecosystem we're in right now and that's
scary because Obama also just said this
we want cyber criminals to feel the full
force of American justice because they
are doing as much damage if not war as
folks involved in more conventional
crime now I show solitary confinement
here because hackers get that kevin
Mitnick we've they both ended up in
solitary now you know they may have
provoked the guards a little bit maybe
more than you and I would but
nonetheless this is the ecosystem that
we're in right now Obama has actually
proposed doing some changes to the laws
that the government has been using to
prosecute hackers and he is suggested
expanding the definitions that could be
used to prosecute cyber criminals I put
cyber criminals in quotes because to the
government to the judges to the people
who end up judging these court cases
things like changing a URL is a hack you
know two people who are less technically
sophisticated
the kind of stuff you and I do every day
is like really advanced hacking this is
a good about the Computer Fraud and
Abuse Act this is the act that ends up
putting away people like mitnick and
we've the problem is it was constructed
many years ago and what's legal is
unauthorized access now that can be
interpreted just really really broadly
that's the problem no one knows what it
means and Nate Cardozo from the eff the
whole everyone at the eff is really
worried about the changes that Obama is
proposing and they Cardozo said under
the new proposal sharing their each view
go password with the friends would be a
felony and that's true and that's the
reason why these laws worry me is
because pretty much everyone here breaks
them almost every day just doing the
things that normal people do with
computers and with the end or not so
what ends up happening is these laws are
used to punish people for political
dissent have folks here have been
following the Silk Road trial a little
bit yeah so I you guys probably saw the
sentencing for the founder now Rob
Graham wrote about this and she said
that we should find this outrageous we
should be outraged and I think he's
right I'm actually kind of outraged this
is me like outraged I don't express it
very much
I'm a CEO and I've kind of learned to
keep everything like under the surface
so I don't you know scare off people
from working with me or with my company
I had a co-founder who got fired for
seeing some sensitive things on Twitter
so I've kind of learned to keep some of
my outrage under wraps this is like his
outrage does it get right here thank you
for letting me share this much outrage
with you today no that would be
extremely satisfying thank you we can do
that at the end we could all break
pencils so there's a lot of text in this
in these slides and I apologize for that
it's because I just thought all this
language from the courts was so so
important I just couldn't cut it all out
so what the judge said here with the
sentencing about silk road is that it's
not just that what the Silk Road founder
did was criminal but that it was
political dissent he was saying that the
laws governing drugs and the
marketplaces were wrong and his
punishment was very excessive for that
reason so here we have the judges quote
the state of purpose of the Silk Road
was to be beyond the law this is deeply
troubling terribly misguided and very
dangerous and she gave him a bigger
sentence than even what the prosecution
had asked for and this is the reason
that she gave whereas Ross told the
judge I wanted to empower people to make
choices to privacy in anonymity I'm not
a sociopath so I can kind of see myself
in front of the court someday seeing
this about you know why I made an end to
end encrypted at I'm making this app
right now that is a way for people who
are cannabis activists or second Rights
Amendment activists to have large
conversations amongst themselves like a
hundred thousand people and have it be
encrypted but you saw like the
government is starting to get very
anxious and very worried about
applications that prevent the FBI from
being able to intercept them so
oh I don't know I I read this and I
relate to it and that's one reason why
I'm anxious and I don't want to have to
leave the country because it's nice here
but I don't want to do something else
because this is what I do and I want to
live in a relatively free country right
now we're free enough that I can have
this conversation so that those are the
things that I'm thinking about right now
now isn't this cute Ross is so cute with
the kitten I love Business Insider so
Business Insider is not like a high tech
blog or security blog so I thought it
was really meaningful that this writer
did this piece about how his sentencing
was too harsh it's like a mainstream
thing you know anyone who's watching
this and and has some understanding if
the ecosystem can see it his sentencing
you know you deserve some kind of a
sentence they had a lot of evidence and
he broke the law but it was extremely
harsh so one reasonable response is just
like I'm out do folks here know who
Quinn norden is do you guys know who she
is a few people but not affront so Quinn
warden is this security researcher who's
really good at embedding herself into
communities so she's gotten to know a
lot of the hacker communities you know
anonymous and aaron schwartz and she got
really tight with a lot of those folks
and ended up handling a lot of sensitive
data like stolen credit card type stuff
in her efforts to be a really good
security journalist and she wrote this
post recently saying we should all step
back from security journalism and i'll
go first this was like a watershed
moment this was the first time that
someone really came out and said it's
too dangerous and I don't want to do
this anymore and it was interesting to
see Quinn do this because Quinn is
different from someone like kevin
Mitnick or
we've or someone founding Silk Road
because Quinn is a journalist in Quinn
has been very careful to not break the
law and Quinn isn't even a hacker she's
not even the one creating the
vulnerabilities or breaking in and
getting the data she's just analyzing it
and sorting out truth from fiction and
then trying to bring that to the light
to the public what she said is I may be
incarcerated for doing my job and she
said I have a family which is wild she's
like as a family I can't do this scary
journalism stuff wow what and this was
in response to Barrett Brown because
Barrett Brown was sentenced to six to
three months just for linking to have to
material no Barrett Brown was involved
in anonymous Barrett Brown has all of
this context that added to his sentence
because political dissidents your social
graph all of that plays into intention
which plays into your sentencing but the
actual crime he committed was pasting a
link and for someone like Quinn who
shares information in the process of
being a journalist that's worrisome and
for me that's worrisome to because
piecing a link is a very easy thing to
do right like I drink too much Saturday
night and I go on twitter i can post all
kinds of things and usually it's all
right but the stakes are high so i need
to watch myself now this is a lot of
text but what Quinn nerd and said is
that the government is chilling the
basic techniques that we're using in
security research and in journalism
because what's happening is if you paste
a link if you share this data that black
hat hackers have got it then it's as if
you hack the day to yourself and and
that that's that's very chilling for
journalists and it's something for
security researchers to think about as
well I was actually thinking about
Jennifer earlier I tweeted about you
you have good lawyers because of what
you do and what your company does and
unique of lawyers it's hard to come up
with like advice or takeaways here so I
don't have a lot of that but I have a
lawyer I'm working with the same law
firm that defended leave and they're
helping me just you know file on my
expert controls and I tend to think of
hackers is being kind of like the Mafia
these days or like they get the Mafia
for a tax evasion and they could get me
for like failing to file my expert
controls or something if they wanted to
I also worry because I'm not that
careful about my social graph like we
will post often all comments on it
because it's like funny or interesting I
could see that showing up in court if I
were going to be more careful I would
like only publicly talked to really nice
people but I don't know I I wasn't
raised the way I haven't lived the way
up until now it would be a real change
of mindset for me to say I'm going to
think about what my court case would
look like if I get in trouble for
building the encryption because that's
scary and illegal now it's not illegal
yet but it's foreseeable it it could be
it could happen I think this is really
interesting but so I hang out in Silicon
Valley a lot and there's a certain
arrogance there now this CEO had it hit
him run so he smashed him one up in her
car and she had some significant
injuries he did it because he was
feeding he couldn't wait he couldn't
wait for the slow driver so he cut her
off and there was this accident and he
didn't have any jail time she didn't die
which is good but like you can actually
in a hit-and-run and just get community
service if you have the right contest so
what the judge said is that he's
basically a good citizen so he doesn't
even need to do the jail time that would
norm
happen in a hit and run because just a
good citizenship so I don't think that's
terribly surprising for everyone but for
me it was just a reminder that
disappearance of good citizenship and
the other stuff that goes on behind the
scenes right like his company raised
something like a million dot one hundred
million dollars so those kinds of
resources can be helpful again you know
what are the takeaways here for me it's
just a reminder that activism and
dissidents as well as truly and
embarrassing the FBI and the government
end up being like the real crimes
because with the vagueness of the laws
that are on the books right now you know
everybody violates these laws in one way
or another you share your HBO Go
password and that's already like fuzzy
so it's really the broader context of
whether you're doing like politically
challenging things like Silk Road Silk
Road was asserting that the marketplaces
around drugs the marketplaces around our
transaction should be different so what
can you do one thing you can do is file
a Freedom of Information Act request and
then you'll see like what the government
has about you which i think is useful
and interesting and they actually will
send you stuff they'll black out a lot
of it and you can send it to different
agencies and you can get in touch with
me if you want to file your FOIA request
so I think of we have a lot when I think
about this because he got jailed for
that AT&T hack which was essentially
just changing links so is this iconic
case where it wasn't really a hack like
changing a link isn't that big a deal
anyone can change a leg and I wasn't
trata in this top right I was like I
don't know what to say like these are
just bad info SEC is dangerous during
our Indian he's like don't see well okay
I'm not going to do that
thank you for the suggestion maybe next
time the audience wants it I don't know
I can bring it up on my phone we got
time so I thought I'd end with this and
then we'll do some Q&A and some
discussion and mix it up which is you
know say what you want about me but I'm
always grateful that he actually fought
this case because we don't want that
accumulation of case law saying that you
can just put people like us away for you
know changing links and then sharing
that with the newspaper we really need
for that stuff to be legal and I don't
think I even need to tell everyone here
in the audience why we need security
research and disclosure to be legal so
I'm always appreciative that that got
overturned and I think it's impressive
that you have returned it from jail so
you know worst case if you end up in
prison and i hope none of you do please
fight it because we really can't have
that accumulation of case law showing
that it's legit to put people away for
this stuff now I think that's my last
slide yep cool so I thought it would be
kind of interesting because you know
you're so just like you guys know a lot
about this stuff new some really
interesting stories probably an insights
I thought it would be interesting to
open it up a bit more in do more QA and
conversation that's okay if everyone
here right yeah ok so I'm going to kind
of move on in and we've got folks in the
back a load of snow and we're getting
close up at a time does anyone have
questions or like a story that is
relevant to all of this yeah
I have not and that's because I'm not
very successful let's wait ask me in
like six months to a year yeah I the way
what I'm doing is following silent
circle's model right now where we just
delete everything and that's what the
government is really worried about is
like they approach you and technically
you just don't have records or like sent
and encrypted and we deleted all of it
so I don't know what to give you when I
end up doing secure storage from our
business purposes then we'll be able to
hand that over but I'm presuming no
one's doing anything terribly
interesting in their small companies but
I don't know you know people do all
kinds of crazy illegal business
transactions so we'll get exciting i
can't wait and i'm ready to leave the
country so I run this startup with my
ex-husband who's a goat herder uh and
way back when we expatriated and we
lived in the Middle East for a while so
like everybody's ready to just like pick
up and go but I do like it here so I'm
hoping I'm hoping we don't have to but
you can ask me about goat hurting other
people had questions or thoughts don't
be sad not shy
that's good question the security
researcher is usually generating the
data like I have a lot of questions
about uber the company and how they're
handling our data and so I kind of like
to spend some time in the app and see
what they're collecting and what they're
sending home and back to headquarters
and I think that they may there may be a
discrepancy between what they're saying
and what they're doing there have been
some hints at that and other research in
the past so that would be security
research going and finding out something
that isn't necessarily public knowledge
yet and then the journalism part would
be like a journalist coming to me and
saying oh this is the data that you
found and then having to verify it what
happened was when Norton is she didn't
verify some data early in her journalist
career and then she published it and
that data was incorrect and designed to
fool noobs and that was she never wanted
to make that mistake again so after that
she had to verify all of the data that
came in if people said oh this is 2
million hat credit card she needed to
make sure and so you end up doing a lot
of security research if you're going to
be a good security journalist and I
think that those kind of journalists are
rare because we're in a click beta right
now people don't have time for that but
there are folks like Quinn who take it
seriously
yeah sure do you know one I don't have
examples offhand I don't have examples
of hand and I think that speaks to the
reasons why people get targeted and
prosecuted right now is because um the
people who are creating what's perceived
as damage are the people who they want
to make samples of and stop you know
they're legitimately breaking laws I
think Quinn's point was that she just
doesn't know and and it was a risk that
she wasn't willing to take because she
has a child yes yes and I think that
that's a really important point it's a
chilling effect because the law is
ambiguous and confusing and lawyers will
say as much I actually saw the American
Bar administration had a post about how
the language around the Computer Fraud
Act is too ambiguous and so that's the
problem it's ambiguous I personally
can't say this is a path where I'm
breaking the law this is the path where
I'm not like I'm safe I'm not safe with
traffic laws I know like I know if I'm
going over 50 and I know if this is an
area where copter patrolling and the
chilling effect is like we don't know I
feel like it's just as bad that I have
public conversations with individuals
that are hated as like any work i
actually do and that's part of what i
think is messed up
I think that's right in terms of the
sentences are beyond what's reasonable
and just the interpretation of what's
hacking and what's unauthorized I think
that's what's worrisome that's what's
really worrisome is they'll say changing
a URL is hacking because it seems really
advanced to people who you know their
lives aren't on the internet the way
ours are so we won't even think of
ourselves as doing a hack we're doing
something that's not publicly accessible
a URL is publicly accessible right but
you know to certain government officials
or justices they'll see changing your
URL is like a kind of sophisticated
thing like that's a hacker thing yeah
yeah I think that's really well stated
and the laws about authorized or
unauthorized access were written at a
time when just computers and the
internet were so different and they
haven't been updated appropriately and
the updates that they're looking at our
laquey in the wrong direction and not
really clarifying things my concern is
you know our government officials either
just technically confused they not
understand it or do they yes understand
it and are going in this direction
anyway and either way I find troubling
and I think it's because like government
officials like the FBI to see
technologists as factions and they're
trying to create a compromised situation
this is specifically with respect to the
debate around encryption we want
encryption back doors and the
technologists Alex stainless from yahoo
like all these really smart CISOs and
and technical advisors are saying
there's no way we can give you back
doors without also letting China and
Russia in and the government's like we
can compromise we can like surely we can
do it but like there's a lot of
compromise between like science and
fantasy like I don't like how do you
write like like this is the science this
is the map this is how math works this
is how crypto works and I actually
watched some of the preceding the like
Senate proceedings around this and one
guy was like don't tell me we could go
to the moon the US could go to the moon
and we could do that and that you really
smart nerds that you can't like make
this happen and it's like well okay yeah
we can go to the moon but we can't like
keep anyone else from going there that's
the analogy but like they're just like
you nerds like you're just not trying
hard enough and we're just like this is
math we don't know how to change now we
don't know how to change the science
does anyone else have thoughts or any
experiences related to this yeah
I did I not only submitted it my start
up before this we were so broke and we
were so scrappy and we're so desperate
and we're so mad about Snowden and the
NSA then we built a little my FOIA
request machine and we took $25
donations and we automated people Zeppa
ye requests so i did my request and then
we spent like the whole weekend sending
out like hundreds of requests and most
of us got the same letter back which
leaked pretty much said nothing and i
think that's because the government
hadn't collected anything on me but
they'll send you that the latter and
it's cool it's like has the seal from
the NSA it depends on how much traffic
there getting and part of our goal and
and I got this idea I got this idea from
Jonathan Corvette who's Lily a chi sa
hacker but he was doing this we're like
we want them to have to hire like five
more people to handle all the requests
so like they had like they're one person
whose job this is or maybe it's too and
then you start like submitting all these
requests and the timeline gets longer it
took me about three to four weeks but
who knows right the NSA is like button
like defunded refunded who knows what's
going on there I don't know anyone who's
following this but like the NSA had that
sunset and then USA Freedom Act happened
and now like everything's back online
they've got another six months in the
clear yeah so I can't even keep track of
what's actually going on there but it's
cool to send the FYE requests and see
what the government has on you and
sometimes they have stuff and i'll send
it it's redacted but you get a sense of
what they know and what they don't know
oh oh man that's a that's a hilarious
question yeah why is this person
thinking about this right right do they
have a person that you know regularly
scans or keywords are you just part of
the whole bulk collection that's so
that's a hard question but interesting
that that's worth looking at
right
right it's so much to eat up it's too
much it's too much data how are you
managing your security research you seem
to be legal
yeah and the laws are changing oh that's
a good question do you actually know
that
Oh
the wrong hand Emma or even discuss
research said I was using the school
there any attention somebody and
especially with all of us at conferences
you know
however that sounds really familiar yeah
i mean this top focused on the US but i
want to start to look the international
scene it gets really complicated and for
sure things like that to happen
right right yeah well and as things
become more inhospitable will all want
to go hang out in canada said the
desktop Kensei cross will become the new
khan i can totally see that kind of cold
look yeah
yeah so we were living in Israel and
ribbon that's his name has dual
citizenship in the US and in Israel he
has some community service there but
that's not a big deal and I started my
process of getting that dual citizenship
and I stopped because you have a lot of
like overhead and taxes in bureaucracy
and I just never finished it but I'd be
welcome to go back there and Israel is
an interesting place to do cybersecurity
because there's so many like really
people working in that now if we hire a
bunch of Israeli cryptographers and
developers and there may be some like
government three-letter agencies who
won't want to work with us for fear that
maybe we've backdoored in the Mossad but
that seems fine with me because that's
just not the business brand I just want
to serve either like small to
medium-sized you know customers and
privacy people for now so I like the
idea of working with Israeli folks but
it would be even better if we can just
stay here and be comfortable but we're
considering all our options especially
because I'm being advised by people who
have companies with headquarters outside
the US because I I don't have a lot of
insight into what actually happens when
the government comes to you and says we
really want to back door and the company
says no because people aren't writing
happy little blog posts about that
that's like a real hush-hush kind of
conversation you have to be privileged
to really get the real real deal on that
but I imagine that it's a difficult
position to be in so that's why we're
taking these precautions and thinking
about it now and just making sure we're
kind of willing to do that we have to
no cuz we're not successful and ah so
that's right yeah so uh right now that's
all fine because we're so under the
radar and as a start-up we have so many
problems just being like Oh will we be
able to pay everyone like in four months
even our tiny little salaries we have
like these really big picture like will
we be in business and four months
problems that overshadow the more
nuanced like what's the logistics of
this guy being Irish well yeah and with
my last stirred up we had all these
problems like all startups do we hide it
we don't talk about it all started to
have all these problems so my last
company had all these problems and
everyone worked in the US and we didn't
have international issues we don't have
any international people right now
because it's I just don't know anyone
who's international hoyt want to hire
and as a small company we're under the
radar so if we do weird illegal things
cuz all startups do half the time you
don't know and the other half no one
cares so we really rely on that like
security through obscurity but yeah I
guess I should think about that huh what
what happened in the last startup is I
knew that I had to do the export
controls for the crypto but I got to the
website where you start to fill it out
and I got so scared because I didn't
know how and it was clear like okay I'm
going to be on some kind of list when I
do this and I don't know how to talk to
about it so I'm going to file all my
paperwork this time around but I kind of
a me is thinking back about my last
company is like just too scary to do the
export controls and we're so small no
one cared maybe they look here now and
maybe I'll get a problem I don't know
what the statute of limitations all not
it
and put in the back we look out a bit of
time yeah yeah you know people don't
always share that they've been monitored
but um yeah I'm thinking of is would you
define Jake Applebaum is like a
journalist or you can actually define
like Julian Assange as a journalist
right like he's sharing this stuff with
WikiLeaks and they prosecuted the hell
out of him and that was for sharing this
stuff now that was government secrets so
you know you understand the sensitivity
yeah thatthat's I'd like to look into
that I think Jake Applebaum's probably
the best example of a person who has
been monitored any tops about it he said
that the feds show up his mom's house
that was awkward for his mom for him
because they really want to know what
he's going to do and they wanted to know
what Julian Assange was going to do
who's just too close to everything any
of that social graph of like kind of
overtly being an anarchist that doesn't
help I like to tell people I'm not an
anarchist so they know has anyone had
any experiences with this do you guys
like think you're being monitored
hi everyone yeah so glad no one
introduced me think we got one in the
back
I was too close to the KGB
that will do it
we've seen a lot of irregularities and a
lot of that's come out in a lot of these
high-profile cases I'm not surprised it
can help you reverse this engines
they're looking at that in the Silk Road
trial looking at some of the misconduct
that happened and that was a big issue
in weaves case wave was able to overturn
because they were like prosecuting in
the wrong state they're all these you
know minor things because he had a good
enough lawyer who is able to suss that
out so in some ways that misconduct is
good because we can use it to overturn
these essentially miss trials but it's
obviously not good right I want our
government to do the right thing
well what's interesting about enabling
illegal activity is the government has
created protections for that for
corporations you know you can upload
illegal content to YouTube you can send
dm's on facebook saying all kinds of
crazy things illegal things and Facebook
isn't liable YouTube isn't liable so
we've created a lot of protections for
companies and and someone I here at this
conference brought that up to me and
said look you know yes Silk Road is
facilitating illegal activity but a lot
of websites do that as a by-product and
we've created a lot of corporate shields
for that so I thought that that's just
really interesting and if your YouTube
and you're hosting a legal content as
they've done for years it's fine if
you're facilitating this kind of illegal
content it's not fine there's obviously
a big difference between facilitating
murder and drug sales and facilitating
like illegal cat videos and I'm
sensitive to that difference but
nonetheless it does say something about
who gets prosecuted and why someone at
this con also mentioned to me that the
companies that had done the biggest
donations to political campaigns tended
to have the most success and prosecuting
their hackers now I don't think that we
can necessarily make the leap that
that's because the government was
partial to them it might just be that
these companies had more resources but
that's not saying anything about the
world we live in that we don't already
know I say hand in the back
sometimes I parents will let me out of
the house
any other ideas
you're kind of nodding you have any
insights
yeah I think that's it I have to try and
remind myself to be more conscious I do
I'm like oh nothing's gonna happen cuz
I'm you know I'm nice and that had
friends in government but i don't know
maybe one day I'll take a talk like this
too far on him I want to watch myself up
yeah yeah so I've had a really exciting
last two years I dated a special DoD
soldier person who did some kind of
background checking on me and I don't
know how much government resources went
into that but yeah I just I don't know
all the details there but um just I I
think I'm proud of the work I've done in
the last two years and I like to think
that people take a notice I hope yo so I
think if there's a small file on me then
that's probably a sign that I've done
some things right in the last few years
actually given what I care about that i
hope the files not too big yeah
oh sure somewhere where you'd be happy
right and that's very personal well it
depends on you care about right so I
have a lot of friends and I think folks
here probably 22 who've gone off to
Berlin you've got Jake Apple bounds who
moved there for the privacy laws Gillian
York from the eff is living there now my
friend has the tekes a lot of privacy
people are in Berlin so that's really
compelling of all places right my
goodness yeah it's personal taste I
would move back to Israel because I
liked it there I was comfortable there
it's obviously a very problematic region
and I fully acknowledge that but it's a
place where I can go and have some
familiarity with the culture and higher
really great people for my team and the
country would welcome me and all things
considered you know that's a some value
like co-founders already a citizen there
but I wouldn't recommend like oh yeah
everyone should just run off to Israel
if you have problems here like hell no
I'm really interested in Berlin that
that's very intriguing but depends what
you want to do I think Ecuador can be
really lovely fight over the go raise
like a hundred thousand dollars and find
somewhere with a low cost of living and
go to your thing silent circle's
headquarters i think is Switzerland so
there are some you know EU countries
they care a lot about privacy and places
like Switzerland your kind of nodding
you gotta have a sense of humor about
this stuff uh I'm a very fierce
libertarian I appreciate some government
as a very petite woman who likes to you
know occasionally walk the streets alone
at night or you know leave reasonable
valuables in a location like I'm glad
there's a moderate level of police
protection I'm glad somebody builds
roads you know like I want a minimum
level of state I think that's great
I think a minimum level of a state is
just great it's just the overreach it's
the other each that I worry about you
know we could all be here today having
gone here in our cars in having running
water without also having mass
surveillance on us mass surveillance is
not adding the value from my tax dollars
yeah just it's an roi thing I like when
the government adds value I'm an
adventure capitalist so we got another
few minutes I'm happy to wrap up early
if folks are done the books of stories
to share I'm really interested in the
experiences of other people here I came
here thinking this is an important topic
but not knowing for sure what other
people if I'm the only one who feels
chilled so that's her I'm not
I got funding through the state of
Virginia which is one such a cheerleader
you give me fifty thousand dollars i
will love you too that's through mot 37
i did a cybersecurity accelerator that
came in through virginia's enthusiasm
for economic development that way so I
know he's genuine about that but yeah
he's still yeah I'm with you alright one
more question last one all right let's
wrap up thank you so much for being here