hey everybody howdy starting a little
bit early of course I do not intend to
run an hour and ten on this so don't
worry I had a couple of people fall
asleep on me last year and I think that
was super reasonable considering the
nature of last year's talk so hopefully
i'll keep you guys going a little bit
more this will be the first time that
i'm talking about really modern things
we're going to dig into the history a
little bit of course because that's
where I draw a lot of my context from
but more and more I have been thinking
about what it means to feel safe what it
means to be secure what it means to be a
consumer of security when you live in a
situation of minimal risk and the fact
is the gross majority of end users of
consumers either aren't at critical risk
on a regular basis or the consequences
of becoming victimized are so smooth by
other important parts of our society and
you know the fifth time that you get
your credit card reissued in the year
because they caught whatever stupid
thing happened to you before you lost
all of your money those sorts of things
are smoothing out a lot of the
consequences for victimization as a
result we're pretty safe yes absolutely
there are swords of Damocles hanging
over our heads but when you're trying to
sell to consumers it's a much harder
sell than it used to be particularly in
America particularly right now so this
talk is going to be about selling
security in a post lock society I'm not
being glib with the post lock part will
dig into that as well I'm Skylar town
case you don't know me I'm really big
into locks pretty super into lock so a
lot of the stock is going to focus
around locks and a head lock in the
title I wasn't joking about that it's
all about locks but historically here at
RV a second other conferences I kind of
dig into the mechanical side of things
and I try to throw as much
the shore as I can so that you guys can
draw whatever conclusions and whatever
metaphors you can from it hopefully
hopefully something useful so previously
at our VA 2012 I gave the talk why do
you lock your door and in the stock I
tried to make a strong argument for the
social and emotional nature of security
that there is a deeper connection to
security than most people realize as
they're moving through their lives that
it can the trespass whether against or
you trespassing someone else has a
physiological effect that you really
feel it in the gut that your heart is
invested in security even if you have no
idea that it is this is going to come up
again today in 2013 I gave the talk
vulnerability research circuit 1851 in
which I tracked the rise and decline of
perfect security the death of perfect
security changed a lot of things I
talked about that in depth in 2013 and
this is going to come up once again and
finally last year I explained how to
make a lock from first principles all
the way back to as far back as i could
start making locks and trying to explain
all of the different things that go into
designing a lock and one of the things
that we kept coming back to slide after
slide after slide of getting the new
format a more convenient format
something easier to use all sorts of
convenience and even regulatory
considerations that take place that have
nothing to do with making something more
secure but are an enormous force on the
security industry and one that could
probably compromise with in more
effective ways so all of this is going
to come back up again today
there are four big tenants here the
first is that community is security when
I started thinking about the post lock
world that we may or may not be in I
realized that i was about to spend a
significant amount of time studying how
people feel about security who don't
have to worry about security like the
data says they don't have to worry about
it the logic says they don't have to
worry about it how do they live with the
idea of security the idea of trespass
how they protect themselves have they
protect other people so on and so forth
and it is I mean I'm investigating white
relatively wealthy suburbia a lot of the
time I am talking to people who have
never taken the time to think about
these things before in their lives
because they have not had to and this
massive segment of people who are
completely disconnected from an active
role in their own security have some
interesting norms that that wouldn't
have occurred to me previously so I
proposed formal debates at conferences a
while back and I'm pretty stoked that
our VA are going to be doing the speed
debates tomorrow I am thrilled to attend
those I wanted to find someone to debate
me on the fact that we are living in a
post la cage and that I would take all
comers the offer still stands but it has
to be an American because the British
are not living in a post la cage which
is a whole other talk that you can get
into with me at the table tomorrow the
reason that I say this is coming out of
1851 you know like three days after my
last talk ended back in history
literally 1851 there is this amazing
editorial that I found where the person
quite poetically and quite earnestly
suggested that now the perfect security
was dead now that we all knew that the
locks could be open now that we all knew
that we were all securing ourselves
behind locks that we knew how to open
perhaps our mutual vulnerability would
create mutual empathy but perhaps we
were merging into a post lock age and we
would
be a better society as a result of it
when i first read that five years ago i
thought it was hilarious go man locks
her everywhere billion dollar industry
still you know worldwide nobody lives
that locks the very rare exceptions that
i could find two people living without
locks were enormous outliers and yet it
was really burning me as a matter of
fact i was giving a talk elsewhere and i
was telling the anecdote about this
guy's editorial and saying oh and i
laughed at it and it was that moment on
stage that I thought wait a minute I
think he might be right so I said so in
that talk I had no idea how to back it
up I didn't know what I was thinking
what this might lead to but it was a
moment of genuine not inspiration but
genuine curiosity and I wanted to
challenge myself by saying it publicly
so then I said it publicly again on
Twitter and I have some people that that
are attempting to take me up on it so
the reason this is coming to a head
recently as I did a show called going
deep with David Rees on natgeo cool show
we talked about locks my segment wound
up being very short and really nicely
done and edited and funny and great I
think they did an awesome job I shot
with them for half of a day and for
about two hours of that was just a
conversation between me and David in
front of a pile of locks and I can talk
for much longer than two hours about
locks and all of the weird things that I
think about locks and so on and so forth
and we were talking about the social
nature of them we were talking about how
you know mechanical peas have been
encoding information that they're your
passwords and so on and so forth all of
these like interesting subtle nuance
ideas because he was so excited he was
thrilled that all of the ideas and at
the moment that I said you know people
approach me all the time and they say oh
where i grew up we didn't have to lock
our doors nobody locked their doors blah
blah blah and i will say to them yes but
an unlocked door is just an unused lock
it is no testament to the security of
your community
if you really want to show that off if
you really want to demonstrate the
security of your community remove the
locks from your doors don't have locks
and as I was about to say to him but
nobody ever takes me up on that but
that's a step too far or whatever I was
going to say as I opened my mouth he
said oh my god let's do that let's go
take the lock off my door let's see how
long it takes people in my neighborhood
to notice let's see how it makes them
feel to find out that I'm living without
a log let's see how it feels to me to
come home with no lock on my door and he
just approached it with such excited
enthusiasm that he completely bowled me
over and I started to wonder if anybody
else out there unfortunately he had had
just gotten a roommate that was not
involved in this conversation so I blame
him not at all for not going through
with this as a matter of fact I think
that it was incredibly exciting that he
approached it with that much enthusiasm
and it completely inspired the next year
of sort of side research for me so I
began wondering if there's anybody else
like David Rees out there who would be
willing to go completely lock less no
lock on the door whatsoever and then
like right as I'm starting to think
about this I got a coupon for Google
consumer surveys sounds like well just
ask a bunch of people if they're willing
to do it and the survey was terrible the
survey data I am NOT going to show it to
you the survey date is awful you should
not believe the number i am about to
show you because I was really bad at
composing surveys at that moment in time
I learned a lot some friend tried to
help me but we combined the data of the
two surveys it's all a complete disaster
and the following information is
absolutely inaccurate but i'm going to
show you anyway I ask people if they
could feel safe without locks at all I
also asked them if they wanted more
locks I also ask them how they like
their locks I asked them way too many
things about locks but the people who
decided they could feel safer that locks
at all taking the data from both surveys
the one that was slightly more rigorous
and my complete disaster of a survey
gonna edit the video right here um I'm
still plugged in does anybody know
what's up with the feed you're getting
it back there what was that oh yeah the
lamp isn't on but not a bad thing that
we started earlier um what was that yeah
yeah can't even show you the damn data
that was such a reveal to that was such
a like here it is killed the projector
what else can I tell you guys in the
meanwhile stuff about locks I'm trying
to think about the stuff about locks it
doesn't this talk of it so far I just
ran my timings like three times on this
talk which is when this would happen of
course which is fine I'm starting to
work on another thing i'm going to vamp
on this for a minute because it's
interesting research it's completely new
to me as i said i intend to have
somebody cut the section out of the
video until we get up into here so not
at all for distribution yet but i'm
starting to investigate a theory that
locks come before all other societal
structures of security i have a couple
of but you guys can interrupt me if you
need my help to do anything just let me
know I'm vamping it's good vamping them
I have a couple of points of data on
this I have a couple of interesting
areas of Investigation a fantastic
gentleman whose name that I don't
remember and I would look it up but I'm
afraid of touching anything over here
wrote this amazing paper studying tele
bekhoon a te ll I think dash e bekhoon
and bak un I don't know why I thought
that one would be the thing that you
knew how to spell and a was the specific
period of this particular excavation and
there he discovers for the first time
thank you guys I'll finish that one
thought and then I will hop back over
here he discovers for the first time the
first door seals we've ever seen the
first time people are sealing doors and
he makes a beautiful intelligent and I
think super strong argument for the door
seal being be transitional technology
between its tribal society and a
civilized society and then the 1851
stuff anyway maybe I'll be back next
you're talking about that so going to do
that I'm gonna so I asked people if they
could feel safe for that locks at all I
also ask them how they like their locks
I asked them if they wanted more locks
ask them way too many things about walks
and so the data is awful but putting my
survey together putting the other survey
together three to seven percent of
respondents suggested that they could
feel comfortable living without walks at
all again that isn't true this is
terrible data please don't trust this
but man it's interesting even though I
know it can't be verified and I need to
do this again at some point in time and
so on and so forth but man I was like
sitting at a bar getting the responses i
was like oh my must have screwed this up
badly and i did it turned out i did i'll
get off of this rant anyway but it's but
so exciting and so curious that there
might be this much of a significant
percentage of people in America again
this is an American thing at the moment
it's probably a canadian thing but but
I'm focused on America but there are
these people that might be willing to
take the locks off their doors that
might actually feel that strong in their
community self the lack of consequences
whatever it is that's making them feel
safe it isn't locks
and there are a bunch of other
respondents that basically confirmed
that there is a big minority of people
who don't see locks as anything that
keeps them safe so even if they're not
willing to remove the locks from their
door they still don't trust the lock on
their door they trust other things in
their environment they haven't had to
think about it they're not sure how to
express it I went and and you know
verbally interviewed several people and
we'll talk about that a little bit as
well so I then thought about David's
other question how would someone feel if
they found out I was living without
locks and what a great question this
isn't what I expected I ask people if
they would feel less safe more safe or
neutral got a lot better at my options
the question is if a neighbor told you
they had decided to live without any
locks on their home would you feel less
safe more safe or neutral neutral of
course was the majority their responses
were a little less interesting but
twenty five percent of respondents felt
less safe as a result of a neighbor
ceasing to use locks I'll explain why in
a minute but that blew my mind I was
really surprised by that so he pushed
further we turned that one into a
multiple and I say we excited people
helping me at this stage if several
neighbors told you that they decided to
live without any locks on their homes
would you feel thirty-six percent would
feel less safe as a result of the
defection of their neighbors their
neighbors defecting against the normal
would make them in their home feel less
safe now when I started seeing this
pouring in and that it was this
significant a number of people oh by the
way we should talk about the more safe
people too because I feel like there's a
decent number of more safe people out
here who just think oh man there's an
easier target than me now great yeah you
don't think like the less safe people
and I'll explain the difference
my initial thought about the less safe
people was that they were probably
thinking oh this is inviting trouble
this is the you know broken windows
theory that if we let things go to heck
then we're inviting trouble into our
neighborhood so on and so forth I
thought maybe this is what the
perception is admittedly I haven't you
know manually verbally in person
interviewed the entire response group I
haven't even interviewed anybody that
was in this of course because it's all
anonymous but as I continue this as I
asked people personally as I you know
got ahold of strangers that I was able
to see immediately in front of me and
I've had these conversations I've met a
lot of less safes a lot of people that
feel less safe as a result of this and
none of them are telling me that they
think it's inviting trouble there is a
significant minority of people whose
sense of their personal security and
compasses their community I'm going to
use my mother as an example my mother is
in her late 60's now she's a delight she
still you know shovels the driveway or
an old Vermont farming stock love her to
death she knew that a neighbor was on a
trip some winter and we live we were in
the safest little suburb of the tiniest
charming town but she went because we
had a sudden Blizzard she went and she's
blew out their entire driveway and their
walk to their door and swept off the
walk so it would look like they were
home hours of effort because of an
unexpected snowstorm and I don't know
that she even speaks to these people on
a regular basis but they're her
neighbors she might I'm sorry mom if you
do and the people that I talked to that
were in the less safe camp this is what
they said to me over and over again I I
would be more on watch it would what I
was getting from them was was less that
they would feel less safe but more that
they would have to be on guard now and
they didn't have to be before this
question was asked that they had to
watch out for their name
is that their security was completely
tied to their community the more saves
as we said got to be safer for them if
some other it eight is living in that
locks you know they're the they're the
easiest path the path of least
resistance for somebody that wants to
cause trouble and the neutrals were
again not as interesting to me but
definitely kind of predictable that's
what I got from a lot of people like it
does not matter to me the locks don't do
anything security is an illusion and
this occasionally bums me out because if
you really need we can we can get you
serious security you can invest you can
make it happen but you know in a certain
way they're not wrong and so between the
less safes and the Securities and
illusion people we have a lot of people
that are I'm sorry I meant to say
between the more safes and the
Securities illusion people we have a lot
of people that are valuing locks less
than our other minorities so well we'll
circle back to that and why that's
important number two here is that we
have nothing to fear that's not entirely
true this sort of advertisement this was
for a safe your house is on fire this
may be the warning cry you hear some
night and they said you know if you have
our safe in your house you won't lose
your important documents so on and so
forth and that's that's how advertising
was that's how marketing was in security
and fire safety in all of that stuff it
was just things are terrifying and we
can help you that is dramatically less
effective now dramatically less
effective I don't mean that we actually
have nothing to fear and there are a lot
of people that fear a lot of things that
logically by the data whatever you want
to say they don't necessarily need to
fear I was recently burgled and that
sucked
but it didn't matter all that much I
lost a camera that was important to me
for my forensics work I had to pick
glass out of a toilet which was really
annoying my wife and my in-laws felt
awful and that sucked I hated that but I
boarded up the window assess the other
damage they did they did a lot of damage
took them quite a few tries to get into
my house I feel good about that the
things that were stolen sucked sharing a
laptop with my wife coasters was stolen
that was frustrating for a while for
both of us she hates Windows but we had
friends sent us payers really fancy
payers from Harry and David right
afterwards and chocolates and mixed nuts
oh we had friends that wrote to us and
said hey let's get together at your
house so you guys get to feel more
comfortable so you feel like you own it
again our insurance company put us in
touch with the contractor insurance
companies is paying what is appropriate
for the things that have happened I went
to work the next day we had 48 hours of
feeling a little bit uncomfortable
leaving our home alone or having either
of us be alone in the home of course I
had all you friggin paranoid hacker
saying man are you sure you haven't been
targeted check the place to see if
you've been bugged so that kind of
sucked for like 48 hours as I was like
oh embracing your paranoia but it was
also really weird i had just finished
this project we i was working with the
guys in ninety nine percent because we
put together an episode on perfect
security on all that 1851 stuff and i
felt like i had put a pin in that and
that went out and i was so excited and i
arrived home and I said oh babe why'd
you leave the garage door unlocked she
didn't walked in together now we even
Berlin is such a surreal experience to
be studying this stuff you know anyway
uh I'm digressing a little bit here but
all I mean to say is that sucked but I'm
not afraid of it happening again
I hate that someone did that but I'm not
afraid of them I had a couple of weeks
of frustration and annoyance but I'm not
afraid that that's going to be what the
rest of my life is bound you know we
keep locking our doors we replace the
lock we replace the window we use our
sash locks all the time now so that's
good those a good thing that we should
have been doing but it's all okay the
consequences of victimization have been
smooth for a lot of us not all of us but
for a lot of us unless you lie to us so
there are a lot of people trying to sell
security that are just lying I gave
Haven lock the benefit of the doubt when
i published my paper last november on
the current state of smart locks they
offered a bunch of facts on their
website such as with ninety-five percent
of break-ins requiring some force hours
creates a stir your support system
that's not true that's not true at all
look at the FBI crime statistics look at
the bureau of justice statistics about
two-thirds require some amount of force
sometimes that and often that force is
very much related to win goose and
things that aren't blocked by anything
like this then two thirds is a hell of a
long way from ninety five percent and
they had a couple of other facts on
there that were provably false and it
pissed me off because i feel like a lot
of the other people in this market a lot
of the other smart hungry young
companies are embracing a lot of the
rest of the crap that I'm about to tell
you they're selling to people on
convenience they're selling to people in
that social way they're selling to
people great optimistic feelings about
their control over their home and Haven
are still trying to sell with fear and
their crowdfunding failed I don't think
that it was as a result but selling with
fear should be over let's cut it out
Paul Gerhardt CEO of lockitron said one
of the most beautiful things that I've
heard in a long time he was talking
about security he makes an electronic
lock but he said walls are designed to
keep people out locks are there to
decide who you let in I love that I
would love to see somebody market a lock
to me asking who i want to let in
showing me my latchkey kid that keeps
forgetting a stupid key and so I never
rekey the lock and everybody in town has
my damn key and I worry about my kid
every stupid night cuz that's something
worth being afraid of but demonstrating
to me not that they're going to be
locked out in the cold and that's
horrible you're going to help me but
just showing them coming home and being
able to walk right in watching the door
unlocked from their dumb smartphone that
I shouldn't have bought them because
they're only 11 but it's the modern
world I don't have a kid yet but I'd
love to see that I'd love to see my kid
coming home safe because of this new
technology that I put on my door that's
a real problem I'd love to see love I
would love to see love in the marketing
of security oh my god particularly home
security how many better feelings are
there then when you and your significant
other have the key to your first place
that's amazing locks are all about love
I want to see a party where everybody
that showed up had an invitation that
was the key through my door to my
amazing party and I want to see
everybody just flowing in I don't want
to be interrupted going to the door and
letting every idiot in after idiot after
idiot I want to be able to roll right in
there because I invited every individual
one of them and we're having a great
time there are so many great ways to
sell me a product without telling me
that my kids going to die out in the
cold or that I'm going to be murdered my
sleep I want somebody to ask me who all
let in I want that to be their slogan I
want that to be the way that they want
to convince me to use their
product I don't need to be afraid at
this point in my life of most security
issues and that is amazing I know more
than a lot of other people that are
living not being afraid just because
they're completely ignorant of things I
know a lot of stuff I could be the guy
that murders you in your sleep if that's
what I wanted to do I don't I know that
people could do these things and yet
even I don't feel like I need to be
afraid and that's fantastic that's our
society those are our communities those
are all of the other aspects of security
that we never think about that are doing
a great job so I don't want to be sold
fear anymore walks have been sold in a
lot of different ways over a very long
period of time back in the late 1700s
and early eighteen hundreds when we were
first finally getting really serious
locks it was super novel super novel
that a lock would like work in a serious
way at all super novel you would have a
lock that somebody else couldn't open
and they were great there were miles
ahead of anything that had come before
and so the people making them published
every bit of information you could hope
to know about these locks this is a new
thing was quite navia to inform people
you had to tell them everything about it
and people read about it people talked
about it people discuss these things
people wrote letters to the editor
saying I'm not sure about this piece of
information they gave and they'd write
back to be like yours also be in philly
about the piece of information it was
all about information and creating
legitimacy for these security products
that's great now those were really bad
times the mid-1700s it's really the rise
of a lot of professional crime it's the
rise of fences in particular which allow
burglary to just explode and the
consumerism of the early seventeen
hundreds had created the market for the
fences for the burglars and it was just
the locks hadn't caught up policing
didn't exist Lynn a real formal
civilized way yet none of these things
existed until the locks came in
and everybody had to be able to trust
them in the way that they were going to
trust them was by getting all of the
information great now things get a
little bit better it's not the bad old
days anymore there's some scary things
that happen after 1851 because all of
the locks have been picked but everybody
suddenly realizes even though the locks
have been picked we're all doing pretty
ok this is in the 1700s anymore things
are okay we have professional police we
have you know the gas lamps have been
here forever thing things are great now
we're not walking and being murdered in
the dark every night it's probably not
exactly what the 1700s were like but
wasn't and so now you see a lot of hard
branding a lot of serious branding
legitimacy in the early 1800s was
patents if you said you have a patent
lock then that information was on file
somewhere you had described it in depth
it was a patent lock that's good enough
we know that the information is out
there that was an important statement
that this is so and so's patent lock now
we see people like Yale in particular
saying things like hey here's the deal
everybody's making LOX LOX are fine you
need to look for Yale look for the Yale
name we make great locks look for the
Yale name and then you'll definitely be
secure we can't say that all of these
other idiots are going to be secure look
for the Yale name Yale created massive
massive ground swell in their branding
there's actually like interesting case
history and trademark law that Yale are
directly involved in early on so this
branding and this just trust us we've
got you covered you don't need to know
anything else we got you covered this
mentality really takes over I mean
people will literally say at this point
in time this is this is when the
information starts coming in the room we
don't need to inform you about these
things anymore as a matter of fact if we
inform you about these things that might
even be more dangerous for you in the
early 1900's and the very late 1800s
this is where that starts to arrive that
if we told you everything that would be
more dangerous for you and then honestly
as everything else got better and better
and better into the 1960s 70s 80s 90s
price was the primary driver for the
consumer price and convenience and
weirdly now even though price and
convenience are still incredibly
important by the way price and
convenience are always important through
every one of these ages but they're just
the most important thing at that point
all of a sudden information is becoming
a lot more important to us again the
reason that I get really excited about
smart locks is not because of the
technology behind them i'm still a
purely mechanical guy but this is the
yes thank you very much but this is the
first time that i have seen a wide
consumer base excited about locks in my
lifetime it's thrilling how much people
want to know about them so information
is coming back and vogue in a big way if
you look at popular mechanics in the
1980s they were a fantastic source for
detailed information about locks 1970s
1980s you could find out everything that
you needed to know about interesting
high-security locks how to properly
secure the lock to your door if you're
doing self installation fantastic
information relax throughout Popular
Mechanics during this time their
circulation at the time was around 1.6
million people over the course of a
couple of decades that fluctuated but
those around where it was Bosnian bill
as a fantastic lock picker who has a
YouTube channel where he talks about
interesting locks he pulls them apart he
describes them in depth he picks them
tells everybody everything that he can
figure out about this one lock that some
Rando sent him on just one of his videos
and a relatively recent one he has 2.1
million views and this is one guy on one
video just one channel the availability
of and the desire for information about
security is incredible right now and
people's ability to contextualize this
information to process this information
is better than it has been and I think
that it's going to keep getting better
especially as we talk to them more
intelligently especially as we continue
to give them enough information so that
they can continue to put these things in
context very interesting to me was when
the lock bumping phenomenon blew up
because we very rarely see descriptions
in media of entry of how it works now
this is
the best description they say walk
pumping is done with a bump key which
means you modify a key with deep cuts
then put it in give it a tap or two and
you're in this is a super surface
understanding of it fine they then go on
to say gene holder with holder security
says this works because the vast
majority of locks are pin tumbler locks
which means there are two sets of
tumblers in the lock and once you tap
the bump key it separates the tumblers
to the key then turns that is so much
smarter than I see anybody writing about
locks up until this moment and this is
at the outset this is early in the wave
of the brief lock bumping hysteria and
you see more and more accurate you see
you know cutaways you see descriptions
people go to youtube news channels go to
youtube to see maybe not bosnian bill at
the time because i think that he started
as a counter 2007 this 2006 but you see
people drying content from those of us
that are already talking about the stuff
in giving incredibly correct
descriptions of what's happening to the
consumer knows exactly what it is now
just because there's more information
out there just because more people
desire information just because people
are able to put information in a better
context does not mean that ignorance has
gone away i know that all of you know
this so Aloha the locksmiths you can
trust part of their logo was added in
2010 sort of at the tail end of the the
bumping thing when they were having a
lot of friction in their community and
elsewhere when people started talking
about bumping when news organizations
started talking about bumping a lower
released a statement saying we've known
about this for 75 years but we haven't
been telling you to protect you that was
what they said it was three paragraphs
in a press release but that's exactly
what they were saying said we've known
about this for 75 years we do this but
we weren't going to tell you and now
that these idiots have blown the secret
you are all less safe if you want to be
more safe trust in a lowest certified
locksmith trust the brand don't figure
it out for yourself
so as consumers of course we also crave
convenience like I said convenience has
always been a part of the model of
selling security and it's an important
part of it I want to quickly cover the
history of the quick-set corporation
because for better or worse and it many
times in their history it was for worse
they were the kings of convenience and
security and I didn't quite realize what
an outsized influence they had on the
American on the American security
consumer until I went back through their
history so you know initially they just
make a lock that anybody can install and
they do the steering the post-world war
two housing boom and they make a ton of
money as a result because now people can
slap their own locks in their doors they
don't need a locksmith to come and
install it awesome that's their whole
concept that's the core concept that
normal human beings now we're going to
be able to install their unlocks and
other people have done this but man did
they pick the right time to come out
with a slightly better design than other
people when you know millions of houses
were being built in 64 they introduced
their quixey packaging and everybody in
their industry is forced to follow suit
this is the first time that you can pick
up a lock on the shelf and actually see
what the hell is going on inside see
what the parts are see what the key
looks like see all of that stuff first
time that you're able to do this and
consumers loved it they love to having
access to that and from that immediate
visual clarification of what was going
on inside of there and as a result all
of their competitors had to follow suit
you go to Home Depot you go to lowes
whatever you're going to see inside all
of the locks not inside the locks inside
their packaging in 98 they had remote
keyless entry for homes I did not know
that I learned that in the course of
putting this together I shocked that in
2002 they introduced their quick install
which was a just a slightly newer
version of their already decent install
it yourself product but the deal with
this one was that all the screws were
like pre together and just kind of had
to twist things in place and so this is
super handy for people but it was also
addressing an important security problem
talk about that in a minute 2007 they're
bringing consumers biometrics
doesn't go great but they brought
consumers biometrics and some people
loved it and it's cool NEETs fine and
the smart key the smart key allows you
to rapidly rekey your lock they were far
from the first people to do this look
back to links look back to you change
there have been designs for changeable
locks every time you insert a key back
to the early 1800s with super cool lever
locks the parrot optic lock that was
central in the great law country 1551
every time you put a new key in it would
code itself to that key you know it
would have to be unlocked at the time to
code itself but so this is existed but
once again man did they pick a great
moment for this to come out with a
slightly better design this was one of
the most important things to happen to
their company as far as sales and profit
are concerned 2009 they had smartcode
home automation they were already
rolling into home automation before
anybody was using the word smart lock
yet really interesting that they have
constantly tried to be on the lit the
leading edge of the wave of convenience
specifically and they've done very well
as a result looking at how master lock
has changed over the years is actually a
little more interesting because quickset
really stayed the course on convenience
always convenience first always more
convenience master lock in their famous
1980 Super Bowl ad had a rifleman shoot
one of their padlocks and then showed
that it still couldn't be pulled off the
shackle they were tough that was their
salwar tough then in the 90s this isn't
the greatest screenshot but that's a kid
stealing out of another kids Locker and
oh my god the video for it is fantastic
it is just like sketchy pans of hallways
as you in the POV of the burglar go
through you see a teacher you duck away
you steal something out of this kids
Locker still something out of this kids
Locker and then go to the next one but
ah you're confronted by a master lock
and another one and another one so you
should be scared and master lock will
save you we've heard this that's fine
for 1990 if you check out their newest
product offerings such as the master
lock dial speed which is a take-off on
the speed dial
which is a really cool lock dial speeds
fine the number of things that they
advertise that this thing is convenient
for they talk about the five-year
battery life they talk about the fact
that you can start using it right away
they have guest passes so that multiple
people can use the same padlock this is
actually a super useful feature they
talk about the fact that it is a
one-handed no look operation for ease of
use they talk about the ergonomics of it
they talk about how they can back up one
of your codes for you in case you forget
the combination to the lock they can
back it up online in case you forget and
they can help you out they also say that
it is high security once just high
security cool and afterwards at the very
end the very last thing we say is
shackles pretty good too they say it's I
think a hardened boron shackle awesome
so they bookend it with we're secure
check it out we're secure and then
they're like 10-15 conversations about
convenience and how it will be easy and
how it will solve small problems that
you've had and implementing security in
the past and for better or worse however
good this lock is I think that's pretty
good because we have to believe that
convenience and security are not a
dichotomy sometimes when you force
convenience yes you're taking a step
away from security but really
importantly inconvenience invites and
security this is actually a really
clever solution to the problem that it's
solving a lot of different agencies and
individuals need access to what this is
blocking so every one of them has their
own lock and they just made a chain out
of their locks but I want to point out
to you that this is a master number
three and this either of these I don't
know if this is a medico or not but
these are some serious all-weather much
higher security bad Luck's but that
doesn't matter because some idiot
someone put a master number three on
there and now literally weakest link in
the chain situation
it's silly and it's probably not the
right lock for it but that dial speed
has five different guest access numbers
that you could share between multiple
people in a community that needed access
to the same space then you could have a
strong chain one lock for better or
worse but at least everybody is on par
there you're not bowing to the the
weakest member of the team inconvenience
invites insecurity because everybody has
to work around it they will continue to
work around it to make sure that they
can continue doing whatever it is that
your product was supposed to keep them
safe while they were doing you're never
keeping someone safe while they're
sitting alone in a dark room you're
keeping them safe while they're trying
to do something and if you keeping them
safe constantly interferes with them
being able to do that if every time they
wanted this open someone had to call the
Forest Service who have one of the locks
on this chain to unlock their
high-security lock people would start
cutting the chain people would start
doing anything but having to call that
one guy every single time they needed
access or egress when you are securing
people you are securing them while they
try to do something and you have to pay
attention to what that something is
because if you interfere with it if you
make it inconvenient for them they will
obviate your security they will find a
way to hack around it and they will make
themselves more vulnerable as a result
some good examples of this so the
Kwikset SmartKey i said i mentioned
again people should rekey their locks
you should occasionally rekey your locks
kwikset introduced home reeking in 1960
some people used it particularly at the
time or DIY action going on but the
smart key came out and now people can
rekey their locks in a couple of seconds
I did it immediately after finding out
that we were burgled even though they
weren't able to get into the locks I
went through and I rekeyed all five of
my locks in approximately two minutes
most of that time was walking from lock
to lock and that made my wife feel that
much better and that meant the world to
me
your latchkey kid does lose his key a
key the lock costs nothing it's so easy
to do now every time like change your
password day comes up I just want to
yell change your lock rekey your lock
you've shown your password to your home
two million people today it's an
exaggeration a lot of people this year
though rekey your locks once in a while
so this is convenience that adds
security it allows people to take part
in a secure behavior and they'll love it
werd lock this might seem silly but word
lock is super cool a lot of people have
made word lock is just a dial
combination lock where each of the
wheels has different letters on it you
can make words all right so people
forget their combinations when people
have a combination delivered to them
maybe they forget at some point in time
if they can't change it up themselves so
it's great that you can change your
combination people to noon that forever
people have been doing make your
password a word to this lock since the
1840s that has existed what's super cool
about word lock is the algorithm when
you buy a word lock all of those wheels
have been chosen the letters on those
wheels have been chosen to give you the
maximum number of combinations of real
words because the problem with word
locks before word lock the brand is that
the key space was tiny yes you could
pick a random combination of letters but
you're not going to do that you're going
to pick a word it's the whole point but
word lock gave you an enormous key space
because they analyzed it they put the
right letters on the right wheels and
the right combinations and it's not all
the same different word locks love
different combos it's fantastic super
cool so this is convenience in all of
the ways the word locks have always been
convenient but keeping in mind the
security allowing people to participate
in the secure behavior residential
keypad locks again for better or worse
in a lot of ways but not knowing whether
your family has access to their home
sucks I
was talking maybe the solo was it you
yes and he said that you know he finally
gave him got a keypad lock for his
garage and it felt great he was
trepidatious about it but it felt great
because when he left his house now he no
longer had to worry if he had the key
could he go out for a run right now yes
he's not going to get locked out his
wife isn't going to get locked out
because he accidentally grabbed the
wrong car keys I've done this to my wife
we both ever stupid sets of car keys and
I accidentally had both of them at one
point I'm worked out but sucks but the
keypad you just wander in and out
everybody knows the password that's
great and it allows people to
participate in secure behaviors so
community is security if you want to
sell security dig into this area dig
into the fact that people care beyond
themselves beyond their families but
care about the security behaviors of
those in their communities and don't you
dare go trying to scare them about that
but communicate them with them about
that we have nothing to fear not
actually true but man it feels true
sometimes feels true when you're going
out to buy a lock it feels true when
you're engaging in other security
behaviors when you're choosing a stupid
password that you use everywhere else
because you know that your credit card
will just get mailed to you in two days
after it gets compromised we don't have
a lot to fear anymore because a lot of
the hard edges have been rounded off and
that's a great thing for society pay
attention to it when you were trying to
sell security let them eat info I'm not
saying drown people with info the first
time that you talked to them about your
product I'm saying make it available if
you find yourself thinking man if I
expose this information it's going to
make people less safe you're probably
wrong you might not be wrong a lot of
you are very smart if it's know you're
probably wrong anyway if you're thinking
you know I don't want to do this because
they don't deserve to know that's super
wrong so just give people access
freaking internet so easy
and we crave convenience we absolutely
do convenience has to go hand in hand
with security but convenience can
enhance security if your tool isn't
convenient it's going to make people
less safe in the end because they will
behave around it and you are not allowed
to get mad at them about that do you
want to sell a lot to me I want to see
that campaign about get in the house for
the first time with my wife I want to
see the campaign about throwing that
awesome party I want you to tell me
everything about this lock and I'm not
going to read it but it's going to make
me so happy that if I ever needed to
read it I know where to find it I will
trust you more just for telling me where
to find the information I love that
don't touch fear don't go anywhere near
it tell me how it allows me to engage in
a secure behavior while enjoying myself
the people my parents my parents when I
gave them a touch pad lock similar
experience but I swear it was the first
time they ever thought something i did
with blocks was at all interesting and
they raved about it they loved using it
it was fun for them and they stopped
hiding keys behind things on the
property which is awesome I digress this
is who I am I'm going to take some
questions and I potentially have a
little more survey data to cover if you
guys are interested in it about some
regulatory stuff but yeah that's me any
questions fabulous I teased you with the
survey data okay here we go all right so
fifth thing I haven't dug into this
enough yet but be careful with
legislating things particularly in
Europe we see a lot of interaction
between insurance companies and the
sorts of locks that you are allowed to
have on your home in in England there
have been controversial programs where
police will go around trying doors and
then reporting to insurance companies
when their people are leaving doors
unlocked if it is determined that you
left your door unlocked
it is it is obvious of course that you
will that you will not get a payout from
the insurance company because you
invited it i'll hit you right after this
thank you so it's a very different
situation there are a lot of regulations
around the standards the standards that
we have in America we have a few things
about physical resistance we have a lot
of stuff about build quality but we
don't have a lot about actual prevention
of access a lot of nothing about
surreptitious stuff really whatsoever
and I think in part that's because we
hate regulation so testing this theory I
asked another I basically I passed this
Google consumer surveys coupon around to
a lot of friends and I'd like ask this
question for me ask this question for me
I got a lot of free data thank you very
much Google consumer surveys I swear to
god I'll pay for some sometime you guys
are doing fine ok if an organization in
your neighborhood or apartment building
mandated the use of locks on all
residences I want to be very clear the
only thing we're asking them is if they
mandated that we have locks most people
have never even imagined I promise I'll
tell you what it says I'm sorry most
people have never even imagined going
without a lock and so I'm just asking
them that baseline what if our you know
neighborhood organization mandated that
everybody had to have a lock in this
community almost fifty percent of people
would be supportive of that about forty
percent of people would be neutral and
thirteen percent would be opposed to
even that level of regulation just
saying they have to have a lock now as
we extend this outward if your town or
city proposes this forty-one percent
would be supportive at the town city
level neutral sitting at 39 and oppose
jumps up to almost twenty percent now as
we expand further away from the
community that we consider part of our
realm of security if your state proposes
it neutral now is winning at forty-five
percent supportive has dropped all the
way down to thirty three percent and
opposed was now finally crossed that
twenty percent threshold now I did go on
to ask about what it would be like at
the national level and oh the script
flipped but I think it might be because
I use the word Congress
word choice is super important so I do
not trust the the final data point but
all man if you're if you're mandating
the use of locks just the use of locks
not special locks not certain locks not
locks of a you know whatever if you're
mandating the use of locks people are
not into that on the national level holy
crap but in their own communities you
can get some traction okay that's the
next chunk of survey data that I'm going
to be digging more into and exploring I
will take your question but thank you
all very much I appreciate you thank