uh yes today i'm going to present a
bodybuilding injection attack on
on a recent soc
and
the main idea is to attack the hardware
es accelerator of this attribute using
body biasing injection
so the motivation behind this this
presentation actually uh i'm going to
ask you a question if anyone here is
familiar with electromagnetic fault
injection
okay this is cool anyone here is
familiar with bodybuising faulty
injection
only three okay so this is my motivation
actually but the biasing injection is is
a
is a certain of of a recent photo
injection attack it's not very well
studied in the literature i think there
are only two or three papers that
describe this kind of attacks
so this is why actually i'm trying to
investigate this attack
and recently i have seen a lot of
devices that have been deployed in the
market such as hardware wallets for
example and my role is to evaluate this
kind of wallets against fault injection
and side children attacks
this is why investigating new attacks is
very important for me
so i'm going to to talk a little bit
about fault and text
uh why we need faults
why why we perform faults actually so
the main idea of injecting faults is to
to perform
to perform a perturbation during the
execution of sensitive operations for
example if you are performing secure
boot and you are injecting faults during
the secure boots
there is a possibility of bypassing the
signature verification for example
the same if you are performing crypto
operations like es for example you can
inject during
certain rounds of the es in order to
extract the key using differential fault
analysis
uh so you can find here a very
interesting paper about a guy who
already attacked the say yes of
playstation using differential fault
analysis i don't know if you if you know
this paper or not but it was very
interesting actually to show a practical
attack
[Applause]
for glitches part which is considered
one of the fault injection attack
techniques
it's a very low cost technique you can
implement it using a mosfet for example
the main idea is to drop the voltage
level of the chip to
to a very low level
uh however there are some challenges
while you are performing uh
uh power glitch attacks the main idea of
the of the first challenge actually is
that the effect of the glitch is very
general on the chip itself
for example if you are attacking a
complex soc and you would like to target
the crypto core of the chip it's very
difficult you'll find a lot of pins for
different vdd and you don't know exactly
which one you have to glitch even if you
are glitching the correct one you you
won't be more precise
the second the second one is
electromagnetic fault injection and the
main idea is that you have a very high
voltage you are going to apply is a high
voltage into a coil
trying to generate electromagnetic and
this electromagnetic when you touch
the problems electromagnetic problem
with the chip itself you're going to
create perturbation
uh well if i'm go i've if i'm talking
about the mfi it has a
this to build a setup it's a medium
coast if you compare it for example with
glitches it's not low cost compared to
bar glitches but it's a it's cause it's
it's between actually the laser and more
glitches
the third one is laser attacks so
uh it's very expensive if you would like
to do it you you need to decap the chip
uh in order to to find the substrate you
you can decap the chip using the front
side or back side
uh the main idea is that you hit the
surface of the chip using a laser beam
and the laser is going to induce current
and the current is going to change the
state of the transistors from one to
zero trying to
create errors
as i said here it's you need to decap
the chip it's expensive it needs more
experience as well
now let me discover bodybuising
injection with you
so the main idea of bodybuilding
injection is to
is to apply a high voltage into the
surface of the chip using a needle so
the main idea is that the needle is
going to bypass a current to the surface
of the chip
trying to create errors
it was proposed by philippe morin in
and this kind of fault injection
techniques you need to decap the trip
itself
so
almost it needs the same preparation
like laser attacks
and the effect of the bbi
i can say it's like a
localized ground glitching
why it's a localized ground glitching so
if i'm
if i'm going to describe actually the
the
silicon model which was proposed by
philippe morin
you can see here
you can see here for example if you are
going to inject a voltage
a high voltage here into the substrate
the main idea is that the ground of the
cmos is going to change as well
the same for the vdd of the cmos and if
you will find the difference between
them is like a glitch however it's a
localized glitch why because
the
the r of the substrate is changing from
from one point to another
well in car this 2020 actually
there was a very nice setup which was
presented by colin
uh it was a very very local setup
the main idea is that you have a
a very small voltage which is
is used to charge some capacitors
and during the injection times this
voltage is going to be increased
using a transformer
and after that you are going to touch
the the surface of the chip using a
needle which is connected to the
transformer itself so it's a very very
low cost setup it's very interesting so
i started to
to think about this uh
to think about this setup and to build
it in in our lab
[Music]
it's very interesting while you are
performing faulty injection to to have
the
double polarity
i mean
you it's very important to have a
positive pulse and negative pulse why
because if you are
injecting a back side you may need the
positive balls but if you are injecting
on the front side you you need the
reverse polarity and also you can find
some
points on the surface of the chip which
are vulnerable to
the positive pulse and also other points
which are vulnerable to the negative
pulse
so i'm going to solve this problem in
the design of colin because it doesn't
support this
this flexibility and also there is a
external power supply that i'm going to
add to to make the system more portable
just plug it to to the usb itself and
you don't need external power supply
so this is my design
the main idea is that you have
yes so when i did that
this is a design of colleen which is in
red
i just added an onboard vcc
that may come from an iot chip or an mcu
for example and after that i added a
charge circuit in order to
to charge this vcc on a controlled value
so you could have the say the ability to
have a flexible voltage so you can
change it if you want and also a
discharge circuit in order to uh switch
off the injector if you would like
and also in terms of the polarity you
can see that i take the the
one point from the secondary of the
transformer and connected it to the
positive and also the negative is
connected to 0.2
and if you would like for example to
inject a positive pulse you can inject
this point to the needle and the
negative pulse to the ground of the chip
and if you would like to reverse it will
be more flexible
so
so this is a final pcb that i already
i already did you can find that here i
use a sid wino shell which is an mcu
that you can use to control
the charge and discharge
and also it can feed the the circuit
with the vdd with 5 volt maximum
here there is an sma connector for
triggering the
the voltage
for triggering the uh the fault
injection and here for example there is
a needle it's connected to the positive
and the negative here is going to
connect to the ground but if you would
like it to reverse the polarity of the
of the voltage policy you can connect it
to the negative and this positive is
going to
be connected to the to the ground of the
device itself so you can see that i have
an mcu that can deliver five voltage the
terminus ratio here is is 500 so sorry
it's 50. so we can obtain a programmable
voltage to until 250 volt
i already obtained the polar uh dual
polarity so we can inject positive and
negative pulses so i would like to thank
my my teammate olivier for supporting
soldiering the small components here
because i'm not very good at soldering
electronic components
so you can find here that i already
proved that i have a flexible uh
flexible voltage that i can change it
very very easy so if i'm going to here
on the
on the x axis this is number of pulses
so if you increase the number of pulses
to charge the capacitor so i have a
programmable voltage from that can start
from lower than two one until five so if
you come if you multiply it by 50 you
will you will obtain a programmable
voltage until 250.
so i need now to verify and validate
exactly
say
if my injector is is able to inject
errors or not so this is why i'm using
to
a device under test but i don't like to
to talk about the name of the vendor for
the moment so i'm using a low ghost and
low power soc
it contains a wi-fi and bluetooth
interfaces it's fabricated on a 40
nanometer technology and recently it has
been deployed in hardware wallet this is
why i'm interested in this chip
so the first thing to validate the
design is the design of the
of the injector is that i did already a
glitchable application so just to to see
if i'm going to modify the value of this
counter during
counting so i'm going to inject the
fault here
so the main idea is to scan the surface
of the chip here from the x and y
and trying to inject faults during the
execution of this code and especially
the
the counter uh
the counterpart so i'm going to run the
glitchable applications and scan the
overall
surface and i am going to try to dual
polarity
of the of the voltage
my setup
if you can see it so
you can see on the right here this is
the injector it's on the top of the of
the chip the chip is decapped of course
you can see it here
and i have a table a very cheap table to
to move the prop xy
and i have an oscilloscope uh
in order to reduce the support traces
and to see exactly what happens while
i'm injecting false
uh sometimes i have external power
supply here
for there are some chips that maybe 250
voltage is not sufficient for faulting
so maybe i will need the help of the
external
power supply
so
i already obtained successful faults
when i have a positive pulse so i obtain
the zoom
that i already was able to
to skip from from the loop to modify the
value of the counter however for
negative pulse i obtain some false for
example in this zone and also some
separate points here
you can see that there are some
physical locations on the chip which is
vulnerable to positive pulses and also
negative also this is very important
while you are doing a fault injection
evaluation especially if you are
targeting uh
maybe if you start
you start the evaluation you inject a
positive pulse you are targeting for
example the cryptocor it doesn't doesn't
work the attack so you have to change
the polarity of the
of the voltage
uh as i said i use a i use the
oscilloscope in order to register the
power traces
so here this is my code without
injecting any fault there is a loop here
so the chip here is doing nothing
exactly just counting so after that
there is a communication to send the
value of the counter that was counted
so i'm going to inject here a positive
pulse you can see it
that it's negative it's like it looks
like a negative glitch
and after that the chip goes for the
same activity like here but in this case
i already modified the value of the
count
if you if you inject a negative pulse
the effect will be positive here and
will be and the
and the power trace you can see that
it's cut
uh
in in a very short time compared to this
one but i already modified also the the
value of the counter
let me talk about the hardware aes
accelerator this is chip actually
uh contains a crypto cryptographic
hardware accelerator such as es sha rsa
elliptic curve random number generation
and also it contains a
es 128 actually the es accelerator you
can configure it from
128 to 156. so this is the main target
is to break the ces using advising
injection
i started to measure power consumption
during the execution of of the es so i'm
very sorry i won't be able actually to
to show the firmware that i called the
es because it as the name of the vendor
you can you can you can you can use the
name of the vendor from the firmware
itself so here is the es
which is uh
which is executed so in my firmware
simply just erase the trigger
and then i call the es and then i i
the trigger value will be low so i will
be able to to know exactly where the aes
execu is executed but here in this trace
it's it's very difficult to
to identify exactly where the ies is as
executed so this is why i i performed
something called
leakage detection using a signal to
noise ratio
for example here this is a scenario on
the keys so you can find here the keys
are loaded
and here is the plain text
and on white the ciphertext is loaded so
in between between of course between the
the loading of the plain text and the
ciphertext say yes is
executed so now i know very well that
the es is during this time period so
i have a very a very short timing window
for injecting
false otherwise i'm going the experiment
will take a lot of time so now i already
reduced the one fault parameter which is
a the offset that may uh increase the
time of evaluation
uh the main idea that i would like to
perform a differential fault analysis
there there was a very interesting paper
published in
uh the main idea is that if you can
inject a fault for example this is the
es this is round nine and this is round
ten but if you are able to inject a
fault
before the mexican of round nine so the
fault is will be propagated in the
overall colon after the mixed colon and
by the end it will be
propagated using uh using this figure
actually you will find that the first
byte is modified and after that you will
you will find that it will be like
diagonal uh
modification uh
to perform this kind of of attacks using
dfa
if you if you are able of course to
inject a fault in only one byte uh on
the on the before the mixer colon what
you needed just for to attack one colon
key you need two volts uh
two folds for per colon here
that that will help you to attack the
overall key of the es
well
so i started to repeat the same
experiment i have the yes which is
running i already know where the es is
executed and i started to scan the tube
so you'll find here i obtained some
faults the
using the the maximum voltage of the
injector which is which is 250 volt so
here i obtained some faults but
unfortunately
the fault is that i obtained it's uh
it's like only uh on the ciphertext
itself so
the output is like uh
the ciphertext and i already modified
some ciphertext values while it's zeros
or one okay so on only four bytes of the
ciphertext so it seems that it seems to
be like the communication of the
ciphertext so it's it's the mcu i think
the mcu uh
i already defaulted the mcu in this case
because it's used for loading
a value into the register however
after that i started to think that the
250 volt
is not able to fault say
the es
crypto uh on the chip itself so i
started to think about increasing a
little bit the voltage so i this is why
i use external power supply so you can
see that okay with 250 i was able to to
fault a cpu application for this chip
but after that i used
an external power supply to give me 10
volt and now i have like 500 voltage
that i can inject into into the circuit
itself uh i spent some time to
to optimize the faults uh in order to
inject only faults for the aes and
and only in round nine so i found a very
interesting spot here that i obtained
already a success rate like 60
percentage that i'm able to uh to fall
to the aes itself so this means that the
the escript core is here
but it needs
more voltage okay
so you can see here
uh i already registered a bar
consumption trace during the successful
fourth of the years so here is the
effect of the body biasing injection
actually
however
this point is saturated because uh
is a vertical resolution of the
oscilloscope
was was like above the maximum so this
is why you can find this value is cut
and flat
uh
you can see here on the right
here's there is a map that shows that
how many
how many times i folded single byte for
every column you can see that i'm
already
above to 80 percentage
80 faulty
cases per column
so i have a lot of interesting faults to
to perform the attack the differential
fault analysis so i was able actually to
attack the overall key of the es using
this result
i have some notes during the this
experiment
if you are going to try this kind of
attacks you have to
have to be careful if you are injecting
a high voltage into the substrate itself
you are going to damage the strip i
already damaged three chips
uh
and also it's very important while you
are doing
decapping the chip you have to be
careful also
because you may
damage the chip itself
and also you have to avoid moving the
needle on the x and y while you are not
while you are in touch with the chip
because also you are going to damage the
uh the chip so it's better to if you
would like to move while x and y to you
have to move up a little bit the needle
and then move move it while x and y and
then make it down again
so the
conclusion
so i i already built a chip and the
compact setup for bbi
i use this uh
it's a homemade injector to
to bring the hardware as accelerator or
fluorescent soc
i just need only 10k trials to to dump
the overall key of the es
uh
the silicon baguette which is my
injector will be i'm going to to release
it on feed days on on the github
uh regarding the future work actually
i'm going to evaluate more resources
using this technique
and also i'm going to study the effect
of this voltage injection
of this injection technique on
uh unsecured elements whereas you can
find some glitch detectors and try to to
see exactly what happened
yeah thank you very much
[Applause]
i don't know if you have any questions
yeah
uh what was your uh reference signal for
your trigger
don't aren't your your your your uh i
can control firing at a specific time
relative to something else i can i can
control the trigger from the firmware
itself
oh so oh so you've modified the firmware
uh yes custom firmware yeah the hardware
accelerator you can call it from a
firmware use
from from the firmware yes but after
that you can easily add a trigger before
and after the
launch of the
start of the es yeah
yeah how reliable is this like if you
were to you know tear apart the setup
and then try and go back and find that
spot again i can reproduce attack very
easily
if you can find here
[Music]
this is my the chip after the the
experiment here you can find that
the i injected a lot of faults here
because uh this is a the fault where i i
already obtained for faulting the
communication of the ciphertext
but here there is a yes and this point
is a
as a whereas the crypto core is uh
is on the trip itself
yeah
do we have any questions
[Music]
a very interesting talk thank you um so
from this picture it's it's a little
hard to tell
if this is the back side of the chip or
the top side i'm assuming this is the
back side of the tube okay and was it
bga so you went through the pcb and then
into the lead frame sorry uh
so are we looking at the back side of
the pcb and you've gone through the pcb
through the lead frame
i didn't hear you very well
um
i'm just wondering what we're looking at
if this is the back side of the chip
yeah shouldn't there be bga or is this
it's an soc it's a mic uh it's a
microcontroller it's not it's not it's a
it's an soc for low power which is used
for low power applications
uh but it's not an fpga no no i mean um
so you've gone through the pcb and i was
wondering if there's metal contacts in
there and then it looks like we're
looking at the lead frame that the chip
is mounted on
ah yes yes the chip uh yeah the chip
actually is
soldered on the back side of the pcb
itself okay okay yeah then there's
nothing yeah you're not interfering with
any signals okay maybe i didn't like to
show the overall setup of the of the uh
of the pcb because we have a i took a
black hat so we will show that there so
okay that that makes sense and i
if i'm understanding correctly did you
say that you can also do body biasing
through the top side of the chip yes the
front side yeah but decaping the chip
from the front side is very challenging
because the bounding wire it needs some
some preparation and in the lab we don't
have this tool for the moment this is
why we use a backside yeah and do you
have to remove the passivation oxide or
sorry usually there's a passivation
oxide that's deposited on on top yeah
i mean you have to be careful because
you have you shouldn't remove the
well if you are performing a front side
the decapping you have to
be careful actually because the bounding
wiring if you cut one wire it's okay
it's done the trip too
so
i haven't done before a front side
decapping
maybe you'll leave it to my ease here
you can
yeah i can do it here
any other questions yeah
no more
then please another round of applause
for cream okay thank you very much