thank you steven sam
thank you very much audio okay
all right
thanks for sticking with us through day
one hope everybody's having a good time
so far and i know we're not butting up
against anything there's a happy hour
after this but uh i think it starts at
eight or something so we won't go quite
that long uh with that introduction we
probably can skip over the first slide
you know the name of our talk here it's
some of the research that we did into
hacking an industrial control system
specifically some building automation
uh for the who am i my name is steve
pavone as mentioned in the introduction
i'm the head of advanced threat research
at trellix uh i also the team i think
lovingly maybe not lovingly entitled me
as the excel guru i think probably
because i have the management title my
name so i'm not allowed to do anything
technical i guess uh but i can write a
mean excel function but outside of that
i do a lot of vulnerability root cause
analysis my background's in network
security reverse engineering
exploitation but this was really my
first foray into hardware hacking which
uh has sam has a lot more experience in
sam
thanks steve yeah my name is sam quinn
i'm a senior security researcher at
trellix steve had a cool line that says
he's the head of advanced threat
research so i wanted my bullet points to
be the same length so i'm the tail of it
the bottom yep the butt
i uh
no one really i self-con
self um identify as elite hacker hacksaw
my core interest could have been
summarized by just hacking in general
but um i definitely like exploitation
hardware hacking for sure
embedded systems like iot devices and
then like os fundamentals and things
like that and when sam and i are not uh
out finding crashes crashes are out
finding us we're both avid bikers as you
can tell here uh these are actual videos
of us both crashing and we'll say the
only common denominator is that sam was
with me on the trip and the rights
because you can't even ride the trail
house neither can you clearly anyways
let's talk about how we uncovered this
target why we went after
access control specifically
and
because we're at hardware io we're going
to spend a lot more time talking about
hardware at black hat we're going to
spend a little bit more time talking
about the vulnerabilities themselves but
you'll get a good taste for what we
found as well so a little bit of a 60 40
there
we look back over the last couple of
years at some of the escalation of the
geopolitical
cyber scene the warfare targeting
industrial control system
building automation systems obviously
we've seen attacks against things like
gas and oil pipelines water treatment
telecom the energy grid going back
nearly a decade or more but access
controls not only for us represented
kind of that transition from the
physical to digital space
but it was also that single point of
failure and very little research has
been done in the area of access control
and it serves as one of those uh really
powerful boundaries that that attackers
still
can
can gain access to
so that brings us to the target this is
the linnell s2 mercury board i know it's
a mouthful but the board itself here is
an access control panel a dual reader
controller
it's it's hard to miss as you can see
bright red and it's manufactured by a
company called mercury which is hid
global but has a sticker on it that's
linnell s2 and lynnell is part of the
global hvac company carrier that
everybody's probably familiar with
now i put a lot of time into this slide
as you can see this is one of the most
you know proud diagrams we've ever put
together here but this simple
representation is just the board and its
usual deployment which is it manages a
number of card readers or controllers i
think this one supports up to 64
independent card readers downstream but
you can daisy chain them together to
support an infinite number of readers or
in any kind of relay they're typically
deployed on the local network you don't
see a lot of these internet connected
unless it's uh probably a
misconfiguration but it's possible and
they're managed by a software called
onguard threadlinell which is the
management software that does all the
provisioning of badges and access
control and users and it just tells the
board what to do the board's just a dumb
relay and inputs and outputs
the other thing that caught our
attention for this and it might be a
little hard to read i don't know how
good your eyes are but
we we saw a statement a marketing
statement that came out a couple of
years ago for this board saying that
specifically the 4420 we're looking at
had been uh following rigorous security
vulnerability interop testing had been
approved for use in government
facilities well of course for us as
security researchers we get the the
finger-licking moment right i looked in
the chops here and this was probably the
most enticing part of going after the
board for us is hey this is government
certified what does that actually mean
and a spoiler alert it's it's not a
whole lot
uh furthermore we found out in the
process that the board was not just
certified for use in government
facilities but also added to the apl
which is the approved product list
meaning a government can go look in that
data sheet or that list pick a product
and it has been as we saw rigorously
tested uh maybe not as much
to acquire the target originally we went
on our boomer friendly marketplace ebay
and and bought this device uh 1500 bucks
or something uh we did not manage it
with the on guard software at first that
came much later in the process and it
really didn't end up being that
essential to actually uh hacking the
device so sam's going to talk to you
guys a little bit about some of the
hardware steps and then we'll we'll
finish uh talking through the the
discoveries that we found as well
absolutely thanks steve so um the next
this whole talk i guess will be mostly
kind of our process looking into
researching it
and we really wanted to focus on the
hardware stuff here so this could be a
review for some of you experts out there
but we wanted to dive into a lot of the
parts and components and how we approach
this ourselves so um the first thing we
did
was um when we get the board the first
thing we like to do is start looking at
all of the components the cpu and try to
start doing some os int and recon on
those devices by trying to look up data
sheets things like that to get pin outs
and and things that you can potentially
use
later on down the road
we're also looking for simple um i o
ports that we can connect to um like joe
grant said in the keynote this morning
um you know the path of least resistance
is what the hackers always like to do so
that's what we're trying to find out
here is trying to find where these ports
are and try to identify them a little
bit
so as just like any experienced
experienced traveler knows exactly where
their towel is an experienced hacker
knows exactly where the uart is
and that's what we kind of identified
this potential four pin output as being
four pins usually kind of relates to
what a uart looks like
and then there was also this nice 20 pin
port on the device which uh kind of
could be could be a potential jtag
so um at this point we're still just
rudimentary poking around with a
multimeter trying to identify what
things are ground where things are you
know power
that can help narrow down what the scope
of these ports could be but really the
main way of trying to figure out what
kind of
data is being transmitted over these
ports is using something like a logic
analyzer that's exactly what we did here
so when we hooked up those for that
potential uart connection to the logic
analyzer and then booted up the device
you can see that one of the pins
this one up the top was
obviously getting some data
so that was exciting so we knew that
that is probably serial uart and
unlike steve he can actually read fluent
hex i don't know it's like the weirdest
thing useless too yeah he got it really
excited about this because he's like
that says wrong boot but to me i didn't
know but so uh that was great so now we
do know that we do have you know async
serial data being sent over this wire
and that is exactly when we ran into our
first roadblock so this screenshot was
the last moment in time that data was
being transmitted over the uart
um and it's kind of in an arbitrary spot
like you can see some services have
already started
but eventually it just halted it was
printing out quite a few messages per
second and then it just went
dead silent so we knew that it was
getting disabled somewhere and most
likely in software because if it was
disabled in hardware we wouldn't have
seen anything obviously
so our approach to re-enabling the uart
was to try to override the init variable
from the bootloader
and this is how the linux kernel starts
up
and if we can overwrite any init
variables
or the init scripts with our own script
like bin sh it wouldn't disable the uart
because none of that code is running
so then our next step was trying to find
where that script is this is just a
sneak preview of the script that
eventually we found
you can see in the the comment there it
says
disable disable the serial port if it's
currently enabled and that's why we
probably saw some messages being printed
across because it was enabled and then
it figured it out and disabled it later
on
so this is the script that we wanted to
find and try to comment it out
one of the other things with that level
of access by changing the init variable
is that we could potentially change the
root password and use the uart console
just as if we were logging into the
linux operating system normally
and then as a bonus dump the entire
firmware and start analyzing some of the
system binaries
manually offline
and this is exactly when we ran into
roadblock 2 when we're trying to change
that init variable and i'll let steve
cover that
yeah thanks sam so what you'll see i'm
going to advance the slide here and you
can see kind of uh part of the u-boot
process here one of the strings we
called out says hit keys to stop auto
boot you've probably seen something
similar there's typically a timer that
counts down from 3 to one zero giving
the user time to to input a keyboard
keystroke and halt the boot process for
us it was hard coded statically to zero
and so that was why we were unable to
have interactive commands to the yaboot
shell
um so
since we had that jtag port that sam
talked about earlier what we figured
here is it'd be a little bit easier to
actually modify the running system using
jtag instead of trying to dump a
modified system image and then
reflashing it back to the device so
that's our next approach here so try to
use
jtag
so we figured out exactly why this
variable was set if we look at the uh
the documentation for u-boot we can see
that the boot delay variable which is
that zero that was set
means if it's set to zero it can prevent
you from interact and entering
interactive commands again forever well
forever is a very short time in our
world just below that you can see that
if you set the variable to negative one
it will disable auto boot so our goal
was to actually patch that value out
from zero to negative one
so as a recap our approach here leverage
jtag to dump the bootloader image we'll
try to reverse engineer the u-boot image
to find out where that boot delay
variable is checked and then we'll use
something like j-link to insert a
breakpoint just before that check is
done patch it out from zero to negative
one and go and that's exactly what we
did so let's look back at the 20 pin
candidate on the board this is a
close-up shot of our jtag
we also could have used something like
joe grant's jtagulator you probably saw
that in the keynote this morning
unfortunately it just wasn't nearly pink
enough for our purposes so we needed
something with a little more color and
we chose the segger j-link so this this
beautiful device here is a
simple it comes with software it comes
with the pin out so you can determine
like we just went on the segger website
and got the 20 pin pin out for jtag here
for our purposes we went through and
tested the ground pins all were on the
right side we checked that the 5 volt
supply was indeed getting 5 volts
through a multimeter and by powering it
with a power supply you can also yolo
the approach and just randomly plug
stuff in and eventually you're going to
get there but it might do some some
damage to the underlying components that
way
as a
snapshot of what our typical wiring
project looks like this is our actual
cabinet in our data center attached to
our lab versus the one immediately next
door to us so this is how our projects
are typically wired this one was
absolutely no different we followed the
doc octopus model and got everything uh
wired up here but this is the jtag after
all those 20 pins or the right pins are
connected here uh we did include a
little uh oregon area brew there then in
casa brew as a shout out to where we're
from
but that set us up to do the software
analysis you can download the j-link
software directly from segger's website
and the way that it works is it
essentially once it runs it's waiting
for the cpu to establish a connection
once it makes that connection then you
can provide it with some inputs here now
sam what you'll see here sam put
together this little j-link xe script uh
we give it the device id which is the
atmel cpu the rest of the parameters we
didn't even bother to really look into
we just took defaults from a script we
found online but most importantly is the
option to set a custom script at the end
there
now we're not typically in the habit of
sharing exploit scripts or anything that
could enable the adversary in this case
we're going to make a little bit of an
exception here and share this so in
three two one
yes that's right sam wrote an entire
script with the letter h in it to halt
the cpu so you know you're efficient as
an engineer when the name of the script
is 11 times longer than the contents
itself regardless it was very effective
in giving us a halt or setting an
automatic breakpoint whenever we ran
that and we could use this to uh to
debug where the boot delay was set
so let's go on to dumping the image here
we had a very good idea of where the
bootloader the ubud image was being
loaded because during the bootstrap
process you can see here uh there are
eighty thousand bytes copied from the
address of twenty thousand two seven
three f zero zero zero zero so we knew
the size and from where and to once it
was being copied and that gave us the
ability to use another command from
j-link which is the save bin or save
binary command
yes they're very creative at naming to
take a copy of that u-boot image for
analysis and that's exactly what we did
the next thing was to open a debugger
something like uh or a disassembler
something like ida where we could look
into this image that we have and
actually find the the strings of
interest and find that boot delay
variable so you know obviously all lead
hackers the first thing they do is run
strings on the binary and we were
looking for that hit keys to stop auto
boot and of course it was found in the
binary that gave us a rom address here
uh and the reason we don't have a i
guess i'll back up for a second and say
ida didn't do a great job of processing
this file because it doesn't know what
it is it's just a raw binary it doesn't
know if it's an l for a pe or whatever
and so we have to do a little bit of
code cleanup function declaration and
definition uh defining offsets and
that's really what we're trying to do
here in addition to just finding that
boot delay variable so anyways we found
this realm address followed that and
obviously that took us to the pointer to
where the string was
then we had to because we couldn't
cross-reference and ida didn't have
context for cross-references here we
used that value as an immediate value to
look up an ida and that gave us the
location of where it was found
when we double clicked on that it took
us here now i may read printable hex
ascii which is again that useless skill
coming from writing ips signatures for
too long but i don't read hex arm
assembly up codes so um so we had no
idea what this says we use the shortcuts
in idap
and f to define the functions and
procedures uh and after doing that we
got a much cleaner view this is
obviously the graph format view of the
where our string was being referenced
more importantly right after the pointer
to that string address is a function
sturt l which i'm sure you guys know is
a string to long now this is actually a
wrapper for start l we just named it
that way but that makes a lot of sense
because that's probably an ascii value
for that boot delay being checked
converted into a long and then processed
in the in the boot process
and so that's that's what we want to do
is set a breakpoint just before this
function call and do that analysis
so here is our set breakpoint command
you'll see the first thing we did is we
took that address just before the stir
to long and the the only argument to
that function it comes from r0 and r0 is
actually that value which has the boot
delay so if we dump the memory at that
address and just take two bytes we can
see that it is actually
hard coded there to the little endian
value of 0 30 right which is ascii 0.
then we use the w2 or write 2 byte
commands to write negative 1 or 2d 31 to
that to that value
and after that we can just hit go to
continue and all of a sudden now we've
we've patched that boot delay variable
so just to kind of recap the process
we're going to show a little video here
i'll set the stage for what you just saw
we're going to kind of repeat it in
video format the left side of the screen
is going to be the device and and the
the boot up process on the right side is
our jtag connection from the attacker's
laptop and the first thing that we're
going to do is run sam's really awesome
super elite script here and it'll wait
for the processor to connect and we
check if it's halted and sure enough the
cpu is halted at this point
so we can continue on by setting a break
point here right again that's the break
point right before that start to l is
checked and hit go and the boot process
continues and it does take a minute or
so to hit our break point but when we
hit the break point what we'll do at
that point is make sure that the cpu is
halted again running the same command
and that it did stop at the break point
that we expect it to and we can see that
sure enough it did stop at the break
point that we expected and now we can do
that inline patch so here is where we're
going to dump the two bytes of memory we
see that ascii
hex 30 which is our zero we use the
write two command to write 2d negative
one
and then we just hit go and what you'll
see is as soon as we hit go here if you
watch the left side it's almost
instantaneous how quickly it drops you
into that you boot shell and from you
boot shell then we can actually do
things like help and run those commands
but more importantly we can now set the
arguments that sam talked about earlier
which is overriding the init scripts
with bin sh and getting us a true root
shell on the device so that was the
command that you might have missed just
earlier there is setting the boot
arguments and the init script and
overwriting it and now we actually run
who am i and we actually have a full
root shell
on the device
so
that's a great place uh for us to
continue we were able to you know from a
root shell obviously this is a great
leverage point to do for the research
and look at the system binaries
down the road a little further we ran
into another roadblock which is our
roadblock 3 here and that was the
hardware based watchdog timer so as we
were doing as we were enabling break
points and hitting them we would find
that about every 15 seconds or so the
system would reboot and this made a lot
of sense because there's a watchdog
timer with a 15 second interval so our
approach to disabling that was very
similar we wanted to find out how did
the developers intend for the watchdog
to be enabled or disabled
if we could use that we would pause the
cpus using the same script and overwrite
the watchdog timer values and then
validate that it was disabled so if we
look at the atmel data sheet sam talked
a little bit about the osnp process
earlier on and the importance of of you
know using data sheets and documentation
we were able to find very quickly the
register that controls the watchdog
timer and the specific bit here which is
the wd dis bit that if it's zero it
enables it if it's one it disables it so
obviously that was the change we wanted
to make
a little further down in the data sheet
we could see the address of where the
watchdog timer mode register is loaded
and more importantly the access so it's
a read write once register that's a
mouthful but what that means is if the
cpu or user or anyone modifies either
read or write from that register at any
point it's then disabled indefinitely
from that point on until we reboot so we
knew that we had to pause or break point
before that register was ever touched in
any way and then again the 15th bit here
you'll see is that wd dis so when we
patch this out we'll be working on the
second byte of a d word or the 15th bit
as we watch the boot up we'll see that
the that this is actually the watchdog
timer mode register value so the the
register address that we saw before up
here is actually pointing to that and
the value is right here
and by if you recall the second byte
here that 2f is the one that has the
15th bit that's what we wanted to modify
so again very similar commands here we
take the memory at that address and one
byte further in so instead of ending in
44 right we go to 45 for the second byte
that's a 2f and obviously we want to
change that the leading bit or the 15th
bit from a 0 to a one that changes to f
to af and that gives us our actual patch
and by hitting go we continue in the
which watchdog timer is disabled and we
thought that was cool af
be here all week actually i'm leaving
tonight okay so we do see the d ward is
now actually modified the second byte
for some reason it actually modified all
four bytes we went back and tried to
figure it out couldn't come up with any
reason why after modifying one byte it
changed the whole thing didn't matter it
achieved our purposes we can see the
watchdog timer disabled and then later
on when the binaries were trying to
access the watchdog timer they had no
context of it and of course they threw
errors as well so this got us to where
we needed to be
okay so that's a lot of work just to
begin analysis we've accomplished
literally nothing useful except giving
us a jumping off point but it did give
us a great place to start uh software
hacking and sam could take over for that
for a while i know don't leave yet
um i know we're here all for you know
hardware and stuff but there is some
cool stuff here so um the first thing
that we we want to do is try to find the
most impactful
attack vectors and obviously as we all
know remote attack vectors are juicy so
doing a simple nmap scan we can see that
the this access control board is
actually indeed running a whole web
server and then it had another listening
port that we eventually found out later
is how it communicates with the onguard
software but look browsing to the
um the web server that's running on the
device we noticed that it had a full
login page and we'll show you just how
impactful that is later but um it was
pretty impressive to see that it's doing
like cookie validation there's users
accounts and stuff all built into just
this little device however
none of the badge or door access control
uh like
settings were managed through this so
this was pretty much a web server meant
to get the device provisioned and set up
on the network for the first time and
things like that so this is like the
network settings that you can see where
it's um you can set up like dns and ip
addresses and things like that really
nothing to do with badge management or
anything but um
we did notice from this
that a lot of the user inputs had
restricted characters and things like
that so got us kind of
curious into
why they want those characters so
restricted and that
could be because all of the websites
are all those pages were dynamically
created in cgi bin files so if you're
unfamiliar cgi bins are compiled in this
case c code that dynamically create web
pages and whatnot um
and when we interact with them they all
run as root so us logging into the login
page you can see it is running as root
so this is exciting
if we can find any vulnerabilities in
the cgi files we could potentially have
we don't even have to escalate our
privileges at all
and um little cherry on top all of these
binaries were compiled with symbols so
looking at them in ida pro
you don't have to even guess what the
functions do you can just read the
function name so that was also really
really great
so this is when we started to actually
start hunting for system calls and try
to get potential command injections
because we already know that we don't
have to
escalate our privileges if we can get
any code to arbitrary code to execute
from those cgi bin files we would
already have root access so looking for
a system
this is the call to system we found that
it was wrapped by merck system for some
reason but um
whatever and
the entire list here i don't expect you
to read it i just wanted to show you the
length
x refing that merck system
there was a handful and and plus three
handfuls i would say
um uh size of the system calls where
all of these could be potential um
targets for us so that's what we started
to look at
however if you're familiar with command
injections and format string
vulnerabilities and things like that not
all of them are created equal so you can
see for instance this called a system
has a
static
argument here where there's no user
input so this is kind of boring so we
did go through a handful of these until
we found one like this next one
that does take user input so like we saw
in the web page we actually can control
uh the host name and then
um you know
that
if we can control that from a uh
attacker's perspective when it goes down
here and reads
the uh with the format string with sn
printf into this this uh variable and
then calls
merck system that could be a potential
command injection so this really got our
attention going um but like we said
before now that we know where the
input's coming from we had to go back to
the original how do we bypass these
character restrictions that they claim
um and this was another kind of uh hold
my beer i got this moment so uh we uh we
got into it um in the first
layer of black listing that we
identified was the client side
and this was done in javascript where
you can pretty much directly see that
this valid character string list
one-to-one lines up with um pretty much
that that uh the blacklisting shown
above
so that was interesting and then the
back end also had some character back uh
blacklisting as well through this xxx
xss string test
while we're not trying to do a
cross-site scripting attack a lot of
these characters that you see in this
list here are still very useful for
command injections like the forward
slash the ampersand and the semicolon
and things like that
so what we did is tried it out we
started with this simple command
injection we wanted to see if the device
would sleep for 10 seconds for instance
so over the browser of course the
javascript kicks in and tells you that
contains illegal characters and doesn't
even post the data to the the backend
cgi script or the cgi binary
however if you use curl no javascript
runs so you can see that we did get
some of our command we get the sigil
opening parentheses and a sleep however
it seemed to get truncated on the space
so space wasn't a part of any of those
characters that we saw being blacklisted
from that
xss string test however we found out
later that the
post data
like the parsing of the post data um
would split on either an equals
3d
equals or space so 20.
um that's what we we had to get around
too however
the linux
command or linux interpreter you know
for the shell does not
um care if it's a space or any other
white space character so in for this
instance what's actually highlighted in
red there is a tab so that seemed to be
just fine it got past all of those um
blacklisting and we were able to inject
this entire command into the hostname
and we'll walk through exactly how that
that hostname
command injection works here
it is actually important to point out
that this whole command that is
highlighted here actually
only ran at boot so
originally we're hoping to get an
instantaneous command injection however
the host name does not get refreshed
until a new um like the new boot up
cycle and
most importantly it's also
during when the device is trying to get
an ip address early on in the network
stack startup
so if we look at actually
the reason why we nest another one is
that we want to actually have an ip
address for subsequence two for this
second command to work we already we
have to have some kind of networking set
up so
we nest the first one in subsequence one
and then subsequence two is now just
pulling commands um directly from a
local
in this case this is our laptop's ip
address so it's just pulling commands
from a web server there and then piping
it directly into ash and the beauty of
that is we can now bypass
all of the command blacklisting that we
saw or the character blacklisting that
we saw earlier because it's not going
through any of that stuff and you can
see if we actually just cur like w get
it our localhost that's running this
server um it prints out this whole socat
reverse shell um interpreter and there
is forward slashes commas ampersands all
the stuff that we we like again um back
back in our command
so um i'll let uh steve kind of walk you
through the impact of that
all right so that ended up being the
first cbe filed you may have seen at the
top of the slides there but at this
point to us it was just an authenticated
command injection which is is kind of
boring so we decided to look into how
authentication was being handled or
mishandled and that's what we're going
to cover now so cookie validation or
session management is typically done by
in a centralized method applied the same
way to all of the cgi pages however in
this case the developers did it on a per
cgi basis and they did it differently
for almost every single one of them for
some reason which was hilarious and and
really led to some failures
ultimately what we did is we curled here
uh our our command injection attack and
we just added a bogus session id of
1337-1337 obviously this should not be a
valid session cookie and it's not
and what we'll see that's a post request
what we'll see here is that the
javascript returns a timeout and an
error so it looks like it fails from the
front end but on the back end or on the
console i should say the debug messages
show that the network data actually was
applied before that they process that
session cookie so you can just issue
these commands completely
unauthenticated if you're using a post
uh versus a get and it'll still run all
the network commands before failing
authentication so this was kind of funny
that developers had just completely
mailed it in on on post requests
pun intended so that gave us now an
unauthenticated command injection but
ultimately as sam mentioned we still
have to wait for the device to reboot
and we're very very impatient people so
we wanted to next find a way to force
the device to reboot so we could trigger
that command injection hostname to load
at will
that brought us to the filing of the
second cve out of eight which is our
firmware upload buffer overflow
vulnerability when we started poking at
some of the more recent firmware updates
we found that there was a diagnostic
menu here that allowed you to load a
file a firmware file and push it to the
device but more importantly it said hey
this will reboot the board and that's
exactly what we're looking for so it
looked pretty good
so the first thing we did
is we we tried to load a file but we saw
when we were looking at the developer
tools and the network data that the
cookie validation was actually being
done right for this page
at least on the front end so when we
looked at the javascript and the html
iframe so it was properly handling
session manager handling session
management for this page
however if you just navigate directly to
the cgi update file that's running
behind this it skips the login process
completely so there's no authentication
done whatsoever and you can now upload
files unauthenticated to the device so
uh just
complete joke at this point we kind of
almost couldn't believe it so the first
thing we did is we took a random file
foobar.txt empty file and we just tried
to upload it to the device
sure enough it went through and started
installing
as a side note it also did some
client-side checking to see if it was 15
megs or larger but it did it wrong we're
able to bypass that by modifying the
javascript won't go into details on that
ultimately the package failed here and
we got this error that said the package
signature is invalid which is
interesting because it tells us it has
an invalid signature size that kind of
triggered a thought for us and maybe
it's grabbing the size from the file
it's like
statically or versus dynamically
building or counting the bytes and in
fact that's exactly exactly what it was
doing
so if i can draw your attention to
bullet point one here when we look at
what's happening in the code behind this
processing the firmware update we have a
file open or an f open and that gets
pushed to uh to update file just above
it there's a static size buffer malik
tier of 190 hex bytes and that is where
the file is going to get pushed to
then what it does is it does an fseq or
a file seek to get to the end of the
file right here
and it actually pulls the last three
ascii bytes from the file signature to
determine what the size is shortly after
that you'll see another stir to l where
it converts those three ascii bytes to
along and those then become the size
that is used here to uh to read into the
file and to write to the buffer so this
is our we we were able to find this
statically and see that this was
definitely going to be a buffer overflow
so this is now a valid firmware file and
you can see the last hex 158 bytes here
are an ascii value an ascii blob of
base64 encoded data that represents the
file signature but most importantly the
last three bytes as we talked about
specify the size of that signature and
that is where it is parsing it from so
instead of programmatically parsing the
size of the update file and passing that
to the buffer instead they allow user
input because obviously we control the
file that's being uploaded and whatever
values are there
so exploiting the buffer overflow we
created a huge firmware file with uh uh
increasing pattern just like you'd see
in like a metasploit pattern creation so
that we knew what was being overwritten
or or modified or smashed and obviously
we set the last we set the size to
999.999
it's over 9000 uh so we we unfortunately
we didn't get we didn't need it all but
we didn't get all of that copied in but
because it truncates the last three
bytes it takes the fold size here of 999
converts it to that long and uses it in
the file read and
we then realized after that
shortly later there's a branch
instruction that references the register
r3 and so we're going to hit this branch
no matter what and r3 if you look has
our pattern data so davu comes from the
pattern that we pushed into the firmware
file so we knew that we could
arbitrarily branch to whatever location
we wanted to by replacing that pattern
with just a pointer
and we chose to replace it with a
pointer to reboot now you're probably
thinking why didn't we do rock chaining
and gadgets and get full remote code
execution we could have probably we
looked at a lot of the gadgets for rop
uh techniques they were pretty ugly they
were not real conducive to what we
wanted to do and ultimately we knew that
we could achieve our purchase our
purpose by just chaining together this
arbitrary reboot with our command
injection from before and achieve full
rce unauthenticated anyway so this may
be an exercise for later if we get uh
interested in creative but
but we had our full rce
so we're only going to cover the two of
these eight vulnerabilities today we
ended up submitting eight zero day
vulnerabilities to carrier linnell uh
the two that we covered today have a
base score of nine and 10.00 10
obviously being the highest cvss score
possible it is authentic unauthenticated
command injection
and there have been patches created for
all of these except for one i believe
it's actually coming out tomorrow is
what i've heard the latest update
it is an authenticated command injection
uh which helps a little bit because they
will have to be logged in to exploit
that the rest of these do have patches
available
as we looked further
in the research process and talking with
the manufacturer and the board vendor we
found out that not just the 4420 we
looked at was vulnerable but all of
these other panels as well including
their flagship and and most common
panels that they use worldwide and
furthermore as recently as yesterday had
a conversation with the board
manufacturer and they said yes any oem
partner that uses these boards is also
vulnerable so it doesn't just extend to
linnell it's every single oem partner
that uses the mercury board so they've
been working with them for for some time
here we don't know what the scope or
scale that is i do know there was an
article from a few years ago that said
that uh mercury has tens of thousands of
sites worldwide uh they have uh
ownership with the uh partnerships with
the vast majority of the fortune 100
companies so there's a huge install base
for these devices
so last but not least sam's going to
take us home with some exploitation and
we'll finish off with a demo showing you
what we're able to ultimately accomplish
yeah thanks steve and so one of the the
things that we always do on our advanced
threat research team is try to bring it
full circle and actually make
a full proof of concept that could be
used you know out in the wild and show
how
these vulnerabilities could be
used so
of course hacking the planet the first
thing we want to do is find out how the
control board is actually interacting
with the door locks so how the relays
are triggered for those door locks
we wanted to create malware um sounds
sounds uh you know bad but uh yeah
create malware then we wanted to try to
force the door to either
unlock without having a badge or a valid
badge in that case
or and then also try to keep the door
locked like that could be a
fun mental exercise if you could think
of how to use that
then we also wanted to try to hide from
the monitoring software all good malware
shouldn't you know people shouldn't see
you out there so we wanted to try to
hide from the on guard server which we
didn't really cover here but security
guards and whatnot would be able to see
if the door has been unlocked or opened
forced opened
things like that we wanted to hide all
of that so it looks like the door has
never been touched
um so
with those symbols that we mentioned
earlier
we searched for relays and found how to
trigger all of the door relays um and
they were simple as just on a simple
i-octyl call where um
you pass the file descriptor for
whatever relay you want to control in a
simple parameter in this case f003
the unlock and lock they would have
different parameters but essentially the
same call
and the i'll show you exactly what
happened next um there won't be audio
but you can see a little led flashing
hopefully
so the
led that's flashing on d17 there that
was
us trying to unlock the door and there
was some monitoring process that we were
fighting with that really wanted to keep
the door locked so uh
instead of going about and actually
figuring out how to do it properly
we just wrapped it in a while loop and
called it every millisecond
and that kept the door unlocked as long
as we wanted so
or locked in that in that case so this
really um
was uh
how we we did it and kind of a really
cool little piece of malware that we
created super super simple um just
really calling their kernel kernel
driver to unlock the relays it's
probably worth stating uh for the record
in case we didn't say it we never
release any exploit code now where this
is all for internal demo purposes so
yeah that's a good point yeah
and so
finally we'll we'll leave you with a
demo here uh steve and i couldn't come
down all the way to california without
leaving us
our hollywood audition tape so um please
reach out with your agents to hire us
later so we'll start the video here
[Music]
[Applause]
hey sam
yeah i'm at the east entrance can you
hack the brain trust room
okay thanks
[Music]
[Applause]
all right well we want to thank
everybody for coming today again we're
going to be talking more about the rest
of the vulnerabilities in detail at
black hat on the software side of things
hopefully this is interesting we'll
stick around for a while if anybody has
any questions but thank you so much
do we have any questions okay
[Music]
so um
you boot you change the code so there
was no secure boot or it was that just
for your development board when you were
trying stuff
uh so let me make sure i got that right
there you're asking if there was any
secure boot on the u-boot yeah because
you changed some parameters and uh yep
so no yeah there was other than i think
they just assumed the um
the setting it to zero you disabled the
uh boot uh interactive console so i
don't think they took any further
security measures so when we changed the
init variable it just yeah
worked
any other questions
okay i think that should be it thank you
thank you guys