over to you
all right
so thank you um welcome to my
presentation about self-labeling
electronic shelf labels uh pawning the
next big thing in retail
my name is stefan roberts and i work as
a security consultant for
second salt which is based in austria
and this uh work has been conducted in
the second side vulnerability lab where
we just have a look at new interesting
topics
that could have security relevant impact
and
start to dig into it try to figure out
any new vulnerabilities there
so what even is an esl tech a esl tag is
depicted in the lower right hand corner
here uh
comes in different sizes i have some
model in the seven inch or like a four
or five inch one
and pretty much consists out of a
display
usually this is an ink display but
there's also some
that are lcd displays
it's usually battery powered and has
supposed to have a runtime of multiple
years since it's usually used as price
tag or shelf label tag in the store
and of course you need to have some form
of communication usually a wireless form
of communication so you can change
what's depicted on the screen
so in most cases there's either
bluetooth low energy
there are some ones that use nfc and
there are some that use a custom
proprietary 433 megahertz protocol
and of course then you need a matching
transceiver for a computer so you can
just change the content of the display
from your regular computer
so when we looked into uh into the esl
text at the first we're wondering if
this is actually something that's being
used because we saw it in couple
austrian supermarket chains
and we were looking into it is it
actually a thing that could become big
in the next years so we found a couple
studies that were showing that last year
the market worth was about 855 million
u.s dollars
but it's estimated to be 980 million u.s
dollars already this year and then
within the next uh 10 years it's
supposed to be up to 5.2 billion u.s
dollars so quite a rapid growth there
this is mostly due to
the convenient price changes that are
possible with esotex can just change
prices every minute or every day you
don't have to change any stickers you
just go into your computer system and
change the prices for the whole store
however you want and therefore you're
better able to compete with online
marketing
also you're it's possible that you have
promotional offers that are quite easily
depictable on the on the
esl text
as usually they come with an led and can
flash and blink as a customer and
therefore draw the attention to a
specific offer or specific product in
the store
so here a couple pictures how the esl
tags are commonly commonly used
so in the upper left hand corner or the
upper row you can say the see the
classic use case as just the price tag
in the store
but there are also a couple more
interesting cases that we got from the
supplier
where the
tags are used in a fashion that we
didn't see in the first place
so in the lower left-hand corner
actually you see a hospital storage unit
where they are using the shelf tags in
order to organize their storage and to
find the right products when they need
for it there's actually a different
version of the
of the station because the shelves have
all these little light columns
and with the light columns the right
shelf will start blinking if you're
searching for something
same kind of thing
is on the right hand side there's
actually a
chord document storage room in china
and it's being using the e-cell text in
order to organize the documents so
actually you have some more impact here
besides just changing a price you could
actually
um
change
where documents are being stored and
make it hard for people to find the
right chord documents and therefore
prolonging court cases which is an
impact we didn't really think was
possible in the beginning
so what are the classic attack scenarios
you could think of
well the classic one would just be to
obstruct the retailer
and hence blackmailed for ransom because
he could see that customer would get
annoyed if they can't see the price for
product and might just go visit a
different supermarket
we also thought about that phishing
might be very possible because you could
just set up a malicious qr code and a
lot of people probably scanned it in the
store because they would see
a regular price tag think that's a valid
one or it would be some special offer or
discount if they scan the code
and you funnel them through your
malicious website then and then the last
case is actually for the maker community
these displays run very very cheap and
you get a nice seven inch display with
like multiple your battery storage on
there
so our own id was actually question if
we could just use them
as this place for our meeting rooms and
just depict the schedule for the
specific meeting room on it
so maybe there's a lot more applications
we could look into
so the specific model i checked out
uh is from a common chinese isl tech
supplier that you can find on alibaba
and aliexpress
um it comes with the base station that's
depicted here in the middle
the base station will convert the
ethernet protocol into a 433 from a
megahertz proprietary protocol that the
esl tags will speak
then i adjust my row of testing e-cell
tags laying around and then two hacker
f's one used as a receiver one used as a
transmitter since they have to flex
which are controlled by the attacker in
my case
so whenever you want to change the price
there is a
esl design tool
this tool you would pretty much just
select the size of the display that you
want to change for
and then you can create a pixel graphic
by either writing text or
uploading a picture in this case it's
the hardware logo
then you just have this field where you
write down the tag id so each tag comes
with an own id on it
you add the id there that's the tag that
you will change
and then there's a status box in the
lower right hand corner which will
depict the changes
and the responses from the tag
there's also the net sdk available
from the manufacturer which you can use
to write your own software for this
and there's also a point of sales
integration
so you're actually able to hook this up
right to a cash register and if you
change the price in the cash register it
will reflect right on the price tags in
the store
so let's get to the interesting start
which is the hardware the first thing i
looked at
so here's a close-up of the regular tag
because he is pretty basic it just has a
display in this type it's an ink display
it has a little hole which is an rgb led
and then it has a
code which is just the tag id
stored as a barcode
which you can just read and this is
this id that you will use if you want to
identify the tag that you want to change
so this casing was actually
ultrasonically welded so i had to dremel
it open
but germany open you finally get to the
pcb
you can see again in blue they mark the
rgb led
then in yellow this is the rf
transceiver chip
marked with ov8 0 e934 802
um however we couldn't find any
information for that ship no idea what
it actually is who manufactured this we
couldn't find any markings on it
whatsoever so if anybody knows oh he has
no idea feel free to give me a hint
what it is
then marked in red we have a regular spi
flash memory manufactured by pouya and
then in orange there is the
microcontroller which is labeled etag m1
so also non
off the shelf labeling we didn't know
what this actually is
if you flip the pcb around you'll see an
orange mark the battery connector that's
just where the battery pack will press
against to form the connection it's
powered by a three volt battery cell and
then there's the four pin header which
usually doesn't have anything soldered
to it but
it looked very obvious that this is some
sort of debug access port that we're
gonna look into further later on
so first i started by just dumping the
spi flash memory since this is pretty
easy and straightforward approach
it was a two megabyte storage of flash
and if you start comparing flash dumps
from multiple tags that have different
pictures you know that only one specific
uh address area starts to change and
that's everything that's following
0x13100
so this is obviously where the image
data is being stored
it's depicted as just
an area of ones and zeros you should
start with a the black color channel and
the red color channel because these
displays are actually multi-color they
can display pretty much off
black or red for each pixel
they just start by going in rows so you
just on the upper left hand corner and
just select by rows
where you encode the pixel if one is on
and the zero is off
and the beginning of uh and director of
the python script for this uh which we
will make available later on in the
second site github
uh but the beginning of the flash
contains something else and as you can
clearly see by the entropy it's nothing
that's encrypted it's very likely that
this is actually firmware uh from the
looks of it unfortunately i didn't have
enough time in the end to uh try to
decompile it but i'm fairly certain that
you'll be able to find the correct
firmware there just in the beginning i
didn't have i had the time for it but
then i didn't know the architecture
being used and couldn't figure it out
since it wasn't a standard arm
architecture and then in the end i had
so much other things found that i didn't
have enough time to come back to this
again
so when we looked at the microcontroller
which was labeled the etag m1 and we
couldn't find any information about it i
just start by continuity testing and
trying to figure out
uh the pin out of this microcontroller
so just look what are the different pins
hooked up to on the pcb
so most of them were unknown a couple
were the rf interface a couple with the
display
so a couple were spi
but the very interesting pins are
obviously gnd and vcc
and then the oscillator that was
connected on the board because usually
with those pins you got enough pin
characteristics to try and look at
common uh
commonly used mic controllers and try to
find just one that has a matching pin
node and they'll just be like alright
they're relabeled with microcontroller
and actually some scm device
unfortunately we were not able to find
anything that had a matching pin out
available so this didn't really bring us
any further
what did then
is that we used this chip and boiled in
95 percent concentrated sulfuric acid
and therefore d layer uh
therefore removed the epoxy packaging
and gather a die shot of the picture
after that we cleaned the ic with a
isopropanol just to clean it up nicely
and you can see that some edges chipped
because i tried to get a really nice and
clean picture so i used multiple
rounds of boiling the chip in the acid
and unfortunately i was using metal
tweezers which chip the brittle silicon
so not for myself we use plastic
tweezers next time
but
what we were able to achieve was
actually we found a marking on the die
itself so you can clearly see that the
marking there is from sd micro
electronics so we're looking at the my
sd micro electronic micro controller
produced or designed in 2010 because
that's most likely what this number
stands for there's another internal
number that we couldn't reference the
r758r which might be some sort of
internal sd number that we don't have
access to
but now we are pretty close and
guessing what architecture is being used
because stm is usually stm v8 or stm32
which would be arm
so now we are very limited at what we
could look at
so next i came back to the debug access
on the back so remember those four pins
that we found there
by tracing those we figured out that pin
one of the debug port would go to the
microcontrollers pin 2 pin 2 would go to
ground pin 3 would go to mic controllers
pin 1 pin 4
went to vdd by knowing that we have an
scm device i was now able to just think
in my head oh what could this be
it doesn't really look like jtag so i
remembered that there is a four pin
debug header for the stm v8
and turns out this is the stm v8 swim
debug connector and the printout looks
very very similar and turns out they
just uh changed where they count the pin
one from and marked it on the opposite
side
so actually the pin one on the debug
header is the reset pin and the pin 3 is
the data or swim pin and i was able to
confirm this by sending
a new price update and while the tags
refreshing you'll see we'll see the
display flashing and it just pulls the
reset pin to ground and it stopped
immediately and i removed the bridge to
ground and the text started back up and
the price was finally depicted correctly
so this confirmed that it actually reset
pin being shorted
so to ultimately confirm this i
gained access to the st with using
st-link v2 using the stm8 flash software
that's just using the swim protocol as a
debug interface
however you have to specify what chip to
use
but we still didn't know besides it's
most likely an sdm v8 right now we
didn't know which one or which the exact
model number being used so just decided
to use the largest one because all the
flash and drum and eprom areas always
map the same address
so i use the
stm8s um which has 128 kilobytes of
storage
and i
then just wrote this little command to
dump this area
into a dump file and looked at this in a
hex view
and the hex view indicated that after 64
kilobytes
the readout was changing from 0x71
to just
0x00 so something is changing here most
likely the flash memory
is finished and we have 64 kilobytes of
flash memory only there
and the 0x71 seems to be the default
that's being read if an sdm v8 is
actually with readout protection enabled
so we have readout protection enabled
but we still gained information that we
have an stm v8 using 64 kilobytes of
flash you can do the same approach for
the eprom section and you'll turn out we
have two kilobytes of eprom so now we
know we have an sdm v8 we have 64
kilobytes of flash and 2 kilobytes of
eprom further limiting what options we
have available here
so there wasn't something like a chip id
or something that would tell you
information about what model this chip
is however there is a unique id for the
sdmba series
if you look up the unique id how it's
set up
you will find this table
where pretty much the unique value of
each chip consists of the lot number
that it was produced in the wafer number
and the x and y coordinates of your chip
on the actual wafer and therefore is
unique
so by looking at different at the data
sheets it turns out that there's only a
common common register used in stm v8s
where they store those information this
is 0x4 0x4acd0x4865
and
0x4926
by just reading from these addresses and
figuring out if the data there matches
this table
i was able to find matching data as
0x4926
that would fit the format and hence our
chip actually is from lot number g904379
with wafer number 22 y coordinate 58 and
x coordinate 31.
so this now actually gives us fully
identification of the chip
we unfortunately were not able to tell
what model this now is however st is you
are probably able to use the slot number
to tell us what actually chip was
produced in the slot however they didn't
get back to us with an answer we
requested it
uh in case anybody has good connection
and wants to request it again or has
access to this databases uh i would be
very interested knowing what actually
this is
but we had one other little bit more of
information left because address
0x4926 where we found this information
seems to only be uniquely used by stmv8l
which is a low power series of fcm
devices
so now we know we have an stm8 from the
low power family and can pretty much
um know already enough about this chip
furthermore we did some ocean because we
didn't find any matching
pin outs for this ship so we're thinking
maybe they actually rebound the chip and
and made a custom pin out and that's why
we can't find anything that matches our
pin out that we figured out
so when you order something from alibaba
and the company is large enough on
alibaba
like ours was then it's a alibaba gold
plus supplied
supplier
and alibaba will actually produce an
independent production line assessment
which will tell you what all devices
this company owns and about the state of
it and this report included that an
ultrasonic fuse
so there's two theories now what this is
either this actually is an ultrasonic
wire binder and they do make a custom
wire bond and therefore we can't find
matching pin outs
or the more likely more boring version
of it is the ultrasonic fuse is the
ultrasonic welding machine that's used
to weld down the
casings around the pcb
we
couldn't figure out which exactly it is
unless we actually know the device
number
so the next thing i took a look at was
the rf protocol because obviously if you
want to attack this chip it's a lot more
interesting if you can attack it
remotely for uh through the rf
interfaces
so first i started by looking at the ssc
filings because that's usually where you
start if you have a knife protocol to
look at
so remember that we have the base
station and the tag themselves so we
have two different fcc files for those
and by comparing them you see that the
base station and the tag both are
reported to run at 433.92 megahertz and
only have one channel available
however when you look at the modulation
type marked red here you'll see that the
base station is supposed to have fsk
with a gaussian filter before just to
limit out of band noise
while the esl tag is supposed to have a
use ask which amplitude shift keying and
this doesn't really make sense to me
because why would two devices that
communicate with each other are supposed
to use different modulation
and we still didn't find any reason for
this
because it turns out this is not the
case and there's just some weird things
going on the ftc files here
because the manual is also talking about
anti-jamming frequency hopping
technology being involved this was
however never
seen and also would be clear violation
to the statement that's only using one
channel and uh that the channels fixed
at one frequency
so something is very very fishy about
this fcc filings as well
further intensified when i looked into
the frequency and it turned out it's not
running at 433.92 megahertz but it's
running at
433.254 megahertz so it's also a little
bit offset to where it's supposed to be
very very weird findings here
so then
the first thing i did
to further
figure out if this is vulnerable to any
sort of rf attack was to just run a
replay attack where
i started to um
where started to just record all the rf
traffic while i was changing the text
picture so i changed the price on my
text picture to five dollars
tag shall show up any second here
and you will see that the tag will now
start
to refresh and display the price at this
time i stopped the recording of the rf
samples
and we'll just wait for the price to
disappear finally we have the price of
five dollar set so now i could imagine
it's the next day the store owner
decides this product is now more
expensive
and i want to charge seven dollars for
it so the store owner goes and change
the price to something else for example
the seven dollars
this will always take a little while
because uh you can't change the prices
too fast they need about 30 seconds
before you're able to change them again
as soon as this is sent
it takes just a little while
and the price is being depicted as seven
dollars now on the tag
however we as hackers one don't want to
pay the new seven dollars and remember
that we have still samples collected of
the image that was transmitted for five
dollar price so we think hey what could
be the easiest way to change this back
is we just transmit all the f samples we
copied from the five dollar price and
replayed it with just being an image uh
being sent without any further measures
then this should just work out of the
box so all we do is change the parameter
to transmit
send the rf frames
and we see
and we see that the price is being
changed back to five dollars without
any usage of the original software or
the base station
so this indicates that actually replay
attacks are possible and there's no
elaborate security scheme in place that
will prevent this
so in order to look
so this caused me to go deeper into the
protocol and figure out how this
protocol actually works
since already everything else was wrong
in the fcc files
i always and there was this weird clash
of the right modulation schemes i
decided to just look at it from scratch
again so this is a waveform display on
the y-axis you have the frequency
on the x-axis of the time so clearly you
can see multiple packets being
transmitted here
and the color then encodes the intensity
or the amplitude of the signal
and as you can clearly see you have
those red lines
one at zero but you also have a red line
at a negative offset and one of the
positive offset which just indicates
that it is fsk being used and that's a
frequency shift modulation
uh in place here
so i then use the tool in spectrum to
further look into the signal because it
allows you to manually decode those
frames when you have no idea about the
signal what's going on and it was very
convenient to use actually
so when you have the fft plot up there
you can just right click into there and
add a drive plot in this example since
it's an fsk scheme i decided to
add a frequency derived plot which is
this medium plot
and then you can right click into that
again add another derived plot which
will just be everything that's going
below zero is a zero everything above
zero is a one which then gives you a
final plot back of ones and zeros with
just a
regular bit stream that you can use to
decode information
you can then also just add those cursors
which are very convenient because you
just mark one sample time with the
cursor um and the sample will always be
taken right in between both of these
cursors
so once you mark once a full symbol
period you can just increase the amount
of samples you want in my case for this
frame it was 184 symbols in here so then
a bunch of cursors is being added you
can just right click in there again and
copy the right bit stream convert it to
hex
values and suddenly you have your hex
button stream that you can use for
further analyzers
i did this for a couple frames just to
get a feeling for the different type of
frames
and came up with three distinct frame
types that are available in this
protocol
the first one is the wake up frame
that's being used from the base station
to wake up the tag
uh since attack usually is a low powered
state where it's sleeping but then it
will wake up randomly listen to the
channel and if it finds a valid attack
for himself it will stay awake and
actually wait for the image data so base
stations start spamming about four and a
half thousand frames in the beginning in
the
first like 30 seconds
where um that are used to wake up the
frame those are transmitted at 175
kiloboard
and consists of a preamble which does
aas so it's a one zero one zero one zero
one zero pattern and so on uh you use
that for timing recovery actually
because your systems are not
timed correctly to each other
you then have a sync header which in
this case is d391 d391 you use that to
determine that the frame is correct and
you know where to start it then follows
the frame length that does actually not
include the crc at the end so you always
have to add the two bytes for the crc to
the frame length
then you have the tag id which is the
number that's printed on the casing of
the tag that's used to identify the
right one
uh some fixed value that i never seen
anything else besides the zero zero in
it
and then you just have a frame counter
this is the 920 in hex and it will just
count down with each frame
then another fixed value and the end is
crc16
for error correction reasons
so spamming this tag will actually wake
up the frame later on
after the tag wakes up we'll transmit
the image data
the image data frame is looking very
very similar to the wake up frame in
that you have the same preamble the same
sync header the frame length the tag id
but then the next new field is the frame
counter so the zero nine zero one
actually stands for you'll send nine
total frames this one is currently frame
one out of the nine
then you have a fixed value and then the
payload field the payload can hold up to
bytes
and everything else after that will be
sent in a new separate frame and then
the end here of the crc again
however how i can imagine if you have
this larger seven inch one or ten inch
one
uh a hundred for 256
frames will not be able to hold all the
pixel information in here
so that's why there is some weird
patched on adjustment for this
where they just decided to
use the frame counter full 16 bit in the
first frame to indicate how many frames
are totally going to send and then they
just start counting up starting with the
second frame at id 0 and just start
counting up from there until the first
value that they transmitted so kind of
really bold on adjustment to allow for
larger text sizes that they probably
added later after protocol was already
done
so in the payload fields there's
actually the image data being sent
so
the image data structure actually starts
with uh some additional headers
so you remember that there is an led on
the tag so the first image structure
starts with the led the zero seven zero
zero for example turns off the led while
the zero seven zero seven turns on the
led so most likely a one is just
enabling one color channel because uh
zero seven turned it to white so it's
probably one bit per um color channel
here
you have a batch code because there's
like a batch mode where you can update
multiple texts at once they just always
will have the same batch code set for
all of those
uh the led time is just a timer because
you can make the led blink and this is
just the time interval to use default i
think is one second
and then there's a compression header
where the fc and then all zeros
indicates a black color channel and the
fc8 and then all zeros indicates the red
color channel because remember that our
displays are actually e ink displays but
with multiple color supports so black
and red are possible
after the compression header
or like a color channel header
we'll have the display height and
display width and then actually the
image payload data
however when i looked at these
samples that i had
it turned quickly out that way too
little data is being transmitted
especially for the larger displays
especially since we know that three
colors are supported we know that we
need at least two bits per pixel to
encode this information
uh in the storage it was just one a one
to turn the pixel on and a zero to turn
it off however this didn't seem to hold
true because the
actual image payload was way too little
so some compression was being used
it turned out to not be a standard
compression algorithm like a gzip one or
something else
so
the quickest way into this was to
download the net sdk and just have a
look into the net
files and figure out how they start to
compress the image data
and it turns out that it's a very basic
run length encoding per color channel
so pretty much if your image consists of
a lot of ones for one color
if it's less than eight ones in a row
you'll just have the first case of your
image data structure where the first one
and the msb will indicate this case one
and then you'll just have the seven
bits depending on if you run
in case two it's if you have less than
uh 32 consecutive bits so you start with
indicating case two by having a zero in
the msb
then you have one bit that will say if
it's a run of once or a run of zeros and
then just the count so up here we could
have for example 20 encode lower six
bits to say we have twenty ones or
twenty zeros in one row coming
case three is kind of similar to this
again we indicate that case three we
indicate if it's a run of ones or run of
zeros and then we just add one byte to
the whole payload where the whole last
byte will indicate how many times this
is repeated
same holds up for case four case four is
marked again we'll indicate if it's a
run of ones or a run of zeros and then
we have two bytes added where both bytes
together will indicate if it's
how many times this one or zero is being
repeated in the image
therefore we can compress especially
images like this with just uh two lines
very much down into very little bits
and
that's the reason for the very limited
data payloads
so the tags actually also respond to
data which is also gfsk
and the tag response contains some
interesting information
they're repeated three times each so
that the base station definitely hears
one of them as some form of error
correction
has the same
structure again of the the sync header
and the frame length tag id and then it
will report its battery voltage which is
actually just the battery voltage
multiplied by 10.
uh an rssi value where i really didn't
understand how it's being calculated of
those two bytes that are being sent
and then the ambient temperature which
is also just multiplied by 10 in order
to encode it correctly
so i then thought let's build a new
radio flowchart for this and i'm by no
means an f engineer i just had some
classes in university about this so i
decided would be fun to do and a lot
better than manually encoding all these
frames
all the time
so the float chart
will actually just start with the hacker
f uh being used as a source i then uh
decimated the sample rate
uh or i was able to shift it with this
block
after that i have a low pass filter to
filter out some of the noise i was
receiving
a correlation estimator to to match the
preamble the zero one zero ones
and then i use the creditor d mod block
to demodulate
the signal
the signal then is samples that are
between
minus one and uh negative one and one
however the the gartner timing
correction needed them to be either
really zero one negative one or one
therefore i use this threshold block
which shifts them again between zero and
one and then just uh some weird magic of
adding constant and uh
multiplying to shift them back to either
negative one or one
then i did some timing correction in
case the
higher qrf is not really synchronized in
time
the output of this is fed into the
binary slicer which will
make a byte stream out of this and then
there's the packaging framework block
which i found on github and just ported
to the newer radio version
the packet reframer block then listens
for the d309 uh the 309 is in the
beginning
we'll find the length field
and then just uh
carve a packet out of this and send it
on actually to a udp client so i could
just use regular python and have my
co-workers work with me on this one
so i then developed a python script
that's actually able to decode every
picture i send here
the python script is being run in the
lower hand window and the upend window
will be the new radio script running and
the right hand side you see the regular
store owner just sending a picture
so running this whole sketch
we'll take a little because
the wake up frames are being sent first
for the first 30 seconds so this will
take a little bit
until the tank wakes up
and until the baud rate has changed the
100 kilobar that my sketch is running at
but now we see all the images
all the frames are being received and
actually i'm able to render the picture
perfectly that's being sent to the tag
so
receiving data is
fun but what's even better is now that
we're able to send all the data with new
radio and create our own tags without
any access to those interfaces
in order to make this possible the
hardest thing to come around was the
wake up
and
to the two different modulators the two
different baud rates because the wake up
is running at 175 kilowatt while the
image data and the responses are run at
100 kilo board
so i wrote my own source block you'll
just feed an image into it tell us the
display size that you want to use
because the image is being scaled to the
right display size
um you give it a sample rate that would
work
the best is if it's an
if it's divisible by both of the baud
rates so in my case 2.1 mega samples
work great
and you just give
the tag id
and it will then take care of
interpolating or the signal
correctly so that um
you won't have a baud rate of 175
kiloboard for the wake up and 100 killer
board for the
regular image data
then i have an interpolating fir filter
which does the gaussian filter here to
limit the out of band noise you don't
actually have to use it you can
deactivate it in case your computer
can't handle too much uh calculation
power anymore
after that you have the frequency mod
block
which will uh just do the fsk modulation
radio and then you just feed that out to
the hackerf to send it
so
running this
you'll see that first all the wake up
frames are being generated then all the
image frames are being generated
and they're being sent now and now you
should see on the multimeter the tag is
turning on and starts to take power
and now the tag should refresh and shows
our customer logo
and after the logo is finally applied
the tag will power back down
right so to conclude we were
able to identify the unknown
microcontroller we gained access to the
debug uh port on the back
we confirmed that the replay
vulnerability is available and doesn't
make sense to dive deeper into the
actual protocol i then reverse
engineered the if protocol and gain the
ability to send and receive correct
frames by generating the right csc
checksums
whether then able to
receive and decode the esl price updates
and display them we are able to change
the tag contents now
to arbitrary information and the kind of
interesting part about this is as well
that the range theoretically is only
limited by rf power so you might be able
to stand pretty far away from the actual
attack and send it because you are not
depending on any response from the tag
the tag only needs to be able to hear
you to change it so
if we don't care about any regulations
and pump just a bunch of if power out
we're able to probably stand uh further
away from the store as we want
so lessons learned here is the protocol
does not contain any security measure
which is always just very bad practice
and just because you're using a custom
433 megahertz protocol does not mean you
increase security just make it harder
for people to look into it because they
need to know some rf basics
to actually decode this protocol but
once you know all this information a
regular c1101 from texas instrument was
about two dollars will be good enough to
actually go into the store and change
your prices so this is not protection at
all
also the protocol robustness could have
been greatly improved from what i know
from my university classes without
having any real term experience here but
there was no real error correction
available
so
if one bit flip is in your image data
the whole
refresh of the image data will fail and
you have to start over however just
adding an error correction algorithm
here would probably save you especially
in the big tanks that send hundreds of
frames
and make it possible to correct any of
the bit flips and thus
have way better reliability in your
in the pricing changes
also relaying a microcontroller does not
protect you against finding out what uh
the microcontroller family is used
because you can always build an asset
figure out who the manufacturer is
especially if it's regular
big term manufacturers that mark their
chips
all code will be released on github
unfortunately i wasn't able to yet but
uh i'll make sure to upload everything
all the custom blocks made for new radio
and the sketches and and firmware dumps
i have so if anybody wants to further
dig into this uh feel free to
if any further questions
good
thank you
so it looked like a lot of your research
was
targeted at changing just the image on
the actual display
did any of your research look at using
the display to reach back to the host
computer with the application no i did
not look into that
do you think that's a possibility of
using that display the rf to communicate
back to the computer maybe
um
somehow
in theory yeah that would be something
very interesting to look further into
yeah
okay
i just had a quick look at the base
station but nothing too much was using
stm32 so
very easy to look further from there i
guess probably not better secured at all
either
so
it might be a good idea to have a look
in this involved
any other questions
okay thank you stefan thank you