[Music]
good morning to everyone first of all I
apologize for not speaking any Polish I
should know better but that's it it's my
pleasure to be here and this
presentation is going to be about
advances in ipv6 network reconnaissance
I modified the you know the slide where
as I was looking at other presentations
and realized that you know maybe some of
you might not you know my had not been
present at the an ipv6 never
reconnaissance presentation before so
what I tried to do with this talk is
provided like a very very small summary
of you know some things related to ipv6
neighbor reconnaissance and you know
after that try to describe a little bit
some of the recent advances that we did
in this field I said very brief
introduction about myself I work as a
security researcher and consultant that
si6 networks I do quite a little quite a
bit of work at the IETF which is the
standards organization for internet
particles meaning that I write you know
protocol standards I have written an
ipv6 toolkit before my current job I was
doing consulting for different
organizations on the topic of
communications protocol security so so
that's my website there's the quote that
she referred to and also some of these
documents a very small introduction
obviously you know what never
reconnaissance is about so essentially
whether you are maliciously attacking a
site or whether you want to do a pen
test in order to be able to do that you
need to learn information about a
network okay that's very very well known
stuff now what's different when it comes
to ipv6 is that some of the techniques
that you typically apply to an ipv4
network
they cannot really be applied to IP
before the most simple example of all of
that is the typical horse cunning
attacks that you might do for example
with nmap you're probably very used to
do like address cons in IP before where
you have like a slash 24 prefix for
example and you go through the whole
address space for that network obviously
that's doable when it comes to IP before
because the address space is very
reduced it's very small
you only need to you know try less than
300 addresses in a typical case and
that's it
but obviously that's not the case with
ipv6 because addresses are much much
larger ok so you know in most cases you
need to do something else
so as I kind of like very brief summary
of where things were at when it comes to
ipv6 network reconnaissance essentially
we had smart host address cans if you
had never looked into this essentially
the idea is that many sites select their
addresses with specific patterns so with
ipv6 you have twin a 128-bit addresses
of which 64 addresses are the host ID
part that you know from the ipv4 world
ok in theory you might expect that the
host ID part is random but in practice
it's not so you know we typically find
that a number of sites rather than
selecting random addresses they follow
specific patterns and we have produced
tools like this one scan 6 there are a
few others not as complete but there are
that you know whenever you specify a
network what the tool tries to do is to
try to it the tool tries to infer what's
the pattern the address pattern that is
used at that side and only target those
services ok this is a very big and
important difference when you compare
ipv6 address scans with ipv4 address
cans in the ipv4 case you just go
through the entire outer space because
the outer space
small you don't need to you know do a
lot of smarts about that but we're ipv6
unless you are able to reduce the search
space you know you will not be able to
you know do an address scan of a network
so this is the stuff that you know we
already had smart address scans there
are other techniques that are quite
useful DNS reverse enumeration you might
have read about it I will provide a very
brief summary about that and other
techniques that are borrow from them
from the ipv4 world okay so what are the
things that we will go through in this
presentation some stuff having to do
with using search engines for host
discovery using certificate transparency
for the same purpose and also one thing
that I will try to describe like only a
few things you know time is reduced is
to see if there are any insights that we
gain you know from using these
techniques in practice so what does this
mean like you know when we were
exploring different techniques for you
know ipv6 network reckon essence well we
came up with a bunch of ideas which in
in theory they would work but then when
we started to play with them in practice
well we had a few small surprises in
there so what I will try to do in this
presentation is provide some comments
about that first one is about liberation
leveraging search engines I mean I have
seen quite a few tools that do this
except for some details that I have
implemented in the tool that I produce
so first of all let me try to introduce
why I you know started to work on this
particular tool I was trying to do
measurements about ipv6 deployment like
different things like for example coming
up with a list of domains like for
specific countries could be Argentina
could be polling could be any and for
example I was trying to figure out
what was the percentage of sites that
had ipv6 deployed so you know it would
be easy just come up with a bunch of
domain names for a specific country then
for each of those domain names just try
to obtain you know the ipv6 addresses
and the ipv4 addresses there are ipv6
addresses that means that b6 is support
otherwise it's not so what I tried to do
when I first started with that
experiment was to obtain a list of
domain names that's not obvious if you
try to do those measurements for like
global sites it's not that hard for
example you could download the alexa top
1 million sites and you know the list is
there i also found that for some
top-level domains like for example dot
SE for sweden and a few others the
registries they published the whole list
of at least their you know the their
registered domain names for other songs
like russia for example the list of
domain names was leaked I don't know how
but it was up there but thing was that
for some of the songs that I wanted to
do the measurements the list of domain
names were not available so I had to
come up with you know such lists in my
particular case it was kind of like a
more of a mass scale or you know larger
scale experiment like meaning you know
for let's say a top-level domain could
be that PL for pollen for example you
wanted to obtain all of or as many
domain names as possible but obviously
it could you know you could just target
you know the same attack if you want for
a specific domain name if you were doing
a pen test it's exactly the same thing
so I you know I mean it wasn't that hard
to come up with the idea that you know
if you have search engines that they
obviously index lots of domain names
rather than trying to find the dominance
by yourself you could you know ask the
search engines most search engines
obviously have you know super keyword
such a site where you can you know
specify like DNS zone and that means
that the results are going to be
restricted to you know to the domain
name that you are specifying there as I
say
before it's useful for particularly for
intestinal specific side and why I mean
and not that much if you want to
download a whole zone
the reason being like if for example you
specify site dot PL or the first couple
of pages you are going to get like
different results but after a while they
are all duplicates because they are all
you know part of the they will all be
webpages corresponding to the you know
to the same domain so what are the
challenges with this first one I mean I
try the most obvious case which is
Google ok and when I was trying to scrub
the results I found that they were like
obfuscated not encrypted but office
gated meaning that what you see on the
webpage is not really what you find on
the HTML and I wasn't going at least in
principle going to spend the time you
know trying to figure out what they were
doing particularly because they might be
changed that over time meaning that I
would not only have to work now but you
know keep working on that which wasn't
an option so what I did after that was
to find which other you know search
engines I could use I came up with this
one which I didn't know before
tyoma apparently they use like Google as
a you know as the motor of the engine
problem being that for example this one
will bun you after you perform like
let's say high number or big number of
queries it's usable if you are for
example pen test in a specific site
because with a few queries you are going
to obtain most of the domain names but
if you want to download for example all
the domain names for a you know
top-level domain say dot PL obviously
you are not going to be able to do it
and thing is with first sample this
particular search engine kyouma they
blacklist your IP address for one or two
days meaning that at least you are able
to change often you're not going to be
able to play for a long time there are
always that
kind of like require you to keep state
meaning that it's not that you can just
you know ask for a page with the results
but there's some kind of like cookie in
the page which you can read and then you
have to submit not a big deal but at the
end of the day the one that I have found
which is in the next one here is Ben
being the nice thing about being is that
it provides at least for this purpose
like good results and it never actually
bans you okay so you can keep sending
queries queries queries and you know it
never complains so that's that's good
for our purpose we do believe so so I
implemented essentially like a script
that just scrubs you know the big
results now obviously the problem with
you know just doing a basic script is
that if you want the target you know
most importantly like you know like a
top-level domain say like navidad meal
or something like that
whoa and if there are like you know many
web pages within that zone you know
after the you know fourth tenth page you
start getting lots of duplicates and
it's hard to you know to get new results
so my first try was to you know submit
to just add to a query string like for
example random letters ABC that leads to
you know different reordering of the
results which was kind of like okay but
not that good and what I try it after
that is essentially use you know Bing by
with a dictionary so that's essentially
what I you know ended up producing for
essentially liberation a search engine
for potentially downloading like let's
say a top-level domain if you want what
the tool does for example in this case
it will produce a query string like
specifying in this case navidad meal for
you know the site and then you know it
starts with each keyword in the
dictionary that we are specifying and
the number of duplicates it just changes
the keyboard so I mean obviously it's
not perfect but for example for some
top-level domain say I didn't try I
don't seem to I don't seem to remember
trying that without pl but for example
without a R for Argentina you know
running the tool for a few hours I was
able to download about a hundred
thousand dominates or something like
that which was quite you know it would
there were many more domains that that
the ones that I already had for the
measurements so there is another
technique that is interesting you don't
say that I mean it's just a different
technique that is complementary to the
one that I described for you know about
the search engines you can discover some
sites that you maybe you might not be
able to discover you know with a search
engine and vice versa so one is not a
replacement for the other so this
technique is about leveraging
certificate transparency and thus a very
brief introduction if you think about
certificates you know obviously they are
useful for example for preventing
man-in-the-middle attacks when you know
the certificates are you know working
properly but obviously as a system let's
say if you have a SSL plan you are not
able for example to tell whether a
certificate was issued by a certificate
authority okay so obviously if you know
this certificate you know you can detect
man-in-the-middle attacks but if there
have been cases I think I listed a few
there were at least two cases DigiNotar
that was issuing you know certificates
that after being compromised
there was another case of trust way in
which they were issue issuing so or
denied root certificates because they
wanted some of their clients to be able
to
sniff traffic these are examples that
you know SSL by itself cannot just you
know prevent if there's a certificate
authority that was compromised you know
there's nothing that you know this as a
system can can do and that's where you
know certificate transparent framework
comes into play so the idea to put it
things to put things very simple is to
keep a centralized log of you know how
the certificates are generated so
essentially it's possible you know for
owners of domain names to essentially
figure out whether you know somebody has
issued a certificate for the domain name
that they own and it's also possible for
clients to some extent you know to be
able to detect that there is something
wrong going on with you know
certificates that they are trying to
employ when it comes to the components
of you know the certificate transparent
framework there are essentially three
parts first one is the certificate locks
so essentially when you know
certificates are issued obviously you
know this is recorded into these locks
then you have the monitors which monitor
all the certificate locks and then the
last element in this framework you have
the auditors which could be like a piece
of software for example in your browser
which tries to make sense out of these
components but the most important part
we don't I mean this was an introduction
for the stuff that we will see
afterwards
but the idea or what what's important
from our perspective here is that as a
result of the certificate transparent
framework now you have a log centralize
log well you keep a log of all the
certificates that have been issued okay
so there's like a kind of users log that
you can actually search where you know
you will find in theory all the you know
certificates that you know have been
issued
so what did I do is I produce oh this is
a website one of the logs where you can
actually search for the certificate but
I produce a tool that you know search
searches is able to search the logs and
you know provide the results in a more
scriptable output essentially you run
the tool like that you specify a song
and for example like in this case I just
specify the zone lacnic
dotnet could be any example but the idea
is that you specify a song and as a
result of that you get all of those
lists of domain names that you know were
present in the you know in the logs that
I referred to before one thing that you
have to keep in mind you might wonder
well what are the domain names that I
might be able to find let's say here
versus you know the search engines well
first of all the dominance that you are
able to find here our domain names for
which a certificate has been issued so
if there is some site that doesn't use
for example SSL at all you know you will
not be able to do anything with it on
the other hand there might be certified
that are not being employed for example
for the web or for FTP for example so in
those cases you wouldn't be able to find
those domain domain names you know with
a search engine but you would be able to
find those domain names using the
certificate transparency framework ok so
again with a certificate transparent
framework you are able to find domain
names for which certificates have been
issued whereas on the other hand when it
comes to obviously two search engines
obviously you will only be able to find
dominance for which you know some form
of content has been indexing they are
complementary so if you try to you know
if you use the tool you know trying to
find dominance for a specific zone with
a search engine you will see the set of
domain names that you find then you
compare with a set of domain names that
you that you find with this tool I
usually you know they are not exactly
the same results so that's why I'm
saying that they are complementary
wheels so these are two you know tools
that I produced recently and when I was
you know studying this topic I you know
one of them you know say main topics
when it comes to ipv6 naval
reconnaissance which is actually one of
the few topics that is specific to ipv6
is the patterns that ipv6 addresses
follow in the real world I was
mentioning before that you know if you
look let's say if you download the top 1
million sites of Alexa and you obtain
all the corresponding ipv6 addresses and
you try to you know analyze those
services you will find that those
services follow patterns specific
patterns years ago when we were you know
working on this topic we produce
statistics about you know what were the
patterns that these addresses were
following at least for the you know
Alexis top 1 million sites but the thing
is that since we did that study there
are some things that change specifically
I think that we have done this study
maybe five years ago and in the last
what was it like two three years we
publish these two new RFC's 72 17 and 18
64 which essentially changed the way in
which ipv6 addresses are generated if
you had never seen how an you know how
an ipv6 address looks like whoa you have
the first example on the left hand side
obviously it looks ugly because they are
oops Oh 50 minutes no girlfriend in
which obviously it's 128-bit long
address written in exodus malformed and
what I highlighted over there is that
what you see in blue is to some extent
or another the MAC address of the
underlying network interface card so if
you did a nice confit of this system you
would see that you know it has the MAC
address 26 is c99 habla blah would you
see in blue I mean there are minor
details but that's kind of like the you
know the idea what were they I mean
there's a bunch of security and privacy
issues with you know including MAC
addresses in the interface ID among
others obviously when you move from one
network to another you know the MAC
address stays the same so that means
that you can be tracked obviously if you
generate ipv6 services by including a
MAC address in the interface ID that
also means that the addresses will
follow patterns obviously because for
example if you purchase like all of the
boxes in your network from the same
vendor
well the MAC addresses are usually going
to be consecutive so they will follow
patterns meaning that is going to be
easier for an attacker to actually scan
the whole network so we replace that
that was the traditional scheme to
generate ipv6 addresses which we changed
like say one to three years ago it was
updated in the standards and then it was
actually updated in you know popular
specifications if you look at let's say
rest recent versions of Fedora 1 2 3 B
as the Mac OS they all employ this new
scheme they randomized the ipv6 services
so what's on the left hand side was
changed to what's on the right hand side
which essentially means the interface ad
they low order 64 bits were replaced by
a random number so the question here was
if you know since we produce this change
in the standard and since
implementations were updated in response
to that we were trying or we redid
measurements that we did a few years ago
to see if you know we had we could see
any changes in the real wall sometimes
you know what you write on paper you
know doesn't reflect into you know
changes in the real world so these are
the measurements that we produce we did
them with three different data sets I
mean there's much more that you can
measure this is just a summary
usually because time is constrained what
we did for this particular slide we got
we obtained the top 1 million sites list
from Alexa and we obtained the quarrei
records for each of them of those domain
names obviously for many of them for
many of them ipv6 is not supported but
for those domain names that support ipv6
well these are their results what's most
important if you see what was that
orange or whatever that is woody let's
say the biggest the larger part of the
pie those are addresses that embed ipv4
addresses what does that mean like well
people configuring the addresses of
websites what they do is they manually
configure the ipv6 interface ID to be
the same as the corresponding ipv4
address so let's say if that memory
interface card has a ten point blah blah
blah ipv4 address they include the ipv4
address in the interface ID you might
wonder why they do that let's say my
guess is that it makes it easy for them
to remember the ipv6 address of the you
know of the server so if you do remember
that they before ogresses blah blah blah
then it's easy to come up with the ipv6
address just you know the ipv6 prefix
and then the ipv4 address and then there
is this part of the this part of the
chart over here this smaller part which
is about randomize addresses okay that's
a much larger set of addresses that what
we had measured years ago okay and you
know when I first look at these results
are these graphics I say okay well that
means that you know the changed with it
in the specs you know actually reflected
into changes in you know the real world
now the part that I couldn't
let's say come up with some sort of
analysis that made sense is that if you
look at the very small part in blue up
there
those are addresses that embed the MAC
address okay
the measurements that we did like four
or five years ago had kind of like the
same percentage of addresses including
the MAC address and that's the part of
the puzzle if you want that I couldn't
solve so what I what I expected is that
you know all the addresses or most of
the addresses that at the time were
including the MAC addresses now would
mean me great you know two addresses
that you know are randomized but they
did not so I don't really have an
explanation of you know why those
randomized services appear there maybe
they are new systems but it's not that
we replace all of those services that
contain a MAC address to randomize ones
these are similar measurements but with
a different data set in the same way
that these guys from Alexa they publish
top 1 million sites there's this company
called umbrella I think they are owned
by Cisco something like that they also
publish their lists of popular sites and
there is another company yet another
company called majestic I don't know
what they do but they also publish their
list of popular domain names which are
useful if you want to I mean they are
supposed to be the domain names that you
find in these domain name sets they are
supposed to contain like you know
popular domain names
okay but you know the results are
similar so most of the addresses embarr
an ipv4 address in the interface ID and
you have like a larger set than before
of randomized interface identifiers
conclusions here when it comes to you
know address scanning from the
perspective of the attacker is that you
have between a fifteen and twenty
percent of randomized
addresses those sir addresses that you
know with the tools that we have right
now for our scans you wouldn't be able
to discover in principle why because you
know they are addresses that are
randomized in a 64-bit address space
meaning that you will not be able to
find that they don't follow any patterns
and you know that means that you will
not be able to target them I also
mentioned before that you know there was
an increased number of randomized
addresses but the one the addresses that
included the MAC addresses are still
there in the chart some comments on DNS
reverse mappings I you know for the sake
of the following slides of the following
slides I will assume that you know this
technique but I will just provide a very
brief summary in the same way that you
can map a domain name into let's say an
IP address like when you you know type a
domain name in your browser it's
possible to map an IP address whether
ipv4 or ipv6 into a domain name maybe
one of the most obvious examples for
that is that when you first of all are
running trace route you get the list of
IP addresses that Colorado IP your
people for ipv6 addresses that
correspond to routers and along with
them you obtain the corresponding domain
names in order to be able to obtain the
main names those domain names you have
to employ the DNS reverse mappings in
the case of ipv6 is the IP six dot ARPA
so that is employed for those reverse
mappings the idea is that you will
decompose an ipv6 address into you know
a string of extra decimal digits and if
you map that string into a PTR record
you will be able to obtain a
corresponding domain name now if you
look at the graphic that I have over
there
you know it should be possible it's
actually possible to walk that zone as a
tree instead of you know going brute
force essentially you start at the top
of the tree and then for each nibble you
try to obtain a domain name and there
are two possible responses that you can
obtain one is an X domain and the other
one is no error if you obtain an X
domain that means that there's nothing
in that part of the tree if you have
obtained no error that means that you
you should keep exploring in that part
of the in that part of the tree this is
an example of using this technique so
for example this is a tool that was
produced but by mark oyster if you see
at the top of the slide essentially
we'll run the tool and we specify an
ipv6 prefix and what the tool does it
what the DNS verse mapping tree trying
to find PTR records for the
corresponding basic services this is not
another scan it's actually walking you
know the DNS tree for reverse mappings
so what's interesting about this
technique is that you can employ the
technique for the discovering let's say
new addresses but there are some new
lessons that we learn when you know we
were employing this in practice I have a
very concrete example I have left this
tool running for I think it was a slash
32 and after a couple of weeks I go to
that virtual machine and I find that I
have like a few gigabytes log of in
theory of results so I said okay well
that was quite nice I'm going to you
know maybe I found lots of systems now
when I actually take a deeper look into
the log I see that there are tones and
tones of domain names like this what
does it mean that there are different
sites that rather than specifying
mappings for specific addresses they
just use wildcards meaning that you
think that you are discovering a lot of
addresses but you're just hitting
Wilkers that happens for a lot of sites
dontcha Telecom comes to mind but there
are a few others DC
like Yahoo firmament correctly yeah
there's another one the another lesson
that you know I learned by you know
running this with lot of sites which is
that in theory you can specify a prefix
of any length when you run this tool
like it / 32 and it should be okay now
in practice what happens is that if he
tried to do if you try to use the these
techniques for example for for prefixes
that are shorter than a / 48 well
somehow your queries are filtered
somewhere so what we learned was that
it's more effective more reliable if you
use / 48 or smaller prefixes so that
means that for example if you want to
scan it / 32 what you should probably do
this you know split that / 32 into
smaller prefixes like for example / 48
closing this this is just a very brief
summary many of these techniques are
split in a you know in a number of
different tools meaning that you run the
DNS enumeration tool and a bunch of
other tools but it's hard to put all the
tools or it's hard to put all of their
results together so I produce a very
extremely preliminary tool for putting
the you know the the results together
which essentially what it does without
getting into details the tool for
example uses you specify for example a
domain name the tool come ups with a
list of domain names then you get
prefixes and you go through all the
techniques and eventually the resource
convert converge to something the I mean
being a football fan and being a year
where we are playing the woke up we
named this tool after our let's say only
hope in winning the World Cup messing if
you are a football fan we wish we had
named this tool Maradona
but for us Maradona is up here so that
would be like a flawless tool which is
not this case
we like Messi but not as much as
Maradona acknowledgments duratomic I
know that I was painful I was at a
conference and I was actually chased in
other speakers so I was getting pain
from other speakers and giving pain to
the chief con people so I apologize for
that and I also thank you for that I
don't know if there are any questions
for your data is exactly the same as the
majestic one do you think you work on
the same data set sorry your pie chart
for the randomized IPS for your own data
set is exactly the same as for the
majestic one well what are you saying
that there are two things to note over
them so first thing is that it's quite
likely that most of the domain names in
all of those datasets are the same so
maybe order differently but they are the
same another thing - you know what might
be interesting to do which I haven't
done it yet is to do the same kind of
analysis but for example with dominance
corresponding to a specific country
let's say get all the dominance from 4pl
or not all but a lot of them and do the
experiment again because when you hit
the most popular domain names things are
different like in terms of many things
like for example if you try to measure
v6 deployment with the top alex has 1
million sites you get one percentage
maybe I don't know let's say 10% if you
do the same experiment let's say we dot
P l dot AR or whatever it's going to be
like quite different
any others so quick note for my from my
side and a question we are happy to have
you here Fernanda so you don't have to
be sorry about anything my question is
about randomized ipv6 addresses have you
have you had a chance or an idea to look
into more deeper into it meaning if you
can see if there are any specific
patterns of
ipv6 address generation based on the
operating system that has generated this
IP address so for example that you can
see a bunch of IP of ipv6 addresses and
based on the just the IP IP physical
address you can say you know is it's a
probably it's a windows-based or Linux
base or Mac Mac base or something like
that so short answer is I didn't
so the algorithm that all
implementations are at least in theory
implemented because I didn't check the
windows code for example is the
algorithm that we specify in 72 17 and
essentially I don't remember off the top
of my head but I think we recommend
sha-256 so the way in which you
randomize the interface identifier it's
a little bit more complex but it's hash
you produce a hash of the network prefix
and some secret key what would be
interesting I mean it would be very a
very dumb thing to do but sometimes
vendors do very dumb things is if
Bender's employed the same secret key
for you know let's say for all of their
boxes I mean I will not name the vendor
but years ago we were working on
something very similar which essentially
was an algorithm that required a secret
key so the whole security of the
algorithm had to do with the secret key
so I get an email from this vendor and
like a big bender and they say well data
quickly really had to be secret and
their idea was that they were going to
set the same secret key for all boxes I
mean there was like this but sometimes
you find that kind of stuff hopefully
they will know that we were know based
on that experience we were very explicit
that you know the secret we should
change and actually what we say is that
I mean without getting into the details
of the recommended algorithm is that you
do the secret key should be a random
number that you generate when you
install the system so it should be
different for all boxes but I didn't do
the measurements trying to come up and
see
if let's say I could infer the operating
system thanks thanks for the talk I
would like to ask you how many domain
names have you discovered and how many
ipv6 unique addresses have you
discovered during your sorry
how many domain names and how many ipv6
addresses have you discovered during
your world I mean depends on the zone
that I explore like for example if you
look at if you use the data set like the
top 1 billion most popular sites alexa
majestic and so on let's say you get a
larger number of 5 let's say of ipv6
enabled domain names i don't remember if
it was like 10 20 percent or something
like that but around 10 20 percent but
the numbers are totally different like
for example if I look into the dot AR
which is the country code for Argentina
the numbers are way worse what happens
is that if you look at you know the the
dominant from those you know from for
Alexa top 1 million sites they are
usually like more popular and bigger
sites which might have decided to deploy
b6 but usually when you go to smaller
sites you know the the numbers that you
get with with ipv6 deployment are not
quite good actually
I recently measured for you know
Argentina and I think the numbers were
smaller than than 10 per cell and also a
changes a lot depending on the type of
organization for example when I did the
measurements for Argentina which based
on the tools that you have here I mean
you could even do the measurements
yourself like I could do them but you
know the tools are available but for
example if you look at some you know
top-level domain for example let's say
comb dot PL for dot-com sites usually
the v6 deployment is way larger than
government sites or that or larger than
educational sites so it changes a lot
obviously when you do the analysis for
the whole country you know you know you
you you
let's say you might assume that it's an
average 10 20 percent deployment but
then you find out that is the calm that
masquerades all of the others okay so we
takes a lot of time and do you serve
some of your results somewhere or oh
yeah so we did we did I did a
presentation last week I pray and I
published the results for Latin America
but if you drop me an email I can send
you even the list of domain names that I
have if you want to explore that
yourself
great thanks I will good okay we need to
wrap up because our coffee break is
shrinking so thank you for Rondo
good luck good luck on a World Cup
[Music]