[Music]
okay and so much so yeah the main point
of this talk is about corporate red
teaming so those of you here yesterday
we heard Justin talking about
I guess his outsourced red teaming where
it's really important to test certain
things to I guess to check certain
checkboxes or flags that our customers
after and I think corporate red teaming
kind of can expand a little bit on that
so a couple of questions first hands up
if you lead a red team good job okay and
if you're in a red team looking red team
people put your hands up if you want to
lead a red team okay so this talk is
really based on my own experience as
well as I can guess look what I call
benchmarking so over the years have many
discussions with other red teams at
various different industries but all of
this is I guess it's my own opinion and
I'm very opinionated so feel free to
disagree or agree and we can discuss
that later also if you're someone that
likes to take notes don't worry too much
there's like 30 pages of Appendix with
loads of different bullets death by
PowerPoint style we lot of little hints
and tips that might be of use so we
start off with I guess benchmarking
warriors red teaming it's a red team to
me is a group of independent people from
a diverse background various different
skills different ways of thinking
different opinions and they're trying to
use this experience to solve problems
give a different perspective and of
course the most important thing is that
we're trying to simulate or replicate
those activities of a real-world
adversary of some sort I think red
teaming is threat centric not
vulnerability centric so it's not about
running scanners and giving an SS report
and also things
and I think that's one of the biggest
problems we have on our industry is we
have no commonality of all these
different things right so someone will
tell you they do red teaming in my
opinion it won't be red teaming they
just run Qualis or something that's
their penetration testing team all
different things so really I want to
kind of try and forget about colors a
little bit I know this is a red and blue
conference but just talk about the
adversary and emulating that so want to
start off by saying red is not best so
lots of people will say I want to be a
red team because it's a silly thing and
it's marvelous red is just different
right so if you think about security as
a puzzle red team is just another piece
in that puzzle it's not a substitute or
a replacement for anything else
and we get this quite a lot when
interviewing people they want to be in a
red team because they want to
up right that's what they say and and
perhaps they're really awesome at doing
that but they might be better off at a
very focused penetration testing team
role right because that's where their
skills and experiences is more
beneficial so we shouldn't be doing red
teaming instead of or a substitution to
anything else this is really
complementary and I think it's important
to keep that in mind as we go through
this right so in my mind red teaming
shouldn't be trying to replicate or
duplicate something else it's bringing a
different perspective a different vision
to bring different learnings and
outcomes for their organization so the
reason for this talk is I think rarely
do we ever discuss kind of what's
involved in setting up a red team so
lots of people I speak to who are in the
red team I say well how did your red
team come to exist well we used to be
the pentest team and now red teaming is
the really cool thing so now we're
called the red team or we used to do
runner ability scanning and now we do
this or someone needed the red team set
up due to some reason so that's why we
called the red team there's no real
necessary reason why it is really a red
team other than people like colors and I
think we need to challenge ourselves to
do better I think as leaders we need to
challenge ourselves to do better and as
you as people in the red team need to
expect more from each other and from
your leaders so this is really hoping
for you to go back to your companies and
give you a boss a hard time and say we
should be doing this better or
different
being inspired hopefully to do it
yourself better
so really want to drive some change and
like I said I'm really frustrated to all
this color crap so it's not red teaming
it's black teaming because we do
physical stuff and it's purple teaming
because just red team and blue team
let's just do awesome amazing stuff and
not worry about adding another color
another brand which just confuses things
even more so try to break down this
journey of kind of building an
adversarial capability into a few stages
so you've got strategy buy-in process
resources people I know it's terrible to
call people resources but it's not just
people it's hardware and software as
well they'll see the execution and then
collaboration so we're trying to go
through these different stages and kind
of give you some insight and think what
seemed very required so I don't think
you can do any of this unless you start
from a strong foundation so depending on
what you're doing already you may be at
different stages so I try and think of
this as like a crawl walk run fly type
situation so perhaps you're already in a
red team and you're at a certain stage
and you think you can't go any further
you can continue you know to push the
boundaries so really the first thing you
need to understand is what is the
business mission so what is it that you
as a red team are here to try and help
this organization will do and really for
me the whole idea of a red team is
you're enabling the business to make
more informed decisions but you can't
help them do that unless you understand
what it is that they're trying to do you
gotta be pragmatic with what you're
doing so you're ready to understand who
those key stakeholders are that are
gonna nail you to do this so a key thing
about red teaming is trust so I think if
you're doing this properly it should be
against live production environments
there shouldn't be scope there should be
minimal restrictions to some extent
obviously we don't want to bring
everything down but that means you're
gonna have to get the buy-in from those
certain people at the top and that's not
gonna happen if you just get in you know
prove them someone who also doesn't have
the courage to push harder to do more
don't be defined by what everyone else
is doing or if the organization your
apps never done this before or other
teams try to do this but they can't do
it
our job is to push harder to do better
right and we're never gonna kind of push
the boundaries of what we're doing as
red team is unless we continue to put up
a fight and a key part of this is going
to be to enable trust right so lots of
organizations I talked to that still say
they do red teaming they're never doing
it in production right or they're only
doing it in it's definitely production
but it isn't or we can only do it in
production but it'll be certain hours
and I understand the reasons for all
this stuff but I'm sure mostly you can
kind of say from experience that a dev
or test environment is never the same as
production right if anything there's
never the same detection controls in
those environments so part of what
you're trying to you know test where
this approaches the ability to protect
detect and respond so how can you do
that effectively I think it's the guy
yesterday was talking about the target
you know where you've got to go around
and find certain people that you can
associate engineer I understand the
rationale for that but the adversary
doesn't do or any of that crap right so
we have to manage to be able to do as
close as we can simulate what the
adversary is doing but we've control and
making sure that we don't proper
screw-up then we've got got problems and
like I say at the bottom there failure
to plan you're just basically planning
to fail so you need to get a strong
foundation need to get the right buy-in
need to get the right support you need
to get you know the budgets and
everything sorted out oh you're not
gonna get anywhere so buying being the
next stage so you've got this plan you
understand what you think red teaming is
you think you understand what it is the
business trying to do and what benefit
you're going to bring now you've got to
try and sell that to the right people
right so hopefully you can get it at sea
level so at the board so basically
they're the people the accountable
people that if you screw up there are
people that are in trouble right so if
you bring down you know the
infrastructure a retail organization or
a finance to institution wherever it may
be
they're the people who's s asked you
want to have you know you want your ass
covered by those people right not
someone who's not the accountable person
so you already want that support and
buying you're going to need things that
people don't always think about or see
financial support makes sense because
you need people to be a red team you
need software you need infrastructure
all these things make sense but lots of
the time
if you're doing this in the way I think
he's right you're gonna be breaching all
your company's policies every day right
because you're not supposed to break
stuff you're not supposed to impersonate
people you're not supposed to do any of
this sort of thing so you need to make
sure you spend a lot of time probably
understanding their stakeholders is who
in HRD need to speak to is it privacy
people are there compliance people all
these different people to get the
approvals of kind of how you're going to
operate so speak to legal and say right
we're going to look at impersonating
organizations when we're doing social
engineering are you comfortable with
that what's it what's the impact we're
going to be socially engineering any
member of the company including the CEO
and the CSO and the financial director
and all these people how does that work
what sign-off do we need what kind of
mitigating controls do we have to have
in place what information we're going to
share all these things are really
important as you can't do it effectively
it also comes down to the rules of
engagement so when you're doing this who
you're going to notify when you're going
to notify them how long is it going to
happen
again I think you often need permission
because again you need your kind of ask
coverage so you're gonna be doing this
for a certain period of time who is
gonna be aware that's happening so I
think you should only have ideally no
more than a dozen if possible people in
the company if it's a large organization
of course if it's smaller should be less
because you want to make sure that when
you're doing this it really is for real
so only a minimum or a lot of people
know that it's happening so they respond
to it in that way
so the devil is in the detail right so
we got to this stage where we understand
why we're doing what it is we've hoped
you've got the buy-in and started to
establish some trusted people and so you
know now it's time to see if we can
document all this stuff we all have
documentation but it's important to
cover us
so you want to understand what is your
operating model so when you do physical
engagements for example are you going to
break windows and smashing doors or can
you is that not possible can you do lock
picking and bumping or that's not
possible what can you do can you drive a
truck through the door all these things
they might seem obvious or stupid
questions at the same time but some
people are going to let you you know
smashing doors and hire trucks and drive
through doors if that's what their risk
appetite is and you want to have this
all documented and get them signed off
by the legal team the privacy team's HR
teams all this stuff so when you do it
and ultimately someone's gonna ask you
that question well what were you doing
going in someone's back doing their
batch it was in our operating procedures
it was signed off right so you need to
have your ass covered and that comes
back to the statement of work as well so
every time you do something like I said
we're breaking the company's policies
most likely in what we're doing so the
statement of work should define a high
level what is the objectives that you're
trying to achieve when are you doing it
who are the signatories so who are the
people that are signing off based on
experience
it can be really hard to get these
things signed off in a timely manner so
when you're doing this from the
beginning you want to try and get things
kind of pre-approved right so you're
kind of asking almost asking forgiveness
and hoping that people you know read the
email and if they don't respond even a
certain period of time and that is your
approval I think that's one of the
hardest things that people seem to get
so when I speak to different red team's
about how many red team assessments they
do in a year you've got I guess the two
schools are for some that say they do
like 50 red team assessments a year and
these are ones that in my opinion aren't
necessary really red teaming because
it's like a one week engagement
including reporting everything and then
you ever ones that say oh we only do
about three because it's really hard to
get the different sign offs for the
people to do other things so somehow you
to find some middle ground
I think Rob covered some of this in his
talk yesterday's you need to understand
what it is you're reporting out on and
what is the communication model so when
you've done this piece of work how long
until you kind of give them the output
so ever that'd be a really lengthy
report you're going to present it or
there's documentation of all the
findings how are you going to do it when
are you going to do it and think Rob
mentioned this because you don't want
people constantly interrupting what
you're doing right it's going to impact
your thought process and your flow and
actually how effective you are if you're
doing this for you know six eight ten
weeks so if you're doing it non-stop
throughout the year you don't want to
have to keep on downing tools like every
five days to give someone on a debrief
on I've been looking through shares for
500 hours it's really interesting but
really that's all I've been doing right
now it's a reality I think a lot of time
with red teaming it's not that sexy
stuff the sexy stuff comes when you find
that password in clear text file and use
access to all the things the other
things again these are all boring things
but important things is how you're
managing and auditing the tasks and the
activities you do so you're going to
screw up because you're humans people
make mistakes
so you need to adequately understand
what happened who did it
where they did it to help fix the
problem but then more importantly I
think because I think most of time you
can be honest if you screwed up right
and helped fix things but due to this
type of work you're going to get blamed
probably for issues and outages right so
then you need this material to again
cover your ass to prove that we weren't
on that system we didn't execute these
commands the activities that were taking
and nothing to do with us I can speak
from experience quite recently that this
is very important then we spoke and
there's been a couple of talks over the
last couple days on intelligence so I
think intelligence is really important
so we'd call ourselves an intelligence
led red team as well of course so I
think intelligence is really important
you want to partner with
I have internal intelligence teams if
you have them or get intelligence from
outside if you have their funding or
availability but I also don't think that
you should be restricted to just
intelligence right so we speak about
adversarial emulation and of course we
should be trying to emulate the TTP's of
the adversary but I don't think we
should be restricted to just those TTP's
right so I give you an example a couple
years back we were doing engagement
trying to gain access to customer
information and the TTP's and I guess
the modus operandi that we had this
tractor in particular never had any
evidence of attacking databases directly
to get access to information we always
went through the application or some
other channel to gain access to that
data we couldn't find a way to get
access that data the same way but we did
find a way to get DBA access and just
take the data direct from the database
then when it came to reporting it out we
had lots of interesting discussions with
the intelligence team saying well that's
not how that sweater operates they don't
take the data like that so we don't
think this information is really helpful
lots of interesting discussion and
debate and two weeks later a phone call
from that intelligence team to say guess
what we just seen this this router that
you know you go to emulating a few weeks
ago and I've been stealing information
tracks on database so it's like wow
imagine that so this is important
because really if we're doing this right
I think we should really be doing
anything within our capabilities and our
budget or whatever it may be to find the
way of achieving those objectives by
earning as possible because the
adversary is gonna be doing that right
if if there's gonna be a billion pound
paycheck at the end of it they're not
gonna go well we normally go that way
but we're not gonna just utilize these
other opportunities we discover they're
gonna constantly adapt it's really about
being effective over a sophistication
right so this comes back to my point I
was kind of asking Justin about
yesterday was why go why are you gonna
exploit something if you don't need to
right if someone's just less than
something open on the internet you're
not gonna say oh I can't use that
because you know normally to xsplit
something cuz you know it just doesn't
make a sense and I think the key thing
with all this stuff documentation is
important and we can use checklists to
actually make our job easier
by the time if we talk about checklists
people kind of my interpret that as
we're taking their skillset away we're
taking their decisions away but actually
I think it's the opposite right so if
you read books on some of the really
smart people over time you're read about
decision fatigue right so we've only got
a certain amount of decisions that we
can make in a day before our brain
doesn't work right that's why that Steve
Jobs always wear the same clothes right
that's one decision he doesn't have to
make every morning so if we document
these things we have checked the list
checklists and procedures then we can
really focus on using our brain to make
really you know educated decisions
solving complex problems when we're
trying to simulate the adversary as
opposed to just wandering or the right
time to get a report in order should
something be okay then we come to
resources so this isn't just about
people that people are the most
important thing of any red team so all
see all the foundational stuff you need
make things possible I want to speak to
other red team's that have they say they
have an internal red team but really
they kind of outsource everything in use
fear parties the number one reason why
people say to me they don't have an
internal red team is they don't think
the work is challenging enough or the
work isn't something that we retain that
talent and I can agree so you the
leaders need to work harder right to
retain that talent make sure we're doing
right things push the boundaries and
kind of related to this foundational
stuff that I said in the first slide
just because you can't do that
in month one or year one doesn't mean
you don't keep on going back people I'm
changing the process right it's just
part of that crawl walk run fly process
you know you're not gonna it's very
unlikely that you're gonna rock up to
this company set up a red team and say
right we're just going to be kind of
hacking your ass all day every day
without telling anyone from day one it's
not going to happen right you have to
start off it's more batteries perhaps
it's just a two-week test and it's a
six-week testing it's a 10-week the test
and then now you're into just doing it
24 by 7 perhaps that took you 2 3 4 5
years to get there because the trust
thing is really important when it comes
to hiring I think team fit is really
more important than elite skills you can
kind of teach almost anyone anything but
you can't stop an asshole be an asshole
right that's just how they are it's true
we try it doesn't it and you should also
ask you should say I'm not hiring
everyone else is hiring I'm not hiring
but when I'm hiring we do have remote
people so and we'll favor for that also
I think you should be hiring people
better than you
and also as much as you can better than
everyone else in the team now better
doesn't mean Sun better skill it's all
about you know different ways of
thinking different ways of solving
problems I think diversity is really
important that's also comes back to the
remote thing right so the adversary is
everywhere all over the place right
they're not all just sat in this one
office in London or Poland or wherever
they're everywhere right so you want to
have people that can reflect that so you
want people that can speak different
languages people have different
backgrounds different cultures because
they bring different ways of thinking
right that's what makes you an amazing
team right it's not a red person it's a
red team so you want diversification
you're thinking different ways of
solving problems and this is I find this
to be really helpful and I also think
that again if it's a team effort obvious
difficult if you're building from
scratch because you tend to be just one
person that you can ask friends for
favors but try not to do this all in
isolation right so you're building a
team so those team of people should have
a say in who is going to be kind of
brought in to this like it's family
right that's the way I think about it
but I will say I've learnt this mistake
a couple of times even though you want
to you know do this collaboratively
trust your gut because the gut often
doesn't lie and the few times that I've
heard someone hasn't worked out very
well I had a bad gut feeling and my gut
was right and my brain was wrong and I'm
learning so now if the gut says no don't
hire them and we really want people that
solve problems right so less bitching
more doing so we want people that when
they find a problem they have the
initiative and the full process to
of a problem right red teaming is all
about solving problems so the door is
closed how do I get it open or how do I
get round it right so we want people
that solve problems and come with
solutions not just this sucks oh this is
crap or I can't do this or I've got
eight weeks to try and break into here
but it's really hard so I couldn't get
past the door so I guess I give up right
because if we were really the bad guys
and our paycheck is behind that door
you didn't just kind of go yeah sorry
and I also think you should test people
so I know there's a few people here that
have worked before I've been into
different places
test the people alright so think about
testing them technically but also
socially so again someone could be kind
of mad skills on the keyboard right but
you can't talk to them they don't to
collaborate they're just going to sit on
their own and again there's nothing
wrong with that but that might not be
the best person for a red team perhaps
there'd be better in some sort of
specialist penetration testing role
right where they can sit on our own not
want to talk to anybody I know in our
industry we don't like to talk to people
so that can be tricky and not also
everyone can't think like the bad guy
right so when we hit these stumbling
blocks we really should be trying to
think about doing things by almost any
means possible right and this is why
comes back to that original foundational
stage is can you only do technical stuff
or can you do social stuff as well so
can you do social engineering so fishing
fishing smishing all that sort of stuff
if you've got physical capabilities as
well if you don't have these options
then you're really restricted and
obviously a bad guy doesn't have those
same restrictions I think as leaders
that's that original point about people
feel they can't retain staff we need to
constantly find ways to challenge and
motivate people right so that's why I
was asking who's in a team and
unfortunate there's not many red people
here it would appear and but perhaps if
you do feel that you're not challenged
or not motivated you know challenge your
leaders to give you more opportunities
you know begin be part of the solution
don't just pitch the I job sucks and
everything's horrible here how can you
make it better come with their options
and also I think all of us if we say not
I think they probably lying we all have
egos because that's kind of why we do
what we do the humility is
really important right especially in a
team I think it's important to
understand the benefit your co-workers
bring so they may not be able to do
exactly the same things as you but
they're on that team for a specific
reason right they have skills or
something that they bring that benefits
overall okay so hopefully we've got all
the funding we need we can boil the
software with a hardware we've hired a
ton of smart people based all over the
place and now it's time to actually try
and do this whole thing this whole
adversarial emulation so as I mentioned
before we want to have some relationship
or some input in terms of intelligence
so we can understand what it is that
we're trying to emulate what's their
motivation what kind of tools and
tactics and things are they using we
really need to understand what the
scenario is so I don't like to talk
things in terms of scoping because by
scoping it sounds like there's stuff
that you can't do right now we all know
there's always stuff that you can't do
by thinking in terms of framing
something in the terms of scoping you're
already limiting yourself right so what
is the scenario and what the objectives
so just to give an example I use this
all the time so someone comes to you and
says we want a Red Team assessment we
want you to red team our DLP solution
anyone have experience with that that
kind of scenario and the answer should
be no because it's not a penetration
testing team is a red team so again not
saying one's better or the other this is
just about a different perspective
looking right so really if you're doing
a red team engagement and that is part
of the scenario you need to take a step
back right so the scenario should be
understanding why is that company put
DLP in place now typically it's to
prevent the loss of intellectual
property of some sort right so the
intellectual property should be the
scenario object is that's what you're
trying to achieve right so as an
adversary I don't think the adversaries
ever purposely trying to screw over DLP
right maybe they are but to get to
something right that's typically not
their kind of motivation so the
motivation is going to be that actual
property of some sort so that should be
the objectives now if you do it right
and you either can or can't steal the
intellectual property as a byproduct of
what you're doing you're assessing that
control right
so to give an example the penetration
testing team may do a penetration test
of that DLP solution and the
infrastructure they may find issues and
weaknesses but I doubt very much they're
gonna find that it's not looking at IP X
because that's not what they're doing
right they're testing the infrastructure
and solution and the software but the
red team will find potentially the fact
that that DLP solution isn't looking for
the crown jewels that you've stolen and
taken it away somewhere
that's the byproduct and the knowledge
they get also think about a vantage
point so I think Rob spoke about some
different vantage points in his
presentation so insider threat
opportunistic seen if you think about
where is it you're attacking from so are
you tacking outside from the internet
are you trying to replicate an insider
so that's a disgruntled and
opportunistic or are we talking about
some sort of breach point so I assume
breach that eventually we're gonna get
breached not know impossible so he's
gonna start from there so the issue we
always have is a red team is we don't
have unlimited budgets we don't have
unlimited times there's always some sort
of constraint so we have to bear that in
mind so vantage point is important and
then of course the level of knowledge
there's been a couple of blog posts
online recently talking about you know
how much knowledge should red team's
have and should you just spend ages
building up your own knowledge and I
think there's pros and cons of each I
think one of the biggest issues can be
when you're starting out is you may
achieve the objectives and then
someone's going to try and discredit you
right because I can say well of course
you do you were from this corporation
corporate corporation and so you know
where we kind of hide our skeletons
where we keep all the gold so if you
take the opposite approach by not
knowing anything and so you have to find
out all your own knowledge and that can
be more credible but see it takes up
time it consumes cycles you have to work
out what the trade-offs going to be and
you also need to understand those
boundaries so like I said before there
are only certain things that you can and
can't do so perhaps the CEO who's not
gonna be very happy if you social
engineer him and steal all this so
you need to understand early on if that
is something that you can or can't do
another thing that people don't tend to
think about in the corporate world
especially from a social engineering is
impersonation so if you send
a phishing email from someone saying
you're from PayPal that's technically
brand infringement right so you're
breaking the law but we know the bad guy
does this right and lots of non
corporate red team's tend to do this as
well because I don't know if the
liabilities are more acceptable you need
to understand you know if those are
things you can or can't do so if you do
them and it's very unlikely that
PayPal's on the found out that you send
that email so not gonna come knocking
but if they do you want to again have
your ass covered you want the backup as
I mentioned before log all the things so
everything you're doing love other
things cover your ass so when things get
bad you know how to kind of hopefully
fix it other things get bad and it
wasn't your fault
you can kind of get out the crap and
continue to main that trust and validity
you have already then the boring bits so
reporting your findings and kind of
taking people through the walkthrough of
what you've done and so I think it's
really important to a red team to be
based on facts and not opinions so you
might personally think that fire is a
big crappy shitty piece of product but
that doesn't have any place right so you
should really talk about what you
discovered what was it enabled you to do
and be constructive with your findings
right sir perhaps you did find a way to
mitigate or control the fire I product
was doing that's what you should be
talking about in a constructive manner
what it was you able to bypass all be
able to do doesn't matter whether you
personally think the product is good or
not be really clear on the impact so I
think we talked about this a lot in the
industry of I got shell but shell
doesn't mean anything and so you need to
be you know clear so you've got shell on
the box what was the impact this enabled
me to do X if it didn't need enable you
to do anything and of course you still
need to tell someone that that happened
but what's the impact the impacts going
to be a lot lower right so getting
domain admin perhaps that doesn't give
you access to the information you're
trying to steal right because it's
another domain that you need to gain
access to to steal the data also I think
a thing that's quite tricky and red
teaming is rating your finding or the
discovery because this can change
depending on the impact right so let's
say that you find default creds on
something and in one engagement that
default creds leaves you on to discover
all the juicy things that enable you to
achieve your objectives right so you
would
kind of identify that was at the
beginning of the kill train or have you
kind of communicated this information so
that we rate it quite high right so
default creds on whatever was very
impactful in us achieving the objective
now if you find evil cred somewhere else
and it doesn't give you jack then
it should be a lower rating right
because it didn't do anything
you still need to disclose it just still
be fixed but the impact is much less I
think the tricky thing that we really
struggle with is communicating in a
language that business can understand
this is something that I think I'm still
trying to get better at and most people
I know are so you can you know explain
in great detail the technical things
that you did but we don't really focus
enough on explaining in an impactful
business way of why it's an issue and
perhaps that's something that we've
failed to understand in that
foundational piece right why are we here
what are we trying to do what is the
risk appetite I think they had that on
the previous slide right so just give an
example again from experience perhaps
you've been asked to steal a certain
amount of money they haven't been very
descriptive of that monetary value but
you're like well two million pounds is
that shitload of money to me right but
then you might steal two million that's
fine that's hidden risk appetite it
needs to be twelve million right so
you're ready to understand what it is
you're trying to do to make sure you're
doing the right type of work and have
the right impact use diagrams and
pictures so people might not understand
technical words come in your mouth but
they can follow through a diagram to try
and interpret what it is you're telling
them so they can understand the
relevance and then the thing that I
think is important is the controller's
effectiveness so as you said with that
DLP example and we're not here to test
the controls but that should be a kind
of a byproduct of what happening this
happened in terms of what we do to
protect detect and respond right so as
you go through this process talk about
the controls that you came up against do
they help do they hinder as far as
you're aware didn't no one see anything
and so you weren't blocked this way you
oft you want to speak to the blue team
and that collaborative stage later to
find out did they really see everything
just decide to do nothing cuz so it's
the internal red team who cares or or
did you really go undetected and now see
when you're sharing this in from
you are doing a timely manner so that
people can fix and resolve things
quickly but we also need to make sure we
do it securely right so especially if
we've got all this information and
diagrams perhaps we're just painting a
picture of how to steal the crown jewels
from the company right so if you haven't
done that securely you're basically
helping people you know just give them a
map now of course you can't control what
someone does with that there's anyone
from various group in here anymore
but I think last year various group did
some work for someone and somehow that
got posted on on the internet right so
again you can't control what someone
else does but do what you can to limit
that exposure oh I guess the one thing
that is really important is disclosure
so I think in general back to the ego
thing we like to hold things back and
not disclose it because we like it
didn't really kind of get us what we
needed but I'm sure next time that's
going to be really important and you
kind of keep on doing this week after
week month after month and then two
years later you still have this thing
that one day is going to pay off
we need to remember why we're here right
so we need to disclose things because
our job is to you know reduce the risk
and help people make those more informed
decisions about what they're gonna fix
fix
but disclosing stuff doesn't mean
handing everything over right so let's
say you've got shells or beacons or
whatever it is you're using on certain
infrastructure disclosure didn't
necessarily mean saying hey look we've
got these 20 beacons on these 20 boxes
the disclosure would mean explaining how
you got them right so perhaps there was
a funder ability or miss configuration
then they would you to get there and
then it's up to someone else to work out
if they understand you still got
persistence or what have you right so
you're still helping them give the noise
to close the gap but not giving the
whole game up okay and so kind of that
kind of sums that I think the red
teaming piece so by day we're these
ninja kind of wearing people but outside
of that there's more we can do to drive
change and collaborate and I guess this
is why the conference is like this
exists so the blue teaming and red
teaming piece and so I think it's really
important to identify who you can
collaborate with in the organization so
I think this is something that happens
later so remember back to your mission
what is it you're here to do so make
sure you kind of establish yourself
first what it is you're doing as you go
spend your time doing everyone else's
job and that's that's great but not so
good for you I guess when it comes to
review time and working out what value
you're bringing we want to get to a
point where you're understanding who are
people you can collaborate with in the
organization so I think typically people
identify that the blue team or the cert
team whatever you call it in the
organization makes sense but you might
think that you only collaborate with
them in this kind of combative
experience right but I don't think it
should be like that so obviously when
you're being the bad guy there is some
combative experience going on but you're
not doing that 24 by 7 or even if you're
doing continuous operations there's
gonna be times where you want to work
with them and help them understand
things so in organizations I've worked
at we did this thing which we call mini
detect and I think it's similar to think
what they're talking about yesterday
with the target guys so we do additional
work with them to check for known knowns
right so we will run and automate
scripts that when we've finished an
engagement if we're left with like 20
endpoints they've been compromised we
will run those scripts in a non covert
way to check certain things perhaps you
can leak information to certain ways or
certain things triggering and this is
just one way that we can be
collaborative in a non offensive way and
really help validate if those controls
are effective and the reason why I think
it's important to do this from kind of
unexpected endpoints so you might say
you do fabric of stuff and you know you
always do it from your work your work
station or from a set work station but
there are problems you're never
discovering things in a non controlled
manner right so typically when you're
doing engagement you're going to have
multiple endpoints you have access to in
some form that typically someone never
would have randomly selected right so by
doing it this way the only helping
validate the known knowns or the gaps
but it's really random and you're going
to help people discover things that they
probably wonder discovered in a very
rapid time and my experience this has
proven to be really really valuable we
can also do stuff to improve education
awareness stuff so the SE stuff is
what's more interesting to me and I'm
sure most of the companies you work at
have things like fish me great things
we won't want you fish me but I think
all of us can probably accept that when
we get a fish me email you know it's an
awareness email right because it's so
poorly written so perhaps we can work
with those people to craft better
awareness phishing campaigns right just
different things like that
and we can combine our skill sets to do
greater things now combining skill sets
doesn't mean telling someone they're
stupid and you could do their job better
than them because that's not gonna get
the right result right so the old idea
is that we bring great minds together to
do great work have in a more impactful
discussions and this is something I
think doesn't happen very often and I
think also is kind of blurred a little
bit with all this labeling stuff right
so a place I currently work we do lots
of collaborative work but then people
have a discussion about we I really
think we should do some purple teaming
well we do all this amazing stuff yeah
but it's not purple teaming I mean well
it is we just don't call it purple team
right so we're getting you know caught
up on a color or a phrase that's just do
cool amazing that has an impact who
cares what color it is right so just we
need to focus more on doing good things
as opposed to where it ticks um latest
trendy box that we're talking about okay
a speak faster okay so just touch on the
leadership piece so I think leadership
is important I think people don't leave
companies necessarily you leave kind of
the bad experience of a leader or a boss
or whatever you decide you want to call
them so I think the leaders job is to
not be a hypocrite so don't expect more
others than you expect of yourselves
your job is to remove blockers right so
you should be the blocker basically
right so these amazing guys when I
concentrate and doing their job your job
is to kind of keep scooping the
away so they can focus on it help people
to follow their dream right so we
shouldn't be necessarily stopping people
from leaving obviously if they're great
we want to cultivate an environment so
they do the best things for us the
organization we're at but you should
give them opportunities to do great
things wherever they want to right to
help them follow their dreams share your
imperfections I screw up a lot and I'm
happy to tell people that I screw up
and I think that helps people trust you
more right so in this type of work and
I've had this before someone makes a big
mistake and then they tell you they
didn't make the big mistake so you go
and scoop all that and then one day
someone goes actually I did make that
mistake right so I think if you're more
honest and open about your imperfections
hopefully they're going to follow suit
make your job a lot easier from a team
perspective I think we need to do I call
start and in the race together so anyone
familiar with the Pareto principle a
Prada you said that wrong so you lots of
people to what it's in the finance world
right so 80% of the world's riches are
in trim percent the people I think is
the same thing in a team right you don't
have a team of people all bring their
different kind of skills and values but
you can have different grades of player
right so you go to a players or B
players or C players no one is better or
worse than anyone else they're just
different right some people especially
this industry we're kind of mad for it
right we just we don't stop work other
people a bit more sensible and at five
o'clock they want to go home and do
stuff that's kind of what is going to
happen in the team so perhaps 20% of the
people doing 80% of the work but the key
thing is we all start and finish the
race together right so when it gets hard
you don't just kind of go it those
two people are really amazing they're
gonna do it all anyway right the idea is
you keep running with them you're gonna
get better and you're doing it as a team
challenge each other constructively so
he thinks someone does something in a
stupid way or a wrong way I asked them
understand why be constructive respect
each other communicate even people that
sit in the same room don't talk to each
other
perhaps they just type on a keyboard we
should talk even more important in a
remote team right that we have open
lines of communication as I said earlier
if you up speak up
your boss is there to defend you but you
can't defend you if you're lying to them
I think also ensure some research time
right so the adversary is constantly
looking for new ways of doing things
there's lots of great information around
people need to research but they can't
kind of flourish if they don't have the
time to do that
so just wrapping up if you're building a
red team or in a red team there's going
to be lots of politics frustrations and
crap you have to deal with but don't be
afraid to fight focus on doing what you
know best so you're not there you're not
a defender right so don't tell them how
to do your job focus on doing what
you're good at
collaborate as much as you can drive
change drive accidents do amazing things
at different people you're going to make
mistakes you can't do everything on day
one continue to evolve continue to push
yourself and the main thing I'm always
focused on is progress over perfection
right so don't get don't let good
getting away greatness whatever you say
have you'll want to look at it just do
good things iterate make improvements on
one day you will be amazing and I
already think that the red team's that
I've been a part of have been amazing
the people I've worked with are amazing
and they really helped me kind of get up
energized every morning I know this is
that idealist thing to say I'm very
fortunate to spend maybe like the last
ten years kind of enjoying every day at
my job there's politics of stuff right
but if you're not getting up in the
morning and energized by the people
you're working with go somewhere else do
something else or be the instigator
change make it happen we can do amazing
things I'm finished yeah
so any any questions from the audience
actually I have a one question so you
you said about the adversary emulation
so how do you how do you measure
yourself against how how well your team
is simulating a real threat is the gut
feeling or something more measurable you
know I hate metrics so I hate metrics so
I think there are lots of different ways
to try and measure yourself and perhaps
I'm just making excuses that and that's
fine I'm happy to say that but I think
partly it's a gut feeling at the same
time I think it's very difficult to
measure yourself I think one thing I
forgot to say is that all the antennas
we get and those people do fantastic
jobs like I can do it
but the only people that really know
exactly what the bad guys doing is the
bad guy right everything else is some
examination or some disclosure of
something so we never really know
exactly what we're doing right back to
that database example I gave so we get
intelligence sometimes it's good
sometimes it's but we shouldn't
like constrain ourselves by doing it so
I think if you end each engagement
knowing you gave it your all you did the
best you could then that should be kind
of the measurement of yourself if you're
doing less than that then I don't think
you need metrics to decide that you
probably could do better okay anyone
else thank you I guess not so thanks
Dave
[Music]