hello everyone i'm dev lindelow i'm a
software developer
at nmeta and i'm here to talk about
introduction
to passato platform agnostic
security tokens first of all i'd like to
thank
besides budapest for this opportunity
i'll be uh sharing you this pasero
okay so let's start
so just to uh refresh our
memory here's um
jwt and some
other things this is json web tokens
you know it's our oh an open industry
standard rfc 7519 method
for representing claims securely between
two parties right
here's a sample uh token jelly belly
token job token
from jwt website so as you can see here
it's divided into three
there's the header payload and
the signature so sub subject
yap issue time
jwt is used today for securely exchange
[Music]
information between two servers and then
also in a single page
application authentication or spa
or authorized operations across servers
we have some acronyms here
we have uh jose or jose
javascript object signing and encryption
also the name
of the working group jose
is actually a framework intended to
provide
a method to securely transfer claims
between parties
the next is the jot you know
representing claims in
compact and url safe means
nexus we have jwe or the json web
encryption
which encrypts content
you know and then jws
which is the json web signature
which secures content with digital
signatures
and then jwk
is the json web key represents
keys used for signing and encryption
and then we have gwa which is json web
algorithm
which is a cryptographic
algorithm and identifiers use
with all the above
and here we have supported algorithms
we have hmac shop
hs and then rsa plus shop rs
we also have es256
which is a symmetric key cryptography
algorithm electric
curve digital signature algorithm and
then
some ps here
so next is signing versus encryption
uh encryption you know for unreadable
data to unauthorize parties
so perfect for confidentiality
then we have signing here is for data
integrity
you know message authentication and
reflection
and you know for uh
integrity in short and then
multiple ways of signing
with a secret uh using hmac that's one
and then
with a private key using rsa easy
in others
and some pointers here
you know multiple systems can issue
tokens a token can be used
by multiple systems
all these systems can use different
libraries
now let's go to vulnerabilities and
exploitation
in chat or json web tokens
first still the first uh
vulnerability that can be found
it's not checking the signature so
some jwt or json web token libraries
methods are decode and verify
so the problem with you know with this
code
here is that this is what
i used to happen before
in in some cases that
uh there was a bridge or something
here jwt.decode instead of
you know verifying it or gwt verify
it's a big mistake here next is
exploitation so how do you explain this
get a token decode
and then tamper with payload then
send the token that's it easy
next vulnerability the non-algorithm
here
and i think i should use this one
laser pointer yeah i think it's better
the non-algorithm
so used to be supported by default in
few libraries
basically don't sign the token
and exploitation
get a token decode the header and change
the algorithm
none or none decode and tamper with the
payload and then
keep or remove the signature that's it
next is algorithm confusion h map
rsa for instance the token
has been signed using hmac instead of
rsa
you tell the receiver it's an hmac and
it verifies
it with the public key thinking it's rsa
so this is the exploitation
get a token sign with rsa decode the
header
and change the algorithm from rsa
to hmac then tamper with the payload
lastly sign the token with the public
rsa key
easy kid parameter
so uh kid is an optional
header claim which holds a key
identifier
particularly useful when you have
multiple
keys to sign the tokens and you need to
look up the right
one to verify the signature this is done
prior to the verification
of the signature
so what kind of exploitation can we do
here
get assigned token containing kit
parameter
decode the header and change the kit
with sql
injection payload then tamper with a
payload lastly sign the token using the
return value
from the sql injection and that's it
rim
next is wikis
so here's an example jwt sign with
hs256 any secret
sn1f
exploitation get the
jwt cracker it's available online and
then
from this code runtime get the wt crack
and then followed by the
token itself you'll
get this secret
it's too short that's why you can easily
do this
and there's more you know in like
invalid
curve attacks yeah
so uh as you can see here
developers need like me we need easy to
use
tools that don't open the door to a ton
of attacks
there are a lot of ways for dwt's to go
wrong
big into the jose standards
the jose uh jose you know advocate
response to this criticism
is use a specific library
so this ships the blame into the library
developers
and the library users
and it has industry anti-patterns
like standard designers here
let's give users a lot of choices it's
not good
right and then the advocates
then blame the implementation rather
than
the standard and then the security
experts
just tell you declare standard harmful
provide no alternative then we as
developers roll our own crypto
so yeah can you really blame the
developers
now we have here pasero platform
agnostic
security tokens
so posero is everything you love about
hosting
jwt kw e jws without
any of the many design deficits that
plague the
jose standards that's good definition
from the pasero
website so here's an example of pasero
token
grab my laser so it's divided into
three and four here version
and then purples then payload
and there's a optional footer
which is an example a version here v1 or
v2
and then local
then the payload here up to here and
then the filter
so what is the version what does it do
version tells you what version of pasero
is being used with the token
and if if v3 comes out
a year from now then users would only be
allowed to use
v2 version 2 or version 3
but no longer version one
let's go to the next one the purpose
which is local the public diff or
different types of pasero
so local means um referred to
as symmetric or shared key facets
because
that is the type of the cryptography
that they use
always encrypted and
an attacker that was able to get a hold
of the token will not be able to see the
data inside unless he has a key
and then the public both paseros are
always
signed but public is not encrypted
so that's the second part of the token
the
purpose
so here um
next is what's inside the passato
payload
this is an example of poseta payload
we have you know id here
email or permissions
and here are the rest the payloads
samples
sub expiration issuers object audience
variation not before issue that token id
key id
and then the last part which is an
optional
footer it's a base64 url
some people wants to do key rotation
so um they would want an encrypted
part of the local token they get stored
like
a key identifier that references a
specific
public key or specific secret
and here are some placenta
implementations
i'm not sure if you can see it here so
let's
uh take a look in the list one by one we
have
for c language here then for elixir
for go language for java
de pasetto which you'll see it uh
later
javascript acetojs lua
for net and node.js
for php python will be ros
and swift then its features
so a jwt versus uh pasetto
um
jwt here yes
that's horror of knobs and levers and
unauthenticated modes are available
so json.tokens has a lot of options
including often
unauthenticated options right or spacero
you have two options version and purpose
everything is authenticated
local tokens are always encrypted so
that you don't actually uh
click sensitive information
for a local system
so locate demo here
i do this
okay yeah
so this is a java application
and as you can see here we're importing
jpacetto from here to here
and now what does it do is it's
just it's going to print some fields
here
so let's go to the top
here all the way to the
print line so yeah
shared secret keypair
here's create token we have great token
here
then parse token
result get claims get audience
and also custom claim here total claims
here's the implementation of the create
token
in the above it returns this passato
version one
um we have set shared secret here
enter then set issued at
set expiration set audience
set issuer then claim
and then make it compact
i also have a parse token here from
pasero
um parts builder set
shared secret set public key we have
build here
then return it
so yeah and then search secret again
required audience record issuer build
so let's try to run this
so there you go there's the paseo token
version one local
then the payload yup over here
we have token claims uh
there is an audience
and here's scott i don't know how to
pronounce his name sorry um
he's the the writer of pasero
so says here's the at least
some some list of cryptography designed
for humans
opinionated interfaces with few options
now you should have an opinionated
interface
so here's we have encrypt and decrypt
the encrypt here should be your api for
any encryption library
then users shouldn't ever need to even
know
what enough is to encrypt safely persian
protocols with hard-coded cyber suites
valid by cryptographers of course then
logically separate
symmetry cryptography from asymmetric
cryptography
api should be simple and easy to
understand and actually there's a lot
more
you should see uh his presentation video
it's in the internet i would highly
recommend you to
watch it so
yeah um thank you for
listening that's uh an introduction to
pasero hope you learned something
okay i'm out thanks