hello and welcome everyone
my name is zaina antoine and in the next
good half an hour or so i'd like to make
a call
to think together the title of this
presentation
is the art of ceso and by the end of
this session
even though there will not be any demo
here i hope that
by mixing art logic technology
and the people behind all of these can
assist us in enhancing cyber security
a little bit of my background i was
lucky that i could have
hands-on experience of a great variety
of
aspects of i.t including cabling
building up new branch offices
supporting client and server side
computers and firewalls
during the outsourcing era in the early
2000s i was privileged that i could
be a member of corporate ito the team
of a multinational corporation traveling
the world
to audit the i.t services provided to
the customers of this company
and the id security posture that was
delivered to them
during the early 2010s
later in the late 2010s i could lead a
program
that aimed to harmonize regulatory
requirements
globally and translate those to id
controls
and in the last one and a half year or
so
i act as a cso
for a number of subsidies of one of the
largest banks in hungary
so with that introduction let me
start to frustrate you on the next
slide
is there anything in common with these
two pictures
well what possibly could be in common
in leonardo da vinci and the i.t
guys of the 1990s the
caesar of our modern corporate world
and the art that we have in the title of
this presentation
by the end of this session we will
establish a link
and see that these seemingly distant
things
are not that far from each other and the
title
hopefully will make some sense as well
but for that
we have to start a little bit further we
need to understand a little bit of
history
where we came from the common thing
behind both of these pictures
is the concept and that concept is
already dead
wow some might say that's gross
how can something be said even
or some might say well hell yeah it's
dead
of course so well the
common thing the concept behind leonardo
da vinci's famous picture
and a computer that i used to learn
i.t in high school is
lying within the concept that
they are representing
leonardo was a polyhistor
or as literature often refer to him a
renaissance man the worst polyhistor
originated from the latin and ancient
greek
meaning greatly learned
they are men who use both
left brain and right brain type of
thinking
and as a result these are the
characteristics of them
curious risk taker creative
has perseverance self-discipline
has a thirst for knowledge and new
experiences
excellence in physical intellectual
artistic
and social fields and
including deep experience in at least
one
of the field and is
exceptional in some other fields
and most importantly they are always
learning in the early stages of the
computing era
when someone knew how to use a computer
and how to fix it they knew the
computers
period at that time the iit guy
of the 1990s was some kind of
polyhistor as they knew the machine
they could write code they could fix
hardware issues
and do all kinds of magical stuff
however like beginning from the
renaissance age
the aviable knowledge started to grow
within this
industry as well well it became
an industry after all and
became first harder and then later
impossible for someone to became a real
polyhistory
similarly in our modern age
things getting more and more connected
and the available knowledge within the
iit industry
grew well it became an industry for
starters
people start to get specialized
corporations became more and more
complex
entities with numerous business units
and organizations within them
of which more often than not have
at least competing interests segregation
of duties
and the specialized and standardized
tasks within a workforce process
resulted in isolation and that
high level leaders are less able to
oversight the cooperation as a whole
compared to
their ability to do so a decade ago
technology became an integral part of
the business
in most cases without senior executives
and the board's consciousness thus
today we live in an era of
monoliths or specialists
well sure you can say
okay so what's the problem with that
well almost 30 years ago
two academic writers highlighted
that business and marketing strategies
should be viewed as interlocking rather
than separate
back then they stated this for
businesses
and marketing strategies and it was
quite
a thinking
today i.t strategies
can neither be overlooked nor handled
separately
what else is a problem
well that humans don't
change as fast as technology did while
culture itself
changed as well edgar shane
defined organizational culture
as a pattern of shared
basic assumptions that the group learned
as it solved its problems of external
adaptation
and internal integration that has worked
well enough to be considered valid
and therefore to be taught to new
members
as the correct way to perceive
think and feel in relation to those
problems
have you ever heard this we do
things this way around here this is the
way we always did it
so what's the problem with specialists
the problem is that people stuck
with one way of thinking they have
blinders on
and they cannot see the big picture
including the relationship
and similarities between different
things
as i said it seems that the concept of
the renaissance man
is dead but what the heck
does it have to do anything with the
ceso and the title of this presentation
well like in any good sandwich and i do
apologize for the vegetarians and vegans
here
the meat is in the middle and in the
case of the word
siso the letters i
and s are in the middle meaning
information and security
and in the media another word is often
used
between these two which is cyber
security
we do believe that we
know what they mean but do we really
know
so let's open up a little bit
information what is information
there are a number of different
definitions according to the
oxford dictionary in general it means
facts provided or learned about
something or someone
in computer terms it defines
this word as data that is
processed stored or transmitted by a
computer
however we can use a different approach
like legal boxes if you like the little
building boxes data
information knowledge
wisdom let's say for example that
someone gets data from my computer's
browsing history and since that
i was looking for information about the
security requirements of the
hungarian nuclear power plant
from the browsing history they can see
that later i was
listening to some german punk metal
music
and i was looking up to concerts of that
band in
berlin germany again later
they can see that i was looking for
flights
from berlin to budapest
so this is data once
whoever got these individual data parts
of my browsing history
can say that she or he
has a piece of information about me and
can make a deduction from these pieces
of information
and try to get knowledge from it
using all these previous uh
examples uh that whoever
got this information um maybe got from
my browsing history
combined it with my family name antman
which which is a german name
someone might deduct that
german cyberpunk wants to blow up pakish
the hungarian nuclear power plant
deduction
yes knowledge and wisdom
not quite see putting it like this
it obviously feels bogus
but in reality leaders
are making decisions based on data that
were
organized into information by incorrect
deductions
and they believe that they are acting on
knowledge
based on information and wisdom while in
fact
they have not
the second letter in the middle of the
word is
security this word is
defined as the state of being
free from danger or threat
well this definition
opens up a question
the question that how could we
know whether we are free from threat
especially today when every source of
news is
full of reports of crimes data leakage
attacking our personal and private
information
and so on the
committee of sponsoring organizations of
the trade way commission or koso
developed the model and although it was
updated in 2013
and it's a cube now i
believe that for this purpose their
original model
could illustrate the concept i'd like to
convey here better
so control environment
this is the basis and foundation of
everything only when we knew
with real knowledge
can we assess the potential risks that
can
affect it once we know the risks
that are applicable to whatever we have
we can develop controls to address these
risks
mitigate accept transfer
once we put appropriate controls in
place
we just have to monitor any changes
change any changes in these elements
and adjust as needed
for which information and communication
are a key and we come
back to the communication part in just a
little bit
consequently there is another word
that is commonly used amongst the
previous two which
i mentioned which is cyber security
so let's have a little
bit under the hood of the
cyber part of this world
cyber according to media
is derived from
cybernetic which
comes and originates from the greek word
i don't even try to pronounce that
but it means skilled in
steering or governing
cybernetics has been defined in numerous
ways
such as the art of steermanship
the art of securing efficient operation
the art of effective organization the
art of
interaction in dynamic networks or
a science that is connected with the
study of systems of any nature
which are capable of receiving storing
and processing information so as to use
it
for control
okay so now that we
know what is information what is
security
let's have a look of an element that
plays
an important part in the equation
namely human beings the individuals
working within a company
and their personality and my apologies
again let's pause here for a second
and let's look under the hood the word
personality this word is originated from
the latin word
persona which was a mask
that an actor wore during a play
which signified his character by
displaying
it in an overamplified way
according to the american psychological
association
personality refers to individuals
differences in characteristic patterns
of
thinking feeling and behaving
this different behavior can
play a part in two dimensions
firstly in a person's interactions with
others and secondly an individual's
reactions
provided to stimulus from the external
verb
in other words in the first case
some folks are talkative in a party some
others
are there to eat drink and to be left
alone
in this second case someone might crack
under pressure
while some others get strength from it
one of the most well known
categorization of the
second case is the myers-briggs
type indicator or mbti which
categorizes people from four different
aspects and assessing people
out of the 16 potential types
for example extroverts and introverts
for the first case minsberg's
categorization is the most well known as
he differentiated between ten roles
and three categories without going
too deeply into the topic i just like to
highlight three which could contribute
the best for a cso
one of the most important roles lies
within the
information category namely the
disseminator role
in the information age one of the most
crucial key element is the ability
to understand assimilate
and appropriately rely information
remember information and knowledge
in the interpersonal category the two
key roles
for a ciso would be the leader and the
liaison as motivation internally
and representing unity externally is
vital
lastly the category related to the
ability of decision making has two key
roles
which are the entrepreneur and the
negotiator
as the prior one needs to realize the
opportunities
both external and internal and negotiate
it
and bring it through senior management
and the board as needed okay
but why the heck are am i
talking about this what do we want to
achieve
what's the end game well the end game is
to secure information
secure information
a data breach is an incident
in which sensitive protected or
confidential data has
potentially been viewed stolen
or used by an individual unauthorized to
do so
ibm defined the data breach as an
event in which an individual's name
and medical record and or a financial
record
or by an debit card
is potentially put at risk either in
electronic
or paper format the distinction
of paper format is important
these numbers are actually
scary cyber attack
occurs every 39
seconds the average time
to identify and contain a breach
across all industries
is 279
days it's more than nine months
nine months and we can see the cost
of the data breach which has
consistently risen over the past year
and the cost to recover from a
ransomware
skyrocketed as well an interesting twist
that ransomware attacks nowadays
are actually threatening their victims
to release data rather than
asking money to unlock a computer than
they started off with
the number of data breaches increased by
in the half or first half of 2019
uh and in total more than 4.1 billion
records have been
exposed in the year
2019 so last year on december 4
2019 a security researcher discovered
2.7 billion email addresses
and plain text passwords for
more than one billion of them in an
unsecured online database
verizon's 2019 insider threat report
estimates that insider threat
caused more than third of all data
breaches
as far as root causes the 2019 ibm study
found
that 51 percent was due to malicious
attacks
and 24 due to human error
only 25 percent caused
by system glitches according to a fourth
article
published in uh april uh this year
70 of all data breaches are originated
from
end points like laptop computers
phones mobile devices
pcs
further due to the skyrocketed home
office
introductions across the globe due to
this
coveted 19 pandemic a may 2020
fourth article predicts that the biggest
cyber attack in history will happen
in the next six months
well how is it possible
that we have this many breaches how is
it possible that
with all of the increased spending and
focus on information security
still 70 percent of
all the breaches are originating from
the endpoints
well at the end of 2019
people are still using the passwords
that you can see on the left
in addition more than 44 million
microsoft accounts
were using passwords that had already
been compromised elsewhere
so the question seems obvious real
people
ever learn but
the answer is not that obvious
the world economic forum provides an
annual platform
and an opportunity for leaders and
multi-stakeholders
to engage with each other participants
of
this forum were asked to
[Music]
conduct and participate in the
global risk perception survey
which is published each year
according to this year's report
although more than 50 percent
of the world's population is online
i let it think a little bit more than
50 percent of all the population
in the world are online
still approximately 1 million
people go online
for their first time each
day let
it fit this a little bit as well
1 million people go online
for their first time every
day therefore
what might be repetitious and obvious
for
us in this conference room and
whoever is listening to this there are 1
million
individuals each day who have no clue
in addition these new users are mostly
from developing countries
and in the world economic forum survey
they concluded that today's emerging
economies
are expected to comprise six of the
world's seven largest economies by 2050.
respondents of the survey also rated
information
infrastructure breakdown as the sixth
most impactful risk in the years
until 2030 and cyber attacks on critical
infrastructure very
very rated as the fifth top risk in 2020
and this is not just some irrational
fear
such attacks have already affected
entire cities
and multiple states
for example in december 2019
new orleans had to declare a state of
emergency
due to a ransomware attack shortly
before that
the governor of louisiana had to do the
same
earlier in 2017 attacker could take down
the emergency services number 911
in 12 states imagine the situation
you want to ask for help
from 9-1-1 or from
1-1-2 call the police
and the service is down
could be shocking especially if you are
in that situation
when you would desperately need a help
an interesting fact is that only
5.9 percent of the emergency
centers had any program or plan to
address events like that so public and
private sectors
are like at risk of being compromised
and or held as a hostage
organized cyber crime entities are
joining forces
and the likelihood of detection
such an organization and the prosecution
is estimated to be
as low as 0.05
percent in the u.s
we all heard about the software as a
service and
platform as a service model well
there is a cyber crime as a service
which is also a growing muslims model
as the increasing sophistication of
tools on the darknet
makes malicious services more affordable
and easily accessible for anyone some
experts
stated after the new orleans state of
emergency that
cisos focus on technological defenses
when they should also be patching their
colleagues
with regular stimulated attacks and
security awareness trainings
besides all of these threats the amount
of data that we generate
both structured and unstructured is
exponentially and we almost could say
concerningly growing in addition
the fourth industrial revolution
technologies will dramatically
reshape economies and societies
who makes money and how has already
changed
and this is still changing doctor zoltan
chef
ambassador of hungary to the oecd and
the unesco
quoted cleve humbly sheffield
mathematician
who stated that data is the new oil
and highlighted that on a data economy
highlighted on a data economy conference
in january 2018
that the age of globalization is over
today there is a shift towards the age
of technology
and new economic models
such as peer-to-peer economy sharing or
on-demand
eclipse collaborative economy and
platform economies
in the data-driven economy ownership is
replaced by
access and products by services
according to the idc by
2020 50 of
large enterprises will be generating
data as a service revenue from the scale
of data
and by 2025
50 of the revenue will be generated by
sharing economy while it was only five
percent
back in 2013. uber
one of the world's largest taxi
companies
owns no vehicle facebook the most
popular media owner
actually creates no content alibaba the
most valuable retailer has no inventory
and rbmb the world's largest
accommodation provider
owns no real estate since the
industrial revolution the world has
developed
a complex supply chain
from designers manufacturers to
distributors
to importers wholesalers
and retailers it is
what allowed billions of products to be
made
shipped both and enjoyed in all
corners of the world however in recent
times
the power of the internet especially the
mobile phone
has unleashed a movement that's rapidly
destroying these layers
and moving power to new places
so it's clear that demographics have
changed
even the skills that brought our society
to
wherever we are today have changed we
previously mentioned
world economic forum survey concluded
that
approximately 50 percent of companies
worldwide
predict that automation will trim their
current full-time workforce by 2022.
and by that same year researchers
expect at least 55
percent 54
of employees will need re-skilling
and upskilling to complete their jobs
folks this is just two years from today
not in some
distant future and in this economy
where data is the new oil the question
arises
who owns and who controls the data
and who is protecting all these
information
ok so we know all this
see this but there is another hidden
challenge
besides the obvious ever increasing rate
and sophistication of
attack vectors which is unfortunately
senior management and the corporate
culture
that's harsh i know i know
still it is our reality
more often than not well we know that
there is no such thing as 100 percent
secure environment security
costs money and when appropriate funding
is requested
from the board who might not have a
clear understanding of the full depth of
the
i.t security as we discussed earlier
the change happened without their
consciousness
they might ask okay so
we are spending this money now on this
fancy new firewall
i understand but what's on the income
side
well this mindset
unfortunately seems to be validated by a
survey
conducted amongst the csos that
found that almost a quarter
of interviewed cesos said that boards
didn't accept or understand that
breaches
are inevitable and said that
they hold them personally accountable
for
any incidents
so it would seem that culture and
corporate and
organizational culture plays a vital
role
here remember we talked about the
importance of the
foundation of everything earlier when we
had a look at the corso triangle
i mentioned that we'll discuss the
information and communication part a
little bit more
later well this is later
as it was mentioned there if senior
management
acts based on an understanding that
it is not funded on knowledge they
cannot
act even with their best
interest in place appropriately
i have seen far too many times that
middle management
simply does not report yellow or red
kpis or
slas to senior management because of
various reasons it has to be green they
said
well in september 2015 electronics
conglomerate
toshiba admitted that it had overstated
its earnings
by nearly 2 billion over 7 years
independent investigators found that
toshiba had a corporate culture
in which management decisions could not
be challenged
and employees were pressured into
inappropriate
accounting by postponing loss reports
or move moving center certain loss
and costs into later years
another example probably one of the most
well known to date
and of course we can thank the birth of
stocks and many regulations since then
is the enron scandal the company
reportedly has had a go-go culture
in which senior officials cast aside
traditional business controls
it is possible that all of these
previously mentioned facts
were part of the reason why 86
of the participants of the 2014 world
economic forum survey
identified a crisis in leadership as the
world's most pressing issue
issue and 51
of the respondents of the 2018 world
economic forum survey
expected that the risk of authoritarian
leadership would increase
in 2019 william
h white an american organizational
analyst said that the single biggest
problem
in communication is the illusion
that it has taken place
one of my first mentors said to me that
thinking is hard word that is why so few
people do it
char sparrow a famous sociologist
described today's world as a complex and
tight coupled system
in which even a small issue can cause
cascading effects
that is why it is so important to start
thinking again
and see the big picture vincent van gogh
said
that great things are done by a series
of
small things brought together vince
lombardi
a famous american football coach said
that
the achievements of an organization are
the results of the combined
effort of each individual
you can say that these sentences
feel obvious or cliche but the fact is
that in our world and day-to-day work
we are doing the trim down blind sign
the downwork
of a whole we might not even oversee
even more and in many cases we don't
even realize this
but we should because in the i.t work
the renaissance was only 30 years ago
so why do i believe that it is an
art to be a cso because they
have to see the big picture understand
the engine room
understand the fly deck and the
environment
the playing field as well speak their
respective languages and have the
ability to relay between these layers
however security is
not even one-man show we are in this
both together
we are all responsible for the security
of tomorrow
the developer cannot say that i code
this because i always did that
in this way or because they didn't
specify
any security requirements why should i
care everyone should work together
do their part because a series of small
acts
from different divisions and laws can
produce
a great deal and enhance security
overall
so it is not just the ceso who
has to do the art it is us
everyone who is listening to this
recording uh everyone who is
within this industry it is our shared
responsibility towards
ourselves and towards each other as well
like in the way we are responsible for
children
we are responsible for those one million
new children
those individuals who go online for
their first time
every day it is our responsibility to
develop
applications in a safe way secure by
design
and not just because of the regulatory
expectation
but because we understand that it is
in our best own interest as well
so if we'd like to see a better nicer
picture of security of tomorrow
we everyone who is listening to this
presentation
have the power we have the brushes in
our hands so let's start painting it
today
thank you very much