hello everyone
thanks for the introduction yes my name
is Alexander papov and I will tell you
how I met fuchsia operating system
I'm a Linux kernel developer since 2013
and I'm security research at positive
Technologies I gave talks at many
security and developer conferences and
I'm really happy to be here at nalcon
and share the results of my research
with you okay
the plan of the talk first I will give
the overview what is future operating
system and about it I will tell about
its security architecture
I will show how to build this operating
system and I will tell about the Zircon
micro kernel
which is a part of fuchsia
and then I will describe my exploit
development experiments
for that silicon micro kernel and show
the exploit demo
big plans so let's go
fuchsia it is a general purpose open
source operating system it was created
in Google approximately six uh years ago
and it is mainly developed for iot
smartphones PCS so the ecosystem of
connected devices
and in December 2020 Google decided to
open Future for contributors not only
from Google
and later they officially released
fuchsia as a operating system of their
nest Hub device which is the device
which controls Smart Home
and this operating system is under
active development and securities one of
the goals of future Developers
and
it is based on the micro kernel it is
called silicon it is written in C plus
and compared to the Linux kernel which
is a monolithic kernel cerecon
implements less services
it implements inter-process
communication memory management
scheduler and Process Management and
other things like networking file
systems device drivers are moved to the
user space
um
and I see several aspects in future
security architecture which make the
system an interesting Target for the
security research and I want to tell
about them first of all what's
interesting fuchsia doesn't have the
concept of a user
instead it is a capability based system
so the kernel resources are given to the
applications
which have the corresponding
capabilities and the main idea is to
have
to have list capabilities for each
application to do the job
that is important for the security
architecture because the concept of
local privilege escalation which we have
for the Linux kernel doesn't work for
future because there is no root user and
like in Linux kernel we can execute the
code AS unprivileged user exploit the
vulnerability in the kernel and
become root here in future it doesn't
work and we need to find some other
approach
second interesting aspect I only already
mentioned it fuchsia is based on the
micro kernel and it has
a smaller kernel attack surface compared
to monolithic kernels
at the same time fuchsia developers
don't have a goal to make it the
Terracon really minimal so this micro
kernel has over 170 system calls quite a
lot compared to other typical micro
kernels
so it is a complex Target
the third thing is that fuchsia provides
very rich sandboxing mechanisms for the
applications applications in the future
are called components and each component
run in uh
separate sandbox
and there is even no Global file system
in future so every application works in
a local namespace and all inter-process
communication between the applications
must be explicitly declared so obviously
this design decision makes user space
security better and isolate
components or applications from each
other at the same time I think uh this
design decision makes silicon micro
kernel very attractive gold Target for
the attacker
the last very interesting aspect is that
fusch has very unusual scheme of
software delivering
um their components in the system are
identified by URLs and when you want to
execute some application of the system
you specify this URL and the software is
downloaded to the system on demand so
the idea here is to make software
packages always up to date when you
start them just like the web pages when
you open it you see the current contents
the same ID is here
and all this for uh
architecture decisions make fuchsia very
interesting research Target
at least for me
some some words how to build it
it is very easy fuchsia has a very good
step-by-step tutorial
how to build it and it works very well
and you even don't need a special
Hardware to run fuchsia
you can start it in the emulator which
is a fork of Android emulator
and I also want to mention that future
supports only two architectures x8664
and arm 64. so
um
you can try it on these two
architectures
creating a component is a toy component
for the system is quite easy as well
there is a command which creates a
template
for for the application and here my toy
application wants to print hello to the
system log
and to to run it I need to specify the
Manifest that
this application wants to bring print
something to system logs that's why I
specified
logging in the Manifest of the
application
so all the capabilities of the
applications must be explicitly declared
and building fuchsia with a new
component to build it uh just we just
need to add a parameter to the build
command but running it uh
on the system is a bit more complex it
needs four steps and I will show it on
this screenshot
in the first terminal we need to start
the emulator it is terminal number one
this one in the second terminal we need
to start the
so-called package publishing server it
is the software which will provide
future
um their software packages in the third
terminal I opened the system logs and in
the fourth terminal I asked fuchsia
please run my application with this URL
and and then I got the
uh hello in the third terminal so
because of this uh
software delivery scheme it is it looks
quite complex
it has four connected devices
now about the micro kernel Circle micro
kernel as I said is written in C plus it
is a part of fusion source code and to
develop this micro kernel you need to
run this system in the qm KVM
debugging it very similar to the
experience of debugging the Linux kernel
and you start koyamo
with a single virtual CPU for better
debugging experience
and
to do single stepping I usually disable
KVM hardware virtualization otherwise on
every single step your debugger always
gets into interrupt timer interrupt
Handler so that's why if I need single
stepping I I use this trick and just
attach the GDP client to the GDB server
and it looks like that very similar to
the Linux kernel debugging in the first
terminal we have the qmo running with
fusion and in the second terminal we
have GDP client connected to the GDB
server in qmo
and uh for every successful security
search of C plus plus code we need some
detector
which reveals the memory corruption box
and for C and C plus plus
for the operating system kernels the
research detector it is kassan Kernel
address sanitizer it can detect out of
bounds accesses use after three memory
Corruptions in the runtime
and the future supports uh building
silicon with with cassan you just need a
extra argument for the build command
and I wanted to test it to test kernel
address sanitizer I added a synthetic
silicon bug in the code which implements
the kernel timers
here
if I set if the the timer is set to the
deadline which ending with the Elite
numbers
but then when timer fire
and then line is met in timer fire the
memory of the object is is the freed
regardless of the
reference counter so it is a bug
and I wanted to hit this bug in my toy
application to see how the memory
corruption is detected to do that I
simply created a timer set it to the
deadline ending for the magic numbers
and waited when the timer is fired and
then when I called ZX timer cancel
uh the micro kernel
they referenced the freed memory so it
is use after free bug and the kernel
address sanitizer detected that
Zircon kernel got panic and I saw such a
beautiful report in the kernel log so
nice at this point I understood that I
have everything for successful
vulnerability of successful security
research on this system
and I had a goal to develop a proof of
concept exploit for some
circum bug
and the simplest way to find such a bug
in the in the kernel operating system
kernel is fuzzing and there is a great
kernel father
which is coverage guided it is called
ciscollar I like this project and people
who develop it very much I use this
color for Linux kernel for many years
and I decided and ciscollar
documentation says that it supports
fuzzing future so I built a circle with
kernel address sanitizer and decided to
fuzz it
but unfortunately I got troubles uh
caused by this unusual software delivery
scheme on on fuchsia actually for
fuzzing future image must have the sys
executor binary it is it should be a
part of fuzzing virtual machine and it
actually executes the advising input on
the virtual machine but I failed to
build fuchsia with this component uh
then I
later I
found out that
fuchsia was integrated with the spoiler
once a point in time in 2020 but it was
then broken and forgotten and so on I
put some effort to reintegrate them
um but I felt
without any success and I found the
context of the developers who
contributed to this functionality I
wrote them email describing technical
details so the bug but didn't get any
reply spending more time on future build
system was
upsetting me
and at this point I understood that I
need to decide on further research
strategy it was a hard moment
without fuzzing successfully
vulnerability Discovery in operating
system kernel requires first good
knowledge of the code base second deep
understanding of the attack surface
obviously I didn't have that for future
because it was my first experience with
this system and did I want to spend a
lot of time to learn it for this first
research
perhaps not
first because committing large resources
to First familiarity with the system is
not really reasonable and second fuchsia
appeared to be less production ready
than I expected
so I was just like this night standing
in front of the stone where various
different bed options are listed the
thinking what what to choose
and I decided not to be greedy and
postpone the zero day Discovery for
silicon and try to
exploit this the synthetic back which I
created to test kernel address sanitizer
and ultimately it was a very good
decision because first it gave me quite
quick results and second I found other
interesting bugs in Zircon along the way
so now I will tell how I exploited this
synthetic buck and what happened next
the exploit strategy for exploiting this
user to free on timer dispatcher was
quite simple first I needed hip spraying
primitive to override the 3D object with
their controlled data then I needed to
choose the data for this object to make
circontimer code work abnormally in
other words I needed to turn the micro
kernel into weird machine which in
parallel executes the normal instruction
in the code and in parallel executes the
actions which attackers controls
it is called this concept is called
weird machine I like it very much so
from
using this weird machine I needed to get
control over future over the future OS
and the first
part was keep spraying what is it
um hip spraying is such activity in the
user space which made the kernel which
is available for unprivileged
applications which make the kernel
allocate a new object at the place of
the freed object and this new object
should contain the Control Data
moreover this data should come from the
user space
and when the freed object with new data
is used
the kernel
turns into this word weird machine
and from Mike's exploit development
experiments from the Linux kernel on you
that usually Linux kernel hip sprain is
based on the inter-process communication
why first of all basic IPC for Linux are
available for unprivileged programs nice
second some inter-process Communication
in Linux allow setting the data size for
a transfer and that gives the actual
control over the allocator behavior I
can put the new object at the place of
the 3D object
moreover IPC usually transfer diet data
so it is good because the Control Data
from the attackers user space
go to the freed object
that was the reasons why I started to
learn future IPC to find the hip
spraying exploit primitive
and I found that I found a silicon V4
it is created with zetix before create
system call and if I create
several FIFA dispatchers as I needed
with the needed size one of them
overwrites my free time and dispatcher
object
that is very good I I got the ability to
change the timer dispatcher contents
with the control data but which data
should I use to to mount a further
attack
to understand that I started to learn
the C plus plus object Anatomy I needed
to understand how time it dispatcher is
organized inside
and compared to the Linux kernex
experience it was much more complicated
in Linux for their kernel object we have
C structures and if the object has some
method it is a function pointer in a c
structure very simple and explicit but
for C plus plus object their internal
anatomy is much more complex I tried
different tools to understand how this
complex timer dispatcher is organized
inside but I failed and I just said I
don't care I decided not to care about
it and I tried this
I would call Minesweeper approach blind
blind practice instead I feel the timer
dispatcher with zero bytes
and started to crash and crush and crush
the Silicon micro kernel with my proof
of concept exploit and uh with a
debugger I started to find
which bytes in the hip spring I need to
to set to proceed in the micro kernel
and execution and avoid crashes at and
at some point I got a very promising
circum crash uh they're congression in
this C plus plus
dark magic
here
there is the get type public method
which is called for the timer dispatcher
object and this public method is
referenced with the c plus v table
the pointer to this virtual table
is stored at the beginning of the object
and I got the new uh null pointer the
reference when this V table was used by
the micro kernel and I thought that it
is excellent for control flow hijacking
so very good kernel crash very promising
but for control flow hijacking in the
operating system kernel I need to know
the addresses of Kernel symbols but we
have the kernel address layouts uh
kernel address basically out
randomization kslr
it is the security feature
which makes the kernel
be located at the random offset in the
virtual memory on every boot so on every
single boot I initially don't know where
the kernel symbols are like are located
and I needed to bypass that somehow I
needed to know this Chrysler offset
secret value
and I decided to try the trick which I
used for one of my proof of concept
displays for the Linux kernel
I tried uh in in that uh
in that research I used the kernel log
to extract the information
which can reveal the castle offset and a
fuchsia kernel look also has security
sensitive information as well and I
decided to do this trick same trick but
for future
this time
and I decided to try to open the kernel
log from my exploit application in
future for that I specify this string in
the Manifest created a channel connected
to a special service in future with
special protocol trying to open the
kernel log and I failed because the
access wasn't denied
because obviously my component didn't
have their required capabilities so
that's how fuchsia
um
capabilities really work so that was
correct behavior in a way
but I certainly found the system call
which allows to get access to the kernel
log
and it has their parameter the argument
the resource and to open the kernel look
I needed a zetix resource kind root
special resource which my application
didn't have
but
just to try my luck I call this system
call with zeroid resource and somehow I
managed to get the kernel look but why I
started to look at the circuit and it
was a hilarious Security check in this
code just look we call validate resource
only if the resource is not invalided so
not new not now it is like at the
passport control you you come and
policeman says okay give me your
password for the check and you say I
don't have a password and the policeman
replies okay just pass it is fine so
this code works like that
I
feel the security issue to Future bug
tracker
and the developers approved that it is a
security issue the the this code is uh
is buggy and they assigned
their cve for this issue but anyway
um reading the kernel log for fuchsia
was not a problem anymore and in my book
exploit I extracted some kernel pointers
from the kernel log and then I realized
they somehow they are the same on the
each boot turned out that kslr is
mentioned in the kernel code but doesn't
work
uh for future and that was another
security issue which I filled in future
bug tracker and the developers said okay
we know this issue it is fine it's not
ready yet
um anyway I knew at this point the that
I can in my
exploit for control for hijack I can use
the point original pointers from the
binary
foreign
to look how the table is organized
inside how it works that that is what
the debugger shows for the timer
dispatcher virtual table
you can see here some values which
definitely not kernel pointers
and to understand how the kernel use it
uses such values I started to look at
the code which it uses but
I didn't I didn't manage to understand
anything from the C plus plus dark magic
so I just opened the assembly and it was
much more much more simple and plain
here
we can see that
this value from the V table is sine
extended from 3 30 T to bit source to
64-bit destination and then add it to
the address of the V table so it is some
kind of upset
when they are added their
um the
register
starts to have the pointer of this type
get type public method of the timer
dispatcher so in my exploit I needed to
reverse this logic to to make kernel
execute my
function which I want
and then at this point I started to
think where to put this fake V table
there the most simple answer is to put
it in my user space address space of the
exploit but Zircon on x8664 supports SM
AP which is supervisor mode access
prevention it is a hardware feature
which
protects from the referencing the user
space pointer from the kernel space so
placing the fake table in the user face
was not possible with this feature for
the Linux kernel I usually bypass smap
by placing the payload in the kernel
space at some known address where my
user space and contents
a data are placed and I could do the
same for the future or I could use
re-implement the red to deer attack
because fuchsia like the Linus kernel
has so-called Fizz map mapping
but for this first time I decided okay
it is too complex for the first research
I I just disabled SM AP and smep in
cuermo and uh for this experiment I
placed the fake V table in the user
space
and implemented this logic which I
showed you in the kernel
here for the table
um
value I subtracted the evitable pointer
from the function pointer address of the
function which I want to call the kernel
to call it is my phone function from the
exploit so I subtracted the V table
pointer and when the kernel
implements the V table handle logic it
it adds the V table pointer to this
value and then calls my Pawn function
just like I want for control for a
hijack
nice so at this point I achieved the
ability to uh to do code execution in
the micro kernel but what what should I
do to get
um the control over the system
um my first thought uh was to create
this fake resource which I already
mentioned special uh superpower Source
but
um actually sircon doesn't use it
that much in the source code so I didn't
manage to do anything uh useful with
this resource and I understood the very
important point
about the micro Kernel Security that to
prev to to make privilege escalation you
in the micro kernel you need to attack
the inter-process communication
because there is no some
super user
entity in the micro kernel
in future
so I returned to learning about future
user space and it was
messing boring I'm a kernel developer
but suddenly I got the idea and what
about planting a root kit into the micro
kernel it's much more interesting than
the user space
I start to learn how ciscals are
implemented in future
and like uh in the Linux kernel Circle
has the assist call table
it is the
the part of the memory which stores the
function pointers
to the Cisco handlers and there is a
x8660x xc66 call function which jumps to
the to the Handler corresponding to the
Cisco number so very similar uh to the
Linux kernels is called implementation
and I tried to overwrite this Cisco
table
with a very old school classics
trick so I reset the right protect beat
from the cr0 register which allowed me
to write any memory in the system and I
over written The Cisco table in it
worked
so uh
I had everything for planting a rootkit
in the micro kernel and I started to
think how to implement the rootkit hook
um usually in Linux kernel root kits it
is not a problem
because the Linux kernel rootkit is
usually a kernel module so you can just
use the function in this kernel module
as a hook
and it is simple but here for fuchsia I
was planting rootkit from the user space
and I was not able to use the user space
functions at as hooks
for my rootkit
and I got the idea to turn a part of
silicon code in into the hook
and my first candidate for overwriting
was this function assert fail message
these functions drove me nuts during the
exploit development because so many um
assertions are around in in Silicon
micro kernel and I was very happy to
override this function
um
first I I want to tell about the hook I
wanted to Simply print a message into
the kernel look so in my hook which
works instead of the system should work
instead of the system call First you can
see in blue I
save the registers push it onto the
kernel stack then I prepare the
silicon printf call
it
and here you can see that I prepared the
string which I want to print and put it
just after the my hook code plus one
byte remember this one byte I will tell
you
why it is here very soon then I uh
restore the state of the register and
call the original system call I wanted
to
hook the process create system call very
interesting Cisco in the future
and that is how I planted the rootkit
um
you remember about this one byte it is
how I disabled the assertions in Fusion
I first of all wrote C3 value at the
first byte of this function this C3
means return so any further assertion in
Zircon just returns immediately
after this red instruction I copied the
code of my hook which I just showed you
and then after the hook I copied the
message which I wanted to print to the
kernel log
rootkit hook this call number 102 roses
Creed so on every call to process create
fuchsia will print this message to the
kernel log
and finally to plant the rootkit I
overrode the item number
102 in the Cisco table
and this item should point to our
overwritten function plus one byte so at
the beginning of my hook code
and now I will show the exploit demo how
it worked
okay
here you can see that I started the log
listener which will show that I executed
the exploit the exploit is executed and
rootkit is planted
yeah now in fuchsia uh I oh sorry
yeah I said
yeah
um
now after after the rootkit worked I
said I I call the youname command
which will show that it is the Silicon
kernel and this you name triggered my
hooks of the rootkit now I will show
that in the log
oh
strange sorry
yeah grab for rootkit and we see that
the you name command
provoked two rootkit hooks and
it worked
now the conclusion
that is how I met the future operating
system and its silicon micro kernel that
was very interesting because
I'm a Linux kernel hacker and this micro
kernel was very new experiments
experience for me and I wanted to try my
kernel hacking skills against this
system for a long time I'm glad that I
had this opportunity
and uh I followed the responsible
disclosure process for the Discover
security issues and
I believe it is one of the first public
researchers on future operating system
security and I think it is valuable
because this work shows some practical
aspects of micro kernel vulnerability
exploitation and defense and I really
hope that this will inspire you
to do some kernel hacking and of course
I wish you a good conference and
friendly conversations
uh any questions
could you use a mic
um the question is about the GDP for
future so uh GDB client is ATT attached
to the GDB server which is provided by
qamo yeah yeah so you don't need ADP
over there no I I need I don't need
anything in the kernel uh silicon kernel
to have it debugged yes it is provided
just by kuemo and nothing is needed in
the Silicon micro kernel
so uh uh had you tried putting uh
calling uh your fake V table from how do
you speak in the mic thank you so have
you thought of calling your fake wheat
table uh from ctar or detour function
uh sorry could you repeat this so did
you try calling the your fake V table
that you wanted to invoke from sitar or
detour
uh you mean from the debugger or no from
the ctar or detour function so whenever
the function is being allocated you have
setar just to lay the space for the
function or detour which cleans up it's
like allocator and
a Destructor just in that uh sorry I
didn't get the question really but I
will repeat about the table trick so the
visual table is at the beginning of the
uh at the time is a special object and I
overwrote the object and I created a
fake table for that and this table was
placed in the user space so I had the
object with a pointer to the user space
and uh this in this paper table I
created the address to my user space
function which I want the kernel to call
my shell code so the table fake the idea
of fake retailable was to make the
kernel to call my shell code from the
user space yes
um
sorry I
um can't comment on that
maybe we will check it later yeah
anyone from this room
while you are thinking about the
questions I will show you bonus slides
what happened next I have a couple of
minutes for that yep uh so in May this
year I published the article
and uh sometime after that future
security engineering manager from Google
approached me and asked for a call with
Google and it was a very interesting
conversation with them they thanked for
This research and I asked a lot of
questions about future security
architecture and what I really liked
um the future security engineering
manager told that he would attack Zircon
the same way as I did but at the last
step he would attack the capability
transfer or try to achieve the
persistence across reboots so changing
the kernel image and save
the attack activity after the reboot
rebooting the system
it was funny they made the call
recording but later they refused to
share it with me I don't know why
strange
um
then later in August future developers
contacted me and said that this is color
integration that was previously broken
is fixed so now you can search for
vulnerabilities in the future moreover
later several days ago Google Google
announced an open source software
vulnerability rewards program
so they play they pay Bounty for their
vulnerabilities discovered in the open
source and reported and future operating
system is in scope
so now it is even more interesting
Target for the research
yeah maybe maybe questions
okay thank you very much and uh again
wish you a great conference thank you