day today thank you for coming
and in this talk let me unlock the
laptop shirt
looks good
let spend with stock on a user space we
already got
the from yesterday Yvonne stock for
example house away from the ufi to the
driver to the user space could be built
in this talk we would talk about user
space because to my experience mostly
last stages also main payload
and even I was there all preliment tasks
are about anti-detection persistence
whatever so
I'm genius I'm with Kaspersky
specialized on a tread hunting rival
sink and
in this year uh I decided to propose the
topic on a new place
to hide file the malware as you
understand file is suggest you remember
NTFS alternate data stream right BMI
subscriptions of Windows system register
based persistent
so it's exists on the level of a file
system anyway so it's not the files but
it's not as plain as a file so security
solution is not that easy to obtain this
data let us take a look on the new way
to hide the encrypted shell codes on a
system uh 40 minutes it's quite amount
of time let's add plan it a bit but this
plants on Goa seems to with oh
Summer is gone already so our plans
would be a little bit different maybe
more boring not a cycle on the beaches
so I actually am
as a threat Hunters we are mostly
observed in a real campaigns so this
technique it's not a proof of concept
from the researcher it's in the wild uh
technique led me first in the uh
beginning of the talk let me present
with our new which I consider most
Innovative part and after it slowly move
to the our parts to this campaign all
other auxiliary techniques like a usage
of the third party code commercial and
non-commercial and ways how they patched
the real event or logging on the Windows
paging MCI mechanism usage a little more
esoteric compilers to protect the
malware from the Security Solutions and
so on
and to start from the how they hide
shell codes into the windows event logs
let us first cover the more typical
usage of logging and shell codes in the
malicious campaign
who is analyzing a malware on a daily
basis in your job
aha I see so sum in I suppose in this
case you also write a familiar for you
using of the logic right in some
malicious samples
the researcher could obtain some hints
from the logic
at the first glance we could think why
why from the malicious alter to help us
with some messages like this model is
already done it job it's a shell coat is
in place it etc etc so it has a two
theory about it it's a Muslim because
imagine you debug your date in some
virtual environment and after it you
have to place in a combat mode right
many things could go wrong so malicious
developers are still the developers they
need to understand which stages of the
attack went well and at which stage it
was something went wrong I suppose
that's why some logging exist I also
remember the malware samples where we
slogan mechanism was in the future
version was wiped so they all make it
the version which is stable not need to
debug in the combat environment anymore
and login message is done also I support
some of them with just laser remove the
logs later in the to-do list and it
leaves for years but it's really
interesting to observe how obvious logic
mechanism is an are working out so uh
it's a more common usage of the logging
like in any malware what about the shell
codes actually shell codes is also you
could observe in your malicious samples
where mostly
so the guys who are into also malware
researchers via
and in fact the documents right they
could be placed so any place where some
small amount of code has to be executed
to initiate the following phases of the
attack
whatever small place in the memory some
document some vulnerability in a
complicated format like a PDF RTF
whatever
and what is special about the shell
codes they couldn't use all the
precious help from the PE or L file
orders right they are on their own they
have to implement some techniques which
could it make the code position
independent and that's why we observe
all this stuff which you could see on
the code snippet like a call next
instruction and pop in the address from
the stack to understand the precise
location in memory like a parsing of
process environment block to get the
real address of the API functions which
shell codes need to execute further and
also a lot a lot of practicing
executable formats like PE and windows
to get the next Stager
or to put it into the memory and execute
it further so actually just a small
Snippets of code are auxiliary mostly As
downloaders as the injectors for the
following stages now we are covering
typical usage of logging and and the sum
showcots right but but here you could
tell me so far not new for us what is
new here
I like actually this engineering
decision
why not to combine
these two tasks why not to use some kind
of event logs to keep encrypted shell
cord for the next stage actually yes
under Windows what main logging
mechanism we have
Windows 7 locks right so you could run
MMC you could take a look at the all
information or critical error slogs over
the windows event logs on a level of
file systems where could you find it
in a bunch of the uh evtx files right so
once again we saw I always place the
file list in a some kind of brackets
because it's exist on the file system
but it's some very proprietary very
unclear format and no security solution
most probably would parse it
that's why some engineer from the
Malaysia site wanted to put binary data
over there but typically so far we
describing logs like text messages right
this model executed this stage is okay
this stage failed it's mostly text but
in case of working with the windows
event logs actually completely legit you
could put binary data over there it's
not a problem at all imagine you
developer somewhere for example simple
driver
you'll get some your device writing and
driver and you expect some messages from
your users and you want to understand
your support server understand what's
going wrong besides the messages in
event logs maybe you would need some
mini dumps binary mini dumps and
operating system provide you such an
ability you could put binary data as a
part of your login message just to
understand what happened while your
program is executing why not to use in a
malware software looks like a place if
we could save binary this binary could
be executable right nobody could stop us
to put over there some Intel comments so
why not
okay but so far I just described it in
the world
let us take a look at the code so we are
coming at this stage at the real
campaign as I promised and here goes the
model which gathers gathers the code
from the windows event logs so what's up
let's take a look what happens here so
if the sound you tell me when I have to
bring it
here or there
what is better over there cool because I
remember from the sitting here I want to
hear it maybe a little bit louder so
allocation of 500 kilobytes right after
it in the new buffer
into the 500 kilobytes we would be
gathering what
the malware registers the event data
source event data source is a key
management system who remember key
management system who is a Windows user
is licensing mechanism right if you
licensing your Microsoft Office your
operating system KMS is the way how you
let the your laptop for example know its
alleged version of the windows legit
version of the Microsoft Office EMS
exists one more completely legit data
source for the logic what's next what's
next I see reading the event logs
reading one after another sequential I
put some comments over there sequential
read so and forward read from the very
old one to the news sequentially all the
log messages related to the KMS right
and some auxiliary tasks if some error
handling is over there and also some
real location if 500 kilobytes is not
enough for all the data getting from the
logs memory would be relocated
okay what you could ask me whom then is
you told us KMS is legit here we are
reading all the messages from the KMS uh
why it couldn't be the shell cut right
it would be the normal messages from the
lodging system let's go further let's go
further here goes some
they Implement some filtering watches
there once again we're taking a look at
the code in the decompiler which I
already analyzed and marked for you all
the fields of the corresponding
structure filtering by event category
right
so all the events has the following
attributes from which event Source they
came which event category
or they use and which event ID they use
event category in this case have to be
in hexed for one for True on the slide
you would see in ASCII format it's a a b
and they knows for sure Legend KMS data
source wouldn't provide any lock records
with such a category ID for one for two
it's a custom for them they actually in
the next version of the malware could
easily change it the only
needed property from this constant is
the alleged data source Event Source
would not use it never for one for two a
b would be all these messages would be
related only to the malware after it
they use some C plus plus container with
time a simplest one is the string and
appending all the messages with such a
category ID to one string just for the
further take the data from the string
and execute it
okay so already two slides with the code
but all of these related for the reading
right so reading messages from eventlock
putting into container
what actually who put it over there for
sure not KMS not Windows right they need
some dropper and here
on this slide I put on your right you
see the familiar code snippet related to
the reading these messages
and on the left it's a separate model
it's actually The Dropper and dropper
put it over there
so let's enumerate all the windows API
functions we need to fulfill this task
legit Windows API so nothing wrong with
the function you remember register Event
Source let us keep W suffix it's just
let us know it's a white all the
arguments is Unicode string register
Event Source and read event log from
which we would read and
some function to actually read it but on
a dropper we need report event
and some new argument important for us
important as a ioc or the incident
response in case of this malware
appeared in the argument of report event
take a look we already know for one for
two it's a category ID right filtering
on which seems like on this clicker I
don't have the red point so I would go
over there
category ID write the same as on our
previous slide for the reading but as
well we also get
event ID
and the various start location of event
ID they know precisely to which category
and which incremental value they assign
to the Mali search malicious event log
one more argument I want to emphasize
here it's a type of this record in your
event Windows Event lock mechanism it
would be just an information record so
you would open MMC you would hope the
corresponding snippet take a look with
all the records you would see it's a KMS
information type and all the data over
there but by default during my
experiment I would see the normal MMC
interface wouldn't show you the binary
addition to these logs so actually all
these binary data always encrypted Shell
Code to read it you need to some other
intro instrument or need to write your
own some tool to read the binary part of
the data okay dropper we are covering
what else we need so watches actually
inside we have a dropper to put data
over there we have launcher to get the
data from the event data source but what
it would execute it actually inside the
after the decryption nothing
special as if you analyzed Sometimes
some shortcuts it could be a quite a
familiar picture for you it's actually
the running next station the one thing I
want to emphasize here
even through this conference you already
seen this typical Hessian algorithm from
the Metasploit raw 13 so for they
wouldn't keep the name of the functions
would keep only the hash codes and get
the name gets the address of the
functions using the Shell codes but take
a look after the uh parsing the export
table of the files or the
founding function it would be the name
of the function would be load by the way
here we would need to implement some
brute forcing because the hash was not
typical it's not the typical name for
the windows API right it's a custom name
from the next station it names lower add
is a capital l
or but with a dictionary you could brute
force and get the right Shell Code for
it uh the start of the hour load
function gets to argument it's a very
last line over there I actually don't
know why because now I got them we got
the next stage and arguments was not
really in use but they keep the ask a
string with I ask a string Dave and use
it as an argument for our Lord function
don't know why maybe in some other uh
next stage it would be really in use but
in the samples we observe this Dave's
string just as skipped oops some I like
natural language artifacts in this case
it was Dave and the constant 4.
or maybe the length of the first ASCII
string they will just use form ASCII
charts this is it when you decrypt the
Shell Code from the event data source
KMS you would get some launcher of the
next station
okay
I think enough from this part of the
attack
I consider once again I started from it
because I considered the most Innovative
part but many other models exist so I
promise you the broad view of all of the
campaign let us take a look at all the
campaign of the actor who Implement such
a brand new techniques what we have are
there actually a non-typical thing was
the usage of a simultaneously of two
commercial tool sets I could say for
sure familiar to you Cobalt strike was
in use oh it's just visible it was a
Cobalt strike models but I also expect
another second commercial to set was a
silent break uh don't mind the name was
I'm not sure it's uh nowadays it's a
proper name it was a company bought by
another company whatever but why I use
it on a GitHub or the repository still
got that name and in this repository we
still have the very old version of the
model named throwback throwback and we
see this
throwback.dll always usage over
encryption same encryption algorithm in
the models during this campaign so I'm
quite sure here looking on some Court
to the guys who gets access to the same
Source called Data that's why I could
think about the silence break another
tool the commercial tool of the company
it's a called
no slingshot and also we observe
original names of the libraries like a
slingshot dll and as well monolith dll
so this commercial tool set somewhere
around okay it's a commercial tool set
choose a
pull some Security Solutions they decide
to use some more isotmoresoteric
compilers than COC plus plus they use
Nim and go and we have to uh to
understand next models we have to fight
with droppers in such a newer languages
okay we successfully did it also some
library was compiled within the
environment in the environment with a
GCC compiler so you see a Microsoft C
compiler GCC and windows neem Gore quite
a number of compiles they trying to use
but I consider just an anti-detection
measures or nothing more actually I will
show you the code an interesting part is
the last stages they actually use two
different Origins and I promise it to
give you the ideas why if you have such
a remote Administration tool seems like
one is enough right for them they use
one for the local area real Network in a
passive mode I suppose it was a fossil
lateral movement
so to make a foothold inside the Lamb of
the victim they use based on the name of
the pipes version of the children and
HTTP version could go to the external C2
and it's a normal Trojan to communicate
with a real control server and the
common set is a completely different
okay these are the stages and let's
describe it one by one
uh besides the commercial tool set they
also that's not the first time the money
factors just grab the publicly available
GitHub repository in this case black
Bond and black bone we observed before
using the campaign when the driver want
to inject some code into the legit
system process collect Bond could be
used once again you could easily adjust
the git clone check the code at some
part of the code needed for the campaign
compiled it and try to deploy it on on
The Targets in this case a black bone
was also the case you see two commercial
tool sets was seems like not enough so
it's like integration process of the
different tool sets and later on in to
my experience I observe more and more
usage of some code Snippets from the
GitHub because why not why not it's so
they could avoid attribution right they
could uh fulfill the task with the
already made code not invest in a coding
so maybe not so bad idea for the money
factors okay why I think Blackburn was
in use for sure it's not the strings
take a look the world who made a black
bomb in the wild
maybe I'm quite a familiar stuff to you
one of the technique was a dll side
loading as usual they take the legit
file their fault dot dll or dot exam
therefore gxz and the windows is
it's a error handling right so error
handling of the part of the operating
system they copy to separate directory
actually with the schedule task
directory and put dll with a very
specific name so so just a very familiar
search of them hijacking and they don't
want to the word fault.exe continue its
execution after the mapping as
malicious the allele into memory they
need to page the entry point of the
ledgered XD file this is it so very
typical Blackboard approach just put
move rocks jump racks and their own or
some own function in this case I name it
wait and exit wait for the thread from
the dll and gracefully exit the XZ
process main process were fought with a
success code
okay that's why I consider Blackburn
over there not the only sign but one of
the signs just the patching of entry
point of Ledger exim
regarding Unity detection
regarding country detection besides the
already mentioned several approach it's
uh several compilers white listed
launcher I didn't mention so far digital
certificate uh typically such an extra
actors try to steal digital certificate
from some vendor and signed up for files
of the campaign it was in this case but
I'm not sure certificate was stored when
I tried to obtain legitimate normal
files with the same digital certificate
I actually failed maybe just our
visibility maybe not it seems like with
this digital certificate only malicious
files were signed
so I suppose maybe it was obtained it
was bought only for the campaign maybe
not skilled from some Ledger software
company
private on the next slide in the details
seems like the actor last you see they
adore event locks they use it a lot but
shall code there but they lost only
their own event logging they don't want
to be locked by the operating system
mechanism that's why several functions
from the normal mechanism of logging of
operating system they would pitch they
would pitch on the level of the ntdl dll
the lowest level on use of space they
could obtain so no kernel component in
this time and they would just take in
the memory of their process and tdll
address of these functions and page as
usual with some adjust MTM returns zero
so all good returning no locks appeared
in your event locks viewer
and also let me emphasize the very last
part regarding the C2 name seems like
those guys did their homework well
they make initial Recon understand which
are actually GOP system was on board in
this corporate environment understands
the name and registers the web domain
this is a very similar name of its legit
system in the environment so the traffic
which some I don't know blue teamers
could observe in their precious
Wireshark would be to some domain which
name is completely related to the DLP
and they could think maybe maybe not or
it just alleged traffic which our
information system generate not a
malware also a interesting idea I
suppose okay
I propose Also regarding them are paging
uh actually also what I want to
emphasize here it's a MCI patching on
the slides you would see a patching of
the function relating to the logs
etw prefix and but MCI fetching as far
as I know nowadays it even exists in a
Metasploit framework so I would consider
it as a already a common techniques for
the money factors and wouldn't stop as
in details as I provide details
regarding them binary part of the event
logs or not the first time I met paging
of MCI are functions
so
um regarding Goa who already revokings
role models
did you like it
me nicer me nicer I said Yvonne also
loves I know the color everything but uh
this time or all what gorm is doing
besides the paging it's just the decrypt
next station
what I need to obtain here uh I need to
obtain all this quite quite a painful
task all this part of the uh code it was
a thousand of them they'll need to write
some script to put it all together
decrypted with the decode visible by 64
as usual decrypted with the IES and get
the next stage nothing more interesting
part on the goal level it's a heavy
usage of the
Cisco's Library actually it was even
back then was a little surprise for me I
familiar with this is called mechanism
Angel Linux right but it's under windows
it's exists it's very version dependent
but this calls also exist and if on
level of go language use this call
library it would be a lot of Cisco's
over there but it's all the codes are
publicly available and you could
understand which women team in ntgl
function is called using this is called
to decide to use this Library so on this
wrapper I need to combine and decrypt
successfully solved and uh you a little
bit details about the patient some one
more Library like the whole Library go
Library I mean this is some lazy
um taking the address
of the API functions and put the empty
functions instead
of the real ones uh in a memory of this
process of the Barefoot dll okay if they
don't want to any event logs besides
their own maybe a normal decision
enough for the esoteric compilers if you
would
get some if you have some question
regarding go or name you would ask
and now I want to spend some time on the
last stage last stages why two of them
and what was interesting inside so I
really love when manufactures on some
level save the version of the malware
for the sun targeted malware I even keep
my own dictionary on now the version
1.7.2 arrive nice nice before I have
only 1.611 let's take a look what's new
in this case in a traffic so generated
in the initial Beacon for one of the
Trojans version exists so also nice to
have it I wouldn't
repeat all or from the our slides just
or some interesting points over there
for me I love the randomization all the
time
this point randomization of the sleep
time to my understanding it also trying
uh make the life of incident responder
harder for example not to correlate the
initial infection data date and first
beaconing date some randomization is a
good idea for the making correlating of
different events harder but with a quite
a strange randomization for example
sleep time they would take from
configuration data and after read
multiply to some random value from 0.9
to 1.1 is it so Random so the difference
would be quite it would be quite similar
values right so the difference is only
about 20 percent so around 20 straight
nothing more but anyway they implemented
and also I laugh in a land version of
Trojan based on named pipes it's a
getting of the how long user is an
active they don't want to be too active
in a time when user is typing something
so maybe operators just check on five or
two hours are negative maybe it's time
to do something on This Server seems
like nobody is watching now the server
time to send some comments over there
all other
I suppose not one more thing maybe here
they adore injection really adore
injection they obsess it not only with
the Windows 7 logs but also to this DLP
process to lsrs process whatever inject
their code they have a separated comment
in a boss Trojans to inject their code
whatever they could use process ID to
inject process name
they really adore this stuff
and some regarding the common system
here it's a common system of short-term
common system from the Trojan but please
keep in mind it looks like they have
some repository like a Constructor and
could combine the media which core of
children would use named pipes or HTTP
and which common system it would use so
they could simultaneously for example
this or in the case of samples we could
observe it was bought to the HTTP Trojan
but we also saw named pipe Trojan with a
similar common system interesting part
here the comments you could see quite
typical for any Trojan I laugh during
the fingerprinting they would get a
machine Grid or maybe when you build
some unique ID for the user not a bad
idea to use machine grid as well and
also
uh let me briefly describe the situ one
more randomization they would keep the
list of control server and in any
communication where they would randomly
choose the C2 from the list
so if C2 is alive they would walk with
this server next time it would be
another a live server from the list nice
nice I suppose
our encryption is a throwback like
already described in the previous slides
common system you see here so next
version
nextration set or one of the original
file name was a monolith dll we saw it
in table so I prefer to call all this
activity monolith because all the other
names I observed here was just the name
of the tool set commercial or not
commercial
and take a look in this case there are
common system far more profound not all
of them is here otherwise it would be
too long at least
and so one more one to emphasize such
HTTP version with the same profound
common system also exists so they could
construct their Trojan as they want
so time seems like we're almost out of
time let me briefly sum up what we get
through this presentation I provide a
new con at least be consider it new and
Innovative technique of keeping
encrypted structural code into the
Windows 7 logs uh we show you the
dropper how to write to the event logs
and how to read so some launcher what
was kept inside the shell codes and all
other modules around it are auxiliary
for the anti-detection models and last
stages which would be active as a result
of all these uh campaign
so I hope you as a researchers would uh
benefit with such a modern type of the
techniques in the car with targeted
malware I really really form any
questions and I really hope it will be
any please fire away questions time
hello
how did they execute the Shell Code
because even if the shell code is
fileless or stored in the event
um
and registry um it's going to get
detected eventually with for example
create remote thread uh at least that's
what I have experienced in Defender
because when you execute that in user
land
uh I think the kernel mode scans the
buffer and the Cobalt stack is detected
basically so I'm wondering why all these
threat actors are using like detected
Shell Code
sorry I was not sure I fully understand
the question sure it was a quite loud
there was there if you for sure I
provide on a slide with the show code it
was not full of it right I just it was a
only part of it to show it's a quite a
familiar techniques for the Shell Code
could you please repeat the main part of
the question so how did they execute the
Shell Code without being got because
Cobalt swag is detected right because
yeah for sure yes it's all the last
stages as a result they have a different
branches of execution some of them
include Cobalt some of them did not the
last stages I suppose we are all the
detected heuristically before but not
all seems to maybe not all the host of
the interest has the security product
installed also we detected it through so
the last stages in memory but to make
all these steps back to the very initial
infection or not of the models were
detected just because some of them do
nothing wrong actually right launcher do
nothing wrong just to launch something
so if I get a question right so I hope I
answered
yeah um you uh if I go understand this
correctly you mean that the last age was
detected but the initial stages were not
detected uh like based on heuristics I
guess you detected that how sorry how we
combine it all together all these
techniques you see we are used using
Telemetry to see if it's all always
connected to each other
foreign
are they using any shell code generators
like donut or something or are they
using custom
shell code generators
sorry once again about the shell code
generators are they using shell code
generators like donut
or um like Shell Code reflective dll
injection like srdi the project
was just the AL auxiliary part which uh
parsed another deliberate data uh to my
intermittal parset my patent to memory
and the ram corresponding function using
the hash of this function in this case
with name a lot with two arguments JF
and four uh I hope sometimes we would
get the next stages for which your
supplements would be meaningful but in
this case it just skipped okay different
length of the day so it's auxiliary
auxiliary as you know to my experience
uh shell codes rarely executes the final
trust right it's could decrypt something
find something inject something it's no
reason to build huge functionality of
light Stager in the form of Shell Code I
supports mostly it would be injected PE
anyway
thank you thanks thanks for the
questions
more questions good good
moral of curiosity you said that they
were digitally signed uh payload so who
was the root sign up like where did they
get this
have to check but it was something
normal like a Commodore some someone
normal which I know the name but I sorry
don't have it in my mind here okay and
the signer did not have information
about the organization that requested
between the Citrus but it was just uh it
was on a slide that supports so some
name I never heard before like I don't
know just security whatever and this is
made sorry my idea here using this
certificate or cereal I wasn't able to
find any legit files so I suppose the
name of the organization is not that
crucial if you Google it yeah nothing ah
it was a fast invest first investment in
this case of this campaign so some fast
invest exist but I'm not sure it's
related because the region is a two
different so luggage of the campaign and
this fast invest I could Google it's not
related at all because of the very
different regions but I suppose the main
part of certificate which you could use
it's not the name of the organization
but the unique serial and using unique
serial I didn't observe any alleged
application actually I suppose they just
bought provide to the certificate
Authority maybe with fake name get the
certificate sign or till the certificate
would be blacklisted I see the technique
like with my understanding of the
technique the part I found interesting
is that for files they got this
certificate for signing but for C2
communication it was still on HTTP not
using TLS with let's say it was about
the files yes it's not about the uh not
about the server not speaking not about
SSL about the file signed by digital I
got that too yeah so anyway thank you
thanks thanks
thank you
actually in several campaigns we
observed something because sometimes at
Legend we just let no the vendor seems
like the secretary gets compromised
please revoke it so it happens
so it seems like such a software
complaints as a Target could be the
Target because as the owners of some
whitelisted certificates
seems like questions are over I'm here
not running anywhere please ping me out
of the stage thanks many thanks
[Applause]