good afternoon everyone uh I know this
session is just after lunch so we'll try
to ask tough questions so that you want
to know the answers for it and I hope
everybody history is awake and just I
hope that people who came know that we
are not going to talk about soccer
which is secretary Operation Center
so yeah uh
I think we have been introduced and uh
just one announcement we will take
questions towards the end because we
have like come up with a flow for asking
questions and we want to take you
through a journey on how the swag has
been 10 years back how it is currently
what are the current challenges and how
it will evolve in the future
so uh the idea is to just make you take
you through the Journey nostalgic and
then what are the challenges and we will
have lost in 15 minutes for the question
so
like let's go with the first question uh
and mostly about because everybody has
their own implementation of Security
operation Center and everybody thinks
that hey my sock is mature but before we
go into that I don't want the nist
definition of sock but what is your
interpretation of Security operation
Center and what it means for everyone
yeah thank you um
well uh sock in any organization is
considered as first line of defense
and obviously there is an expectation
that sock should be able to detect
attacks malicious activities at a very
early stage in the entire attack phase
uh to give you an example stock is
something similar to what you can call
as airport security at all the airports
so if you guys have ever watched on
National Geographic there's a program
that comes on Airport security where the
airport security team watches each and
every passenger who passes through the
customs and their job is only to
identify out of millions of passengers
those three or four passengers who might
be doing uh drug trafficking smuggling
Etc
and that's the thought process which uh
I think uh we can use in the sock so
that we can identify the threats all the
malicious activities early on and uh
make sure that we have and secure
environment in the organization so
that's my definition of stock you want
to add your like you have been a veteran
in stock side so please go ahead yes I
know you mentioned uh we should mention
nistcs if I I'm gonna just use that
definition so for me you know the detect
respond recover aspects is sock and I
totally agree with shweta like you know
we are the first line of defense
um and my example is similar to hers
like you know like airport security I
like uh medieval fantasy movies so you
know they show the old castles and Fort
and two guys standing in front of the
gate letting people in and identifying
people who are not so I think that's
tier one saw but sock is pretty much
I feel like you know it's much much
wider uh like I said you know detect
response yeah I would hold my thought
because when somebody says airport and
security nine level comes into mind like
9 11 was a kind of a moment where
everything changes has there been such a
movement on the circuit operation side
but for later but we will go to Vivek
first yeah sure uh for us right I'm
looking it from a product perspective uh
stock is two false right one is how we
are protecting our infrastructure and
there it is more like how do I collect
all the information from every place how
do I uh consolidate that and how do the
incident response happens on a timely
manner right so that's that's something
that constantly happens and then as a
product that how we provide to a
customer as a managed service where it
happens that we call it the incidents
happening across customers and then see
how how things are evolving what are the
patterns what are they anomalies
evolving and then how do we just respond
faster right this is how we treat shock
coming one from customers perspective
providing a managed solution having a
strong stock team looking at how various
things are working and uh what are the
various incidents happening across
customers and how do you correlate it
and respond quickly right so because
you're reacted we are discussing so any
uh I know everybody loves like a story
right like if you you have to just give
me some incident or some Stellar moment
on the operation side which you recall
or what happened see even I mean just
looking at recent examples right like
what happened uh when uh say the war
started right and Ukraine war has
started and other things incidentally
you started seeing lot of attacks
happening across boat just not Russia
it's both Russians and Ukraine there
were a lot of attacks that was coming in
right so we had to uh look at it and
then improve the response and then
improve the threat levels for requests
coming from these areas so those are the
things that immediately bubbles up if
you have a strong stock system in place
and there's a strong monitoring in place
and ability to handle anomalies at the
scale yeah I I'll just add to what he
said so this is an example of
situational awareness and
when this whole War started I remember
connecting to my uh business partners at
Microsoft Google uh Palo alto's uh I
told them my problem statement is
twofold okay because India is
considering to abstain from uh taking a
decision and Russia is a friend of India
at the same time U.S Europe is also
friends of India so the attacks are
getting launched by Russians onto the
other side as well as from the West to
the Russia so India is kind of more or
less getting sandwiched in both the uh
you know parties so I have a two-fold
problem which I need to address so uh
this is part of situational awareness
which we need to think as part of cyber
defense as a whole information security
as a whole and not just limiting to
stock yeah so yeah it may be a similar
question what is your most aha or
Steeler moment on your the journey so
far like in the Security operation side
so I think I'll just follow the trend
here like and since you're talking about
war
um I got interested in security uh after
I read that about structure like you
know the whole thing so for me that was
a just going through that book
um had multiple aha moments and I
decided you know this is something which
I really want to explore uh so since
I've been working in this industry I
come from a SRE background so for me the
biggest I think uh Revelation was in Sr
you know everything is time like
sensitive you have to get things up back
and running very quickly but uh
incidents on the security side uh are
equally intense
but there's a different version of time
which comes in right like you can
actually sit back and sometimes when you
know what the attacker is trying to do
or you're curious you just wait
sometimes and which is what was very
alien to me when I first got into this
side so I think those things definitely
are you know aha moments for me so I
think definitely stuccinate was a
milestone like
for quite some time the stock sniper I
think definitely a lot of other
incidents in recent solar winds rather
have been also taking the news and the
social Ukraine war the most interesting
thing which I witnessed well it talks
about the preparedness of the Cyber side
lot of people who started targeting
Russian servers the Russians were
responding by saying hey I am a teapot
and that is HTTP 418 error saying that
hey server is like so they were able to
direct such uh attack on their
infrastructure and they were like trying
to mock the people from the other side
so uh that's that's the fun thing which
I learned with this new one
so um so this is about the first
introduction around the security
operations what it means what the
panelists have been through and what is
there there have been their moments and
so coming to the later part where we
want to
like everybody's like hey does your soft
sucks but like what are we going to talk
about in this the theme is like how do
we know that my sock is a mature uh what
are the key things to consider to
evaluate if you are my security
operations center is at which level of
maturity so that is one uh question
which I have which will talk about the
visibility the meter tdp's attack
framework and all that so um Sweta you
want to take a go at it uh yeah sure
so one important thing is uh when you're
building a sock or when you are
sustaining a sock at whatever stage it
may be
visibility is very important and what I
mean by visibility is not just the
network level visibility or endpoint
level visibility the business visibility
is also important okay uh your detection
rules should ensure that you address the
risks that are posed for the business
okay
because end of the day I think many of
the organizations since many years have
started calling cyber security risk as
one of their business risks okay I
remember in my previous organization
five years ago they actually called it
into the annual report saying that these
are the top 10 risks the organization
faces cyber security is one of the key
risks that was identified uh at that
time right so visibility from the
network point of view from the endpoint
point of view from the user point of
view uh location point of view and
business point of view is is very
important many a times what happens is
you integrate a lot of uh infrastructure
you integrate firewalls uh you integrate
Enterprise proxy but then there is some
remote location uh operating some small
business function which nobody has
visibility and that may not be part of
your Enterprise security control
ecosystem just to take an example I have
seen these cases where there isn't
firewall at a particular location it is
a standalone firewall it is not
reporting to a central console for
example if it's a Palo Alto firewall the
central console of Palo Alto call is
called as Panorama so that firewall is
not even visible in the central console
of the firewall right and it's a
standalone how will stock get that
visibility because the tools that are
used in stock is primarily the Sim Tool
uh it doesn't have that capability of
doing a discovery and identifying the
Assets in your organization that's not
how it works so there is some amount of
manual Intervention which can be solved
by having a proper process inter
functional or interdepartmental process
okay especially on the new deployments
that happen the new changes that happen
are
the existing infrastructure whenever it
undergoes a change it is important that
we make sure that the it organization
keeps the security organization and very
specifically the stock informed about
those changes
so I'll just stop at that and see I
would like to know more about like uh
when we say visibility but what about
the auto Discovery like they're like
definitely happens advice and all the
other problems so but yeah uh what's
your view about this Yogi like so I
agree with shweta like mostly with what
she said about visibility
um
this is maturity doesn't come in one day
right like it takes a while to get to a
certain stage so I think every company
is a different stage of maturity how we
Define maturity in stock like we have a
lot of Frameworks which you know give
you a good idea on like micro attack
framework and like you know there's a
you can use scenarios from that
um but one
one area I can I think I've heard some
someone say this so I'm paraphrasing but
the question is not if some company is
going to be breached it's when
like it's it's just a given at this
point right so I think the maturity
which
um I think about ways like how many
levels or layers of protection you can
build in and visibility is definitely
one of the key aspects of that there's a
whole uh plethora of things we can think
of like in our case we have you know we
we focus a lot on process people
technology so when I talk about process
it's about you know run books uh doing
tabletop exercises you know doing all of
that things and people obviously we want
to invest in skills and training and so
it's you know it's the whole gamut of
things like you just have to do it and
the best thing to evaluate how mature
your firm is is to you know either get
someone from like a third party external
uh something like manly into something
to come and you know benchmark you so
that gives you a good sense of sure uh
if you want to add
ah from our perspective right how we
look at maturity is uh and from the
stock perspective right it is about uh
visibility collecting informations then
Consulting it and then the most
important part is about a response right
how quickly are you able to respond
um and nowadays just response is not
enough reporting is also becoming
mandatory so how mature are you on that
front right you have compliance mandates
where you have to report incidents in
very timely manner so how are you
looking at it in a holistic manner right
and which stage of the maturity level
are you in at and from where we see it
in the industry it's more like people
are good at visibility side of things I
mean they are getting the the reporting
side is also getting there but the
response part right that's that's where
I mean the when the challenges still
remain yeah so maybe
um I also want to have an audience uh
poll sort of thing like just a show of
hand so how many of you have seen like
the meter attack framework being
implemented and somebody actually
mapping the ttps and like hey do we have
security controls in place and being
followed in your own organizations
diligently
wow that is a good number what is the
current miter attack version
that is to the audience
11. how many tactics are there
how many seconds we are hiring right now
how many situal
okay one two
14 who's at 14. one okay now everybody's
saying 14 okay so there are 14 because
um from the version nine onwards uh the
pre- attack and the attack uh mattresses
have been merged so that's how you have
14 tactics
um how uh how many techniques
any guess
more than 150 okay
too low
exact number is 222.
so that's version 11.
so
now you cannot have the detections
across all these tactics and techniques
in your stock
uh stock currently in many uh cases is a
reactive function only if it gets the
signals it can build correlation rules
and identify those signals as malicious
right so most of the rules that you
build in stock are static condition
based where you Define a threshold okay
um X number of failures in X minutes
just a simple example right uh and
therefore it is important to understand
that if you say that I have implemented
Maita attack framework it does not
necessarily mean you have implemented
detection across all the 222 techniques
and it is even miter says in their FAQ
that it is not possible to cover all the
hundred because of various reasons if
you are an 100 on-prem organization
there are tactics techniques which are
specific to Cloud environment you just
cannot implement it uh if you don't have
certain security controls implemented
for example if you don't have an
endpoint DLP or a network DLP those uh
specific tactics and techniques
associated with let's say data
exploration uh you may not be able to
build rules around it because you don't
have the security control to throw those
signals into the SIM yeah yeah so you
were actually like caught me ahead
so because we are at nulcon I was like
more curious about also from maturity
perspective like uh we have script
queries we have
because we have purple team red team and
we have apts so if I'm talking about
sock preparedness and detecting this
sort of things so uh maybe a mid-level
mature sock what do you think like uh
what sort of attacks you will able to
detect at least
uh I think we all must get our Basics
right okay
uh you have a firewall
it's an internet facing firewall or a
perimeter firewall as it is also called
and you have a rule on that firewall any
any what does any any stand for
anybody
what does that mean what is any any any
excellent source destination Services of
Oats
okay if you are having such kind of a
rule on your firewall at an Enterprise
firewall internet facing firewall then
obviously you will have a lot of attacks
coming your way your firewall will be
flooded with events okay second
important thing is
you are not enabling logging itself on
your machines okay this typically
happens in the server environment uh
typically on the Windows servers Linux
servers databases applications uh you
don't enable OS level logins okay
because of that you don't get the
signals from those servers coming into
your sim
okay a lot of people say that okay we
have implemented domain controller and
we can you know pop forward those logs
but then there are local logins created
on the servers with administrative
privileges which stock will not have
visibility unless the logging on those
servers is enabled and those logs are
pushed or pointed to the Sim and then
you build use case on cases on top of it
so again I will go back to the miter
attack framework if you have gone
through how The Miser attack framework
is organized after describing tactics
techniques and sub techniques it also
gives a mapping of those to the attack
groups how do you do the detections what
is possible to detect what is not
possible to detect okay it gives a very
elaborate way of uh you know it
basically helps the stock to understand
what is it that they can do and what
scenarios they can build what events
they need to collect to address the
scenarios and make sure that those
detections trigger in the environment
so Yogi maybe like you have been seeing
also a lot of incidents and with the new
certain directory you're on the hook so
you want to add add like how the
preparedness and how ready we are to
respond and uh maybe like with this new
certain directory sort of thing
yeah so uh I think we already had a
certain session earlier so I won't
comment on that but
just to further shweta's point right so
preparedness that's what yeah so I think
[Music]
like you know now we are moving on to
you know there's a lot of different
environments we operate into now like
cloud is a big one so things change
everything is evolving
um earlier used to be ioc is you know
very important now ioas are becoming
very important you know you know
indicators of attack so like what
so might the way one of the ways might
attack framework is used is you it it
helps you visualize scenarios and then
plan according to them and so the the
maturity aspect comes in by that like
you know how well you use these uh
techniques and how well you can predict
what's gonna happen so going back to our
definition of sock right so now you're
bringing in threat Intel as well into
this whole equation so all of these
things working together is essentially
you know
um where we are going with in the future
yeah like if I can add supplement to
that question so what could be impact of
like we have seen recently a lot of Red
Team Tools being leaked so how soon you
think like uh once that zero day sort of
thing happens or like great teams tools
are getting leaked how fast we can
detect those animals like do we wait on
the vendors signature detection like to
be added to our info hour like we do
something on the Fly okay yeah so I
think this is going into a different
territory but like we talked about
hybrid socks like earlier in our before
we were talking before the session so
hybrid socks is one way like and by
hybrid stock we mean like you know where
you have your internal sock you may be
partnering with external Partners like
crowdstrike or some other you know uh
vendor who's helping you at the same
time and so yeah you have different
flavors of that but one way to prepare
for these kind of thing like you know
solo wins for example like who would
have
who would have warned a company that hey
solo wins is coming so there are a lot
of uh they're one of the advantages of
hybrid stock is you can have these
relationships which help you better
prepare for these kind of things so like
a mid-level mature company might be able
to ward off like script kitties but uh
more mature uh organization might have a
hybrid soft kind of a model
so so I think uh Vivek you want to add
something to this
but I think I think I agree with what
they are saying right and you you
it depends I mean it's all about
you have different detection techniques
now then how do you correlate those
right and uh maturity or how do you
respond faster would come down from uh
that's the stock team understands the
various detection techniques happening
if not are you asking the vendors to go
back and then give the right
informations for you and is the
different techniques being configured
well and all those things right it comes
down to that and that's really means it
I I'll just take one example here
um how many of you remember Wanna Cry
all of them okay so what was the root
cause of one Accra happening
somebody said
missing patches of water
what is eternal blue
smb1 vulnerability when was the patch
released for that vulnerability
March of that year right and when did
Wanna Cry actually happened me
right so we almost had one and a half to
two months to ensure that the patching
is done but then we have various reasons
of not doing that patch I till 2019
there were reports circulating that
there are uh you know systems which are
vulnerable to smd1 and this is not just
Windows machines but any
um infra which uses Microsoft's smb1 uh
in their infrastructure is vulnerable
right so uh now how do you make sure
that the sock is able to understand
these vulnerabilities and create
detections on it so what does smb1
what are the ports related to smb1
okay 443
or 445
445 others 139 138 137 right so uh what
sock can do is Define detection rules
for inbound and outbound communication
on those codes
very specifically which are allowed okay
and then deny once you can take it on
later as part of your additional
analysis so this is the approach when it
comes to vulnerability which is known
you can use it as a detection in the
song
so thanks to thanks Twitter for summing
it up um and I also have like basically
I also have curiosity for example we do
a lot of operations and we do a lot of
correlation
so one thing with correlation is
definitely attributing the incident to
any apts or threat actors who but what
on the internal side like do we also
have something to basically tag identity
to the incidents and how can we know
that hey
who is being targeted inside the inside
the organization uh some something on
that specific threat to Intel do you
want to take that yeah so
you know they're they're a threat Intel
again like how you get your Intel can
vary you know based on the size of your
company uh but if you have like an
in-house threat Intel team they
they should be the ones driving the
detection strategy so you know there are
a lot of inputs you know which can help
but if you want to just have a focused
strategy I think that that's a really
good way of going about doing it and the
way they do it is you know multiple
fronts
um
like you mentioned the APT actors but
yeah so mostly my question is around
like active directories that they have
been the target for all vectors hey
let's get the people's identity like I
want uh admin access and then then
basically you get the keys of Kingdom
maybe you can do a golden attack or
roasting whatever but if once you have
the hold of active directory and then
you can simply use that so maybe Twitter
you want to add something other identity
um so basically we are trying to address
um two things one is an external attack
gaining access to your uh valid accounts
which is one of the techniques under
four tactics of miter and uh inside our
thread Okay so Sim coupled with ueba uh
is more likely to give you that Insight
uh because
ueba has that uh very good analytical
module uh for example if I am
let's say I'm using uh g-suit in my
organization okay or even o365 okay
uh if you are logging from a compromised
device okay you get an alert that there
is a user login that has happened from a
compromise device okay
if you are logging from multiple
locations simultaneously which are
geographically distant locations uh you
get an alert that is something which
ueba can you know stitch together based
on the uh identity related events and
give that context to sim to further
investigate and uh you know analyze
really in depth so
ueba coupled with Sim I think is a great
combination to identify such attacks uh
we make you you want to add anything to
this user entity Behavior so yeah those
who have not heard the term ueb is
entity Behavior Analysis so whoever's
the user entity uh there happen like
basically
when I was doing my engineering uh we
were talking about anomaly detection and
intrusion prevention system and that
thing has definitely come a long way
maybe uh we can take as big as uh this
is the current situation where Smitha
was saying hey there are a lot of static
rules still like we are talking about
which port a very static binding maybe
some people change their RDP Port from
3389 to something else or like having
run this not to use the commonly used
ports to just have some deception uh but
where do we see this industry going
forward like uh is that would be like
too hard with all the kind of perimeter
getting diminished and our workloads are
running everywhere on the edge in the
cloud uh multi-cloud and like we have
something like hybrid on-prem so with
the boundaries getting diminished where
we don't have perimeter we are looking
at zero trust jtn is sort of a lot of
companies are coming with that approach
as well so when
would it be very radical to think like
hey
um a world without sock like do you
think we can get rid of the security
Operation Center and because everybody
has been talking about AIML blockchain
and all the jargons and geotrists but um
will there be a uh soon we can see an AI
powered stock where human intervention
is like less than no one like this is
like
a good sock fighting warm
a bad AI board or something
so uh see AIML is something that is like
right I don't want to throw it down
right but aimless is there and it will
definitely help in lot of those
detection techniques and even automated
response right but it is a utopian world
to think that AIML is going to like
replace the manual intervention right I
mean how we see it and how we think
about machine learning and everything is
machine learning is should be used
to uh to analyze uh huge data right and
ability to analyze which is yeah not
humanly possible but then uh pass on the
anomalies detector or the relations that
is identified but let human
be there to respond right or at least
decide whether just right or wrong I
mean I think you're discussing and you
don't want AIML to decide whether okay
for some reason the system is saying
that hey the CEO's laptop is misbehaving
and then I go and wipe it off right
that's not something that you want to do
and you don't want such instruments I
mean coming from an application security
perspective how we see it as uh even a
minute's downtime in an application cost
cost companies right and in that cases
you don't want AML to to kind of okay
it's seeing a huge surge of data or
requests coming from a business area
like say say from Singapore and all of a
sudden the block Singapore which is
their biggest business centers so that
will cause huge huge issues right so I
don't see uh aaml replacing it obviously
it will be complemented so I think you
are killing uh like a lot of Buzz here I
think so everybody has been selling
silver bullets in secret industry like
hey my aim will solve this problem like
you definitely killed a lot of birds
I'm not killing it I mean again see we I
mean nobody that's
that's lower bullet right I mean the
problem with how industry is trading
AIML is that that is the Silver Bullet
which is going to solve everything I
mean I don't see that happening very
fast okay I I'll just add to it
um anybody who is used as your Sentinel
as their Sim in their environments
what is the ml based rule in Sentinel
called
Fusion so Fusion is ml based rule which
addresses at least 120 different
scenarios
which otherwise in a traditional Sim
like oxide or QR you would have to
create either 120 static detection rules
or a combination of those 120 use cases
so that is where ml can help and uh
second thing is uh
human intelligence
can never be replaced with artificial
intelligence is my personal opinion I'll
give a small I'll give a small example
uh how many of you know the dabbawalas
from Mumbai
almost everybody
now when their case study was taken up I
think it was in Harvard if I recollect
correctly
they had zero automation
right everything is manual process but a
seamless process so can you run a sock
without automation the answer is yes but
to what extent that is a questionable uh
thing because it all depends on how big
your organization is how many signals
you are getting into the stock and uh
how is your attack surface expanding
okay so I would say that ML and AI will
complement uh the stock but not
necessarily replace it and the human
intelligence element is very important
yeah I think
the trend which is going on is like hey
how much logs you are collecting and I
think sometimes the Splunk is the big
bet like everybody has so much data like
the storage cost has gone like I I feel
like I should buy that but yeah there
has been a different uh things but uh
Yogi you want to take a take something
on like last closing comment before we
take any questions on like a world
without how outrageous it is to think
like one thing I'll be without a job so
I don't want to imagine a world without
thought but um I feel no I mean I
completely to watch it I said I like and
what Vivek was saying earlier there is
really
no replacement for human intelligence
all the tools and everything are meant
to help humans make you know informed
decisions quicker we don't want all the
noise so we really do depend on the
tools but not
as a replacement it's more of an
addition yeah I will convey this message
like there are a lot of companies who
are saying that hey we can potentially
prevent zero days from happening use our
ML and AI so yeah otherwise you can
expect the robot the rajinikanth movie
Terminator so let's go back like and
questions now the question time oh I see
a lot of hands there
um
yeah
[Music]
hello hey hi everyone a quick query so
recently pandemic happened it changed
the world in many ways right so what
change did it you know brought to soft
like when I say change in terms of say
being remote or remote friendly and how
it changed sock as an industry maybe
right now or going forward
so I can uh yeah
um so for us it was actually a very
happy uh change like not to take away
from the covet pandemic itself but
because of the work from home initially
it was very challenging because we had
to instantly
shift to a you know work from home model
we have to get all the right to the
security aspect of it but what we saw is
one like you know we got more employee
morale boost somehow
um we were able to hire more easily
because we also operate in night shift
so people were like okay we don't have
to commute in the night we were able to
hire uh more and I think in general
at least for tier one so it made up
somehow surprisingly a more positive
impact to the work environment now I do
have the other side of the story also
where we hired a lot of people during
the pandemic and they are missing out on
knowing the team like I met like
right here right now I met him for the
first time but he was hired nearly two
years ago so I think that's the downside
of this whole thing but but a happy
stance was that we did get some positive
thing out of that as well yeah and just
to take it forward from there um when
the pandemic happened I was with a
different organization and uh in our
sock at that time uh we already had l2s
and l3s uh you know remote access
enabled so it was matter of quickly
enabling that for L1 so from the ways of
working nothing much changed but what
changed is the amount and pressure of
because new technologies got implemented
VPN which was restricted to maybe few
thousands of employees had to be
extended to more than one lakh or two
lakh employees which means more
infrastructure more events right so
ingesting those events was a big
challenge because we had an on-prem SIM
EPS became a bottleneck events per
second so we had to increase our
licenses I think uh in just six months
we renewed our licenses or got
additional licenses maybe twice
so there was tremendous amount of work a
lot of servers had to be put in place to
address the bcpdr so again ingesting log
events from that and then making sure
that they don't just ingest the locks
but they also reflect in the detection
rules you're ingesting the loss but
whatever you're existing is not getting
correlated is another problem so again a
thorough validation of making sure that
those infrastructure is part of the
rules also it was a big challenge for us
uh we have any yeah
well we'll take a couple of more
questions
okay so I think this question uh started
when the pandemic started and laptops
and desktops were sent to people's home
the cmdb went for a toss and it
continues as uh as on date also that the
companies are not having a complete cmdb
with them so how is the visibility
Factor being taken care of by the sock
teams to ensure and help the it have a
complete cmdb because infosex is it will
do it and IIT says how exactly that's
always a conflict
so
um I see I think
um one thing is clear as as a leader
this is something which I follow is uh
closely connect with the leaders in the
it organization and the people who work
on ground that's very important so if
you connect with a leader at a high
level you will get a high level
information but if you connect with a
person who is actually implementing a
firewall you will get more information
okay and make your l1's L2 l3s also
connect at the ground level once you
establish that connect you can define a
proper process which is the change
management process and how infosec can
get visibility infosec I think should be
part of all the cab meetings at least
the emergency and the high or critical
severity changes
thank you so uh yeah also so some of the
organizations may have multiple Cloud
Technologies so how do we protect from
apds and what are the challenges we are
facing uh when the organization having
multiple Cloud Technologies
he is in my team as a biased questions
[Music]
yeah
maybe
I'll go like you know what we are doing
so he's going through a bunch of
training so that's where I think part of
the reason of that question that one
thing is obviously you have to it's not
easy
even though we sometimes say that it all
Cloud technology is similar but
everything you know everything is
different so every single time we
onboard something and that's what we're
seeing is you have to retrain the
Personnel you have to go through a lot
of you know tooling training
um folks have to get certified and it's
the same analyst doing that role
um you know doing handling customer
queries and also then trying to figure
out you know what what the attacks is
going to look like so I think there is
definitely a to answer your question the
first question so there's an increased
sense of burnout as well in in this
scenario so that's what we experience as
well
[Music]
I think when it comes to uh multi-cloud
uh environment
um
you can uh do definitely one thing you
use the native uh tools for example AWS
AWS has guard Duty gcp has uh security
Center or and
Azure also has ASC Azure security center
now they call it as as your Defender for
cloud I think that is something which
you can you know enable uh if you are
using Azure predominantly one good thing
in Azure is that you can have something
called as Azure Arc we which can cover
your workloads in other Cloud
environments and you can get those
signals in your Sentinel and then of
course the correlation rules which you
will have to develop
so I think there's just one last
question in the that corner and then we
will wrap up good afternoon uh I have
sometimes noticed that after
implementing Sim in a sock the at what
utmost use of it is not implemented it
is just used for logging and as a tool
to provide the data for your
um the you know whatever the data is
provided that is just used what would
your advice be on optimizing uh the use
of a Sim tool because it is just more
than collecting the data over there
so I mean something that we see from our
customers also right they end up
implementing same
and then they come back and ask okay
what is the use case that I should do
around this right so I mean I would I
would suggest that when you are going to
implement a stock and what you
understand what you are getting into
right and why why you are collecting
various data it's about visibility then
how do you correlate you should be able
to come up with the use cases that is uh
relevant to your business and as as it
was pointed out in the beginning it
should be looked from the business
perspective right security is no more uh
uh just a thing that Technologies are
talking about it's a boardroom
discussion so from that point of view
what is it and how what are the use
cases that uh is relevant to the
business that has to be decided and
write data has to be collected and
correlated that's that's probably the
problem there where people collect data
for probably a compliance reason or
somebody is telling them to do it and
then they are like okay what should I do
with it that's that's probably I'll just
add one point always remember Sim is not
a Dumping Ground of logs
okay you need to understand why you are
implementing Sim make sure that the
objective of implementing Sim is first
addressed and then the compliance on the
audit becomes the byproduct because of
the implementation
okay I think that's all for this panel
discussion I think we are already
waiting for the next one yeah if you
have any questions let's sync up offline
and uh let's say I I hope you had a
great one thank you thank you very much