uh as part of TCS operations there and
shaped a lot of policies he's also been
a great influence continues to be in the
government of India in a number of
security related uh decision-making
bodies where he advises the government
while also managing certain to a large
extent and part of the reason is we are
here is again thanks to him because of
the recent notifications which has we've
seen a lot of regulatory work happening
in the certain space for the information
security community so we'll use that
framework for today's discussion then
there is anuprita Daga you must have
heard her yesterday some excellent
sessions that she was in and she was
also talking about csos and the kind of
stuff that they can do she's also done
something very unique which is put
together almost two thousand
csos and information security people
together because this is a concept which
is very close to my heart that if if
your adversary is united in some ways
then why the defense cannot be
disjointed we have to be equally
connected to each other speak to each
other so the good guys have to be as
well connected amongst themselves as the
Bad actors and therefore she's been
doing a lot of work besides her work as
CSO of yes bank and again she's been
almost 20 years in the CSO information
security leadership space besides a
longer career in the information
security space and then of course we
have Mr Ajit Menon he's ciso TCS and old
colleague of Dr behal again many years
almost a decade Plus in major leadership
positions in the information security
he's also a business leader he's set up
centers globally and he also deals with
a lot of regulatory complexities from a
Global Perspective so we hope to learn a
lot from him just a few quick opening
words cyber security as we keep talking
about is a very complex and shared
responsibility so there will be a lot of
positioning from the government of India
because they have to protect the nation
from one perspective and also we don't
know who the adversary is the adversary
could be a non-state actor the adversary
could be a state actor wanting to create
trouble in important institutions like
yes bank or TCS because if they can take
out one or two institutions that's a
huge blow to India's national security
and its Economic Security so there are
different perspectives that have to come
in somebody like ajits will be working a
lot dealing with similar kind of
challenges and Regulatory issues in
various other companies so a lot of that
experience can feedback as a loop into
our national posture which again will be
very important and anuprita handles the
bfsi sector and she's got decades and
Decades of experience in that sector
which again is one of the most critical
information infrastructures which we
heard about yesterday from dgnciopc so
that's the format that we are looking at
I'll request uh all the opening speakers
to have their opening remarks for five
minutes and we will start with
discussing the certain notifications and
what was the intent behind it when I
spoke to Dr behel I realized that there
is a lot of miscommunication floating
around and those notifications are
actually supposed to be helping all of
you do the work that you do as
organizations and as individuals in the
infosec space so let's hear Dr behel and
the others and then we'll have a more
interactive session so thank you for
these very kind words and good afternoon
to all of you
he's literally gone and
built up a lot of expectations amongst
everyone so I hope we can uh
live up to those but having said that
you know there's a huge amount of
after covet digital transformation which
is happening in the society government
as well as industry
and I made sure that this
cyber infrastructure becomes borderless
for all to thrive
but also generate huge volume of data
and this
has attracted a lot of attackers
criminals Etc
and also as increase the attack surface
you all come across
incidence of solar winds Colonial
pipeline
all of them show that industrial matured
and we all are deeply interconnected
and are now susceptible to
vulnerabilities on a global scale
but our ability to handle risks
and incidence is not at the desired
place
and you've seen with all these incidents
which are happening but so what's the
sort of threat landscape that we are
actually seen
psychat mentioned about ransomware I
don't know how many of you have seen the
H1 2022 report which has been put up on
the certain website anyone seen it not
seen it aware of it
hello
need coffee
okay you have seen it so you've said
that there has been a 51 percent
increase uh compared to
you are seeing malware we are seeing
targeted fishing there is obviously
apt's data breaches and leaks there's
also uh fake apps unauthorized access to
social media and digital payment threats
which are increasing
what are these uh
actors malicious actors doing they're
using binaries which are already
available
[Music]
in the Target environment rather than
deploying custom tools and malware for
example they're using any disk for
remote Administration
they're using NG Rock reverse proxy
applications to maintain persistence
so we've seen all these sort of
incidents which are happening in fact
last year a cert handle
one incident every 30 seconds
so you can imagine the volume that we
are handling
and we gave out advisories
one per day three advisories
which is huge making an advisory is not
easy you have to go through a whole lot
of details
look at what will work or not work
should not break systems Etc and then
publish them
so publishing three advisories per day
handling one incident every 30 seconds
is humongous task
and these are all the sort of threat
environment which I mentioned you're
seeing none of them are connected
they are all different type of skills
that are required to handle these
so it's mind-boggling when a person is
sitting and trying to handle and you are
expecting someone to handle more than
one type of incident
but that does not mean we have a huge
Army of people doing all this huh don't
get that impression
let me take some cases since uh
mentioned that
what made you come out with these sort
of directions
see we've seen incidents where
the victims
in their ICT environment installation of
new software has happened but they are
not even aware of it
okay
because there is no auditing there's no
monitoring mechanism
there are no logs being kept
people have used VPN and logged in from
outside India these are not detected and
there is no reason for anyone in that
environment to log in from outside India
we've seen Brute Force attempts and
these were not captured group policies
were being modified after compromising
the domain users and all this was
undetected
so you know seeing all these things is
not just one incident two incidents
we've been seeing this for the last few
years and then we thought you know let's
get to the root cause
one of the issues everyone has been
raising was about reporting of incidents
which you said six hours
if you look at
the itac
it already says report incidence in a
reasonable time frame though that action
can be taken
now when you start
you know we all have the ISD
Indian stretchable time
so when you start stretching what is
written with the right intention
then there's a challenge
now reasonable time frame people started
informing or reporting
after six months after one year
is that acceptable
is that a reasonable time frame
I can understand you give it to me after
one day two days so that
as Michael mentioned this is all a team
sport
if it is a team sport and if you have to
cook collaborate to cooperate Etc how
are we going to collaborate and
cooperate
if you're not going to inform brush it
under the carpet obviously the other
entities are not going to be aware of it
no one can protect themselves so one
after the other everyone starts falling
is that acceptable
so you know we saw all these sort of
gaps now there was some incident uh
I said we don't have a huge Army of
people so normally I would
be leaving office around
9 30 10 so it's if you people think that
being in the government one can go home
at five
change your impressions about that it's
not no longer like that
so
I gotta get a call from someone at nine
that we are seeing a huge
attack
uh sort of stuff happening and they
might it was in the financial sector and
there might be huge amount of
money that might be lost
we don't know how to reach out to that
particular entity can you help us
so if you have a point of contact
obviously you can immediately reach out
to those persons and take action we had
a point of contact reached out
fortunately they were doing some
reconciliations they were in office he
told them what is happening can you
immediately look into your systems and
see what is happening and revert back
within 15 minutes everything was taken
care of they said yes this was something
happening thank you for alerting us
we've taken action we checked back are
you still seeing this they said no it
has stopped so within a span of about
half an hour everything was
taken care of so that's why we said you
have to provide us with the point of
contacts if you do not give point of
contacts whom am I going to reach out to
how am I going to take care and
Safeguard you
and if you expect that no we should be
taking care and safeguarding if you
don't provide such details so just now
also when I was walking in here someone
said we are just wondering as to who
should be the point of contact I say
what is there to wonder in this I said
you just tell me whoever we can pick up
the phone and talk to 24 7 that person
should be the point of contact
and whatever language that sir talks if
it is a technical language that person
should understand that that's about it
nothing more than that
it's nothing complex
then there was a issue I Believe on
uh vpns Etc
so
how many of you here have uh
given your
house on rent
anyone
quite a few okay so when you give on
rent
do you do background verification checks
inform the police that so and so because
those are some guidelines which have
come from uh the ministry of Home
Affairs saying that you should report
whoever is your tenant and uh
check the antecedents Etc do you do
those
yes
what we have seen the data centers Etc
are giving out services
they have no clue
what
it is being used for
now if you rented out a place and if the
person inside there happens to be a
terrorist
says there makes the bombs takes it out
in the
physical space
and then never returns back
and when you start tracing and you come
to this house a law enforcement what are
you going to do
catch the owner right
so when we are seeing such incidents
when we trace it back do our analysis
and you catch the owner they say yes we
have rented this out
but we have no clue who have we rented
this out to
so this is where the challenge starts
that's why we said you have to have kyc
for all this and
well ransomware everything is being
demanded in crypto
so that's why this issue of crypto came
in so with that that's the background of
how these
directions were given I hope that gives
you some flavor as to what's happening
what's not happening what do you say so
I I was going to ask him a few more
questions but sir sort of preempted me
and gave the answers before I could post
them but just to give you a background
like
some of many of you are csos here but
some of you will at some point become
cxos and csos why the regulatory
environment is very important is because
to understand it from their perspective
they have a large mandate and they have
a large responsibility and they won't be
able to do it unless there is some
enforcement like if you are expecting
somebody expecting them to protect
somebody but they will take reasonable
time as one year obviously that's they
won't be able to do their job so that
that sensitivity needs to be understood
when you understand the kind of role
certain plays and there is a lot of
material that's already available not
only on their website if you look at
what cyberswatch Kendra is trying to do
again you will get to a lot of
information and many csos I think 700
plus csos are already connected to you
where through a sticks taxi format
they're giving back a lot of threat
intelligence and now the threat
intelligence is being recognized
globally as some of the best feeds
itself so this is a work in progress and
there are of course questions and I'll
be raising some questions here but there
is a lot of good that is happening now
the bfsi sector is a very matured sector
in that sense and it's dealt with these
threats for a long time how do you see
be certain as a as a as an end user and
who has to comply with some of these and
how much do you think this will help you
as a CSO in the sector that you're in so
uh I think question of how much it will
help is obviously if you see like in my
introduction you talk about the
collaboration right I mean and
government and it is good that at
government level there are a lot of
proactive actions which are happening
and those proactive actions let's say
that you know whether it is a
manufacturing company or any other bank
or any other BFI sector and the way the
crunching on ioc and uh suggested as he
said that okay when we are issuing The
Advisory or alert then definitely there
is lot of work which is happening and
obviously that relevant is coming to us
and we ourselves have also seen because
it's a very one is the bank says and
then other csos also there is quite a
good small salt Pockets where people are
connected and when something happens at
least we take help of each other and I
myself has experience in last three four
years saying that you know when when
there is either we have reported or
somebody has reported and four to six
hours that was also in the industry in
banking four to six hours is very normal
because we are doing it for a long time
but for other than banking I think that
is one thing which where people fit and
Sr said like six months one year you
know maybe one day two days but we
ourselves have seen that you know after
reporting it you know this is quite a
bit of work which happens and the same
thing as a advisory which comes to all
the banking side right and there's a lot
of coordination and it's not only
certain from Sir to Seaside to RBI to
other regulator there is quite a good
collaboration also which happens which
we experience it and how does that help
us proactively like when I'm giving it
it is helping like all other 200 300
banks at the same time when somebody is
giving it definitely it is helping us
also so the whole system in one limited
pocket is really working very well and
we are a part of that uh and when that
is being extended to all the industries
I'm sure that the threat Intel what we
have right now that will really be
multiple and India will have their own
in set Intel also and which we all will
be able to use that so from a
notification perspective you think this
is really helpful from us it's very very
helpful and now this has become such a
BAU now for us that when we get the
threat until obviously there is another
background process which you know we we
go ahead and do that because we have not
seen uh whether false quality or
irrelevant or anything like that so for
us it is very very helpful like it's a
very strong input which is coming to us
and thanks to the whole team for that uh
one is that that this whole threat Intel
and during pandemic right many times
this is also a good connect where
whenever we need something happening or
or you know some doubt you know and they
also have a point of contact where we
connect with them we take their guidance
or you know we also if there's anything
we discuss with them like what need to
be done I think this quite a bit
multi-fold collaboration which is
happening between the government and the
industry and also I think the
notifications have brought in a lot of
clarity where certain areas where that
Clarity was not there and if you see the
subsequent effect used there was a lot
of rethinking also which then brought
further clarification and I think it
also took some feedback to the initial
notifications and eased certain things
where they felt that yes some time needs
to do this yes definitely it is a lot of
things to us also and again in uh in the
CSO Forum of Banks and all we also got
the clarity on that uh for banking this
is like a normal right
for other industry it's a new Norm but
while making it new now for everything
which is starting is going to have
initial job and then obviously when they
get the visibility of that obviously
they will also understand the the
meaningful activity behind it so today
when uh sir was talking about uh
reasonable time period right why four to
six hours this is a reason for that and
that for reason to uh to see that okay
why quickly we need to report it because
for us it is containment within our
company
for hemp contentment within the country
country yes that that's a huge
difference right and uh I think once
people start you know seeing that whole
life cycle uh people will understand
okay why uh certain is talking about
four to six hours why certain is talking
about ntp your time synchronization by
certain is talking about log management
uh but yeah it's a cycle like they have
to if I am confident to talk about it
because I have experienced it if
everybody has to get that confidence
obviously they have to go through a red
life cycle Ajit you've seen a Global
Perspective right and you've dealt with
other search what what changed when the
note came and how does it compare with
the other search and how they operate in
the countries you have worked in
oh thanks
um that's an interesting question
because if you look at what cert India
is trying to do versus what others are
trying to do we do have a good amount of
threat Intel coming in now if I compare
it with can you hear us
he said okay hello
yeah okay so if I compare the threat
Intel we get in other geographies
because we connected in most of the
geographies where we operate um I can
tell you that the iocs that we receive
there are hardly like one tenth or less
um the actionable intelligence that we
get from cert in have really been
valuable we get threat Intel but the
importance is to get actionable
intelligence and that is what keeps you
a step ahead of your adversary so that's
something that really makes a big change
and that is I mean I would agree with
what uh on Twitter said the amount of
information that we get back from cert
obviously gives us the motivation to
report so that it helps not just us but
also others who are functioning and we
have to remember that um unlike maybe a
decade ago where each of us were
individual organizations today it is an
ecosystem in some way you are connected
like we are connected with a bank the
bank is connected with someone else and
that one is connected back to us so
unless we take that thought that we have
to protect the ecosystem you are never
protected so you have to move beyond the
boundaries of saying that I want to
protect my organizations it just cannot
be about yourself because you're no
longer an isolated entity in the larger
ecosystem the supply chain attacks that
we're talking about that today is the
biggest concern that exists most of our
customers talk about it like if
organization like you us which are
service providers are attacked and we do
not have the right protection they also
become partied to an attack right so
these are concerns which we keep hearing
from customers these are concerns that
we keep hearing from Regulators outside
with whom we uh discuss these issues so
the whole thing goes around in terms of
how quickly can we firstly identify how
quickly can we share and resolve it
collectively because it's not just a
one-person game anymore
so um if you talk about
um other Regulators we're not seeing
enforcement to the extent that we're
talking about but I think the need of
the r is that we get to that level so
that the sharing happens we have to look
beyond the demand but we have to
understand the underlying intent
okay so in that sense I would say that
so that intent part that you mentioned
is very interesting so if intent can be
established then without enforcement you
can probably get a lot of people to
agree to do some of these things so if
if you were to then say that if you
wanted to see the notifications as there
would you want to tweak anything in
those notifications today
uh okay so if you ask me if something
could have been done differently on
those notifications
um there are a few things which possibly
I may not be very convinced about
um first and foremost uh is let me go in
the sequence so that I I recall when we
talk about uh the sync time
synchronization to be done but that's a
given without that no investigations can
ever happen but uh
if I bring the practicality of trying to
say that every System including the
OT systems how to be time synchronized
to a particular clock okay that becomes
overbearing uh and I think it got
diluted a little later in the next thing
that it can be in line with it but
um
I I think we're gonna just stop by
saying you need to have time
synchronization right with the Nic and
pl could have been avoided because that
just brings in an additional layer like
today if there is an attack on company a
versus Company B you start with when it
started in company and your timeline is
from there on you need to make sure that
there is time synchronization versus
Company B will have their own and even
if that is let's say a minute or two you
can always compare that okay this is a
start and uh this is the sequence in
which should happen Okay the seconds
within the organizations will not vary
as much unless it's a connected
organization so that's my perspective
there uh the reporting part is uh as I
said I I completely agree as to why we
need to report uh timelines people may
have their own opinion we are okay and
this is not new reporting requirements
were all established uh when you get to
the
kyc part of it that's where the
complexity starts and I think um Sanjay
gave a classic example of uh when you
try to establish the identity of your
tenant okay now what means are available
to organizations that's also something
that we have to look at so we understand
the need but how do I go about doing it
how do I if I'm a service provider who's
giving out a VPN service and maybe an
individual is connecting with me what is
the identity that with which I can
validate if I have to go back to the
ground and do it it's impractical in a
large country like ours
um if you say aadhar is a verification
mechanism I think the Supreme Court
ruling is very clear that aadhar cannot
be the only way to authenticate so as an
organization if I have to align okay
then what what are the means available
to you it's not that I I do not want to
but can I how practical is it but these
are questions that come on to the
corporate side that we understand the
objective but the implementation is
where the where as we say the rubber
hits the road is where we really have a
problem too many potholes that creates
an issue
so you heard uh so so let me uh
talk about time synchronization first
how many of you have
carried out bcpdr in your organizations
show off hands okay very few
surprising
so if you carried out bcpdr
have you considered a scenario that
you are no longer connected to the rest
of the world the undersea cables have
been cut off
now how do you connect to the rest of
the world
and in that scenario
how are you going to get your time
if you are not connected to NPR or Nic
or whatever we've said
where are you going to get your time
from
have you thought of that scenario
consider it put it in your bcpdr plans
no
so
what I'm saying is that you need to
consider various aspects in today's
complex environment
due to the variety of geopolitical stuff
that is happening all around us
so with that
we have been trying to say yes you can
connect outside but when you have a
challenge you should be aware
what you will have or what you will not
also these attacks are
Crossing Borders
now when I have to
get some help support from overseas
search or other agencies whom we are in
touch with
the first thing they ask is give us the
logs
so that we can check and give you back
some data
if the logs are not going to match well
did mention that you can try and
correlate
one or two minutes what we've seen is
that even a few seconds here and there
no one is going to come back they will
say this thing has not emanated from
here
the no one has the time to sit and do
that for you so if the synchronization
of time is not correct there will be a
huge challenge you will never be able to
complete your analysis
[Music]
is the second one was on
the customer said as if I'm audio
service how do you do your kyc for
example let's say there's a company
which offers free VPN services and
hundreds and thousands of people across
so how do you do a kyc
completely agree on the Supreme Court
ruling this that aadhaar cannot be the
only one we have not said that should be
the only one
we've said that you can do it in
multiple ways we've given ideas that you
can do it in the fashion what uh the RBI
has suggested or what Savi has suggested
or what dot has suggested you can take
any of those for as long as you have a
mechanism because those will be only
required when there is an incident and
the trail leads up to coming to that
situation
and that time if you say we have no clue
as to who this is what is it
there then you are stuck
so we need that detail only at that time
otherwise we are not requiring those
details at all
so wait for some more time probably
we may come up with a few more
additional
FAQs to address some of these issues
which have been raised so maybe there
will be a few handful of FAQs which will
further come
I can't help but ask is there a time
frame to that new episodes
so I used to be a journalist so I can't
help it
there is a time frame so uh is it within
the six hour
[Laughter]
FAQs are ready it has to go through a
certain process so it's in that process
let me go to that so the moment it comes
back to me it will be up yes yeah so uh
actually from industry perspective I'll
tell you uh I'm not talking only from my
own perspective but what happens is that
every regulator is is
the maturity of every regulator is
different right and for these guidelines
what happens is that uh
even with within bfsi as Ajit was saying
that the way RBI Ida uh and again within
BFS there are enormous Regulators
honestly
PF RDA NSC I mean although NSC BSC are
not Regulators
so we have regulator and costly
regulator and being the financial
industry we have to report to everyone
right and what happens when the the
guideline comes
it is the same guideline which is
getting forwarded but when we ask the
question and this is not my problem but
when within the industry when we are we
are talking we are here wanted to hear
your point huh we are here to hear only
your point yeah no no it's not only so
I'm here I'm talking about intent at a
country level so intent of certain is is
correct and which has to be there right
I mean there is no doubt about it
and whatever intent when we try to meet
that intent obviously eventually we will
only get the benefit of it because if
everybody starts reporting the incident
obviously no why only from Bank you know
even other Industries also that is also
going to benefit us only thing is that
all the industries are not matured to
that level to start adopting it right
and that is one of the biggest problem
what and also if you see a seesaw CSO
also ranges rest from 10 years
experience to 30 35 years experience
also so that industry is matured at a
different level csos are matured at
different levels Regulators are matured
at different levels
of that that is the biggest recognition
of that is that they gave additional
time to smes and other companies which
may not have the same maturity so that
end I think 28 September is when so they
extended that time so that recognition
is there to an extent recognition is
there I agree and and there were
discussed so
if Industries are not matured and even
for interpretation of that eventually
any company will say okay let's get the
consulting company and then do it but
that kind of linkage between the central
government to regulator to the industry
I think that one change I think if that
is being done that will help yeah that
will help the systems so I
I'll just add one more question which I
had for you and Dr behel
that is that intent we all agree was
good and there is a methodology and we
can discuss the methodologies a plus
here and a minus there Etc but also
we've seen that businesses also have
legitimate interests not to reveal too
much of data because this could have
major business implications to your
customers and so on and so forth
so a notification with the right intent
could very easily become a tool for
surveillance as well so where and how do
you ensure that it does not become a
data capturing server installed but
actually serves the original intent
because Dr behel is there today so we
can trust him but tomorrow somebody else
could take over after him and use the
same notifications for different things
so how would you look at that and after
hearing your answer something from Dr
Bell and some additional points that you
wanted to uh sure so when we talk about
um the reporting aspects
yeah
sorry so when we talk about the
reporting aspects and the log collection
and other things I think the rules today
I say that the organization should have
the logs for six months
um across anything that might need
investigations and as required cert may
ask for those logs if they get involved
okay now each of these are independent
statements and depending on the intent
uh maybe as you slightly said maybe the
successor could put a comma somewhere
and the whole thing changes and it can
actually mean that organizations may
have to continuously give data because
it's a demand from the government right
at the end of the day cert is a
government body in that sense so it
could be misused I think it is important
that we set up checks and balances so
that the intent is maintained and also
organizations have a right or to appeal
somewhere in that sense that this is
something that is getting excessive so
today it is logs tomorrow it could get
to data so how do we make sure that
productivity the intent is maintained
second the other point that I just
wanted to put on the table and I think
this is important for us enjoy Also to
reconsider is that the the aspect of
reporting
on organizations perfectly I understand
that intent and that's perfect but when
you talk about a service organization
like ours and you say that whoever
observes it first has the mandate to
report and if you fail in your duties
there is no indemnification technically
it translates to if my organization is
providing services to her company and
I'm running a stock okay I I will only
see incidents so before I tell her I
have to tell sir also right so these are
areas which are catchy because then she
would come back as a customer saying
organization but you have happened to
see it first because that's my that's
the service that's not yours to me I'm
the first person to see it I'm running a
song okay so before I report here or I
have your parallel reporting for some
maneuvering room so that she gets to
report it rather than the exact thing is
that a fair asks her and if he's
servicing me obviously he will have
obligations to first report to you first
and until unless I say okay do you think
that's a fair point
I will probably disagree because of what
we are seeing on ground
uh
if as a service provider he has reported
to her
cases have been there where it has been
pushed under the carpet
now again the moment you push it under
the carpet no one knows about it the
service provider is aware now when
something else happens and it you do an
audit or you find out some other
incident link it to this and then you
investigate and you find out this is
what had happened why was it not
reported that is where it is all Linked
In
oh we would have reported it's in
reasonable time frame we were about to
report
that's how it gets extended to six
months one year Etc
so we've seen cases and that's why we've
said whoever sees it report now morning
you know uh over breakfast
having some very interesting
conversation about how some of the other
countries uh look at security Etc and
what popped up was Israel
now if you go to Israel from the
physical security space
they are taught that right from
childhood even if a small child
sees someone suspiciously acting on the
road
either they will go and tell that person
why what Etc or they will report
now they don't have to wait for some
CCTV camera to capture it and then that
should be informed Whoever has seen
something just report
that is how they keep their country safe
now if you are wanting your cyberspace
to be safe and you say that okay it is
their responsibility because there is a
contract
but the contract says yes I'll report to
you and then you shove it under the
carpet that's not acceptable
so that's why I differ there
and the point that they mentioned about
reporting a four to six hours in the
banking industry now
if you see everything is interconnected
as I mentioned
if the banking industry can report in
six hours within six hours
it is the other industry which will pull
everyone down
that's the weakest link then so I
everyone will have to come up to that
level and then start making sure that we
are safe and secure in this digital
world how many of I'll just be one
moment how many of you believe 5G is to
be implemented soon around the corner
and will change everything
so what will change from a threat
perspective do you have any idea
huh
[Music]
more risks and more complex traits
so I was just reading somewhere it is
predicted
that incidence will rise to 5 billion
every 10 minutes
if that is going to happen 5 billion
incidents every 10 minutes
are you saying that I am going to report
something after 72 hours and 72 hours is
for privacy not for security
so I have exactly two minutes so I'll
ask two questions and then we'll end
this session
but uh the organizers played a trick on
me at 12 30 they said 15 minutes at 12
37 they said five minutes so there's
time synchronization needed right here
just FYI so first of all it's a welcome
step from a question I need a sharp
questions
it's a welcome step from an Auditor's
first question question I'm giving I'm
coming to a question question give me
one second sir we don't have one second
okay how do you enforce these six hours
and all these mandates that you have put
in Indus in this because I'm clearly
seeing that most of the Caesars are not
very comfortable with all of this how do
you enforce this into an industry see
the enforcement will start happening the
moment there are incidents that's why I
said if you report you have seen
something a DDOS attack Etc happening
and you tell us we will enforce it if
there is an incident the moment we get
into it and an analysis it'll come
because there there will be some two
three four cases which will be put up
and then everyone will fall in line if
they are not doing it
[Music]
one more thing to clarify to you is that
it's not that most
most issues are not comfortable I'm not
saying that I'm saying that people has
to understand and start adopting it so
that was my point yes you had a question
so just one question when somebody
reports let's say you know for the
namesake TCS reports something to you so
when you propagate that information do
you capture the essence of the industry
or you just circulated uh like Anonymous
no no it's
first of all the name TCS will never
come
we see what is happening from the
industry perspective we are seeing what
is happening outside the country also
and then the advisories are made that's
why I said advisory making is not an
easy subject advisory is one part when
you when we come actually when we put it
from actionable perspective the
indicators or compromise the hashes
domains Etc all those are propagated in
a automated fashion so if you have the
capacity to digest it automatically
through six taxi formats you will be
able to do it
okay one last question yeah
yeah so sir my question to you is that
uh from a corporate perspective once uh
the first time I received FAQ it looked
a bit nebulous a bit ambiguous but the
subsequent FAQ clarified most of it so
uh what are so what is your plan firstly
to scale up as you said that you're
short of Manpower and secondly uh when
can we see a future wherein The Advisory
itself would cater for most of the
scenarios and we don't lend a land up in
situation like this one where you have
to issue multiple FAQs to clarify no
there is no multiple FAQs I'm just
saying there was some specific questions
like
the raised here also
which will be addressed so it's not that
multiple FAQ will keep coming
because those who are in in this field
and who understand it technically they
understood what has to be done and they
are complying to it because we are
seeing an increase in the number of
reported incidents okay already but
those who are from the legal perspective
are still looking at the commas and full
stops which they can do because that's
their job and that's how they get paid
yes yeah I I don't have a question I
just wanted to uh provide a comment on
the issue of principal agent which uh
which was raised so terrorism is a very
attractive simile to apply in many
situations see something say something
but cyber attacks especially the serious
ones are to be treated like economic
offenses which go on for long period of
time and they have to be detected in a
different manner now in banking for
example the banking regulator puts the
responsibility clearly on the principle
and all outsourced entities have to
comment through the principle which is a
bank in this case so I think choosing
the right metaphor is important and in
this case I would recommend choosing
inside a fraud or economic offense as
the metaphor because that will detect
the more serious ones otherwise you will
hear a lot of noise which can enable be
detected by other means but to detect
the real serious ones we should take a
principle as the responsible party and
the long term approach
[Music]
okay yes so my question is six hours of
recording understood but how do you
decide what you can't hear what
can you hear me now yeah so six hours of
reporting understood how do you decide
what an incident needs to be reported
you can't afford every possible I think
that list has been already provided
there are some list of 20 incidents so
have a look at that list it clearly says
what has to be reported
q and any final words
[Music]
any okay we'll have one more yeah hello
uh so certain has this uh
so I have a small question if I have
this question from like three years I'm
not sure whom to ask since you are here
I'm asking the question to you uh so
it's a very good concept that you are
empanadling security uh companies and to
provide to maintain a standard rate so
the objective is very good uh but when
it's put into action right
um I always see that government
especially when it raises tenders right
for security Audits and stuff they
always go to the least bidder and in
some cases I saw that 30 government
websites are provided uh the least
bitter Pro quoted for like 30 000 rupees
for 30 websites of government in such
cases how do you ensure that the quality
is being maintained
this is where the issue of the awareness
at the user side is lacking okay I think
with these and whatever is happening in
the cyberspace we are trying to make
changes so that they understand that
this is not the way it will work because
that's where the incidents start
the moment these incidents come and
that's when we start talking to the
Senior Management and inform them what's
happening they start understanding what
mistakes they've gone through yeah
because most of the senior uh I think uh
I'll add to your point uh so I I think
long back because we've been for a lot
of government contracts and we had
suggested that why don't you remote uh
split the boq into the functionality and
the security component so that the
security is not the area of compromise
you want to look at it differently
because different organizations May
package it the other aspect anything
going back to the user um the user
Behavior part you take any government
tender for that matter the email ID is
hardly the government ID I have seen so
many contracts where there it's either a
Gmail or Yahoo or something I I really
shocked at times that you can say that
you Tender Is to be responded to our
questions are to be put out to a Gmail
ID surprising
so a lot of I I do agree with you that
what we say versus what we do a huge
difference there's a joke in the
military that the rifle you're using for
fighting has been bought from the lowest
uh bidder in that sense so that's
something that you could possibly look
at also certain has a responsible
disclosure responsible vulnerability
Destroyer program as well as we are a CV
numbering Authority so if any of you
ever find bugs Etc and you're looking at
getting a CV number kindly report to us
so that we can help you get a number and
acknowledge accordingly and give your
letter Etc and also if you look at the
booklet that was given to you when you
got your batches that booklet has an
advertisement from certain which gives
details about that program so have a
look at that with that thank you so much
sir thank you very much cycles for a
great panel thank you both of you
I hope you all enjoyed and Ajit it was a
pleasure and a privilege hearing both of
you and look forward to more
interactions at nalcon thank you
pleasure was all us thank you thank you