good afternoon everyone
um I am Aran prakash founder and CEO at
pinksafe we are a cloud security
platform backed by Sequoia uh some of I
started my ethical hacking journey in
2013 by finding a bug on Facebook
which they rewarded with 500 and then
subsequently made into top five
Whitehead hackers in Bounty programs of
Facebook Uber Twitter LinkedIn and
Salesforce also made into forms under 30
list of Asia in 2017 in Enterprise Tech
category so in this talk we'll be
discussing some of my findings in these
major Bounty programs and the tricks
that have been used on finding these
vulnerabilities and how you can find
similar bugs when you do bug bounties
and then we'll be moving on to some of
the case studies in Cloud security
so first of all how many of us uh get
here a message request saying hack my
can you hack my girlfriend's account or
boyfriend's account
so this uh bug took me quite around one
one and a half month of time uh to
figure out uh so this was so if you go
to Tinder what do you see on the login
page you see like two options one is
login with Facebook then there is login
with OTP and
I as a bounty hunter I went on to the
site and saw that uh the OTP service is
powered by account kit which is uh which
is powered by also Facebook so both the
login login mechanisms were on Facebook
so for me to hack into your Facebook
into your Tinder account I have to
either compromise your Facebook account
first or account kit account first
so context I combined like two different
vulnerabilities to create a very high
impact bug I found first bug in account
kit login where I go to login with
account kit option enter my phone number
enter my OTP which has been sent to my
phone number and then I kind of uh enter
the access token which is supplied by
some other app on account kit and uh
interestingly
there was no client ID validation which
is like the most common bug in North 2.0
so but for me to compromise your account
I can't really get hold of your access
token right which is like a very long
string I can't really get hold of it so
to make it like more high impact bug I
went on to account kit dashboard account
kit had a dashboard account kit.com the
service is not active it has been
decommissioned by Facebook now I went on
to the dashboard uh looked at the UI and
uh
yeah
looked at the UI and there were only two
options you can stop some messages from
getting sent and you can ban apps for
login and stuff like that but then I
went on to the JS files some of the
JavaScript files figured out a hidden
endpoint which was meant for updating
phone number of a user uh maybe that was
being used for some internal purpose or
something like that and I kind of
figured that endpoint out from the JS
file and if you look at the API request
the updates Inc async phone slash
confirm APA call this was the exact API
call so in the update phone request I
kind of enter my phone number and OTP
will be sent to my number and then I
will also get a request code which which
is also belonging to my
OTP itself but interestingly what was
happening here is the new phone number
was missing validation so update
underscore request underscore code and
confirmation code were getting checked
but it was not really getting checked
with the new phone number where my
number was supposed to be entered so
basic simple validation bug figured out
in the hidden endpoint but now I could
compromise like any other account kit
account in the world so simply entering
your phone number I will have access I
will be directly logged in to your
account kit and I will have a cookie
named AKs uh AKs cookie supplied in uh
supplied by the account kit dashboard
and now I use that cookie to kind of use
that in tinder's API request which is
which have two parameters token ID was
not mandatory you simply enter the other
accounts token that you got and you will
be logged in into any account you could
read their chats and everything
so
like very basic bug combine multiple
bugs to create a high severity bug and
most of these times if you I I if we
report a very low severity bug company
say they argue that this is not a high
severity about critical severity debug
we'll put that in backlog for like six
months of time or something like that
and you would end up ignoring that so
it's kind of necessary to fix like low
severity bugs as well this is the
screenshot showing the AKs token
um
cookie which you can use like a master
token and any other company who was
using account kit was vulnerable to this
Reverb saw one every everyone was
vulnerable you could login into all the
other accounts as well so very high
impact work very high user impact uh due
to a security misconfiguration
final impact ability to take over any
Tinder account
even though I found found like two low
severity bugs but I combined them to
create a high impact bug and every
bounty hunter or blackhead hacker they
work in same way try to figure out uh
two-step three-step exploits to kind of
uh create large scale large-scale impact
to companies
moving on to Uber so this bug allowed me
to compromise any Uber or Uber driver
account Rider account uh very basic bug
so I kind of went on doing recon process
what we normally do figured out the
domain saying
bonjour.uber.com and it was a domain I
kind of tried looking out like what this
domain is really used for
then I by doing some Googling and stuff
I kind of got to know that this is used
to sign up drivers in U.S I kind of
entered a U.S number went on to the flow
and figured out an end point in the
figured out an end point uh in the same
flow and if you look at the request
there is a small request which basically
says RPC equal to get consent screen
details and there is a user uuid going
in so if I so bug was very simple I kind
of enter some other users uuid and then
I kind of see your extra information
which is leaked in the API so if you
look at the response of the API use can
see
yes sorry
you can see that there is a token
parameter which is being highlighted so
can you guess what this token parameter
is
any guesses this is a web application
can you guess what is the token
parameter
this is the mobile apps access token
so this is like Master access token if
you have logged in into your Uber app on
Rider as a rider or partner this is like
Master token you can call all the apis
all the apis which are being hit by the
mobile app and if you look at like other
extra data which is coming in the
request in the response is like sign up
latitude sign up longitude
but the problem is I can't get your Uber
uuid how do I get a random string
then I spent some more time I registered
myself as a driver my friend has had a
restaurant I onboarded him to the
restaurant tried figuring out another
low impact work had like 600 endpoints
tried looking out for a bug which would
leak Uber uses uh uuid
so this is the second bug very low
impact bug uh if you look at this
request this was in like the Uber when I
registered as a driver I found this
endpoint there and this request is like
you add driver
you enter any phone number country code
and similarly there is another request
where you enter email address
of any other user and the response would
be driver uuid not found
so even if you enter a rider or driver
phone number any number you would get
the uuid of another Uber user so think
of a case you entering my phone number
in this API call getting my Uber user
uuid and then you using the first bug to
kind of get my mobile app success token
and then you're seeing all my past write
history uh seeing my credit card details
you take you can take rights from my
Uber account everything so this was
impacting all Uber users and uh
then fixed
so even though initially I thought I
failed into get into Uber account when I
saw the uuid long random string if I
report it to a bounty program they would
say how how would you get the uuid of
other user
but I tried exploiting it figured out
multiple other endpoints to create a
very high impact work so as an attacker
we kind of do we try to get access to
apps like agent applications driver apps
restaurant apps and uh then kind of
figure out other second order
vulnerabilities to create a very high
impact bug try to create correlation if
you are in new if you are new into bug
bounties try to create correlations in
two different different apps and combine
multiple other vulnerabilities to create
a critical bug
Facebook
so this was very weird uh
uh this has not been disclosed yet till
date uh so this was in the main
main Facebook app I was testing main
Facebook app capturing the traffic in
main Facebook app they had access token
going into authorize all the requests
and that access token is basically used
to get your messages notification
whatever you do on the mobile app and uh
all of you must be aware about login
with Facebook functionality so when you
go to any third party site you go to
login with Facebook and um you kind of
do next next next and uh and kind of you
some some sometimes you see like
permissions being given to the other
third party app but what if you have
given the basic permission to a third
party app only access your email address
or user ID but still that third party
app is able to access your messages
notifications and everything of your
account
so this bug basically allowed any
third-party application if you have
authorized any third party application
in your Uber in your sorry in Facebook
account they if they obviously they will
have your access token in their database
right uh they would end up getting
access to your messages notifications
the entire Facebook app
this was the API called all the APA
calls were vulnerable this was one of
them this request is basically used to
fetch number of messages you can sell
change number of messages to thousand
nine hundred so any third party app
would have kind of used this endpoint
to get your X to get access to your
entire messages and other details order
history payment information whatever
apis were there
so an high impact billions of users out
there it had like any other app wherever
we use login with Facebook they would be
able to impact billions of Life which
are out there due to a simple uh
security misconfiguration and the
takeaway is mostly like when looking out
for bounties don't think some something
is very obvious I see most of the folks
trying with Recon first Recon process
first and then kind of go they kind of
hesitant to go into main application and
try to figure out bugs so you should
also focus on Main applications because
you will end up finding these weird bugs
sometimes
but impact of application security bugs
so we talked about some of the
application security bugs here uh
high impact bugs critical impact bugs
companies end up paying uh large Bounty
amounts for this as well but our data
breaches really prevented uh because of
this
so so I was doing like bug bounties from
these many years and then I realized uh
this so the impact is very high right if
you kind of find bugs in apis uh you
would end up accessing some user data
partial user data but Cloud related
issues you would end up compromising the
entire company itself in 2020 as per
hacker ones uh report there was a rising
12 000 to 86 percent uh in security
misconfigurations uh reported on the
platform
and the impact of cloud security
vulnerabilities because of the extent
because of exposure you would end up
compromising the entire cloud is like
very high
so
we'll come on to some of the cloud case
studies this one was an assessment which
we did for a company
we were obviously we had like subdomains
and everything we figured out an open
port Docker registry was open to uh
public
I could have downloaded
we downloaded the docker registry we had
permission to do that we downloaded the
registry uh
we pulled out all the images created
containers and then got access to the
application code and uh in the
application code uh this is like very
very common you companies end up hard
coding like secrets in the code right so
they had like AWS access key and uh
security hard-coded
then
like further steps we use those AWS
credentials to list down cloud formation
templates and in those cloud formation
templates they had jira slag
so you use GitHub token to kind of get
access to like all the repos that they
are you compromise slack you end up
compromising Zera and you know what
happens is when we go as Security
Professionals when we go to a company
and say that uh jiram everyone is having
like all access all projects access
restricted so what we found using that
Zera token is uh it had access to like
security project you could find like all
the books that have been filed in their
security project
so like from cloud ending up to SAS apps
which are out there and you understand
the impact right so how big the impact
is when a cloud uh when you're when
someone's cloud is compromised and this
is how most of the breaches happen we we
should solve for like these low hanging
fruits as well uh hard-coded Secrets
obviously opening a ports authentication
like basic basic uh stuff
this one was uh so how many lost money
over here
quite a few ends so this one was uh very
uh interesting we uh we kind of
publicized we published it uh yesterday
so Shiva you know one of their
developers
had put their AWS key on a public
Repository
so it had like all the permissions we
were able to get hold of the key within
like one minute of leakage and uh we did
some some smoke test obviously it's a
platform so you can't really go and
exploit things like when you do in
private engagements we were able to list
down ec2 instance it had permissions to
kind of create new ideas instance drop
RDS instances modify S3 buckets
everything
so like entire Cloud compromise of 6
billion market cap crypto coin and high
time it's like 5 500 million billions of
dollars being created uh daily so like
very basic bug uh
these were the keys
they removed the credentials yesterday
they created a new repository also to
make sure no one kind of figures it out
these were some of the some of the
screenshots uh to kind of list down the
ic2 instances
final impact
full key permission who would kind of
use keys and we were able to kind of
you you could do like extra steps but we
can't do really when you kind of uh do
in the Bounty programs they were
obviously they were not even having a
bounty program all developers were
Anonymous we tried reaching out our
Twitter telegram no response so we had
to publish this the key was deactivated
after uh two days of time
takeaways try harder if you are new to
bug Bounty uh persistence is the key
you have to be very persistent if I can
do it you can also do it anyone can do
it
ethics are like Corner Stone for Success
don't exploit a bug too much if you
don't have permission don't try to
extract uh
money from companies
for simple simple bugs go I started my
career as an application security
engineer then completely transitioned
onto a cloud security profession I I
still do like try to figure out these
bugs
but you can also start learning cloud
security very emerging area and last but
not the least
do not rely on tools too much don't be a
tool monkey try to learn what is
actually happen happening on the back
end obviously you can use tools to kind
of automate some of the tasks but but I
and other folks are also seeing is uh
Bounty and just trying multiple tools
getting few initial dollars but that
that won't last for like many many years
so you have to learn coding uh
infrastructure everything try things
combine multiple bugs and then do this
thank you
[Applause]