I'll talk about a patch demo a framework
for building distributed therefore
policies this is a joint work with
cheongyang coal nutrient sauna tango 1
okay my advisor Cheon Guang Shan so
let's think about the execution of a
distributed word count this application
is expressed using a high-level
programming model so here we map each
word to a pair of word and a count of
one and for each word we sum up the
count and this application will be
converted to a runtime directed acyclic
graph or a dag by a compiler so the map
function will be copied to the map
vertices and the reduced function will
be copied to the reduce vertices and the
data dependencies will be specified by
the edges then this dag will be executed
by a distributed runtime with the master
and executor processes so let's look at
this runtime more closely and we see
that master has a scheduler with the
runtime director scheduled then it
acquires the data center resources and
then deploys executor processes and
distributes the mapper receives first
these memories will process their
portions of data and output the data
partitions to a data channel abstraction
in this case disks and the reduce
vertices will be scheduled next and they
will fetch the partitions effectively
shuffling the data so in this setup our
observations are on resources and data
so the current trend is that these
resources and data are becoming
diversified the examples are
geographically distributed resources
cheap transient resources and also the
data are becoming large and skewed and
in this talk I'll just talk about cheap
transient resources and large-scale data
so let's consider using cheap transient
resources suppose one of the executors
is running on transient resources and
the problem with these resources is that
they are
cheap and also frequently evicted and
this causes a lot of recomputation that
degrade the performance and let's look
at the second case of large scale data
shuffle so with large input data
naturally we have many map and reduce
vertices and that naturally lead to many
data partitions that need to be shuffled
and you know shuffling a lot of these
partitions cause a lot of many disk
seats that degrade the performance so
there are these various issues and the
question we ask is how to optimize
distributed execution for these
different scenarios and the existing
approach is mostly direct specialization
of the runtime so mostly just write a
specialized scheduler for this optimal
scheduling or write implement
specialized data channels for more
optimal data communication and so on
however this approach makes it hard to
ensure these properties so first is
correctin is how can we ensure that the
optimized execution after the
specialization produces the same result
as the original execution second is
reusability how can we ensure that the
single specialization works across
different applications and third is
composability so we have these different
specialized component how can we compose
these to deal with cases with combined
resource and data characteristics and
our goal here is to make it easy to
optimize distributed execution by
providing such properties so our idea is
an intermediate representation or our on
IR so given these different applications
written using different programming
models we convert this up convert an
application to an intermediate
representation dag with the vertices
representing logical operations and the
edges representing communication
patterns so here we have a shuffle
dependency and then we introduce this
abstraction called optimization path
which is simply a function for me from
an IR deck to a new IR deck and our
claim is that writing these passes are
much easier than the direct
specialization because you just think in
terms of how to transform this IR deck
and then our system will reflect the
optimizations in the distributed
execution so a Putsch demo is our system
and I'll first described the its overall
workflow so name-o user job submission
parameters are simple and easy you have
this existing application for example a
spark or beam application and then you
additionally specify a list of compiled
time passes here we have three passes
and then a set of run time passes so
here we just have one pass and one time
passes are invoked during the execution
of the IR deck so these are the
parameters and the system first apply
the compile time passes so the
application first becomes the IR dag the
initial IR deck and then we apply the
passes in the list order so the c1 is
applied and we check the correctness of
the output IR deck and then c2 is
applied and we check again correctness
and we also check that c2 does not undo
any of the optimizations that c1 did so
we check for these conflicts between the
passes and then we apply the next c3 and
similarly with the checkers and if all
checks pass then we are good to go and
we convert this IR dragged into a
runtime deck and the runtime will
execute this while reflecting all the
optimizations and then comes the run
time passes so during job execution a
Nemo message can be produced from the
runtime and forward it to the compiler
to invoke a corresponding runtime pass
to further optimize the IR dag and
because the IR dag and the runtime dag
are decoupled we can
lately update this new runtime tag to a
to the existing runtime running runtime
dag to ensure correctness so that was it
for the overall workflow of Nemo and
we'll talk a little bit more in detail
some of the optimization past examples
hey what a path does is typically it
traverses the input IR deck and it
inserts utility vertices and annotate
execution properties so a utility vertex
applies a specific function and an
extraction property configures a
specific scheduling or communication
method we've implemented various passes
for different deployment scenarios but
in this talk I'll just talk about large
shuffle paths and transient resource
path since they are the ones that I've
been talking about and both of these are
compiled time passes so first pass is
large of a pass our goal is to avoid on
disk data shuffle so we aim to shuffle
data in memory right shuffle data to
disks and read from disk sequentially
and a related worker is riffled and
here's the algorithm for the past
so for each shuffle edge II we insert a
relay vertex which is a utility vertex
so given this initial I our dag on the
Left this pass produces the optimized IR
deck with the relay vertex inserted and
this relay vertex applies an identity
function simply forwarding the data
downstream and then we set we annotate
three extreme properties on the incoming
edge of relay so we annotate push which
means that we execute em and relay
concurrently and then we shuffle data in
memory without persisting the data in
memory so with a push based in-memory
data shuffle with M and relay and then
we annotate the outgoing edge of relay
with this a line of code so we annotate
pool which means that our execute after
my relay finish and then we annotate
disk so that our data handoff is
done via disk and because this is a
one-to-one dependency we do sequential
disk reads okay so the pass produces
this optimized IR dag and Mo compares
the origin IR there with the optimized
IR deck to check for correctness and by
simply looking at this real utility
vertices and the exigent properties demo
is able to confirm that they are
equivalent and thus this optimization is
correct so hence the execution so we
scheduled the relay and M map vertices
concurrently with to honor the push data
flow and then we do they do this in
memory discard shuffle and then the the
shuffle data from relay will be written
to disks then the relay at no sorry the
reduce vertices will be scheduled and
they will fetch the data shuffle data
sequentially so this reduces that this
see overheads that we had with the large
data shuffle the second pass is changing
resource pass the goal is to minimize
three computations so we aim to place
computations on transient and reserve
resources judiciously and we push data
from transient to reserve so the related
work is puddle and this is the algorithm
so here we visit each vertex and if a
vertex has an incoming edge there is a
shuffle then it is costly to recompute
so we place that on reserved resources
and the others on transient resources so
we have this placement with the end in
the optimized IR deck and then we
annotate a data flow push for the edges
that are from transient to reserved so
we have this additional annotation on
the IR dag so again the past produces
desired egg and again we demo can check
for correctness and confirm that they
are they produce equivalent output so
it's good to go
so we execute this new IR dag and we
place the memories is this
on trends and resources and reduce
versus on reserve resources and they are
executed concurrently and we have this
interesting data shuffle going from
transient to reserved resources and this
you can see that with even with
evictions this moves data out of
returned resources quickly thus reducing
the recomputation overhead with using
trends and resources okay so we thought
if two passes and they can be composed
so given the single ayah deck we apply
the large shuffle pass on top of that we
can apply the transient resource path to
get this nice ir that with the to
optimizations combined and name-o checks
that this ir deck is indeed correct and
there was no conflict between the two
passes okay I'll move on to the
implementation and evaluation so
approach demo is open source it has 32 K
lines of Java code including its own
runtime Nemo has good integration with
other approach Big Data projects you can
run your beam and spark applications on
demo and demo itself runs on resource
managers such as yarn and metals with
the integration with a patch reef so
we've evaluated various deployment
scenarios and in this talk I'll just
talk about large data shuffle trends and
resources and large shuffle on trendy
resources since they are the ones that
I've been talking about and we've
evaluated different systems here I'll
just talk about sorry I'll just talk
about Nemo and spark and paddle which is
specialized for engine resources and
spark is a state-of-the-art they are
processing runtime okay so this is the
result of large data shuffle so for this
one we run a MapReduce on 20 easy two
instances y-axis is a job completion
time the lower is better x-axis is the
input data size so as the input data
size grows SPARC degrades or due to the
disk seek overhead
whereas Nemo outperformed spark with the
large shuffle pass optimization
we saw earlier this is the result of
transient resources so here we run a
machine learning algorithm on tenth
engine plus two reserved resources
y-axis is again job completion times the
lower is better x-axis is eviction rate
so as the eviction rate goes up SPARC
suffers from the heavy recomputation of
the evicted data whereas Nemo and paddle
they handle the evictions gracefully and
we observed that Nemo is actually on par
with paddle which is specialized for
Ranger resources and Nemo is optimized
with the trending resource path that we
saw earlier
now this one is large shuffle on
transient resources so we run a one
terabyte MapReduce on ten transient and
ten reserve resources
y-axis is again job completion time
x-axis now it's the path used on Nemo to
run this workload and the default path
works similar to how SPARC executed the
job so without the transient resource
pass default path and large of a path
they both suffer from the recomputation
x' whereas transient resource passed
itself runs in total memory while
pushing a lot of data to reserve
resources whereas two passes combined we
have what we are able to further improve
performance over using just a single
pass for handling this or combine the
scenario okay so all this is a summary
of a patch demo the problem we try to
solve is we're trying to make it easy to
optimize distributed data flows our
solution is optimization passes that
transform an intermediate representation
deck the result shows that Nemo up
performs a state-of-the-art Apache spark
with clean and simple optimization
passes and is on par with specialized
runtimes and further improves
performance for scenarios a with
combined resources and data
characteristics okay so I'd like to end
the top by
saying that we hope you find them more
useful and we hope you use Nemo to build
your own passes for your data flow
research thank you very much thank you
now we can take some questions
well I have a question I mean I guess in
the wild sort of what percentage of
spark jobs do you think are amenable to
this approach and if it's a lot you know
should you just patch spark mm-hmm so I
don't have the percentage number because
I don't you know work for a company or
anything but patching up spark is a
possible approach but again to ensure
those properties that I talked about the
correctness reusability and
composability I my feeling is that you
need something like demo to make those
work so you need some kind of a policy
layer on top of spark even if you want
to patch the spark to do that to just
keep on using spark all right great any
other questions
all right well let's thank our speaker
again
[Applause]