thank you for the introduction good
afternoon everyone I'm kids only from
jong-hyun University I'm going to talk
about on asynchronous I use tag which is
a low latency kernel I astagfirullah a
low latency SSDs this is a joint work
with Hakka Xin one sock zone jejunum
jelly and my advisers engage on today
CSS these are really fast
typical flash-based SSDs are on order of
a magnitude faster than traditional disk
and emerging ultra-low latency SSDs such
as samsung g SSD and intel obtain SSD
ultra fast they can deliver a single IO
in a few microseconds which is several
orders of magnitude faster than disk
with this ultra low latency SSDs the
kernel IO stack becomes overheads in the
total IO latency this graph shows the
breakdown of the i/o latency using
various SSDs with the low SSDs the
corner portion is negligible in the i/o
latency however with ultra-low latency
SSDs its portion is no longer negligible
taking up to 37% in Reed and 35% in
right this leads us to optimize the
kernel I expect to make applications
experience such super fast storage
performance in a computer system when we
need to run the to operations and if one
is computation and the other is on Io
a typical intuitive way to accomplish
these operations is to run both
synchronously however if the two
operations have some independent parts
we then we can run we can apply the
asynchronous i/o technique for example
after performing dependent parts in
computation we can run the i/o and
independent parts in computation at the
same time by doing so we can utilize
both IO device and CPU consequently we
can improve the store photo bus system
and also reduce the total latency to
accomplish these operations our idea is
to apply this asynchronous i/o concept
to the iOS take yourself to reduce our
latency and improve the storage access
performance before we get into the
details let me briefly over
our approaches first in the red path the
original red path runs many io stack
operations synchronously to the actual
operation in our scheme we run some of
the IO stack operations asynchronously
to the IO so we can reduce the reduce
latency of the sit read system call in
the right path a buffer the right has no
chance to overlap computation with IO
because all operations are done in
memory so we focused on the F sync
system code because it is the latency
critical operation and it actually
generates the IO operations in the
original F sync path on a journaling
file systems such as ext for a single F
Sync system called causes 3 right I use
our scheme our scheme is to overlap our
you stack operations with previous I
operations so we can reduce the latency
of the F sing system call in the rest of
the talk I'm going to present the
detailed analysis of the IO pet
behaviors in the Linux kernel each
analysis is followed by our approach to
applying asynchronous IO concept to each
i/o path and I also talked about a
lightweight block I you layer which
provides low latency block all your
services to the criminal then I'll show
you the emulation resource of our skin
I'll show you the vanilla read the path
first this analysis is an average of 4
cure by treat on obtain SSD when a
reduce system call is called the page
acacia layer
first the hinders the read request it
searches for the request page in the
page cache if page is missing it all
locates a new page and recast read the
IO to the filesystem leader in the
filesystem layer it inserts the
allocated page into the page cache and
locates the logical block address of the
request default page for the next step
it generates block or rickets and
submits it to the block layer the blog
layer transfers block our request to the
device driver layer which also case D
mail orders of the buffer page and some
of mates on Io command on
I'm very comment here
the threat is context which it and when
the device are you is finished the
interrupt handler do located email
address and handles compilation
functions for the request
finally the thread is woken up and
recast data is memory copied into the
user space our first focus is page on
location and DMA address or location or
DMA mapping to take off these operations
from the critical path we maintain a
pool of three pages in which DMA address
is assigned in advance the pool is a
simple link elite link the list of four
kilobyte three pages for each core this
is to simplify the operations to put and
get pages from the free page a pool so
we insert our page a pool or location
into the critical path in doing so when
the read system call is called we use
the page II from the free page pool
during the critical path after our user
is off mission command we run the two
operations asynchronously to the i/o to
refill the page our next focus is page
caching insertion operation in the Linux
kernel when the page is missing in the
page cache a new page is allocated and
indexed in the page cache then our
request is issued this is to prevent
other threads from issuing the issue in
duplicated aggregates to be same file
index
hence this sequence has a trade-off
between overheads on page cache
operations and preventing from
duplicated re requests since our goal is
to reduce the latest AG latency so we
move this operation to after submitting
an i/o command one problem of this
approach is that if two or more threads
miss the same file page
duplicated our requests can happen to
synchronize this situation in page cache
only one thread can succeed to insert
the page insert the page the other pages
they failed to insert are freed through
our evaluation we found that the
frequency of duplicated our request is
tremolo in practice the last target in
the read path is DMA a mapping operation
which is performed in interrupt handler
after a device IO is finished in our
scheme we delays the DMA or mapping
operation to when a system is idle or
waiting for another I requests this is
an extended version of the different
protection scheme in Linux which it lays
the on mapping of the DMA addresses to
avoid the overhead of iommu operations
because this is related to security of a
system we offer the option to disable
this feature the remaining long latency
overheads in the ready path are the
operations in the block layer and the
device driver layer to reduce the
latency overheads of the current block
are you layer in the Linux kernel we
proposed a lightweight block a layer
which is specialized to nvme SSDs the
Linux kernel uses multi key block layer
for nvme SSDs to scale with multi-core
CPUs and multi SSDs however the current
the multi key block layer has many
operations that hinder low latency block
are your services to the kernel it uses
two structures viu and recast to
represent a single block I request when
functions of API is called a be our
object is converted to the request
object during the conversion many
time-consuming operations are performed
such as are you merging and commented
Tagle a location after the request
object is made it passes through the
scheduling layer software and hardware
context in the block layer finally the
device driver layer requires many
auxiliary data structures to submit an
i/o command many previous works
suggested that these operations are
obstacles to low latency block our
services first the i/o merging operation
is inefficient
invest storage devices many studies
mentioned the inefficiency of our
scheduling for low latency SSDs as there
paper suggested replacing the softer
side are you scheduling to divide on
scheduling in addition dynamic memory
allocations take tens to hundreds of CPU
cycles which prolongs the i/o latency to
minimize these these latency overheads
we implemented a lightweight block aisle
layer which replaces the current
multi-block layer and provides low
latency block on your services it uses
only a single object called ldiot to
represent the block I request a bearer
has only essential arguments for to make
and vania requests including the DME
order it so it can eliminate unnecessary
structure convergence and all locations
also we maintain per CPU l be able to
support a long list object or location
and it also simplifies commented taking
operation through the logic block layer
the device durable layer requires only a
single dynamic memory or location which
is the physical region page at least for
the Mme protocol so this figure is the
read passed timeline before applying
lightweight block layer and by using
lightweight block layer we can further
the reduce you can further reduce the
latency finally compared to original
read path you can notice that our scheme
reduce the length of the critical path
in the read the path along now let's
talk about the right path as I mentioned
in the right path overview we focused on
the F single system call with ext for
journaling file system in these systems
when I have synthesis Finkle is called
on application third writes factory data
blocks to storage and waits for the
composition of the iOS then he wakes up
the journaling third or jvd two in the
journaling thread it first prepares
journal blocks which are usually
filesystem metadata blocks then he
issues the journal block i/o and waits
for the composition of that finally the
journaling thread prepares the comic
block and issues the i/o command a
foolish comment is enforced between the
journal block IO and the commit block IO
to enforce to to insert the ordering
between the two rights in our purpose
they have sink paths we also write back
three data blocks first and you wake up
the journaling thread in advance -
although the journaling thread performs
is computation while the data block IO
is ongoing the journaling thread
prepares journal blocks in issues dojo
no block IO at the moment instead of
waiting for the compilation of the
journal block IO the journaling thread
continues to prepare the commit block
then it waits for the compilation of all
previous iOS associated with this file
system transaction peniston's of flash
comment to ensure the ordering
constraint finally it issues the commit
block io as a result the total latency
of the F seeing system call is reduced
because the computation parts are
overlapped with the i/o operations now
the evaluation we implemented our scheme
in the Linux kernel and evaluated our
scheme using Samsung gsst and Intel
obtain SSD we measure the performance
using various synthetic and real-world
roca loads because of the time limit
this talk only covers the results using
obtain SSD first in the random read
performance
the figure to the left shows the random
read latency with variant block sizes
using a single thread our scheme reduce
the latency by up to 20%
one thing we want to note here is that
when our scheme works by polling our
scheme achieved a single-digit
microsecond IO latency seven point six
microseconds in four kilobyte this was
not viable in the vanilla you stack the
figure to the right shows four kilobyte
random mill throughput with varying the
number of threads we over committed the
number of threads to the available
course to mimic I could've IO as you can
see in the figure until the device is
saturated our scheme shows higher
performance than the Linux team 10 the
original Linux when the pig when the
device becomes the
polic he shows the simulator put the
next is random right followed by F think
with ext4 ordered journaling mode with
the same experimental factors such as
block sizes and the number of threats
our scheme reduced the latency by up to
26% and improve the throughput by up to
27%
however with increasing the number of
threats overlap computation and i/o
naturally occurs thereby diminishing the
performance benefit of our skin for
real-world workload evaluation we used
the PP bench redundant my first think
workload from rocks TB each experiment
shows performance improvement by up to
27% a forty four percent respectively in
our scheme but similarly with increasing
the number of threads the performance
benefit of our scheme is diminishing by
natural overlap computation with ru now
let me conclude the talk are
asynchronous I use take enable to
overlap computation with IO by applying
asynchronous IO concept to the corner is
take itself in addition we proposed or
lightweight block are you lightweight
block are you layer specialized to low
latency nvme SSDs finally we achieved
high performance gain in real-world
workload the source code is over lever
at this the key table repository this is
the end of my talk thank you for your
attention and I'm ready to take
questions
[Applause]
questions so your work is very good
about latency but what about throughput
I mean on these devices it's not so easy
to get the full throughput of the device
do you have any experience with them
yeah we we are more focused on the
latency so we need to we need more study
with with the improve the throughput as
you mentioned okay Sudarshan doctors can
you comment on the increase in CPU
utilization inside the kernel layer with
this the number of kernel threads
additional kernel threads that would you
would require and the overall system CPU
utilization can you comment on the
overall CPU utilization increase in the
system and does it have any impact on
the application I'm sorry for their said
to you so if you're going to do a lot of
asynchronous operation inside the kernel
right I'm assuming everything is
happening in the filesystem layer right
yes yes so which means that you're going
to increase the number of threads in the
inside the kernel right you're going to
use more number of CPU threads inside
the kernel I'm certain you take it
offline I'm sorry maybe I'll just
rephrase his questions slightly
differently in a more straightforward
way so the operation is complete faster
yes but you consume more CPU or less CPU
than in the vanilla case
do you do more work or less work or the
same amount of work but in a different
but in a better overlap with the i/o I
think that's your question
oh I'm sorry I'm sorry I can't I can't
understand okay well maybe we'll
probably both take it offline then okay
thank you very much we should thank you
oh one more question
yep go ahead a Jason Hennessey from
NetApp I'm wondering if you took a look
at the effects of your changes on the
variability so like the 99% latency and
the predictability you showed some
really great latency improvements I'm
just wondering if that if what the cost
was so do you have any ideas on the
variability like 95th percentile latency
99th percentile latency yes you mean you
mean the concerned about latency right
the tests are good that's a good
question but our focus is the it's the
general area of the highest Excel is the
none of our focus but I think it is the
good question to to improve our future
work so okay thank you yes thank you
okay let's thank the speaker one more
time