good morning everyone and thanks a lot
for for coming today I'm going to
present the work that we've done at the
University of Toronto on the evaluation
of file system reliability on top of
solid state drives in the last 15 years
the storage landscape has changed first
SSDs have started replacing hard disks
as persistent storage units however
their failure characteristics are
different for instance partial failures
associated with SSDs are an order of man
who hire than those for hard disks a
trend that will likely get worse with QC
drives second FTL has been shown to be
more prone to bugs during power faults
mainly due to its high overall
complexity finally file systems have
evolved significantly ext3 has been
replaced by ext4 while new file systems
have been introduced such as battery FS
and F 2 FS these three file systems
cover three different points in the
design spectrum ranging from journaling
to copy on write to the log structure
approaches in our study we are we
explore how file systems the ability of
file systems to detect and recover from
partial Drive errors so what do we
currently know about this
the RM file systems paper studied for
file systems that were common back in
2005 however this study includes errors
related to hard disks only and does not
consider file system checkers in our
study we focus on three modern file
systems and explore their ability to
detect and recover from errors along
with the ability of their file system
checkers to resolve issues of line in
our study we focus on local file systems
deployed on top of a single SSD and in
our study we ask the following questions
what happens if the underlying storage
device starts misbehaving and generating
errors how can the file system deal with
those errors and what are the actual
errors that can take place so we begin
our study by considering all the
different faults that can take place
within an SSD and map each fault to the
corresponding manifestation of the file
system level for instance while reading
a block an SSD may encounter an anchor
bit corruption which will result in a
redial error at the file system layer
since the corresponding data is no
longer available second an incomplete
program operation within the SSD can
manifest either as corruption or as a
shortened right note that this
particular fault is silent the SSD
itself cannot detect kind of detect the
error using its own internal mechanisms
ash on writing particular denotes the
case where of where a right issued by
the file system is partially persisted
within the SSD and can only occur after
a power fault so future reads after AB
storm right has been persisted will only
receive partially written data finally
dropped writes have several
manifestations at the file system level
for instance they can result in a write
i/o error if the corresponding SSD
cannot accommodate the request or worse
the write request can be completely
disregarded with the SSD never returning
an error about it we refer you to our
paper in order to find all the different
faults that we considered in our study
so as considering that the SSD itself
cannot be modified and also that we
prefer not to modify the source code of
file systems then we had to come up with
a different way to test the resiliency
of our systems against the different SSD
faults an important observation that we
made was that all these things look
exactly the same at the block layer and
for this reason we decided to emulate
the false manifestation by injecting
errors at the block layer specifically
we implemented our own device mapper
module which sits in between the file
system and the block layer and is
capable of intercepting every single i/o
request in particular the module can
fail a single request and return an
error to the upper layer it can silently
drop a request to the disk or it can
alter our blocks contents online in
order to emulate foreign rights and
corruption for every particular error
that we inject we study the file systems
behave
in detail understanding the effect of an
error depends on which part of the file
system is affected file systems employ
different policies depending on the
operation and the type of the affected
block for this reason it is very
important to identify and target
specific data structures and fields
within blocks to achieve that we use a
combination of different techniques
which involved tracing of all i/o
requests and offline file system tools
such as dam in order to be able to
inject different errors into targeted
data structures and fields within blocks
applications interact with a file system
by issuing system calls we consider
different applications which
pedantically follow posting semantics
and call F sync to persist their data in
particular its application focuses on a
single operation such as mkd or creates
during our experiments we run an
application and collect all the
different blocks that this particular
application accesses so by using the i/o
trace we can collect all the different
blocks and then what we do is that we
repeat the execution by injecting a
single error into each access block
targeting one block at a time
this approach gives us the ability to
better isolate and characterize the file
systems behavior and reaction to the
corresponding injected error so for each
individual test case we categorize the
file systems detection and recovery
policies by using all visible aspects
such as logs and return codes and also
by comparing disk images at the end of
each test case we also invoke the file
system checker and observe if it was
able to actually recover the file system
we have several recovery and detection
levels along with a few additional
categories that pertain to file system
checkers for instance error detection at
the file system level can take place via
error codes or by sanity checking the
return block while recovery can take
place by retrying the operation or by
propagating the arrow to the upper layer
we refer you to our paper
in order to for the complete taxonomy
used in our study in our experiments we
considered different applications data
structures and mode exploring over 7000
test cases in Toro this is a complete
view of all our results in the remainder
of the presentation we will focus on
each file system in detail and present
the most important findings for each one
of them but as a general observation we
would like to point out that in 16
percent of all these cases the file
system became completely on mountable or
completely unrecoverable by the
corresponding system checker this is a
five five thousand mile view of our
results as we observe ext4 reliability
has significantly improved compared to
ext3 butterface excels at detecting io
errors and corruption events but the
file system fails to recover in several
cases F 2 FS has the weakest detection
and recovery against all the different
errors that we emulate despite the fact
that is actually a file system that's
tailored for flash devices so beginning
with ext4 we observe that it will x4 is
actually capable of detecting and
recovering from a large range of fall
scenarios despite making little use of
checksums the file system is capable of
dealing with corruption due to a very
rich set of sanity checks due to the
robustness of its system checker several
data structures can be reconstructed or
flying still due to loss and thrown
rights sometimes the affected data
structure cannot be recovered resulting
in their loss overall we conclude that
its reliability has significantly
improved compared to ext3 I'm sorry
so what about butter FS butter fess is
capable of consistently detecting Ohio
errors as well as corruption invents due
to the usage of checksums however better
battery FS disables metadata replication
when the underlying device is an SSD and
that and that behavior is the default
one
according to the official documentation
there are two main reasons for that
first SSDs can internally duplicate two
identical logical blocks by remapping
them to a single physical copy
however this behavior would negate the
purpose of increased redundancy and
would waste filesystem space second due
to wear leveling techniques an SSD
controller may put data written together
in a short time span into the same erase
block therefore if the erase block is
lost due to an internal fault both the
primary metadata and its replica will be
lost this design choice causes severe
reliability issues as the file system
relies on metadata duplication to
recover from errors for instance we will
see how node level check sums can result
in data loss because of these particular
design choice so a battery FS organizes
its data using a forest of trees with
each tree serving a purpose a particular
purpose also we observe that also the
file system uses checksums for or in
order to protect all its B 3 nodes
however in case a single byte is
corrupted then I'll check some checksum
mismatch will be triggered and due to
the fact that battery FS has disabled
meta data replication for SSDs then the
file system will lab will end up
discarding the entire node suffering
from data loss in one particular test
case that we ran into the file system
completely discarded sever of 70 files
and directories moving on we observed
that in some cases butterface
could not make use of the existed in
redundancy for instance battery FS
maintains two separate data structures
for its directory in case one of the two
becomes corrupted then the file system
does not use the other for recovery
despite the fact that the information is
right there
finally we observe several cases where
the file system became completely
mountable and a few crashes while the
file system tried to recover from errors
even in those cases invoking bots or FS
the file systems the file system checker
could not fully recover the error last
but not least we present our results for
F 2 FS keeping in mind that this is a
file system that's tailored for flash
devices first of all we observe that ffs
is can successfully detect and
appropriately appropriately propagate
redial errors in most cases however the
file system consistently fails to detect
and recover from right IO errors as
injected by our framework also the file
system suffers from data loss due to
lost and certain rights regarding
corruption
inodes and checkpoints are protected
using checksums but still even for these
data structures recovery sometimes can
be incomplete resulting in data loss
over all corrupted data can have severe
repercussions throughout the file system
as the remaining metadata structures are
not protected using any form of
redundancy and sanity text cannot detect
every single issue finally sometimes and
depending on the error the corresponding
file system checker can actually bring
the file system to a consistent state
however it cannot always restore all the
affected files and in general it cannot
deal with read io errors as the system
checker instantly terminates its
execution with an assertion error based
on our experiments and experience with
all three file systems we would like to
highlight the need to verify the
correctness of metadata as well when
that particular metadata is being read
from the underlying storage device
especially if the metadata is not
protected by any formal
dancy second we have observed that
checksums can be a double-edged sword on
one hand they can actually they actually
increase a detection but on the other
hand coronal RT checksums can lead to
severe data loss
finally throughout our results we
observed that there are certain key data
structures that can cause maximum
recovery failures especially when these
data structures are affected by a silent
error such as such as corruption or
dropped rights we have made our tool and
device mapper code online and with that
I would like to end my presentation
thank you very much for your time and
attention and I would be more than happy
to answer your questions thank you for a
great talk it was a bit frustrating to
see that better FS has a specific
default for SSDs which makes it work
worse do you think in retrospect that
replication of the of the meta data
would have helped in that case in the
case of better FS okay that's that's a
very interesting question so at the
creation of the filesystem you can still
provide the flag and say that okay
enable meta data replication explicitly
but yes in some cases without particular
flags then the file system would have
been capable of recover and detecting
and recovering from some from some
errors but depending on the underlying
SSD and the way that new blocks are
written in place into physical blocks
then there is there still a chance that
the filesystem cannot recover due to
errors in the underlying device Rick
wheeler Facebook - question first a
great talk they like the work have you
thought about trying it for other file
systems like XFS and also have you
reached out to the kernel developers
with some of your feedback yes
so to answer ok so two answers a lot of
the second part of your question yes we
have already submitted some bug reports
and we have already
I am talked to the developers of the
file systems some of the issues that we
have reported have already been fixed
and we are currently working on two or
three different fixes for some of the
errors that we have encountered yes
regarding XFS it's actually a very nice
addition and we are currently
considering of expanding our study to
that thank you thank you Peter does know
Aris northeastern so you know in
contrast to butter FS where that
basically is something that could just
be patched by changing a default in the
make FS program you know did you find
for F 2 FS did you find that any of the
issues are basically baked into the
format or you know would it require on
disk format changes or is it higher
level you know could code fixes change
some of these things yes so regarding
butter of s at first we were a little
bit surprised that the file system
actually decided to turn off data
metadata duplication just because the
underlying device is an SSD but
regarding F 2 FS indeed when we first
began our study I note were not even
protected using checksums right so in
the process they did like the update is
the definition of an inode and added
checks in order to protect them against
corruption so I would say that for some
metadata structures they are not
protected at all against corruption so I
would say that even using let's say
carefully implemented sanity checks you
cannot always detect every single issue
so I would suggest that you know for all
the crucial metadata structures they
have to protect it again you know using
some form or redundancy in order to
basically be capable of recovering from
several different errors thank you thank
you if we have a little layer below the
fair system like so Sam what kind of
errors can be shared up as a little e
can you please repeat your question
because you know I wasn't able to so
basically your experimental you assume
that the fastest enzymes as single SSTV
and
if you have a set of different SSDs and
the way builders really on top of SSDs
sound like what the kind of errors can
be protected by that literally yeah so
using multiple SSDs and using techniques
like raid you can you can protect
against different types of errors but
still even using those techniques
doesn't guarantee that every single
letter will be actually you know
recovered right still the file system
has to perform each own checks and each
own recovery policies to deal with any
others that can take place beneath
beneath it thank you again thank you
very much
[Applause]