hello everyone I mean John and today
I'll be talking about a system that may
raise some trademark issue for me called
Lego s so a few years ago I started to
look into an idea called hardware
resource aggregation and yet the idea is
quite simple so in a datacenter instead
of having servers and having a metapod
that hosts a bunch of devices how about
we just separate these devices into
independent network attached devices so
this is called hardware resources of
Education now for the natural question
is why should we do something like this
so if you look at applications that we
are running in data centers they're
essentially already distributed and
functionally disaggregated so what
clothes like data analytics machine
learning they essentially are running in
a distributed way but more than that
functions are in English the
applications are becoming more and more
fine-grained with trancelike so less
computing and micro services so the
current practice is to run a distributed
system on top of a monolithic linux
server and then to group these different
server server functions into different
function pools but the problem is
there's an overhead of having a
distributed system interaction layer and
also there's only so much you can do to
customize a monolithic server and
monolithic Linux so what about the
layers below distributed systems so
these are oh s and hardware so these
layers
unfortunately for decades they have been
built with the assumption that every
application is essentially local but if
you look at applications in data centers
now they are distributed so are we
actually have your wrong assumption for
these lower level systems so what we
believe we should do is to have a clean
slate design for these low level systems
what I mean by that is to have built-in
support for this tributed resource
management for fine-grained failure
handling for a fast Network for
functioning separation customization and
with this I believe we can reach another
level of performance management
and customization so that's on the
application side
what about hardware so if you look at
data centers these days they're actually
becoming more and more heterogeneous and
domain-specific specific where things
like TPU TPU FEG and and the N so now
this is good good news for data centers
they all want to use all these fancy
hardware but the first thing they need
to do now is to find server slots to put
these devices in and if they don't have
the need to buy new servers and retire
own servers this is a costly process and
because of that is how to incorporate
many of the new hardware ideas but
imagine refuges can directly connect
devices to network and to deploy a new
hardware you just add a new device to
your network and to retire out one just
take them off the network so this will
gradually improve the heterogeneity and
elasticity of hardware in data centers
so now we just looked at application and
hardware so what about some of the real
problems data centers are facing one of
it is a resource packing so essentially
there are centers when they want to
allocate resource for T dimensional
being a packing problem let's look at
the very thing for example let's say we
have two machines and this is the
occupied resource on machine 1 and
machine 2 and we have this waiting job
which needs three yellow to red and two
blue and one red and together machine
when a machine to have enough resource
but because this job has to run on a
single machine we cannot run this job
and the related problem is that usually
because you cannot easily move a job
around after it starts to run you have
to allocate pre reserved more resource
than what is actually used and because
of this we are seeing in major data
centers like Google and Alabama the CPU
and memory utilization is only 20% to
60% so there's some current solution to
this which is like you can split
application into fine-grained smaller
pieces with things like micro service
and then run them separately on
different machines and communicate
through things like our DMA
swap and distribution memory but they're
still performance overhead to this and
also there's no core support for for
fine-grained failure but imagine if
every device is just separate and
desecrated on its own and when we want
to allocate resource for this device and
when you want more when you're seeing in
the hide amount you can just allocate
more and when you see in the demand
starts reduce you just turn off some of
the device and if the demand keeps
increasing you can add more devices so
with this we can easily reach
auto-scaling
right sizing and tight resource packing
and together this would improve the
monetary and energy cost of data centers
so with all these trends and limitations
what I think we should do is to move
data centers to a new paradigm what I
call this Agra data centers so
essentially we should look at the
problem from the perspective that we
should admit that it operations they are
distributed and functions are
essentially separated so what we are
proposing is to do this disaggregated
data center from the hardware all the
way to the application so from hardware
we should just distributed and
disaggregate hardware devices and then
the core always part we also distribute
and functionally this algorithm and then
after this aggregating we run each of
these separate OS smaller pieces on the
hardware and for application already
speed energy so edit now they can take
through anomalies disaggregate Hardware
OS easily so when this we have started a
multi-year effort into building what we
call a core do you see another trademark
issue I guess so this is an end-to-end
solution for the segue data centers so
we're dealing with the problem from all
the way from hardware to network to OS
to distributed system and a little bit
into application programming language
but today let's just look at the OS
layer which is called lego OS and it was
originally presented in Ostia so SDI so
the first question
when we had is one sweet this a create
hardware
what type of hours should we build can
existing OS work unfortunately existing
OSS they were not designed for this
upgraded resources and they cannot
handle a lot of issues well for example
now a lot of the resources they are now
moving the cross network and traditional
OSS they do not handle this remote
result as well and not only are they
remote but they are also distributed and
there's no support for this low-level
distributed resource and also existing
OSS they do not handle fine-grained
failure well so what type of us should
we build our idea is quite simple so
when hardware it is a graded the oil
should also be so this is traditional OS
which has process management virtual
memory system and file system and
network stack so what we
you
and hopesfire and star system to storage
and by moving functioning close and loco
to the device we believe we can achieve
faster and better management and we can
also customize these different pieces
better where this we propose the
architecture cost split colonel so let's
build colonel
we split always functions into what I
call monitors and for example we have
process monitor running on CPU GPU
monitor renowned GPU memory monitor in
our memory and when of you may invent a
new hardware you can just build your own
customized monitor and then plug that
into the network and here we assuming a
general purpose network that only does
messaging what that means is we leave
into a component coherence to
application which solve a lot of our
performance issues and also the split
kernel would handle a failure and
resource management so what's this
Bitcoin idea we build Lego OS it's a new
distributed or a sport is a great
hardware so the first question we ask is
how should level always appear to users
so we have to to very extreme design
choices on one end the whole thing can
appear as a giant machine and we can
hide out it are the details of the
circuit in nature and on the other hand
we can expose the desalinator to cure
users and let it appear as a set of
hardware devices we choose something in
the middle which we call v nodes so this
is closer to a container but not exactly
a container so this is closer to what
application developers are already
familiar with and also we support more
common Linux api's so this is what house
v note works so we note is a protection
domain and but when we know that can run
on multiple devices and one device can
remote e4v nodes and also we allocate
with me node we allocate the resource on
the amount so internally Lego s has many
detailed design and I won't be able to
cover all of them so today I will just
be focusing on the first which is how we
separate OS and hardware from
charities and briefly talk about our we
managed use us for the the most
difficult part we faced when we were
building Lego OS as two separate
processor and memory so these two have
been fundamentally built together for
decades so how do we separate these so
the first step is just to separate and
move the earrin across network but
that's not enough we also move all the
hardware units that used to manage
memory also cross network after that we
move these software system that used to
manage memory which is virtual memory
system also to the memory and run it in
a in a controller at the memory device
so after this what we are seeing is we
are separate we can separate the whole
virtual memory system into the memory
side and that leaves us what we call
would I call P components for process
and M component for memory and for the P
component now we are we only deal with
virtual address because all the virtual
memory space physical memory space and
the translation are handled at M
components so what that means is we
change our levels of CPU caches into
virtual caches which are virtually
attacked and virtually indexed so this
functionally this whole thing now we
have things are pressing our
functionality but what about performance
so if you look at this diagram you will
see that every last level cache miss
would involve a one network round-trip
so what about network delay so let's
look at how network speed has improved
over the past couple of decades so this
figure y-axis is bandwidth so higher is
better so this blue line is a single
single line Ethernet and this is called
length of four times speed and this one
is a single Bank DDR memory speed and
this is DDR bus so if you we are just
looking at comparing single lane
ethernet to a single bank memory DDR
memory you can see that throughput is
actually close and some projection is
network would even be faster but at the
same time if you look a latency
network is still 10 times
around ten times worse and the
interesting another interesting part is
met many of the local drm they are
actually facing both capacity and
bandwidth war so what I think we should
do is to resync the whole memory
hierarchy and memory memory system so
what we propose is to separate
performance and capacity of memory so
for performance we handle all that at
key components and what we do is we add
another level of what we call extended
cache years cache below last level cache
and we use a small few GBS of high
bandwidth memory for that and this X
cache is managed by the hardware on hit
paths and OS manages the miss path so
this with this we can actually improve
the performance on the P component side
and now we move or the capacity side
across network what we do is we can
increase the size of each M components
theorem or even use number at our memory
and we can have multiple of them so with
this architecture we improve both
performance and capacity and we can
separate and mention independently so
now it is very briefly talk about our
distributed resource management so our
idea is to use a two level management so
at a lower level we do fine-grained
management where each components they
just communicate on their own with for
fine-grained resource allocation and
fine-grained access and then we have we
maintain one a multiple global resource
manager that has that this process
global process management global memory
management and global storage management
and every time when you have a
coarse-grained resource request like
when you want to allocate a new process
you go to the global process management
but when you create a new thread it will
be local so I don't have time for
channel have time to go into a lot of
the design details of our leggo us if
interested you should check out paper
out so now let's move to instrumentation
evaluation so we implemented Lego as
from scratch I think it's more than two
hundred thousand lines of code now and
we parted a lot of drivers from Linux
and so at the time we were just using
normal servers to emulate the security
devices and currently we are building
our own hardware solution so here we
show results with a modified tensorflow
that are running imagenet and cipher ten
and we compare Lego s with several
systems so the first and the baseline a
single machine Linux which essentially
unlimited memory so no swap and all
memory is enough or the local memory is
enough so this would give us optimum
performance we also compare Linux swap
to local ram disk so in memory disk and
also a system called infinite swap that
swaps to remote memory through
InfiniBand so this figure shows the
unsafe return result and our image net
is similar so y-axis here we are showing
performance per dollars our per dollar
is calculated by Hardware energy cost
and it's roughly with Lego as we can
roughly save half of the cost so here an
x-axis is the memory size local memory
size our X cache size so if you look at
just pure Lego OS how it compares to
single machine Linux we can see that
Lego has came proof performance per
dollar by up to 1.5 1.4 times and then
this is in Finnish WAP swap into remote
memory and swap into local Ram disk so
if we are only comparing pure
performance level OS improves
performance of these swap systems by 1.3
x tube 2.0 2.1 x so this actually is the
power of building something from ground
up and solving things from OS and
hardware level so to summer summarize
levels firstly it's open source and I
think just looking back I think the key
contribution is in demonstrating the
feed ability of separating something
that is very fundamental and court who
OS that is things like how do we
separate process from memory and after
separating there are a lot of new
opportunities we can do we can customize
application hardware
I think this could encourage a lot of
the future and Hardware OS research and
like Ramsey said conclusion are always
different from summary so to conclude
conclude this this is most probably the
most controversial sentence of the whole
slide that that what at least what I
think is the identity success allegation
is not an if question but it's a Hawkeye
stream so what we believe the approach
to antenna salvation is an to end
solution that do things from ground up
we are pushing function disaggregation
the distribution into our layers of the
systems that and another interesting
thing that we found is that especially
to students here that building Kura is
fun although you write a lot of code but
it's new fun and nowadays we are seeing
new ways to build OS so maybe OS can
part of the OSS the user space it's this
equity distributed or maybe you
computerizing hardware and with that I
want you to think about my students who
work on Lego DC and happy to take
questions hi
we we spent a lot of time trying to put
components close together in order to
decrease latency I was just wondering
this seems to fly in the face of that
and then it introduces the latency which
doesn't seem to be compressible beyond a
certain point due to physics so I was
just wondering what the effects of a
latency might do to systems that are
running a data center like this so this
is a very good question so there are few
angles are probably answer this so the
first is lego OS and this separation
does not solve problems of our problems
so I would say this is better for a
throughput oriented or orient oriented
applications but also if you see the
memories the X cache that we added so we
think
latency should be handled separately
from throughput and forth Ruppert
network is in enough at least for the
things that we see and for that we can
actually push a lot of the support
oriented
a lot of the data across network a for
latency-sensitive we should just focus
on optimizing the processor site with
the cache yeah so that's my take on that
hi I'm curious since you have more
different distinct components now don't
you increase the probability of failure
like if one of those components fail and
as well as security exposures so that's
a very good question
so depends on how you define failure so
the do I think it's true that we may add
more components but just to remember
because our resource utilization is
better so the total resource that you
will need essentially decrease but each
resource you are now adding more
components so I would say this is
roughly similar but in terms of what do
you when you when something fail crash
what it fails now it's more fine-grained
currently when the processor failed the
whole machine fails and our model when
the process affair it only fails that
processor the whole application still
exists so it depends on it's a different
way how you handle failure but don't you
have more network connections and more
like independent power supplies
potentially so it seems like you have
more of a chance for very small
uncorrelated failure that would make
your applications harder to write
because now they have to deal with
partial failures they don't get to like
crash or like go away when the whole
machine crashes now you have more
chances of these more probable partial
failures happening so well like first
like I said the whole resource that you
need is less because utilization is
higher so the independent component the
amount of increment component may not
increase and the second is it depends on
how you build applications and who would
handle this failure so our approach is
our level we will handle all these
fine-grained failure with Lego s and
hide that those from application some 2d
application point of view they are just
running a set of Linux
containers let's see if you do like
replication does your system expose like
Network locality of resources to the
user like is it there any notion of you
know I want to make sure that I have ran
that's in my rack versus the rack next
to me versus like a totally different
data center currently no and currently
our scale is like a one or two racks but
I would say we are working on we are
working in larger scale and thinking
about some of the locality hierarchy
problems thank you for the great
presentation it's very impressive so
first question that I feel the overall
system availability all reliabilities
highly depend on the availability of the
global monitoring system if there is any
issue about the global monetary system
that will impact a lot yeah so like I
said the global monitor system first is
we can also replicate the global monitor
Carl Bo resource manager it's not a
global monitor and the other thing is we
actually saw the global management guess
all can reconstruct all its information
from contacting the individual resources
individual devices so they keep
fine-grained knowledge of resource
utilization and other things so the
global thing can be reconstructed and
that when it fails you can just go to
the find way which is a little bit
slower I'm also thinking about another
question may be very interesting so
think about I'm a developer I want to
improve this kind of system and I find
out that this bargain in my global
resource management and the impact of
this part could be see when one memory
slot or all name is slot I think it's a
potential impact of a small part you
know any component will be could be very
huge how do you think about that Wow and
so this first one I would also answer
the other security was so the what we do
is we
prate lien you can think of a Linux OS
into smaller pieces and each piece it's
mostly independent you can protect it on
its own you can develop and debug it
only a song so from this point of view
it's easier to to to protect you to make
it more more reliable and also the
global saying that I think any any
system that uses a global management
what happies would have similar issue
and we we actually reduce the amount of
dependency on this global management
just take one more question and so my
question is more about performance
prediction how is the dividing this
operating system into a lot of pieces
talking to each other through network
making the system is it more as it
becomes more unpredictable because now
the components speak with other
components through network which it
could be subject to noise that's a good
question so first is I want to say that
this is a big move and we are also
building our own network solution which
and there are others network solution to
research this equation but in terms of
all right what's your original classroom
predictability of the application given
that the network is noisy they predicted
I will say that like I said in the
beginning of the talk a lot of the
applications they already distributed
and this aggregated so I would say that
if you can manage this disagreed in
nature you know in the lower system like
OS you can manage this and predictably
and predictability better than if in the
current way that everything is just hold
is a created from the application point
of view
okay now that's sexist speaker
[Applause]