hello everyone I'm ninja man from Peking
University in China today I will talk
about our work new graph parallel deep
neural network computation and large
graphs they seojun's work with Microsoft
Research Asia deep neural networks have
achieved the processes in many areas
recently the area emerging training of
random neural diplomas and graphs known
as graph neural networks and they have
achieved a commencing model accuracy in
many real-world application applications
free demo it can learn features from the
user item graph for higher quality
recommendation genes aggregates
information following in the graph
structure specifically each voters are h
in the graph can be associated with a
set of data as its features so children
can consider multiple layers with the
authority of publication conducted a
layer by layer over the sink graph as I
said each layer the buttress our age
features are transformed and propagated
along edges and then aggregated as the
target vertices to produce new features
for the next layer traditional genes
have small and regular grade greatest
structures which is friendly to chip
jewels
however engines graphs are large sparse
and irregular we are to instability and
efficiency problem
there are many if not in systems like
conserve low for neural network
processing here is a simple example to
describe how if learning systems wrong
first with near several placeholders for
input data then with layers forward
computation logics ways operators deep
learning systems can automatically
generates the parallel computation
without word differentiation to compute
the gradients with this code we
construct a graph called the flow graph
as
intermediate representation in deep
learning training the data flow graph
abstraction easily price neural networks
and the affection for neural network
occlusion however is hard to impress
graph operations and handle large graphs
because it takes the whole graph at
attention without graph awareness most
recently tgl was deep learning systems
as graphic interfaces for teen
programming however it has a single
scalability and associated problems
because the patient works as euro
without her prefer wellness
there are also many craft engines for
last girl who are computing the problem
as an example describe how car engines
run first we define the keidel function
to describe how a vertex gets
information from its in neighbors then
the apply function used to update itself
ways gather the information fanime the
battle send messages to the output to
the out neighbors with the scatter
function the whole procedure is defined
in your bottles bill called butters
programming thus graph engines candle
each motors minor it is easy to use
graph models to program graph
applications like page rank and apply a
grant for organizations and skill to
very large graphs
however these systems are hard to
impress neural networks and an
instruction for neural network occlusion
due to the lake hub data flow
obstruction we propose new graph which
bridges graph and the data flow models
to learn wisdom and benefit from both -
supported fashion skill Bojan processing
it contains a second model for
programming applications trump a static
flow graph translation and streaming
processing auto imperial court to
support large graphs we also designed
highly optimized
operators of aqua publication and the
chin based parallel stream means
strategy for fashion the material
culture with these standings new graph
outperform state-of-the-art
implementations and smoke was 13 to TPO
memory and skills to large graphs with
trip use first let's talk about the
certain objection
there are four stages in stock first the
scheduler propagates information from
works to the age to prepare data for the
age transformation then the ages
recommends new network computation on
age to transform the H theta then the
transform the each data are gathered to
the destination vertex finally the apply
button represents the neural network
computation and robotics to transform
the approach from the can the from the
Kaiser stage those four stages the final
layout and users can define multiple
layers in second schedule and gather
work operations which are transparent to
users where her age and apply buttons
neural network operations where users
define neural network computation with
data flow hurried here is an example
describe how to my graph convolutional
network to occur in t-cell information
from neighbors much pride with the
scanner value underage so we implement
multiple operator in the apply age as
accumulator item to sum up neighbors
information then this in highly
connected the neural network on the
Balkans so we implement it in the apply
bottles the skoda represent a layer of
the cell and we can implement multiple
layers artisan by staking it layer by
layer in each layout ian the buttress
features and
from the previous layer used to compute
the new voters features however most
real-world graphs lunch and kind of it
cannot fit into GPU memory thanks to the
model in second we can leverage
competition to scale to large graphs new
graph carefully combines competition
wasted Pro to solve the scalability
problem India specifically will average
the truth equal partition the vertices
and edges are partitioned into trunks
for example to compute the new budget
Ronco federal cloud which contains
butters the arrow industry they need to
gather information from neighbor waters
1 & 3 in trunk in general and y1 0 then
we can precise the world trunk by trunk
in the limited Egyptian memory there is
a scheduling problem we can consume the
trunk row by row or column by column or
any other orders however we observe that
the intermediate data can be accumulated
in GPU memory to reduce host device
communication thus we take the column by
column scheduling policy with grand
partition
new cough translates the second program
to trunk base that inflow graph existing
as either example to compute the trunk
by the rocket we need to control a trunk
with video either 0 and trunk V 1 Y 1 0
with a column by column scheduling
policy we first calculate either 0 with
scatter of her age gather an object a
human of this trunk
specifically idea GT only has a
multiplier operation for sauce bottles
an age which cannot match prior operator
between scattering gather thus the sauce
bottle stator invaders are much more
with age
in a barrel and gathered to the water to
upload an app you
an interesting manner for trunk you and
arrow
after that the neighbors information had
been corrected as a destination but he
says then the robotics the function used
to transform the data and outputs the
way the robot and me one code can be
computed in a similar manner thus we get
a trump base that is a program for the
forward computation logics and the
backward computation can be generated by
Auto differentiation
okay next as graphs are your lunch we
would like to sketch into much more
cheap use for faster processing a naive
solution to that chip geotech a column
of a trunks and outputs the Rigveda
buttress trunk however the precise lines
are limited in modern servers so the
precise which is introduced to support
more tip shields in one server because
Egyptian will take other important
improve also trunks the redundant data
transfer through shared upper links
results in bandwidth bottleneck we have
served sites the links to the new
particles within the same pieces which
are empty and each GPO will load the
same data so we can let you directly
load data from its neighbor GPO well GPO
p2g communication which reduces the data
transfer on the shelter darlink
therefore we formulated to use within
the simplest ie switch either chain to
elaborate
Elgin processing here is an example
first the left the left of most GPO 0 &
2 in each piece I switch load trunk we
want from the host memory then GPO one
load transfer one from GPO Sderot and
cheapest way load transfer one from
- meanwhile GPRO and one low trunk way
to from the Xhosa memory then tip you
wanna delete the consumed tranquil
weather and Lauren big one from CPU
Darrow and to mean well cheerio dear on
to low trunk mystery from host memory
then the interviews to the same manner
for next runs this procedure describes
the team based parallel streaming much
modules finally let's talk about the
corner organization in new world
traditional graph algorithms like
Barranca
you only have scanners are vertices our
edges so conventions make point them
over vertices are edges we are in
different interactions and different
strides which you know in fashion for
GPU well turns your lay have regular
high dimension features are vertices are
edges so we appoint prism feature
dimension to achieve sing instructions
over strides which he fashioned to TPO
okay the evaluation we implemented a new
graph on top of principle and compare it
with tangible and DGL we also
implemented TF shaka a baseline without
any of transitions introduced before to
choose the sous-sous priority of our of
transitions we do impairment our server
equipment awaits a trip use which use
three typical gene applications on three
small and three large thin sites for
small parts fit into GPU memory because
of our kernel organizations new graph
achieves
up to phantoms speed-up over tensorflow
and up to nineteen pencils be up over t
GL also new graph gets higher speed up
for graphs with high intensity
for large graphs that cannot fit into
GPO tensorflow and the TGA out ran out
of memory on GPO
so we come here new graph with tons of
procedural version and TF zonka issues
that new graph achieved up to 47 times
speed up over Kiev simcha version and up
to 5 times over
chef Santa baseline we can also see that
the TF Sanka simcha version is faster
than Jeff Scipio because trunks in
Jeff's and Scipio contra concurrently on
Scipio and achieve a higher CPU
utilization finally we should the
scalability over multiple GPUs with an 8
without with we funded without stream
new graph gets no speed up for two GPUs
because of the Penguins bottleneck
increases which thanks to the chimp a
streaming strategy new graph can't get a
nearly linear scalability through new
graph were advocates unifying deep
learning and the computing for efficient
and scalable team processing new graph
represents critical step in the
structure by showing not only the face
ability but also the potential of such
unification this is accomplished by
defining the second model to apprise
genes and fusing graph out of
transitions such as repetition
scheduling and tourism into deep
learning frameworks and achieving
efficiency and scalability
engine training that's all thank you
questions comments I don't know if you
guys notice but we had a GPU paper a
disk paper a GPU paper and the last
papers in this paper so for what I just
sing great talk
so it's interesting to see that you
build this on tensorflow
right right do you know any of the
optimizations from graph processing GPU
world I know what possible because of
its processing model or its data
management or any of those some of the
optimizations which are already there in
existing GPU based growl okay I know I
know this right so well where the
difficulty is in porting them some of
them you couldn't put because tensorflow
was adding some limitation to it maybe
so I'm coming from graph processing
perspective that's why I'm trying to
understand this okay okay you said you
want to know the difference between the
other gpo based graph processing system
that appear and they saw these are
transitions sure yeah okay sure
so there are a lot higher GPO based
processing systems
Ranko Cuccia but if the most focus on
the traditional applications like
PageRank as a peer and when we have Xu
is before we have we have shown in the
previous slide that in those
applications the the data on the
vertices are edges are always scanner
values so they make poem over body
states are edges then they were achieve
some more some problems some problems
like try conflict but in Qi and the data
on the but voters are edges the high
dimension vector so we can make a poem
over the
dimension the future dimension to
achieve to achieve a piker performance
fight thank you other questions so
there's one aspect of cables question
that you didn't address which was you
built on top of tensorflow right what
would you change in tensorflow to make
your job easier and were you limited by
tensorflow
in any way all right first first of our
way to not change the change the code
the absence of row we implement some
operators as a cone organization graph
corners to these operators to tensorflow
but the earlier in the earlier
limitation in principle because when
it's precise tensors are operators a
need to load the whole tensor to GPU
ices a quantity very sparse domain load
a lot of useless data because the other
only some works are useful in it so to
to resolve this the problem we also did
a selective scheduling organization in
our paper
you