all right my name is Christopher Michael
John I'm going to talk about scaling the
distributed actor runtime with partisan
so distributed actors distributed actors
have been used on a lot of highly
scalable highly concurrent applications
they have tremendous industry success as
I discovered yesterday during the poster
session not many people know that these
programming languages even exist
so hopefully this talk will raise some
awareness about that I hope that in the
video just because okay all right
and so you distributed actors really
successful and you probably know some of
the applications that they've been used
on for tonight is pretty popular
application Gears of War for Halo these
are popular games League of Legends you
may have heard of and whatsapp I'm sure
a lot of you are probably using at this
very moment especially when my mic fell
off my lapel and so each of these actor
systems uses one of the three major
industrial-strength each of these
applications uses one of the three major
industrial-strength out there actor
systems so for tonight for instance uses
aqua cluster for the Scala programming
language Gears of War for use as
Microsoft or leans as does Halo and
League of Legends and whatsapp use the
Erlang programming language now part of
the success part of the reason that
distributed actor systems are so widely
adopted is because of this programming
model it's very simple so first I'm
going to explain this function
definition here so this is defining a
function called call it takes three
arguments a destination process ID a
message and a timeout period we use this
banks syntax here destination bank
message to send a message to a
destination process and we use this
receive primitive to wait for a response
and this will perform pattern matching
and finally with this after clause in
this timeout I'll wait a particular
amount of time for message then I'll
timeout and return an error to the user
so once I define functions then I use
this spawn primitive to instantiate
actors in the system so here I say I'd
like to create an actor
here's the function I'd like to call and
the actor will run that function to
completion and then terminate so this is
a nice programming model and it's really
really nice for building distributed
systems because you don't see networks
you don't see sockets you don't see
serialization you don't see desolation
you don't see any of the stuff that we
usually don't like writing when we're
writing distributed code and all of
these three actor systems whether it's
akka or liens or Erlang all of them have
the same programming model effectively
but slightly different because they have
different host languages so in this talk
we're going to look at how we can
improve distributed actor systems
considering their two limitations the
two limitations are scalability and
latency now in terms of scalability
we're going to increase scalability by
growing clusters to larger clusters of
nodes and in terms of latency what we're
going to attempt to do is use available
bandwidth to perform scheduling in
parallel to reduce latency and increase
overall system throughput now we're
going to achieve this with minimal
modifications to the programming model
we're gonna do this at the library level
which is really nice it's extensible we
don't have to ship a custom runtime we
don't have to ship a patch set for a
custom runtime we don't have to make our
own runtime so let's dive into the
limitations so the first limitation is
around scalability here I have a cluster
of three nodes each is running two
actors and these nodes are connected in
a full mesh topology using TCP and what
this means is when I add a fourth node
and I spawn two actors and stancy eight
two actors on this node I also have to
connect this to all the other all the
other machines in the cluster
now these assumptions around having to
connect all of the nodes together
because these systems have to transmit
metadata information they have to send
heartbeat messages to keep the system
operating because of this scalability is
limited we end up exhausting
communication and spending a lot of time
in serialization for messages that are
just for keeping the system running not
even considering the requests or
responses and this is evidenced by kind
of these two data points that we have
here art work focuses on Erlang so my
two data points here on Erlang but one
is that the only people who have been
able to run distributed Erlang at 200
notes is Ericsson the people who made
the language
and similarly the database that I used
to work on before I quit my job to do my
PhD that react is a dynamo inspired
Cassandra Lake database this database
only used to scale the 60 nodes so that
sound good for a distributed data
management platform surely now the
second limitation is around latency if I
consider a two cluster node to a two
node cluster and I connect these two
nodes and then I spawn like thousands of
actors on node 1 and thousands of actors
on node 2 what I need to do is use that
single TCP connection to multiplex
online communication for any actor to
any other actor on either side of the
cluster on either node and this results
you know in queuing delay this
head-of-line blocking that happens when
you have messages sending at different
rates and different sizes network
congestion issues we're running this in
geo distributed scenarios or you're
running it at large objects and finally
everybody's contending for access to
this socket and that doesn't work when
I'm mapping like a hundred thousand
actors into one TCP connection so how do
we solve this so the work that we're
going to talk about today is called
partisan it's a library that I've been
working on for at least two maybe more
years now it's a system that's designed
to remove assumptions around current
implementations that are made by
runtimes these full mesh assumptions
these single TCP assumptions as provided
in user space as a library so that it
can be extensible it can you know you
can use a debugger all this nice stuff
and can be leveraged immediately you can
use it in applications today and so the
key contributions of partisan are first
allowing the application developer to
specify the communication strategy the
communication overlay that's used at
runtime without changing application
code and the second is enabling parallel
transmission on the network so let's
look at the first contribution so the
first thing is around selecting the
overlay so like I said before we connect
all these things in this full mesh
everybody communicates with everybody
and the insight here is you know if we
want to change the communication
strategy we shouldn't let that be
evident in the programming model we
don't want that to come up and expose
itself in the programming model we want
to keep the programming model the same
we want to preserve these distinct
semantics and so here you know just to
reiterate the point we really want to
look at this does not changing anything
because we have a model it's really
successful that people are building
these great applications in so in
partisan today we we use we have this
full mesh topology this is the default
topology it's a simplest reason about it
operates really well when you have
smaller clusters and what happens is I
connect all my nodes completely and then
I use direct messaging to do
point-to-point messaging so my API is
point-to-point messaging we also provide
a second topology called client-server
this is a familiar hub-and-spoke kind of
model right servers talk to servers
clients talk to servers and what this
means is that clients do not directly
communicate with other clients and so
the programming model to remain
point-to-point we have to have servers
around messages on clients behaves so
that clients can still message one
another similarly the the the
peer-to-peer topology scales to massive
clusters ten thousand nodes twenty
thousand nodes and because of this every
node needs to only see kind of only
connect to a portion of the network
right and this means that you might not
even have a server to route messages on
behalf so we have to do is transitive
routing we have to have messages handed
off between peers to get to the final
destination
now the second set of optimizations will
look at is around application enabling
parallelism on the network we're gonna
break this down into two techniques so
the first technique is called named
channels and the way named channels work
is under the assumption that we have you
knows custom nodes with different actors
sending different types of messages so
some are request responses and some are
maintenance traffic for the cluster
maintenance itself right and so in the
react distributed database we have to
gossip or ring around we have to gossip
metadata we have to send failure
detection information and what we want
to do is we want to say get all that
stuff out of the request path unless
it's absolutely necessary put this on to
a different channel and let's pipeline
these requests on this single path now
we have to in Erlang we have to annotate
all the call sites with message types
this is unfortunate but this is because
Erlang really has no types you you don't
know what anything is everything is
basically just a term or a tupple or a
couple of terms and so we don't we can't
this at runtime automatically but in a
system like Scala we have a really rich
type system and a system you know in a
programming language like C sharp we can
do runtime reflection and by doing
runtime reflection we can do this
automatically and so key here take the
types and partition traffic on multiple
connections based on types now a special
case of that technique a special case of
named channels we can try to keep actors
connect are working on one connection
and we can do this by a finit izing the
traffic from multiple actors on two
connections based on their sender
identifier and based on their recipient
identifier or we can use a logical
identity if actors happen to take on
different roles over time which is
common in actor systems and so what this
does is it lets us kind of take
advantage of kind of pipelining
operations where we have these request
response patterns to a group of actors
such as in a distributed database so
let's see how all this stuff runs let's
run some experiments I'm going to talk
about three sets of experiments today
the first experiment I want to talk
about is a scenario that came from a
industrial partnership we had with Rovio
entertainment who makes Angry Birds this
is a advertisement counter I'll explain
it in a moment the second set of
experiments will look at is
point-to-point experiments for for
looking at roundtrip messaging kind of
round-trip performance and messaging so
these will be a set of micro benchmarks
to examine the impact of our techniques
on latency and how we can reduce latency
and then finally the last set of
benchmarks are based on the distributed
programming framework react core which
is an implementation of the Amazon
dynamo model in Erlang this is the
actual framework that's used in the
production react database that's
deployed at the NHS and all these other
places and we build two applications on
top of this so we build a simple echo
service so we're bound only by this to
be to the network and then we build a
little mini key value store distributed
database rights to three nodes waits for
a majority kind of like Cassandra
operates so let's talk about the Rovio
example so the romeo example is an
advertisement counter so if you consider
if you're playing Angry Birds
some of you might be playing Angry Birds
right now for all I know if you play
Angry Birds sometimes you'll see a net
and what we want to do is we want to
aggregate the ad counts we want to
aggregate the number of times ads have
been displayed to all of the users and
we want to turn the ad off when we've
shown a minimum level a lower bound so
at least 5,000 impressions now we're
going to do is we're going to replicate
this counter on everybody's device and
we're going to periodically synchronize
this counter and then we have this
threshold trigger when the ad is shown X
times so here's our three node cluster
we have two active we have an actor on
each node we increment the local counter
and then we propagate that counter to
the other nodes who merge it in and so
this keeps this counter moving forward
as its incremented locally and sent to
all the other replicas in the system now
we've run these experiments on ec2
they're not simulated we didn't use
Pearson and we're going to look at two
of our topologies client-server and
peer-to-peer we're going to use a fixed
number of increment operation x' and
this means that the amount of state that
we generate for every experiment is the
same but we're going to see the effect
on redundancy in the overlays and can be
different communication paths on the
amount of data we transfer so here we
have a graph on the y-axis we're
plotting data transmission to complete
the experiment in log scale on the
x-axis we have the cluster size from 32
up to 1024 the the the black bar
represents the client-server topology
and the gray bar represents the
peer-to-peer topology now what we see
here first is the data transmission
serves as a proxy for redundancy so in
the client-server one all the messages
are sent to each destination once
they're routed through the server so
that's kind of our lower bound the
minimum kind of data we have to transfer
but with a peer-to-peer topology we see
because there's redundant links people
might get the same message down multiple
links multiple times and so what we
observe here is that at these lower
cluster sizes these these less we're
done in overlays that are better for
smaller clusters they're more efficient
on the wire they send less data but as
we observe here the trend with
peer-to-peer is that the peer-to-peer
keeps scaling and we we had to stop our
experiments here because I had I had
spent quite a bit of the European
Union's money where I was doing this
work so we had to stop at 1024
but we could have kept going and so at
this 256 when we get to 512 we see the
server instance runs out of memory to
start addressing the clients actually
message queues in Erlang are unbounded
so when you send somebody a lot of
messages they've run out of memory and
then the UM killer kills the instance so
kind of the takeaway here is
peer-to-peer kind of got nice scaling
properties but it's a little bit more
expensive when we don't need it and then
the client server is really efficient on
the lower the lower end so latency
benchmarks we'll get right into them so
with the latency benchmarks what we're
gonna do is look at round-trip time for
sending individual messages on the wire
we're gonna simulate 20 milliseconds of
round-trip time latency to simulate
intra DC in the same region for Amazon
we have other experiments but I I found
this one interesting to show so this is
the one I picked we're gonna use a 512
kilobytes a load size and we're gonna
graph in red distributed Erlang in in
green partisan with only a single TCP
connection this will serve to show how
much penalty we pay by being in user
space and then in teal we're going to
see partisan without with some of our
optimizations and 16 connections and
then in purple we're going to see the
total optimal config so again just to
reiterate the things you want to be
paying attention to your two red
distributed Erlang that's the baseline
partisan that's the purple alright it's
the first thing we see when we see this
red to green is that the partisan
performance is competitive even with the
user space implementation so regardless
of you know not being in the kernel not
being written in C we remain competitive
we see that with the green bar we start
paying in term when we have a single
connection we're paying penalties for
context switching and user space but as
soon as we have finit i's connections
and take advantage of our optimizations
we can get a 13 point 5 X improvement
for 128 actors we have details in the
paper why we chose 16 connections now in
throughput the throughput experiments
are going to use a key value store and
an echo service that where we will issue
requests to to a normal distribution
over 10,000 nodes we'll look at how many
operations were able to perform per
second
and then in our key-value example what
we'll do as a fan out fan in Cassandra
like pattern and so here on the x-axis
we're varying the number of actors we
got throughput per second on the Y in
the red we're gonna have one kilobyte
payloads green is 512 and the bottom is
8 Meg if we focus in on 128 actors we
see that we're roughly the same when it
comes to does that count the mic part
like we see that we're roughly the same
performance when there's red and green
when we have 1 kilobyte and 512
kilobytes and then finally we get to
here with 8 megabytes we get a 2.8 for X
improvement alright so I'm basically out
of time but I want to show this last
graph because this is kind of the most
important graph here and so this is the
key value store this is the fan and fan
out problem fan and fan out pattern so
it's like Cassandra now what we observe
here if we focus in 128 is that we have
roughly the same performance when we're
dealing with one kilobyte objects now
when the object size starts increasing
here two we get a 1.5 X when we move to
512 K and then when we move to 8 Meg we
have 104 operations per second with the
partisan performance but distributed
Erlang stupid completely collapses and
we only complete a single experiment for
the duration of the of the execution now
this is an interesting result because
react operators anecdotally we're told
in the documentation it's still online
you can go look at it too don't store
objects in this database that are
greater than 1 Meg because you'll kill
the throughput of the system you'll
actually crash the performance because
like network carrier will collapse all
right so to conclude distributed actor
systems here have typically been limited
by implementation assumptions they have
not been limited by the programming
model as we saw it's just sending
messages most of these design decisions
were made in the early 90s when we were
deploying to single data centers and we
believe that our work designs and design
fills a need for improved large-scale
actor runtimes now we believe this to be
true because previously react
implemented their own transport for
large objects and geo distribution
they're considering partisan as a
replacement in react CS this was
software that was developed to store
large objects under the s3 API
did one megabyte chunking so an engineer
spent a long time building one megabyte
chunking because of a problem in the run
time and then finally we there's two new
applications I'd like to mention that
have been built on partisan barrel DB
uses our parallelism optimizations and
our overlay for providing a large-scale
peer-to-peer replicated database this is
built by developer former developers of
couchdb and then Bondi is a RPC
transport layer for hundreds of micro
services that is been running in
production for 18 months using partisan
so to conclude we believe that our work
enables new types of applications built
using distributed actors and you know I
think we've shown evidence that you can
do large objects and you can do geo just
distributed applications and we also
believe that we paved the way to start
using actors where they haven't been
seen before maybe client-server
applications maybe mobile devices who
knows and so thank you for coming to my
talk if it was your first time thanks
for it and if it was your second special
thanks for it hi do we get to ask
questions so so i'm eric ID from the
university of utah this is I think
really great work very interesting work
so so it seems that partisan is like a
win in every dimension so it should just
go into airline tomorrow so so why won't
it go into airline so that's a great
that's a really great question so there
are there are a couple things going on
there so first first since we didn't
have runtime support we we don't support
sending closures now this is an
interesting thing because I don't
believe there's anything stopping us
from doing it but we're also a little
dogmatic about it because we think it's
really bad to send the reference to the
number of a closure in some source file
that the remote mode might not even have
loaded or have a different version
loaded so that's a functions or a
problem another one is is around
there's references we actually no
references are fine there was one more
around some of the failure detector
behavior so the failure detector
basically counts
it sends heartbeat messages and it waits
for like a heartbeat interval to elapse
like oh I missed so many heartbeats I'll
consider all of the remote actors dead
and so this is you this heart beat this
failure detector is used to build links
and monitors and so people like doing
this cross node and so it's really
difficult to do this efficiently with
the peer-to-peer Oh overlay because it
kind of assumes that I I have if I need
to know that some actor on that remote
node is alive then I need to maintain a
connection to it so I can I can tell
that right and so the this existing
semantics of Erlang would not be able to
be mapped into this immediately until we
had a good solution one solution is to
transitively find out if somebody is
alive but then that makes the failure
detection interval really long so maybe
the failure detector is less useful
there so these have been kind of these
have been like the big things these kind
of two features that we don't we don't
really know how to handle just yet so
yeah so that's kind of kind of the
blocking stuff with with with OTP inner
thank you yep or the beam rather one
quick question I just had a quick
question about actor migration it seems
like actor migration is made more
complicated with partisan because all of
a sudden you don't have this full mesh
topology so which which actor migration
if I wanted to my game I agreed an actor
from one host to another yeah so I mean
in Orleans so the Orleans solution there
is you know to to kind of coordinate via
cloud storage right so I say like I'm
gonna terminate my actor on no day and
I'll store the state and durable cloud
storage that's addressable by anybody
and then I can kind of rehydrate that
actor on another node based on that
cloud storage so I think that's the
right model and I don't think that
anything about our model would prohibit
that model from working and I think
that's a proven model that's been used
on Halo and all this stuff we're
actually doing this stuff at scale so I
think that's the right model for
migration Thank You Christopher
Thanks
you