I'll be presenting our study of the
design and operation of cloud lab like I
mentioned the lightning talk this is the
study run by the same group of people
who designed it built it and operated
what is cloud lab again back to the set
in the context it's a testbed for it's a
distributed testbed for research in
cloud computing and distributed systems
the hardware is deployed across three
sites University of Utah University of
Wisconsin and Clemson University and the
experiments run on physical machines
physical Hardware as opposed to virtual
machines here there are over 4,000 users
using the testbed from different US
institutions and overall it's a plate
it's a place where experimenters use the
hardware to build the software
environments of their choice whether
it's cloud computing or any other flavor
of distributed computing and the way we
like to look at it as a laboratory or
facility to study in those types of
systems rather than an individual system
of that type back to the map of the
hardware resources each site in cloud
lab has its own focus and set of
features it provides yeah it's got
unique set of hardware available overall
there are 19 different Hardware types
available and you can learn more about
them if you go to cloud lab us there's a
hardware page with all the hardware
specifications so cloud lab was built to
support cloud computing and distributed
systems research and it's an interesting
topic to see how that mission translates
into published work and here we looked
at recently published papers we did a
survey of almost hundred papers and we
see that research on networking and
security aspects of these systems add up
almost to 50 percent of the research use
of cloud lab and in this long tail
distribution we see that users use
low-level access to the hardware they
will
for specific features the hardware
provides and also they take advantage of
the strong isolation performance
isolation here's why we study cloud lab
we would like to better understand how
well it serves the needs of the research
community we like to would like to
analyze the impact of the design and
implementation decisions and reveal the
associated trade-offs but would also
like to generalize the lessons that we
learn and make them relevant to the
design of other test beds and
infrastructure of the service facilities
a couple of examples here showing what
kind of research requests the facility
can serve so one user can ask for
several servers immediately another
person can come in and ask for machines
of certain with certain features there
are some requests with specific
networking requirements and also more on
the demanding side user can come in and
ask for a large set of machines when
they become available and cloud lab
tries to meet these fulfill these needs
in terms of scale time and features it
also tries to guide users to to help
them choose feasible configurations for
their experiments and also if something
goes wrong the facility needs to provide
meaningful and actionable feedback in
this study we question these question
these goals in trying to understand like
weather cloud lab fulfills these goals
or not how it can accomplish them and
also try to generalize the lessons that
we learn in this analysis we just saw
this list with which is sort of the user
perspective and in this study we dive
into analysis of these components that
are responsible for helping with these
goals we have reservation system have
constrained system and we have error
reporting system
all right we're going to look at the
reservation system and to better set the
context for this analysis is we need to
go back and look at the historic data
this is sort of the measure before you
build reference to Ramsey's key node so
what can we learn from the historic
usage data we've captured a number of
metrics related to the growth and usage
of the facility we have number of we
have the number of servers growing over
time we have an increasing user activity
represented by the number of active
users every month we have a growing
number of projects and we also have the
node hours going up where node hours
captures how active how busy the
facility is and overall we can summarize
here that we have so far we have not
found a limit to this demand all right
we're going to go one level deeper here
and look at this this second question is
there enough hardware for everyone so we
started this analysis by looking at
individual time plots time series plots
for different Hardware types and we
started with this highly volatile plot
on the left and we sort of derive this
more interpretable in kind of more
interesting curve on the right and
that's the number percent of the time
available as a function of percent of
the notes we're in the left top corner
we have one machine that is available
almost hundred percent of the time in
the right bottom corner we have the
opposite hundred machines are almost 100
percent of the machines aren't almost
never available and we have a nice curve
between the two plots we repeat this for
different Hardware types and we get this
nice spectrum of different availability
curves one of these points here indicate
that for this particular hardware type
200 machines are available 80% of the
time and that's that's really nice that
that allows for large experiments on the
other hand for the hardware time
hardware type that is
used we only can get 50% 50 machines for
30% of the time and that's not so great
but that's still it's still reasonable
but for this case we would like to
really use reservations so those users
who are interested in the features that
that hardware provides they should
submit their reservation requests and
here I have a slide really just one
slide described in the design of the
reservation system so it all starts
but these requests follow in a
particular format where a user needs to
specify how many machines he or she
needs the specific type in the interval
of time when the hardware is going to be
used so the accounting on the cloud lab
side is done per project and on the per
hardware basis these requests are
subject to validation checks where users
can check if it's feasible or not
according to the current schedule before
they commit to one of these and also
this is the the reservation system is
built in a way that it so the
experiments are not launched
automatically according to these
reservations it's up to the users to
come in again at that time and launch
their experiments so this can be
compared to hotel reservation system
where Hotel doesn't check you in in the
room when you give them a call and ask
for a room it happens when you arrive at
the hotel same thing here user submits
an advance reservation plans the usage
and then at the time when the time comes
then he or she launches the experiments
so how well does this work in practice
so this reservation system came into
production in at the end of 2017 and
we've been gathering information about
its usage so we can do immediately is
look at the sizes and durations of
experiments compared to the sizes and
durations of approved reservations this
plot at the bottom so something about
reasoning here relates to Ramsey's talk
again it's
about careful measurement and careful
reasoning for these types of
distributions we can't just compare
averages we need to look deeper and
compare certain percentiles because
these are long tailed distributions for
both of the dimensions so we do that in
the paper and we look at things like
medians and 95th percentile so we can
see quite difference between the 95th
percentile for experiments and 95th
percentile for reservations with respect
to the duration same happens for the
number of notes and other percentiles
we've analyzed and here's our summary
for that reservations allow users to run
longer and larger experiments that's
what our analysis confirms we'll also
look at the time line when the active
when the reservation system is very
active when it's mostly used in the
increased activity there aligns well
with the overall high utilization of the
testbed which which which makes sense
it's a very intuitive summary when the
hardware is busy people sort of
participated in the competition for the
resources and they can they can address
it by using the reservation system this
slide here
talk kind of gives us information about
reservations allowing users to meet
their deadlines and the spikes here
correspond to increased activity around
conference deadlines in the spring and
in the fall
all right we're switching gears here
we'll talk about errors and for this
discussion it's important to note that
errors come from the resource mapping
face of the process it's a complex
process where there are a lot of
potential scenarios and outcomes and the
system needs to be clear about what's
going on and communicated to the users
generally speaking resource mapping can
be solved through one of these
approaches so general algorithm would
make very few assumptions about the
facility and really solve this problem
as a constraint satisfaction and
optimization problem on more specialized
and we can design a more custom and more
tailored solution that has more
knowledge about the facility and can be
very particular about its process and
its outcomes so cloud lab takes a hybrid
approach where there's a general part
and more specialized part so the general
part is is what solves the simulated
annealing problem for solving graph is a
morphism problem and on top of that
serve as a wrapper we have a set of
deterministic heuristics that help
improve the feedback so this is what
comes out of this process these are the
errors that weave the system recorded
and we've analyzed we have top ten
errors produced by cloud lab and their
frequencies on the right and the column
called helpful is really just our own
assessment of whether they were helpful
and actionable or not and even though
there's some room for improvement mostly
this error messages are are poor or
helpful we summarized it here with the
following statement so we've identified
the common error scenarios and address
them through the custom heuristics these
numbers add up to about 86 percent of
the last year's errors that we found
interpretable and actionable
all right we're switching gears again
and now looking at the constraint system
and there's the main question here is
that do constraints help avoid some of
those errors so it's it it's good to set
the context here with an analogy we can
compare constraints against the error
reporting system where one is similar to
the feedback that you get from an IDE
and the report system error reporting
system can be compared to the feedback
that you get from the compiler in one
case you get like faster more
interactive feedback before you put in a
lot of work and then once once that's
done you can compile it or
in the case of cloud lab you push the
button and launch the instantiate the
experiment in that case you get more
definitive more concrete feedback but
you as a user obviously benefit from the
orderly feedback as well and that's what
the constraint system provides so behind
the scenes there is the valuation
procedure built around the boolean
product of sums I'm not going to go into
details here you can check it out in the
paper I'll just mention the context in
which it's used so the constraints are
like show up in two places it's an
interactive topology design and cluster
selection those are steps in the
instantiation of your when you
instantiate your experiment on cloud lab
and we summarized here that the
constraint system running as a
lightweight system in front of the
complex and heavyweight mapper procedure
improves user experience and helps avoid
some of those errors in conclusion I'll
just mention that we in this study
analyzed three components in cloud labs
control framework the reservation system
the constraint system and error
reporting system and we have for each of
these components we have findings and
analysis that we present in the paper
one more conclusion slide here so for
cloud lab that take that runs
reservation system constraint system and
error reporting system we we see that
the testbed satisfies diverse research
needs helps researchers find feasible
configurations and provides helpful
feedback and the paper presents the data
and analysis that back this statement
the data in the code that we worked with
are available at this URL you can see
from the numbers that it's quite a bit
of cloud labs history and what's
interesting about this repo is that
through the binder integration we made
it so that you can not only see the the
code but you can also run it with
minimal effort
more about cloud lab so this is my last
slide go to cloud lab dad you yes and
you can sign up for an account if you
haven't done so already and if you want
to learn more about it
join our birds of a feather session at
7:30 tonight and that's all I've got
thank you for your attention few
questions from University of Washington
just curious how do you to promise
isolation in cloud lab especially in
networking
Palomas oscillations are there any
interesting observations right right so
there number always to look at that one
would be two so cloud lab offers a set
of programmable switches so you can get
your own machines connected to a
programmable switch and then you control
how it runs you control the software and
you know what what's what
what goes through that switch so that's
one of the strongest examples of that i
mean i'll mentioning it i guess so
on the hardware so on the machine side
you also don't get other users you know
you don't see other users using the same
machines at the same time when you have
an experiment running on a machine
that's that's only you so it's
explicitly assigned to your experiment
hi great doc i I had a question about
reservations how so in case there are
multiple reservations for the same kind
of hardware and the quantity how is this
race condition result when there are
multiple reservations that are seeking
same kind of hardware at the same time
span
all right so there's a kind of overall
schedule for that hardware type right
and so when a reservation comes in the
details of the reservation that checked
against that schedule if it goes through
its accepted and kind of in the schedule
updated when another reservation comes
in then it in might not fit in and I
will be rejected first-come first-serve
basis
for the reservations yes and not so if
you get multiple requests for an empty
like unassigned hardware at the same
time how do you decide which one to
which request would you assign based on
the time stamp I mean yeah in practice
that will never be exactly simultaneous
right so though they'll have some
difference in time and also it depends
on the class or size of reservation
small reservations will be granted
automatically if if possible and longer
ones will be reviewed by the admins and
that's how the conflicts can be resolved
thank you so much I one more question
Thomas from tubing so what type of
metrics does your platform provide for
experiment run so what type of metrics
are are people who run experiments
interested in is like energy consumption
or network traffic so you can you can
collect and so measure and collect all
that yourself so we're on we don't
really do you I have to do that myself
right we capture some lightweight like
CPU utilization metrics but that's
mostly for different reasons for
understanding if the experiment is
active or not and we can ask people to
release the resources if the ulation is
low but it's really up to you - yeah
like dive deep and capture all the
interesting metrics okay that's time
call speak again
[Applause]