good afternoon everybody today I'm gonna
introduce an exotic kernel called chess
kernel bridging monolithic kernel -
peripheral course this is a joint work
between strong guy for each how and my
adviser Felix link from Purdue ECE once
in the summary what is transcranial it
is a novel OS model that runs unmodified
monolithic kernel binary on a micro
controller like a core of a
heterogeneous SOC it features a novel
combination of two key techniques
dynamic binary solution and kernel
service emulation to motivate this work
a little we first introduced ephemeral
tasks in smart things and here we refer
those markings to be smartwatches smart
speakers and other IOT devices if
thermal tasks they are prevalent among
these smart things they could push
notifications periodically sensor data
logging etc to execute such an ephemeral
tasks the kernel has to go through a
phase called device has been resumed
where the kernel wakes up all your i/o
devices for you some graphics controller
your MMC controller and then it can ask
you the task after that it will put all
the i/o device devices back to sleep
that is suspect however these different
tasks are energy-hungry shown by price
study they consume 30 percent or even
more higher energy in these smart things
we find that devices memory zoom is the
key button neck
why is devices memory room so efficient
in efficient the first reason is that
the i/o devices
takes time to do power state transition
and as a result the CPU is kept waiting
and the second reason is that the
complex device dependencies it prevents
the process for further organization as
such a procedure mismatches CPU and our
proposal is to round Sussman resume on a
peripheral core what is a peripheral
core you may wonder just look at the dye
photo you may easily notice that large
areas are occupied by CPU and GPU
however there is oh this little guy
shown here is our perfect what we're
talking about
it is a microcontroller core and it's
much wimpier however it delivers lower
idle power and with higher PC execution
energy on this heater geniuses SOC
are
CPU and our peripheral core there are
asymmetric processors this year Hitler
genius however similar Isis the ISIS
from the same family however with
different profiles also the CPU and
peripheral core they are loosely coupled
they can be turned on and off
independently they shared the platform
resources including I accuse and direct
we find that many of C's feed our
hardware model back in 2010 we had OMAP
4460 which is equipped with peripheral
core m3 + the CPU a nine and at prison
time will have address fear which is
Microsoft's IOT reference platform
equipped with the peripheral core m4 and
the CPU 87 so here's a problem now we
have a hitter genius SOC which has the
CPU and the peripheral core we're
running a commodity monolithic kernel
Linux for our own sin and we want to
offload the devices been resumed to the
peripheral core because we want to keep
the CPU asleep as much as possible
resulting in the following workflow
where the device super-sperm resume is
purely running on the diff peripheral
core and the user task is still executed
by the CPU so what are the approaches
one we want to use a multi kernel right
you can write both kernels from scratch
man colonel and the perfect kernel where
the preffer kernel only runs devices
permission code these two kernels
communicate through a message passing
fashion without sharing any states
however you lose compatibility with the
Linux look how sad the penguin is and
also you may it's not easy for you to
reuse the Linux kernel driver which is
diverse and mature the other approach is
you code transplant the existing devices
burn resume code the Fonda Linux kernel
and static compile it to run on the
perform these two kernels share the same
single instance of current state however
this also has a problem because the
suspend resume code is not self
contained at all instead they are
dependent on a complex
stack of kernel software including
driver Carol traffic library code and a
current library code and this code are
stacked on the interfaces which is known
to be unstable
the third approach is a little bit crazy
which is you run a full virtuix acute
another peripheral core the simple you
can implement a light weight virtue as
secured on the peripheral core for
example a DBT because the the provoker
lags hardware support for virtualization
you are facing a 25 X overhead if you
just port that qumu for example the DBT
to the perfect core and run it and why I
should also consider that the peripheral
core is much more wimpier than the CPU
and runs on a slower clock speed so that
this result no energy benefit at all
instead our approach called trans kernel
the goal is to ink offload that in
efficient devices memory encode of Linux
kernel run it on the peripheral core
however with an affordable overhead and
thus achieving energy efficiency the
approach is that the peripheral core
dynamically translates the kernel binary
and executes it however underneath it's
supported by a small set of a militia
Colonel services by email here the
kernel services women a small set of
functional equivalent services that's
required on the code suspend resume
called path we will explain these
services later
let's pull transfer toe in the OS design
space compared to multi kernels
behravesh m3 where you write kernels
from scratch you share lose
compatibility with nascaro however we
have compatibility with the main
external compared with k2 popcorn which
span a monolithic kernel to
heterogeneous course we actually don't
have to reason about the interface
problem and compared with the DBT for
example qumu we have a much more lower
overhead Transco follows the following
four principles first translate state
for code emulate the stateless code by
stateful code women the offloaded code
that must share states with the kernel
and a stateless code does not and for
example we translates the que malloc
function because we want to maintain a
single instance between the CPU and the
prep record however we choose to email
it as scheduling services thus the
peripheral core has this
copy of a scheduler which does not share
a state with a current with a min
colonel
the second principle is to identify a
narrow translation emulation interfaces
this is the interface whether translated
colonel translated code makes down call
to the emulated code requesting colonel
services for example scheduler services
and the spring-locks
by doing this will make the maintenance
of those emulator services much easier
because you don't have to change your
emulator services every time when
colonel changes the third principle is
to specialized for hot paths
we are observed that for 99 percent of
the execution device has been resumed
follows a comma beaten path which is
this no error and it will get all the
resources it requested these are the hot
paths that we talked about when we
specialized for them in case we go off
the hall pass we can migrate back to the
CPU to continue execution and this
simplifies our DB teaming Foundation and
also make the engineering efforts
tractable the fourth principle is to
exploit the ISIS similarity between the
CPU and the peripheral core and here the
ISO second origin means the same set of
general purpose registers the identical
usage of control-flow register as well
as the conditional flag semantics this
reduces in the immediate instructions
for DBT and it is key to the low
overhead we introduce arc and ARM based
in trans journal implementation and
Platt for an OMAP 4460 equipped with the
peripheral core n3 plus the CPU ni here
is the software stack you can see
running on the prep work or where the
Linux kernel is taking aim and
translated by our course I saw from VC
m8 to ves mmm DBT
end up with in the box are the full
colonel services that will be translated
they are stateful
because we want to maintain the single
instance with the kernel the included
driver specific code driver library
kernal library
irq handler and deferred work which is
the bottom half of the irq Hendra
underneath are the analytic kernel
services we provide they communicate the
way the translated code is - there is a
stable interface
this emulate services only have small
number 12 functions plus one variables
arc reports the commute to the
peripheral core to implement the cross I
so DBT and we are able to derive the
translation rule from the formal
specification we found that out of 558
on v7a instructions there exist 447 that
can be directly translated to a single
v7m instruction which is shown in the
screen part for others in the orange and
red part they are we have to emit
additional one to four instructions to
emulate and our DBT engine is able to
correctly execute over 200 million
instructions through our benchmark we
verified us that by dominic dynamically
comparing the execution results with the
native kernel and also statically
examining its kernels translated code so
in evaluation we want to answer the SARC
incur low overhead does arc incur
tractable engineer efforts and desert
does arc actually yelled at in the
energy benefit and it will run the
benchmark as follows we use a user space
test script to run the hosts perm resume
pass which will invoke nine diverse
drivers and will record their execution
time cycle counts of the crucible and in
peripheral core as well as the energy
let's first look at the DBT overhead
from the figure which we separate the
suspend and resume DBT overhead the
x-axis stands for the diverse benchmark
drivers the we we used in the benchmark
and that the y-axis stands for the
overhead where the overhead is a ratio
cycle comércio between the peripheral
core Intel CPU as we can see without any
optimization where is the baseline Q it
exhibits up to 25 X overhead however
with arcs low overhead DVD were able to
bridge that gap to a 2.7 X all across
the benchmarks we show that our kriyas
as Linux with low efforts with 10k
implementation which is one-time efforts
we're able to transparently reuse 40k
lines of kernel driver code
in our evaluation only and conceptually
more drivers can also be reused we show
that our maintains good compatibility
with multiple versions and
configurations of Linux we support from
version 3.6 Singh and obtuse kernel
version 3 4.20 so the Linux penguin is
happy now let's look at the end of
end-to-end execution time and the end
actual energy benefits let's look at the
execution time first from the top to
bottom we run the native execution which
is suspend resume on the CPU only and
the arc and then baseline queue as you
can see indeed I could prolong prolonged
the execution time this is because the
way around the DBT has its own overhead
and that the peripheral core runs much
slower than the CPU let's look at the
energy in fact arc indeed saves energy
resulting in a 34% of energy saving
where does this energy come from you may
wonder this is because arc runs on the
peripheral core which which has some
much lower PC execution energy as well
as a negligible idle power as you can
see in the orange part and a green part
which is completely shortened or removed
in the arcs energy consumption however
there is one thing interesting in our
experimentation is that arc incurs
higher different energy and we conclude
that is because the prep work or only
has a small size of a class level cache
which is 32 kilobyte and the thrashing
of the small level smallest last level
cache causes the Heidi rain traffic
which ultimately results in the high
energy we conduct a what-if analysis
because the energy saving is majorly
impacted by two factors the db2 overhead
which is the x-axis you see and the
kernel execution behavior which is the
percent of time spent in the native
execution in the busy execution which is
the y-axis and the red zone is is the
part that we actually wasted energy and
the green zone is a part we can save the
energy without any help the optimization
out simple baseline straightforward port
of the DB T can actually waste the 3x
more energy than the
of execution however with our DBT
optimization and arc were able to push
all the way to the green zone ultimately
resulting in a 34 percent of energy
saving this is made only made possible
by our low overhead DBT so to conclude
sound takeaway messages arc and trans
kernel is a novel OS moto it features
two key techniques dynamic minor
sensation and identifying appropriate
translation versus emulation boundary in
a monolithic kernel chill operating
system we contribute a new model to span
a monolithic kernel across heterogeneous
course to DBT we'll show that while the
cross-ice at DBT is under the assumption
of efficiency loss it can enable
efficient thinking even on the on the
off-the-shelf hardware and also we show
that DBT can be applied to translate a
specific path of a very complex software
stack to architects we advocate of
heterogeneous SOC design that is
friendly to change kernel we advocate
the equal rights for the peripheral core
which shares irq DRM with the CPU and
has the right size of less of cache and
that concludes my talk I would like to
take any questions
[Applause]
nice work I have a couple of questions
so you exploit the is a similarity as I
mentioned on the slides
how does it work on a truly
heterogeneous core say for example armed
plus say a risk five that is very good
question
so the Isis similarity we we we exploit
it here is based on the assumption that
they are actually from the same
eisah family however with different
profile that is assumption that we think
made by the architect so they choose to
implement the same the different profile
that has simpler semantics so that they
can have energy saving in terms of
cross-ice are really like a crossed
family like from xxd says to arm that
will have a consumer presumably higher
overhead and we have a discussion in
translating arm v78 to reason we we 8287
in the paper so you can check it out to
see how our can apply in this scenario
thank you one more question so so you
said like if there's a failure case you
hand it off back to the CPU all right so
I'm not sure if I've missed it so do you
turn off the main core yes we're handing
off yes so if there is a hand off back
again so you wake up the CPU core right
yeah so do you measure in this corner
case like how much energy do you consume
more energy in this case or less energy
in total that is a great question so the
work flow of work works like this first
the CPU of the CPU the kernel main
colonel wishes all but one CPU then he
handles control over to our perfect core
then he shuts down the last viewed and
our key will finish all the system
resume work and in case of emergency we
will fall back to the main CPU by
sending an IP I and then also we will
chanced will also migrate the stack
running on the preferable or back to the
kernel stack and on the main kernel to
continue execution so the implementation
detail is also in the paper and the way
do not measure the energy but all but we
measure indeed measure the time to wake
up the CPU it takes around 20
microseconds so it's pretty fast all
right thank you speaker again
you
[Applause]