all right good morning or close this
session we we got the internet defense
price
use an executor for a comprehensive
evaluation of third party cookie
policies the focus of this talk is on
the on the web browser and its
extensions and to which extent the web
browser is typically implementing the
policies let's say as promised we all
know that there are in the web
environment a lot of security challenges
and a major one is caused by the sharing
of cookies historically the the web
protocol HTTP that was the driver of the
big success of the World Wide Web is
stateless and of course application
builders had from the very beginning to
invent and create a technique to share
state and the somewhat funny name cookie
emerge from that the cookie is basically
state shared between a client on the one
hand and the website that your that your
service by on the other hand however a
web page in its own right is it's a
composite of many ingredients very often
generated by third party so the simple
example that you see on the slide is
that a domain a includes an image from a
domain B and cookies that are basically
representing the state of the of the
browser session between domain a and the
client are automatically or by default
shared with the domain B and that allows
domain B to abuse eventually
authentication tokens as one principle
example or just leverage on information
that leaks from the clients to that
domain B and that leads to undesirable
ads tracking privacy breaches and so on
it's it's a well-known problem I'm sure
so that's where we come from and it
leads to two major problems as I already
indicated here there are let's say
severe security problems on the one hand
and and maybe also severe privacy
problems on the other hand and the most
common example of that is the cross-site
request forgery where an attacker can
perform authenticated actions with the
account of the victim
let's assume a very friendly website
being visited this leaves
authentication tokens and relevant
information in the state somebody in
hacks that site and inputs malicious
code that is downloaded with for example
an image or a serviced page and that
allows that image would allow the
attacker to force the victim to use that
information to do an undesirable
transaction on a bank this is the
pedagogical start to say that what is
this all about now some of you may say
cross-site request forgery is not so
much a big issue we know it has been for
a long time and many big events have
occurred it has been in the OS top-10
for a long time it is getting out of
that picture for many reasons I'm sure
bug bounty hunters have revealed enough
problems to the website developers that
that's sort of the awareness and the
how-to on how to secure the the code at
the server side is a it is an improving
skill and that's a great thing but on
the other hand it would be much more
powerful to make sure that from a client
perspective the leaking of these cookies
is blocked and that the quality of the
server that you visit is definitely not
the cause or the or the only reason why
you would be secured so in from that
respect cross-site request forgery still
is a problem because you have to
advocate easily apply best practices on
the server side while you could maybe
have just a default security
implementation on the on the client side
on the browser side in order to deal
with the latter same side cookie has
been introduced which delivers your
security by default what is the same
side cookie it's a cookie with an
additional attribute called same side no
surprise and it would label that cookie
as one that cannot be shared at all with
any other webpage apart from the one it
was serviced from and that would be the
strict option or it could be a relaxed a
little bit where you have top-level
domains sharing it via get nope no post
obviously or pre-read
during facility so that is a sort of an
intermediate version that really
restricts the sharing of the cookies and
these type of evolutions are what we
call third-party cookie policies that
are proposed as a standard and
subsequently adopted by browser vendors
to make sure that that client-side
security quality gets better and better
so the same site lacks option for
example would be as of version 76 the
default in google chrome it takes a
while to adapt that's what we say here
in practice if you look at the example
again a victim could go to the bank get
cookies but the same site cookie policy
attribute would then not allow cute
kittens in this example to take
advantage of that information and
subsequently it would not be possible to
do have that malicious behavior I
mentioned here cross-site request
forgery as as a sort of a pedagogical
example we have cross-eyed code
injection
we have timing attacks in the browser
they all there's a broader range of
attacks that should not be explained in
depth here that all leverage on that
potential problem this is a big problem
many cases have been have been reported
in the public with big financial losses
and impact that's the security bit the
privacy bit it's clear that independent
of heavy weight attacks with significant
financial losses in these days I don't
have to tell you that trackers is a huge
activity there are recent studies for
example here showing that almost all
pages visited contained third-party
requests to trackers this is a corn kind
of a default we are dealing with so
there are good reasons to to improve the
posture on the client side to deal with
that client-side cookie policies in the
broad sense have to defend against these
problems and they're very often a built
in browser option just to block
third-party cookies for example most
browsers have that option support for
the new
proposal of same size cookies as I
introduced to you specific browsers have
additional element and Firefox for
example with this tracking prediction
opera with the ad blocker Safari with
intelligent tracking prevention and so
on so there is a knowledge on the site
of the browser producers obviously to
deal with that and and this shows that
in addition there is an API that allows
other parties to build extensions and we
have ad blockers and privacy protection
extensions a numerous amount of them
that can be installed in the context of
your browser to hopefully potentially
enhance your security posture the
question now is and we come back to the
opening of the talk is the browser
correctly enforcing the claims that
these browser based standards are
stating and/or the promises of the
extension builders are they fulfilled in
practice that was the question we
started from and we had two years ago a
master student evaluating a couple of
setups and that was like like not really
encouraging we saw quite some problems
and and the next step beyond that was
let's try to systematically evaluate
that for all browsers for a broad range
of extensions and see to which extent we
are dealing with it with the severe
problem or not is it easy for a browser
builder to to deal with that
well one illustration if you think of
Firefox you might say what is a web
security talk doing in a systems
conference well in terms of complexity
thirty-six million lines of codes in
2018 in Firefox and and I'm this is
probably the most public case and and
therefore easy to retrieve is huge the
complexity of systems is comparable we
can have a philosophical debate about it
but we talk about the huge complexity
and the question is can we in such a
complex piece of software can anyone
easily intercept all the requests and
strip third party cookies from a request
where are the requests generated in that
huge codebase this is not unique to fire
folks if you think about the number of
options supported then you see that
they're all competing and if you look at
the announcements that the edge with the
lowest number of features will will
definitely grow if you look at the
release notes of their future versions
so we have to evaluate that browsers do
not necessarily implement the standards
accurately there are with all these
features interactions between features
that call side effects that actually
still enable the leaking that's a
potential risks and we know that
extensions have been bypassed in the in
the past for example through WebSockets
it was a very well known and published
case so that's the motivation and a
little bit of the pedagogical intro in
case you might benefit from that why we
did this and why this is a non-trivial
case we had the indications but but
there is some rationale as I I try to
sketch to you so let me give you an
Outlook on on the on the result the
standard browsers didn't make it and all
of the exchanges was not by possible so
there was actually no no no good example
this is interesting because we don't
have to say there's a good and a bad one
we were able to bypass all these
vehicles in an experiment that we
finished in June last year there has
been after the publication of the paper
in August 2000 18 we have done an extra
run because you wonder what happens then
you responsible disclosure you share
that information with all the vendors
and they pick it up or they don't pick
it up but it's not so easy for them in a
release plan with the number of features
I was referring to deseo let's let's
reengineering or that because these are
not always minor issues they may have
design flaws at the base which you
cannot quickly incorporate in your
ongoing release plan so that is a delay
in picking it up and we we noticed that
because we we didn't
additional evaluation in in the fall of
2019 and that has been published in the
I Triple E security and privacy magazine
as a sort of an extended version of the
of the using acuity paper and the
situation has evolved but very gradually
and I'm not blaming anyone in particular
for that as as I made clear so what is
the core work that we have did we had a
testing framework to be developed to do
that kind of massive evaluation at large
scale and with the idea to repetitively
do that to have also launched
longitudinal information that's the idea
and as it's kind of crazy to go at
source code level with these types of
code bases we retreated the browser as a
black box and the idea was was to
actually generate all the possible cases
that could lead to a bypass of cookie
leaking and apply them systematically
alone on all the instances that we
wanted to look at so all the browser's
their versions and and the size of that
framework actually depends of course on
the number of test cases that you
generate and in practice here is a rough
classification that is articulated in
detail in the full paper obviously where
there are a number of obvious so to
speak for people familiar with these
with web development obvious
possibilities to to bypass an
interceptor that says I want to get all
the requests that go out I want to
verify whether it's it's safe from an
information leakage perspective and
otherwise I want to block the request
and or strip the cookies that I don't
want to leak the latter is the key issue
of course but if you look at the at the
way we build we build web applications
there are for example obviously HTML
tags but images in which you can embed
functionality and that functionality
could launch a request so there's a
bunch of HTML tags that's a huge
category with almost 200 scenarios
sitting behind it
response headers can also apart from
the direct resource that is being
requested include additional triggers -
to add functionality and therefore
trigger a request that could be harmful
we include redirects as well which is a
bit debatable if people look at a strict
description of certain policies but a
redirect offers that possibility as well
and then there is the big player
JavaScript that obviously by adding
functionality anywhere can launch
requests and also can do that from many
PDF viewers which is interesting PDF
viewers can these days PDF asking can
add also functionality typically
embedded JavaScript as well most of the
browser vendors make their own version
of that viewer and in and that is in
itself another source of vulnerabilities
and then there are a couple of api is
including the application cache being
deprecated on the one hand but being
overly used still on the other hand and
actually that application cache is
currently replaced by the serviceworker
api which more or less creates the same
cross-origin possibility but because
it's shared by all the web servers so
that is sort of a rough classification
of hundreds of scenarios that can be
imposed on the web browser and/or
extensions to see to see whether leakage
occurs and then this gives you a quick
overview of the framework where you you
see in the upper left corner a browser
control engine that actually starts from
a number of configurations that you you
you built based upon all these scenarios
that I was trying to classify briefly on
the previous slide the framework manager
generates all these test cases and that
produces web pages that try to have the
browser downloading a page that bypasses
the the third-party cookie policy so on
the one hand the browser talks to browse
the browser control creates browser
instances that are tested and these
browser instances are confronted with a
number of web pages that correspond to
all the potential bypass scenarios that
I have sort of classified briefly on the
previous slide of course between that
browser instance in the right column of
the slide there's a proxy that monitors
what's going on and that reports on the
leaks and put that in a register that
engine has been obviously applied
extensively here here are the seven
browsers on the left-hand side there
were 40-something 47 exchanges a
combination of ad blockers and tracking
protection players and and here are in a
nutshell the results of applying that or
deploying that framework in the context
of all these tools and facilities so if
you look at the full paper and I will
not sort of go into the boring rally of
at this point rushing through a number
of results but you will see both for the
browser and the extensions you will see
that in light of the seven categories of
of ways to bypass actually the the
protection that is imposed or prescribed
by a policy you see the whatever there's
a black circle then it means actually
that a request with cookies that
third-party cookies in this context was
able to be sent
despite the configuration that was
suggesting the opposite and for example
you see that because redirects are are
not actually taking care of formally in
the policy this gives you a huge
opportunity you also see surprisingly
that for example the PDF viewers from
opera and chrome failed to do the job
and allow JavaScript to leak third-party
cookies and so on and so forth so the
the sort of the main body of the paper
or oral tale after the description of
the framework a large inventory of
result is described by zooming into
particular cases where you say well this
is surprising and also reporting on our
interaction with the vendors on how to
deal with that so I'll give you this
just as a methodological example but but
it's clear that that there is
a huge amount of information sitting
behind that which we actually report on
a website that is updated so whenever a
new release of the major browser vendors
is coming up we update that information
and as I said you can see from that
experiment that it's not so trivial for
these vendors to run fast certain bug
fixes can be done major flaws cannot
easily be fixed necessarily at least not
in the short term okay so as far as the
built-in browser policies is concerned a
major element that I mentioned was the
bypassing of via the PDF viewer in
chrome and opera some of the blocking
options for example in action Safari
were completely not functioning they
were not doing the job at all and it's
clear that many categories also a
Firefox and opera of tracking protection
that was built in not by an extension
provider but by the browser produces
themselves were not functioning so it
was a little bit shocking but on the
other hand I introduced you to the way
it grew and the current complexity of a
browser it's it's easy to write a module
that says if I intercept a request I can
analyze it strip the cookies I don't
want to leak and then forward it that
piece of logic is easy to imagine for
all of us the problem is from where from
which locations in the source code do I
need to call it to be complete in my
coverage and apparently that's a
non-trivial situation today with this
huge code bases so you can wonder about
the modularity there as far as the
browser extension is concerned some of
them are really offered to to bring you
that tracking protection and advocate
action they could all be bypassed so we
we had a couple of we had a workshop
later on also with let's say is a
special interest group close group to
just sort of collaborate on on how to
improve and share ideas on how to avoid
design flaws and common implementation
stakes but it was a little bit
overwhelming as you can imagine if we
now look at the same side cookie case
which I introduced in the beginning
which is supposed to do to be a solution
and a new standard we could see that in
a number of browsers this it was not
working either Chrome and opera for
example were sending a strict cookie in
a pre render request which is inherently
a relaxed version as a detail but also
there were bypasses despite the
specification of the inside cookie
attributes in edge so it is a it's a
it's a rough landscape of of required
improvements so all the details are
obviously in the paper and not in the
scope of this presentation but for those
who are very much interested I recommend
of course reading it as well as the
extended version in I Triple E skewed in
privacy so our browser evaluation
framework validates the correctness of
implicit and explicit policies that are
to be enforced implicit because a
browser claimed to be complying with a
certain standard the framework supports
all browsers in various configurations
and we we believe that such a framework
is not just here to say well we we are
here as security researchers this is an
alarm signal and please and please
listen we found a lot of problems it's
it's more like a target for us to to
make sure that we can validate
implementations before release that's
the goal it's a constructive tool which
is a little bit unlike to too many
security research results that you may
see in further evaluating our findings
we saw a lot of opportunities to buy
pause we crawled the Alexa top ten
thousand websites with a max of up to
twenty pages per site to see whether the
potential bypassing that we discovered
through our systematic analysis was was
actually found in the wild it was not it
was not an
so to a large extent there were
potential abuses not not being exploited
as far as we could see there's a
validity issue here okay
so in conclusion bypasses for ad
blockers and privacy extensions as well
as for built-in browser policies
understand this this situation the
complexity has been grown to a huge
level and our framework in this context
is supposed to be evolving to deal with
other policies as well mobile browsers
and so on we got that award from
Facebook and we will we will sort of
invest in extending the work and and and
utilize that moniker for good purposes I
want to finish with this example to sort
of again say we are not saying hooray we
found a lot of troubles it seems to be
very difficult to stay consistent that
was the pre-render book in the same site
cookie policy it bypass I mentioned
earlier on the slides it's just one of
the problems out of the many it was
reported four versions 57 of Chrome it
took them five releases to get it out
and it reappeared as of version 66 tells
you a lot about the difficulty of
dealing with with this type of policies
despite their huge relevance and
importance thank you I'm happy to take
questions if there's timeless I will be
from Indiana University so from what I
understood like there are two
motivations for work one is the turtle
tracking and the other one is like
attack like CSRF right so as you know
probably recently there like a lot of
tracking happening with the client-side
browser fingerprinting and they don't
even use probably the cookies anymore
and you you can't know even if they're
tracking you or not and they're selling
your data to other like it's like
they're actually being transferred
between
websites and I think there are no like
actual solution for that like the the
the best solution is like tor that
totally disables the JavaScript because
otherwise they can take and use like
unique information from your browser or
from the client browser to track you
down
so how does how do you think that
affects your motivation in your in this
work you're absolutely right that the
the problem of tracking is is not only a
matter of leaking third party cookie
policies thirty party cookies obviously
correct more advanced techniques like
fingerprinting which we studied in other
papers are part of the spectrum so I
believe that if if the consortium
including dub-dub-dub and in other
working groups jointly aimed for a
certain policy to deal with part of the
problem that is not fighting
fingerprinting obviously and machine
learning based advanced techniques then
it is not and it's important to deliver
software that to the maximum possible
extent complies with the policy it
claims to implement okay do we need
other policies other possibilities to to
maximize fingerprinting protection I
think so I could refer to other work
that did with the Nick Nick if Iraqis
for example in that space and and that
is another line of research but I don't
think it it evaluates the relevance of
doing this right I don't think so but we
we can argue during a break that it's my
opinion all right thank you and that's
the end of the session
you