my name is Ramon Casillas and I'll be
describing the Zanzibar theorization
system this is joint work with great
many people so determining whether
online users have permission to access
digital objects is central to preserving
privacy online so for example here we
have on the Left user Alice post a video
on a video sharing service such as
YouTube when the question arises can
another user in this case Bob on the
right access the video now there are
many examples of the need for these
authorization checks in any service that
allows users to share objects that could
be videos photos documents locations
calendar entries etc etc so Zanzibar is
a is a system that does these
authorization checks for hundreds of
Google services we have a few examples
here again YouTube photos Drive Google
cloud etc so Zanzibar serves two main
purposes the first one is to store
access control lists or permissions so
we have two examples here
YouTube acting on behalf of its users
stores in Zanzibar which is the orange
cylinder in the middle a permission that
says the video X is public for example
another example at the Google cloud
platform a store in Zanzibar permission
that says that group Y manages cloud
project Z the second purpose of Zanzibar
is then to perform a thorough zation
checks based on those stored permissions
so for example YouTube math Zanzibar at
a later date when a when a user comes to
try and access a video can Alice view
video X or when a cloud user comes to
use a virtual machine the Google cloud
service can come as Zanzibar can Bob
Korea
a virtual machine under cloud project Z
so Zanzibar has a number of notable
properties that really come from
requirements of a system such as this
Sansa bar should be consistent and by
that I mean that it needs to respect the
causal ordering of updates to access
control lists and object contents in
order to allow its clients and users to
reason about when it is that permissions
are there or not there this is very
important for privacy the answer bar
needs to be flexible to support a very
rich variety of access control policies
we have hundreds of services that are
our clients and they have very very
widely different access control patterns
Zanzibar needs to be scalable many of
our client services are themselves
global they work worldwide they have
built over a billion users some of them
and they manage billions of objects so
Zanzibar has been shown to scale to
trillions of access control entries and
millions of acts authoritative checks
per second as we'll see finally an in
terms of performance Anza bar needs to
be fast authorization checks are often
in the critical path of user
interactions and it's in the case of a
search application for example it may do
tens or hundreds of authorization checks
before it can present a single search
result that's that's a col aware so in
this in this case Zanzibar as has very
good tail latency less than 10
milliseconds at the 95th percentile and
finally a system like Zanzibar needs to
be highly available and the reason is
that if an authorization system is not
there its client services must assume
that the answer to an authorization
check is no for privacy reasons and so
if the authorization system is not there
there's a huge denial of service problem
so how does it work so what happens is
our clients get to create arbitrary
namespaces and there's a new one
namespace roughly for every type of
object say a video videos or photos or
documents etc within those namespaces
our clients define arbitrary relations
between users and objects examples of
relations are owner editor commenter
viewer etc and Zanzibar stores these
this information that comes from from
our clients in what we call relation to
pools which is a row in this table a
relation to pool is a three tuple
consists of an object or relation and a
user set so here we have two examples
the first one states that user a is a
viewer of object of video X and the
second one states that all users are
viewers of video Y all users is just a
system constant that is how we implement
public objects so when it comes to check
authorizations Zanzibar will read it's
stored relation to pools and evaluate
the check so for example the question
comes is user a AB you or video X the
answer here is yes is user be a viewer
video X the answer's no user B does not
appear in the in the access control list
for video X and since video Y is public
all users are viewers of video Y so the
answer is always yes for that so things
get a little more complicated or
actually a lot more complicated because
user sets that third column in the table
can be more than just a single user or
all users they can also be a set of
users that have a certain relation to a
certain object it's a it's a it's a way
of having an indirection here so in this
example here in the second row we have
that in addition to user a being a bit
of your video X all the members of Group
one are also viewers of video X and to
it to evaluate that the answer might
needs to expand that indirection and go
to another namespace in this case groups
and see who are the
birth of Group one so and you can
imagine that this creates sometimes very
deep hierarchies of permissions
sometimes very wide hierarchies of
permissions and this is a challenge when
you want to evaluate an authorization
check with low latency so if we want to
do a thorough nation checks here for
instance user B is it is it a viewer is
of video X the answer is yes because
it's a member of group one whereas user
D is still not a viewer video X I hope
that's clear
so another subtle
another important but subtle point here
is that our clients very much care about
the order in which Sansa Bar is able to
apply changes to access control lists
and to object contents and in particular
it wants to they want to protect against
what we call the new enemy problem and
here's an example is again user Alice
has decided has been sharing a document
with users Bob and Charlie and sadly
despite the fact that Alice and Bob have
been appearing together and talks and
papers like this one for more than 30
years they've had a recent falling out
and Alice then decides she's not gonna
work with Bob anymore so she removes
them from the access control list for
this document and it's important now for
the system the service to not allow Bob
to access any new contents that may be
added to a document to the document
after bob was removed from the access
control list and he had access to it
before so he's already aware of of all
that contents earlier but maybe Allison
Charlie when I have new sensitive
information a new you know confidential
information that Bob should not see so
zanzabar solves this problem by offering
a consistency protocol that it executes
in cooperation with its services all our
client services are
friends of ours they're all Google
services so we are we work in
cooperation with them it's not an
adversarial situation so the first step
of this consistency protocol is in this
example alice has removed Bob from the
access control list so the document
service sends a request to stanza bar to
remove Bob from the as a viewer of
document X and the key to this
consistency protocol is to exploit the
linearizable commit timestamps provided
by the underlying database system which
in this case is spanner it's a
fascinating database system I if you
don't know about it I invite you to to
read this paper from 2012 but in
particular we use these commit time
stamps to mark the order in which events
happen in Zanzibar and so this change to
the access control list for document X
receives time stamp t0 and its answer
well where we turn that time step to the
client in case it wants to use it later
by continuing with this particular
example what we really want to protect
against this is these new content
updates so when another user with
permission to update the content in this
case Charlie could be Alice or anyone
else the the document service will then
send another request to Zanzibar to
check whether this content update is
allowed in this case the answer let's
assume the answer is yes but this and
the important thing is this content
update will receive a new timestamp and
the answer will ensure that this time
step T 1 is larger than the timestamp T
0 for the aqwal update and finally when
let's say Bob tries to access this
document then the document service will
send that check on a kolcheck for Bob to
view a document X but it will send back
that the timestamp that disease answer
bar had sent the document service before
the document service will have
associated that timestamp with the
version of the document in its own
storage system separate from Zanzibar
and now Zanzibar can evaluate this Akal
check knowing that it needs to do so at
a times
at least as fresh as t1 and it does so
and this this protocol ensures that Bob
cannot access new new contents of the
document after bob was removed from the
access control list so how does it sense
of our work inside so it's a very large
system starting from the top we have
clients and we have a small well-defined
API the two things the two parts the API
we've been talking about so far are
right and check writes are used to
create modify or delete access control
entries or relation to pools check is
this isolation check that I've been
talking about there's two other
read-only api's read and expand that
they allow our clients to read back
their apples and reason about them
there's one other API called watch which
provides our clients with a neo
real-time stream of changes to their
apples this is a very useful API for
clients that want to keep up-to-date
indices that are Akal aware for search
when a say a check request arrives at a
at Zanzibar it arrives our main server
types call a co server these are
organizing clusters and requests can
arrive at any server in the cluster and
that server will farm out work to other
servers as necessary
remember those levels of indirection in
the data whenever you see one of those
typically results in Akal server doing
an internal request to another actual
server to evaluate that part of the
request and these things these requests
can infer in turn contact other Akal
servers so it's a very rich graph of
internal are pcs these is all remote
procedure calls here so that's how our
clusters work and as I mentioned before
all the data is stored on the spanner
global database system we have one
database for their main space
configurations which is how our clients
configure our system with namespaces and
relations we have one database per
namespace to restore the relation to
both for that namespace
and finally we have a changelog which is
a record of all the changes to the
through all the namespaces that it's
used by the watch sir so satisfying all
the requirements of a system like
Zanzibar simultaneously presents very
difficult engineering challenges I don't
have time unfortunately to describe the
many implementation techniques that
we've included in Zanzibar to satisfy
these requirements I invite you to read
the paper but very quickly we have some
freedom to choose these evaluation time
stamps because that protocol I mentioned
clients will give us a time stamp and
they want us to evaluate the cheque at a
time that at least as fresh as that but
we have we have freedom all the way back
to that time stamp and often it turns
out clients are satisfied with
evaluating time times that are more than
ten seconds old or mean minutes old and
that gives us the ability to choose a
time stamp for data that gives us data
that's already been replicated around
the world so that we have a local copy
so it's nearby we have a number of hot
stop hot spot mitigation techniques such
as caching and deduplication of requests
we hedge requests which means this is
all internal requests we hedge request
meaning that we send multiple copies of
the same request to multiple servers and
take the fact that one that comes back
first that's a very important technique
for reducing tail-end seen in the
distributed system there's always one
slow server somewhere so if you if you
have bad luck and you're only sending
your request to that bad server you're
going to have high latency so in some
cases we farm out the same request of
multiple servers and take the fastest
one we have a lot of fine-grained
performance isolation to protect against
misbehaving clients and finally we use
in a specialized indexing system called
Leopard to optimize up operations on
very large or deeply nested sets and we
that's runs in memory can get back
return unions and intersections of very
large sets in microseconds
so in terms of deployment Zanzibar has
been in production for more than five
years it manages over 1,500 namespaces
defined by hundreds of clients it stores
more than 2 trillion in relation to
pools replicated several dozen places
around the world
it receives more than 10 million
requests per second from various clients
mostly read-only kind and we have over
10,000 servers also in several dozen
clusters around the world to serve these
requests so just a couple of performance
notes here in terms of load this is a
typical week and how many check queries
per second we have two kinds of check
queries we classify them as either safe
or recent a safe request is one for
which the time stamp that the client
requested is at least 10 seconds old
again that means that almost guaranteed
we'll be able to find the data at a
nearby server because it's already been
replicated worldwide by spanner we have
an 8 minute replication heartbeat I'm
sorry it's 8 second the other kind is
recent that's when the time stamp
requested by the by the client is lit as
less than 10 seconds old and then in
some of these cases we're gonna have to
go to a faraway server because the data
hasn't been replicated yet so those are
slower but as you can see then the great
majority of requests are of the safe
kind of the fast kind orders of
magnitude more about 4 million QPS
peeking every week for the safe whereas
only about a hundred thousand for the
recent in terms of latency which is one
of our major goals here again this is
the same week we have different
percentiles of latency for check safe
which again is the most common operation
by far orders of magnitude and we're
very proud of the fact that we we are
serving check responses in less than 10
milliseconds at the 95th percentile and
less than 100 milliseconds at the 99.9
percent off finally availability as I
mentioned the very important
consideration for an authorization
system and we're very pleased that we've
been able to maintain available
over 99.999% over the last three years
if you look closely you'll see that
around New Year's every year the system
seems to take a little break I don't
really know why but I it's it's still
very far above the 99.99% so to
summarize I hope I've convinced you that
robust Authority authorization checks
are central to preserving privacy online
it's answer bar is a unified
authorization check authorization system
for Google services and it respects
causal order of user actions supports a
wide variety of access control policies
it offers very low latency very high
availability scales to trillions of
access control lists and millions of
checks per second to support hundreds of
services used by billions of people and
please come to our poster tonight if you
like to learn more thank you very much
[Applause]
before any questions it's our final
speaker okay so yeah any questions
[Music]
Peter destroyers northeastern this is
fascinating it's curious the the
relations are those opaque or are they
semantic do have semantic knowledge of
what Viewer means our member so Zanzibar
does not understand the semantics of
their relations we they're fully defined
by our clients in their configuration
files we simply check for matches
whether users have the certain relations
to certain objects okay thank you I
suspected that Ana Cornfeld Simpson
University of Washington really cool
work
I was wondering since you know that your
clients are other Google services and
you have this watch server already
whether you could end up with something
along the lines of the key transparency
work where clients would be able to sort
of
keep a I don't know internal in this
case but internally public track of any
changes that have been made and recorded
by the system well thanks I am I'm not
familiar with the key transparency work
I'd love to learn more afterwards but
yeah so I'm not sure I can answer your
question I'm just not familiar with with
that hi
I am mr. Sandler from Oracle is that a
global system meaning that does it span
worldwide or is it a system that is
local to see yeah our production
instance is global we we have 10,000
servers on in several dozen data centers
all around the world to be close to our
users and our services aren't our
clients for latency and also for high
availability and the data is also
replicated globally again at several
dozen times all around the world again
to be close to our clients and our users
for for both low latency and
availability thank you ok let's thank
our speaker
[Applause]