okay so I'm Stephan savage I'm an
academic I'm currently a student at the
University of Washington soon to be
assistant professor at UC San Diego and
as with as observer for assistant
professors these days I also have a
company listed here that works in this
denial-of-service space and I've been
invited to give a talk about what I know
about the state of the practice and
perhaps the future in tracing back IP
packages so for those of you who have
been asleep for a little while and we
give you some context about 30 years ago
some guys anyone from BBN in the
audience here about 30 years ago some
guys at BBN got together said we're
going to build the internet it's going
to be a great place our friends are
going to play it's going to be an
environment of goodness and harmony and
peace and love and that worked pretty
well in 1969 and these days we have very
much a different environment and there
have been ongoing attacks on ebusiness
for the last several years culminating
with last march and some very publicized
denial service attacks that took down
sites such as Yahoo and so forth so the
problem that I'm going to talk about
today is wetting tiles and a low service
attack we're in an attacker overwhelmed
and networks in situ resources by
sending spurious responses to the
network either overwhelming their
network resources using up all their
buffers or using all their CPU resources
and they're really three components to a
solution to this problem one is
detection that it's figuring out that
you're under attack at all which is not
as simple problems you might think
localizations which is finding out where
the attack is coming from and then some
countermeasure and I'm really only going
to talk about localization right now but
the other two problems are are very very
curious and necessary for any real
solution to this sort of that sort of
problem so the reason localizing attacks
is difficult is the internet
architecture today fundamentally from is
anonymity the IP source address is
strictly written as on a voluntary basis
and as I like to say much the same way
as a kidnapper when they send an array
no they tend to not write their true
return address on that ransom note
people attacking the internet tend to
not write their true IT address on those
packets and you know if everyone put in
ingress and egress filtering that would
solve some of this problem but I'm
pretty dubious about that I think
there's a poem we're gonna have to live
with for some time
so using these false source addresses
packets of statement to the network and
one of the great advantages of the
Internet is that stateless design which
here turns out to be a hindrance because
once one of these forged IP packets has
hit the network its origin is absolutely
is absolutely anonymous it's there are
no audio trails for you to go back and
figure out where these things came from
and so the challenge is to figure out
how some new trace attack back towards
their source and this is valuable even
so I like to distinguish between the
forensic uses of trace backs which is
you want to find the guy and take them
to record and so forth and the
operational uses and from an operational
standpoint it's valuable to be able to
trace back attacks even if you don't get
all the way the attacker just in using
stall filters in the appropriate place
to your customer can go on serving
content so the rest of my talk is
basically broken up as follows I'm going
to explain a little bit more formally
that kind of problem I'm talking about I
look at the current approaches that are
available today for casing denial of
service attacks and then we're talk
about some other soldiers that have been
made means of power so what I call the
operation will trace back problem has a
small number of basic elements the
number of attackers listed here a a sub
one is the juice of three there's some
routers in the network and some victim
and there's what we call an attack path
which is simply the set of ordered
routers between the attacker and the
victim and the goal of facepack is
simply defined that attacked at the set
of routers that an attack must traverse
through in order to reach the victim
places you could install filters in
order to mitigate that attack so the
current state of the practice today
is a Robert stone turn into debugging
this is log input on iOS boxes and other
we have equivalent features and the way
this works is if you're under attack
you'll call up your ISP you'll say hi I
think to be under attack and the attacks
has such-and-such a signature and
hopefully a signature is something that
can be well described with a bitmap or
like it's sins or something like that
and you will install a filter in your
router and all the packets that match
that filter you say please log-log the
input on which the input port or MAC
address on which needs change and then
you'll take that input port and you'll
manually match to what the upstream
router is I say well I'm getting 200,000
packets that came in on interface 6 to
interstate 6 is connected to this other
router then you go to the next router
and you repeat the process until you get
outside of your administrative domain
and then you try to call the FCM is P
and convince them that it would be in
their best interest even it's not in
their economic interest to aid you and
so forth and this is really how
traceback happens today and it's roughly
detailed in this in this web page out
there and this is to the best of my
knowledge how most of the trade specs
that you ever read about take place it's
very time consuming and it really
doesn't scale to more than you know sort
of single stream denial service attacks
so you have the effort and time of your
own person within your ISP is a
limitation into provider cooperation
problem I think is really showstopper
here because it requires a lot of
different ISPs to work together for you
to trace back to any meaningful distance
there's been some efforts to automate
the enterprise provider overhead that is
the time that your operator spends
typing things so there's an old tool
from NCI called dodge package I believe
is defunct but used to try to basically
log into your iOS boxes and do this kind
of stuff for you with some perl scripts
and there's a new proposal as Roberts
tentative unit is made called Center
track which has tends to item 8 using
bgp tunnels and here's a paper coming
out and using security symposium
detailing his proposal on doing this the
other problems you have to deal with and
some architectures you have some
significant router overhead for doing
infancy bugging
a little bit on the design if it's
fundamentally requires all the IOC's in
the past participate you can't trace
pass an ISP that doesn't want to
participate if someone's further
upstream towards the attacker wants to
participate they can't really help
because you have no way of knowing you
know when you went from sprinting unit
to a PMT of unit didn't want to play you
have no idea that 18 feet with the next
hop you needed to trace through and
finally you really need to observe the
attack in progress for this kind of
approach to work if the attacker stops
attacking well end of story you can come
back later after you've given up but to
previous information when you put
together it and help you that much so
another approach that halbert's at CMU
and built says look at I got a cover a
solution that's right there loosing came
up with is what I call controlled
sweating and this is something you can
do with no involvement whatsoever from
your ISP and it's incredibly dangerous
but it is Network you create a map of
the network using a set of trade routes
and so forth you have some idea of local
or sort of moderate topology and you
have some well I'll call helpful
upstream host and in this case helpful
means that they have not plugged some
security holes but maybe they're really
helpful maybe they really want to help
you and so the basic idea is that you're
going to load each upstream link from
the victim iteratively
and by coercing the helpful host into
sending traffic across that link in
there by overloading it and what you'll
notice is if you overload a link that is
on the attack path the traffic that you
are getting from your true attacker will
be perturbed because it will be
competing with this overflow of traffic
that you have intentionally sent and so
that means that link is part of the bad
path and you can follow it back and you
repeat until done so for example here
here is a you know here are some
examples of how you would do this in
this in the example here on your left
there's some helpful hosts - h1 and you
get it to send traffic across the link
between those that are our
[Music]
one hour for an hour two and that's not
on the attack path and so you're not
going to see any any perturbation in the
attack coming from a tube because
they're not competing it off however
here on the right
h2 goes across the router besides of the
link between r3 and r2 and it will in
fact return to traffic and it drops off
knees okay
that link is in it so now don't look
upstream of there the drawbacks of this
are well you know Europe it requires a
map of the network that's not so bad but
it requires fundamentally abusive
upstream hosts and even if it's not a
dude it isn't in and of itself as an
alum service attack on the other hand it
has been used successfully this actually
does work if someone is really desperate
facility if you're a shadowy
organization you can do this and you can
actually find out what's going on it
becomes harder and more expensive on
high-damage link because you have to the
amount of perturbation you'll get from
the SPL support some more traffic to
perturb me to perturb the attacker in a
way that you can actually tell that the
attack is going across that link and
it's also not well-suited to distributed
attacks because as soon as you have the
multiple different edges contributing to
the attacks it becomes very hard to make
that differentiation simply by adding
work more noise to the signal but it has
this huge benefit that it doesn't
require providers to be involved from
the standpoint of the victim so there
are some recent developments those
basically those are two things you can
do right now more or less the recent
developments are proposals for modifying
the way routers work generally things
that make small changes to the
forwarding path and in order to enhance
traceback capability and to either
reduce or eliminate overheads on ISPs
and doing trace back to a lab trace back
to be done post-mortem that is after
attractive attack is completed
allowing partial deployments and
fundamentally they all seem to use
probabilistic path reconstruction I'll
explain what that means but the caveat
is that all of this is working
you're not going to find you're not
going to find something that is works
completely in any of the students taken
something any other things not that's
for them so see Belvin has a draft specs
for something called ICMP traceback that
is an example of these and the idea is
that you sample packets in a router so
roughly let's say every 20,000 Achatz
that comes through your router you'll
pick out one of those packets and you'll
generate a special ICMP message but
you'll wrap around the packet which will
include some information about the
forward half and the reverse hot some
identification information and then as
much as the origin packet content as
will sit so you can match this special
ICMP trace back message with me with the
actual data traffic and the ideas and
that'll slide even though you're
sampling very few packets you'll get
enough of these that you can
subsequently reconstruct the link that's
nice that is charged and the other
little special thing that you do is when
you send these ICMP messages if you'll
set the TTL to its maximum and the
reason that you do this is because that
that allows you to slightly improve the
way you can reconstruct the past because
it means that the TTL will always
decrease monotonically in sites that are
further away from the victim so the
closest reverence to the victim will be
sending tradesmen tags through the TTL
of 254 and one further away will be 253
and so forth it's something that can't
be spoofed with all the routers are
going to decrement the TTL so the idea
that you get these ICMP messages that
your victim either have your demarcation
firewall site or maybe actually have the
victim post you'll pick these up and
they'll each represent a sample of your
pad so there'll be you know one of these
guys 50 messages that will reflect a
particular particular router length and
another one that will reflect the next
router link and so forth and you will
use the TTL to order order these
different packets something you'll try
to match the forward and reverse
interface information and there's a
graft on this that is in very early
stages
[Music]
there we go so the limitations of this
approach right now that that we're where
everyone is this ICMP problem which is
that you know ironically at least in
part in response to denial of service
attacks people are increasingly
filtering in rate limiting ICMP in the
network which is a pretty new thing it
used to be that people only did it at
the edges but now there are providers
who are just cutting off ICMP that
aren't from their direct peers so ICMP
may not be protocols based on ICMP may
not may not be working too much longer
people continue down this path the other
problem is the because of the way before
the reverse path information is
specified be pretty hard to deal with
partial deployment in these schemes
because when you get a discontinuity you
say well previously I was on interface
sick for some upstream router and then
you don't get anymore you know there are
no more messages for you know five six
seven routers there's no real way for
you to match those two together and
understand that that those two messages
actually constitute consequent routers
in the same attack path and then finally
and this is probably the most
[Music]
problematic and it's problematic for all
the schemes is that I think the trace
bag is fundamentally vulnerable to
chassé that is that an attacker can
generate these false trace back messages
that say things about where the attack
test is that aren't quite true and so in
order to deal with this it requires an
authentication infrastructure with some
kind of forward security so that when
you send out these messages about that
you know here is such-and-such part of
the past you require some authentication
information that's constantly changing
and then you go back in query and say
did this thing really sign it and that
itself is a problem for denial service
attack specifically if your routers now
need to be going and verifying sign
secrets all the time then someone to
just simply hammer on your router so
this is this is sort of an open problem
that that the people working in trace
back has not yet come up with a solution
for
there's another technique which myself
and some other people at u-dub came up
with that's appearing in the next big
time and it's called packet marking and
it's a look it's it's very similar
actually I think the trace I accept the
distinction is that you don't generate
any separate messages you encode the
data that you need in the existing
packet so again you probabilistic lay
marks packets and routers so with some
probability P you go and mark this
packet and put some information about
that particular edge and the attacks at
that particular link in the packet and
we had a couple fields ignore for a
moment entirely where I get these do
pretend though they're I'm an academic
will feel that a second so so there's
one field called edge field has two
adjacent router addresses and another
field called a business fields which is
a number of these edges the number of
links in the between routers that are
actually participating that it's been
traversed since you marked effect the
first time and so this serves the same
function is TTL so if the packet didn't
work doing from that the distance if you
mark it you set the distance to zero
that way that distance field always
represents how many hops since the
packet was marked and no one no one can
spoof that no one can make a false
distance field any closer than the
attacker actually is and then you know
it's a reconstruction is similar you
collect these packets you have a bunch
of edges you construct a graph and
there's you know here's a funny little
formula on the bottom that says how many
taxes you need to reconstruct the graph
and it's actually really easy to
understand but I'm not going to waste
people's time it's not very big
that's good that's the bottom line you
don't need that much so the practical
problems are that I didn't don't have
this field you know I need 72 bits to
make something fly so we came up with a
bunch of really hairy ugly encoding
tricks to try to fit all the data into
the existing IP header file overloading
on what we feel is a horrendously
underused packet header field and we're
actually before I get there we read you
a couple things
first to shrink the amount of
information that we need and then we're
going to set everything into 16 bits so
the first thing we're going to do is
we're going to compress all the edges
using XOR so I had mean edges that set
I'd I've traversed between whether you
know r6 and r5 or here r2 r2 and r1 or
eyes traverse between r3 and r2 and I
don't really need to see up send all
that information I don't need to send
the full edge instead I can send the XOR
of the two adjacent edges and so what
will happen here is you know normally I
would send a message there would be
let's see one two three three methods to
read four different messages that I
would get one with our six and our three
and these in this whole attack type here
one with our three and r2 and so forth
but by just sending the X ORS that's
actually sufficient information because
I'll get I guess I can use this pointer
I'll get r1 the priests of the last
router before the victim will send a
message saying all right so the last
name came from r1 and an upstream
middleton r2 ex-ored with r1 and r3
experts r2 and so forth and then you can
just sort of unwind this because xor has
this great commutative property and
reconstruct the entire path from the X
ORS and that that shrinks the space by a
factor of two and then what we can do is
you know that's so let me get this down
- I don't know 32 bits or something like
that and so we'll divide those exports
what we call edge ideas into chunks
we're going to essentially fragment it
and then we so when your market packet
you'll pick one of those K parts of that
32 bit thing and you'll send that and
that increases the number of packets you
need to get but again not that much and
I'll give you some empirical numbers and
then we do some stuff into chunks mean I
to be unique and use a hash to validate
that affect things go together and
there's a paper that describes all the
detail the in terms of how we actually
encode this we're going to overload the
proposal what overload the ID field
observation being that at least on the
links that we have gotten a measurement
data that there's very little real
fragmentation out there because you'd be
nuts to send real traffic fragmented
because your performance goes to
and so in 99% of the time that feels not
use it off so we have a really ugly
scheme for dealing with fragments it it
makes is that fragmented people who use
fragment alive won't like this however
if you don't fragment a lot we can
actually fit everything in the 16 bits
in the ID field in a way that lets you
reconstruct the entire path and so we
actually built a filter system and and
this is basically results for
reconstruction time for various paths
length and it's you know on the order of
a couple thousand packets to reconstruct
a path of just about any length and you
know when you're dealing with the kinds
of attacks that Yahoo is dealing with
that's a fraction of a second so in that
sense that's reasonable
so limitations of packing marketing
rates presentations you know we can
fragmentation it'll still work with
fragmentation but it's significantly
degrades fragmentation worse than
fragmented slows were before it can also
break a defect because IPSec once the
the authentication header wants to cover
the the add you field so you know that's
a problem the Colonel Gumm algorithms
that we have in the paper though scale
very well for large distributed tax and
dealing with hundreds of sites and as
with the sec transact message is
vulnerable to chat you still need some
kind of forward of suffocation scheme
and that's a real problem
so other possible approaches that you've
ever been proposed or people have
thought about theirs just doing
distributed analysis of package counts
using Netflix that people exchange
necklace attachments they look here
where the big flows are coming from and
this is where they're proposed and the
sources don't seem to match up and they
came in on this interface and you can
pretty much in series put that together
in a way that you could trace the
attacks back you can actually do packet
logging
using something like you know coral
where you if you have a if you have a
good implementation of port mirroring
when you're router you can actually do
sampling
do some logging and gnash things up
there's a pretty hairy database
integration problem but this is doable
and then there's been some unpublished
proposals on doing well what I call the
overhead audit trail where you'll take a
packet you'll hash it into a bitmap on
my router and you'll subsequently go
back to the router and present them with
the packet is it possible that this
could have gone through there and I'll
say wow there's a 30% chance and then
you go back to the previous router and
you build that with reasonable certainty
that particular packets went through
particular paths and then the hybrids of
all these approaches now as I said
before trace back is really you know you
saw the trace back from yourself some
very big problems leftover detection how
you know that you're under attack is
actually a really big problem the guys
at Yahoo we're spending several hours
during their attack thinking that their
router was crashing that I kept you're
booting their router it is really a
problem understanding and then once you
figure after your attack how to identify
the attack in a way it's meaningful that
it is distinctly identifies the attack
and doesn't identify your customer
because there's not really you know what
distinguishes the Victoria's Secret
homepage from a place under attack
not much they're getting a lot of
traffic all of a sudden it's very
popular you know someone could build an
attack just like that and then once
you've been attacked there's the issue
you know what do you do you need you
need again this very good identification
so that you can filter the attack but
not the customer traffic and right now I
don't think there are a lot of really
good capabilities in this space and you
know getting this to work in an inner
eyes speed context where you want
someone who's not receiving any money
from you to actually install a filter
for so this is this is a real challenge
so in conclusion basically the schemes
we have today for IP trace back are
pretty straightforward but they have
pretty high overhead and don't scale
we're going to need something else to
deal with this problem unless in this
the hackers give up
[Music]
so there are some new proposals that are
better but they're not perfect and
they're going to require changes to the
network infrastructure so they are not
going to be here
you're not going to be in six months and
even what you saw these starting
different dependent talks but there's a
lot more to traceback than just the
landlords announcer has been just going
to trace that problem so there's a lot
of technologies we're going to need to
be developed to do this and little
Postgres as a consequence of some of
this work uw has a spin-off it's about
four professors doing analysis
management solutions for ist selling
stuff to folks to deal with their denial
service problems ask the network's if
people are interested but with that I'll
take any questions that people have
[Applause]