kind of happy that could be reporting
that what I'm going to do is give you a
brief history is only difference review
the problem that multicast this time
song makes you take about 12 seconds a
brief history of what went on where
we're at and then what's going on now
where were you what's new and I'll take
a little bit about one case study that I
happened to get some slides more which
the supreme and I have a few conclusions
and if you want to look at the slide
start there so this is the multicast
thing right the idea was you're going to
put one one copy of packing on any
Lincoln it's if it's a nice I got these
cool information see um I don't know how
to do this but I can feel pretty good
sometimes as long as they're not
completely gratuitous but the point is
that you wanted to put one cup one copy
of the packet on every link and so you
can optimize a lot of different things
that way um so there was two things
about multi guess people were saying
wearing the benefit so that one is
obviously that it's possible that you
could at get been with savings of a
multicast the other one was that there
was a service model that allows people
to write new and interesting
applications so this was the multicast
story that we were working with over the
last five to seven years I'd say so what
we really wanted to do was we wanted to
be able to scale bandwidth without
accumulating a lot of state which was
always a problem because you have this
you had this cross product for the
number of sources x number of groups and
that was something that scary people off
quite a good because these are all / 30
to use essentially and then there's
always the issue of how you to sign
McCloskey address space because there is
that much of it so maybe to aggregate it
when posting how to do that and maybe a
way to do it dynamically
to peruse it socialism a very
intelligent so that it does were kind of
that issues we are working around now oh
so here's a brief history of the
multicast University very brief I just
by the way the flow of this is so that
you can put some context here so when we
get to what's new you'll know why it's
new and not wife's old but ok so look a
little bit of history where we are now
on similar problems consequences so is a
quote from my favorite movie so we have
the emblem how many people had embalmed
tunnels dmdd MIT tunnels and okay so
what that was about but you got a couple
of few quite a few really really bright
and productive people and you get this
stuff right you get dark net and get DVM
RPM and being white boarding and now to
this day I don't think there's something
better than that out there for
multimedia conferencing it's really
impressive thing so in these things all
evolved but really what was underlying
all this when I came along was on the
BBM RPM bone and this is this virtual
tunnel thing many of you guys had
connections and you know you don't rip
like rallying because of the first
emerald geez I know Bill many can you
correct me i think that person Matthews
were really serve derived from routing
EST Rockies and it was flooding frame
technology which means you less excuse
me just last the package every where and
when there's no receivers at the end of
one of these things that that router
sends back up police don't blessing
tactics here and so there was a Marathi
and it this is very popular but what was
the problem tell us well first off you
didn't have anything like you know you
have it you had a really pretty large
tunnel infrastructure and I think I my
eyes eyes through this picture called
planet the multicast oh nothing buddy
remember that I try to find out by using
the first M above the meaning because it
showed that these tunnels were sort of
everywhere I think my letter told me
once the thermal
100 tunnel is crossing the fix or that
kind of reduced that on the multicast
benefit and when it was flooded
frameless people didn't want because
they were imagining if they have like
HDTV flows or whatever and you wouldn't
want that kind of a flow pressing your
network and then have to set it back
down you wouldn't have that happen and
DB MRP didn't scale to internet sizes
and there were policy issues and then
over the address allocation problems we
never really solved that we had a
program cholesky r or s dr sdn SDR and
then you have this Malik working group
that we haven't really solved a address
assignment problem for multicast at
least up to this point so and that was
because that multicast address space is
too small to be administered via
ministry or Sully think so all of that
stuff is in the past more or less and
today what we're doing as for routing
everybody most people lecturing on multi
protocol bgp and there's several
interoperable implementations amount out
there for tree building according to the
multicast RQ routing and porting are
done by two different protocols we use
almost everybody's using pins bars which
used to be RFC 2362 but now is
completely confused and as being
rewritten so hopefully we'll get
something a little bit more on staying
out of that resource discovery there's a
protocol called chemist EP that was
built about two years ago and there i'll
give you a little bit of an example of
how that works our address allocation
Peter and I have this idea that you know
we could do the same thing it's a Class
A assignment experiment something to
class a something experiment if only at
the I Anna would give us a /a to mess
wit and so they did and that's RFC so I
2070 basically again map the tube you're
a asked to it too objection to the long
text and you get a slice 24 I'm
statically assigned to you once or
nonetheless 24 according on Anna
management of multicast networks is it
and those conductors is one thing come
to my own will you know everybody's
working on this so this is the state of
the world now what's interesting about
Tim smart mode which everybody's running
now is this last sub bullet there which
is you know what's what happens when I
guess I have another animation by the
way I don't know how to make these
things are how to make them on an innate
or anything but so this is the whole
thing so PMS is not share trees so what
happens is when you get a receiver like
down here at the but generally system
okay so you get this receiver push on
the top well that's nice eliminate the
target meanness um so when you get a
receiver down here what happens is the
receiver sends a what's called an
eschatology joint or two sources are
times of it what's called the rpe
because it really doesn't know the
source at this time that's the point
that doesn't know the source just wants
to join a group and what happens is the
RP bill to share tree down to it and
there's what's called star comedy state
which is sort of aggregating all the
sources in the star that was a benefit
when the protocol was designed and then
if a source comes up the way sources
work is on they do what's called
registering for this thing is an
encapsulated multicast activist
encapsulated in what's called a
registered back you need just to the RP
and then RPX wasn't on the share tree
like that and then one that is the other
thing if you type the heads humans to
get emanates unexpected animation anyway
what happens is now now our data packet
came down and that last out router here
can say hey I know where the source of
this thing is because it saw the data
packet it's over here and what can
happen is oh oh I think when they did
was I went one too many okay so here's
what the data packet comes this I can
see the source now and now oh this one
right here was just that the RP would
like to have a native path you don't end
capsule
whole time so it's making a native that
back to the factory source enough very
nice for now packets low multicast
encapsulated that's all nice and so this
is the way the data flows right now now
the RP will also tell their people also
tells us to stop sending registers when
it sees negative packets so that's nice
too okay so now what happens is traffic
plugs this way down the down down the
share tree and now the last hop router
can see where the sources like this
router right here towards the receiver
and this is the thing that I they you
need to keep in mind pence first know
does this normal operation so what it
can do is it can join back to the
sorcery which is right here because I
source got back to the source string so
what it does is in the join that way and
it creates best commenting state along
here which was the state people were
worried about just that's kind of the
cross product of two slashes 32 and
trafficking now flowing in that way Owen
and this sort of superfluous but this
router can send up on what's called a
Escom grp bit prune to shut off the
ferry personal data can be both ways as
possible so that's on I ok so now this
is gratuitous animation but the bottom
line is this guy said ask comments he
join here and got data to flow this way
once he saw the sources ring okay so the
question you might want to ask you such
kind of live in cary and all you wanted
to do is get that last step where you
had a source tree from the source of the
receiver you might be able to do that in
a little bit more efficient and easy way
if for example there's a well-known
source like a broadcast television
station or something so the question
really you know came to mind as well
what if the receiver can just tell the
first hop router is designated router if
there where the source for the group
wasn't could just send them you know the
last thing i did you just send a mess
ecology joined wall send out that I I
can t be three which is the protocol
that hosts uses to signal if you will
the horse up router can specify that so
that's a new protocol so just hold on to
that for a second okay so that whole
thing with yourself is actually in the
interred in tirado main case so that's
happens inside and enterprise but what
about what about in the interdomain case
as well we have this thing called ms.vp
and MSD fees real simple protocol all it
does is it sends around if a domain is a
source it just sends a packet so say I
have the source in this group and what
so here's the example this receiver up
here just came up in this thing right
here is that whole can spar snowed
interaction where it built the share
tree okay and that's what the thing has
been sitting there there's a receiver
now someday some a source comes up down
here in some domain well the source is
going to send ms.vp source active
messages towards that towards the domain
without where the hot receiver is
actually fled them in kind of this funny
fashion towards the towards and they
will wind up going towards the receiver
by me now with what this means is that
the receiver can now just send an Eskimo
G joined back to the source just like
them squares no that's right again the
thing to notice here for your own
thinking about this is that again we're
just trying to join directly to the
source none of this other machinery all
we're trying to do is join a sorcery so
what happens is well then data starts
flowing this way through the RP but now
at the last hop router which is not
being shown on here but just like last
time it sees the data and they can
switch to the source got three shuttles
and it'll send on a technology join and
that path might cut off that party or
may not close through it at the bottom
line hairs you went to this whole thing
just to get how can you just to get on
the leaf from the sorcerer and so this
could be you know broadcast source and
somebody's some content aggregators
network and you wind up with a source
team and again I receiver didn't know
where the source was right and that's
what the RP and all this mechanism is
for
[Music]
so that we can find out what sources are
receivers and sources community so just
keep those things in mind I just want to
give you a brief outline about what's
going on in the real world today a lot
of this stuff is out there I think Penn
sparse tonight has been out that it's
hard to nail this down because Tim
sparse notice something that started
morphed into what it is now and I'm just
kind of marking into something else at
the moment but I think it's been I think
there have been implementations around
for about five years and if anybody
knows different women let me know and
multicast bgp or multi protocol bgp for
multi casting them if you've been around
and out in the field for like two years
the whole glob thing everybody's using
it and unfortunately it's less 24 is in
a lot of radio stations if you like
broadcast calm or something there's
about 200 ases that have that are
involved in doing msdp so you see on ASM
you see SMS just a little over 200 same
thing with mptp which makes sense there
may be about 8,000 networks in the NB GP
table and there's you know 12 or so
public public exchanges and I one of the
one of Kevin Elmer off students made a
really nice webpage that really
summarizes all the stuff that's down
here it's pretty nice there's a few
other things there's a lot of groups
active in any time but really if you
look at the number of groups that have
been transmitted on in the last say time
period 24 hours or whatever you'll see
that like thousands of them intransitive
on so the avocent problem really is
significant there's a lot of there's a
lot of multicast traffic around and
there's a lot of pretty powerful alone
backbones around two and all if I have
enough time at the end of the social
experiment it's kind of interesting
because it works both of the examples so
there's a lot of multicast out there a
lot of people doing multicast it's been
a lot of success with moc plbg p.m.
smart stuff but it's there's still
things that haven't consult so this is
the
slide and as the work has the real news
on it basically do all this work just so
that we might be able to construct
source trees and if we didn't and if
that's what we really knew a front that
we wanted to do there may be a simpler
way to do that this is quite a bit of
missionary so the question really is
what we could just build these things
directly how do we do that well that's
that's what the news and multicast is
right now and that's where the whole
multicast universe has has some
excitement going mines and it's going on
around something called s SMS or
specific multicast it's called search
specific and cuz we know where we're
assuming that the host will know is the
laptop host that's wanting to join this
group knows where the sources came till
it seemed at ease all right another nice
review this animation here basically
what you want to do is you want to just
optimize for that case with us what a
host already knows where the source is
ok so that's like you could get it up
you know who knows we get it but you
know it's basically you want to build
source trees and you don't want it do
all this other machinery just want to
get the sorceries established as quickly
and as simply as possible so the idea
here is welcome to simplify this get the
sorcery immediately eliminate
dependencies on things like msdp and fix
the address allocation problem can we do
that oh by the way if you look on the
site for that allocated adversus there's
out there these were the beach v10
addresses that were resource reassigned
to the certificate multicast me and I'll
show you why I need that but basically
Prince porcelain Ariana students rightly
saw that it can join some sorcery last
hop router synthesis of source can
switch still so nowadays we've got
something called pence or specific mode
and which is sort of informal but this
is what this is about ok and so this is
the big news and the best those people
mostly applications around or one many
or few too many and this this style of
multicast could really support munda
menu well and probably few Dominion well
so basically how does have some out of
and way of combining the sources you
know the canonical thing you think is
it's a website is click on the thing and
say funds us and then what you do is
well sir price this ms come to you post
report and the first up rather the senza
that's kind of you joining and this
traffic all that other stuff and this
can be injured on the afternoon or hands
my domain all that other stuff don't
even but what you do need is going back
up into second we do need this right
here is you need i to mtv3 to make this
happen right because the current
versions are like to give you that's
shipping whatever whatever hosts you
have sun or whatever as I igmp d3 which
doesn't have the capability to sign
which doesn't have the capability of
stress line posts so okay so that's so
that's the thing we get you can build
site you can build a source tree really
quickly using almost the machinery
that's in income right now so what why
why can't you use it as bids well the
first thing this guy when it gets this
has come to G report for some range of
Elvis's it shouldn't send a star comedy
joining up this way to try to to try to
UM build a share tree down here because
you don't want that this guy and the
source things up shouldn't register
remember what registering was to send an
encapsulated back into the are key and
it sends attend the show tree and if
this guy doesn't register the RT 17
chemist eps a message receiver so how
can you know how can any of these
routers this guy or this guy Last Supper
router second they know well you need a
special piece of address space to do
that so then they won't send you'll have
this so specific behavior into 32
slicing basically okay so let's see also
got here so to state the obvious on this
SSM thing really simplifies multicast
deployment in the one too many case and
I would argue in a few them in case to
you just don't you don't have a surf
location problem because you got it out
of am somehow you don't have an address
allocation so that you don't need msep
and thatís allocation problem because
you're joining now to the source so the
effective is
that all of that all of the plus the
addresses are local to the source
because you're sending in s comedy so
they start with my ports a little bit so
there's no address allocation call and
it doesn't it does give you a little bit
of source control you know you won't see
this thing like John lander was telling
me when he was trending on the National
cessation of some guy who consistently
put up a picture of a Lego Space Shuttle
on the same Channel and you could get I
didn't ever see that Denis Leary sheena
johnson Johnson it was wearing I never
saw athlete he could do that because you
have to share a tree and anybody could
get a packet down under the circuitry
but now you're in the source tree that
you're unless you can inject a packet on
to that tree split with backing onto
that three somewhere on between the
source and receiver there's no way
fantasma number so and that's not going
to be an easy thing to do so you will
it's not it's not like security or
anything like that but it does prevent
these no-brainer things from happening
and as I said earlier it tends bar
can almost do this already and the way
it's going to work is in the t32 space
the receiver the router closer to the
receiver won't send star come and he
joins towards the rpd right because we
don't mean to share tree the first
operator for the sender won't register
because we don't need to send that data
down share tree and since it didn't
register the RP one the RP will send us
a message is but in any of that your
piece shouldn't send us a message okay
so on that's that that's the big news of
multicast right now which is so specific
and everybody I mean everybody's doing
multicast it's kind of excited about
this so let me like the sprinting so the
sprint guys have had this network up for
a long time couple year and a half or
two and it's they've done a lot of
things with it but basically it's the
standard entered on anything where you
have sparse mode
[Music]
so sometimes forgotten Stein had 101
minutes on the next time actually okay
so okay so this is my network basically
they have you have six RP spread out
across them across the country they have
whole mess msdp between them and they're
using this trick that we're a local NHS
RP we're basically what you do is you
define a new loop back with anycast
address which is just some address that
you inject into your IEP so you have
advertised the RP or static reconfigure
the RP from that address and what that
means that is that you get convergence
at the rate of your your IDP because
since thing is any cast wherever you are
with the sort of the club since that
prefix is valueless is going to the
closest one so this is it there's a home
internet dropped on that completes
interest that I could tell you more
about so then they had then they have
these connections and various maps and
they also connected with Peters network
I see em I think it's bigger snowing and
and also with the old de amor p.m. both
dreams and so okay this is the picture
of what their back on architecture looks
like basically that a bunch of customer
access ravaging a couple of backbone
routers and these things for all when
you come in Addis ocean 48 backbone and
this thing run really pretty well the
most part or does run pretty well okay
and then they provided they provided
multicast to orlando's which work pretty
well and that was that was a pretty nice
example of how you could actually do
this and make it work there are some
complexity because they're long pieces
that you know we've got done something
at work nicely the work you learn
actually so okay so here's what they
want to do they want to augment their
existing infrastructure because a lot of
most people still believe there's a
place to the shared free msdp style
thing but there's also quite a bit of
excitement and a place for this stuff so
they want to have they want to they want
to do the sort of obvious thing which is
allow customers who want to who want to
have sources and
who want to receive that content to use
SS you know that's the same as possible
so this is what you really have to do
you have to get igmp v3 to this to the
hosts you got a modified Pam on the
edges of the way I mentioned rights or
specific in basically don't don't send
star comedy joints towards the RP and
don't register here if the groups have
been to 32 / me and then this is always
an issue for providers because that's
where the most of the customers might be
for at least low bitrate services so not
so that's where they're at and I got
this this slide thank God from Kristoff
couple days ago some invisibility think
I GF what's up to the idea well there's
this whole mass massive number of
documents surrounding us but basically
of cheapest i am ok so basically this
this document was written by some guys
in spring and some other people that
sort of give a spring workers how to do
this included a lot of stuff about their
own implementation which we kind of
ripped out this is an architecture
document about single source multicast
and how it changes the service of models
at all this is this is about the changes
to them that we're next named sam jones
nakamichi joins for 232 etc this is all
the igmp v3 stuff and then there's a
greg has a bcp about what you do at you
think you Celeste 8 which is somewhat
controversial right now because the BCB
is she doesn't you know anybody has a
content provider has customers might
want to comment on this but basically
the bcp is saying that what you got to
do is filter it and not allow some
groups that are into 32 / 8 into this m
stp environment so that means that if
you don't have like a mtv3 enable posts
then it could be content sources that
your customers can
and that's a little bit controversial
right now I it so few conclusions this
is the one that just kind of after i
looked at my smile I slides it man I
don't know how to start point but as my
major conclusion but SS family it is a
really good and exciting thing that's
going on for multicast I think there's a
lot of applications that are going to be
able to take advantage of a much simpler
way of delivering multicast reigns
doesn't replace msdp share trees all of
that stuff for many too many
applications yet and the reason I the
reason I question it is I put that yet
in there because it seems to me that at
least a few too many if you're going to
be able to survive the state for one
domain and you can do it for to them at
the LCD and then the whole thing is
gated on on the availability of like I
j.mp/b three stacks for house and you
know the question everybody has is one
will Microsoft habit and i'm not sure
but that's that's probably the biggest
gating factor right now because router
vendors are getting igfbp-3 and us and
social Civic and not to feel quickly so
questions or comments
you
[Music]
[Applause]