[Music]
greetings we're going to talk today
about both sides of the enterprise both
the old TV part the OTP side as well as
a dns who is and chat a little bit about
some of the things that we've been doing
lately to start with the total number of
registrar's accessing the registry today
in production is 44 that's up from about
high 20s last time we spoke there are 42
that are actually qualified rated going
to production so we expect over the next
two months or so to have about 80 folks
in production that will be about we
expect the rest of the 32 be in
production about a couple months after
that on to the daily transactions on the
OTP side in terms of ads mods deletes
and checks of domain names using
registration our protocol we're
averaging for the quarter about 19
million 19.5 million operations a day
that's wise to do this sort of with
lower in beginning part of the quarter
we're actually running about 23 25
million a day substantially above our
projections and our rejiggered
projections after the fourth quarter
last year breaking that down with
furthering the types of transactions can
actually talk about the number of ads
vs. ma's worst elite lumping all those
together we're seeing about 8.4 million
of those a month at least in the month
of May about 80 million queries and over
600 million checks you can see the
growth rates have been pretty astounding
fortunately check is a pretty
lightweight operation but even the reads
and writes are on or increasing pretty
rapidly this case is busy in terms of
our service level agreement the actual
penalties for the agreement go into
effect June fifteenth next day or two
we've been abiding by it since
a year and basically a through January
February we had actually generally had
several planned outages to implement
some government mandated upgrades are
[Music]
averaged around to time for a check
within the data center was about 600
milliseconds about two and a half
seconds for add that were not that we're
in February in terms of our performance
and there were no planned outages at all
or unplanned looking at March April and
May most of the planned averages were
for upgrades to try to deal with the
exploding our load a bruh was
particularly difficult we have we nearly
double the capacity of the application
servers coming into the registry we also
being large deployed the new mechanism
for measuring the service level
agreement part of the requirement is
that we actually measure for each
individual operations around third time
through and data center can see got a
full a good time today when it comes in
when you push out the last buggy pull it
again into a difference and we actually
have to take all of those every single
one and measure and average enough of
the month so the reports just to figure
out the SLA for the month run for about
24 26 hours right now generates about 8
to 10 gigabytes of log a day just rly us
just a measure guess la anyway with that
we went to a much finer grained
mechanism to measure what the time with
the performance is at those were using
before and these numbers are actual
averages of every single operation done
for the month so you can see when up a
little bit of Naples we were trying to
deal with the load we put in a lot more
capacity so the performance went down
and oh the pecans got better may we also
this doesn't show we actually had a an
unplanned outage in the very beginning
of Kim a Power Distribution strip blue
and both the primary load balancer and
the backup were on the same strip so
they both went down not too bright we
went through a nature that wasn't the
case anywhere else anyway going to a DNS
and the root server this displays the
total number of UDP queries in per
second and you can see that the red line
is a good night this is a five-minute
average so it tends to smooth Peaks
you'll see Peaks that run into the 12 to
15,000 per second range over a you know
a second or two we're seeing somewhere
between ninety five hundred and ten
thousand a day I think this is a later
in the week weekends drop down to about
5,000 or so 4500 you can also see their
30 minute average for a longer period of
time looking at drops the a route right
now looks pretty sharp very few drops
apart from the restarts if you're
wondering what the the other restart at
midnight is due to some memory leak
issues we restart name d since this
graph has been taken either we would
move to restoring it during one of the
regular loads there's no reason that we
started three times right so rather than
reload we we start one of the reloads in
and do really so there's only two of
those a day looking also at the gtld
specifically one of the more on busy at
gTLDs apart from the romney a route is j
and it shows you the approximate you
know during peak attend two to six or so
we're running about 2200 to 2500 per
second you can also see em which is in
hong kong and that's substantially lower
[Music]
doesn't get much above 2000 per second
the interesting part about all this
actually let me back up for a minute a
couple of the stats that aren't up here
who is we're seeing about 17 to 20
million who is clearly zayday most of
those over ninety percent are split
between folks that are mining the data
or registrar's that have done a
recursive who is so if you go to their
site do a whois query and will come to
us if it's on their database and resolve
the figure out was very start to go to
improve data so but but most of it is
folks mining with whois database tons of
wild countries
a1a etc the other thing is in terms with
customer service we would get we're
averaging about 120 130 calls a week
there's split between relatively simple
data or technical things from some very
painful policy issues you know getting
through all the agreements with the
registrar is getting them started up the
policy calls averaged more than half an
hour 30 33 35 minutes per call the other
ones are much quicker in your spots kind
of a range one is also about some of the
things we've been doing to try to scale
the operation for a couple minutes and
talk a little about what happened David
recently some of you may or may not have
been familiar with some of the
experience there would be a wee
performance basically the bottom line on
the back end side as we saw some
dramatic growth our SLA was going to
affect will cost of somewhere between
four and five hundred thousand a day
paid back to registrar's when we don't
meet performance or availability
requirements and what the kind of growth
rates we need to do something different
for the database we evaluated the sun
IBM HP and then actually did a hands-on
evaluation of IBM porting all our code
most of its Java in the main oil PP park
so it's pretty quick and also to look at
the 10k in the end what we found was
that the IBM surprisingly because we've
been the Sun shop since forever was just
just a screamer very fast got some great
support the Java implementation actual
with real sharp we were pretty surprised
to find out that how much IBM is
invested so the bottom line is we put
this in shadow production mode for the
last month and a little bit in parallel
with the Sun we switched over this
weekend and our Layton sees have dropped
for the database heavy operations by
about a factor of forty percent fifty
percent as we're averaging on a busy day
about 260 270 milliseconds during peak
they drop to about 150 160 or so why
that's important Zara Pisa is a
synchronous protocol so especially for
registrar's in North America that kind
of a drop in the latency of the command
where the network latency is preloaded
in with will substantially increase the
amount of 2-butene get poor connection
because we're running you know newer to
the thousand or more connections per day
and that's increasing the other side is
scaling DNS as some of you at least have
heard of the fact that we're putting out
the next generations who supported
architecture I'll talk a little bit
about what happened with a route shortly
but anyway we we evaluated the various
platforms and went with an IBM ma the
the Sun box just didn't have the
horsepower at least at this time given
that binds without a single threaded and
the HP product was real solid it
compared to vary it had actually won the
performance benchmark but compared to
the last generation IBM the bottom line
is we're deploying m-80s for more than
half the gTLD servers were also into
doing a deal with sun to put twenty four
gigabytes in the 4500 and four
processors and run two versions of mine
for 4500 to get some sort of reasonable
performance in the meantime though what
we were doing all this this shows you
the resolutions per day on the a road
and sort of how things were falling off
as we were watching the Avery over
between november and january februari
early februari we noticed that you know
the classic world curve about doubling
every six months hit just leveled off
and we're thinking you know well this
could be great because at the rate we
were growing I mean we were trying to
figure out how much hard work going to
need all those seem a little suspicious
that you know this curve that's been
going on since forever someone just sort
of stopped the percent drops started
increasing and then all of a sudden be a
root just started to trash I mean we if
you actually saw I don't think I haven't
yet if you actually saw the the packet
with a packet drops literally over a
period of of two three four days the
package drops went from you know ten
% to fifty percent amor God about twelve
thirteen people working on this round
the clock and the end result was there
was no ddos nothing was just pure load
had just overcome the box and there were
a couple little issues we were getting
more dynamic updates as a result of a
certain deployment we can talk about it
was a relatively small percentage but we
had actually had login turned on and the
walking's were pushed it over the edge
so basically what we did is we took the
box we've been qualifying for the next
generation deployment and put that into
production and then upgraded that to
ibm's biggest box of juice in that ad
which is the current a route we also
tweaked we were surprised how many a tcp
connections which is lingering we're
having hundreds and hundreds of tcp
connection from a route we wrote an
assassination server which basically
when a connection language for the loss
and the reset but we decided to turn
down people to turn down the keepalive
defaults and sure enough turns out the
word into the 10 so a lot of them were
connects tcp connections established
that whatever route went away or
whatever the client was no longer
visible but the connection stayed we
also filter out dynamic updates are
going to get to the room so this is
basically what happened when would you
can see literally the days of deployment
the total number of resolutions for the
day doubled over what it was before
another way of looking at is looking at
the drops if you look at this generally
the the load on the a roof goes up
around nine o'clock eight to twenty
eight and ten and it stays pretty level
there until about six or so we can see
where we deployed it was exactly eleven
one last bit is in terms of making more
of the operation of the registry both
the OTP side and DNS accessible to folks
were piloting them some near real-time
stats in other words a towards the end
of the year or very early q1 we're going
to have
a site in a central where you'll be able
to go to and and click on the various
gTLD a route service at least we run and
take a look at some average stats take a
look at a real-time feed go back and
look at some historical what you see
fear which may be very hard to read is
on the left hand side by the way this
thing updates about once every five
seconds so we'll show you the actual
type of request those per second and
percentage coming in by request type it
will show you the packet counts UDP
packets kind of going in and out it will
show you the TL bees that are getting
hit per second as well as the most
popular the twenty ten twenty thirty
it's configurable most popular things
that are being queried and where they're
from and how many duplicates as we've
been watching this a lot more closely
we're finding that there are a fair
number of misconfigured servers out
there there was one particular fellow
who was running a server that had gotten
caught in an infinite loop and was
clearing the same domain name about 100
per second on the area no idea why we
called him up he was very apologetic and
stopped but uh actually is amazing we
got updates from him on a couple hour
basis for a week as to what he was doing
he got a little nervous about the whole
situation but as we were following up on
this a lot of employee ID estimation was
in kind of fifty percent of the low
neighborhood is just spurious about
misconfigurations queries coming from
the exact same client for the exact same
name same IP address you know hundreds
of times a second so we're following up
on those but anyway in terms of openness
look for Vienna central over the next
probably about three or four months and
you start seeing some near real-time
stats on what's going on rent utility
consolation any question
yes fall only only one minor comment 0
which is that those about to run digital
Enix on our comm service don't have any
memory problems really so my name D runs
six months at a time to clean up grades
and it has the only reason it grows is
because calm gets bigger okay we're
seeing some memory leak it may I will
talk to David with women were started
work pretty closely phenomenal on that
thank you the by the way the comment
about memory leaks is for the version of
mind we're running on sun which would be
8 12 with with all the patches that we
put in place in some tweaks as well so
that's not a comment about the current
version ii to write a time to direct any
other questions thank
[Applause]