I'm Dave Katz I'm a software engineer at
Juniper Networks I did five years at
Cisco before that and I was in Meerut
before that so pretty much anything
you've ever run into you can blame on me
I'm going to talk about is is and OSPF
and talk fairly technically about what's
the same about them what's different
about them and as providers what that
should mean to you start with a little
bit of history for those of you who
aren't as grey as I am the this will
seem fairly ancient for those who were
around shout me down if my memory is bad
a whole bunch of nuts and bolts about
you know how little mechanisms in these
protocols compared to one another a bit
about scalability which is everybody's
favorite paranoia in routing protocols
some pragmatic considerations on
[Music]
choosing protocols and finally some
conclusions this is from memory and it's
a long been a long haul so if the dates
are off by a year or two I'm real sorry
back in you know 87 Dec brought what
became is is into ANSI which is the
American part of OSI so as the protocol
for OSI and it was actually the decnet
phase five protocol it did clmp which
was the OSI IP and that's all it did the
next year this thing called an
assessment phase two happened and it was
one third of a t1 built out of great big
piles of IBM Artie's it needed an IG p
so jakob found an early draft of is is
and wrote a routing protocol around the
same time OSPF was starting in the ihds
because people thought they needed a
link state code of our rip wasn't really
going to take us too far into the future
so they actually grabbed the eye-fi
aspect and started with that because
link state protocols are notoriously
hard to do well so to their credit they
took one that was likely to work and
based on that and one very cold December
in Ann Arbor and 98 or 88 excuse me a
bunch of the usual suspects got together
and said hey we could extend is is for
IP just slap some TL DS in there it'll
be great
89 the OSPF RFC was published
Rodion remember them started shipping
OSPF is is was moving along in the iso
standards body and i think was the
honolulu IETF in 89 where there was much
sort of public shouting about duo is is
and OS PS and which one should go
forward as a standard and and so the
IETF blessed them both as standards
going forward but OSPF is preferred it
meanwhile behind the scenes all the
right people were talking to one another
and so there was lots of stealing the
protocol features going on behind the
scenes 90 is the duo is is RFC was
published 91 the next OSPF spec was
published cisco shipped OSPF in 91 I
believe and there was also is is for OSI
only shipped that year 92 there was a a
partnership between Jack and Cisco and
they made this two little router about
the size of the VCR tape and it needed
it was running cisco software but it
needed to support phase 5 decnet so
cisco started shipping IP capable eius
eius at that point and OSPF meanwhile
was taking off everywhere and nobody was
using is is 93 this is the first
shadowing part Novell published a spec
for a routing protocol for ITX because I
px rip wasn't good enough they had made
a couple of stabs at defining a link
state protocol for IP x but link state
protocols are notoriously hard so they
got smart took is is changed a couple of
things that neil didn't like publish
this back the next year cisco shipped NL
SP but since n LSD was so much like is
is it was decided that rather than
having two separate implementations of
almost the same protocol there would be
one implementation with 10 or 15 places
where it says if NOS p do this if i ask
you
as a side effect most of ISS got
rewritten and about that same time this
concept of a large ISP started popping
up and people like you you net and MCI
were knocking on our door saying what
IGP should we run and since is ice had
been recently rewritten at the time and
since there had been some interesting
field issues with OSPF and said let's
use is ice it'll be great there was also
this NSF mandate that you had to support
GL NP but and that's the revisionist
history that everyone uses for why
everyone's running is I us now but it
really didn't matter that much 95 the
ISPs started deploying this stuff he
went through the usual cycle of panic
and disaster and repair and things
stabilized pretty nicely is is continued
to spread within the niche because
people looked at the unit said well
their network seems to be working
let's do the same thing that they are
and so it sort of snowballs within the
niche is is became fairly popular and in
fact some people started switching from
us yes because they wanted to be like
the big guys so that they decided to run
is is interestingly it became a barrier
to entry for people building routers
which it was not intentional at Cisco to
choose is is because no one else had it
but as it turned out it was a handy way
of keeping the riffraff out of the out
of the router market going forward you
can read this back it's not that hard
other folks started shipping juniper
shipped in Hardware in 98 I think now
both protocols have continued to be
extended traffic engineering is probably
the most notable extension to both
protocols I'm going forward and here we
are today the two protocols are really
if you stand back far enough they look a
lot the same and this is not too
surprising because they started from the
same place they're both link state
algorithms and only state protocol each
router distributes it's it's local
neighborhood and floods it within the
within the network and everybody ends up
with a map of the whole network and then
you calculate raps based on the math you
have they both have a two level
hierarchy and OSPF you have the backbone
area and nonzero areas and ayakashi have
level 1 and level 2 pretty much the same
thing
they're both deployed for some value of
widely deployed and there are multiple
interoperable implementations of both
now OSPF if I had to characterize each
one OSPF isn't optimized there was a lot
of hand-wringing back in the late 80s
about we want this to be you know as
lean and mean and so directed toward
ipv4 and so and we want all the
mechanisms mechanisms to work just
perfectly and to make the adjacencies
come up just a little bit faster and so
there's a lot of sort of tinkering kind
of complexity in OSPF ifs was a lot
simpler on the other hand it was not
originally designed as an IP protocol
and so there's some weird clunkiness to
it like you have to assign OSI addresses
to your IP only routers encapsulation
for sorta from the bottom up here OSPF
runs on top of IP which is the way IP
routing protocols have have
traditionally been done one of the side
effects is you can have virtual links
since you're sending IP packets you can
send an OSPF packet from here to the
other side of the planet if you aren't
the downside of that is it also means
that people can watch OSPF denial of
service attacks at your network since
you're just sending in a variety packets
he can lob them in if LSA is get really
big you use IP fragmentation to make
them sit one of the supposed to
advantages of the IP and capsulation is
you can use vc MUX and caps on ATM which
is basically a null encapsulation
everything on your VC has to be IP so if
you're running OSPF you turn off all of
your encapsulation then you configure
tcp action the single ATM cell and it'll
buy you a 30% bandwidth gain or
something on your ATM network is is on
the other hand runs directly over layer
to sort of architectural e next to IP
and to me that's always made more sense
because you outing the protocol your
routing protocol runs on top of always
being slightly strange but it does mean
that you can't do virtual
link's without doing true tunneling to
do things like partition repair and
there is something respect for it that I
think only Jack ever bothered to
implement and it's certainly not
deployed the fact that it doesn't run on
i.t means it's fairly difficult to spoof
because there's no way to get an is is
packet you know into the inside of your
network from the outside because it's
not an IP packet you know so unless you
accidentally leave a GRE tunnel open or
something you can't do it it does
require a snapping capsulation because
it's not an IP packet and so you lose
your 30% overhead in your ATM network
but connects mate came up with this cute
hack where you just look at the first
byte and if it says 40 through for asset
must be IP if it is 81 MSB is is and
this is in fact the way you discriminate
protocols in OSI so it's somewhat ironic
but that's a whole lot easier than
trying to run is is an up of IP which
there is a draft spec for that doesn't
seem to be garnering much interest
because there's an easy hack to make it
work both of them support lands and
points and point links in pretty much
the same ways is is does not have an NB
m a mode non-broadcast multi accesses
there's no specific support for things
like frame really an ATM if you want to
use those networks you can either model
them as a LAN and expect full
connectivity fully transitive
connectivity or you model them as assets
and point-to-point a set of points point
Lakes which is what they really are but
is eyes relies on the operating system
to do that for you so in Cisco parlance
you have to have point-to-point sub
interfaces in order to make iOS work
safely because the trying to run it as a
land is just insane there's an NB ma
mode and OSPF in the original stack
which is it takes a whole lot of
configuration and you're still out of
luck if you lose your link to the
designated router there is a more recent
draft
I'm not sure what the standardization
status but it's widely deployed the
point-to-multipoint mode which
essentially implements point-to-point
sub interfaces but does it inside the
routing protocol so there if you have an
operating system that can't do virtual
interfaces or if there's too much
overhead and you don't want to generate
a separate you know sub-interface reach
of your 500 ATM circuits
point-to-multipoint can be handy that
way
packet encoding then the number the
amount of hand-wringing in 1989 over how
the packet should look was really
amusing it was just you know 32-bit
alignment was you know there's the holy
ground and and there's much argue about
what was most efficient we're not
talking about switching data packets
here these are these are relatively you
know sparse control traffic but you know
should the bits go on the left side of
the word or the right side of the word
so you get came up with really nice
pictures and looks great in the spec but
it really accomplished nothing else what
it did not accomplish is extensibility
all the fields are positional you can't
sort of add an extra thing under the
under router LSA because you found of an
interesting thing that you wanted to
extend it with you can't do that so you
can't extend LSAs by using opaque LSAs
but you can't extend hellos so if you
wanted to say support ipv6 and notice
yes you have to rewrite the protocol
which is what they did there let's see
and it unrecognized I'll say types is
thrown on the floor so you can't really
add new LSA types either ok Galois say
is we added a few years ago and enough
people support them now so that they're
likely to get from one side of your
network to the other eius eius on the
other hand is TLV encoded type so
there's a feel that says type and then
there's a feel that says this is how
long the data is and then a bunch of
data then I sparked about that encoding
is that you can skip those and go on to
the next feel of V if you don't
understand the type so the spec says if
you don't understand a type field you
skip it
go on so it provides you a crude hook
for extensibility and you can extend all
of the packet types because they all
have TLV encoding in them which is how
you manage to say make hellos carry IP
address information is just through
another TLV onion you can nest clvs in
theory you can design a TLV which is
defined as Moorthy all these inside it
so if you want to create a structured
piece of data you can do it that doesn't
exist in the base back but the a couple
of the recent extensions are included
that leg and OSPF
uses the same concept in the traffic
engineering extension so the nice part
about that is you can add things to the
traffic engineering part of it in the
future and still be backward compatible
in theory with earlier versions that
support traffic engineering or backward
compatible with versions that don't
support it at all
both protocols support areas and a two
level hierarchy with a blob in the
middle and a bunch of blobs attached to
the edges of it this reduces the the
route calculation on each router because
it doesn't see all of the details the
entire network it just uses the detail
of the areas that is connected to you
know SPF the area boundary is in the
middle of the router so you assign on an
interface planar page basis which area
of the interface is going to go in IFC
is on the other hand the area boundary
is on a link rather than in the router
and people find this really hard to
picture and it was done this way not so
that you could have lots of areas
because the idea was you didn't have
very many areas they're going to be big
and what you want to be able to do is
merge them and split them apart as your
network changed so it as it turns out
most people can't seem to picture this
in their heads and you know that makes
it fail my test score is this
displayable
there are some people starting to look
at multi-level is is but there hasn't
been much need for it because even in
the largest core ISPs they've been
running one flat area and it seems to
work just fine now database granularity
is probably the key design different
between high Esiason OSPF and a lot of
the details of the way the protocol is
unfold are driven by this now in in OSPF
the idea was the anatomic hunk in your
database should be as small as possible
so if you have 10,000 externals in your
SDF domain there are 10,000 little lsas
and each one is a separate thing you can
look up in the database and each one is
a separate thing that has to be sent and
acknowledged and the idea was that if
you have that fine granularity than if
you have say 1 external out there that's
flapping then you just send this little
update with a 1 LSA in it for each flap
now network and router LSA since there's
only one router LSA per router and one
network Alice April and those things can
get arbitrarily large so as it turns out
since people don't usually put lots and
lots of externals into their OSPF
domains you tend to end up with a few
fairly large LSAs anyhow when it's time
to flood these things you build update
packets out of multiple Alice A's
because they may be really small but you
wanted sending packets so there's a
bunch of complexity in deciding how to
build an LSA update when you send it and
since each router is generated
separately the packet that goes through
the network changes at each hop it gets
bigger and smaller and the contents may
change because each router has a
different view of what needs to be
forwarded is is on the other hand the
database is built out of link state
packets so each one is a bundle of stuff
and the originating routers can build
them however it wants so it'll throw
links between routers and externals and
stubs and whatever else you want any way
it wants into this hunk and that hunk is
what gets flooded and what you can look
up in your database and and each of
those is flooded and intact from hop by
hop across the network so the LSP is
that one router generates is exactly the
same a low speed
show up on the other side of the network
what that means is that that LC has to
be small enough to fit through any link
in the network so the size of the nel SP
is an architectural constant just
essentially 1500 minus a few bytes the
downside of this is that if you have one
you know if you have just 1500 byte LSP
and there's one piece of information
that's changing in the middle of it you
keep sending the 1500 bytes as it turns
out the 1500 bytes don't matter to the
packet count that matters so look at the
cost of processing incoming you know the
overhead is the packet rate not the
number of bytes you can throw away the
bytes pretty efficiently if you know
what you're doing
and you can also do things like notice
that a few things are flapping and move
them off to their own little LSP since
you can pack them any way you want I
don't think anyone's been crazy enough
to try to do that because it doesn't
really matter but you could in theory
make it even more complicated when each
of these boxes brings up a chance
protocols brings up neighbors you send
hellos and each hello essentially has an
a I heard you mechanism to establish
two-way communication there is a
settable rate at which you send these
things and a settable rate at which they
expire because if your router crashes
there's you wait the dead time and then
you declare the other guy to be down you
know SPF all of the holding timers and
hello intervals have to be identical on
an on a subnet and if you try to change
one of them then those hellos are lost
and it's very difficult to actually
change your hello timers without
disrupting your network it changes them
all in less than 40 seconds then the
network would stay up but you have to
type really fast or have really scary
scripts right eius eius there's this
funny padding stuff which has caused
nothing but grief the idea was to detect
links that were less than 1500 bytes of
which there are very few media in the
world that have smaller ends he is so
the idea was that in some cases you've
had these at 252 MTU size and if the
other side can't receive them then you
probably don't want to bring up that
link because the LSPs won't be able
make it across just remember they may be
1,500 bytes you can't fragment them
they're always the same size as it turns
out this is useless and it's caused
nothing but support calls and has never
done anything good for anybody so you
don't actually have to pad them and
nobody should be checking on the receive
side to see whether anything is padded
so in fact you didn't decide not to have
them and no one should care so in some
cases were only padding to 1500 rather
than to MTU if you still trying to
bridge FDDI if you Ethernet and some
people were trying to do that and
wondering why the adjacencies wouldn't
come up in one direction that's a lot OS
PF there is now a check in the database
exchange for MCU matches and the you'll
get stuck in X start state if you're him
to use aren't set the same the reason
they have to be the same is they the guy
who is creating the links they update
packet made build it to MTU size on a
link basis so if one guy thinks going to
4k and the other guy thinks it's 1500
and the guy 1500 and can't receive jumbo
grams then your network is in a world
that heard now when neighbors first come
up you have to synchronize databases
because the whole algorithm is based on
everybody has the same information and
essentially what you do is you say
here's everything in my database you
know and in one case your neighbor will
figure out what you're missing and send
it to you or in the other case you
figure out what you're missing and
asking for it but that's essentially the
way the process works but the
granularity of the database is a huge
issue here you know SPF you may have
literally tens of thousands of items
that you have to synchronize between
adjacent routers because the granularity
is very fine so there's this amazingly
complex and frankly brain-dead protocol
for synchronizing databases it's weird
it's the windows eyes of one and
master/slave and all this stuff and the
idea was you synchronize the routers but
you don't want to
move traffic across the Lincoln so the
databases are synchronized so there's
all these phases that you move through
and you don't declare the link to be up
until you reach full state and and that
way you don't end up black calling
traffic and a lot of the complexity of
OSPF is tied up in this whole database
exchange process and it's really a side
effect of the granularity and it takes a
whole bunch of DVD packets going back
and forth to list all of these LSA is in
your network eius eius basically says
and flooding is what synchronizes
databases so we'll just turn on and plug
in and the right thing will happen and
things will become synchronized now and
this is that easy because remember LSPs
can be big and you know there aren't
very many of them and so it doesn't take
much to say this is what my view of the
world looks like because there aren't
very many items in it so in a couple of
packets you can describe your entire
database so the things called complete
sequence number of packets see snps and
if you're really worried about
transiting traffic before you have a
full picture there's a really great hack
there's a bit called the overload bit
which is really there to say I've run
out of memory I don't have the whole
database please don't forward packets
through me and everyone calculates SPF
around the router well what you can do
is turn on the bit when you're booting
out and kind of wait around and say well
I haven't seen any new LS B's for a
while I must have everything in turn the
bit off since it's probabilistic anyhow
that's probably a good thing to do and
it's about 10 lines of code but that's
not what the bit was for but there's a
whole bunch of opportunistic hacks in
eius eius that I thought happened to
turn out to be really handy that way
both of them have this designated router
concept on lands the idea is if you have
10 routers on a LAN
[Music]
if you just did hellos and brought up
adjacencies each of those 10 would have
an addition C to the other 9 and you'd
end up with you know order 100
adjacencies and order 100 entries in
their link state database and so a
designated router is elected and it
models the land as a node and everybody
is adjacent to the land
in the case of 10 routers you have 10
adjacencies to the land they both use
the same concept OSPF they wanted to
optimize they want to minimize the
failure time if the designated router
fail partly because it there's so much
overhead in becoming adjacent because
you got to toss all those DVD packets
back and forth so you'd find a backup
designated router and it knows to jump
in if the if the main designated router
goes down furthermore they didn't want
the VR to hop around if a new guy came
in and said my be our priority is higher
the OSPF designer said well we don't
really want that guy to become VR
because it'll disrupt the network and so
the the giro ship stitch to the last guy
that got it and so this is not
disruptive but it's also
non-deterministic if you've ever played
with a network and tried to make a
particular router your designated router
you'll find that it's arbitrarily
difficult with OSDs and the algorithm is
fairly complex and hard to understand in
is is everybody just says I'm adjacent
because the there's so little overhead
in synchronizing databases so you don't
you know SPF you don't you're only
adjacent to the designated router and
the backup designated router and it's
nobody else in the land and as I say
we're adjacent there's a GRA election a
really simple stupid ER election scheme
if the gr dies there's no backup DRS so
everyone has to elect a new one the
overhead of doing that is really just
the time to detect the dr has failed
because everybody is already
synchronized so there's no huge database
exchange thing to go through it's
deterministic because it's based first
on the priority that you advertise in
your hello and second by the highest MAC
address and but if you don't really want
the dr to hop around where the new guy
comes in with a higher priority there's
a hack in NL SP where you say if when
you become dr bump up your priority by
20 points and that effectively makes it
sticky and it's you know five lines of
code and it's once again an accident of
the design of either size certainly
what's the thought of that line
land flooding everybody likes you
multicast packets on lands because
they're so wonderful and they save so
much but if you're sending a multicast
and you're happy at unicast
acts back you've saved half of your
packets and half is not an interesting
number now unless you're so bandwidth
clogged that you can't even support the
protocol on the land in which case
you're so dead because you can't even
live data throwing the saving half the
package is really an uninteresting
optimization there's a whole bunch of
per neighbor state because you have to
keep if you're flooding it you're the
dir you're flooding it's 100 routers you
have to maintain stay for each of the
hundred routers as to who needs to have
a retransmission who's active and so on
and so forth then there's a bunch of
acknowledgment suppression of stuff
because they wanted to optimize the
packet count even though they weren't
optimizing the packet count so there's
some tricks for not acknowledging under
certain conditions as a whole bunch of
mysterious rules in the acknowledgement
scheme but it's also not that exciting
and in particular if the more routers
you add the more flooding traffic you
get it grows as the number of routers
because of the Act essentially eius eius
has actually a fairly cool scheme which
is whoever has a new LSP multicast stood
on the land so everybody receives it
there's no acknowledgment and instead
what happens is the dr periodically
multicast his view of the world and if
everybody agrees with his view of the
world then nothing else happens if one
of the other guys says hey the dr is
missing something he'll send the LSP to
the dr well he'll flood it on the land
and everybody will hear and if the dr
you know if someone who says boy i'm
missing something the dr has and you can
send a p SNP which is essentially a
request for the the LSP so once you're
synchronized or you know under normal
circumstances the traffic is the
flooding traffic is constant regardless
of the number of routers because there's
one flood and there's one D are sending
c snps no matter how many neighbors you
have there's still fallow traffic so
it's not completely flat but named
flooding it's flat so it's really cool
but it doesn't matter because nobody
puts hundreds of routers on a land so
so well one of the big complaints about
is is is that in the base spec link
metrics are six bits wide which doesn't
give you a lot of granularity for trying
to map them to link speeds and that sort
of thing the reason that was done is
there's a an optimization you can make
in the route calculation that will
remove an order log and out of the cost
of the calculation but CPUs are really
fast and LSPs even in the SPF even in
the biggest networks seem to take on the
order of milliseconds and so you know
it's really pointless but it did make it
really hard to assign meaningful metrics
[Music]
so there's an a wide metric extension
which is now broadly available in your
favorite vendors routers which expands
them so that they're as big as or maybe
bigger than OSP ops and you can do all
the your favorite metric games with it
one of the other complaints about is is
is that they went folds the other way
from OSPF in terms of how much
information went into level one areas in
OSPF the default is you send everything
in two nonzero areas so you have optimal
routing you don't have all the
complexity of the topology outside the
area but you have each individual wraps
you know the best exit point from the
area in is is they went full the other
way and said the only thing will
advertising the level one is default and
you go to the nearest level two router
and follow that out to the world and
that may not be the optimal exit path as
it turns out people really really like
optimal exits from there from areas so
there's a route leaking extension to ISS
now so you can in fact leak your level
two wrapped into level one and get
optimal routing out of the area both
protocols support md5 authentication use
it wisely particularly with OSPF because
I can launch OSPF packet bombs in your
network you'll hopefully be packet
filtering on the edges of your network
and throwing away all OSPF packets that
are coming in from the edges but and
that's probably you want to do that in
addition to cryptographic because I can
still send you
100 megabits of OSPF package with bad
check sums on them and kill your router
and it's
IGP hacks are really really dangerous
if you're lucky your whole network melts
down and if you're unlucky someone's
cover enough to subvert it that could be
very interesting
there are MPLS extensions to both
protocols and in fact they're identical
the idea is you're carrying around this
extra link information how much
bandwidth is available on this link what
policy color is this link and you used
the routing protocol as a mule to carry
all this data around and then there's a
separate traffic engineering module
which is not part of the protocol which
looks at this database and says oh I
want to set up a the other LSP overuse
terminology from one end of the network
to the other and it can find a path with
the right policy and so on and so forth
since they're independent of the
protocols they are absolutely identical
by design so these two extensions are in
lockstep in the IETF scalability
everybody worries about scalability but
nobody does anything about it
scalability is almost a non-issue in
terms of what the protocols are capable
of we'll get to the one case where it's
actually interesting in theory your SPF
topology is limited by how much you can
stuff in a router LSA because you'd
rather get one router a let's say it
can't be bigger than 64 K because that's
as big as an IP packet can be so you can
get about 5,000 links in it so it's hard
to imagine a router with 5,000 neighbors
but I've seen routers with 400 neighbors
an order of magnitude doesn't take that
long but it's it's kind of pushing it in
other ways as to whether this is in fact
practical or sane to have a topology
like that externals and in Terraria
routes are essentially you can have a
billion you have billions of them until
you run out of LSA IDs in eius eius
you're limited by how many LSPs a single
router can issue and each product an
issue 256 LSPs
nominally fourteen hundred and seventy
bytes of data and you have to pack
everything you can have you want to
advertise into that much and that in
fact well not if you were foolish enough
to dump full BGP routing into is is you
will run out of space about ten percent
of the way into the you know into the
the redistribution and not be able to
advertise the rest you can in fact come
up with various interesting hacks like
having a fake land you know to pop
topological to look like a land and all
you do is face is this this air sacs
land that has a zero possible link to
view and then you get another 256 LSPs
and you can do is up to 256 of those and
if that's not enough you can create you
can act like two routers and that are
adjacent to one another because you can
just lie through your teeth in in what
you send out to the rest of the network
and as long as you act like what you're
advertising then no one can tell but at
the end of the day if you haven't even
slightly same network none of this
matters you know you shouldn't run out
of space this one's a little bit more
interesting when you flood an entry into
the you know out into the world it has a
lifetime and if your router crashes
you've sent all the stuff out into the
network if you die eventually all of the
information you flooded will die by
itself but since it dies by itself if
you're still alive you have to keep
refreshing it so that it doesn't die
when you don't want it to in is is
there's a lifetime field which says this
is how long I want this LSP to live 16
bits wide which and it's in second so
you get up to 18 hours and I know one by
one basis you can pick this and send it
out and as long as you refresh it in 18
point six eight hours you're fine in
OSPF for some reason they decided they
wanted to count up rather than down so
the field in ospf is the age and you set
it to zero and you send it out and then
it counts upward and since you haven't
told anybody how long it should live for
there's an architectural constant which
says one hour in one hour seems like a
long time
[Music]
but if in fact you redistribute full
routing into OSPF you'll be refreshing
on average if you smooth it perfectly
every 23 milliseconds just in refresh
load with nothing interesting happening
in the network now of course doing that
is crazy but there is a do not age LSA
which is created for the demand routing
stuff which in theory you could press
into into service or you can send it out
and it just lives forever and you throw
it away if connectivity to you fails but
that's not backward-compatible you can't
if you deploy this in your network today
with with implementations that don't
support it your network will get weird
so you can't really get there from here
unless you want to cut over your entire
network but at the end of the day if you
don't do something stupid it shouldn't
matter so don't do anything stupid now
this is the only interesting issue is
what's the load of flooding and it's
only interesting if you have one of
these networks that is a full mesh of
ATM or frame relay pcs and a number of
large ISPs have built network with
hundreds you know so with 300 routers
you have 90,000 links and each of them
is a point-to-point link and when the
flooding algorithm says when you receive
a new LSD or LSA you flood it out every
other interface you have so if you have
300 routers something happens the one
router sends it to the other 299 drivers
each of those says oh this is new I need
to send it to the other 299 routers so
boom boom you get N squared copies of it
and each of those is order in in size
because it's typically the router LSA or
the LSP which gets bigger with the
number of routers so if a link fails you
get order n cubed information banging
around now if a router fails since your
adjacent to everybody all of the other
routers have to flood is their router
LSA or LSP again so then you get order n
to the fourth information
hammering around and in fact a number of
probably around 96 this started to
become a serious problem
and we came up with a happy in is is it
just happened to be built in such a way
that you could just kind of not bother
to flooded out a bunch of your links and
no one would notice and since you could
in theory partition your flood you know
what you're doing is creating a flooding
topology by hands and you could in
theory partition that but you can send
SI snps periodically which will heal all
of the partitions so it's an awful half
but the entire world is depending on it
right now
oh SPF there isn't any way to do this
without changing the protocol the is I
attack is completely backward compatible
the guy at the other end doesn't have to
know your dunya and so this is really
the only serious scaling issue in any of
these protocols and it's only serious if
you have a really crazy network
pragmatism the OSPF spec is reads really
well and if you want to implement a
protocol and you don't really know much
about routing protocols you could pick
it up and do everything that it says in
the order that it says you're very
likely end up with something that works
it will not scale really well but it
will work the problem is that the spec
number says why do you do these things
there's a long list of rules and so if
you stray outside of those rules you're
you're a test pilot you're in no-man's
land so you you have to if you want to
build a really scalable OSPF product you
have to really really intuitively
understand everything about the protocol
before you try to do it or it will fail
in interesting ways which makes it a
barrier to entry in high end router
market which always works for me
um is is is a simple protocol but it's
in this arcane foreign language called
ISO speak and if you learn the lingo
it's actually pretty straightforward and
it's a simple protocol plus there's so
much boilerplate on the spec that as the
pages fall off you won't hit anything
important so I actually have my original
1990 hard copy is is we just lost a
dozen pages up front
back and I never worry about that's
great and this is also barrier to entry
in the high-end router market because
people look at the spec and go ah so
once again you have to know the protocol
intuitively in order to be able to
understand this is what the language is
saying in order to go implement the
simple protocol now there was a lot of
shouting over the years about is is
because it was an OSI protocol and it
was going to be you know you'd have to
go to foreign countries in sit in rooms
with people wearing ties in order to
make any changes to the protocol as it
turns out OSI died and nobody other than
a few people cared in the IETF about ISS
so in fact it's really easy to extend
because you get the same ten people
together in the room and you say let's
do this everyone says you asking you you
print it and send out an internet draft
and people go off and implement it and
it's fine this is a lot harder to do
with OSPF because everybody's an expert
and lots of shouting in the inner them
and so forth is is because it is run in
the biggest and scariest networks in the
world that's a tremendous amount of
self-interest on the part of the vendors
to make sure that it really really works
and when it gets extended the extensions
happen quickly and they're and they're
happening because they're necessary not
because they're fun so things tend to
happen quickly
they tend to scale well they tend to be
stable quickly because everybody is
screwed if if the implementation is bad
oh SPF is fairly difficult to extend
because it wasn't designed to be
extensible and fact people were very
proud that this is I got an ipv4 only
protocol and itv4 will be great for the
rest of eternity and then ipv6 came
along so they had to start over so
there's this whole thing it's called
OSPF v3 it has you know unless you step
back from it it doesn't really look very
much like OSPF v2 so if you want LSPs
for ipv6 they're gonna have to wait for
your vendors to sit down and implement a
protocol it's even more complicated than
the last one is is the encoding is
pretty simple minded but it as it turns
out it's easy to
and so you know coming up with the ipv6
spec change for is is a weekend project
you know and coding it is probably you
know a two-week project if the rest of
the ipv6 stuff is already in place and
as it turns out it was IPX ready as well
somebody talked about extending for
appletalk once but they never happened
oh SPF was optimized for things that
don't matter and there's much paranoia
about using link bandwidth which when
the internet was made out of 9.6 links
probably made more sense the cpu
alignment you know when you had four
point seven seven megahertz 8080 s 80 88
you know maybe it mattered moving all
those bikes around but none of that
matters anymore
is iOS is optimized for things like
large lands and a cheap SPF but none of
those things matter anymore either so
there's all these great optimizations
that are really complicated and they
don't matter but we can't get rid of
them and I guess this shows the the the
fallacy of early optimization it's true
in software and it's true in protocols
if you're going to deploy this it's
probably a lot easier to find the people
that know about OSPF is lots of books
and you know lots of wonderful you know
seminars you can go to and everybody
knows about OSPF and it uses words like
packet that everybody's familiar with is
iOS on the other hand is well understood
in this niche and people are very
comfortable with it in the large isp
market and people will have demonstrated
they can build really in the same lee
large networks with it and that they
work so if you're trying to decide what
which protocol should I use these are
things to consider at the end of the day
other than that crazy full mesh case the
protocols are pretty much the same in
terms of what they do and how they scale
so trying to choose one of the other by
technical means only it's it's a wash
you know and stability and scalability
really boil down to how well is
implemented you can you can build wildly
unscalable implementation
or worse implementations that work until
you reach a point and then they fall off
the cliff which is the way these
protocols usually fail and that's no fun
at all but it's not the protocol design
ultimately the drive step the biggest
factor is probably you know what are you
comfortable with how do you want to
design it or who can you find to run
your network and have they ever heard of
is is before it's not maybe you should I
will use SDF there's been some question
about do we really need two protocols
and in fact as time has gone on they've
become more and more the same but since
they're more and more the same the irony
is that nobody wants to switch because
there's known a motivation to switch
because they do the same thing and
there's entrenched constituencies that
people that are running them it deploys
the network and changing them in the
middle of the weekend you know on a
Saturday night because you want to
switch protocols people do it but it's
not really very much fun and as long as
there's two protocols
you'll never get everybody to agree on
which one they want and not even the the
demise of ipv4 will help because there
is already these six versions of both
protocols and people will continue to
argue so they never go away there
they're both over ten years old they're
getting a little long in the tooth but
they still work and the graphs very
they're based on goes back to assembly
lines in the system theory you know in
the fifties they're still works in
progress even after ten years which is
you know testimony to their longevity
and and their extensibility within the
area that they're being extended
[Music]
diversity is a good thing for a lot of
reasons you know you get cross
fertilization you get you know diver
divergent opinions on things which have
proven to improve both protocols along
the way and of course it's job security
of this place is much to know so well
I'll keep our jobs use the one that
makes the most sense it's all to me what
it boils down to there's there's no
there's no magic right answer they both
probably make sense to everybody so use
the one that you're most comfortable
well that's it
Thank You Deb time for questions anybody
first thing with a short question about
Reggie piece where they can until people
are heading for microphones or not using
both in the networks people have used
both protocols in a network usually when
they're transitioning from one to the
other so you turn them both on and you
set the administrative distance or
preference of one higher than the other
people have used them use multiple
protocols to get administrative barriers
or to you know or or to get three
layered networks and scary things like
that ultimately you have to be really
really careful with your about
redistribution like you do whenever you
do registration mutual redistribution is
really dangerous so try not to do things
like that unless you feel you really
have to and then ask your vendor and
they'll try to talk you out of it yes
Chris big littoral zone technologies how
many network prefixes you put in your
NGP how many network prefixes dude well
I'm a vendor so I don't run a network so
I have seen you know typically thousands
in large ISPs when I've gotten a chance
to poke around inside them I've seen one
multi area OSPF that had about 2,000
summaries and you know 70 routers in the
area that I could see in the router that
I had a picture picture out I've seen
you know lots of redistribute connected
zorats juniper equivalent at the edges
of large networks so you see you know a
couple of thousands source W things
around the edges and people try to
eliminate that stuff or to summarize it
as best they can and at those levels you
know all of the implementations seem to
do jugg along just fine and once again
it's not the number in there that's the
real issue if the topology is where
scalability gets interesting anybody
else what's the distribution of
deployment of distance lecture protocols
like the IGR PS crystal proprietary
versus is is and OSPF I know distance
effects are more likely to be in spies
in enterprise networks they also in
smaller ICS or I've seen people using
rip in small iced teas and it's usually
because they have certain vendors
terminal servers that don't support
better protocols the problem with you
know traditional DV protocols is hold
down and I once was dialing into an ISP
in Santa Cruz and switched phone numbers
and went to the other router for some
reason I didn't have any connectivity
for three minutes I said oh they're
running ribs there there are people that
use rifts or sort of edge connectivity
things and redistributed in but to my
knowledge
you know most sizable ISP and most
people in the ISP community are using a
link state protocol II I GRP
if you're in all Cisco network you can
use it has other interesting issues that
I could talk about over here but you
know it's a cisco only and so there's
there's there's a lot of pressure for
people to back away and there aren't
very many ISPs particularly since yep
unless you have all cisco terminal
servers and the whole nine yards then
yeah yeah GRP is a non-starter thing
take one more they didn't seem to be
matching the scalability issues between
eius eius a notice appear and yet you
said is is is widely used in the large
ISPs why is that I touch down a bit on
the history part of it is an accident of
what the state of Cisco's
implementations at the time the large
IOC's were choosing now that was really
the driver for how ISI has got a
foothold
then it sort of snowballs because people
saw what the other guys were doing and
wanted to do the same thing because it
seems like it was working
and ultimately the full mesh issues
became added you know became an issue
but it was sort of an issue after the
fact because they're already running is
I am in the few networks that they had
this topology and so it was yet another
reason that you could never possibly
switch but other than that it's mostly
an accident of history thank you very
much
[Music]
[Applause]