hi everyone thanks for joining my talk
this is my first time doing b-sides for
Greenville I've met him several times in
the past and it's just never really
lined up with my schedule so I'm really
happy to be part of this even though it
is remote so my my talk is it's a topic
that is very dear to me which is on on
writing I guess open source software for
application security purposes so kind of
similar to the previous talk but
different and most of what I'm gonna be
doing here is it's really kind of a
show-and-tell and some of the projects
that I've worked on but I also want to
get into a little bit of technical
details in case people are interested in
doing some of their own and yeah so
that's basically it so it's about burp
suite and but let me let me get into
first of all my bio I am my name is
Jason go home I wear many many hats
sometimes far too many so a security
consulting I do I was teaching a class
this week on application security I also
do software development you know so a
bunch of stuff and and I love
application security so i although i do
pen testing and you know various
different aspects of that application
security is kind of where where i'm
really feel comfortable so you know i've
I'm an OS lifetime member I'm a regular
at other B sides this is like I said
this is my first time here but for those
who know me you've probably seen me
before it be sighs Asheville or
Charleston or Charlotte you know I've
worked with Shaha a lot in the past as
well I've been programming for a really
long time hate to admit it but yeah my
first computer was a Commodore vic-20 it
is the one that's actually on this slide
I saved up all my money when I was
mowing lawns as a teenager and when I
bought a computer
which was pretty awesome and I started
programming on it mostly how the kids
were playing games on it I was I started
tinkering with it and in my spare time
when I get a little bit now and then I
really like craft beer enough that I
actually brew some of my own so the
picture on here is is one from it's
actually from a couple years ago but
it's a it's a stout that was dry hopped
so that's what all that all the Hawks
are on top there's that's dry humping so
before I get into this I know that my
talk is gonna be around burp suite
extensions and burp suite itself is a
commercial tool but I wanted to take a
minute to acknowledge all of the open
source tools that are out there because
we as information security professionals
we rely very very heavily on open source
tooling the last whole presentation I
think everything in there all the
PowerShell stuff I think everything in
there was all open-source tools a lot of
it extendable and there's a here's a
bunch that are probably familiar to to
anybody's in InfoSec you should be
familiar to at least some of the ones on
here on this screen here especially on
the red team side there's I know more
tools open source to tools evolving on
the blue team side or have been over the
last several years but on the if you're
looking like from the from the attacker
perspective almost everything's always
been open source so we rely very very
heavily on that I want to throw a couple
names out there in case you haven't seen
the names before okay so these aren't
the only people who do open source info
type projects but here's a bunch of them
so thanks all to all of these find
people for all of their contributions
over time it's been really great to be
able to do our job on your shoulders so
very thankful for that
now to get into what I want to talk
about so so for those of you who have
done
pentesting before you should already
know about burbs sweet it's it's the
it's an interception proxy it's the only
real commercial commercially available
proxy and there is a free version you'll
find it in cali and other places but
it's written for those who are it so
this is this is one of the main tools
that we use aside from the browser which
you know you're going to need a browser
when you're talking to web applications
aside from the browser the interception
proxy is the thing that you're going to
use most there are there's more than one
there's a open source version wasp zap
is extremely popular as well but as far
as commercially supportive ones its
birth suite and the reason why why i use
it i just prefer the tooling in it overs
out and and i basically the company I
work for we standardized on this is what
we use so it's for man in the middling
your own traffic so you're gonna be
taking you know whenever you make a web
request it goes through that proxy goes
to the server and then the response
comes back through the proxy and then to
your browser and so in your proxy you
can get a history of everything that's
gone on and then you can also do things
like take one of those requests and then
rerun it and make some changes to it and
build fuzzing tools around it and that
sort of thing so what I when I the I
guess the essence of what I want to dig
into here is the fact that Burke has a
an API you can you can extend it to do
more things so birth extender allows you
to do that it's actually a very rich API
I'll get into some of that functionality
in just a second
in in terms of like there's a lot of
hooks in there you can hook into a lot
of different parts of what it does it
works with Java Python and Ruby so if
you are have any sort of programming
experience in any of those languages you
probably have the skills to extend verb
now that being said I will add a caveat
in there
burp itself is a java application right
so if you're going to extend it and you
have expertise at all in Java then that
is probably the language you want to use
even ports figure that the makers of
burb burb suite they're gonna tell you
that hey you know although all of these
are supported python is actually
supported through JSON and Ruby is
supported through JRuby which are
basically Java wrappers around those so
from from a you know memory management
and program efficiency perspective it's
better to write an extension in Java
because it's a lot easier inside Java to
just you know load some more classes
into the class loader than it is to like
load up an entire Python or Ruby
interpreter so and the other thing is is
the way that it loads those it basically
you can only you can only really run one
or two extensions that are Python or
Ruby at a time whereas the Java
extensions you can actually load up
quite a few without having a significant
impact on the the memory footprint so
alright so that's that part so how does
this work how do we actually build these
so what you do is is part of the API
I'll show it to you in a moment I'll get
into some some demos I just have a few
slides to go through first but the the
extender I burp extender is the sort of
the main interface so it's all it's all
set of interfaces for those familiar
with Java it's just a set of interfaces
that you implement so burp extender is
it has just one method on it which is
register extender callbacks
so you basically implement high burp
extender and then you you you do a
basically implement that regice regice
tur extender callbacks take that
callbacks object and then from there
that's where you can call into that to
to get to hook into the various
different aspects of birth and what can
you do with that there's a bunch of very
useful cool things
so one of these is one of the common
ones is the h IH TP listener and I proxy
listener which basically let you hook
into all of the burp history so you can
on-the-fly examine requests and
responses and even make some changes to
them which is really cool so a lot of
the stuff that burp inherently has in it
you can extend that sort of
functionality inside like for the proxy
history and make your own changes to
things which which can can be very good
for you know certain types of scenarios
there's also a pairing here of I of the
intruder payload generator an intruder
payload processor so both of these work
around intruder which is the fuzzing
tool inside of burp and they let you you
can generate your own dynamic fuzzing
payloads with the generator or you can
process existing payloads with the
payload processor I'm gonna actually
show you one of these in a couple
minutes so and beyond that you have the
ability to plug into where the were the
issues shown so in that I guess that's
in the dashboard now right because it's
all changed from where it used to be so
you can let's let's say you you can you
build an extension that is able to
detect type of vulnerability that the
burp suite doesn't natively tech find
you can have use the scan issue
interface to add your own issues in
there right so then they show up in the
dashboard along with everything else
which is kind of cool you can also as
you've probably seen if you've used any
extensions before a lot of them have
user interfaces they have like extra
tabs that show up on there so there's
this whole mechanism for building those
now if you're building a UI inside of
burp verb for an extension I recommend
that you go down the path of using
IntelliJ for that for your IDE that is
what ports Twitter already uses I talked
to them about this so like building
building a new
tab sort of interface around there is
really not that hard it's kind of a
drag-and-drop sort of thing when you
when you're using that and then you can
plug that in through the tab text editor
message editor extensions there's others
too these are just this is just a
sampling of what's there and then
there's a whole like if you have custom
session management maybe some special
type of token or something like that or
something that needs to be handled you
can actually build custom functionality
around there if it's again if this is
for cases where it falls outside of the
norm okay so that's it for that's
actually pretty much it for slides so
I'm going to hopefully everyone can see
this I am going to show I'm gonna drag
that off there we go okay so this is
burp suite this is what it looks like
you know this is the pro version there
is a community edition which has some of
the features to say but like most of the
automation is disabled the extender API
is actually still available in the
community edition as well so there are a
lot of extensions that will work without
you having to put any money down on it
which is which is kind of nice so we
have on here I'm just going to run
through this very quickly just a couple
of these tabs because they're important
or what I'm going to show after so we
have the the target what's really
important here for what I'm working on
today is the the scope tab so I have I
have a little silly little application
that I've built just for demonstration
purposes and it's it's it's white listed
here in the target scope and that will
come into play a little bit later I have
a proxy the proxy history tab is the
next one right so under proxy there's
the the history we can see that I've
visited exactly one location at this
point in time so I have a browser set up
here with like let's say I just I'll
just
to professional evil calm here so we can
see that as well
oops and now you can see house you know
some more resources have been loaded you
know again if you've done a bunch of
applications security of seeing this
before and then we have intruder this is
our fuzzing tool right so if we have a
request and we want to send that request
multiple times to the server but well
swap out different values like we're
using a list of payloads and we're going
to try you know a list of username
password combinations or something like
that as an example you can use this it's
sort of a mail merge type of
functionality repeater allows you you
can take a request put it into a
repeater and then send that request to
the server multiple times so so far what
I've talked about this is all the
built-in functionality inside of burp
suite and some of that functionality
we'll look at extending in just a second
here okay so extender extender has this
is where the burp extensions get loaded
you can actually load you can bundle up
an extension into a jar file and just
load it directly here which is what
you're gonna do if you're you're
developing one if you're working on it
locally one really nice thing about the
way that they do their class loading on
there is I can take like this nonce
payloader for example I can unselect it
ok now I can go to my my source code on
here recompile and then once that's
recompiled I can then just click this
box again so I don't have to actually
delete it and then bring it back in I
just click the box again and now it will
reload from the whatever version of the
jar file was produced from my ID right
so it has a fairly tight development
cycle on there which is but you know one
of the things that I aim for I don't
like to have like some lengthy you press
a button you have to wait half an hour
before you can actually use something
again or go through you know 30 or 40
different steps to make it work so this
is just a couple of steps it's not too
bad I can mix
changes in the source code bundle up in
another jar file which just takes a
couple seconds and then load it back in
very quickly and then try it out some of
them will have their own tabs so oh wait
hang on before I get to that there's
also the bap store I'm here this is a
definitely worth looking at here so the
BAP store you can see that and it's
although it says store all of these are
free I should point that out too
but it is these are many of the
extensions they're not all of them that
are out there but these are many of the
extensions that have been produced
everything in here is open source and
they all extend the functionality of
burp in a variety of different ways
there's also like a rating system on
there and that sort of thing which is
kind of cool so lots of different things
in there so if you if you're using if
you're doing a web app pen test and
you're using burp and there's you run
into some scenario where you're like oh
man I wish I could see this information
a little differently or a little better
or if I had a you know a little extra
tool to do something before you start
writing one go check and see if somebody
else already did because there's there's
a lot of stuff already out there which
is you know pretty cool there's also the
API tab on here and if you're you're
building if you're building against
Burks so you're making your own
extension you'll need to save these
interface files that's what this button
is for down down here right so that
saves the interface files off that way
you can compile against them
so you'll need that ok so let's look at
an extension so I'm gonna look at co2
first which is an oldie but a goodie and
the reason I bring this one up is is as
time went on when I when I first started
in application security and and
discovered burp and how awesome it was I
I started building extensions when I
needed them for various different
purposes and eventually after you know I
don't know a year a year and a half of
doing that I'm like you know I really
need some way to keep all of these
together
cuz a lot of other people want to use
them and so I I bundled them all
together into what I call co2 and co2 is
a reference back to my home brewing it's
you know carbon dioxide which is also
happens to be the gas that makes you
burp when you drink too much beer
so the I'll just run through a little
bit of functionality here quickly so we
have a sequel mapper so if you've used
sequel map before or if you haven't one
thing that you'll notice when you do
sequel map - even - H on there but
there's also a - page for super help um
it has many many many different options
on there and so I found for me I was
always having trouble remembering you
know which option do I use for what
which switch to use and then also stuff
like like where do I put where what do I
need to double quote or where do a
single quote you know just trying to
figure out all of that because it's a
command-line tool right so I made this
thing here in which you can do with this
is you can take any request out of your
history here so I'm just gonna I'm just
going to take this one here and then you
you send it - this is actually it also
demonstrates one of the other things you
can hook into you can hook into this
context menu which is really helpful so
I can send this to sequel mapper and
then that opens that up inside a co2 and
now you can see the command has been
basically built for you which this one
has a ton of cookies in it but there we
go
okay so so now I can right click copy
that line and then go into sequel map
and basically just from the command line
sequel map space and then just paste my
line in there it it properly quotes
everything if you like need to let's say
not put the cookies in you can unselect
that all of the functionality or most of
it anyway because as it evolves and it's
hard to keep up with but most of the
functionality is is in it's been mapped
from from sequel map has been mapped
into the user interface here so it
allows you to dynamically build that
command so for example like let's say
you go into text techniques you're like
you know I don't want to do the
time-based blind that just takes too
long you can click that and then it'll
automatically put that technique equals
BS quue now how many people knew that
off the top of their head probably not
that many right it's one of those things
I got to go researching the dogs and
figure it out which is fine but you know
I'd rather I'd rather just quickly do
this and then I can right-click and copy
that and then wait and go on my merry
way which is you know makes this a whole
lot easier there is this auto run thing
in here I actually don't use that I put
that in there because I had several
people ask you know is there a way to
run single map directly from within
there and it's like you know but I
actually use it from the command line so
I'll run a command and then I'll up
arrow and then tinker with it a little
bit and then you know run it again that
sort of thing so I actually don't use
the run directly out of here but I know
some people do ok a couple other things
right quick so laudanum
I will admit this particular tab does
not work right now so laudanum is a
project it has worked in the past it's
basically it's for for web shells right
so when you find somewhere to get a
shell onto a web application this would
be the type of file that you want to get
on there now laudanum the project itself
is an older shell and what I was aiming
for with this is I wanted to be able to
dynamically build one that had some
security features in it but also gave
you more of a like using basically using
Ajax requests gave you the feel of a
real terminal right so you you have a
prompt on there you could type something
hit enter and that would send that and
then you see the response come back and
it would move render it as if it was
inside of a terminal so that's kind of
where I want to go with this one I just
really haven't had time to get back to
it and do that but you know would
support PHP JSP war shells ASP and
asp.net s-- that's the idea behind that
one anyway
so a couple that that I do use quite
frequently so the user generator I find
extremely useful there's a lot of cases
that you're like hey you know I need to
I just need a list of users well which
users do I use so and this is based off
of census data so one of the things is
especially when you're sending fuzzing
payloads you have a list of things that
you want to send into an application we
know that sending a bunch of things into
an application can take time right so
there's no way I can send a list of a
million things in that's just gonna take
too long and it's gonna put a lot of
load on the application and we don't we
want to be as we if we can we want to be
nice to it our goal isn't to the denial
service every application that we pen
test so so when we want to list user
names we want we really want is a list
of the most likely user names that will
work and so that's what the goal of this
this particular tab is right so let's
say I have its let's say it's a website
with functionality and we I know that
its functionality that relates to
retirees I'm gonna say okay well let's
pick first names from the 1950s because
all of the data in here is pulled from
census data and so it's the most common
two least common and that's how its
ordered so I can say let me take first
names from the 1950s and I go click
alright and they always for some reason
Scrolls down and so the most common name
from the 1950s was Michael and then came
David and then James John Robert William
Christopher Joseph Jennifer Richard and
so on and so forth down the list so if
I'm looking for first names that that'll
work for me if I'm looking for surnames
I also have those right so I can just
say let's just add surnames and those
are the most common surnames not based
on date that's just the current census
data
all right so Smith Johnson Williams
Brown right so those are your most
common surnames you can also have it
just like combined things so let's say
you know that the user names tend to be
first initial last name for an
organization so what are your most
what's the most likely successful
candidates for that if you have no idea
who actually works there well you can
add the combos on there
and you you can you can guess that
there's a good chance that there's going
to be a J Smith a jeh Johnson and then
Smith the Jay Williams and M Johnson D
Smith like so basically ordered again
orders them by you know what's most
likely going to be available because I'm
gonna need it in a moment I'm gonna grab
first names on here so next name Mangler
this is very simple I put a name I
needed something cuz I I knew that in
this case I knew who some of the people
were that I was and I was looking for a
username harvesting flaw but I didn't
know what the format was for that they
were using for their usernames so if I
put myself on here and just you know
there's a couple of things you can do
and there but basically it gives you a
bunch of different options so I didn't
have to manually go okay well let's try
J Gilliam and Gilliam and Gilliam J and
you know and it just basically spits out
a list that recombines these in
different ways so that was that one
cooler so ramen would digi ninja big
shout out to him and another open source
developer who does a lot of pen testing
as well so he has one of the old tool of
his cool and I asked him I said hey do
you mind if I if I take your tool and
take the concept behind it and basically
rebuild it into burp and that's what
cooler is and so in this one here what
you do is you take let me take
professionally evil ate oh wait hang on
that one's not gonna have anything as a
three or four
I don't know if this will refresh in
there hopefully there we go okay
I needed the actual content to send it
to cooler all right so so you can send
multiple at a time and so the premise
behind cool is that people tend to use
words associated with a website in their
password for that website so if we
extract all of the words from a page
then one of the main purposes for that
would be to see if any of those
someone's use one of these as a password
right so that's what what cooler is so
pretty simple there's some configuration
on there I'm word size and stuff and
stuff but at the end of the day you get
a bunch of words that came off of that
page and then you can you can copy all
of those masher notice also most of
these end in ER i was trying to keep
with the the naming convention inside of
four okay so i'm going to take actually
going to take my list from cooler for
this so i take this list and so you
start off with a input list of words and
then what you're going to do is you're
going to go hey the password
specification which I happen to know in
this case requires an alpha uppercase
lowercase numeric and it needs to be
anywhere between let's say seven carat
well say nine characters and eighteen
and then this actually creates a payload
generator and it will you can also
generate samples on here and the samples
will be mixes of whatever was in the
input and it does start fuzzing them too
it'll start adding like the number one
at the end and if you have symbols that
are required then I'll start putting
exclamation points and you know that
sort of thing the generator if you use
that it basically just keeps going it
keeps generating them indefinitely and
that will show up under intruders so if
I go to payloads here under the payload
type since I've generated it I can go to
extension generated and it will actually
it should show
in this list here there it is I don't
know why it's small it's probably
because I changed my phone so you can
see it better okay so that's that yeah
and then there's there's a couple of
other little bits and pieces on there so
now the problem that I want to show is
because one thing I did want to get into
is a little bit more on developing one
I'll show you a little bit of source
code in a second so I have this this
mocked up silly little login thing and
if we run this let's just run it with a
you know random user I'll just call it
random okay we have no user session with
that user if I try a user that I know is
in the system called test it says login
error try again
so basically the idea here is it's a
it's a login form right and then there's
also this little profile link over here
that I just threw this in here and we're
not authorized we have to be logged in
to get to that so there is a harvesting
flaw on here but it's not a harvesting
flaw that we could normally get get
through with with the built in
functionality inside of bird and the
reason is is because what we can see if
we analyze it which we should always do
right we analyze the the request
response traffic we realize that what's
happening is when we click on something
or sorry when we saw when we submit
something like here was the user random
what's happening is we're getting a
nonce back in this case it was a zero
because the user didn't exist and in the
next case where I put in test user which
I know is a known user in system I got I
actually got a nonce back that nonce was
then used to attempt to login okay so if
we're looking at the request here it's
the user was test the password was
password and the nonce was was the
whatever nonce was produced and I won't
go through you know verifying exactly
how this works I'll just tell you so
basically it's it it requires these two
requests in order to login one to grab a
nonce and
ii actually used that nots to log in the
knots only works once right so this is
meant as a as a method of preventing you
from being able to brute-force through
the login or you know send a whole bunch
of fuzzing traffic to it if i just said
okay well let me try a bunch of users
and and a password list against this and
just keep using reusing the same knots
it would always fail even if i guess the
right password it would still fail and
so that's that's kind of the way this is
built now it does have a bit of a flaw
in that and that although i can't do
that with the built-in tools in burke i
could make my own just think about all i
need to do is is set up my intruder
payload so let me let me just pick one
here like let me take this one here i'm
going to send this to intruder okay so
if you haven't seen this before again
this is like a emil merge type set thing
so I have my users I have my passwords
and then I have these nonces so I need
to figure out how I'm gonna handle those
okay so we'll bill I'm gonna build a
little solution for that actually I
already have it built but I'll build the
code around that and I'll show you show
it to you in a second but before we do
that we need to know what are some valid
users so let's let's look at a slightly
simpler version of this and we know that
the knots that we get back is going to
be a zero when the user doesn't exist
and a longer string when the user does
exist right and that's just by passing a
user into this so let's start with this
okay so I'm going to send that to
intruder and clear this out and for the
user instead of test I want to get some
actual user names right so I'm gonna go
back to CEO to remember how I had the
user generator here I'm gonna take those
I'm going to pass them into I'm sorry
I'm going to pass those into intruder
here
and then I start that attack and it goes
by very quickly and I can tell by the
length that there's at least a Kevin in
adjacent in there okay and you know if I
if I look inside the response I can see
those ones produced nonces all these
other names I got a zero back right so
that's basically for if you haven't seen
this before if you haven't seen a
fuzzing attack before that's basically
what it how it works we're looking for
in the results table we're looking for
what's different what are the outliers
okay so Kevin and Jason are valid so
going back to here if I set this up as a
cluster bomb sorry not this one
number two you set this up as a cluster
bomb we have the test the password and
the nonce cluster bomb is the attack
type that tries combinations of things
okay so our payloads for this our first
payload is going to be user names so we
can just type them in I'll type in Kevin
I'll type in Jason okay
the second one was our password so we
need a password list I happen to have a
short password list I'm going to need a
short one because I need this to run
fast okay and then for the third one
this one gets a little bit tricky so now
we need to generate a nonce and the
nonce we know is based on the user right
so if I go back to that proxy history
and look at how that works we pass any
user we get back a nonce okay I don't
see that so how are we gonna make that
work so what we do is me bring up here's
the nonce payload processor and I
basically have hard-coded this whole
thing so I have the template of that
request I was just showing you right
here okay and then I have here's that
remember how I said here's the one thing
you have to implement right register
it's
callbacks so let me just zoom in just a
little bit here
there we go okay so register extender
callbacks in this case here all I did
was set the extension name from the
callbacks print some output into it so
that way I know the right version is
loaded and then I have a register and
true intruder payload processor and this
whole thing actually is the payload
processor halo processor has two extra
things that you need to implement one is
the name you know so that way you have a
way for it to show up in the interface
and the other one is the actual
processing method method which is
processed payload and it takes the
current payload the original payload and
then the base value as parameters on
there and so based on on those I'm able
to take an existing payload so we're
going to use the username as a payload
and and then make and then return back a
replacement payload
payload a replacement version of that
which we're actually gonna return the
knots so the way this works in here so
inside this block I don't know how easy
that is to see but I'll just tell you
what it's doing it's basically taking
that the username so whatever value
we've used for that and it is
constructing a request that request is
going to request a nonce and we then
parse out the knots and then we return
the knots okay so not too hard one more
like him how far out did I zoom that
okay so going back into burp suite that
was or nonce Pro so what I'm gonna do is
I'm I'm just gonna copy another payload
for the generation of the payload which
is gonna be our names because we already
have those that's the Kevin and Jason we
have in the first the first position
right going back to the positions here
the name was already here
so I'm going to use the name again for
this payload position but I'm going to
then use my custom payload processor to
swap that out for them
so one of the payload processing things
I can do is invoke the burp extension
and anything that I've registered
through the callbacks will show up on
here so I have ASCII payloads is a
different one and then at this nonce
payloader right so I'm going to invoke
that and that's everything that I need
to do so now I can start this attack and
it is in this case it's going to run
very slowly because I'm making these
extra requests out and yeah so this will
take a little while so while this is
going we can let me just explain what we
have here we have the three different
payload positions and their values are
actually showing up in the results table
and what we're looking for again is
something that's different so any
anywhere where the length has changed to
something else and that should tell us
whether or not we've guessed the
password for one of those two users
Kevin or Jason these are going slow so
once we once we've guessed that then
we'll be able to look into the next step
which is you know can we actually login
with that account and then what's inside
of that that profile page that's in
there so one little trick actually if
you have something that's that's
processing along is you can take the
request and reverse that and that way it
kind of shows up at the top like this
makes it a little bit easier to see
right away when you see the length
change on something and there we go
actually there's one that just changed
so now that it has Elsword on it and so
we can see what it is
Kevin's password is not surprisingly
Star Wars okay right because the lengths
the length on that one was different so
that's the outlier which is we're always
looking for the outliers but look at the
response for that when it says success
you are logged in all right so I'm just
going to let that keep going and now I
can go back to my application try Kevin
and the password Star Wars and we'll
just sign in and now it actually says
you are logged in and lo and behold I'm
able to get to the profile which is just
a dummy screen it just
doesn't say you are not authorized
anymore now it says hey this is Kevin's
profile so something's tied to a session
is working alright so we've been able to
log in with the nonce and we can
actually see what happened here in the
the final version of it we use Kevin and
his password and we we actually won't I
don't think we'll see in the history
hang on Kevin yeah there we go so first
it was Kevin and we got the nonce back
and then in the post right after that
Kevin is password and that same nonce
was used and we were able to to log in
with that now when we go to the profile
let me look at the request here one
thing that you'll notice on this one is
there are a whole bunch of cookies in
here I've just said a bunch of dummy
cookies which might make it hard to
figure out well which one of those are
actually important for the session in
which ones aren't so / amyl Iser and
I'll get to that in just one second but
it ties right into parameter which is
another plug-in that extension that I've
been working on and this one initially
started with a hey I just want to be
able to see what everything is inside
when I have a really big test that I'm
working on you know a very busy
application or maybe I'm going across
multiple applications and so what you do
is well let me go back just one second
here what you have to do is first of all
it only analyzes what's in your target
scope it only analyzes what's in your
target scope I have to say that twice
because people go like hey nothing came
up so once that happens it will analyze
your history only right and it just
basically puts everything out into this
nice table it does its best job at
identifying things like here we have
this value here it says if you just
click on one of them down here in the
details in the bottom left in the middle
it'll say hey what is that
and it says yeah it's it's a hex string
of 40 characters in length so it's
probably a sha-1 hash right and they'll
give you a few other details on here is
it'll also do its best guess at guessing
which one of these would be considered
secrets or things that you want to
protect in some way okay
so and that's just purely based off the
name really so you know that we we have
that much information on here one thing
that we might want to do is go okay
looking back at that proxy history on
here we have all of these we might want
to know which one is that those are
important for managing session and which
ones are just basically garbage tokens I
like to call them sometimes that are
maybe used for like analytics or
something like that and one way of doing
that is like you can you can manually go
into I can send this to repeater and
then just you know one by one eliminate
them and see and what how my response
changes I got tired of doing that I'm
lazy so instead of doing that I decided
to spend hours trying to come up with a
solution to do it for me so what I did
is I took this one here and send this
over to cram Eliezer so you can do it
from anywhere in there but basically it
take any requests ideally what you want
is you want to request that is a good
one to use as like a heartbeat of am I
still logged in right so going to a
user's profile would be one it's not
making any changes right you don't want
because this is gonna automate some some
testing on here but it's easy to tell
whether or not the user is still logged
in if you're trying to access their
profile right because if if the session
cookie isn't right it shouldn't give you
their profile if it does then you have
another whole problem on there um so I
can send this to parameter and what it
does is underneath the sessions tab it
opens this up and you can first of all
verify the baseline I like I like to do
that first that's that's basically run
that same request again and I can verify
in the response that it says hey this is
Kevin's profile so I know that that's
still working the baselines still gonna
be accurate and then I just all you have
to do is take this analyze button and it
makes all of those requests it literally
took less than a second
and then based on those requests again
we're looking for outliers that's what
we do right
so and we see that hey yeah they're the
only outlier on here is the session
underscore ID so what this means is in
most it's most likely that the session
underscore ID is the only cookie that we
need to be considered logged in and all
of these other ones are just garbage
cookies you can right-click on any of
these and I've built in again through
the the burp api's you can build in
context menu is to send a request to
other tools so I can send one of these
to repeater all of that was built in
through through that okay so I think I'm
right near the end of my time let me
just I have a couple of closing things
bring up PowerPoint right so a couple
closing things many open source tools
out there are extendable and some
commercial ones are as well ok so just
because a tool doesn't do exactly what
you need it to do that doesn't mean it's
incapable of that and often the those of
us who write these tools we write them
to be extendable I mean there's lots of
examples out there Tim tones again I'll
throw his name out there recon ng that's
always been a very much a modular
framework right it's meant to be
extended and map is another one you can
you can build scripts additional scripts
onto onto n map which you know we all
use for port scanning purposes zap of
course and burp and then even if you
look at like the previous presentation
there were several tools like posh r2
extendable tools right so bear that in
mind
I mean this our tools get better when we
have you know feedback and additions and
and and you know we actually look at you
know how can we improve on these things
second everybody like please support
open source development that doesn't
mean you have to develop the stuff right
it also doesn't mean you have to donate
money to it or anything like that
but you can help in other ways report
issues if you see something that's
broken don't just go off that tool is
broken maybe they're not maintaining it
and then don't say anything right I know
that I have like in co2 I know that
there are things broken in there that
nobody has reported and I'll easily have
not actually opened an issue for but if
somebody reported it I'd go okay well
somebody wants that fix and so that
would get my attention and then when I
get some time I'll get around to it I'll
fix it
I don't expect pull requests for things
like co2 it is a I would like to say
it's a well-written Java extension for
burp suite but it's all the
documentation for it's really in my head
so so I don't expect anyone else to be
able to make sense of my crazy ideas in
that case anyway
also though share ideas get together
with developers of tools and and if you
have an idea for hey how could we make
this better share it with them I mean I
I I'm very passionate about my tools I
would love for to for people that talk
to me about and say hey have you thought
about maybe using it this way or could
you add this functionality to it I'm
glad to entertain that and I'm not going
to say we'll go submit a pull request
right I will for some things but
generally not for my burp extensions you
can help with Doc's like user user
documentation or videos useful videos
that sort of thing and just you know
express some things I know a lot of
people do I often forget way to way too
often to say thank you to all of the
people who have built solutions and put
them out there for the industry to use
because that our industry is built on
open source it really is so that's it
for my talk my name again is Jason
Gilliam if you want to chat with me at
any time either later today or anytime
afterwards I can be found on a slack
Channel professional evil calm and my
github repo is it's Jay Galle and this
person stole last name if you're trying
to find me and some of the tools that
are out there so thank you very much
thank you so much Jason for contributing
your knowledge back to the community
some of those um statements you made
right at the end that they weren't
specific to your presentation were
really hard-hitting for something that
all of us should keep in mind that this
community has built on all of our
contributions and you're an example of
it right now
I'm an example of it hosting this this
room and we're all an example of it
consuming it and hopefully giving back
to the community