good day ladies and gentlemen i'm going
to give you a briefing on the
development of chinese military bio
weapons
as i mentioned my opening soliloquy this
will be a reflection of the chinese
communist party as well as the chinese
military jun dway
if you have any questions please ask
those you may not like the answer but
i'll give it to you anyway
this is being recorded and presented
under traffic light protocol red
and of course chatham house rules if you
have any concerns or questions about
this please stop watching if you're
unfamiliar with chatham house rules
please google that before you continue
so today we're going to talk about china
specifically the military use
consideration planning and development
of
bioweapons as a prescription for
enduring
conflict capacity and defeating
adversaries on the battlefield now as we
go to china you'll note that the middle
of this map represents their view of the
outside world everyone is subversive
dominant and less than equal to the
chinese people this is just culturally
the way it is if you're offended by that
you know too bad but the chinese are
calling themselves zhongguo which means
literally middle
kingdom jung is middle gua means the
king or queen's riches surrounded by the
four borders of their kingdom remember
the chinese dream and the manifestation
of their culture is one of dominating
others and unfortunately you are if
you're not watching this in our chinese
you're already perhaps curious about
where this is going if you're a
foreigner like me you are subservient to
the chinese domination and that's just
the way it is so this is a third part in
this series that we'll talk about how
unrestricted weapons of war will shape
future conflicts specifically bio
weapons as developed by the chinese
military now the abstract of course is
just to let you know that this is third
in a three-part series examining the
chinese military use of biological
reagents in a kinetic capacity that's a
mouthful isn't it
years one and two presented at the
biohacking village i
suggest that you go back and look at
those on youtube
year one in 2019 essentially predicted
what was going to happen with covid 19.
year two last year essentially
demonstrated that indeed the wuhan virus
or
virus called covid here in the western
world we will not say what uh some
failed leaders have talked about what
the
cultural attribution of this is really
in year two i demonstrated that it did
in fact come out of wuhan
go back and look at that if you'd like
but today we're going to talk continue
to discuss the unrestricted warfare
strategy that goes back to the early
1990s and really defines the military
strategy and initiative including things
such as the supply chain program 863 and
other supporting components that discuss
the chinese military bio weapons
strategy all those are going to be
revealed during this discussion remember
this is traffic light protocol red
here's our agenda we're going to take a
look at three basic elements everything
from no hyperbole bio weapons programs
uh the china's chinese communist party
or ccp science and technology programs
and then an examination of future state
and planning using the daim mnemonic
meaning diplomatic intel information and
economic will be the focus for this now
as we go into this you'll note that the
biological weapons will have very much a
military flavor last year it was
research from a military civilian
perspective year before that it was
definitely a civilian with a taste or an
hors d'oeuvre of military response to
covet
now we're going to of course talk about
nuclear biological and chemical if
you've served in the us military or
military of any other country when you
heard the words nbc you remember your
gas
chamber training many of us remember
that with such uh rapid abandon it's
like yesterday well we're going to talk
about that from a non-can perspective as
we progress through this now the old
version of china is important to
remember that historically they have
indeed had
foreign troops stationed on their soil
and the response to that occupation in
the 1900s
impacts not only the information warfare
component which i'm known for primarily
but also in this age the bio weapons
capability now we'll talk about why
that's important because the chinese
fear above all the fact that a foreign
power will occupy them again and as you
know with some of my previous
discussions the communist party the
current regime
historically knows that if the
population is dissatisfied with the
discourse that it is giving from a
leadership and political party
perspective they will rise up and
essentially be
requesting that the ccp step down
communist party will never allow that to
happen as long as they're in power now
when we talk about china you think of
the dragon you think of the red dragon
that's my hacker alias but more
importantly what i would like you to do
is know that china is a major superpower
and as such they believe of course that
under the communist party rule that they
will dominate colonize
and otherwise rule the rest of the world
which is their mandate of heaven if you
know your chinese history now some of my
foreign research as you know from other
presentations that i've given has been
redacted removed and cannot no longer be
accessed
in this particular presentation i have
started to make a decision to not
include those urls if you want those
urls and you're in a position that will
help your research i ask that you reach
out to me i'll be happy to provide that
i know that this presentation will be
seen by the communist party it will be
seen by my friends at the chinese
military think tank it is not meant
disrespectfully or any sort of
dishonor towards the culture history
of china that is not the point it is
really to educate from a military
perspective what is going on in china
now
that military revolution that you
probably heard about the revolution of
military affairs coined by thomas
uh mr thomas down at fort leavenworth
really also speaks to the some of the
breakthroughs of biotechnology and how
future war
will be able to use this as a combat
force multiplier and it's interesting
because in the chinese military press
they are really researching and trying
to understand this especially in a
post-covet world and i'll tell you about
that in terms of one of the conclusions
is why it's important to listen to the
end
now when it comes to chinese military
history and certainly the history from a
cultural perspective of the way that the
chinese view
bio weapons control it's important to
revisit the fact that they are not part
of the opcw and hague
while they adhere to it they do not
belong to it in the chinese military as
you can see in this url which has been
redacted i believe uh firmly believe
that while this is necessary for other
countries it does not apply
to the chinese military and as such they
will prepare vigorously in order to
prevent this from happening now why you
may say are they so aggressive well it's
important to understand that during
world war ii the chinese were
invaded by the japanese here is yet
another historical chapter of what the
chinese fear which is foreign domination
and perhaps uh colonization by a foreign
force thus there is no love lost between
the chinese and the japanese in fact if
you go to beijing
as i have done recently you will note
that there is the
japanese war of aggression museum
outside of beijing it's a
fantastic historical view
of what the japanese military did to the
chinese civilians and military in the
form of biological weapons testing some
very nasty stuff was essentially leveled
against men women and children
the japanese were very brutal and the
chinese remember this as a result they
have developed their own
weapons grade chemical weapons and toxin
agents and i'll give you this as a a
review
in terms of what the chinese military is
doing in the present day in response to
what the japanese did to them
historically now you may have seen this
during last year but i want you to
remember that weaponization of
biological agents
really is something that they take very
serious and they look at it from a
intelligence perspective there's no
secret here believe me they want the u.s
the main protagonist to know what
they're doing in terms of developing
chemical weapons because they want it to
be a fair and equal round when it comes
to war they will basically state from a
military perspective we told you so you
need to be prepared for this now what's
interesting is i will reveal here
shortly they do not only always test
these on military uh troops in order to
prepare for that next level of warfare
or unrestricted warfare using bio
weapons but they tested on civilian
populations within the people's republic
of china you may have heard of rest of
xinjiang province and the muslim
population there they are not without
their uh
mistreatment by the chinese
military and government this is not a
political statement it just is a fact
and we need to come to grips with that
some of those bioweapon bio weapons
development terms as you can see here
include a variety now i put this out
there for the scholars that would like
to research this
if you're unfamiliar with the terms in
chinese then certainly this gives you an
opportunity to grab a screenshot again
tlp red and research these on your own
now from a nuclear biological chemical
weapon perspective we go into the
military revolution
understanding that bio
technology is really the mainstay of a
future battlefield if they need to go in
the kinetic space and the way that they
are researching this is to integrate not
only academic institutions
military scientific
programs within china
to develop some military oriented
initiatives or programs which include
active
aggressive collaboration and procurement
of dual purpose commercial civilian
technologies that can be applied in a
civilian military purpose and you may
say bill yeah we've all heard about ip
theft what's new well i was on a
briefing yesterday with the fbi
and i asked them about 863 plan and they
said they would have to get back to me
they had never heard about it
well let me tell you with all due
respect to the fbi uh the chinese 863
plan should have been top of the list of
the the discussion from that uh that
agent yesterday uh really this tells
about how that dual use technology goes
back to the third month of 1986
in terms of the active cyber espionage
targets and you may be saying yourself
well bill you've given us the url it's
all in chinese how are we to translate
this well i'll tell you
you can easily do a google translation
as long as these
urls are up but within these active
targetings of all of the areas of
critical infrastructure science
technology and research are indeed
biotechnology and you may have said well
yeah this is nothing new and i would
tell you that
if you're in a counterintelligence role
in the federal government of any country
and you don't know what china's 863 plan
is you should look in the mirror and
fire yourself because this is really the
road map in terms of the companies
within china that you should be
targeting uh from an active intelligence
and counterintelligence perspective part
of that of course is the thousand
talents plan and the success here's an
example of a gentleman who works for an
interesting institute of zoology as part
of the chinese academia academic
sciences cas
what's interesting is he is really
working on
developing not only biological weapons
but looking at different types of
applications in a military perspective
and one of those is really genetic
weapons and what he talks about is that
these new generations can be made by
modifying
the genetic code of disease-causing
microorganisms think of covid for
example use gene editing technology to
find the level of
oh
offensive capabilities from a military
perspective that will affect the enemy
at the genetic level
on the battlefield meaning they can
essentially defeat any nuclear
biological or chemical
weapons training and preparation
therefore giving the chinese military
that first mover advantage and
competitive military success that they
so are desiring to enjoy
now of course
not to delve back into what happened
last year certainly with covid but if
you're familiar with a biosafety lab 4
that's the highest level
we have them here in the us and
certainly the one at the woolen
institute of virology was a bsl4 and you
may ask yourself well that's such a
tightly controlled
environment for bio weapons development
and bio research how did the
kovat19 escape that well that's another
lecture from last year what i mean to
tell you is that they are talking about
from these bsl4 these genetic weapons
are going to essentially impact
positively the development of future
warfare planning
capabilities and future acquisition of
technology to help the chinese military
be successful on the battlefield
including a development of a biological
atomic bomb
achieving military goals much like in
the information warfare impromisation
space where you don't need to have
soldier on soldier or mourinho marine
and that they do believe that from a
strategic deterrent role genetic weapons
will serve that purpose now what's
interesting about this
is their national security does face
some of those biotech challenges meaning
that they know
that there are specific biological
weapons and terrorism that can take
place through research methods that may
go awry vis-a-vis may maybe the one
institute of virology but of course our
intelligence here in the united states
is working on that according to
president biden's edict so we don't need
to go into that suffice it to say
man-made biological disasters will occur
and they can occur and they have
occurred due to careless use this is one
of those national security challenges
that really sets the basis for the
development of military-grade
bio-weapons by the chinese military now
the application of this field of
endeavor biotechnology has become more
and more extensive meaning that they are
integrating not only emerging bio
weapons and equipment into
the health of sustainable combat
initiatives but also looking at it to
shape that future battlefield meaning
that strategic and tactical decision
making will focus based on the success
of these bio weapons and of course from
that comes the consistent theme of
combat power generation if you can get
inside a adversary's uh observe orient
decide an act or ooda loop then you can
essentially control the battlefield
produce a strong army using science and
technology and defeat them in space
of course the us military has had three
decades plus of experience in iraq and
afghanistan in the marine corps my
service has never seen the second place
so what that means is the chinese are
really trying to use biological weapons
in this new
military revolutionary affair meaning
that they are looking for an urgency and
exigent development of bioweapons that
will last them from a national defense
perspective over the next three decades
so think about that when you think about
future planning and of course there is a
variety of relationships between both
chinese national defense and technical
innovation of course this is in chinese
and i'm sure you can all read this but
i've done some translation for you and
suffice it to say that there is a
subjective
nature to this which means that they
know as a chinese military and
scientific world that there is a
significant
ecosystem historically where a lot of
these intelligent substances arrive and
arise and originate from that they can
take advantage of but they do know that
this complex ecosystem of virology is
incomplete and what it means is that
they can use big data and information
processing and artificial intelligence
to enhance the biological bio weapons
development for the military what this
means then again from a combat
generation perspective is that they can
get the full measure of combat power
projection using biotechnology
but that what that means then is that
they need to have security around this
program meaning that it must remain
somewhat secret so that other nations
adversaries that they may face on the
battlefield cannot realize what is
taking place
and of course some of those major
factors as you can see from this
narrative are quite concise and
development of course i don't intend for
you to translate this other than to say
that there are a variety of different
factors now it should be no surprise
because as we apply the diplomatic
information intelligence military and
economic mnemonic dime you can see that
there are of course political and
economic factors meaning they want to
stay in powers the communist party there
are social factors meaning that that
colonization and domination is the
manifestation of the chinese dream
is supplemented by the fact that bio
weapons and biotechnology must enhance
national security and then of course
there are institutional and governments
which means these factors are really
tied to the national scientific
national security focus of the people's
republic of china meaning while there
are ethical issues
nonetheless those don't necessarily
apply to the adversaries outside of
china remember they are the middle
kingdom and they are dominant and we are
subverted and subversive
meaning they intend to colonize all of
us and bio weapons as a military
projection of power is one of those
institutional governance factors that
they consider important now another
series of major factors is to
essentially look at what other countries
such as the united states are doing look
back a few years in terms of their
development it's all right here in plain
chinese for you to look at however i
haven't taken the uh
largess to translate this for you and of
course there are competitive factors
that the chinese look at from a
biological weapons perspective taking a
look at the defense
advanced research project agency or
darpa in terms of what they have been
doing the chinese military wants to
dominate this field of endeavor perhaps
even surpassing those programs of the us
military and what they consider to be
darpa's baby child of course there are
diplomatic factors they do realize that
they cannot just lease or lose these bio
weapons on other countries however that
they do realize that these major and
significant changes cannot keep pace
with the diplomatic world when diplomacy
fails of course the projection of force
and power is always necessary from a
military perspective as part of this
indeed will be the fact that the chinese
military will be called to use bio
weapons in order to colonize attack and
make an enemy uh secede to them
now of course there are right to speak
factors in terms of uh what the u.s
intelligence community has talked about
in terms of gene editing and the genome
editing project for example related to
weapons of mass destruction uh the fact
that this is in the open
or in clear text for the chinese
military to pick up is interesting
because this gives them a signal that
indeed they must remain competitive and
keep pace with this
and then of course the internal factors
within china include those scientific
and technological
hurdles uh that could impede or delay
the progress of biotechnical innovation
but nonetheless it is important to
understand that this model for the
future in terms of bio weapons is a
necessary condition for success of the
chinese military that will be the uh the
arm of diplomatic failure in the force
of power projection that the chinese
military will undertake perhaps in the
future against the us military other
adversaries they may see on the air land
and sea so please don't relegate this to
just a land discussion
and of course this is really interesting
because the evolution of this national
tech biotechnology under the chinese
defense act really comes into the way
that there are dual use weapons in the
future being developed and it's
important to understand that when it
comes to biological warfare uh there are
major things that are recurring thing
remember i mentioned that there are con
arms controls in the international
biological space opcw that i talked
about the chinese observe but don't
belong to it they also know that there
are emerging technologies that will lead
to new biological weapons that they can
carry out
and of course there is always the fatal
temptation of inception meaning
that uh one must not be reborn in the
image that is one because it may flash
back or blow back on oneself
and then of course this leads to
avoiding the nuclear trap the failure
that the chinese observe of the russian
loss of the cold war and the nuclear
run-up that the uh
the u.s
faced down russia with they believe that
they as the chinese military and chinese
people will have no competitors in the
bio weapons and defense biotechnology
realm they will control the space and
there's nothing that we can do about it
according to this
now of course 2035 not too far off in
the distant future is going to be a
tipping point for national defense
biotechnology now i certainly hope that
president biden's intelligence community
is reading watching and paying attention
to this of course
i've been ridiculed on youtube i've been
ridiculed in space but i will tell you
i'm not going to predict this i'm just
reporting on what i see
and i've taken the
opportunity to let you know that when
2035 comes around
that development from by the chinese
national defense biotechnology
initiatives will be the core product
outside of information warfare for their
protection
of course they're going to look at
organisms and controlling them micro
ecosystems and essentially looking at
ways to operate a
biological
taxonomy of military biological
organisms from which they can pick and
really direct at any adversary on the
battlefield
they also understand that there are
national treasure treasures of military
technological innovation
meaning they can prevent early strikes
by other adversaries including the
united states by essentially creating a
very highly maneuverable highly active
responsive reactive reagent that can
identify defeat delay degrade destroy an
adversary's capability to control them i
hope you're paying attention out there
us government and u.s intelligence
community and of course there is the
calculation of biological bioinformatics
meaning using biocomputing to
essentially map these genes to the
purpose which is intended for a military
dual use capability
and what's interesting is while there is
information collection that may be
needed for retention they believe that
by
examining new different forms of life in
this bioeconomic economic system
preventing those from being shared by
some of the adversaries or countries
that have dominated them they can
maintain that first mover military
advantage and destroy an adversary on
the battlefield
and then of course that gets into some
of the more esoteric origin of life
origin of consciousness uh talking about
cognitive memory uh dissonance which
hits a little bit uh jean-paul satra for
me but nonetheless it's something that
they're talking about in terms of
synthetic mind control uh certainly
we've seen that in the us military not
meant to reflect anything that has or
has not happened in the past
realistically of course then uh
anticipated 15 years on beyond that in
2050 of course it's right here for you
in chinese uh certainly you can read
this however i've taken the
the liberty of taking a look at a new
world order
meaning a human machine environment is
inevitable meaning that man society and
integration and the possibility of
eliminating biological warfare through
that competitive biotechnology and
national security matrix is going to be
necessary meaning that a calculation of
what will happen in predicting that is a
necessary
intelligent attribute of this capability
that they will develop the military
within china will also come combine
bionics
of weapons and equipment meaning that
these automated systems will essentially
locate seek and destroy adversaries that
propose a problem to them in the form of
third generation weapon system
development
and then of course there's environmental
technology making sure that while they
don't necessarily care about destroying
the earth they're going to use it for
their advantage now when i say earth i
mean air land and sea
and they're going to make sure that if
even if there is a incorrect
interpretation of the united states uh
convention opcw
or the prohibition of biological weapons
uh it doesn't necessarily apply to the
chinese well they are part of the
national security council of the united
nations uh it's certainly something that
they believe that they can be a first
mover and write the policy on that as
they have tried to do with the internet
control with russia
and then of course cognitive revolution
and human birth uh meaning that there is
a way to use nanotechnology in order to
avoid what had happened during the
nuclear trap and uh dilemmas of the late
uh 60s early 70s into the 90s between
russia and china
and then last but not least here's a
little bit of
historical uh trip down some of the
military origins of this of course
they've been
they being the people's liberation army
or the pla or june way have been really
focused on the advances of biotechnology
and the way that it can change future
conflicts uh in 2010 guajiang wei
worked on a significance of impact of
biology on the future plans for china's
military meaning that over a decade ago
they were already looking at this in
terms of future warfare planning
five years later major general future
really started to talk about bio
materials in terms of controlling an
adversary to make them think that they
have been defeated on the battlefield in
order to fix them in place and destroy
them this sounds pretty far out but if
you think about it there are agents out
there that can certainly render a
adversary
incapable an incapacity and he was
certainly talking about this from an
academic perspective
and then we have a retired general uh
jean-claude
who talked about seven new domains of
warfare including modern biotechnology
development what's interesting meaning
that he believed that the strong
offensive capability could be included
with specific genetic attacks that
should be employed now think of the rest
of xinjiang province and there you have
a living battlefield environment that
from a laboratory perspective that they
could use
and then finally signs of military
strategy i've talked about this in the
information warfare talks came out in
2017 you can actually get it on amazon
in english
really talks about that domain of a
military bio weapons capability
making note that this is indeed a force
multiplier
again with an emphasis on specific
genetic attacks uh suffice it to say
they being the chinese have been talking
about this for some time uh certainly
hopefully our military and our
intelligence world here in the west is
taking and keeping pace with this
now
this gentleman i mentioned him last one
it really was on the cutting edge for
the biological frontier and he talked
about confrontation in new methods and
when he met new methods he indeed meant
genetic weapons
in terms of how this can be done and i
talked about this earlier
vis-a-vis how these new genetic weapons
will affect the chinese use of in
control of
future war and really chemical weapons
being the precursor to this the
bio-atomic bomb
with a huge lethality imagine a kinetic
atomic bomb and what happened to the
chinese cities uh during world war ii
well the chinese believe that this can
be done from a bioweapons perspective a
bioatomic bomb
and meaning that
really one soldier does not need to be
placed enough
in the
face of war
to achieve military goals that these
genetic weapons will play that strategic
role to preserve the tactical troops
from being essentially pawns in a larger
adversarial role they do not want
foreign militaries to face them on the
battlefield and have that first mover
advantage the chinese believe that
indeed they will do that for you
and of course they as you saw last year
do train to the same standards that we
do it's interesting that this chem
biosuit and masks look similar to the us
but i digress this is not about
intellectual property
you should be aware of the
china national gene bank as part of
their initiatives i mean it's right here
in english it's right out on the web
certainly you can all read chinese and
go to the url yourself but it's
interesting because they have been
tasked
with developing some of those genetic
resources that will safeguard
bioinformatics with a focus on national
security
and it's really interesting because
you've heard about
seizing strategic commanding heights in
the information or cyber warfare
perspective they believe that in the
military domain of biotechnology that
this company the national
gene bank
will do the same for them it's important
to pay attention to organizations like
this
and then of course when we think of
military use coming out of gas masks
we've all done that uh in biological
weapons as distasteful as it is is
something we should pay attention to
last but not least as i conclude my
presentation here are some of the
conclusions uh the dual
chinese military and civilian
recollection of japanese horrors of
weapons of mass destruction during the
war of aggression world war ii
really endures with them historically
they distaste the japanese economically
they'll use them but from a military
colonization perspective they hate them
they do study the horrors of this and
prepare actively for the terrorist use
of a bio weapon as a weapon of mass
destruction
they do believe that dual use civilian
military bioweapons programs is
necessary and they are pursuing this
and they also believe that bioweapons
acts and accidents are inevitable in
china via the wuhan institute of
virology and the western world as a
result of that they need to prepare for
war
and then of course similar to what the
foreign military militaries us and
others are doing to prepare
no one wants a war but they know that
vigilance is necessary and really when
you look above they don't want to be
subject to any sort of other country
coming in and using these bio weapons on
the civilian or military population
number six of course
bioweapons development and the
procurement of that technology comes
under the china's thousand talents plan
if you want more about that uh certainly
come and see some of my presentations on
that in the
cyber warfare information dominance
perspective and load they are using
human intelligence and active
intelligence collection make no mistake
about it
number seven of course from a china
manifest dream
uh world domination culturally and
economic is going to be their goal and
weapons of biological mass destruction
will be the military sword uh that will
take care of those that do not want to
play
and then of course they're actively
preparing for weapons
bioweapons deployment in the shadow of
the world's failure to convey co
contained covet i apologize it says
kovic it's not a new acronym it should
say covet
that concludes my presentation 32
minutes if you have any comments or want
to contact me uh please do so through
the biohacking village thank you very
much and have a great day
three two one