all right i'd like to introduce casey
ella ceo and founder of bug crowd and uh
he's gonna be
uh speaking on
what's your topic today casey it's
called it's called inside the unlikely
romance
all right again just make sure to speak
uh a little closer into the microphone
yep you got it
all right oh good i'll i'll let you take
it away thank you
thank you um greetings concon uh thanks
john and uh thanks to uh you know the
the team there for putting this on uh
for giving me the invite excuse me while
i do the uh the awkward
zoom
thing that always happens at the start
as you go into presentation mode here i
think we're good here
yeah um so it's um it's it's great to be
able to
go to be able to see you guys i'm
actually uh dialing in from from sydney
australia um so it's about three o'clock
in the morning here uh but that's become
kind of my new normal over the year the
past year and a half so so we're all
good the coffee's the coffee's kicking
in and we're good to go um but yeah the
subject today is is inside the uh
unlikely romance um basically just uh
for some backstory of who i am i'm the
the founder chairman and cto of bug
crowd i started off as founder ceo
brought a new ceo in uh probably about
four years ago at this point i'm in the
chairman cto capacity now uh also the
founder of the disclose io project which
which we'll touch on a little bit um
i've been in security pretty much since
i finished high school from from a
career standpoint uh you know grew up
hacking stuff as a kid
um i basically tripped over into a into
an i.t engineering job
out of high school and and realized that
i could
you know break into stuff and and uh do
you know bad person things um in a good
context and actually turn it into a
legitimate career so you know i was
hooked at that point been doing that
ever since um
but crowd
basically you know
i got to the point um from from a career
standpoint where i had done a fair bit
of technical work moved across and done
a fair bit of solutions and architecture
and sales kind of front of house type
work those two experiences got together
and conspired i got in my head i wanted
to be an entrepreneur so i broke bad and
started working on that stuff and and we
eventually uh formed spug crowd which
actually pioneered the crowd source
security as a service space we didn't
invent bug bounty or vulnerability
disclosure but we were the first to come
out and basically intermediate and try
to make it easier and more useful for
everyone um
and that worked that's you know nine
years nine years ten years ago now um
started working on that and obviously a
lot's happened since then um that's
that's really the foundation for a lot
of what i'll be speaking about today
proud aussie as i just mentioned and if
you know you didn't catch that before
you're probably hearing it in the accent
uh husband father of two and yeah as i
said i actually normally live uh in in
san francisco we've been there um
pretty much since the seed round of bug
crowd uh
you know doing doing the startup thing
and growing the business uh in the in
the us we actually returned to australia
uh just the head of covert uh in march
of last year
on account of family and different
things like that not wanting to get
separated from being able to look after
parents and whatnot so it's definitely
been a mixed up mixed up you know 18
months or so i think everyone's got a
version of that and
um definitely not complaining too much
but that's that's kind of where things
are all at right now very much looking
forward to getting back to the us at
some point in time in the future and
being able to do this this sort of thing
in person again but that's where we're
at today
um in terms of bug crowd just where
we're up to uh
we we are you know a crowd sourcing
platform the way that i describe it to
folk um at this point in time i would
presume that a decent chunk of you
you've have heard at least in some
degree of us and others in the space who
subsequently join
um
you know essentially what we're doing is
is
basically connecting all the latent
potential that exists in the hakka
community and and plugging it into the
unmet demand
in in the cyber security space um you
know i do believe that uh cyber security
is a fundamentally human problem um the
technology just makes it go faster so
yeah with with this incredible hacker
community kind of you know waiting at
the table for an invite as they have for
the last 35 40 years or so um really
what i saw with the company was the
opportunity to plug plug those two
things in together um you know make
vulnerability disclosure programs
normalize you know enable workbending
programs get into crowd source security
in the form of pen testing different
things like that um and yeah a lot's
happened since then you know with 250
employees series d 80 million raised
about 170 000 volumes have gone through
the platform at this point that we've
that we've been a part of nuking which
is awesome and and so on so that's
some some backstory in terms of uh the
point of view that i'm speaking from
um and i do think you know corncons uh
we've got a
kind of a long history with this with
this conference um
you know we uh
if memory serves i think it was 24 20
and 14 um we actually you know sent
chocolate covered
um you know bugs literally like
scorpions and all sorts of other stuff
for the kids and some of the education
track there um
don't recommend those for for a snack
but it's definitely a fun novelty that
kind of goes along the theme of what we
do
um this slide really is is you know i
think some of the similarities of what
i've seen uh from corncon as as like a
core kind of cultural aspect and
priority of the conference and how they
kind of connect with a lot of what we've
seen um
you know be a lot of fun frankly and
quite successful with bug crowd like
we've had the opportunity to to educate
a ton of people all around the world and
actually give some careers into
information security um you know we've
been able to influence policy
in
the form of of having you know vdps
mandated across
um the federal government in the us
there's all these different things that
you know we get to do um
really as a product of of the unlikely
romance which is the the subject to talk
this idea of of hackers and and
companies actually
really needing to be able to have a
productive conversation and get along
well not really having a rich history of
doing that um but there's been a lot of
progress there and and this is some of
the cool stuff we've been able to do as
a as a byproduct of that
so next slide here so agenda um how we
got here in terms of you know where the
whole thing's up to a couple of war
stories around what we've seen
um practically with with you know what i
refer to as research driven assurance um
i think a lot of the time uh you know
historically assurance has been done or
approached as a checkbox exercise or
something that's you know mostly focused
on
on you know the output of automation
those sorts of things we're getting to a
point in time in security where that's
no longer acceptable as an approach uh
and this idea of researcher driven
assurance to actually dive into risk
i'll unpack some some of that stuff
um broke versus woke is really just
talking through i think we're at a point
where most folk in security have
some sort of notion of what a bug bounty
program is and and what von disclosure
all those different things are um you
know i want to kind of bring some
insight on on where i think they're
going so it's really you know how we got
here what's happening today and and
where we're going in the future
and we'll leave some time for q a at uh
at the end as well because
it's a fun subject and i love answering
questions when when people have them
does that sound good
if you can if you're in the audience
there um just give me a wave this is
yeah there you go that's very cool
it's it's it's funny doing the virtual
presentation thing it's um you know i'm
sitting here in in a dark room at three
o'clock in the morning and the
interaction this has definitely been
something to get used to with more of
this format but it's it's really cool to
be uh to be speaking to people actually
physically present as well so thanks for
thanks for coming along
oh let's rock and roll
so how we got here
so yeah as i mentioned
i've been
you know a computer security enthusiast
um you know a hacker in in in many ways
um
pretty much my entire life and
you know if you go back to 2012
um
you know i think it's safe to say it was
it was a simple time for for us in in
the industry we were basically
doing our our breaker thing we're doing
our curiosity and persistence thing um
you know we rollerbladed a lot
apparently
and and did all that kind of stuff you
know the um the folk that do
you know particularly offensive security
work but even deep technical defensive
work
we had our own little
click and our own little thing and we're
just kind of getting along doing that um
i think the downside of that was
you know from my experience um finding
it difficult to have people actually
take security seriously in the real
sense
um but we'll get to that in a second so
you know 2012 was good uh but uh also
you know to some degree i think rip good
times
um
yeah really what we saw and as i
mentioned before the thesis uh behind
starting bug crowd and you know
what has pretty much become my life's
work at this point um i think is kind of
summed up in this illustration right and
i think this is the thing that's become
increasingly obvious over the past over
the past 10 years this idea of of a tug
of war going on you've got you know the
adversary on on one side and there's
lots of them you've got you know
a diverse range of skill sets you've got
a diverse range of different motivations
you've got more of an incentive
for success than a constraint on the
number of hours a day you're being paid
for and so on um and then on the other
side you've got whoever is is tasked
with
with pulling you know
against them on the rope um with the
computer in the middle and that's that's
the battleground in the meantime you've
got you know folks from from the the
white hat or the you know the good faith
security research community
kind of standing right behind with their
hand in the air saying hey tag me in
like i'm here to help you know really
what we wanted to do was to solve that
um and as i said you know with with the
initial proof that we saw when we first
kicked off and i think you know a lot of
the work that we put in and others as
well put into basically
shifting the um
the mindset that people have when they
when they think of what a hacker
actually is
um yeah i
feel like there's still a lot of work
to be done there um because people do
still tend to freak out in a lot of
different places but we're at a point
now where this idea of of their being
you know equivalent to a locksmith in
the digital domain is something that
people broadly understand or they at
least acknowledge the existence of you
know i think prior to
prior to this
prior to a lot of what's been done over
the past 10 years or so we're basically
all burglars by default so you know how
do you do that how do you plug it in and
really why are you doing it it's because
math it's because of this idea that
um
you know there's not a level playing
field uh you know
as i said before like that diverse group
of adversaries versus
you know those singular constrained
people
um i see this almost as a war of
creativity to try to
try to fix the next thing
first
um
and ultimately it doesn't actually
matter how smart or or not potentially
uh you know the the individuals that are
tasked with defense are like the problem
is actually that the math is wrong like
they will eventually lose because of the
symmetry of of the uh of the setup so
that's kind of what we do in terms of
plugging it in
um so you know as i was talking about
you know 20 2012 like carefree times all
good
um
one of the experiences i had when i
first arrived in in san francisco was it
was this ride with a lift driver uh
where we ended up talking about security
because that's just what tends to happen
when i when i get in a car with people
um
and he trotted out this incredible quote
like all security is the product of
something bad happening which is
kind of
it's a pessimistic in some ways view
view of things but i actually do think
it captures it well um
you know people that build software
people that that make decisions that
impact security they're not
necessarily downplaying or or ignoring
or choosing
to to leave mistakes in place or to
create weakness right like they're
focused on making their thing work so
they actually need to have some sort of
some sort of event or some sort of even
message-driven event um basically point
out to them that yeah you should
actually lock your front door at night
it's a bad neighborhood um so you know
that's sort of summing it up and
as i was saying uh 2013 this was
actually the same month that we landed
in in san francisco which was pretty
um interesting from a timing standpoint
um yeah i think one of the one of the
really
major
side effects of the snowden disclosures
and people actually starting to talk
more openly
around
how you know cyber security and the
intelligence community uh
operate um
was this idea that like oh hacking is
actually a thing for the lay person
right so people that they kind of looked
at us all uh in our funny movies doing
our funny things prior to that thinking
oh that's kind of abstract i don't even
really know what that is i'm just going
to ignore it now all of a sudden they're
in a position where they're forced to
try to figure out how it applies to them
um and you know to me
this was a keystone moment i think in in
overall security awareness right
but then obviously it kind of escalated
from there so 2014 you've got target um
and and you know all of the the kind of
chip and not the chip in the uh the
dumps and and track two raids that
happened in that year so all of a sudden
again for the consumer hacking is
happening to me now right
fast forward a year this happens um
which hurt um opm was was in this year
as well so all of a sudden you've got
records and and things being stolen that
you that you can't ensure like if it's a
credit card you know it's inconvenient
but
most of the time you're gonna get that
money back in in these sorts of cases
now you're having you know breaches that
um
[Music]
that can't be insured and and oftentimes
what's taken from you you can't actually
retrieve so now hacking happens to me
and it hurts right
2016 you've got
hacking happens to my country um with
all the different things that happened
around around the election and obviously
that narrative continued on beyond that
so you can sort of see what's what's
going on here in terms of the general
population i think for us
in in in the security space
none of this
from my perspective came as a huge
surprise
um
but for everyone else outside of it like
what is this stuff like this is this is
really starting to become a uh an issue
that you know i don't necessarily know
how to understand it i'll get my arms
around it but i know what matters uh i
know it's important right
then 2017 to 2020 uh you know software
is eating the world
and and the bad guys are eating the
software again it's escalating
you know 2020 itself um okay now my
five-year like my employees
five-year-old is responsible for my
corporate attack service
this particular shift
in in how we use technology and i think
some of the risks that have come from it
i do believe that we're only just
starting to see
how that plays out from from a risk
management and even from a threat
modelling standpoint um you know one of
the things that uh
that we observed um early in the
pandemic was the fact that
um you know basically
zero day in in uh consumer products um
like iot you know
soho routers those those sorts of things
that stuff's been around forever but no
one bought it because it wasn't super
interesting on the offensive side um you
know come april you know may of 2020
that stuff starts to starts to fly off
the shelf so
you've got the adversary thinking
through
how this shift in in your behavior um
creates new opportunity for them and
that's that's obviously something that
rolls down to us
and this is meant to be 2021 but um
you'll get it um you know it's the year
of the xyz
like looking
[Music]
definitely from from a a supply chain
standpoint again not a huge shock to
people in security we know that's been
a risk and and you know somewhat of a
trash fire in different ways for a long
time but all of a sudden you've got all
these points of proof popping up to to
basically impact
you know folks that are on on the
receiving end as victims of the use of
this type of thing when it's when it's
done you know maliciously um
and people start talking about it and
all of a sudden it becomes a focus right
so
the thing with this is if it's repeated
enough at the dinner table it ends up in
in the boardroom um yeah this idea
that's
that's um
you know the spouse or the children or
the family of executives and and board
members um actually elevate you know the
the the awareness and the thinking
around security is an issue of risk
management for an organization
like i do believe that that's been a
fundamental driver of of you know us all
now being
very busy um and probably having you
know a pretty good feeling from from a
job security standpoint because it's
just dinner table conversation now and
that hasn't always been true
yeah i think
um going back to the because math thing
uh you know we had the uh the cso of
national australia bank um here in
australia actually join us as our cso at
bug crowd
um
what was that about six months ago now
maybe a little bit more than that
um
for this reason he's he's looking at it
through the lens of someone who's done
risk management who's done offensive
security defensive security like feed
out ir you know protect detect respond
all those different things in a banking
context which is you know amongst the
most
i would say mature
thinkers
in terms of cyber risk management
and
he kind of came to this this conclusion
that i was talking about before like
diversity is is key like the the idea of
being able to broaden out
your talent pool and where you're able
to get answers from is actually a
critical and overlooked factor in in
security and control strategies um so
he's he's joined it's been fantastic
to have to have him involved like to me
this is sort of evidence of what i was
just saying about you know these issues
these pressures and this idea of like no
we need to be able to figure out how to
have dogs and cats play nice together in
the form of hackers and organizations
like if we can do that then we've got a
chance of actually you know maintaining
a level playing field as we go forward
so there is again biggest math right
um
so that's my setup in terms of you know
how i feel the the back story has kind
of driven us to this point my camera
will come back in a sec i still have to
figure out how to stop it from doing
that
um
yeah something something to to talk
about and this is kind of getting into
um a bit of a a geekier end of the the
talk and some of the war stories uh that
we've seen where this idea of researcher
driven assurance or research driven
assurance um yeah what does that look
like in practice
um so struts two uh aka the the equifax
vulnerability it's the the one that was
used in in you know the fairly high
profile attack there
um
we actually saw that getting
basically put through the platform prior
to
you know the the public dropping of a
proof of concept
and what we also saw was organizations
that we worked with you know being
notified of where that existed in ways
that had fallen outside of their their
normal
you know patch and asset management
program
in a way that allowed them to get it
fixed and this was four months before
the actual breach uh took place on
equifax so this idea of that that
curiosity the diversity of skill being
applied to it all the different things
that are going and actually approaching
assurance from a research driven
lens um you know closed a window of
exploitability within that vertical for
this particular organization by by four
months which is a pretty cool win
um
yeah the the confluence issue um i've
i've dubbed this one conflue
which hasn't caught on yet maybe it's
too soon to be joking about that but you
know
whatever i'd love if that would if that
could catch on because it just seems
like a great name for the bug but
that aside um what we saw happen with
that one is the patch dropped on
on the 25th
um basically end day reversing on that
patch started immediately
um
we saw
artifacts of active exploitation within
a day or two and then the public exploit
dropped and and everyone kind of went
went ham at that point so this idea
again of of this you know research
driven
kind of tenacity being applied uh to
things that impacts the internet at web
scale um that's an example of where
we've seen that all these by the way
i'll put these slides up after the talk
i've got a bunch of links in here for
for any any you know homework or
follow-up you'll want to do so there's
some stuff attached to each of these
so another one f5 to muay
again same story you know there was the
introduction of a vulnerability there
was
you know arguably private availability
of the exploit and exploitation
potentially from offensive actors
um there's a fair bit of evidence around
to suggest that that was actually taking
place before uh the exploit itself got
commoditized and and you know nation
states actually started using it to
pretty much hose down the internet
we saw again the vulnerability coming
through
prior to
the dropping of the public exploit and
that that commoditization taking place
like for those of you who've heard of hd
moore's law um the idea of basically the
the sophistication and the size of your
attacker pool is proportional to the
availability of the exploit which makes
sense when you think about it right um
this was very much an example of that
story
and and again we were seeing that
um
basically used uh to to identify risk in
organizations with an incentive attached
to it in context of a bug boundary
program so that risk could be eliminated
you know prior to the the the wider
scale stuff kicking off
um this is an interesting one from from
a um
less of a
a vulnerability uh
in and of itself like a discrete you
know cve
type of type of issue and more of a new
attack class so type confusion
um
is effectively a supply chain um exploit
in terms of some of the assumptions that
can get built in to where
where supply chains of the software
supply chains are pulling packages and
code from
um you know what we saw with this one uh
prior to
a paper that got written i think it was
in january or february of this year we'd
actually seen that same
attack path
um exploited in the wild for probably
six to nine months beforehand it all
kind of got tied together around i
believe was node.js
um but then all of a sudden you know
people are looking for those those same
sorts of issues in in ruby gems and and
all the other kind of foss you know
package
ecosystems where this type of problem
might exist
so yeah again you've got this like real
focus on not just using the things that
we know
uh from an attack technique and from a
from an assurance standpoint today but
actually thinking about what's next it's
this diversity of
of knowledge and then you know frankly
the um the incentive and the curiosity
that exists within the white hat
community actually connecting
with companies um in a way that makes
them makes them more secure and that's
you know when i'm talking about the
unlikely romance that's that's kind of
an example of that this idea of
wow i didn't think they'd get on so well
but here we are um
pretty cool one
[Music]
uh another that was
really fun this was actually in a um
fortune
20 company
they had they had a
basically a front door website
um
that as you could imagine has been
absolutely pummeled by
by adversaries but also by you know pen
testers scanners like all sorts of
different things for for for a really
long period of time um what we saw a
researcher do uh with with that was
basically
you know put a fair bit of work in this
this was actually a difficult exercise
xxe to find and this was actually fairly
early i think in people's awareness of
injection as a as a you know exploit
path
but they created a code path they got
through and and were you know able to be
in a position where they could have a
code path that allowed them to to
basically execute xse off the back of
that they were able to drop off inside
the the core basically web server farm
so not just this particular site itself
but all of its adjacent systems so on at
that point you know they uh they
basically waved the white flag and said
i don't think i should go any further um
we looked at it the the client did as
well and agreed with that but yeah to me
that one is is fascinating because
these systems have been looked at
um pretty intensely for a really long
time and this was basically
you know joe internet to god mode
as a vulnerability that existed on that
system so you know the fact that those
things still do fall out when you apply
this kind of firepower i think is is
quite um quite compelling
and probably the last one and this is
definitely a um
an unlikely romance uh in a lot of ways
um you know one of the one of the bits
of pushback one of the assumptions that
i think a lot of people have around you
know security researchers hackers like
bug bounty or crowdsourcing um
is that you know you've got to be
a fairly fast and loose
organization from a risk you know
acceptance standpoint to engage this
type of model like we've been working
with the department of defense
for seven years now um just uh just did
a like launched a partnership with with
cisa around um you know vulnerability
disclosure programs for all federal
civilian agencies these these are
conservative like traditionally
conservative groups that are recognizing
again that they need this help they've
got plenty of smart people it's not a
dis on you know pen testers or red
teamers of their employees they just
know they need more because of the size
and the veracity the the adversary that
they ultimately have to outsmart so
this was a um a private
private crowdsource pen test that we did
on a cloud computing environment for the
for the us air force um
you know pretty much all of their
workloads go up to this thing so there
was nothing in it obviously when we were
testing it because of the comp up
analyzation side of things
um
but they're pretty good at building
things securely so we weren't expecting
to to you know completely hose the thing
down
we went through it pretty much with a
fine-tooth comb so like source code
analysis you know the the us air force
actually releasing source code out to
you know the the dirty population um
there's tons of vetting all these
different things to go in to this type
of program on our side but it's still i
think
logically a bit of a a mental leap
um for those guys to take to even adopt
that model in the first place this this
one was very cool um social engineering
crowdsourcing that that
that was experimental and and they they
actually flagged it we said yeah let's
let's find ways to do that and give it a
shot
um
really interesting and was incredibly
effective because again you've got this
diversity of thought it's not just one
person's way of of trying to social
engineer it's it's like a lot of people
and you know you have collaboration kick
in and different things like that that
was actually quite effective which is
pretty cool uh you know 54 volumes 123
grand paid the top reward there was was
20 000 which was
a pretty fun uh gig
um you know and for those who are in the
audience either in the room or online
who
you know are thinking about this from
the researcher angle
uh
yeah i honestly i think this kind of
content what this is is a list of a list
of content creators and places where you
can you can get
you know educational content that's
talking about all the different areas of
research that you know you could be you
could be thinking about that are i think
most
relevant right now to the to the
industry in particular
um
but also you know what's coming down the
pike like what are the different things
that are cutting edge like the um the
type confusion issue that i was talking
about before it's like these are the
kind of forums where those things pop up
um you know buck grade university is our
effort to do that um actually everyone
who's on this list uh actually works for
bug crowd or has worked for buckrad in
the past so that's kind of going back to
what i was saying about education being
something that's quite important to us
but yeah as i said before i'll put these
slides up online if you want to check
those links out later on i do recommend
them for
for folks that aren't necessarily
thinking about this in terms of becoming
a hunter or becoming a pentester or
doing security research as a career as
well um
we often see
you know csos
and and you know folks on the
the governance and management side who
have
either a technical background or like a
really strong technical inclination um
absolutely loving this this type of
stuff because it gives them an idea of
what's going on like how how other
people are thinking about it so
yes all right so broke versus why let's
get into this part and then we'll throw
a q a
i'm actually just going to have a
quick sip of water here real quick
you guys probably heard the coffee kick
in about halfway through that last
section it's like okay let's go
so i'm slowing myself down so it all
comes out clear all right
so broke versus woke um
yeah
as i mentioned before we're at a point
now where
if you if you say even the phrase bug
bounty to someone um
in in you know definitely in the
security space and oftentimes in the
technology space as well
they're almost immediately going to have
some sort of opinion um and a lot of the
time that's really good um you know what
i what i have seen is that
there's so much more
texture and and
kind of nuance in the ways that you can
deploy this model it's not just one size
fits all which is the part that i think
a lot of people miss like bug crowd
i didn't start the company and i you
know frankly didn't start the category
just to do bug bounty um in in the way
that you know facebook and google uh do
it right like that's that's one
variation that's definitely a way to do
it if you're that kind of company you've
got that kind of resource and approach
to security it's appropriate it's
probably not a fit for a lot of other
people
um
you know as i mentioned before we do a
lot around you know vulnerability
disclosure programs which i believe is
something everyone should have uh but
then things like you know crowdsource
pen testing and and researcher matching
to do you know work on cars and
and different things like that so
there's quite this sort of spectrum of
ways to get it done so
this is you know me going through some
of the things that i see as assumptions
um
and uh you know trying to trying to give
my view of better ways to approach them
going forward
and this is a this first one's a kind of
an overall cyber security thing um you
know rub some blockchain or automation
or ml on it and it'll go away as a
problem right
um
yeah i think technology is incredible as
a leather you know the metaphor i often
use is the iron man suit
um
you know the suit without
the human is is dumb
uh you know the human without the suit
is is weak if you can put them together
then all of a sudden you've got you've
got something pretty cool happening uh
but the idea of
you know installing a blinky box and
making your problem stop at that point i
think
um yeah people still buy it people still
believe it i think it's fundamentally
inaccurate because as i said before
cyber security is a human problem
you know the technology just amplifies
and accelerates
the the anti patterns and the decisions
that we that we put into it so you know
you can't just solve it with tech from
my perspective you know
and and really that's kind of i believe
the uh the the kind of woke
interpretation of of that particular um
thesis that people have no it's not just
about the tech like you got to think
about it in terms of
you know the creativity the uniqueness
of your organization what the sign
decisions what your risk and economic
factors play into creating risk um and
then work out if technology can give you
leverage around you know what you do
with that information from a risk
management standpoint so yeah cyber
security's a people problem detectives
makes it go faster
um broke uh vulnerability disclosure
programs as a marketing stunt uh we saw
this a lot in the early days um
you know people and it still is the
thing that happens today um you know
less frequently but it's still very much
a thing people going out and launching a
program
mostly for the sake of of getting into
inter tech crunch or or you know
sometimes even in response to um
security research that's gone bad or a
breach or something along those lines i
do think you know for public
vulnerability disclosure programs and
bug benny programs the marketing aspect
of it um
is a pretty powerful thing like the idea
of being able to describe
you know what you're doing to to make a
user safer is like neighborhood watch
for the internet like the layperson can
actually get their head around that
which is
which is pretty cool but that can't be
the only reason you're doing it i think
you've got to actually be thinking about
how to
how to get smarter off the back of this
stuff like not just finding
vulnerabilities but actually creating
feedback loops between the builders in
your organization and breakers who can
who can think differently um again back
to the unlikely romance right the more
that's a feedback loop and a transaction
of thinking i think the uh the more
powerful it becomes so you know woke is
is you know basically vdp showing to the
organization but to to to the to the
market as well that like failure is a
part of being human um
no no one's perfect i i do think
actually launching one of these programs
is an antidote to what i call like
ostrich risk management where you know
people just kind of bury their head in
the sand and assume that if they ignore
uh vulnerabilities then they won't
matter like that's being increasingly
shown as not a good strategy and this
actually short circuits that pretty
quickly
all right bro bug ban is a silver bullet
woke bug bounty is a way for the
business to internalize the idea that
the boogeyman's real
um
this is a really powerful one from a
security awareness and education
standpoint i think
the the thing that we've observed
consistently
is that the uh
you know
the the call it the psychological impact
um
i don't mean that in like a overly
strong way it's like how it how it
changes the way you think about
everything not just
the information it gives you
um that impact on an engineer
when they see their kid
their code you know get owned by some
kid halfway across the world
is is very different to when they get an
alert from a scanner or you know um get
a report from from a pen tester in-house
because
what it does is it begs the question you
know that person who submitted the
report like they're friendly and i i
trust them and this all seems to be
working out great but i wonder what
their next door neighbor's like and i
wonder you know who all else
is in that neighborhood oh my gosh like
this can actually happen this is real
you know the idea of exploitation being
possible if you introduce a
vulnerability like it's gone from being
this abstract idea to something that you
just saw happen literally so i think
that's actually
you know that's that's a really powerful
phenomena um
you know you're never more security
conscious than just after you've been
breached as an organization i think this
is a way to achieve some of those
upsides without obviously the mess and
the fast of an actual breach
uh broke literally uh total payouts is a
vanity metric um
this is a valid strategy for for
companies that that can afford it i do
think you know the list of those
companies that can actually you know for
starters pay
um
you know multiple millions of dollars
per year
um
and and you know
seconds who actually should do that uh
as a part of their overall strategy i
think that's quite a small list um
and it does kind of get touted i i see a
lot as like the pinnacle of doing it
right if you if you're paying out a ton
of money you know all that kind of stuff
then then obviously this is a successful
bug branding program like i love making
sure that researchers are getting paid
um
you know hackers are getting paid
they're able to actually turn this into
more of a job frankly on on their side
but if as a as a company running one of
these programs you feel that like the
more you pay out the better you're doing
it doesn't really
say good things about your overall
security management strategy within the
organization it's like are you fixing
these issues like are you actually
getting better at not introducing them
in the first place
um
from my perspective the work version is
is really the repo
required payment
uh
to to create an impact um you know
taking that and actually using it as a
business metric
for the cost to attack the organization
overall so
yeah if you think about it in terms of
like a fireproof safe
um
if you yield a fireproof safe into the
sun it's going to burn so it's not
fireproof it's fire resistant and what
you see is that this thing's going to
protect your passport for seven hours at
1400 degrees fahrenheit or whatever that
might be
you can get those kind of metrics out of
out of uh
you know bounty driven payments um if
you're you know at ten thousand dollars
and all of a sudden you've not seen a
critical issue come through in in the
last 90 days like congratulations you
graduated
you put it up a little bit you'll see
more because at that point you've
increased the heat right like folk are
looking more intently you're probably
going to activate people that weren't
as compelled by ten thousand dollars as
they might be by 15. all those different
things and you just end up with you know
this progressively
increasing amount
that
really reflects what you've done to
increase the cost to attack the business
for for an adversary
and you know from my perspective that's
one of the easiest ways to explain what
we do
like across the board to to uh you know
a board of directors or to someone who's
not from our space um the fact that
there's a dollar sign in there helps
because people just
you know pay more attention to that to
the number like compared to the number
of alerts you've seen or the number of
vulnerabilities you've fixed so i think
that one's a a pretty pretty hot tip
um bro pentester is an assurance only
model work
assurance and impact together to create
build-a-breaker feedback loops i've
already
gone over this quite a bit in in the
last section so i won't label this one
too much but you know graduating like
graduating from this idea of security
testing just being about
checking checking the box and making
sure that you followed a methodology
yeah the challenge i've always had with
that as a practitioner and something
that i've seen is be able to do
um
or
shift frankly in in context of research
driven assurance is that proving a
negative is kind of impossible like the
fact that you've looked
doesn't mean there isn't
something there um like we know this in
the space i think folks outside the
space can get a little confused by it
i do think that if if you kind of you
know set the bar around assurance
activities
and basically render them as though
you've proven a negative what you're
ultimately doing is missing a whole
bunch of stuff so this idea of tying
that with with actually going after
after impacts in a in a more i think
focused and aggressive way um is is a
pretty good way to get the best of both
worlds um your bug crowds next
generation pen test product um actually
does that so what we'll do is we run
people that are going through very
methodically
yeah effectively
incentivized to complete tasks
but then what they've got next to them
is a whole bunch of people that are
incentivized to create impacts in a more
traditional uh bug vantage reward model
so you can you know
assemble things together and actually
get some you know better frankly risk
management data
from from that whole
exercise
um this is a new one broke uh
nation state wouldn't bother with my
stuff um
yeah i think there's this there's been a
period in in cyber security where we
really over rotated on the whole apt
thing it used to drive me nuts it's like
oh you want to keep
you know this bear or that panda or
whatever else out of your network that's
the most important thing and this is
exactly what they're doing and in the
meantime you've got you know single
factor authentication no one's rotating
passwords you're not patching anything
whatever else um so i do think for a
period it was
really an issue of like no you need to
actually learn basic hygiene before you
go off and try to solve you know cancer
um as a metaphor there um i do think
that's changed like solarwinds
you know there was
in terms of what got reported out a
limited number of agencies and targets
that had active exfiltration and active
use of the shells that that's um ended
up all over the place but the reality is
that a lot of people got popped in that
particular attack um you know half diem
with with the exchange stuff there's all
these different examples where
you know it does feel to me very much
like nation states in general are taking
the gloves off quite a bit um and going
out and getting whatever they can um
really
just in case they want to use it later
uh there's a there's an overall trend
that i'm seeing from an attacker's
standpoint sisa and nsa going out and
doing advisories on this type of things
i'm not not on my own in having this
opinion um
yeah really what it comes down to is
that you know the woke version of that
the the kind of his how we probably have
to think of it next is you know how am i
going to detect and contain a nation
state assuming they're successful so
thinking about your your defensive
program is building it like it's broken
you know how do you do
like blast radius management um you know
compartmentalization uh you know
detection in in context of that um yeah
i think deception technology and honey
that's as an entrepreneur one of my
favorite
things um in terms of how it fits into
this i do see that
playing a bigger role in the future but
in general this idea of okay i'm gonna
end up dealing
with with you know folks that are very
well resourced
and i just you know need to need to be
considering that and in how i do my um
do my do my math as a as a defender
um you know the the actually the
ransomware gangs are in a similar bucket
too now so some of the stuff that we're
seeing out of cyber criminals who've
traditionally been a lot less
sophisticated than what they'd use
um
ransomware's working so
what that means is they end up with a
bunch of money that they can use to hire
really clever people to
procure capability that makes their next
attack more effective and that's just
continuing to escalate so the cassia
attacks were i think a pretty good
example of that that was
some fairly
high end
you know kill train construction they
did to get that done
uh that's not necessarily that typical
of of that type of group so you know
looking at that is something that we we
continue to see it's sort of in the same
bucket
um last one so so broke this is this is
one for the you know the folks that have
done their own vulnerability research in
in the crowd you will have definitely
experienced this you know security at
domain.com uh routing to devnull
um
it's a thing yeah i i think as as the
unlikely romance as this relationship
between hackers and companies becomes
more normal
um what you see as a byproduct of that
is more people reaching out and and
trying to help
and half the time
getting crickets in response because you
know folk just haven't been proactive
about setting that stuff up yet
this is where discloso comes in you know
bug crowd as an organization helps
companies manage these these types of
programs um
we got together with a whole bunch of
well i got together with a whole bunch
of other folks that have been working on
this issue of of basically standardizing
policy um making it easier to
implement and to actually read and
understand
for the sake of adoption like how do we
just make this as bone dead simple as we
can
for as many people to do as possible and
just make it normal across the internet
i do
fundamentally believe that some
you know security research and this this
relationship between hackers and
companies is going to be a pretty vital
part of how we stay safe in into the
future
and do think of them as like the
internet's immune system uh you know in
some ways we've got a bit of an immune
deficiency historically that we're
trying to trying to recover from and
that's really a lot of what the
disclosure project's about
so
a bunch of different things you can
check out
essentially you know policymaker is is
helping people actually it generates
policies uh um it's got a standard
uh that's being translated into
different languages now which is cool
but what it also does is spits out a
record which lets people know where your
policy can be found and and where you
want to receive vulnerability reports um
dns security txt is a
is a new proposed standard that came out
of a bunch of the folk that um help out
with with disclosure it's an open source
not-for-profit
project uh by the way so if you're
interested in
you know
helping out or being a part of it
through that lens
uh we'd love that
um so there's that hacker connect is is
really about um
you know solving this question of i've
found a vulnerability like who do i tell
um i think there's been a couple of
other talks in in the conference so sick
codes earlier on um is definitely
someone who actually helps out with this
stuff a lot but has used it as well to
get information into the right hands
it's a hard problem to solve you know
what tends to happen there's
a couple of dozen people of which i'm
one um that usually gets a phone call
it's like oh casey probably knows
someone like hey dude can you help me
find the right place to send this issue
um you know trying to find ways to scale
that out so it's effectively a forum um
go check that one out and you know
there's a bunch of other stuff that
we've got as open source projects i
think the policymaker one is is the one
that's most relevant for people that are
considering launching a program and even
trying to explain it to other people in
your team like lawyers look at this and
and breathe a huge sigh of relief
because they don't have to go through
all the mental gymnastics of of trying
to you know write a brand new policy
that's quite novel for them from a legal
standpoint from scratch so
shout out to that guy
all right so in summary and we'll cut to
questions after this yeah it takes an
army to outsmart an army the community
is at the table it's ready to help it's
doing that we're seeing
adoption and we're seeing like positive
impacts of this relationship going
forward right across the board um
obviously you know part of how we've
seen that is that bug crowd as a company
has grown um
i get excited about that for obvious
reasons but i also get excited about
like what all else goes on outside
um that doesn't necessarily directly
translate to or transit to us as as a
deal or value or whatever else because i
just do think this is the right thing
like hackers
in this position hackers with a similar
background to myself and others that i
work with
you know we want to help we've been
trying to help for a really long time
it's becoming easier which is awesome
and yeah there's tremendous leverage
available to folk that'll think
differently
and actually take some of this stuff on
so yeah for those of you in the room who
are considering this
from from an implementation standpoint
uh there's a link there
um where you can actually look at the
crowd platform sign up just have have a
play as a researcher or a hacker you can
check that out shared a bunch of other
stuff as well again i'll post these
slides so you can go back through the
links
um
and yeah i'll i'll finish off with
with our patron saint grace hopper you
know a ship and poor is safe but that's
not what ships are for
uh i i do think this
this acceptance of
of you know some of the things that that
could be even a little bit uncomfortable
to start with when you first start to
interact with the hacker community and
get their feedback
um
that's that's the ship it's like you
know not doing that uh is is keeping the
ship in poor actually doing that is
actually taking it out and taking
advantage of everything that's available
on on the internet you know all the
brains we have and all the brains we can
borrow so it's really a matter of
stepping into that so
i will end it there
thank you so much
any questions
i'm actually not sure how we're going to
do questions here but
can you hear us
yes gotcha good
i had a question about where you see
things going from here you talked a
little bit about how
uh you're doing source code analysis for
your course or you're talking about
message ben testing
so the kind of evolution of just having
a bdp or bloodbathing for a web presence
versus
more of a scoped engagement or a
targeted time box kind of thing
yeah no
it's that's a it's a great question um
the interesting thing
for for us as bug crowd i've seen
i've seen other platforms in the space
have have a similar challenge is that
you know public bug benny programs and
public vdps are so freaking noisy
that all of the other stuff that you do
under the hood
kind of gets drowned out if that makes
sense
bug crad actually did
basically crowd source pen testing that
was the that was the bulk of what we did
for for the first year or so
uh before we started building out a
disclosure management platform
um
alongside that so
yeah i mean to your question um i guess
really what i'm saying is that that's
already happening now
this idea of you know
basically
connection of distributed talent into
use cases that are pretty
counterintuitive before you're doing is
looking at a kind of web focused uh you
know bounty programs different things
like that that's been going on for quite
a long time so
to your question i think it's going to
expand like you know those those
different use cases like part of what i
had
in in in my thinking um you know
starting starting the company and
kicking the category off was that
like this is this is really the future
of work in in a lot of ways um
not across all of security obviously
because there's things that you you need
to be in the same room for those things
that you need to actually be
consistently applied to to a problem to
to be able to solve but for stuff like
you know finding a unique vulnerability
um you know testing a social engineering
strategy like even down to like
analyzing malware um you know doing a
source code review uh you know tearing
apart a car and and seeing um what kind
of vulnerabilities might exist in in the
construction of that car
yeah
it's to me
mostly a matter of trying to connect
the best possible talent with the
problem that needs to be solved
um
you know obviously there's a there's a
reason for doing that from a work and an
opportunity standpoint but the biggest
thing i think is because that's how the
bad guys do it so so the reason they're
so successful is because that's how they
operate um which is why i think it's
it's going to continue forward in in
that sense
um you know regardless frankly of of
what folks like me do to try to
facilitate that i think there's more of
a sucking sound around it than anything
else
can i answer your question
any other question
well i'd like to thank you
casey thanks for coming again and
participating in corncon i know it would
have been a long drive
probably a wet drive huh
yeah a long long way drive or a long
kayak maybe i don't know
what uh
what what what time is it there for you
you're uh 4am just going for it you're
in the you're in the down under upside
down that's our theme this year right
with corncon
yeah yeah no well i i do want to thank
you again
audience please please thank our speaker
and
i i hope you can uh
get get back and get a couple hours of
rest before sunday starts
abs absolutely absolutely hopefully
we'll uh we'll see you on the ground
next year all right that sounds great
take care thanks john thanks all