all right well i guess we'll get started
thanks everyone for uh coming in today
thanks for coming out during a uh
yeah crazy time
but uh i do want to talk about something
that's
been on the forefront of my mind
intended in our industry that needs more
attention as mental health and self-care
really we look at cybersecurity
professionals spend most of their days
focus on health and well-being of their
environments and their care
however the cost of reducing risk and
keeping our networks often comes at the
price of our professional's mental
health and it's just a reality so many
different
information security professionals
suffer from burnout suffer from anxiety
depression and really we often see
people turn into really unhealthy and
coping mechanisms which further just
really exacerbates a lot of these
otherwise problems
so my goal with this talk now let me
give you for
almost
18 months now um it's really kind of
legitimate
i'll share my journey
we kind of try to reverse engineer
some of the stigma about mental health
in our business and a couple of ways
that we can
really hack mental health and more
productive ways
i will say there are some things that
are going to accomplish
[Music]
can make you feel like you're
experiencing past trauma so trigger some
level of psd sometimes
you don't even know why it's happening
you know listening to something
earlier this year it was a tim ferriss
podcast he was talking about early
childhood trauma
and i found myself really upset by it
like physically not feeling loud and i
don't know why but those were these
triggers um and that would just turn it
off
something that was okay that was
triggering something so if there's
anything i'm talking about that makes
you feel uncomfortable do not have to
sit through it
just unplug walk away that's completely
fine and feel bad
uh
the standard disclaimers are not adopted
or what i played on tv
so the
content of this presentation is meant
for information courses only not a
substitute for medical advice
all content including text
graphics images and information is only
just for general information purposes
only
i splunk
foreign
information contained or available these
presentations
this is not medical advice
never disregard professional medical
opinions or if you need help get up
there you got regular wednesday
and when we talk about some of these
topics there's important definitions of
context so mental health from health and
human services
includes our emotional
psychological social well-being
it affects how we think feel and act it
also helps determine how we handle
stress relate to others and make our
choices so many factors contribute to
mental health problems including
biological factors such as genetics
brain chemistry life experiences such as
past trauma reviews and or family
history of past mental health issues
so that's kind of the health and human
services
version of mental health
self-care is any activity that we do
deliberately so it's these things that
you really need to
in order to take care of your emotional
mental and physical health
they're not passive actions but the
things that you really come again that
are self-initiated that you go through
and it can be self-control
and neurodiversity is a relatively new
topic but it's something that i deal
with at work a lot because i'm on the
employee resource group for
neurodiversity it just encompasses a lot
of different areas so the definition
that i've kind of heard multiple sources
that i've been using is
murder versus the idea that neurological
differences like autism adhd
mood and other functions that have
historically been viewed with this very
negative perception are the results
quite frankly just normal variations in
the human genome it's part of evolution
as we change and grows as a species so
this represents a new and but really
different way of looking at conditions
that will traditionally pathologize
and it's a viewpoint that's not
universally accepted but it's getting
more and more support through science so
that's good
and it's this idea that neurodiversity
and neurodiversity advocates point out
that neurodivergent people often have
exceptional abilities alongside
what society is traditionally viewed as
problematic or disability so we try to
look at it and know that when you have
brain functions
they're not disabilities or just
differences it's almost like
different operating systems everything
is a little different how you interact
with those operating systems might be
different ones not necessarily
better or worse than the others whatever
works but
going into what we're going to talk
about today i'm not going to die between
a reversing
i've been talking about cyber security
19 for 30 years in front of audiences
uh and right now i really changed my
focus to diversity causes
mental health and other
issues
and it's
interesting because you know
i can tell some of those crazy apt
stories of chasing people out of
networks from state-sponsored threat
actors people like that's cool and i do
this talk generally people who send a
lot of messages afterwards saying thank
you for talking about this this is
something we're not talking about about
so once i started doing that i realized
that this was something i really need to
dig further into and continue to speak
about because it's i'm talking about one
of the other areas of sound security and
fixing enterprise networks for so long
um i might as well try to fix people
government as well because the people
process technology
the people are really showing the
support of them
but after looking at how long i've been
doing some level of instant response or
crisis management i really think that's
like where i stand out professionally
is being able to
deal with
high stress environments and
this is a plaque i got in 1996 where a
friend of mine we were a ski trip
we were back skiing was
he falls gets hurt he's crying i went
and got help i got him situated and they
they gave me an award for like clear
thinking in a crisis situation and it
really sort of relates to everything
i've been doing my whole life because i
really think of myself as a wolf in
surveys from pulp fiction where i can go
into crisis situations you need to hear
what the dead body just called but you
have to do what i say when i say it and
do it
it's focused
because i don't tend to get shaken in
these environments
[Music]
my mind just goes into that zone
but i have really bad design like
crippling anxiety attacks and it doesn't
show and so that's the monster in the
closet it's been something i've been
dealing with for so long so even though
i can do
all these things almost seamless kind of
way it's underlying means it's a fight
every day you know something i have to
deal with i'll talk a little bit into my
journey about it but it is something
that is
part of who i am um i can't change and i
just have to accept advantage
even though i can do this things really
well this is something that's part of my
uh
and the reality is as i started talking
about it
more and more um i started seeing all
the research that supported the fact
that i'm not alone in this and that
a lot of folks feel the pressure of
these environments and would not manage
properly to really have some long-term
effects and andrea marcus said in an
interview a couple years ago there's
never a downtime it's not stopping every
day it's about and that's cyber security
it's just it's on and you're worried
about things that are going to happen
every day
but frankly you have to be right scenes
all the time
and attackers get to be right once or
twice
exploit a couple more abilities and get
in we're trying to manage massive
environments or visibility it's
stressful so it's known it's really
surprised that depression around even
suicide becoming more common with
cybersecurity professionals
really when you look at it from the
world health organization they say
depression is the leading cause of
disability in the world
heart disease so this is it's a serious
issue
and then people with mental health
conditions are the highest risk root for
suicide
most of my days
focus in with almost coaching and
mentoring csos and how to manage their
environment be more business focused and
i started looking at some of the numbers
specifically for that curricular quotes
that i deal with on a daily basis of
csus
so there was spending done in 2019 and
this is just for cesar's gold season
but i think the numbers can really
extrapolate well instead you know about
91 percent of the cso survey said their
levels of stress they were suffering
from moderate to high
sixty percent rarely disconnected from
their work role
work more than 40 hours per week with 27
working 60 hours a week in the world 89
percent of us-based cso's have never had
a 2-week vacation in the world
that's insane you know
and most feel about their teams are
unappreciated by senior leadership and
almost all field outreach was inevitable
but they're seeing those in these
organizations
and surveys only about 15 to 60 percent
of that breach was memorable so it's a
huge parody or a disparity i should say
in the way that
organizational leaders look at things as
far as impacting business from a cyber
event versus what diseases have to do
with the daily
basis but all these seasons nothing
either written up or could potentially
lose their job if there wasn't reached
so it's there's no surprise really that
there's this high turnover
in
these roles you know we normally see
individuals that are in their roles for
about 18 months they start maybe
affecting change at that point they're
burned out done with senior leadership
move up
enough cso comes in
they take about six to eight months to
cover their speed by the time they get
momentum really go they leave so it's
this vicious cycle it's only talk from
tone from the top of government's
leadership
my name is that mental health has to be
part of this as well we have to kind of
govern this down and really support that
a little bit more levels
because we're not really getting the
changes out on one scene
and
people not having the tools for stress
management
it really exacerbates a lot of
underlying issues
and some of the tools that we'll talk
about later but that we've done
traditionally it's been
coaching coping mechanisms
it's been you know if you go to
you know hacker summer camp it's been
alcohol drugs strip clubs i mean it's
just a party scene
to blow up steam that's not for
everybody
and jamie tomsela said it a couple years
ago
speaking of black hat 2018
she would talk about the stigma being a
recovering alcoholic in this
community
really hard yeah
we did a couple weeks ago at
blue team comp done at an involved
attack
but then they
provide these other safe spaces so as
community
we needed more of these types of things
to support our
members in our community with other
factors and other things to
develop the stress management techniques
because we've really done a miscourt job
and i'm obviously
not against going out and having fun but
i think it needs to have some balance
and that's one of the things from her
community it should not be our only
answer
and again i've been really bad about
that and
i'm trying to do better i hope everybody
else will too
because it's it's not okay to say kind
of velocity and just go
we don't
do
enough layered security in our mental
health as much as we do in our you know
environments it's not like saying hey
we're just going to throw an ap it will
be good and the same thing more this
thing now let's go more outcomes
protect our neural networks as well
and really kind of maintain this layer
of mental health
because it's getting worse this last
year i think we all know has been it's
been full of suck
you know out of the corona has just been
made thing that has really exacerbated a
lot of people it's been a hard year
people who have lost loved ones
distracted working school routines
i'm used to doing this on the road all
the time and this is only like my third
in speaking event in those two years
and i'm not used to not being in front
of people and it's really thrown off my
game
and
i'm not looking for painting but to say
we're not alone in this if this is the
way you feel there's multiple times
today that i'm talking to friends and
family that really start to struggle
with this this is long-term effect as
this
languishing as i call it
with uh clover right now it's just one
quote i saw and it describes it
somewhat accurately it's this
unrelenting horizon also the coded world
like when is this kind of just feels
like it's never commented
on delta
so again we have to do things that are
better at this point managing this and
again for me i feel
helpless at times because there's people
that i want to help and i can't because
of this environment so it sucks for me
not to be able to scoop in like the wolf
from whole fiction just fix everything
there's just things i cannot do right
now and so we're all starting to feel
that and it's getting worse you know
one of the long tail effects of in this
language is burnout these mental health
is suicide
i live in colorado we're seeing a spike
in it both just about every age you can
imagine
there is an increase in suicide
and they're otherwise and it's great
people feel helpless
but again one of my favorite bands of
all time is h2o
because
this is such a great quote from james
baldwin you know not everything that can
not everything back in space can change
but nothing can be changed until this
face so we have to
go at these issues and we have to talk
about mental health
and it cannot be what it is
and so i really try to pledge this
community to continue to talk about it
raise awareness
i definitely do not have all the answers
and i won't pretend to but i'm not going
to be shy about talking about those
issues any longer
because as hackers we can figure this
out and organize so with every problem
there's a solution
together so the obviously corona side
which is the elephant in the room has
only
exacerbated a lot of these overlying
issues
and i really didn't start doing some
root cause analysis of a profession
itself how did we get here how are
how are we
at the point where people are going out
and feeling unsupported
mentally and if you really think about
what cyber security is it's still a
relatively new industry but really the
way i look at our teenage years is this
frankenstein monster that has been long
together from i.t consulting operations
legal compliance
privacy so we have a bit of an identity
crisis right now and it's made it harder
to really understand what works and what
doesn't so there's a lot of good in our
business practices but there's also a
lot of negatives and so i've seen one of
the things we have to change is removing
some of this pressure and really
stopping things better
so it's not this idea well you have to
work harder you have to toughen down you
know you have this high legalization
rates you just have to go to local
compression regression pressure is
winning and i think i've done really
well in that environment but it's
definitely not for everybody it's
probably hurt a lot in the industry
so it's even done things in my own
behavior
that's that's caused problems i think in
the industry because i've supported a
little bit
because this mental construct of just
pressure and now this work for
and
some of the things i started looking at
as i started hiring like younger proud
folks over the past 10 years
they were like we don't want to do that
we've seen that affect our parents we've
seen that
in my family i don't want to work eight
hours a week don't work four hours a
week on my weekends off and i'll be able
to turn off
and then wanted a better work life
balance so that was me as a leader i
thought okay how do we do that that's
never been in the way
and as i started looking at it there was
ways to do that i'll talk about that a
little bit later
um
but it can be done we can do this
work-life balance
and i know it sucks because we feel that
okay well you know lives can't literally
be online with a lot of what we do
and it's different than what we trained
in somebody's a pure
i.t with a lot of things in i.t
you can blame a bad patch certainly
those down okay
but
nobody really gets
it's usually involved that some part of
that people process acknowledging that
people part somebody missed something so
they're feeling
that stress they're feeling that weight
we don't teach people how to cope with
that level of stress and we've called
organizational harm and if you're in
certain industries if you're a motif or
medical that could be somebody's life
and we don't really provide a new
foundation as an industry to help people
cope with that level of stress and
that's one of the things i think we'll
have to work on changing because it's
not very healthy or skilled
so i'll talk a little bit about my dream
in general
and
i was born in 1976
so i'm 30 years old and
but you know i grew up in the 80s and
90s and
for me it was this
it was
pumpkin hard for pumpkin hardcore music
skateboarding comic books all the things
that are cool now that actually get a
lot of attention work or got my ass
kicked high school for yeah so it was
really tough i always felt like the odd
man how um you know socially and
organizationally in school i just didn't
fit in
i got through
and then graduated high school but i
never really
felt like i belonged there and the lord
was like you're smart but you know this
is not the right organization for you so
i kind of got through but it sucked and
i really didn't have good um i would say
coping mechanisms my parents
my sisters all really kind of
type a personality so by the time i'm
getting towards my
years of getting collagen it was kind of
what are you going to do what are you
going to do and i just felt the pressure
that's getting out of high school i'm
prepared to
meet the real world and
you know i started with some friends and
some friends were like oh obviously they
happen to
you sneak beards get weak whatever it is
i had smoked something and i had never
done that and it was fun the second time
massive attack what turns out is that in
my brain chemistry there's
um just imbalances i didn't know about
so a lot of this underlying stress
anxious being really manifested itself
really horribly by a chemical that threw
something off was because of basically
the difference between the synthetic
parasympatic nervous system so the
synthetic nervous system is what
prepares the body for that fight or
flight mode uh the parasympathetic
nervous system it hits the body from
overworking and restores that balance
mine goes off and mine was just in like
full out
just rush mode i felt like i was going
to die
i didn't know what was going on this
went on for days in and out of the
hospital when
parents were taking notice i was like my
heart was racing like there's nothing
wrong with blood tests coming right it
finally took about
three or four doctors to
maybe you're having like massive panic
attacks and anxieties what is that we
didn't know it wasn't something that was
readily talked about in the early 90s
and he said yeah go downstairs to the
psychiatrist downstairs and he'll get
you sorted out and did and i sought got
help that i needed
but was that really that first bout of
anxiety in the early 90s that i but i
didn't know what was going on
and didn't know it was this online
medical condition so it
became something that i kind of worked
out of high school and like okay
well i'm really into computers and
technology and people were like well you
live in an ibm country but working with
building mainframes can i not do that is
there anything other than that because
there was these computers things
computers this internet this stuff might
have caught on but you know this was
growing even in the 90s why don't we why
am i not focusing there well that's
where those people are spending time
with technology and business in their
personal lives but there wasn't a
program for it so i'd go out and start a
business
doing a lot of kind of great fix stuff
it was a managed service provider it's
not
worked really well i
had this huge market share you know
totally addressable marketplace all
these people that had home computers and
business computers that would not be
held and i was business called computer
house calls
i was able to market it got a bunch of
press and pr it took off and i was doing
really well eventually i started getting
some more enterprise clients and
eventually i had merrill lynch and all
these big banks i was doing work for
them and going to convention centers
like this because you know i've been
traveling since the
before when my parents had their own
consulting business but i was traveling
the world setting up networks
and i was just going ongoing and then i
had another kind of burnout
trigger event in the late 90s that
really was my first bad burnout that
brought back a lot of those
parasympathetic
synthetic imbalances and i was just
totally crushed i was unable to do
anything the anxiety depression just
came in i couldn't work i mean i was
literally just because i was just going
15 16 hours a day and traveling and just
going going and it was just i never gave
myself any down time so i worked out
hard
and had to step after everything for
about two months kind of like get myself
every morning
and it was uh it was a really
tough period that i got out of this well
that was nothing that i triggered it
because i was thinking well then i was
like
through the early 2000s i
met my
ex-wife at the time we
got married in 2008 we had a kid and
then 2012 comes around and now i'm a kid
and i'm having a lot of running my own
businesses so at this time i had a
company called digital friends here in
new york city
doing cyber security litigation work
and i had to kind of give that up and
people wasting my entrepreneurial stuff
to go in the house to a company because
they had health care you know it was a
big thing it was a big light choice for
me to have to support my family it was
the new identity crisis because we as
entrepreneurs somebody has always been
against the system having to go into
dufferin phelps versus an institutional
banking consulting firm
and put on the suit every day and do
that it was just a
an odd cultural thing for me
it didn't feel right but i had to get
through it it was
kind of going through the motions and
that was really what set into what
this kind of lethargic
low-level depression that went on for
years that i really didn't understand
why i was so unhappy because i really
didn't
work through these issues really
understanding i just felt i had to do it
um and that went on forward i'd say
until about
2015-16 where i was like i can't likely
do this anymore i was working at a
company where
culturally was bad fit but i was going
to make some changes with the leadership
that i had there
and
even in my home life where i struggled
with some things um my expectations like
i just i have to change
and then again i actually some of it
when you find happiness in life is not
always self-initiated i basically had um
the manager i was working with my mentor
female from dublin falls to this other
company
they fired him
like
unceremoniously in front of like us the
team where we had about 15 people
so we'll come here now
you're the new leader of this group you
don't have to stay we're going to be
opposed but if if you if you decide i'm
saying to me right now too
um thanks
okay so this is kind of sophie's choice
that i'd deal with but i went in and
took things on and i had okay enough
people that are directly reported to me
i have a big piano i don't know and i
really kind of something just click that
pressure that
turned on where i was able to
really dig into things and
get things going i started practicing
meditation and those other things in
self-care
it really focusing on organizational
management and caring for the people in
my care
and things got better things got better
at home things got better at work and i
went through this
kind of rebound i was feeling
alive again because i was now under
control about the destiny of this
company they were giving me a lot of
free reign to do this and i was back
through my entrepreneurial self working
with the company so it was very
entrepreneurial
and this went out great but then i felt
like living in new york city with a kid
a dog and i'm traveling all the time
the ex-wife started to take the kid in
and out of
the building well that's just
one of those things that was obviously
great so you have to live better because
it's a stressful environment but if i'm
focused on
self-care in a better environment where
we go and i literally did risk
management i pulled out a map of the
united states looked at everywhere that
had fault lines protected potential
uh nuclear strikes
i looked at everything from risk
management perspectives about opening
the data center so wow colorado keeps
coming up as a great place to live
um
great quality of life schools
i can live with my income so i'm going
to go there i mean and i would we're
going to go wagons
made this decision to move from brooklyn
to colorado
two weeks before we're about to move
we're packing up everything and they're
showing our apartment in brooklyn
and we're just basically going to try to
find a place to go have
lunch
and
all i see is coming out as a car just
out of nowhere we were going through an
intersection with somebody on the phone
wasn't paying attention blew through the
red light hit us just missed my center i
spun us around
um
and it was an incredibly just
crazy event that was just traumatic
but at the time i didn't feel anything i
was all adrenaline but the next day when
i woke up i couldn't move and my entire
right-hand side of my body was
just in an excruciating pain when it
happened was
during this period i blew out two discs
in my back and i didn't even know at the
time because it was just getting the
adrenaline's going but the discs are
bulging so bad that they're chris got a
nerve that i couldn't i couldn't lay
down it couldn't sit down
it was just
non-stop pain 24 hours a day physically
and then also i'm like oh how am i going
to move like i got to help my family
move across the country and i can barely
move my body
and then you know making this big leap
of faith with the company that moved
office out to colorado and
i can't show them that i'm not having
this weakness now so i just try to bury
and get through it
and it was really
upsetting time sitting and trying to
orient
this idea of moving some
you know this entire family west to get
into a safer place i can't do anything i
felt completely debilitating when we get
out to colorado and
you know i'm trying to get through this
i'm getting some
amazing pt and other medical care
because it's
really colorado you have
doctors that deal with olympiads and
all the professional athletes so i was
getting people to lost care
which is great because pain was going on
the words trying to grab there's going
to be surgery
um now i'll get through it and then
about a month into it
i had um got a phone call from the
company they said hey just want you to
have a caller
immediately and i'm watching them
reloading my computer just turning it
off as i'm talking to them
and it was just for like
how did i stand like what was your
seventh package and i'm like not saying
like
you know who i am but i've been an
executive level
he did a job tomorrow like not in my
role that's like as a security that
takes six to eight months happening i
don't need to make a lot of choices like
that it's not
it's gonna go up into a montreal job
this is my life and career like
not our problem to them
it's a business decision you're just
aligned on spreadsheet and it's just
this
total punch of god to say like i'm here
i'm like physically in pain you're
cutting off my
health care you're coming off my source
of income i just spent everything to get
out here
um the little heads up would be nice and
i'm just like you're just
a line on a balance sheet
and so i was like okay okay i'll just
fight through it's like the rules let's
keep going
i will really kind of process this right
now i'll get through it i started doing
some stuff in the local community out
there reached out to
the cesar community i knew so with those
in issa osaka
with security you're like well yeah get
involved with b science denver which i
spoke at and organized yesterday but
four years ago i was like i'm gonna jump
into this and i'm not physically or
mentally really good about this one but
i'm just gonna ignore that and i
remember moving a box of um there's a
bunch of routers and power cables that
was gonna break down the network
so whatever like little steps that i had
made were just totally washed away and
the pain was even worse than it was
before
and that's like really when it all hit
everything kind of collapsed around me
at that
specifically
lining up for in so much pain
and just really the the weight of the
world in the closing round with the
feeling of the car accident
the
loss of the job the move everything just
started impacting you and look at this
scale of home training spills really
kind of measures these levels of stress
in your life and when you
compound these levels of risk um you're
trying to avoid getting 150 scores it's
like a cvss score of a
three below
not maintain low level stuff um
unfortunately you know
i got up to over 400 um when i really
got this up and that's like
that's bad
the high numbers are bad over three and
look at 300 points or more is an 80
chance of help right now i'm well i'm
just unable to
function
everything that i've ever felt before
came as far as anxiety depression
and my mental pain was
unbelievably high
so again one being the feeling of you
know emotional leash deletion you deal
with stress again stress is not bad
in your life in your human environment
it helps do a lot of things but it's a
balance and if you start looking at some
of these things that were
more on the severe scale
you know i was easily out of tense if
not
again the worst mental emotional
distress possible covered by physical
pain that's neurological
the inability to take care of my family
um and basically this this sense of
worth being taken away again i was just
a number on balance sheet that got taken
out
and i can't take care of my family i'm
in physical pain and the depression just
started
setting up it was inevitable everything
that i was fighting against to not
manage and not
deal with
came crashing in and so this is about so
we moved in march
april
15 17
time frames right after easter is when
they
ripped us off um
early days when we took my back and by
june
i was just
i was just basically functions i
couldn't
sleep i couldn't eat that couldn't stay
awake like everything was just this
weird kind of moment of just feeling so
detached and valid and worthless
and you know father's day is coming up
and it's
you know mid-june and i'm just feeling
like i'm the worst version of a father
here i am
and it's really dark thick to have to
feel and live with your feet
there's nothing left worth living for
and that you're on your life into your
family
and willing sauron
styron wrote this because 1999 about
depression
and usually not a slice and put a lot of
text out but i think this is one of
those important ones to kind of read and
hear at the same time because it really
sets
he says it's so eloquently like how you
feel at that time he says the great
drizzle of horror reduced by depression
takes on the quality of physical pain
but it's not an immediately identifiable
thing like that of a broken balloon it
might be more accurate to say that
despair owning some evil trick played
upon the sick brain-invited handling
psyche hung to resemble the diabolical
discomfort of being imprisoned and
fiercely overheated
because no breeze stirs his culture
because when there's no escape from this
smothering confinement it's entirely
natural after the victim
begins to think ceaselessly
and uh yeah that was nothing more than
what i could say after that it was it
was just a
dark pain of despair and i had no health
care i can't even get mental health
support because we're so
poorly designing this this
country when it comes to health care
about tying into a job which i now don't
have
social services i could get
help with you know i was on some
government aid at that point
basically
government food stamps i couldn't get
health care i was not unplugging
everything just felt like i just
couldn't survive
but i luckily found
after calling around somebody that was
willing to see me right away he said oh
yeah i deal with high stress
professionals all the time that you're
not alone
you've seen them treat a lot of people
in your
position so i'm wondering not a little
too his way out but you need to kind of
follow the directions and he became that
girl he was like you know shut up stop
arguing with me and stuff
these are the steps you're going to take
through medication and other types of
common periods and
and within
a couple months so from
june until about
eight august
i really did a full recovery and it was
not easy it was a hard road and it took
its toll on
my marriage it's my daughter
financially i just got out of that
um but it
i was able to get into a new
organization
started this in response practice and
grow that from you know
zero people to ten people getting me
back on my feet within a couple months
which felt good
and it's uh
you know able to get into this new
product this new
life and things are going great but well
i think what i learned out of all this
is this level of resiliency
is that you can get to this you have to
plan for this because
you know this year has been a tough year
for many ways and if i go back to that
stress scale you know this year just
this summer alone
um
my dog
like debated put her dog down so he died
two days later my phone was stolen in my
driveway um so yeah it's pretty much
john wick at that point there was a
russian night club i was going to
people up but i'm just i'm a little out
of shape right now
but yeah and then you know
get a divorce so it's just like all
these things compressed within a couple
of weeks
people like are you okay i'm like
actually i am because i learned a lot of
things from resilience about this and
that might kind of focus on
organizational resilience but it
reflected easily
to a certain way to
my
learned how to kind of
be in the moment with it and not hide
from it and let it build up to the point
where the system crashed
in reality is that what i learned out of
all this is that mental illness is an
illness and we really need to move past
a stigma and shame that people feel
about
the illness and their differences
because what happens is it forces people
to self-medicate it forces people not to
deal with these issues and they don't
seek professional treatment and i
probably should not treated and all the
stuff was going on much earlier before
things got that bad
but the stadium of doing it me being a
type a personality was nice got a tough
now
and it's stupid i mean we wouldn't tell
somebody that's diabetic to suck it up
right i mean
tell just a smile
we wouldn't use language like hey just
be an insulin baby about this shut up
you know we we
don't have this parody of mental and
physical health that we're going to be
able to have so we need to look at um
how people feel mentally and physically
is the same
aspect so we need to put this together
and just go back to one of the things i
was talking about earlier
people said well you know is this
uh you've been through all this so
you're just being really sensitive now
it's being altruistic and i said well
hold on a second like i almost got
knocked out of the account and now i'm
back doing a lot of things making huge
organizational changes for companies
across the world i'm just not a person
that like one of many
got wiped out
you know so if we don't treat each one
of these
issues and each one of those people
right we're going to lose a lot of the
people that
could affect change on a larger scale
and one of the things i started looking
at is when i built out that practice in
2016 i was really focused on
the health of my professionals now i'm
starting a new office in denver with
very high utilization targets
and i took in a bunch of things i said
okay look
at this more realistic how can i make
sure these people
aren't resilient and maintain their
ability to be high output performance in
this
and i was able to do is really able to
build a team
that balanced
time up they looked after each other and
what we ended up with were
people that were happier and healthier
they were staying in the game longer
and i ended up with happier customers
higher top line revenues higher profit
margins
we didn't have to redo work constantly
our customer satisfaction was higher my
retention rate was higher every employee
survey was higher so when i realized
it's not the zero-sum gain we don't have
to treat mental health as this
thing we don't want to deal with in the
business because if we do it's going to
cost us money if you don't deal with it
it's going to cost you far more so we
have to look at things like mental
health as something that isn't bit into
the way that we do business
again this reality is that pain is
inevitable to suffer this often i can't
sit there and let people
go through this and not
deal with things so that's some of the
things that i'm trying to work on and
look at what are some of
within the mental health community
there's specific things that we'll talk
about
treatment outside of self-care which
we'll talk about in a second you know
there's things that i use um i'm not
afraid to talk about those medications
like lexico i got my mother recently had
an ssri because she was having issues
and that's like you know 83 years old
you're going through life change should
not come along
talk to somebody get some medication so
there's different types of therapy that
work for everybody for me what work was
accepted as a training therapy or act
and it's this evolution of cognitive
behavior therapy that worked really well
for me because
really what i learned out of that and
why it's been able to orient me to the
summer of doing things is
really stop avoiding and denying
um with your inner emotions and this
idea is acceptance that i have these
issues they can't be fixed nor should i
try to fix them because that was the
struggle i was constantly struggling
every day to
fix my mental health issues instead of
just management
once they learned how to manage it it
was much easier i stopped fighting it
constantly
and that's how everyone can really get
through a lot of this
and
some of the other things i've done is
along the ideas of self-care and this
idea but there were things i could do
that i could literally put into my
operating system cycles that are going
to maintain my health and prevent and
deal with long-term moments
and so this is going to be think of
self-care as this kind of proactive and
preventative steps that you do at work
whether it's vulnerability research and
management threat hunting patching
funnels whatever it is that you're doing
to get ahead
of issues proactively and so there's
different things that you can do
it really kind of helps regulate your
dopamine and serotonin and these are
really the two most popular balanced out
neurotransmitters that help regulate
moving well-being
and so serotonin does a variety of
things in the body that's
really unknown exactly why
levels are so tied to
mental illness but the basis is a
regulation effect because it really has
balance throughout all functions in your
body particularly mental health through
the way that you
digest food and it's really a strong
regulator the dopamine is this feel good
transmitter
it's what the brain releases when eating
food
or
meat food that you create we have sex
uh contributes to
pleasures feelings of pleasure and
satisfaction
as part of this reward system
so it's a really important neural
chemical and a boost movement of
motivation
so
this idea of how do you kind of balance
out your serotonin and dopamine ahead of
time before things get unregulated
and there's a lot of things you can do
and some of the things that i encourage
people to do is
um take you know all these things you
know some things that are worth me and
stuff is sort of is reducing fatigue you
know on this phone i don't have people
nobody believes me but i don't have work
email i don't have slack
on the weekends that take off twitter
right it's really hard to get ahold of
me individually
actually a couple of businesses
you take all this stuff off
because i found myself being very
reactive i'm the best kind of woman so i
took off a lot of those things that
would cause distractions or words that
raises levels of anxiety in my body
and managing that
also there's other things like you know
calling a friend just writing to a
friend making those human connections
that's been really hard for a lot of
people this is one of the hardest parts
of the last 18 months of people doing
the self-care management
and really
toxic uh kind of environment
whatever level of connection you have to
make please do because that's really one
of the most important things
in regulating a lot of these things
the other parts really simple things
like exercise getting out there's
walking you know you can start small you
don't have to go and do any kind of
crazy
shame routine just getting out there and
getting outside the environment
and
what i found particularly in the last
year is commuting home now i work at
home so how to do that because i would
put everything down my office close the
door and i walk out and then go for a
walk around the neighborhood and never
come and at that point i've
put everything behind me when i entered
the
and touch the house
but it's this way of just getting away
from things adding some exercise allows
me to decompress
this little breaks and time management
and boundaries that become
uh incredibly important and what else
about this here is as much as i like
going out and drinking and doing stuff
because i really had to focus on
alternatives um because early on at the
economics problem we saw our wine bills
go through the roof um
i was like this is not a sustainable
long-term financial
because that's one of the dangers of
self-care is you can really kind of fall
into base self-care
of dying uh going from one stream to
another
um
saying bad things about yourself i found
myself doing that early on thinking okay
i have to motivate myself i should talk
to myself um and it's a really hard trap
upon where many people kind of really
beat yourself up and do the things that
are not true self-care things
so really try to focus on what what is
important out of the size you know it's
just getting away from the fake
self-care you're not going to miss out
things by
not being you know rushing out and i
think the photo thing is so important so
it was like i'll have to go if
somebody's doing something loud meet
them and do this and really not spend
the right time with my daughter or
something like that so it's really easy
to displace those efforts in the wrong
areas and really not
take the self-care steps that you need
and some people say do you really need
it can you do it there's a lot of myths
about self-care that is selfish or
really basic in your life but it's not
quite frankly deserved like i said we
feel better we treat better and treat
others better and work better
and some of the stuff we really have to
do for
some of these self-care steps like i
said just pick out three good for 21
days it takes 21 days to develop good
habits on average or break them so do it
for a couple weeks it's not a big ass
try to go through some of these things
and start managing your stress better in
your life but then understand that this
needs to be a lot of moral practice
you know some of the things that i
really kind of want to leave you with
and wrap up
is that you know again you deserve this
that you deserve this life
don't think that any moment you're
you're not worth what you are
um and ultimately treat others well
because you never know what somebody
else is going through and robin williams
unfortunately did pass away from suicide
has this great quote you know everybody
needs by battling nothing about and
that's so true
just take a moment to be nicer to people
and that's hard for me because i like
tell people when they're wrong and i
think a lot of times they might not know
that they need to tell them
so it's really that people look like
unsolicited criticism
but i really have to change that in my
behavior dramatically particularly last
year because i realized people have been
more
on edge their nerves are burned out and
i just don't know what else is going on
in life i just need to step back and i
really that was one lesson
last year and we all do and
warren buffett
framed it the way he's talking
um
he said one of the best pieces of advice
he got from his friend thomas murphy he
said
if thomas is a reward you can always
tell something about helen
which is just an easy way of putting it
right you know
if they really need to be told off put
it down for a day and come back if they
really need to but then you can tell
them about that but if you don't have to
do anything because this idea of stop
being reactive and i talked about that
and we went into the response work all
the time this instant response that is a
reaction you gotta do the same thing
with what we do so just slow your roll
and do what goblin does
just look nice
and ultimately it's because you don't
make time for your wellness you will be
forced to take time for yourself
so by treating yourself right making
sure what you're doing is
feel self-validated you feel that you're
worth it um you'll feel better i would
encourage everybody to do this if you
could
tonight
um
you know really kind of
you know continue to
support each other
um
and one way to support yourself is
tonight
we're going to get back to your house
and it's not going to tonight or every
monday or something take out like a
written piece of paper
telephone or anything else and just
write down five good things about
yourself when you wake up the next day
because i put the piece of paper with
the pen there you wake up in the morning
and that's
surprisingly hard to do and people are
so self-critical if you sit there what
are five good things about yourself and
try to do that one more thing the next
week you'll find how incredibly hard it
is but how incredibly powerful it is for
you to be able to think about yourself
and better lives and how the
frame seems to treat others better
because you really have to kind of
support each other if we're going to
continue to have the plan
so
really take some time to look into some
of these issues uh feel free to reach
out to me if you know others that are
struggling you know there's a lot of
crisis centered stuff that i have a new
level of mental health hackers
organization definitely check them out
check out the neurodiversity groups
inside your organization if you're
looking to start one i have a ton of
resources on that we've done really well
explode with that i have people that are
willing to reach out and help your
organization start that so with that
have a great day take care of each other