good afternoon everyone thank you for
coming out to corncon and yes john is
right i'm as old as dirk as far as i'm
concerned
uh
john's been on an office conference and
i've always
supported the community as much as i can
and this is some of the areas
that i kind of wanted to bring out with
that um to give a talk a little bit
about that from a corporate introductory
perspective with that i see so for lower
level mobility i have responsibility for
our parent company
as well so on a day my day job is
managing
a global organization that has
60 billion dollars in revenue operates
in 170 countries around the world
uh
then it does things at scale
that usually most organizations don't
on that side of it so
that being said i've been cso now
going on 15 years
so i've been to the place i've had
different reporting structure i've had
different owners of the company i worked
for google for a while
uh i worked for the roll up as a whole
and so i rewarded up for things so 15
years can be sliced
however you want to but i stay around
i'll also give you some other
points of interest on that i have the
same team that i started with 15 years
ago uh except for two people who got
sucked in by the google store uh and
could not come back and the other person
had to retire or wanted to retire
so uh it's pretty much the same proof
that i've been doing with new editions
from that side of it that's there
um
as everything goes um i really wish
ransomware would have encrypted my
slides but it didn't so you're in for a
presentation
so i always use a background reading
perspective
which says
this is usually how i feel than most of
the times where i go
the center cartoon is one of my favorite
far side cartoons i have a coffee cup
for it and everything else because i
feel this is the perfect scenario for
cyber security
we go into these situations where we're
looking at things and it doesn't matter
our choice
we're damaged or do be damned if we
don't which whatever we're gonna choose
and that is usually the paradox that
we're hit uh nine times out of ten
uh if i fix this this breaks if i don't
fix it this other thing happens just
even worse than if i break things
and so you run into those scenarios
daily
and
how you navigate those scenarios and how
you
communicate those scenarios it's kind of
the key to success
in a lot of areas
that's there
i have an interesting back story i've
worked for
large organizations
i do a lot of tweeting you can follow me
at sec rich on twitter uh i post things
out there almost daily on that you can
find me
in a linkedin fairly easy uh that's
there i'm not the rocket scientist that
works uh in birmingham
but uh i'm the other one uh that's there
uh for those and my wife usually comes
to conferences she'll be here tomorrow
uh we're kind of a partnership of doing
crazy things together that's there we
kind of
work together
in a lot of cases she's not in cyber
security but she has been around it long
enough that she she does do things and
hooks me in the right directions in most
of the cases that's there
i've done this all my life
i've done my first
pin test was back in 1984
which was a dial-up modem bank for a
bank located at valley national bank
located in phoenix arizona at the time
that was there that was my first pin
test that i had paid for and that i did
and all i had to do was guess a password
to the motorbank that was there that was
a pin test at those points in time that
was there and i've produced that all the
way through i've done this pretty much
like i said most of my life has been in
security i've worked for large companies
i've also founded a bunch of startups
along the way so i've done multiple
things that were around it i've done
writing
this is an article how we've hacked the
white house
agents go
in dark reading
i've done stuff on wi-fi security this
was right after the tgx exploits and we
talked about wireless security and how
there really was none and if the area
that circled down at the bottom
basically discusses the default
passwords account they're really bad and
they're pretty much standard in some of
those areas not much has changed in
those periods of time those are still
issues we deal with today
so
this is my my other side why did we go
wrong because we usually come to a point
where we have to stop and we have to
choose the direction that we need to go
uh in cyber security and this is part of
the issue some people that have a longer
life more security may select one
direction other select other directions
um and we don't really have good areas
but one of the things that i thought was
very interesting this came out of the
corporate executive board and from a
gartner organization where they looked
at metrics they looked at the way people
generate stuff because that's how
organizations and that's the first thing
people will tell you generate stuff so
you can show what you're doing
that's good but you need to understand
that just by just making mounds of paper
powerpoint slides excel spreadsheets
doesn't mean anybody's reading it
and that's exactly what these surveys
actually said was one 60 of these
metrics are manual process so it takes
your staff or yourself time and effort
to produce things
but on the other side of it
it's only used about 25 of the time to
make decisions
so the rest of the 75 it's a gut where
it's like we've done this before
or something else and i think that's one
of the things is you're making all this
work
to make something that's going to make
better decisions yet no one actually
uses it
to make decisions
hence part of the problems that are
there
and i think that's one of the things
that go and then as you move up the
ladder
most people don't understand it a third
of them
they don't see it on a regular basis
because there's not a cadence there's
not a
monthly meeting reportedly meaning
semi-annual annual meeting where you're
presenting findings
that are there and if you're not doing
it often enough it's going to be a
surprise every time
it's there
almost a quarter of them is mixed no
difference it's not part of their
decision making process
dollars
cost
people
those fit into some of those decisions
risks
security
don't often fit
and i think that's one of the things and
again it's about 10
are used for influencing decisions so
you're coming from a position when you
start doing this
of like
how am i going to get better how am i
going to show i'm getting better
how do i convince people that i need to
do the right thing and that's a portion
of the things that like wrong is that
hard and so i took a look at that and
said why is it so difficult what's wrong
with this i've been doing this a real
long time and i've been good at it
what's secrets to success or some of the
other things that are around them it's
just not my gray hair or my lack of hair
um what is it that's part of that and i
think it's one of the ways this
perspective has a lot to do with it i
came in from the world of the dark parts
the black hat whatever you wish to call
it came in from
the outside and into this because there
wasn't cyber security when i was growing
up i
when i went to
school for university and everything
else i went to my first computer
information management
function and we had a speaker coming in
and that was the first time i asked a
question i was like what are you working
on oh we're working on this
at the time it would be equivalent to a
crm tool
written in cobalt running on a mainframe
and i was like oh that's good so what
else do you work on well i've been
working on that same code for the last
nine and a half years i was like i this
is not for me i'm out of here
because for me that was not where i
wanted to be because i'm not i don't
want to work on the same thing for nine
and a half years i will unfortunately
probably die of boredom or something
around my mind i need other things that
i want to be able to do and i think this
is the perspective that i said well
let's take a pic how would you attack
how would you
get into your network that's what cyber
security you're trying to stop bad
things from happening so how do those
bad things happen just go to the root of
the cause whether it's internal whether
it's external packers criminals all
these elements how are they doing it and
looking at it so first you gotta look at
yourself
because it's like hey am i getting
robbed because i'm using an atm at 2 am
in a bad neighborhood oh yeah okay don't
do that anymore that can be a very quick
thing but is it portion of that so how
is your networks how do you see do you
even have visibility into those
do you know where things exist anymore
and is it the same way that you thought
it was
because again i
stretch a long period of time i looked
at this five years ago and this is the
way it looked i look at it today
completely different
technologies changing everything else
well
that's not the way we designed it that's
not the way it was orchestrated as part
of that and you just stepped down
through it
awareness are your employees aware of
things do they need to be reminded of
things
and then how do you train people
um one of the key things that i've
leveraged and used in the past are tests
that people are like
my tests well i can either produce a lot
of power points
and you go through or i can just say hey
we're trying to collect information can
you take this survey for us and figure
things out and you have three answers
what's the correct answer the other two
are thought provoking questions and i
mean by thought provoking not like
what's this think of like asset access
management and controls of that and
you're trying to tell people about
changing passwords and everything else
around that you can say that oh do you
realize that your passwords need to be
changed every 90 days 60 days 30 days
whatever your flavor is
on that is the question but you can also
go back password should be simple
and you're like well that's the wrong
answer but it causes the user to think
and it causes those areas to go oh our
passwords
aren't should be short you can even know
that you actually should be long and
they should do that so this is the
correct
one but instead of them going through
three powerpoint slides one single
question got their thought process
provoked on that side of it so it
becomes a training exercise and they
don't even know it's a training exercise
for what they're trying to do because
you're building that relationship with
them but you're also
kind of
coercing them into a decision that
you're trying to get without them going
through i was like oh i don't want to
take training again another death by
power woman we've all been there and
it's there so you really have to know
thy enemy but you have to in doing so
you need to know yourself and you need
to learn to think how the enemy is going
to attack your network because if you're
still on
the idea where hey i am safe in here
you're living in a world that doesn't
exist it's full of unicorns and poonies
that's great but the real world is all
black and
not a pleasant place
on the internet that's actually there
so part of this was the idea to say hey
is this like a mission impossible
can it even be done is this something
that is is google would call a moon shot
is this something that is just out of
the norm that's actually out there and
it's like
no not really it's not an impossible
mission it's work
but that's what security is about
it's about work there's always something
to do
on the other side of it that's why i
like it that's why i stay here as
there's something to do there's a cause
and an effect that's there yes there's
lots of running involved just like in
the mission impossible
you're gonna run there's a lot of moving
parts in your organization so yes
there's a lot of complexity that you
have to unwind unbox untangle to
understand truly the way things are
either built work or process that's
there
if you don't know how your organizations
built something from start to finish or
how it produces something or how the
services are delivered and everything
else it's hard to understand how you're
going to make it better when you start
trying to put controls and constraints
and other things around things they're
like oh that'll break that that will
make your things go our marketing
company won't be able to send email
anymore okay you just turned over the
apple cart as part of that but we'll be
more secure
you're going to lose that argument
so you have to figure out how to argue
with someone and i'm like the same thing
i have
kids and it's like arguing with kids is
much different than our game with
parents
that side of it that's there you you
have the same and i'm like okay how am i
going to use the manipulative word but
how do i how do i how do i change your
opinion on something how do i do
something around it and it's a little
more different
so you really have to look at that
um
there's bad news as part of this because
as you get into this area and wanting to
make changes
you are
you accepted the mission whether you
said yes or no
you accepted it
the question is
if it goes wrong
um what
there's an impossible you will disavow
they'll be like we don't know him
he's gone he's no longer here
um bad things happen
they're not always if you if you are
guilty of it the best thing is mess up
and say yes
i missed that
i did it
on that but at the other side of it
hey there's not any protocols or
anything else that's there
that is an issue and you're gonna have
to live with that but don't let it
paralyze you into making non-decisions i
see a lot of people that are i don't
want to
rock the apple card or anything else you
shouldn't be
you should never have that decision
that's there things are baby steps it's
not a security is not a binary function
that's on or off like a light switch
that i turn on and grip if the lights
come on and turn it off and it delights
go off it is a dimmer switch and i can
take small incremental steps it needs to
be brighter it needs to be bright it's
right it may not be as fast if they may
not be as that but you can at least take
those time to be able to do it otherwise
you're going to be like flipping it's
like oh
factory down bad
uh oops factories back on well
productions now has to be reset and yeah
that's not something that you want to do
but
if you've got enough
capital or social capital in your
organization that they trust you
which part of security is about trust
they already do
that's inherent
for what you actually do
so they trust you so use that trust
um on that side lean into that don't shy
away from it
and you've discovered that you're safe
when you're out going in a lot of things
the business will ask you to do the
possibility they do it
every week
of hey and this
no no no no can you put this into the
cloud
no
you will be asked to do the impossible
and you may be required
to do the impossible
that's there
and those are things that are you have
to kind of adjust accordingly it's like
this is a really bad idea that's great
we're still doing it um but it's a
really bad idea okay i can't walk away
from it
because in doing so you're getting that
sour rape story
because it's like oh you just don't
wanna you just wanna work on the easy
stuff the simple stuff you don't wanna
do the hard things
and it's like no this is the dumb thing
that i don't wanna do but
we'll be here
we will help
just when bad things happen i do get to
do that i told you so dance uh at your
next staff meeting because i did tell
you that it was going to happen and it
did and so but that
doesn't give him much satisfaction i've
done it enough times
uh but it's part of the site that's
there
but i think one of the other things
that's offered there is
we often overlook of why
people can't do so
is there a hindrance that i don't have
resources people
cost no money budget
et cetera is there some reason that i'm
not doing this i'm busy
everybody's 120 utilized i can't add any
more to their plates
and those are topics that you need to
bring up
before it
because if you're not bringing things up
ahead of time especially around
resources and constraints that you have
for doing things you will run into
problems when you now pop up the oh we
need more people everybody needs more
people and you're not getting more
people because it's late in the program
things budgets have already been aligned
things have already been done cost
estimates given and changing that
upstream is now problematic so you want
to be really really upfront with people
uh that's there and there's nothing
wrong with it
and there's nothing wrong with sounding
like a broken record
that says and
hey
i always mean people always need money
every single meeting need more people
need more money and that's like you
sound like a world record because it's
true
not lying not telling you nothing this
is what's needed you want me to be still
this way and still what we're doing this
is where we're going at that level and i
think that's super important
now the question is how many
missions do you go on how many things
are there what depends how much is your
environment changing how much is fluid
how much is legacy how much is
organization and there are certain
levels every organization is different
every management structure is different
every personality is different
there's a lot of difference in there
they all have to come together work
together to have an outcome that's going
to be a success
so
all those differences need to be
addressed as you're going through that
and that's oftentimes they're looking
out for this
um
one of the things i've always looked at
is things like
maturity index and people talk about
cyber security maturity and i'm like
what does that mean old
you think about it people always like
hey it's people processing technology
wow we have old people
running whole processes
and old hardware that doesn't sound good
and i was like okay step back that's not
what you wanted and i think that's one
of the issues that comes up and you see
it a lot of times with compliance people
are like oh work apply
well what's the scope of your compliance
see oh it's this one data center and in
that data center there's a rack and in
that rack it's it's compliant so
whatever standards you want to and
you're like well
that's good but your scope is really
narrow right focus that may be because
hey that business requires it
but everything else is just
you've seen the pictures of things
cables everywhere they're like okay but
one clean rack is the good one and
everything else is that really going to
work well
so you start looking at things that's
there
people try to things like well
this is big this is hard
it's not that people are like oh i need
a framework
frameworks work
compliance works
and the issue is that
you have to be mature in your process
you have to be mature in your
organization for those to actually work
from the get-go if you're not you're
spending a lot of extra time trying to
mature your things
over a period of time i cannot go take
wine that has just been
crushed in a barrel somewhere and it's
been in there 30 minutes and go i want
to mature this to five years
now it takes five years
so the maturity of an organization
takes time you can't have no shortcuts
there are no shortcuts it takes time to
do that and i think that is one of the
key areas that often people overlook is
they take a framework or they take a
compliance and they go this will just
work
these processes are not mine these
controls are not mine how is this going
to work i've got to change everything
it takes time
i think that's what a lot of people get
hung up around it's like hey it's been
24 months
why isn't the world changed and it's
like what
in 35 years
still dealing with freaking password
issues
takes time
as part of that
now as a part of that focus is to keep
because there is things coming after you
from every vantage point noon
and once you get popular once that you
find it they will win
it doesn't go down
my inbox is folded
on things of hey
can you look can you do this what about
this
there is more and more and more
that's
a good thing
but you need to keep a focus because you
can't do everything no matter how big
your team is it is not going to be able
to deal with the influx of things as
things pick up and do
as part of that changing a security
culture or working to change security
culture in an organization
that becomes security aware kind of like
ai awareness how security is important
guess what they're going to talk to
security team before they do anything
how do you manage that
and that's the problem you got to stay
focused on what is important
and then what you need to do to
to fix the rest of it because they just
can't stand they're asking for help
if they don't get an answer
they're not going to respond anymore but
if they get an answer they'll ask you
more questions
so you it is a yin and yang you really
have to look it's like what can i focus
on what is low hanging fruit what is hey
we don't have time and it's part of the
same thing when you're talking with
people and communicating just be honest
you know i can't get to that until
october
is that okay
and if their answer is no we go live in
september well how long have you known
about it and you can you can put the
evil hat back on
hey
your your poor planning does not
justify me
changing
so you can play whatever you want to but
you do have to communicate ignoring
things will just silence things and all
that good effort
goes away and just imagine too that good
effort you're doing try not to do things
that are too
crazy and notification and increased
voice
in some of those cases
of changing something oh we're going to
do this is the only way you'll create
more animosity than most of the time but
you do have to manage your time very
well
that's there
and
i think from the maturity
you look at it and people say what
really is it and it's like hey we assess
the effectiveness of a person or a group
that's there and it helps us derive some
capabilities
in order to improve performance it's a
quality metric if you want to think
about it
hey is it good quality bad quality what
will make it better
just there
but
it's very narrow it's very looking and
it's very focused on some of those areas
and i think a lot of people just say hey
here's our maturity model it's the five
steps we're
at two
we're at four
i can survey an organization and given
the title set and where
i'm asking the question if i go to vps
and everything else they will give
between threes and fours senior vps give
fours to fives
if i go ask the engineers they give ones
and twos
because they're like this is just f up
sorry for dropping a bomb but it's true
but
who i ask determines my maturity of my
organization whoa that's not right
so this is where i start getting in some
of these areas where that rating side of
it is it's not that maturity it's yeah
we're taking things and not making sense
for them
in other words
the person the engineers that are
measuring the ones and the two those are
the real
ratings but they never get elevated up
just like the information that they
provide as it moves through
this telephone tag side of the equation
go to the same thing
like oh this is not important this is
not there where is it actually out and i
think that's one of the other sides of
it now people have looked at maternity
cycles and say you can do a top-down
approach which is your classic stair
step
one through five you can do what is a
bottom-up approach where they'll say hey
these are clusters so if you have two
levels of maturity we'll cluster all
those together because maybe it's a
system that we can fix
and we can increase it and so they have
a clustering idea to say hey put all
these objects or all these things that
you're asking about for maturity scale
into a cluster and see if it correlates
together instead of having 500 things
you're now having 50 things to be able
to deal with and some of that but again
it's people technology processes that
are there that you're measuring on those
sides of it that's there
uh and if we were really measuring
technology you would not have legacy in
your environment
so we're not really measuring
or maybe we're measuring wrong
because the main frame you know
what if you look at the maturity level
hey it's got a 5.
it's almost as mature as like windows xp
that's been around for 35 years you can
sit there and go well yeah age has
something to do with it but it doesn't
make anything different it's
about the controls and some of the other
aspects that are there
always think about the actions of people
out in the world
if
it's bad
and they can do nothing about it that's
a problem
it's two problems on two front one
you can't do something about risk and
that's
a bad thing
but secondly
you don't have a choice so
on the other side of it if i can do
something why is it not done
and i think it's one of the key things
you see it time and time again somebody
will be like
oh you didn't do your accessory cookie
right when you built the application and
then developers like yes i did you're
like oh
and you're like oh here here's burp and
look and i just
got three two laptops and a power supply
shipped to my house for free is that
okay
uh and they're like oh yeah we'll fix
that but you had to take that effort to
prove to them because they looked at you
and said i don't do anything wrong but
that action is the action that you
wanted to occur on the outside so
action's always going to speak louder
than words corrective action so we'll
speak hey we fix something
you should always take credit for things
that you fix
because most of the time you fix
something
and we're off to something else and no
one knows about it except for that small
little group
that was there that you helped
the problem is that hey they don't tell
people and they don't communicate
and if you're trying to grow that
cultural wise and everything else and
maturity wise you need to communicate
that and communicate it up well that hey
i fixed this
and here and you don't have to tell them
how
you just fixed it
and that's all they care about okay
that's something that's checked on the
checkbox because eventually what ends up
happening is you end up going like oh we
have all these findings that no one's
taken care of oh well we did
okay we didn't report on that but no
one's tracking it no one's seeing it
that's there now hey let's not if return
a lot it gives you a finding wow you've
got to do something immediately on that
one on my point on cyber security
you're like oh yeah that's important too
but
you your actions always speak louder
than words
and who you ask
will always be those results but also
who you tell
is just as important enough questions
that are asked that are part of that
one of the most common things is like
hey i need to identify
my risk
what's what keeps me up at night
and whether it's at the executive level
board level everything else who we're
communicating with and everything else
wow and i tell people the first thing is
you need to know what you have
and people are like i do
and then i ask how many laptops do you
have
and the first answer is like
around
5 000 and i'm like that's not the answer
you need
unless your answer was well it was 498
yesterday and i'm pretty sure we had two
new employees getting new ones that's
there that's a different answer but
should be exact numbers how many cloud
instances do you have how many of other
things you have to do what you have if
i'm actually trying to secure anything
that's there and you really have to
hammer on that because i can tell you
the world of like hey
i don't know but i can go look it up in
my cmdb
i'm liking it's not going to strike me
at this point in time but we all know
that it's like oh that stuff that was
outdated like three years ago and not
accurate whatsoever so where's the
source of truth who has the source of
truth does anybody have the source of
truth
and no one's gonna come up and say yeah
this is 100 accurate
doesn't need to be but it needs to be
somewhere close
so it's there because hey is this our
internal id address external are cloud
instances what's going on how is this
there and that's a portion of it so once
you kind of build that
first
you can get it on the next leg
take that all that information and slice
it into it as many ways as you can think
of using it
slice it into geographic location so hey
if i want to know all the systems in
china i can get a fee
hey if i want to know what type of admin
systems are out there here it is my
phone and type of my windows 2003 that
are end of life here it is
slice and dice the data in all these
different ways and keep it
so that it's always because you'll use
it
it'll help you make decisions but if
that is not there
how are you making your decision
how do i know if i need to push this
patch for adobe reader when i don't even
know how many people have adobe reader
and i don't know what it's going to
impact maybe it's five
maybe it's 50 000.
there's an issue and i need to
understand that and until i actually
know what i have making decisions and
flying by the seat of your pants or
using your gut
you're not making good informed
decisions
that's there
and then once you're done with that
rank
the assets and what i mean by rank
is it important or not because there are
some of our assets that are not
important as far as i'm concerned
uh that may be important to other
departments
and supporters of things and people are
like well how do you verify importance
because if i ask every different group
every group is going to tell me yes
mine's important
critical to the business that's there
the business won't run anymore if this
goes down
you're like okay
so how do i verify that because
everybody's going to tell me
everything's important and then i just
have a list of everything's important
about that sucks
so how do i verify that
use your own
information go into your ticketing
system help desk
see if those systems are marked as a p1
critical vulnerability
so if something happens it immediately
escalates to p1
guess what those are your critical
systems already been done ra verified
already there if it's not in there
maybe you should elevate it
or maybe not maybe
it's more important to that department
not to the rest of the company
but
help desk tickets are a great way to see
what is critical and what is not
critical because if it's built around
that and it's an itunes system yes
business owned systems they not even
have how it does
but they'll scream if it's down
so look for those kind of things that
are there
don't you don't have to create new data
you don't have to create an index you
don't have to try to do something but
you can look and say okay i have no idea
well does it contain
any of the kind of data that you were
scared that somebody else has pii
privacy data customer data employee data
what's on it where is it at
what can happen with that i think those
are the critical things you can ask
yourself and make it a simple decision
but you also have the data that
empirically that's out there already and
i think that's one of the key areas
that's part of that
risk is not simple
everybody's seeing this heat map
don't
ever
use the heat map
[Music]
uh
it's not a good visualization it works
great for people like oh this is great
but it's part of the thing risk is not
simple
risk models are mathematical
representations of systems
on that side of it that's there
the problem is that
we do simple math we have skipped it
down to as you can see the impact and
likelihood hey here it is here's our
little matrix and look we have different
levels and everything else that's there
so
here's the impact and here's the
likelihood
so how many people have heard that it's
like it's not if but when
you get breached
and you've told that to ceos
multiple times awards multiple times or
other manages multiple times
so you just took the likelihood and
skewed it
it's done
likelihood is very likely
scroll
okay my my matrix now is just a bar
chart that's all based upon impact well
that makes no risk decisions based on
impact you can
hey this is critical but where is it
actually at
but what if i have controls around
zero
day du jour whatever this week is for
microsoft or
f5 or pulse secure fortinet whatever it
is there's one out there that's been
released multiple
that's there
are there any mitigations that are being
used
because that
changes
that portion
of that
what's the value of that asset
hey if we burn this cloud infrastructure
down we lose all our data
that is a lot of stuff that will
not be done that is a hundred million
dollars
gone
that's there
so there's a value that's associated
with the stuff that often is not looked
at
that's there and so there's pluses and
minuses behind it that we've forgotten
about
but they're part of your toolkit it's
kind of like you know i'm still using
the hammer and the screwdriver and
that's my only tools and it's like yeah
you have sockets and pliers and all
these other things but i like the hammer
and i like the screwdriver
it's like that's good you're comfortable
with it step away
from those and pick up some neutrals
because it's the key
now one of the things about wrist
that's there and i'll show some slides
that developed is like
visual is the key because i'm taking
risks which is a really complicated
understanding for mathematical functions
that are there and i'm trying to talk to
business leaders
about it so we try to simplify it as
much as possible but i think we try to
simplify it too much we should have
tried to visualize it as much as
possible
because visualization sometimes makes it
simpler for them to understand what is
actually occurring
that's there versus hey this is 2.6 and
we move from 2.6 to 2.3
that's good right the lower is better or
is up more better which one is it
we miss kind of the boats that are there
and we do a lot of extra work to not get
the outcome that we want
or be able to display
in some of those
so one of the areas here's
some areas that
we'll go through it's like pick four
major categories and this could be for
any manufacturing organization it's like
hey brand damage really really bad here
are things that we
want to look at these may be in your
risk register these may be questions
that the board is asking you these may
be questions that the ceo is asking your
cfo any of the people along those lines
of hey what about third party suppliers
what about if they steal privacy data
intellectual property
software supply chain all those things
fall in there
and what's in red
those are important but i don't have the
budget or staff to do this
so i'm telling you ahead of time those
are important and they're ready
not going to worry about them
it's a good discussion competitive kind
of like an icebreaker but
they now understand that
now everybody's data is more important
than our employees
i tell you that's the same for every
organization but no one will put it in
writing
but that's one of the key things that's
part of that same with supply chain
disruption sales disruption
business processes disruption
and then we use the same
matrix
risk and likelihood
and we plot the little colors
on the chart and says
now you know where things sit
my risk ratings and everything else are
there
they sit
hey here's my high residential risk
here's my low risk you want to be in the
lower quadrant it's a gartner quadrant
or something
i'm doing here okay there you go
okay
i'm gonna wait and see what you're doing
for my laptop
turn up on my port ah so you have it on
to the left side of it and says hey
here's where bubbles are
here's where my risks are associated
with those scenarios that are there
the second chart is here's how i root
from my 2020 risk to my 2021 risk here's
what's actually occurred some risk got
more
some risk got lower because i had a
program i did something about it we
changed the way we do business
things changed on that so i lowered some
of my risk
other things naturally
got worse
and they do it's no fault of your own
you didn't do anything
you did not do something but you didn't
do anything and it just got worse
and if internet is like that things will
go hey we we still decided that we think
exchange is like the greatest email
system in the world so we decided we're
still sticking with on-prem exchange i
think that would have been changed this
year but those are things that you run
into that get sucked back in but
in a visualization side of it everybody
in the room gets the chart on the right
immediately
it's there you can use a a circle or a
line that says here is our risk
acceptance threshold
that's there we're trying to bring
everything that's on the outside of that
to the inside
maybe that's your full things that
you're targeted is everything that's on
the outside because it's not acceptable
we want to bring it in
that's there maybe you're driven by your
supply chain maybe you're driven by
business maybe you're driven by your
third parties and partnerships
maybe driven by vc funds guess what all
those things pull into that equation but
the visualization of it is what you're
trying to get your point across
it doesn't matter what kind of matter
you use where it's at
but the visualization to tell people
here's what when we've done
here's how we did it
that's there and it's aligned to a
project a person more priority and
technology
you can
find that and do a story with each one
of these
and communicate that story
that's there and it doesn't have to be a
risk conversation
and i think that is the key
that our visualization of risk is still
an excel spreadsheet
and that's a problem
doesn't mean that you don't use an excel
spreadsheet to create it
but that's not what i'm going to present
to people that are outside my area of
focus
because now i have to explain everything
to them
what is this ts the
tls and cypher suite stuff that you're
replacing on all the web servers that
are there
and then you're getting into it like oh
no it's kind of like when you take a
straw and you put it into a soda and sip
that's the tunnel that's built and
you're like you've done run down a
raffle you're done
you don't want to do that that's why i'm
saying this they get simple
straightforward here's what's changed
here's what's getting worse
let's talk about it because that's the
conversation you want to have
what are you going to do about it
what do you think i should do about it
because that would be the next
conversation
what are you doing about the ones that
are moving into the room
not what about this gray one that's over
in the left hand corner
always the hr department
so
one of the key things that i always look
at and this has been done from that is
where is it being driven from in
decisions in the process on that and if
you look at it from
the staging of it
every level you're away from your ceo
that's another gating interference
communication effort even if you have
direct communication that you could send
to the ceo everything else it's about
how the information is gathered up and
not gathered up and this is different in
every organization but a lot of times
hey if you if the
i report
cio and the cio reports the cfo and the
cfo reports to the ceo
so all my information that i give to the
cio he gives half of that to the cfo and
the cfo takes that and cuts it in half
again to
the other one
when i first started doing board of
director things i remember you had four
slides you got through three and then
you were allocated like a half an hour
and they cut you to like 15 minutes and
10 minutes
they were there now you have a special
event you're on for an hour and you have
another whole day
kind of scenarios in your life
yeah thank you for coming wishes and
dreams coming true here's the outcomes
of that more work
but
hey you're able to get this and it is
now moved up
media has helped it's like everybody's
concerned about it everybody wants to
ask questions about it but everybody
wants to ask questions and then it's one
of the key areas that you have to be
careful of
so
i don't want to say that ceos don't care
about cyber security
but it's not on their top kid it may be
maybe in their top 10 like i'm concerned
about it but they think someone else is
handling it
it's kind of like hey i'm concerned i
won't be able to get employees hr is
handling that problem
i'm concerned that we're not going to be
able to sell more products sales is
taking care of that
it is dissemination of that and you need
to be ready for that because a lot of
people
five
years ago ten years ago people were
complaining that they didn't they
weren't sitting at the table
well when you sit at the table it comes
with the responsibility of sitting at
the table what are you bringing to the
table
that's the question they're going to ask
and they're going to expect you to be
able to answer
and like hey we want to do this is this
okay and you look at it well i think
i'll let the business decide
and they're going to look at you like
you're here
to decide
you are the business as a part of this
so you need to make a decision
and you need to be ready for that
because a lot of times that doesn't you
are the point person you own it they
expect you to own it they expect you to
deliver for it and they expect you to to
be accountable for it trying to
shake it push it move it
you're gonna get into
bad situations across the board that's
there
you typically have to manage you have to
manage expectations you have to manage
deliverables you have to manage
different things along the way and how
you communicate that is also important
that's there um
you will own things that people hate
shadow i.t is a perfect example of it i
i take over shadow ip things
why because they're unloved uncared for
sitting on someone's desk and it's like
this is really bad
let me take over the responsibility for
doing this
and they're like thank you here
but i'm thankful because now it gets
patched it gets updates it gets fixed
versus before it's staying there and
it's not going to change
it's been there for four years it's
gonna stay there for another four years
until the russians break in and hide on
it in the lab environment to shift on
that
and that's there
at some point you might even unpatch it
i don't patch it for workstations
simply due to the fact that that was
like i'm tired of not patching stuff and
they're like don't touch the servers and
i was like fine we'll take over the
workstations
because they have a larger footprint
we did this long before covid and
everything else and it's really nice
that we did
because hey if we had to rely on you
guys it would take forever
to meet their sla which you may not need
but now hey
all the workstations all the attack
surfaces are being greatly reduced
in some of those cases you will own
things that are that there be prepared
for that because you're you will get
asked on those sides and you will butt
heads at those times
and sometimes it's just like well fine
you take it over
you're like but i don't want to take it
over that you complained about it and
you complained last three meetings so
it's now your responsibility
but i don't
you still do and right you have more
people that are added to your team
as part of that
that's great but you will own what you
don't
complain about in a lot of times so just
be prepared
on that it is a mature process to go i
own it great i'll make it better
thank you
don't oh i can't do this because
immediately you down in the doubt
oh you don't you want to complain about
it but you don't want to take action on
it we all know those people they all
drive us crazy crazy in meetings on
multiple times a day
but yeah i'll complain and complain and
complain but i'll never
do anything about the planets one
complaint
that's great
time waste
on that so when they give you something
take ownership make it better
that's there
um
be prepared
and i think this is just a maturity
cycle it's there
the second you turn over a rock you find
bugs
the second you
look at a server a little closer or you
five bucks second you do a vulnerability
scan for ports and then you go onto the
device and scan it you find a lot more
stuff
you're gonna find more things
just be prepared it is like hey this is
the tip of the iceberg and we're
bringing
everything down
and it's gonna get bigger and bigger and
bigger on that will work to get it done
you have security debt you have
technical debt you have i.t debt you
have legacy debt you have all these debt
things that no one wants to pay the bill
for
that you're going to have to do
something with so figure out where it's
there
figure out your own ratings what's
important what's not important what's
your short list what's your long list
[Music]
it's there i always carry the list
as a topic on that i carry a list if the
business said hey you need to cut
everything by 25 what would you do
there you go
everybody in supply chain organizations
has those lists you should too
also if they say here's another check
how much do you need well here's my
current list wish
me less not this
on there
already done
here give it to cfo did you write me a
check today
bitcoin actually
um no i think that's one of the key
things
but
you need to figure out how you're
stacking stuff how priorities are
generated
because you can do it by dollars you can
do it 110
but standardize on something
[Music]
and keep it for more than a year
because if you go hey this is working
good we're we're the consumer reports
little dials
and everything else
25 done half done 75 time complete
uh it's fine just make sure you keep it
and that's what's being shown
if you change too much people now don't
understand make it visual so they can
simply understand that colors are great
this is why you have blackjack charts
hey red i know that's bad
green's good red's bad yellow is okay
so
hey people will understand that that's
why they're kind of sucked into that
doesn't mean you use it
because once somebody figures it out
it's easy but you need to standardize on
it and keep it because otherwise it's
there you also need to do some things of
hey here's my stack of stuff
that we want to do
what's the minimum what's the maximum
what's the average is it all horrible
and high risk is it somewhat there maybe
a little bit less where does it sit and
what's the plan
that's there
um
note to self any global organizations do
not use a through f
that is a very very us-centric breaking
system
didn't figure that out until i used it
and then i had half of my people
overseas going what is it
is that good
and i was like i was like uh
that's like what we get in school oh we
get ones and i'm like oh okay sorry
something that you thought was simple
doesn't always get in the other thing
share things openly before the final
product goes out
in a lot of cases it will save yourself
from making assumptions on that that's
there you need to figure out your own
schedule where it will be dictated to
you
and if you're like hey we're completely
fully
utilized until
november
that's there
but you need to show that you're fully
utilized don't make it up and like i
don't want to work on november
that's there because you will be called
to that and you will be told that no
this needs to be done you need to
re-prioritize so always be able to pick
something up and move it
that's there if you can't pick it up and
move it
do do other things you everybody needs
to know that
oh we have consultants on site we have
this this is going to be two weeks we
can't do it here
don't commit to it
and not do it because that just gets you
in hot water
somebody's watching you and will
determine that and i think that's one of
the key things you really have to be
there
if it's really broken
is it worth fixing
that's an assumption
it's not stupid i mean it's done it's
legacy it's not and you'll find those
things oh this just takes this invoice
and emails it
to this company um
don't we have a whole system that does
this in finance yes
well why can't we
use this now well this is the way this
was our first vendor that we set up and
this is just the way it works so you're
like
get rid of it
stop it
it's there
so
be aware that things that are bad broken
in legacy always ask the question should
i fix it or should i
kill it
get rid of it
because sometimes people try to fix
things that should build
unfortunately hey this just doesn't work
it never worked really well just move
on from that
that's there
um
it's all fun
until someone gets hurt and the reason i
say that is most businesses that define
what they call critical risk and their
policies and controls standards that are
there
that are there and they're typically
around like three areas
unfortunately
this is not my thing one
that two people have to die not just one
person two people have to die from some
defect or something that's actually
there
uh that's part of that there's always
dollars that are lost in sales there's
always dollars that are lost in revenue
and that's usually it
there's no cyber security there's no
ransomware there's no anything else
that's human life and money
because again that's usually private
business
there may be others and organizations
different verticals different things
that are there but it's always there
the term material risk is also important
use it incorrectly the lawyer in the
room
will laugh at you
and maybe correct you or may not say
anything
on that material risk is typically some
percentage of your total revenue targets
that are actually there so the more
money you make the larger
your
revenue
is therefore the larger risk acceptance
they are willing to take or what is
material that would impact
the revenue stream now becomes critical
and that can be huge
that's there
and if that's huge
you have an issue
because if i define my risk as like hey
this could cost a million dollars
and that is not a material loss for an
organization
guess what
if a million dollars is not enough for
you
what is 50 000
what is 100 000
so you really have to be careful on that
side of it what is the material risk for
your organization willing to accept
is it three percent of your revenue five
ten
that's there you're a public traded
company
not
all those are questions that there and
then you get into third party and fourth
party risk they're associated with your
side of it you're also into
am i doing assessment questionnaires is
it human interaction or just electronic
how are things being structured and
moved along in a lot of cases that are
there and then who are the players what
are the audits where do they go
um that's there is there a winner
talking about rest there is not a winner
it's kind of like the casino
house wins 50 of the time or a little
more than 50 of the time
so you take your winnings and walk away
before they steal them back
if you're trying to understand risk you
have to understand your audience who's
talking to where they act that
visualization is key
you also need to get buy-in and the
issues have those conversations where i
reach out to someone communicate with
them and get them to agree with me
this is bad
like i said it's hard talking to
children in some cases
yes you agree that this is bad and we
don't want to do this we don't want to
lose intellectual property to the
nearest competitor no we don't okay now
that you agree and get consensus on it
you can move and step forward it's like
a conversation
going up the stairs
and i think that's super incredible and
you need to do that on that
uh you can use your competitors with
what they find
for your community must must your
competitors see someone talk to you
and actually a lot of good friends on
that side of it and they have
conversations and you can talk to them
that's there
same thing goes for standards best
practices who's best practices that are
part of that
and that what is important to you what's
not it's not trade secrets
it's sharing
of that and we all get better when you
share this kind of information
uh that's part of that
when you do risk
there's things you can do with it you
can try to defend it
you can try to transfer it you can
mitigate it or you can accept it or you
can get rid of it
erase it
each of those has a good thing
and a bad thing
and it's one of those things it's it's
there there's not a good and bad each
situation is going to be different i
wish i could tell you 10 of these are
going to be defend
40 are going to be transferred
the rest are mitigation or
one percent is going to be acceptance 50
is probably closer to the real
acceptance level just be aware
different organizations have that risk
appetite that's there
that's there
i want to thank everyone i really
appreciate the opportunity to speak with
everybody and everything else that's
there again follow me find me you can
send me email
don't put me on spam list because i
returned the favor
i'm ninja lenovo.com or r rushing at
motorola either one stupid uh
please take a time to introduce some
yourself to someone uh in here i am
really about community and making the
world a better place the only way to do
that is we can work together
and i'm really strong about that
security is about doing
it's not about
talking about it it's about
doing it and we all have to do it that's
there
and if you want to get stuff out of life
and get what you wish for it's a lot a
lot of work so if you want to be the
person
that reports to the ceo and everything
else it's not an easy thing
is it rewarding oh hell yes
is it a lot of work
yes
but
every day you make a difference and you
make a change and you can see it so i
strongly recommend it and everything
else and i really appreciate the time
on that i'll be around uh all day today
and tomorrow so if you have any
questions i know we have another speaker
coming up
and i appreciate it from everybody so
thank you again i appreciate it
[Applause]