welcome to
um track one it is
ten o'clock nine fifty nine but we're
starting a little bit early our next
speaker is scott
schumer
yeah
he's using that degree uh scott is the
ceo of
aerotronics systems
um he is the president and ceo um
out of new jersey oh welcome
uh and he does world-class wireless
tests and security solutions he is the
author of three best-selling security
books hacked again
cyber security is everybody's business
and senior cyber
is a highly sought after author and
expert for live security events media
appearances and commentary on the topics
of ransomware wireless threats drone
surveillance and hacking
security for consumers and small
businesses no big deal that's a lot
he is often seen on abc news bloomberg
tv al jazeera america cbs this morning
news cnn fox business and many other
networks scott also serves as the cso
and chief media commentator for cyber
security ventures and sits on several
cyber advisory boards for various
companies so
i welcome scott to the stage
[Applause]
how you guys doing there
and i should mention i think i'm
supposed to mention at the end we'll do
a little book signing out in the hallway
there so you can get a copy of my book a
complimentary copy there thanks to a
horncon i really appreciate that having
me come out here i know it's a smaller
crowd but that's okay if you do have any
questions
while i'm talking just feel free to just
put your hand up there and i'm happy to
try to answer the best of my can or get
to the answers later on so that way it
can be a little bit interactive
especially as a smaller group there now
and today what i'm going to be trying to
talk about is skimmers
and it's kind of a problem in the world
of cyber security that not that many
people talk about in fact a few years
ago
as i started to learn about skimmers and
the more and more
i heard about them and i started doing
research about them writing about them
and understanding
how effective they are it opened my eyes
up to a lot of different things and i
think that's kind of a
an interesting starting point just think
about cyber security in general
how much damages that there actually are
and certainly skimmers at the top at the
top we're going to talk about a little
bit here how much that makes up
in damages and credit card fraud things
each and every year it's amazing so just
to to kind of set the stage
[Music]
jump there just to the first slide i
just want you to think about this let's
just really put it in perspective
cyber crime damages will cost the world
six trillion dollars by 2021.
that's a lot of money
here we are in 2021. i had the privilege
here some of you guys
may watch the show shark tank or
whatever robert herzog um
he's got a really cool company worship
group up in toronto i was up there for a
particular event but this was another
occasion i got to sit down and interview
him for about a half hour and just ask
him some different
questions and get his pulse on the
industry of
and they do a couple hundred million
dollars a year so they're heavily
invested especially with a lot of the
stuff with the sony breach and other
breaches where they're very uh
instrumental and when i brought up this
statistic i asked them the question
about the
the damage of cyber security
and he thought that number was actually
conservative and was much worse
so again it speaks to how bad of a cyber
security problem there actually is out
there with all these compromises
and that kind of sets the stage thinking
about skimmers
skimmers are multi-billion dollar
industry stealing our credit cards
commonly from any type of retail
point-of-sale terminal
in the united states gas pumps are
targeted hugely and of course atms
so pretty much any bank and we're not
just talking united states but really
globally they're very effective and
there's different types of skimmers
and i'll talk about some of the
different things and show you a couple
different pictures from some of the
research i've done and some of the tools
that we've actually developed in our
company and just as a short background
more on the technical side
who am i what am i i'm just here
speaking about the problems and things
we're actually we have a company i run
and we develop wireless threat detection
tools so we do research we find problems
in the industry we actually provide
solutions most of our solutions are
hardware some software but most hardware
that we provide to dod agencies in this
particular case for skimmers we actually
develop skimmer detection tools so we
have to actually understand how skimmers
work how to find them and how to get
them out of whatever they're placed in
i'm also part of the skimmer task force
on national waste adventure so i work
with them sharing knowledge training
from different groups everything from
fbi secret service and local law
enforcement as well so i had to go out
make sure i'm trained understand how to
visually spot
skimmers how they're hidden inside of
gas pumps for example spent a day down
in florida learned a lot and then taught
a lot as well as a result just to give
you a little bit of context and
background which i think is always
important there
now
just to kind of high level what are some
things that we'll talk about here what
are skimmers the types of skimmers the
different methodology installing them
effectively how psycho criminals do this
how are some things practical things
that we can do to stay safe and then
also talk a little bit about dark web
i'll get into that i won't dive into any
of this real deep and technical unless
you have a question or want to oh i
could try but dark web more from a
standpoint of
how is this information that's stolen
actually sold because that's where most
of the stuff is going on is in the dark
web there so we'll dive into that a
little bit as well and again as a
reminder
just put your hand up there and yell out
if you have a question it makes for a
more lively discussion otherwise
i'm just going to be talking up here for
now trying to keep you guys all awake
okay so first of all what are skimmers
well skimmers are have been around for a
number of years ever since credit cards
really took place so they've been around
for decades we've heard about them and
then it kind of got quiet for a while we
didn't hear about them as much most of
the time when you hear about a skimmer
in the past it was always something that
would slide down the throat where your
credit card goes in we're used to that
right and what is a skimmer a skimmer is
basically a second magnetic head
a secondary read head that reads our
credit card information so that magnetic
stripe on the back of your credit card
that second re-head it pulls off the
track on track two cpu all that
information
that tells them hey here's the credit
card number and so on and so forth and
that mag stripe information is what
cyber criminals really are trying to get
they're trying to basically steal that
off of our cards there
as things evolved the wonderful world of
wireless things are more convenient now
we now hear about bluetooth skimmers and
then there's also cellular skimmers so
basically these are wireless skimmers
and again it's a magnetic read head and
then it's coupled to a wireless module
typically bluetooth is the most popular
because it's it's ism band 2.4 gigahertz
fast frequency hopping a level of
security there and it also allows the uh
the cyber criminal to have convenience
think about that for a moment if you're
a bad guy
and you go into a bank what do you do
you got maybe your mask on you got a gun
your getaway car outside you have all
these different things that you have
that could kind of give away
who you are and get caught now think
about it in contrast let's think about a
bluetooth skimmer that you place
let's say inside of a gas pump how would
one go about doing such well obviously
you got to buy the bluetooth skimmer
you just need some money for that
anywhere from i've seen them six hundred
dollars to maybe twelve hundred dollars
in the dark web actual cost in parts is
probably about thirty forty dollars but
they command a high price because they
know a lot of these guys have stolen
funds
and then they can easily buy a lot of
these skimmers it becomes a business
model in supply and demand
so they've used a couple common modules
typically these bluetooth modules inside
the bluetooth skimmer and how does it
work it's usually a simple microchip
that's got buffers of memory in it it's
got a bluetooth module in there that can
now transmit the information and there's
a cable that you can see it in this
picture here uh to the right of my
picture there when you plug that into
the top of the point-of-sale terminal so
your card would normally go in say it in
the gas pump all right your magnetic
card will go in there that cable plugs
on top so now the transaction will
happen you pull up to the gas station
and normally you would buy gas and pay
50 for gas the transaction will go
through but a copy of that information
with distorted credit card information
off your max tray would go into this
buffer
and now it just stores it it records a
couple hundred of these stolen credit
cards each day on each pump
and then what happens the cyber criminal
obviously wants to have it placed in the
machine they never have to go back to
the crime
scene right there to get caught they
could stay within about 75 foot
proximities about what you'll get out of
a typical good well-placed bluetooth
module and a gas pump
so we kind of get a sense of how easy it
is they'll pull up a parking lot
alongside the gas station with their
laptop
and then they'll pair they'll sync up
with that bluetooth module
and then they'll just download from each
machine each gas pump all those stolen
credit cards
and then
later on use those to process online
cell packaging talk a little bit more
about that but that's the beauty but see
how convenient it is now you probably
are sitting there and saying oh well gas
pumps are locked aren't they
sure that's what i thought too
how many keys do you think they are
there are for gas pumps to get into it
this is about 90 of the million plus gas
pumps throughout the united states
you're pretty close five six six keys
generic keys
isn't that scary
so you got six keys that you can get
into all these pumps now does that make
any sense it actually does from a
convenience stand
so if you're a guest station attendant
you're the owner you're the guy
delivering the petroleum uh if your
national weights and measures you have
to come in and actually verify the
amount of
there's a lot of reasons that people
need constant access they've got to
change the paper that's printed out for
the credit card receipt and all of
that's good and fine and legal the
problem is the cyber criminals realize
i can get inside the rat's nest there
just simply plays a bluetooth skimmer so
you go on ebay or dark web now you buy
these six generic keys about fifteen to
twenty dollars that's even sold for
you're in business
now you pull up say two a.m at night at
the gas station no one's looking the
cameras are off
open up the door you take your bluetooth
skimmer that you purchased you plug it
in the top you close the door you lock
it
you leave
they provide power within the pump for
you you're in business
about 15 to 20 seconds the average cyber
criminal could put a bluetooth skimmer
upon
and a lot of the distinct operations law
enforcement that i've talked to and work
with the interesting thing is as fast as
they find the bluetooth scanners
take them out report them investigation
federal investigation a lot of work a
lot of money law enforcement does a
great job there however the next day
they'll be replaced again
it's that easy to put them in so you see
the common problem
i said to myself well this is stupid why
don't you change the locks
change the locks and you gotta have
different keys everybody doesn't have
access to the keys and it becomes that
locking key situation so it becomes more
of a physical security problem and many
people back away and hesitate from just
simply switching over to doing that so
and hence it makes make sense then
why the problem is so prevalent
now there's a lot of different types of
skimmers too the old days you see the
little kind of the green plastic that's
somewhat translucent it's outside of an
atm it's very common a lot of times
you'll actually take a skimmer and place
it
inside there and these things are pretty
smart you've brought one with me so you
can see it but it's something that'll
fit you know between my two fingers here
very small a couple inches across
small lithium battery there that's
typically on there they use a lot of hot
glue to affix them to different surfaces
um and then typically they'll actually
print with the 3d printer which is
anybody could use that these days
they'll actually print their own bezels
they'll try to make them look a little
bit warm they'll epoxy them on top of an
older vessel and that's more old-school
to do on an atm that could be done on a
gas pump i've seen it that way and again
they'll embed that circuit there
it could be a traditional skimmer or it
could be a bluetooth skimmer as well
there doesn't really matter
now for atms the interesting part is if
you think about it if you're using a
debit card obviously on your mac stripe
is is your credit card data your debit
card data that they want to steal they
need one other magical ingredient what
is that
your pen your pin right so how do they
accomplish that there they have to use a
small little pinhole camera and there
it's interesting because they'll place
it in any spot that you really can't see
and oftentimes if you look at the way an
atm is designed to see where the pinhole
cameras are you have to really be a
detective you have to get down
and look up underneath some of the spots
at the angles wherever you see a little
crack or crevice that's a great spot
where they tend to hide them and
sometimes they're actually again behind
other fake bezels i've seen them behind
stickers where they just put a little
pinhole over the camera so they can do a
lot of things to hide these cameras
what's the point of the whole camera
again so they can see your pin code one
two three four that allows you to have
access to your debit card and take the
money out and all they have to do now is
correlate their little video
with that of the stolen debit card
information put those together your
credit card information and your pin
code now they can go in business the
difference is with the debit card
when they take the money what happens
they take it out of your account
immediately
so i always question people think about
a debit card there's advantages of a
debit card it's convenient
you go into any machine anywhere you get
money out maybe you pay about for two or
three or if i mean four or five dollars
sometimes for a fake
but you don't have the same liability
protection that you do with a
traditional credit card
in other words traditional credit cards
compromise what happens you call up your
issuing bank credit card company my car
was compromised
uh mr shover will shut it down we'll
send you a new card you'll get a few
days what's your liability as a consumer
anybody know
fifty dollars right and nine out of ten
times and i've had my card compromised
more than probably all of you combined
because i was targeted and hacked within
my my company and myself personally
another story i may talk about it later
um
the interesting thing is if you call the
bank and say hey i'm a loyal customer
come on
we'll wait we'll wait for fifty dollars
mr chauffeur and how about your debit
cards compromised
not the same thing again they took three
hundred dollars out of mr shover's
account and i had to go fight to get
that money back will i get it back
probably because the bank wants to work
with me who pays for all this
who pays for all this money that's
stolen
a lot of people don't realize this the
consumer we do yeah
about four percent of all of the
interest that's paid
for these people that run balances don't
pay their car all the time about four
percent of them
bazillions of dollars i don't even know
how much money that it's a lot of money
that was just to fight credit card fraud
to fill claims and things like that with
all these problems people can make so
you start to see how big this problem is
huge
billions upon billions of dollars when
there's an atm or let's just say a gas
pump that a skimmer has found
think about that for just a moment what
what harm does that cost obviously
consumer credit card
that goes in that pump each pump usually
they get about two to three hundred
cards a day by around us
so you've got that issue and then make
their skimmers in three or four of the
pumps and then you're talking a thousand
parts a day
once they find the skimmer they have to
shut the pump off
they call it local law enforcement
becomes a federal crime scene so now
federal
has to be investigated
time money
costs you start to see the problem
the average gas pump with a skimmer
placed in gets about 116 000
stolen
credit cards before they find it
on average
now multiply that by
they're reporting thousands and
thousands of skimmers being pulled out
of machines
in many different states florida
texas
certain states are really bad so you
start to get a sense of how bad this
problem really really is
and we just need to be cautious what can
you do as a consumer
if you're pumping gas let's say to stay
safe
getting your credit card scammed
please
visual check
you can do a visual check excellent yeah
and that makes a lot of sense so you've
got an outside plastic bezel you can
jiggle it
and see if somebody tampered with the
machine something doesn't look right
um
now let's say it looks beautiful it's
not tampered with it looks like a brand
new machine
guess what maybe there's a bluetooth
scaler inside so no matter how good your
eyes are how would you check that
machine now guess what you may not see
it that's scary
that's really scary um and we even
developed some tools that actually go
down into the neck
of the actual credit card to see if we
detect if there's a second greenhead
basically it's real simple so it's a
green light red light a few hundred
dollars to stick it in there it beeps if
there's a skimmer placed in there if
it's clean it gives you green light now
that's good if it's an old style
traditional skimmer what if it's a
bluetooth uh skimmer in there well there
it's a little different we have a
different tool attached to the
directional antenna we had to design
conical directional antenna nine dbi
gain allows us to steer that people
think about a geiger counter so that
could steer inside to which gas pump and
we actually will pair with the actual
bluetooth module we'll establish a
connection pair with it and we talk to
it and then we can have it so just that
bluetooth module hangs out and talks to
us and what we've done simply is
identified
based upon an address inside each
bluetooth module which the cyber
criminal gangs are mostly using because
they're cheap they mass produce these
things they're built in china and these
these bluetooth skimmers so they're easy
to identify we've got about six of them
that have been identified in the wild so
we'll actually scan and look for those
specific addresses
and if we see that put the unit into a
special direction finding mode and
actually
hone in on it and now you walk up and
say that pump has a bluetooth skipper
pull it out next that one does those are
clean move on to the next station
it's that much of an effort to actually
have these task force work with law
enforcement to actually check and read
these things every day what's another
thing you could do so you don't become
victim
you probably don't have a tool to scan
the machine right if you're a consumer
what can you do
cash cash cash is king right old school
that's what i do
because there's no easy way as a
consumer pull up and know that there's
not a bluetooth skipper
no matter how good you are
it's a numbers game yeah statistically
you take the pump in the center that's
closest to the attendant has the lowest
number of skippers put in the one that's
closest to light and cameras you can use
some common sense
to minimize your chance and analyze the
risk so you don't get busted but if you
pull out
cash it's a lot safer it's not
convenient
i always talk about when i present to
different audiences balancing
security versus convenience and that's
really a decision in the world of cyber
security every day we have to make
do we want to take a moment extra and
use multi-factor authentication
well it's really it's a lot more secure
oh it's going to take an extra 30
seconds to look up that passcode and
enter in so what do we tend to do it's
not convenient so we shy away from it we
shy away from encryption we shy away
from backing up our data lots of these
things we tend to do
because it's convenient for us
so the balance is we hope that more and
more within the industry they can
develop products that are more
convenient and secure please go ahead
are there uh
contactless skimmers yet
that's a good question in fact
that bothered me for a while because and
i'm going to a long discussion going all
the way back about credit cards and
security
and maybe just briefly touch on it but
really to answer your point no there's
not a lot there's very little part of
the problem
and i don't want to get into the world
of politics and red tape but
if there's not a federal law there's not
a mandate
to put security into things it doesn't
typically happen because there's a cost
involved so in other words if you had to
take the million plus gas pumps out
there and upgrade them to more secure
payment methods it ain't going to happen
and if it does when there's a mandate
it's going to take years to happen i
believe it was last october the mandate
took effect where they're saying now
station's got to start
updating to put in more secure payment
and when i say more secure payment what
does that usually mean typically it
means chip and pen so let's back up for
a second here who here has chip and pin
and they're waller cars be honest i do
right probably all of us
who here when they go to the store
i don't know what your store is here
while quick check or whatever you do you
take your card and put it in the front
of the machine right you'll put it in
the front of the machine not
perpendicular so it can read the chip
and then who's entering a pen
oh wait a second you just said go on
chip and pin cards
do you really have chip and pin cards
yeah chip and pin cards but you're not
entering a pen
right we talk about security is achieved
in layers like we do multi-factor
authentication two-factor authentication
additional layer of security very
important yet you all have chip and pin
cards but you're not in your companion
what are you really using
chip and signature that's really what
you're implementing chip and signature
in other words i could take my chip and
pin card or my instrument bank sticking
it to any point of sale terminal and now
i can sign mickey mouse and they
validate me up on mickey mouse and the
transaction goes through does that seem
very secure to you
it's not please come here so um i lived
in the uk for a while and they did have
a chip and pit yes what was the what is
the difference because you know the
technology exists within the pos systems
that we're using
what's the reason that we're not using
the pin along with the gym a great
question uh it comes down unfortunately
to the old laney dollar
and in the case of what you mentioned
the united states is decades behind in
security i hate to say that living here
but it's true if you go to the uk you go
to canada you go to many countries
around the globe they implement security
along with credit cards much better
ironically who has the best liability
for credit card fraud in the united
states
so if you're compromising the uk when
you were over there
it's hard to get your money back in the
u.s it's really easy because the us
wants you to spend your money on credit
card and pay
interest rates and so on and so forth so
the system is backwards it's throw money
at the wrong thing so instead of
spending money and implementing security
properly
it's done backwards now let's take a
step back let's go back 2013.
do you guys remember when the headlines
all went crazy target breach
right
credit card i remember that day very
well that night i was sitting there with
my wife who happens to love targeting
shops there every week
i said oh great we're gonna be
compromised sure enough we were um
the next morning i got a phone call i
don't know what it started i think at 4
am i had five interviews that day i'm
close to new york city so i have to go
in and off and weigh in on different
breaches that's when it really kicked in
five different major news networks i had
to hit all in one day or cnn bloomberg
fox down the whole channel i was like
what happened how did this happen what
we've done is that the one thing nobody
really wanted to hear nobody really does
today
but i'll say it anyway back in 2013 a
little prior to that
when the whole target breach started to
unfold 2014 and 15 we learned about all
the details of it target actually was
the first to adopt chip and pin
technology
they actually went did a pilot and spent
tons of money
testing proof guess what it works it's
more secure the negative side to your
point
it slowed people down at the register
it wasn't as fast so now again
convenience or security what do you want
to choose
money man convenience that's what
happened unfortunately they abandoned
the whole project so they they quickly
disbanded wasted a lot of money in doing
all the r d research to prove that it
actually works but they went for the
money did they pay for it i think so
brand damage right just alone we're
still talking about it today years later
so it helps to put things in perspective
the importance of
if you have a small business
to apply security within reason it can
make a difference between your survival
and your failure sometimes a lot of
people don't realize that but it really
does make sense
to properly deploy security and use it
now the mandate happened with
the laws
that
if all the retail
locations didn't update to new chip and
pin technology by a certain date this
again was an october something dated a
few years ago if it didn't happen then
there was a liability shifts and then
you've got a bank and issuing merchant
it basically goes down to the retailer
so if you don't update and there's a
breach or a problem you're held liable
then you're going to pass so guess what
happened
the spend happened and everybody
suddenly updated chip and pin so they
have the ability to accept it they just
don't implement that's all so it's kind
of a backwards conversation in some ways
please good
working in the industry i've heard a lot
of chat about
reputation damage reputation damage
reputation damage
i'm looking at target stock price
and they're at record high yeah so is
there really a long-term reputation
damage and therefore an actual monetary
cost to the companies yeah yeah there
actually is in fact i did an article
appeared in the huffington post a few
years ago and talked just about that um
specifically i got into detail if you do
a search on the internet you can find it
i talked about the brand damage what's
inflicted who are all the parties
involved
now in the case of a target the
interesting thing is they're a huge
brand that was growing growing broke so
put them out in the news a lot
but then what happens is over time
people tend to forget they get a little
complacent
and
where does the money often come from for
a large public company
it's the public
so again who's paying for it
people are buying shares of it right did
they take a head did they take a loss
that they they have a lot of problems
yeah clash class action laws and so on
and so forth cost them a lot of money in
the end though
did it tarnish their brand i think it
did for a couple years
i think they actually came out pretty
good let's contrast that that's a really
good point think about this you guys
remember it was two years later jp
morgan
when they were compromised now here you
are different sector we're talking
financial sector
and they were they suffered a terrible
data breach
the difference is in my opinion
they came clean right away because they
said we were breached we were
compromised here's what happened here's
how it happened here's what we're going
to do about it oh by the way we're going
to commend
500 million dollars to upgrade our
security
here's probably the most the strongest
bank from a security posture out there
and they said where breeds were
compromised here's what's happened we're
going to go out and spend over the next
couple of years
500 million dollars of security
was there brand tarnish i didn't think
that much
despite the rumors and stories breach
and compromise all that other stuff they
came out pretty good
so it does have different effects for
different companies and i think that's
important to realize and get a better
sense now since we're talking about
credit cards debit cards we're talking
about skimmers different ways to
compromise
what do you think is another method that
you can use as a consumer or business
owner
that you can still use your credit card
but safer
what do you use
what should you use keep a separate card
with a low balance you could it's a
hybrid you could do that keep a separate
car it's a good point some people do
that
limited amount you could also contact
your bank and say hey if a transaction
is ever above this i want to get a text
and i want to improve there's a lot of
things that kind of do
not as convenient but they work
what about this what does everybody have
on themselves right now
smartphone
digital payments
who here uses
google wallet or apple pay
wow okay so it looks like two or three
people out of this whole room and myself
included
why are we not using
that i talked to someone the other day
about it and said oh it's not secure
i said it isn't is that your credit
card's more secure yeah much more secure
i said oh that's surprising please
one of the problems out here in flyover
country is
out of all of the shops i go to
maybe 15 20 of them support
yeah yeah and that's it you hit nail on
the head that's part of the part of the
problem right there please go ahead well
and what's funny is
you will walk up to people and they do
not realize that they support it right
they don't do a good job of telling the
people that work there that their
machines their terminals actually
support it so there have been times
where i've used it and they didn't even
know it was supported yeah and that's a
brilliant point there lack of education
and understanding makes a really good
point there so educating people it
hasn't happened yet hasn't taken on
widespread adoption there's also a lot
of misnomers about it i hear all the
time and i say oh i use apple pay and
they say well you're not very smart and
said what do you mean well apple pay was
compromised
i said well not exactly
what was when it first was launched
people started adopting and using it
what happened was
the
cyber criminals caught on quickly and
they said oh okay so and basically i
don't know if you guys notice your mouse
do a high level deep dive how does apple
pay or google pay work
it simply is a digital transaction so
it's sending a one-time encrypted
tokenized
message let's say it's not sending your
credit card information
nothing associated to you so it's used
one time it's token it's encrypted
to simplify it's secure
so anywhere in the ecosystem it can't be
compromised no cyber fee to steal your
credit card does that make sense
so now
ask yourself where's the weak point of
that
issuing bank so cyber criminals said ah
i got an idea let's call the bank up and
i'll pretend i'm mr scott shower
and now i can simply say oh yeah i'm
signing up a
a credit card which happens to be stolen
credit card over here to my new iphone
that i just got oh okay mr sugar where
do you live and uh what's your social
security number great you're all set
you're
done
he said hey so they started doing that
easily so where was the weak point
over here the bank
that's the problem so now they have a
laundry list of more secure questions
and carefully before they just quickly
sign somebody up and but the headlines
said oh no
pays breach it's not secure so now the
stigma in the industry is insecure don't
use it you see the problem
please
is there a cross-platform
mobile payment system
that isn't run by an advertising company
is there a cross
platform so i can use it on my wife's
iphone and my android
no
no unfortunately so the only one that's
doing there's probably a bigger reason
yeah again not to get into tech but the
way it's handled in the world of android
versus apple let's just say different
ecosystems you've got end-to-end
encryption over there and android which
is secure this and that apple into an
encryption on a software level but they
also have a secure enclave which is
hardware that adds a layer of hardware
encryption in there too so it's kind of
like apples to oranges and it's not real
they don't play together real well so it
makes it difficult
for the world of security and credit
card processing and things like that
just to make but when you think about a
credit card you process it there's a lot
of stuff that goes on behind the scenes
when you dig into it the fact that it
works to me is amazing enough
but the fact that it's so complex some
of the things helps you see how cyber
criminals can take advantage of that
right
so again when we get back to this
concept of skimmers just to reflect upon
that a moment again
um
if you think about it
eventually we can get that mag stripe
off of our credit cards and we could
really use chip and pin or like the
payment methods near field communication
we bring our digital wallets
toward the terminal do the near field
communication short distance different
frequency that's secure encrypted
we can do some amazing things and still
be secure and have convenience at a cost
so it's kind of balancing all of that in
i see it coming in the future it's
exciting i don't think it's there yet
a lot of people talk to me often i feel
a lot of space also with cryptocurrency
and that's the answer
[Music]
i'm not a firm believer in that yet that
it's going to be coming that quick only
because the sheer amount of stuff
associated
to cryptocurrency
and cyber criminal gangs and
the problems associated to it
kind of a different subject a different
problem there for sure
[Music]
just to show a couple more pictures and
some of the stuff that i've been
involved with looking at different types
of skimmers here and
i i always thought it was interesting
when it went for training and really
understanding and then got to to kind of
cross train and teach others
if you look to that far picture there
inside of a gas pump do you start to
understand why it's difficult
to find a skimmer
it's a rat's nest in a lot of these
guest packs not all but some of them are
almost
impossible to be able to pinpoint it out
in fact when i was in florida after a
long hot day working with the task force
and law enforcement we're going through
a machine they're quickly going through
them and i'm looking with interest
because i kind of knew what i was
looking for and toward the very end it
was almost the last machine we were
inspecting
i said guys stop a second i said you
missed something over here
there's a skimmer in that machine like
no no they went through it no i don't
see how it happens three or four more
guys came over and looked
i said there's a skimmer in there sure
enough moved some stuff
secretly hidden i just quartered all the
corners it's that hard to look at so
here you've got people who are doing
this every day
going through know where to look at
paddle blow and i found kind of a hybrid
solution skimmer there
just somebody that was going on training
for the first day so it's that hard to
identify
so you really get the sense of how bad a
problem is now oftentimes
if we talk about atms slightly different
i should just bring up this point as
well just so you can kind of reflect
upon it we talked about how easy it is
to get into a gas pump
right obvious reasons key
atm is it easy to open up your local atm
here in iowa no
not as easy
so a little bit different techniques are
used now i should say this now i've got
a whole bunch of atms when i was doing
research on this and took them apart to
understand and learn it the part that's
kind of fascinating with an atm machine
is the safe that holds the money
the safe in there and this is pretty
true all
atm machines it takes you about three
hours just to drill
a small quarter inch hole with a good
carbide bit three hours
that's a good hammer for trying to get
in there so you start dancing
what did cyber criminals do they come up
with the ultimate thing to get into the
safe no
but what's on top of an atm most atm
machines you have the paper dispenser
where the checks go in to the drawers
and everything else what tends to be the
weak point in an atm machine they always
run out of the paper for the receipts
and the top of the machine you can open
up
i thought it was funny when i bought all
these different atm machines i didn't
want to mix the keys up but i had a
couple of the same brands
and i tried a key on one and worked on
another i said how could this be
this is like the world of gas pumps
again they have some generic keys for
atm machines
for the top of it now again it doesn't
give you access to the safe
but i didn't need access to the safe if
i was cyber criminal i just needed to
know where i could place my bluetooth
skimmer oh there's there's a connector
right there it's labeled in the power
and everywhere
you start to see the problem
so
it's much easier than i ever thought to
get inside a typical atm machine and
place a bluetooth skimmer a little bit
different in that
sometimes
if you're at a bank it's bolted into the
wall there's cameras there's lights
those are harder to get into they're
going to typically use a different type
of skimmer where you go deep skin or
maybe down the neck where your card goes
in or super flat some of the pictures
they showed
or they're going to take a bezel and put
it over the other bezel that type of
skimmer there not a bluetooth skimmer
but if they can open that top up just
about every time they put a bluetooth
skimmer in there because they never have
to come back again and it works well so
if you're using atms the ones you want
to be cautious about say you're in a
convention center like this and there's
a small little kiosk atm machine in the
corner and it's got maybe a generic key
or an access door or means they can get
in there i tell you what my
my battery-powered sawzall works well
too
just go in the top pocket hole
take it out put the bluetooth skimmer in
and then i take a big giant sticker and
right you know this machine is secure or
something on the side whatever to cover
the hole i mean so you see how easy it
is to get into these things and actually
place the hardware in there so we want
to be very mindful again as consumers
we're not going to be able to identify
those things unless we do a full
inspection we're not doing that we're
trying to get quick twenty dollars to
buy pizza
so use caution for any type of kiosk
skimmers if you're in the city
gotta be careful
funny story we're developing our tool
for uh testing skimmers and atms we
started we had a crew we gave them out
to each employee we would go around to
different
uh etm's and test it to see if there
were skimmers
well about three weeks after we did all
of our testing we improved the product
so and so forth i get law enforcement
shows up on our building
and they say are you the owners yeah can
we talk to you okay
they take me aside and they've got a
guy's like holding his gun here the
other guy's here and the other guy's got
handcuffs
i said is there a problem they're like
well we got this license plate we got
these photos and they had a whole file
from three weeks
from all the banks that
recorded us testing we weren't too smart
we didn't call ahead i guess again
permission to test we thought well we'll
just go in test real quick to see if the
skimmer move on all that's being
recorded so it was kind of funny when
they sat down with all the evidence and
said what are you doing
i said oh we're testing our product here
to see if we're looking for skimmers
that's pretty cool let me try it
at fortune we didn't get arrested or
anything else but it does tell you that
atms have good security they have
cameras and they work closely with law
enforcement do do a good job but it is
hard it's very hard to catch these bad
guys because they know
which machines to target and that's part
of the problem eventually they could get
caught up please go ahead so in terms of
you know the process side and not just
the technology side what are banks doing
at this point to say like we are
responsible for going to our atms every
day and having an employee wiggle it a
little bit just to see what happens or
because
there's other things they could do in
terms of either monitoring or checking
things
that question you would assume they
would do the best job they can test the
machines every day so on and so forth
i can't i can't say that isn't the case
i can say for some banks i can't name
them but some banks that we have our
customers they will traditionally buy 20
or 30 of our tools and then they'll have
us actually train the employees and
actually every morning and as the bank
closes they actually test each atm
to make sure there is no skimmers that
were placed at any time or through the
night
and that's that's very common and a lot
of us are trained we actually built even
because it was so difficult to support
and train different groups between law
enforcement national weights and
measures banks um we built a box that's
got a skimmer built in so we built a
skimmer into one side
of a point-of-sale terminal and one
that's green and one that's red
basically so we hit it and we trained
and we built an actual training box to
teach people how to identify so they
know what to visually look for but also
they know how to actually test it with a
simple little tool yeah
it's a good point though i wish more
people would do that if all the banks
did what they probably should do i
probably wouldn't be standing here and
be on a beach somewhere retired right
now but not enough money is spent there
for security unfortunately and part of
the reason they say well
it's covered liability will cover
consumers will cover it
you know make those fees because that's
what the atms do they're really a fee
generated type of thing the other
problem is i've learned
many of the atms are now outsourced to a
third party that actually maintains them
loads the money
provides the security and they may have
it by us we have one customer and
they've got about a thousand atms in new
jersey new york
and they say oh the banks are so cheap
they won't spend a dime
for us to just check for skimmers that
maybe they pay us
50 cents to a dollar a day i don't think
that's all they would spend to get
something that could potentially take
thousands of dollars of consumers money
out that's concerning but it helps again
it is reality you have to look at
reality but it's a great question
unfortunately
oh i can tell you a quick oh please guys
um so you've been talking about the
banks and their atms um
has have you had any interest from
shell citgo the the big gas companies
um
at least for their stations and
having the ability to test those
yeah absolutely in fact in fact we have
um i can't mention who it is but we've
had some that have
thousands of stations
uh approach us and more more of the
it's ironic the companies that are tied
with convenience store
and and gas pumps why i kind of learn
if somebody goes to the gas pump and
they realize and trace it back that's
where my card was compromised
they don't go there to shop at the
convenience store so it's a money issue
again you follow money for all this you
can find the answer unfortunately so
they spend the money the larger brands
you guys all know we all use them that
have that combination gas pumps
convenience store
they will spend more money and buy tools
and training and inspect and rid the
skimmers quicker
but remember again the goal is in other
stations i've kind of come across too
here's the irony of it one station
we talked to
and
he was looking at skimmers all the time
what do you do with them what do you
know what i do with them i throw them in
a box and back back and you've got 100
of them in a box
so how could you do that that's you
can't do that you gotta report it i'm
not gonna report that law enforcement
will come in here and shut me down i
can't make money
do they care whose money they're taking
it really doesn't matter that's part of
the problem there's no incentive for a
gas station owner an independent
franchise to report this
and then unfortunately when it is
reported to law enforcement it costs
money and time they're chasing after
cyber criminals often organized it could
be a russian cyber criminal gang they
send over 100 people to place skimmers
with maps and everything else is very
well organized
so do you want to spend money on that or
do you want to have law enforcement stop
bad guys that are killing people right
it's tough there's only so much
resources and money and time so it can
be very frustrating let me tell you a
funny story
um this is a true story what's going on
in one particular state especially but
it's other states as well again highly
organized cyber criminal gangs
talk about gas pumps and skimmers
the criminal comes up places skimmer
bluetooth skimmer inside the gas pump
starts collecting
you know from his car within 75 foot
proximity stolen cars goes back burns
some fresh cards as they call you you
can buy these i buy them a couple
hundred at a time on the internet not
that much money and they basically have
a mag stripe and you can simply take
that your stolen credit card burned onto
this fresh blank credit card you're in
business he takes that fresh credit card
of one of our stolen credit cards
because we went to that gas pump goes
back to that same gas station
this time he goes back with a large
pickup truck with a 600 gallon bladder
on the back of the pickup truck
what does he do takes your my stolen
credit card buys 600 gallons of stone
usually it's diesel but it could be
gasoline depends on the case
fills it up
it doesn't end there now he takes that
stolen gas
you know that it took him from our
credit card goes around the corner he
meets the tanker truck
and pumps that 600 gallons of gas back
into the tanker truck that then goes to
that gas station and sells it back to
that gas station
you see what's happening
now you start to think about gas at
three four bucks a gallon
600 gallons they're doing this day in
day out day in and day out
problem
so when you when i talk to you in the
beginning about 6 trillion in cyber
security uh breaches and damages and
then in that there's billions upon
billions just because of skimmers that
seem kind of far-fetched
but when you see what's happening in the
bigger picture
billions and billions of dollars that's
only what's reported
so we start to see how big of a problem
this really is that is concerning to me
and more needs to certainly be done
unfortunately not enough is done there
i'll share one other thing that i
learned in some of my research and
talking with different individuals a lot
of times we focus our attention so much
in a particular area we miss the obvious
what am i talking about look at that
middle picture right at the arrow
they're pointing
so you're going to a bank did you ever
go into those your bank is bank xyz
atm's well-lit security cameras and you
say this is secure i go to this one all
the time
and now to get in after hours oftentimes
there's a glass vestibule to get in
where do you stick your
debit card in to get in right outside
the door there's a little slot when you
stick your card in here and it's a solid
line that opens the door and locks it so
they know okay it's a legitimate
customer open the door you go in
where do you think they put the scanner
right there at the door
why it's more convenient they don't have
to get in there and get into the atm
machine now guess what they just stole
your debit card information before you
even stepped foot in the back isn't that
smart
scary but nobody knows this
nobody i've ever talked to realizes this
yet it happens every single day
please do you think that there is some
sort of perverse incentive i guess you
could say from the bank's perspective
not to educate customers
because i think there could be some
really easy morning signals like watch
out for skimmers or essentially people
stick around an atm that goes hey
be aware that they're not doing it
because the consumer would receive the
responsibility
of skippers to be the bank to protect
them and they don't want to run into
that
i think it's a great point
i'll play devil's advocate i'll say for
the gas pump industry they tried that
what they did was they actually had
national weights and measures and they
still do this they go and inspect each
pump eventually every pump gets
inspected i think of course about two
years throughout the united states they
open them up they inspect make sure
there's no skimmers and other things too
and they put a security seal on their
sticker that said this pump is inspected
and secured in a date
and to a consumer they were told if you
see that seal it's safe to use
so now i'm a cyber criminal and what do
i do on the dark web or on ebay i sell
rolls of stickers that say this pump was
inspected and secured so i placed my
skimmer in and i placed it up there and
now suddenly i'm in business now i'm
having people drawn to this machine
because it looks like it's secure for
this cheap five cent
that that's part of the problem
unfortunately it's a good point i
brought that up myself years ago while
researching this and it bothered me to
no end there's got to be something okay
now here's something here's a silver
lining some of it some of the stations
are starting to upgrade that's good it's
coming really slow taking a long time
but it is starting to happen just like
point-of-sale terminals
for our chip and signature are happening
so it's better security but it's not 100
secure and again nothing is
but if you go to costco i don't know if
you guys have costco here in iowa
costco actually is one of the few
companies and they do sell a lot of gas
and they sell it at a good rate they get
the standard gas pumps in and they spend
a lot of money
ripping off all the locks and putting
them in their load box
so therefore the chance of finding a
skipper in a costco pump is
minimal unless it's an inside job or
something else for what that's where
nobody ever talks about that but to me
if i'm a consumer that's good
information to know especially if i have
a hospital card and i think they're
doing it right
so again sometimes spending the money in
the right areas makes sense
so that they should certainly be
applauded for that i think um
just kind of in closing i briefly want
to just touch the surface of this again
i might be presenting later and i can
delve in deeper here
i just wanted to mention
when credit cards and debit cards are
stolen just because you steal it doesn't
mean you have an audience to sell that
to or a customer base how do you sell
the stuff
well that's the part that's the easy
part for the cyber career most they're
using what's called the dark web if you
guys have you guys i'm assuming that's a
cyber security audience you know what
the dark web is if i just show of hands
you've heard of it you're somewhat
familiar okay
most everybody is here
so
just in general the internet the surface
web where we all work doing google
searches and visiting different websites
through our browser and such as about
4.5 billion websites that are indexed by
different search engines so the
service web represents roughly two
tenths of a percent
of the internet right
so that tells you what is below the
surface web is so much bigger and so
much wider and this little iceberg is
the very common thing that's kind of
been associated with the dark web that
many people will often uh get used to
which depicts it i think goes so well
the google wikipedia and stuff up at the
surface and all the stuff in the deep
and the dark web below there and again
those are really just to say it's simply
it's unindexed underneath there so it's
hard to find these unique sites and
they're repositories it's not all bad
stuff
everybody associates although the dark
web is bad and not necessarily it could
be repositories of databases and patient
information and all kinds of stuff out
there
but it's not indexed the same way as the
surface
so therefore to go into the dark web you
have to know the specific address to get
in there and the means to get in there
and typically use what's called a tour
browser
and the tour network designed by the
united states naval research group i
believe a number of years ago so it
could help people communicate
anonymously and securely dissidents
reporters anyone else can use that cyber
criminals also can too because it's free
and and it's very wonderful because it
allows you to do things anonymously
it'll bounce around
traffic around the globe so nobody can
pinpoint exactly where you are
which is important the data is encrypted
so again it protects the user there um
which again is important if you're doing
legal things now if you're doing illegal
things it's a protection too
unfortunately that's part of the
challenge so on the dark web a lot of
these bad guys learn wow i can hide
information here i could work with other
cyber criminals i can buy and sell guns
kids drugs stolen credit cards so so
forth
that's a huge problem it's
very successful and law enforcement's
been working hard and done a great job
and slowly
taking down these sites you probably
heard of silk road and silk road 2 and
so on and so forth
pretty fascinating i've done a couple of
these
projects working with different media
groups and in this particular case it
was actually cbs what we did was i went
on the dark web did research for a
period of time collected masses of
stolen credit card information
uh identities social security numbers
breach information
and then i work with law enforcement and
then and then they actually went out and
contacted the individuals literally
kind of knocked on their doors excuse me
do you know your credit cards on the
dark web
what are you talking about and then help
them remediate it was a bigger project
kind of stink project but it's kind of
cool because i got to actually collect
all that information so that that was
really neat to be able to actually see
it unfortunately most of the people that
were contacting had no clue their
information was out there had no idea
how it got out there most likely it was
a skimmer that took it or they were
buying something online they were going
on sites that they probably shouldn't
have their information was compromised
and out there but it's interesting when
you get behind the scenes and understand
how fragile the whole system is
yet every single one of us here has a
credit card
or debit card in our wallet or purse and
uses it properly on a weekly basis
that's scary so just before you quickly
shut that card just stop and think
that's what i encourage people to do
because it's very easy to be compromised
myself personally when i was targeting
hacked my company a few years ago i
think it was 11 times my card was
compromised
personally the company's close to that
and then i had debit cards also for each
so i've been through the process
it's painful
suffered the whole ddos attack twitter
account takeover
sixty five thousand dollars stolen from
my checking account i was targeted
and any of us could be targeted again
i'm a cyber security expert
what does it tell you
nothing's 100 i'm sorry nothing is any
one of us can easily be targeted to be
compromised
it's fairly easy to do so i just
encourage you don't don't give up
implementing best security practices
is something that really does make a
difference because what's it going to do
it's going to deter the cyber criminals
move on to the next target
that's what's important
that's really what's important
there is out right after this after we
conclude i'm happy to answer anybody's
questions if you have any more i'm gonna
do a little book signing and get a free
copy of my book cyber security's
everybody's business
uh out and i think the main lobby that
they're gonna do that there so i welcome
you stop by a signed copy and happy to
hear any of your horror stories in the
world of cyber or answer any questions
um and two other books the first book
that that's been out a little bit longer
happening and that's my story of being
hacked as a company and personally what
i went through the things i learned in
the process
and then more recently i released
another book senior cyber and that's
really dealing with age parents and
grandparents trying to educate them i
was so frustrated that i could not find
any good information that talked at
their level it all talked down to them
and talked in tech jargon
and just got people more confused i said
that's it i'm going to write a book
that's big font so everybody could read
it without their glasses
and share tips throughout and explain
things without getting techy on it so
hence the the launch of of senior side
with their fun project especially
interviewing older people and
understanding their frustrations with
technology and security there so
anyway feel free to visit my website
there just simply my name's
scottshover.com if you're interested in
a book please come out there get a
complimentary copy thanks to uh
this event for putting this on and
getting some flying books for everybody
and uh appreciate that the time and
listening thank you again
[Applause]