[Music]
good morning everyone thank you so much
for attending corncon 7. we're so
excited to have everyone here and happy
to be back out in the real world again
instead of doing a virtual call line
last year
uh thank you again so much for attending
we really really appreciate the team
here
they'll be your track to dj for most of
that and uh first up we have tim schultz
uh from site he's going to give a great
talk on
purple team attorney model
again
thank you very much
thank you so much for that introduction
so this is the first talk i've given in
person in two years
so uh that's what funny enough the last
time i gave a talk in person was at the
sands purple team summit where i met my
now boss was not at the time george
ortiz
so it was kind of fun to uh mark that
two-year with another purple team talk
this one a little bit more progress
so this is my first time in the quad
cities i've had a lot of fun it's uh
it's been a great time we talked i got
to meet a bunch of the other speakers
and attendees last night
through a series of
moving between restaurants and different
rooms depending on what clothes at a
time so that was uh reminds me of
growing up in mississippi
so who am i first of all my name is tim
schultz i am the adversary emulation
lead here at uh site so prior to site
i've been here since about february now
and
i was at uh before i was at mitre who
most of you have probably heard of
especially with attack who worked on the
attack evals team with the attack team
and then
also one that you may not have heard of
is sandia national ladders and so
between the two of those spent about six
years doing habitat emulation although
it wasn't quite called that purple
teaming and so it's sort of uh
culminated into everything that i'm
going to go over today
so a quick road map of what we're going
to do here we're going to talk about why
does purple need a maturity model and so
if you're not familiar with purple tv
don't worry i'm going to go over what
purple teaming is what it looks like and
run you through sort of a quick purple
team exercise so you'll get an idea of
what i'm talking about and then from
there we're going to go into what is the
purple team maturity model and then how
to actually apply it and that's
something that's always fun with models
as well this is good in the lab but how
do we apply this in the real world
so the first step we're going to dive
into is why does purple need a maturity
model and what does purple team do so
the infosec teams of today that walk
through a little bit of history is that
everyone's
started with either a blue team or red
team most companies have blue teams
these days or whether it's outsourced or
they have a
service provider or they have their own
internal team
red teams are something that have
existed for a long time sort of military
background as far as the term but we see
more and more companies today are trying
to integrate red team and really what it
comes down to is security testing
into
their uh into their day-to-day workflow
and now a newer player to the game is
cyber threat intelligence so this is
something that the question always comes
why purple teaming why now and part of
that is the explosion of cyber threat
intelligence we remember back when the
apt-1 report came out it was it was a
huge set shockwave throughout the entire
community internationally as well
because it gave attribution it talked
about all these activities that people
knew about behind the scenes but no one
was willing to talk about and so from
there we had more and more private
companies private and industry
have released reports we had the release
of attack that sort of put those all in
a library that everyone could go look
through and analyze i'll talk more about
attack later but that's sort of where
the explosion of adding contents to the
previous red and blue team attacks uh
and so that's where blue teams before
were just having to fend off whatever
was at their firewall they didn't
necessarily have strategic plan because
they didn't have the data necessary and
same with red teams it was and still is
at times up to the creativity of the red
team which sometimes can supersede what
adversaries are doing that becomes
problematic when you are trying to
actually give metrics to your leadership
teams and drive change in organizations
so as far as what purple tv is it's the
culmination of all those together and so
your first purple team experience would
be essentially bringing those three
teams together now i say teams if you're
a small company this might be just you
this might be you with three hats on or
people that only have
one or two infosec professionals they're
going to be able to do this by
themselves as well and so
what we do at scythe is we have the
purple team uh exercise framework that's
sort of our our introduction to purple
teaming for people that don't that have
never done this before and so this is
where you're going to walk through a six
step process and i've got a nicer on the
next slide here that's got a couple of
different predefined holes that's part
of this purple team exercise framework
that is that first time you're walking
through something
and so your exercise coordinator is
going to introduce what the test is so
the entire test is transparent that's
something that's very different from red
teams as well is that you have a
transparent task if i'm the exercise
coordinator i'm going to tell you
exactly what commands i'm going to run
and we're going to walk through a couple
different steps the first one is a
tabletop exercise
that tabletop exercise is going to be
the first data point it's
what is the expectation when this uh
when this command is run
what is going to
oh yes
yes uh so we do have table top exercises
and by we mean uh
corncon and scythe and bryson my ceo was
actually running i think the ics one
this afternoon so go sign up tabletops
are great because you don't have to be a
super league hacker in order to
participate and to understand
what's going to happen so that's
something that this is why tabletops are
important and a part of this
this chain of steps so that expectation
asking what do you expect is it the edr
is it going to fire do you have another
defensive tool or vendor that you're
assuming is going to pop up an alert
whether it's an email or something like
that it's your first data point
second uh the next step is going to be
actually running the tests and so then
you have the ability to compare what was
the expectation what was the actual test
result and you have those that you can
work with leadership to address whether
or not uh if specific tools are working
or not and this is something that you
repeat over and over and over again so i
do have a couple other steps in there as
far as the blue team process and i want
to highlight that separately so part of
purple teaming is addressing not just
the technologies but also the people in
the process when we're going through a
purple team exercise
we are at well in the past year and a
half we've mostly been doing it
virtually and so what this means is that
you are screen sharing and often times
the challenge with zoom in some of those
is interactivity which is really
important part of purple team and so
what i'll do is i will execute the test
after we've recorded the tabletop and
say all right who is your analyst that
would first pre-options and so working
from like a three-tier stock model we
would work with the level one analyst
and say share your screen show us the
dashboards that you're going to look at
what is this going to populate and so
for one exercise we they have a firewall
block and they said this is this url is
not categorized and an apple register as
that would be an alert and so at that
point i would take it i'd go do some
just a little bit more in depth checking
and make sure it's not false positive
pass it up and so that's where it would
escalate to our level two and so they
stop sharing their screen level two
person gets on and shares their screen
and so you can see how we can evaluate
the entire process and especially you
can identify gaps if there are gaps in
not just your technology coverage
also as people are trying to respond to
ransomware for instance i do a lot of
ransomware emulations and so time is of
the essence there you need everyone to
have a concrete process that they are
going to follow to the letter
potentially when you're in crisis mode
so
that is what purple team means in a
purple team exercise uh framework is
you're going through that over and over
and over again it's very deliberate
testing it can be slow and a little bit
different than your typical red team
test which is why it can be uh
some folks might not uh like it as much
but the value you get from it is really
what is important i mentioned those
there's a couple of those key data
points in addition to
being able at the end to
evaluate the people process and
technology you also have that feedback
loop of i can rerun the test for
instance i'm not trying to uh not show
my cards here and that's something that
a lot of times when you are doing
security testing if you're doing pen
testing or red teaming you may not want
to reveal
what your tests are doing however since
we are being fully transparent about
this if you do have uh detection
engineers for people that can write new
logic to try and detect that test you
can do it in real time and so that's
where the value for the business really
comes in and this is from uh some of the
purple team exercises that we've done on
a recurring basis we've seen enabled
we've been able to get people from
essentially zero percent detections to
60 in just a couple weeks
so the challenges as i've mentioned a
little bit you've probably picked up on
some themes here is that
purple teaming at this point we talk
about it and it can be a singular
exercise people do it once and are like
great that's awesome
we're done
and maybe they do it even quarterly but
the the real issue between this is that
teams are silent or communities are
silent and so we see this across red
teams blue teams and cyber threat
intelligence we all have our own
conferences to go to and and the
expertise that we're trying to build
within our own garment environment and
so the challenge is that you're not
necessarily going to do that
cross-pollination except every quarter
or once a year and so even though the
the business metrics and the value that
you see are are very clear and so
all of that comes down to communication
and teams
especially if they're separate if
they're in separate
directorates even they don't have to
communicate it's optional and so that's
where talking about
why we would move towards purple teaming
as an actual team it's because we want
to take all the business value and the
justification that we've seen and
keep it together forever
and so that's what i'm pitching here
with the purple team maturity model is
the first step is you are going to have
a purple team that is not going to be
just an exercise is going to be moving
past that and taking a team of people
and i would even say potentially in the
future this is going to be the majority
of teams because you're going to need
people that have
a mixed series of expertise to truly
defend against the current threats
so that's where talking about the shift
in blue teams have their own business
case right teams have their own business
case and that's where i don't want to
necessarily say that if you're a large
enough organization you're not going to
have the resources the people or the
need to do all those things
but
together when you are trying to defend
an organization as a whole the purple
team is going to be and having that very
deliberate testing and making sure that
you're
able to figure out where in your
defenses how gaps where in your process
you have gaps that is going to become a
mindset you need to have every day
and so that's why we need a maturity
model is to evaluate how do we how do we
move from that concept of just having a
team into
measuring it because that's what that's
part of what has gotten purple teaming
to where it is now is the ability to
measure results
and so that's why the purple team
maturity model as you'll see we're
working on building out a measurable way
to look at teams and evaluate how teams
are in that process
so i've gone over a little bit of this
this is where we're at currently is that
we have these three separate teams
they're working together sometimes or
when they're forced to at the end of a
report for instance if you're doing a
red team engagement and so we need to
move to all those three into a specific
purple team
and so the way we are moving past just
purple as a team into specific areas of
expertise because that's always
something we need to figure out what
we're measuring
is these two that i've i've broken down
into threat understanding and to
detection understanding
now if you're a red teamer or a blue
teamer or a little bit of both you can
probably see a little bit of yourself
or the expertise in one of these
now
if you're cyber threat intelligence you
might have a little bit more difficulty
picking one specifically now the reason
i chose the word understanding for these
is because the context as i talked about
that cyber threat intelligence provides
earlier is critical when you are trying
to determine what you're going to test
because you want to make sure that the
adversaries that you're targeting
if you are doing adversary emulation are
going to be adversaries that are going
to target your organization because if
you're picking just random adversaries
that could be good but everyone has
limited budget everyone has limited time
constraints and so we want to make sure
that everything that's chosen has a
reason
and so the same with detection
understanding
so we tend to write detections and maps
or for the latest vulnerability and
throw everything together i think of
david bianco's pyramid of adversary pain
here and
the very bottom of that is
indicators of compromise because they're
super easy for blue teams and everyone
to integrate because you have tools that
can just you can feed it in it'll scan
the network for those and any time it
pops up on an end point you'll squash it
but the challenge is those are super
easy to change from the attacker's
standpoint it's really easy especially
with all the automation that we're
seeing and the
shift in business case for ransomware
developing new capabilities at a
pretty rapid pace
you we have to move beyond that and so
that's where detection understanding is
so important is you need to understand
what detections are in your environment
and and what depth do they work because
that's something that we've seen a lot
of teams once you write a detection you
just assume it works all the time even
if you push out new detections if you
push out uh any configuration chains who
goes and verifies that all the old stuff
still works and so there are a few
projects in place that are looking at
how to do some of that i'll give a shout
out to splunk and their attack range
project because they've tackled a little
bit of that
but that's sort of the key a key
challenge with this is as automation and
our infrastructure is scaled we have not
necessarily scaled our testing methods
and so that's really a key thing with
the understanding behind each of these
is making sure that your teams are aware
of what's going to
actually take place in their environment
and choose to be very deliberate with
their time and their resources
so as far as detection understanding
goes let's dive into each of these a
little bit more
these are some of the questions that
your folks that are working on this
we're going to ask what are the log and
telemetry sources we have everything
starts with data where are we getting
our data what can we do with it can we
analyze it and then what is our process
i mentioned before this is going to be
that people process and technology
and so all these things are going to
inform your threat understanding
what are the adversaries that are
targeting our organization or
are vertical and so trying to understand
that bringing it all together is going
to be key
to
having that back and forth between your
threat understanding and your detection
understanding because
it all starts with data and if you have
good data you have a good understanding
of who's targeting your industry you can
go collect samples you can go do
analysis but if you don't have any of
that you're not going to be able to
even start through this process
so as far as actually building out the
model i mentioned we have these two
different things now we have three
different levels and so the first one
that i outline is deployment so this is
where everyone starts this is where you
get that fancy new shiny tool regardless
of what it is and you put it in your
environment and it's great you use it
it's fantastic it gives you either
visibility or or puts a couple of things
uh into a single dashboard for instance
but the challenge with that is uh and if
you've ever seen an analyst screen that
has splunk you have like 40 tabs open
and at all times and so it's well we
have 10 different dashboards and we have
these different things and and that's
that's just life
which is fine but that's where we need
to shift up to level two integration
this is where you're taking multiple
tools multiple processes and putting
them together in order to achieve
something that alone they could not and
so that's what's so important about
integration is you have to be able to
take all these tools as everything's
scaled you got to put them together
and then the last level is creation
this is the ability to create your own
novel detections your own novel tests
based on your own internal knowledge
and integrate them into your pipeline
and so this is the peak level because it
does require the most expertise it
requires the most familiarity with the
tool
but at this level you're able to adapt
with adversaries as they're coming out
with new techniques
and so i do have two examples that we're
going to walk through for these
specific for these specific detection
and threat understanding so hopefully
you're familiar at least with one of
these
so the first one i'm going to go over is
sigma so this is essentially
more standardized logging across vendors
that was something that florian roth is
the original creator of this project
from a couple years ago
and he releases a lot of free detection
so i highly recommend people check this
out if you haven't
and so
the first step would be
just deploying your sigma rules into the
sim again this is where you put it in
and
hopefully it works
the
after that though
after seeing whether or not you have any
detections that come as a result
triaging it hopefully tuning some
because that's something that's also
very challenging is that everyone's
environment is a little bit different
and so
after you've gotten all that initial
deployment done this is where you want
to start integrating with your other
tools if you have a sandboxing process
can you run these rules earlier in uh
before something hits your users this is
uh where you're gonna have to get
creative with your current technology
stack because you may have tools that
i'm not even mentioning up here and they
could be part of your pipeline and so
putting all these things together to
minimize the amount of people time that
need to go in and actually perform the
analysis the triage things like that
that's really going to allow your
organization to scale that much better
and then the last one is deploying
developing new sigma rules of course
this is going to be specific to your
organization potentially maybe you are
able to lock things down in a way that
no one else can and that's where you can
essentially have sigma rules that are
a bit over sensitive to
environments and and that's great
but that's where you need to be able to
make those adjustments and you need to
be able to figure out how do we develop
this how do we tune this to our needs so
that
it's not a tool that's going to actually
take more time to use
than it's providing value
so with that we'll shift over to atomic
red team for threat understanding
so atomic print team for those of you
that aren't familiar quick introduction
about it it is red canaries open source
testing suite and so it links to miter
attack which is great and basically
allows you to do singular tasks of a
specific technique at a time and so they
have it's got a pretty good
community contribution effort going to
it so we've contributed a few ourselves
and just want to highlight it's it's a
really cool project
and so after you've used it and run it a
few times it's a great way to do that
initial
running a single test to detect a single
detection and this is i mentioned before
splunk's attack range we use tonic red
team
to validate their
testing and so after you've deployed
that you've run a couple of tests you've
validated that things work this is where
again
putting it into your development uh
pipeline is going to be really important
because if you write a new test the new
detection you want to make sure it fires
almost immediately see if that logic
works because this if if not then it's
going to sit out there you'll have false
confidence or if it oh it runs too much
then you're going to flood your sock
with a bunch of additional tickets that
they don't want to deal with
so this is where it's really important
to tune those things as early in your
testing process as possible
and then the last step
is developing of course new atomic red
team techniques so this is something
that even if you feel that you don't
have maybe the expertise to do some of
this stuff and tell you you probably
have pretty unique data everyone is
getting hit with similar strains of
ransomware things like that but things
do shift slightly depending on
depending on where where your
organization sits in the landscape and
so
just diving into that a little bit
if you are able to collect new logs at
your firewall for instance and see if if
you're if you have a honeypot or
something like that sitting out you can
collect data on who's trying to attack
you even if it's mass attackers just
trying to scan the entire internet and
so that's kind of stuff can help inform
you because or you might want to figure
out who is that that's scanning because
say they did get it what are they going
to do next that's always the questions
that should help inform your testing and
maybe those next steps have been
profiled in
some
cti report that's been released but you
don't actually have in your testing
there you go you've identified a gap and
so that's that's where you can really
take the data that you have to build
these new techniques because oftentimes
uh it tends to be folks that are newer
to
influence how can i give back or how can
i contribute we have all these experts
doing things all the time
and that's why i say there's always
variations on things and so whether it's
a different flag those types of things
uh you'd be amazed red canary also
releases a threat detection like overall
report that i also encourage you to look
through but they showcase different
flags that adversaries use when they are
running powershell commands and they
shorthand things different ways so if
your detection for instance has
for powershell looks at for encoded
commands looks for a fully spelled out
encoded command
and somebody uses dash ec
instead is your detection some way to
catch that those are the types of things
that are going to allow you to further
build up
new tests for your environment
so all this comes down to communication
the teams need to work together you have
your threat understanding you have your
attention
but everybody still needs to be working
together because that is the point of an
accuracy perfect team and a formal
purple team is going to be bringing all
this together
so
i've got a little bit nicer one here and
so this is what it looks like so it's a
quad chart essentially uh with our
well nine block and this is essentially
allows us to chart our path through it
and that's going to be really important
when you are trying to develop a road
map because that is part of also what
we're talking about here is how we move
a team that has been focused into
deployment now they have a path forward
so what do we do about that how do we
get them to integration how do we get
them to creation and so besides just me
giving you philosophicals here um
i'm also going to walk you through how
we would use it and so i'd like to
introduce you to unicorn inc
we have alex is from the blue team
representing the sock we have brooke who
is representing the red team and then
casey is our cyber threat intelligence
professional and so they are going to be
going on a journey of becoming a purple
team
so their current roles at unicorn theme
is alex as i mentioned in the sock
builds new detections based on the
latest indicators of compromise the
casey senzo now this is good and this is
very common that we see that the cyber
threat intelligence folks and the
sock folks tend to work together
sometimes they're even co-located and
the cti folks are sitting in the side
so this is this is a really good start
to our communications
and we have brooke who is
surfs twitter uses the latest and
greatest bypasses and red team tools and
is able to get in every single time
and then
we have casey who reads every single
cyber threat intelligence report that
comes out
now the challenge with some of this is
everyone's doing their job
and so
the how do you how do you shift that
focus into
a singular
one team
and like sometimes you'll management
will do that for you you are now a team
congratulations your purple team
get along
and so
they don't know where are we
and so trying to chart this out and
figure out how do we shift the roles
into a common
language or common goal that everyone
can work together at is really what it
comes down to and so i've outlined here
alex who remember was our blue teamer
sock person that pulled into the purple
team
now runs new detections by brook our
former red teamer
to ensure that they work and to see if
they're easily bypassed this is where
you have that communication is key
because if it's something that gets
bypassed just instantly the question
becomes should we even deploy this maybe
i should go back and work on it some
more
also incorporates new uh detections for
for new malware that casey is looking up
and so that's going to be
again tying the cyber threat
intelligence reports already done some
of this so this is really just keeping
it a step up because it's identifying
the techniques so we moved up from
indicators of compromise up to behaviors
and then also researching integration
points because they're currently at
deployment how do we move beyond that
what are things that i use that i can
integrate with others in order to make
all of our lives easier
so brooke our former red teamer
now builds tests to validate detections
so this is going to be uh this is key in
that it's using your creative mindset to
make sure everything currently works
and then also making sure that they're
incorporating techniques from the cyber
threat intelligence professional that is
real malware that's real data that you
can tie to that's something that's
always i've had
challenges getting red teamers to do is
because you're scoping them
you're you're forcing them into a box so
to speak and that that's something uh
that can be a challenge because most of
the time red teams uh and especially if
they've been on a lot of uh a lot of
different engagements they essentially
have
they have no restraints and it's great
it's fun if you're on that team because
you get to use your creativity uh to the
max but that's where
focusing and channeling it into figuring
out how would an adversary adapt from
this how would they use how that team
take what they currently have and build
more capability is going to be how your
red team will really bring a ton of
value to this role they can still be
creative it's just going to be a little
bit more focused and then any time so
brooke is still on twitter and anytime
they find new techniques from uh from
twitter that they think are interesting
pass it on to alex who's the detection
engineer to figure out how to create new
detections for
so again
still doing very similar roles that they
did before
but they are now doing it as a team
and so casey is going to research
attackers that are targeting the unicorn
industry so remember before
casey was looking at every single vendor
report which a couple years ago might
not have been too bad but these days you
have enough reports coming out it's easy
to get overwhelmed and this becomes a
point where you also need to scope your
cyber threat intelligence to focus on
your industry first doesn't mean that
those other ones are not valuable but as
far as actual focusing
to a specific industry or specific
organization if you're large enough then
you should do that and so then as as
we've already covered essentially is
providing reports and techniques to
alex and brooke based on what specific
technologies malware is using as well as
new techniques and zero days that we
discovered
and so that's overall how we've shifted
all the roles it's not a massive shift
necessarily but it is a mindset shift
because it requires communicating with
colleagues more than before it requires
really being deliberate in deciding that
your cyber threat intelligence person is
going to have to go out and look for
specific unicorn uh malware or unicorn
threat actors
and so with the joint goals it does
allow you to chart where your way
through
uh through the purple maturity model and
so the other thing i want to highlight
here is that most teams that i've
encountered have actually started
they're really high on the detection
engineering side of things
and the threat understanding is where
they are struggling or trying to figure
out how do we do security testing and
how do we do
do
do testing against ransomware use
ransomware has been the driver for
almost everything now and so
trying to chart your team through this
this does allow you and this isn't going
to be necessarily a quick process so
despite me walking through it uh on in
the presentation or can organizational
change takes a long time uh that's
that's the real of it and it's going to
potentially take months or even years
but this allows you to help chart a road
map into
it's generic enough that allows you to
fit whatever you have in it but also
provides guidance in how to move to the
next step
so
with that we have covered all of our
three major
what is what is purple teaming and then
why does it need a maturity model uh
what the maturity model is and then how
we can use it
so any questions thanks for attending
coming to the morning talks
[Applause]
oh
all right
uh i would say some so
part of what i like about purple teaming
is that everyone gets to see what we're
doing in real time there's no hiding and
so
one test we ran uh there we figured we
found out and helped our customer find
out they had an 18-hour delay between
when logs were
taken on the endpoint versus showed up
in the site
and so we're doing a ransomware
emulation and
time is critical so that would you know
that's you get a phone call before you
see it in your sim which would have been
a problem
so yeah that was that was probably the
biggest thing that we've seen so far
uh so they
they they're a pretty large organization
and so they had a good team that's a
thing and luckily it was a multi-day
exercise so we like ran everything and
at first
well this is going to be rough there's
no detections at all
so we're starting from zero but then
everything started coming in their team
clearly had they had good process and
all and they had good people and
that was you know the nice thing is they
got the um
the sizzo
on on the phone or like hey this
happened and that became priority one
was get it done figure out what if it's
an architecture problem get on from the
vendor uh to figure out if there's
something that they can do to help us
with this but
i think driving that change so suddenly
is what was at least good
good question
anything else
i'll still be here afterwards so uh
thanks again for coming and uh
appreciate y'all's attendance this
morning
enjoy