[Music]
I would like to introduce our speaker
john curran he is president and CEO of
Aaron and today he will be giving an
Erin Internet routing registry in our
PKA update thank you very much Jeff I'm
John Curran president CEO of the
American registry for Internet numbers
Erin I'm here I'm going to talk about
what Erin is doing on its internet
routing registry project IRR and what
we're doing with our PKI as well let me
try to give you a quick update on what
we've been doing and how it affects you
with some pretty important changes so
Erin has been in the middle of doing a
major upgrade to our infrastructure we
did Erin online in 2019 and we started
our IR our new internet routing project
at about the same time we had done the
requirements document with the community
talking about whether you even wanted a
new Erin Internet routing registry and
the consensus was that you did so we did
a requirements document identify key
stakeholders and have been doing the
design we're now past design we're into
deployment and QA and our initial
deployment for our new internet routing
registry that's integrated with Erin
online will be June 10th so it's just
coming up next month initially there's
going to be two ways to create objects
in Erin's internet routing registry
using the existing email template
processor to create objects just as
people have been doing but we'll pick up
the new way of using Arin online a
web-based interface to create internet
routing objects now in the process of
updating Erin's IRR we had to do quite a
bit of work first the back end is was
quite a historic routing engine or a
routing registry engine we've updated to
a new platform we're using IRD 4 and
then we had to come up with processes
for migration of data and then how to
distinguish valid
data and to keep track of that within an
errand because we have a lot of data as
people know in the existing Arin IRR and
there was a call from the community to
be very careful and clearly distinguish
the data that was being created by
people we knew and people we could
validate versus data that was just being
carried over so we created an
architecture for that and we'll talk
more about how that gets published but
there's actually two data sets involved
here and then of course a front-end
interface to allow people to go and air
online and create new records for
internet routing registry objects so
what's going to happen is that all of
the existing objects and the NR and IRR
I get migrated into the new internet
routing engine internet routing registry
daemon all them get migrated and they
end up in two data sets one of them is
Erin which will be everything that's
validated is meeting our requirements so
we know who it is and if the resource is
associated with a normal organization
and it's it's got our own services
associated with it
that will end up being published in the
Arin data set and then for everything
else that's in the IRR those get moved
in to the new IRR and get published in
the Erin no off unvalidated object set
so a fairly simple approach you've seen
it before if you're familiar with other
routing registries and other are IRS and
we hope this makes it clear going
forward we expect to see more and more
valid objects in the Arin dataset and
over time the error and no offset will
become a Don auth will become less
important people will still be using the
old email processor and that includes
people who aren't known Daren or
validated people who had an email
address and managed to use Aaron's old
IRR service each day we will migrate
newly created objects for our paid
objects
into the new database if it lines up
with a valid user ID a valid org ID
that's associated with the addresses in
Aaron then as long as we validate the
organization and there are current Aaron
online user then it will end up in the
Aaron data set if we've never validated
the user we don't know anything more
than what you know their email address
we don't know the organization or why
they're representing an object it may
not be assigned to them we may not even
know what organizations involved it ends
up in the non auth data set no new
maintainer x' will be accepted into the
irr email system to create an object you
need a maintainer object and you folks
who have them are fine but we will be
winding down over time the irr email
interface and so no new maintenance will
be accepted if you want to create new
objects where after you validate use
that aren't online to do so the objects
what objects are we going to support
we're not going to support the full RP
SL we're gonna support a reasonable
subset so that's route route six
autonomous system number a SM route set
and those are reflect 99% of the usage
out there so that shouldn't be a problem
when you create an object in our online
you only can maintain it and update it
in our online there's no access to that
object you can't switch between that and
email templates in fact if you're using
the email templates continue to use them
but once you go in and begin creating
objects in our online we're going to
disable your email template so you only
use our online to create the objects and
the reason for that is because there's
some interesting migration issues we
don't want to get into a situation of
how to reconcile objects that are
updated in email objects that are
updated in our online so the email we're
happy to provide a way to get that data
into Aaron online so you can have that
and have that published but we're not
going to provide ongoing back and forth
it's
intended to be a street that's from one
way when you go into Aaron online and
you say I want to start creating four
objects with the iron online web
interface it will say we're going to
disable your maintainer ID so you will
not be maintaining things using the old
email template system okay
so pathetic ated iron objects you've
been paying them with the old email
templates when you want to have a Fenna
gated irr objects you can continue to
use the old templates and not use our
online or you can start using Aaron
online and then that's what all than
anyone knew coming into the IRA will use
and you'll end up using that and all the
objects created via the Aaron online web
interface or posts are authenticated
just the party logging in using our
online we know they are we know what
organization they're associated we're
publishing all the data on the
fabricated and authenticated ira objects
will be publishing via ftp and we'll be
publishing them by n TR M so for neilton
for near real-time monitoring NT RM
feeds we ran off or two streams one for
the validated irr one for the
unvalidated if you're relying on Aaron
IRR data today you're using that for
your own route waiting what route
filtering you need to start pulling both
streams you'll need to configure that
after June 10th the serial numbers get
reset on the NR TM streams so after June
10th you'll need to update your
processor and start pulling new streams
both Aaron and Aaron on off if you don't
do that you're not going to need a tour
unless you use the new serial number
obviously FTP will have to FTP archives
for that data you'll be able to pull
down both you'll if you're using FTP to
pull irr data you'll need to update to
pull both Aaron nan off and Aaron
sources
future IRR functionality so we've had
requests to have an API to manage IRR
records and we will do that where the
process of specking that out so that
people who want the new ir functionality
want to have some automation and but
don't want to end up using a male based
approach we'll have a tool that lets
them switch to using the new IRR and
still have some programmatic interface
working on API to that purpose we have a
team looking at other IR enhancements
and we're to continue to have them do
any other cleanup or any other
functionality that people want through
this year and potentially a little bit
beyond now as much as we love the
internet routing registry out there
there's a lot of big push to actually
have something that has even tighter
attributes in terms of useful
information and that is rpki and so I
want to spend a little bit of time our
work on IRR is not designed to displace
work on rpki
it's in fact intended to be
complementary but we're also doing quite
a bit of work Erin on rpki or in the
middle of a big rpki infrastructure
upgrade and to that end we have done
some changes already we are now doing
repository generation on a faster
schedule every five minutes so if you go
in and create new objects on our hosted
service you'll see our repository update
and a rapid time we've added our DP
request our piano repository Delta
protocol to allow more timely repository
retrieval than what our sync was
providing we've changed our row up the
validity period we had it set to many
many years we're now using a more
commonly used 825 days we're going to
we've updated our rpki delegated support
to have full support for our fe80 2883
uptime protocol and we spent a little
bit of time testing that out with
different implementations there's now
some very good implementations for
delegated RPI service you can run your
own CA and link into Erin
end up with your records validated that
way
but at the same time have full control
over what gets published and we've added
the capability to list and delete row is
via our restful registration services
they have an API for that right now
using our restful web interfaces let's
see what we're going to be doing in the
backend we have some changes coming
we're going to be moving to a new HSM
our prior HSM was getting long in the
tooth and so we're moving to a new HSM
and with a more streamlined interface
between the HSM and the Internet online
application we're gonna be removing some
limitations we've had notations on the
number of CRO certificate revocation
lists and those will get cleaned up in
this process makes some other
operational aspects like key signing
ceremonies simpler and that's coming
later this year and we'll also be adding
better tools to make it easier to use
rpki some notification enhancements and
UI improvements and then the last one
was we're going to tying these together
to some extent we're gonna make it
pretty easy to synchronize on our and
our PGI data so that people who want to
provide the information that people no
matter what they're using whether
they're using run validation with RPI or
whether or not they're taking
informations or IRR
will make it easier for our hosted
customers to be able to put their
information and keep them in sync
both IRR in our PKI with that it
finishes my formal presentation and I
guess I'll now turn it back to questions
hi John oh hey how are you thank you
thank you for the update and thank you
for being here happy the next one we
have some questions for you I'm just
going to read them as a game the gaming
okay the first question is will our
invalidate against rpki internally so
right now is a sort of a gave an idea
we're doing the new IRR and getting that
in place we're looking at how to do AI
are our PKI integration later this year
right now our definition of validation
is as I said in the slides as long as
the organization as long as the routing
object is associated with a Nolen
organization that has services from Arin
it'll be considered valid and in the off
data set or the Arin regular streams
we're not doing in the immediate
validation against rpki
so that is something in the future we
don't know if will validate or provide
that as another opportunity to
automatically feed IRR objects from we
need to talk to the community about that
so initially no long term we do want to
do an integration but we want to talk to
community about how they want that done
thank you
the next question is are you moving to
IRR d4 um yes I think I might have
mentioned that real quick at the
beginning so the new routing engine is
based on IR d4 we'd like to thank Joe
and Sasha and the whole team working on
that it's a major step forward for Aaron
and just happy to have access to such
high quality open-source software
next question is I currently utilized
the rod b4 IRR I'm in the process of
setting up rpki with Aaron how painful
would it be to decommission their RB and
move to the are in IRR ah okay so um the
community had told us for many many
years
don't bother working on iron and that's
actually what we did we let it sort of
languish out there and about four years
ago people said hey your IRR has gotten
so far behind you need to update it so
we're offering a new IRR and certainly
you could decide to use Aaron's new IRR
if that's what you want to do a couple
of things to think about right now we
don't have a programmatic interface so
this is really useful for someone who
wants to go on web interface create a
few route objects that's suitable if
you're currently doing a template-based
update automatic updates for the
customers are similar then you probably
want to keep either using the old Aaron
template what based one or continue to
use our ADB for a while until we can
give you a an API in an interface in a
programmatic interface so if you're
starting from scratch well that's a
great question if you can maintain
things manually you might want to just
create I our objects with the new Aaron
IRR coming out on June 10th if you need
a programmatic interface they don't want
the way your project you probably want
to use something else and then look at
Aaron after we have one
thank you
lesson is do you in still intend to
allow other IRS access to authentication
of objects have you figured out how to
do this well okay so we do n rpm and FTP
access to both data sets Aaron and Aaron
on off so people can use either sets of
data they want but the only thing that's
going to show up in the Aaron
data set going forward is information we
can actually validate where we know the
organization we have a current
relationship with them there's a lot of
information in the old IRR that is
impossible to validate the
organization's have gone away the
maintainer --zz have gone away so we're
not providing other IRS access one way
or the other what we're doing is
creating a clean data source with the
Aaron stream which anyone can use in any
way they want I guess I missed that
question you better ask it just just to
make sure that I got it correctly as
well do you still intend to allow other
IRS access to authentication objects
have you figured out how to do this so
mix the next question if I proxy right
is there objects they for my customers
what happens to these objects if I use
the web interface can I continue to
proxy register for my customers the
whole idea of proxy registration is kind
of a oxymoron i we're moving to where
we're going to have validated data and
that means that already for example in
aaron you cannot do it a read allegation
to a customer without them creating
their own object so i'd recommend you
not
try to build a model based on proxy
systems if you are you might want to use
another set of tools thank you the next
one is in rpki question why did you
select a 5-minute repository update do
you have any data on a periodicity of
client polling intervals hmm don't have
any data on that it's an excellent
question I'm going to need to dig a
little bit for that is that mr. key
that's probably mr. Houston
so let me Jeff I'll I'll dig that up and
get back and look the 5-minute if
there's a rational basis for it I'll let
you know and if that's not if you ever
suggested one send it to me indeed it
was from mr. Houston okay next question
on the Flag Day Erin will be reset and
have they authenticated also known as
web submitted objects is Erin know not
starting with the current Erin content
or also from scratch excellent question
actually to be honest this is the most
complicated part of the migration so
because the first two times I looked at
this I wasn't quite clear I understood
it every day we will take what's in the
old I our database and move it into the
new publication points which are being
done under IRD for when we move it
everything that matches a and
authenticated Erin organization ends up
in the Erin stream and everything that
matches that doesn't ends up otherwise
in the Erin dawn off the sum of those
two is the full set of information so
every day whatever it in the old
template based email based IRR is going
to end up in Erin on off being published
the set of that that's validated by Erin
where we have a valid organization ID
ends up in the arrow on the string so
it's some
the answer the question the short one is
it's not from scratch it's fully
populated - those things that are
authenticated and those are only in the
Aaron stream not the Aaron long and
every day that updates thank you the
next question is is there day one bulk
import function functionality in
web-based irr or is that pending the API
no bulk load right now we're gonna have
to figure out how to create an API that
makes sense for that and there's no
standard for this folks so I am
interested in ideas if you have a
suggestion parents and schefren process
or the iron consult mailing list we
would be happy to take your input as to
what you need for API functionality
other than the obvious that you've been
doing templates right now two more
questions so one before the last what
does the timeline for Aaron look like
for some of those of those new arctic ki
enhancements for example the
notification to take and routing
contacts for automatic are away even new
ones it's a priority for this year to
get done by the end of 2020 I don't hear
screams on the background so I think I
got that right and we have so far and we
still have seven minutes is an LRS a
required for access to this new IRR
service now that excellent question so
the only things that end up in the Aaron
stream is authenticated objects and that
means we actually know the organization
we have an agreement with them there's a
lot of old data we don't actually know
who put it in or whether the party that
put it in for the old objects the old
legacy blocks for example whether or not
that parties still own associated with
it so yeah if you want to have us say we
know who you are
and put you in the authenticated service
then yes you're going to have to end up
becoming a customer and
that's been consistent with Aaron's
approach people are legacy resource
holders are published in the database
can update right now can continue to do
so for now not a problem with that if
you want to benefit from all the new
services we got to validate who you are
and you've got to begin a customer thank
you very much John we don't have any
more questions so I think and conclude
our session thank you very much for the
update and have a good evening thank you
[Music]