Hey
[Music]
you
good morning and welcome to the second
day of virtual Nanog 79 coming to you
live from the entire world I'd like to
welcome you my name is Alex I'll be your
host this morning a couple of quick
things before we start there's a women
in technology lunch virtual it's on the
agenda please don't forget the virtual
Expo fill out the daily surveys we're
going to be doing a special survey
during the presentation today to see
what you want to have as off breakouts
later in the conference stay tuned for
that then without further ado mr. Tom
Daley advisor at fastly with Tuesday's
keynote thanks Alex good morning
everyone if you're I guess west of
Boston and good afternoon everyone if
you're east of Boston it's a pleasure
and an honor to be here during this
keynote I am hopefully going to convince
you that certain aspects of our network
are becoming disconnected and we may or
may not realize it if you want to shoot
me comments afterwards my email address
is below it's TJ d @ Q 7 dot IO a tiny
bit of housekeeping to start which is
some acknowledgments for engineers
around the world that helped contribute
to this presentation
throughout the presentation the
perspective will be through that of a
operator that is building content
delivery and edge compute and while the
perspective comes from my work at fastly
the views in this talk don't necessarily
reflect the viewpoints of fastly so
there are some major technological
themes that are going on as networks are
being built around the world today we're
all trying to deal with scale as traffic
and volume through the network grows as
we saw from Craig lava vistas talk
yesterday and the co mid-nineteen
pandemic we are all trying to build
resilient and available networks
that are agile and reconfigurable to our
customers needs everything needs to be
private and secure there's just too much
work to do in the networks are too big
today so we have to rely on automation
as a means to get our jobs done and we
want to think of our networks today as
infrastructure is code so that way that
automation work can be done all of this
is being done with a mind towards
simplicity because the networks of today
whether they be in the data center
across the inter domain routing fabric
or down into the user bases have just
gotten too complex for one any one
single human being to reason about and
therefore the simpler and more
repeatable that they can be the better
off we are in operating them and all of
this comes from many many cycles of
innovation in those networks and how we
tend to operate networks today
innovation is really important because
it allows us to react to changes
discover new opportunities it allows
network operators to come to create
competitive advantage it allows us to
scale delivery drive efficiency and in
some cases that cycle of innovation
allows us to attract top talent to our
to our companies so that way people want
to come and work for us innovation isn't
always plan though serendipity in many
cases leads the way in terms of
inventing some of the greatest things
that have come to be on the Internet
such as being able to host an on
virtually so I want to talk about
innovation cycles as part of this talk
today and then try to convince you that
we're missing a piece of the innovation
cycle and I'm going to do that I'm going
to shift back to the 1900s of an article
from telephone magazine in August 1904
sale cheap a 110 dropped standard
telephone and Electric Company's
switchboard in good order can be
delivered by September 15th from the
Tigray telephone company in Washington
this 110 line telephone operated switch
ordered gave us 110 lines of 9.6
kilobits per second or just under one
megabit per second of voice switching
capacity and this was the manual plug
board
switches and really was the advent of
switching switching technology that we
know and appreciate today but how did we
jump into automated switching well along
comes the gentleman by the name of
almonds stroker and it turns out that
stroker was an undertaker
stroker also had a competitor across
town and the rumor mill or the
conspiracy theory says that strokers
competitor his spouse was a telephone
operator and she was actively diverting
calls away from strokers business to her
husband and so struggler became very
frustrated by this and decided to
implement effort and decided to invent
the first automated telephone switch
called the Stroger step-by-step switch
this technology the the intellectual
property was purchased by General
Electric and was used to build some of
the very first automated telephone
switching cos that we know today and so
you know roughly over a hundred and
twenty years even 140 years of
innovation we go from the manual
switchboard to the step by step switch
eventually to the crossbar analog switch
which became the basis for the common
control platforms that we see in chassis
based routers and switches today all the
way up to the automatic digital switches
that we knew of the early seven or eight
70s and into the late 90s these are the
equivalent of our BFRs our big chassis
type devices that we've seen in the IP
world and then in the late 90s with the
advent of soft switches and voice over
IP technology this incremental
innovation in terms of you know adding
more capacity adding more lines adding
more automation to the voice Network
gets totally revamped as technology
changes and experiences a fundamental
change as voice over IP rules out and so
the case I'm trying to make here is that
these incremental innovation cycles
occur time and time again until you have
a period of fundamental technological
change and I think we're about to have
that happen in the network inter domain
space excuse me in the network inter
domain space so for the rest of this
talk I'm going to give some thoughts
about what's happening in the inter
domain at sort of the layer 1 through 3
layer 1 through 2 area of the network
what's going on in the application
domain layer 5 through 7 and I'm gonna
make the case that we're missing
something in the layer 3 domain or the
network inter domain between networks
that are interconnecting so let's just
look at history of where IP routing is
gone we started off with basic
hop-by-hop
routing box-to-box forwarding we moved
on to a time in period where one box
started to rule them all we have the PFR
similar to the crossbar switches where
we had common control and a line card
architecture up to today's you know
distributed architectures similar to the
to the talk we saw yesterday about
distributed super nodes where you know
we can think of individual chassis x' as
a line card and a matrix router up to
this notion of the last ten years
fundamental technological change
occurring in the advent of
software-defined networking that many of
us use to drive our networks today so
you know we have an evolution in routing
and at the same time we have an
evolution in the underlying technology
where you know just a few weeks ago we
saw an announcement for broad coms
tomahawk for processor we now take you
know twenty five point six tera bit of
switching capacity drop it into a two ru
chassis for under 1500 watts of power
consumption whereas you know just the
previous generation 12.4 terabit first
switch chip our 12.8 terabit per switch
chip we need six of them probably
drawing around 3,000 watts for the same
switching capacity probably for our you
abroad space all of this is iterating
and compressing down now
the advent of Sdn has allowed us to
massively instrument our local networks
far more than we've ever seen before and
what I
leave here is that this is giving us the
prevalence of single sided intelligence
in the network meaning that either as a
Content operator or as an edge cloud
operator or as a hosting provider we can
see a lot more of what's going on in the
network but there is still a blind spot
in the inter domain space we get some
viewpoints due to absorbing telemetry
data from clients directly by a you know
an out-of-band channel connection across
the internet but we still don't
necessarily know what's going on in that
third-party network so let me give you
that to you visually you know
traditionally a Content host would run
their own data center or they would run
their at their content hosting somewhere
in the world maybe their internet
connection would come from the data
center itself or from an ISP we've seen
that construct evolve as content
providers got into the business of being
their very own ISPs and connecting much
closer to the core of the internet we
can see that we get telemetry coming in
from users directly or from clients
directly so that way we can see what
that user experience looks like but at
the end of the day the third-party
network the last mile or the middle mile
that we're transiting through is not
necessarily participating in that
transaction we don't necessarily have
visibility there we can't find out
what's going on in the network we don't
have any points of introspection or
telemetry coming our way and so what
that means for content providers is that
we're constantly pursuing the edge of
the network we're trying to go deeper
and closer to the users to understand
what's happening in the network so that
way we can make the big for the best
possible experience that we can give
them and sometimes that might might mean
that the content of the host is going to
build far more deeply into the network
then we've historically seen and what
we're trying to deal with here is we're
trying to cut down on the amount of
inter domain information asymmetry that
exists right and this
concept of information asymmetry goes
back to managerial economics and
business strategy right for a market to
function efficiently participants must
have reasonably good information from
all sides right and that in our world in
the world of networking that can be
about interconnection network conditions
patterns of congestion day-to-day usage
patterns and without having that
information from both sides there's a
number of inefficiencies that occur in
the system so you know I would agree
that anyone knows their network their
own network better than anyone else and
that comes from their policy economics
constraints and preferences but my
question is is with that network piece
not being part of the transaction is
there an opportunity to open that
information up and I have a few more
words on that later so let me flip from
sort of the physical network piece and
go up the protocol stack to what's going
on in the HTTP world because I think
that this is an important consideration
as we move ahead if we look at the
history of HTTP similar to what we see
with inter domain routing similar what
we see with datacenter fabrics the
switch chips we see an evolution right
in 1991 we have HTTP 0.9 ratified by RFC
as the one-line HTTP protocol RFC 1945
comes along in 1996 what gives us which
gives us HTTP 1.0 so we get things like
versioning and status codes and headers
and content types in the protocol and
then really nothing happens for a while
until 2014 2015 where we see updated
specifications for HTTP 1 1 come out as
well as RFC 7540 defining HTTP 2 and
HTTP 2 takes an incremental approach at
improving the protocol primarily so we
can eliminate head-of-line blocking in
HTTP so we now get a protocol that
provides multiplex binary encoding on
the wire provides for header
compressions something called server
push more on that later as well as HTTP
alternative services
get ready because in 2020 were expecting
the newest version of HTTP HTTP free to
come out and start being used live on
the web
and that's available to you today so if
you go to HTTP 3 is you can see a demo
site of HTTP 3 now on the left hand side
on my laptop I just have regular old
chrome running and HTTP 3 does not get
used but if you go grab the Chrome
nightly build at Chrome Canary build and
throw these flags - - enable quick and -
- quick - version each 327 and use the
Chrome Canary and hit HTTP 3 is you will
see a demonstration of HTTP 3 and I want
to tell you a little bit more about
what's going on with HTTP 3 because I
think it's important in thinking about
how we manage networks in the future so
as I said it's the upcoming version of
the hypertext Transfer Protocol
it has feature parity from HTTP 2 but
unlike HTTP 2 which is carried over TCP
HTTP 3 is carried over quick which is a
brand-new transport protocol so just
some reminders HTTP 2 functions over TCP
so while HTTP 2 fixes the head-of-line
blocking problems associated with HTTP
1.1 we still have issues with
head-of-line blocking in the tcp
protocol itself and that's what we're
trying to address with HTTP 3 the other
thing that's very interesting about HTTP
2 is that it implements something called
HTTP alternative services HTTP 2
connections are meant to be very very
long-lived and so therefore as you're
trying to do traffic engineering in the
network you have a couple different
problems traditional load balancing and
global global server load balancing
traffic engineering techniques today
really sort of boil down to one of two
things
BGP anycast which for a long live
connection if you move those endpoints
around you're going to
great the connection on behalf of the
user at degrade the user experience or
you're going to use some sort of
dns-based GSLV system which requires new
lookups which requires those connections
to get restarted and therefore you're
not going to have the same traffic
engineering control of the network as
you may have had a HTTP layer in the
past so HTTP alternative Services exists
as a way for a server to notify a client
of on alternative URI to fetch the same
content from and there was some some
investigation into the security of that
it looks like there was some missed
misguided implementations of how this is
supposed to work that's being fixed but
fundamentally this technology works so
we now have a means to control how
clients are connecting to server
endpoints in band to the HTTP protocol
itself we don't have to use the DNS we
don't have to use BGP any caps for this
anymore and that's all available in HTTP
3 adding to the complexity of this htv3
is no longer it is not carried over TCP
it uses a new transport protocol known
as quick which is actually carried over
UDP and the designers of the quic
protocol and the HTTP 3 protocol use
quick because it resolves the
head-of-line blocking issue in TCP the
other thing to take away from this is
that connections in quick are not
defined by the traditional 5 couple that
were used to there are connection
identifiers in the quic header that are
actually used to identify client and
server connections the other thing to
note is that much more of the payload in
quic is natively encrypted using TLS 1.3
so as network operators there's a lot
less inspection that we're going to be
able to do in the network more on that
in a few seconds now the parameters for
mobility in quick changed dramatically
as I said we now have HTTP alternative
services to move clients to different
server end points but what's interesting
about that is not only can we move
server endpoints around similar to a
direct server return like connection
management on the on the serving side we
can also move the client connection
around in a stateful manner on the
client side so we serve quicks one of
quicks goal is to serve what they call
the parking-lot problem where you know
you're leaving your office at the end of
the day your mobile device has it
transitioned off of your Wi-Fi to get
onto the LTE network the connection gets
interrupted and quick that connection
can be seamlessly migrated from a UDP
endpoint on the wireless LAN to a UDP
endpoint on the LTE network and we can
again use HTTP alternative services to
move the server location around
depending upon local network conditions
so you know with all of this mobility
both client-side server-side we can
imagine what the future of things like
kubernetes containers deployed along the
network or serverless functions that the
edge can do for us where now when I want
to get to my user and maybe my core data
center isn't the most optimal serving
site I might move that workload to a new
UDP endpoint far deeper into the network
than I had before and this happens
seamlessly to the user it can happen
seamlessly to the user and that means
fundamental changes for network
operators are going to occur on the
middleboxes that we're all used to
having in our networks whether it be for
nap or for firewall or for content
inspection really can't touch the quic
protocol the way that we've seen the TCP
HTTP protocol get touched
interference with the payload of any
sort results in a connection reset the
user will know that something happened
to their connection we're now seeing
that routing protocol decisions in some
ways are moving up into the application
protocol stack through HTTP alternative
services and if you watch Paul vixy's
talk from a couple minutes ago
we're looking at Moo we're investigating
the DNS lookups moving alongside the
HTTP traffic and so you we can plan on
having much more localized effects of
well my internet doesn't look like your
internet anymore and what's going on
here and what that means for operators
is reduced observability less traffic
classification and perhaps less
opportunity to create value in the
network if you're a network operator and
you want to study up deeper on what's
going on with quick
I would suggest reading this IETF draft
for quick manageability it's currently
at version six as to what these
fundamental changes look like for
network operators in detail so we have
these massive innovations occurring at
the intradomain level and at the
application domain level and you know I
want to acknowledge what's going on with
rpki in the inter domain space but I
still think that there's an opportunity
here and as network operators we're
missing something what I'm trying to say
is that the remote infrastructure that
serves the client from the perspective
of the serving stack is just not a piece
of the equation yet as content operators
we've been able to bring together the
application layer the serving stack
infrastructure and the physical and
logical layer but what's going on in
that remote network is really still
quite opaque to us and so that remote
network is very much disconnected from
what developers can do today
developers can do way more in with the
network than they did 10 years ago
they can write more client code than
ever before companies that are
responsible for running their own
serving stack as well as their own
client stack under a common mission can
control all these aspects and really
relay on very very rich telemetry as to
what the user experiences I mean I'm
always thinking about what the Netflix
folks can do because they control the
serving stack deeply the control plane
for their application stack as well as
the client stack in in a very native and
common way so they can
those missions we never used to be able
to see that with browser technology
because we always have a third-party
client but with the advent of the
optical system that changes dramatically
with HTTP 3 and alternative services
we're starting to get some of that
functionality right into the native
browser and so you know what I believe
is that developers are doing a lot more
guests cheering in quotes about what's
going on in the network to try it and
find out conditions of the network in
real time and that leads to a lot of
inefficiencies in how we operate
networks one thing that's very
interesting about quick and the quick
altars wanted to have the capability for
is to iterate faster in this network
stack they wanted developers to be able
to think about future improvements to
this network stock in a rapid manner and
so what's interesting is that the
initial implementations of quick are
actually user space implementations so
the way that you get a quick process up
and running as you take your serving
software and you bolt on a module so
that way you can understand the quick
transport protocol and then go bind that
to a UDP socket so by deploying that
software in user space you can iterate
on what that software is doing far more
rapidly but I want to get across here is
that information sharing information
does not mean that you're giving away
control of your network and so I think
that there are opportunities using
technology that we have access to today
to share information in between networks
that ultimately benefit all of our
collective users so one example of that
is you know can we do some more
suggestive
signaling in the network using something
like BGP large communities if I'm
peering with another network can that
network signal to me some alternative
paths in the network where if that
peering links should saturate or congest
how does that eyeball network want to
receive overflow traffic and you know I
have some example communities that I
wrote up that you know someone
like an AT&T could use to signal that to
content operators or perhaps there's
congestion in a particular metro market
and we need to shift traffic completely
elsewhere or as a content provider where
we are exposing different dips to the
Internet in different IP blocks perhaps
we can provide some signaling to network
operators about the type of traffic
that's being carried on those blocks so
that way we can be smart about managing
congestion or can we use BGP large
communities to signal readiness for
bilateral session establishment across
ix route servers so that we then
software and automation can come and set
up bilateral sessions rather than
trading emails between human beings or
scraping down various internet peering
databases and you know using a spray and
pray type method I believe that
information drives simplicity in that
word and if we can make the network's
more simple that we can actually
significantly reduce waste
we can stop over provisioning that works
because we don't know the best path we
don't have to guess about what the best
path is through the network anymore
maybe we can move workloads based upon
prevailing Network conditions or
historical network conditions with quick
if we can sort of move the fly around
and move the server around seamlessly
without resetting connections for the
user that gives us much more moment
mobility of where we serve those
workloads from and maybe we can reduce
significant amounts of human energy
that's spent debugging reconfiguring and
engineering to find ILO pass through the
network when computers can do it anyways
you know we figured out how to do this
in the network intradomain with
software-defined networking so how can
we extend that across network boundaries
across a ton of autonomous system
boundaries in the future now I think I'm
going to get a lot of objections to this
because you know we've heard some of
these before like things like well my
network topology and the conditions on
my network are my competitive
but I think that telemetry data coming
from clients is already telling contact
operators about that or maybe my router
can't run more processes in its control
plane but I think we've learned that
from software-defined networking and the
deployment of our PKI we know how to
side load data into the network you know
we can process large Maps we can process
vast amounts of information and then
really load only into the forwarding
plane what we need to implement the the
desired state that we're looking for in
the network or you might say that I'm
you know reducing the network to being
the last common denominator but I'm
actually looking for is the most
efficient allocation of resources or you
might say sharing this information
allows for Network arbitrage I would
argue that it's already happening so I
think that there's a whole nother round
of innovation that can occur in how we
operate networks we're seeing a lot of
innovation down in the physical layer in
stn we have an evasion going on in the
in the application domain and I think
that there is something missing in the
inter domain you know the inter domain
has had a rich history the Nanog group
has been evolving this for a long time
it goes all the way back to the late 90s
with the advent of naps and peering VB
the global peering forum but I think
that there's more that we can do there's
an his signaling that we can deploy
between networks there's such an
creation automation that we can look
into there's flow information sharing
that can go on between networks there's
some great work around something called
dots which is a DDoS you know
situational awareness protocol between
DDoS mitigation appliances on Prem and
the cloud and that we can look at the
advent of edge compute severus functions
containerized workloads to think about
how we move workloads around the
internet dynamically to coordinate for
better and user experiences and I think
once we can get to that state then we
can realize a place where the
application layer the local
infrastructure serving stack the remote
client infrastructure stack as well as
the physical layers brought together in
a harmonious fashion and the network
will be
are more efficient that's my take on
some ideas for the future and I would
love to take any questions that may have
popped up along the way feel free to
shoot me email with complaints or
suggestions as well TJ d @ q 700 is the
email address thank you for this time
[Music]