Hey
[Music]
you
vogue everybody like to welcome to your
next session this is a panel session
specifically on the rpki and it'll be
moderated by Mark coster's and I'll let
him take it from there and reduce your
panelists today
great thanks John so I'm Mark Osler some
CTO there and when it in things that's
very interesting to me is that Tom Daley
gave a presentation yesterday first
keynote talking about new innovative
services and one of the things that he
talked about was our peacock and I was
really glad to hear that for a couple of
reasons one is even though this is
something that y'all are seeing fairly
recently this is something has been in
been in the works for over a decade so
this is a work that's been under
development or has been deployed for a
while and we're starting to see some
real traction within the community and
one of the things I like to do with the
panelists here Adam that Davenport CF
lagerfeld and Nimrod levy is talk about
how this could be used within your
enterprise and hopefully when you leave
this panel you say if you haven't been
doing this already that this is
something that you'll look forward to
implement within your own Internet
service provider so I'm going to go to
the next slide what I like to show you
here is oops is is that you can see over
time that we're starting to see
accelerated growth on on our number of
people who are using our PGI within the
Arin region and it's not true just
within the Arin region but this is
internationally with the other four
regional registries as well and when it
things I'll note a note here is very
recently we started to see a lot more
traffic with delegated using up/down so
this is a is because of new technology
that's come out that's made it fairly
easy for people to use most people are
still using hosted solutions which
majority of our customers are using and
talk about that more with the panelists
about which solution that they've used
and so that you can see as you go
forward what you should think you should
do here's the panelist bring the faces
to the names Adam CF and Nimrod and
working for GGT tell carrier and ATT
respectively and here's our agenda so
each of the panelists is going to talk
about the current state of our PK within
their networks and then we're going to
go through a question session where each
of the panelists is going to be question
asked questions about their planning and
implementation at planning and testing
say stages their implementation stage as
well as future phases and if we have
time afterwards we'll open it up for
questions so let's go ahead and start
the the panelists so the first question
I'm wondering we'll start with you Adam
if you could tell us a little bit about
the stave your rpki implementation sure
probably four to six weeks ago we rolled
out the final phase of our validation
deployments so we are now dropping in
ballots essentially at all quarters so
peers and customers great great and UCF
well we start our journey by mid-2008
inna tell ya and we finalized our
deployment by last night on beginning of
February this year by dropping both from
customers and peers excellent excellent
and you Nimrod so we've been dropping in
ballots on our peering edge since for
about almost a year and a half now since
this prior to that our last February and
we're working on some some solutions to
filter routes that we learn from our
customers they're not filtering directly
dropping a balance on our house
correctly are you playing to do so
um we're planning on we're looking at
some some interview solutions where we
the affection will be that there will be
we won't be propagating in ballots I
don't know that we're going to get in
your turn on where we're going to be
directing filtering on on everything
okay great great
so let's not talk about the planning and
implementation that you had to do to
make this all happen and the first
question I like you to ask you guys is
how did you make art became a priority
within your organization and what was
the business case to do so um so Adam
let's start with you sir
we began seeing our ki KI asked about in
customer rfp's probably starting around
two years ago within the last year
though we've started seeing it become a
requirement and those are Effie's versus
a would be nice additionally we've had
multiple existing customers experience
what I'll call unauthorized announcement
events and definitely call us direct
impacts to their operations so they were
calling forward as well and given kind
of those factors it was pretty easy to
justify internally okay CF well I agree
with Adam we thought about the same time
frame they started popping up in
customer
discussions in 2018 but also with the
number of PT behind X at a large scale
not declining the opposite really we saw
more often hijack that - down typer
scales and others so we started a
project that Telia which was good for
the internet where we saw bi and also
joining manners steps to at least do our
part in helping and make sure that then
that gets better and safer okay okay
Nimrod in how about you so our path was
a little bit different than I think we
started earlier Mike Connolly J Griffin
Hagen has been very active in the groups
where the vendors are bellum and so he's
been asked
in that noun for quite some time and so
we were we kind of pushed it
you're from from a few man hold
individuals really internally drove that
to to make it important ready
employed I'm not aware that may have
come from some customers
what's it well but I'm not aware of that
okay great I think it's kind of
fascinating from Adams perspective that
there are piece that came out saying you
need to have RPG I I'm wondering if
that's going to become more of a trend
as we go forward what you guys think
about that
what do you think well we already
started seeing it especially after well
the press releases I last year so yeah
almost all of the bigger customers they
are requiring it or requiring the
attendee to have a timeline for
implementing it we're kind of
interesting the Nimrod I take it you two
have also have seen that or maybe I've
heard about it so I'm not really in tune
with the requirements coming in but I do
I think that that's a motivator for for
all of us to do a lot of things this is
what our customers want so doing and so
you know it's these are things that are
really positive or they internet adult
should be doing okay great great
so when you were going through this and
he said okay gonna set up our PK I'm
sure that you all put these things in
your labs and actually trying to make
this stuff work what sort of steps did
you do to make sure that you when you
were going to deploy the site you felt
like hey this is gonna work out and just
go or cotton pretty a pretty good way I
don't let's start out with you yeah sure
yeah we definitely deployed in the lab
setup initially you can only get so far
in a lab environment though so for
are you know kinda live test we
identified five different boxes that
were can all over the place in our
network different models etc and
basically deployed full validation on
those five devices to see you know what
you know if any issues would arise and
you're probably not a super exciting
answer but honestly speaking there
weren't any real issues with catch it
did pop up as part of this and things
went pretty well as expected so we
didn't really have any surprises there
okay in Carl and what about you well we
started actually rolling at also going
by device type or software type and
checking okay so how does it handle
their two-hour sessions and checking
that it does an impact and we started by
marking all the received routes with a
community depending on foundation state
this made us so we could track that in
an SLO data and see how much traffic do
you really have towards these
destinations that are invalid prior to
us making any decision and that helped
us well we've seen a lot of small tiny
bugs but we all work around the bug that
we have from day to day so as long as
you're aware of them it's quite easy to
actually implement this okay Nimrod what
about you yeah we did a lot of the same
things I mean so we we did our
deployment I think earlier then then a
lot of the larger networks so we didn't
have as much history of other folks to
be able to to play off of and so we did
exactly what uh what carl fredrik
mentioned there is that we had our you
know relying Hardeen software in place
for a long time we actually had the
session put up through the routers
without doing any actual filtering but
we had that in place from I guess was
like October of 2018
before that previous nano and and so we
were tagging routes and and monitoring
traffic and really trying to evaluate
what the in
actually we already done our lab tests
to make sure that that we didn't see
didn't expect any problems with the
routers and the technology itself it was
really more of what is this policy going
to do to real-life traffic at that point
but you know it's your standard test and
review and and intended rate and then
white kind of a process great
so min round if you could just get a
little bit close to the mic that would
be useful so I'm wondering it did any of
you all have any surprises when you went
from the lab environment to production
or D was it just a really smooth rollout
and if there was any gotchas are you
willing to share any of the gotchas so
Adam let's start with you sure I would
say for the most part it was pretty
straightforward we did have one kind of
minor blip I would say you know our
particular vendor has an open bug that's
rpki related and certain certain
scenarios ops a really disconcerting
message in the logs type thing but upon
further inspection this is largely
cosmetic and not a real issue so
basically that was pretty much the only
thing that we had pop up and again it
ended up being more cosmetic than
anything and not impacted and impacting
excellently in current what about you
we've only had one boat that has been
serviced impacting for a very few
customers and it was with one vendor
related to brows Anthony when there was
a delta update received from one of the
RTR caches the router was connected to
that is sold in releases that are
popular by now but nothing more than
those tiny things in the Murad you I
don't think we saw any significant
vendor bugs there are things that that
we have to work around like we said you
know as long as you know those things
going in you can usually work around
them and I don't think we've seen
anything significant the thing that I
think surprised me the most
was the volume of traffic him impacted
when we were doing our measurements the
amount of traffic that's associated with
these invalid prefixes was so small that
that was really surprising hmm
okay okay interesting okay so this sort
of brings up the sort of next question
in terms of we sort of moved on into the
implementation phase so when you were
doing this I there's a lot of people
have fears and say hey this is gonna bog
down my routers if I have to do this I
know I'm going to make mistakes or
something's going to happen which is
going to impact my customers did you see
any performance or operational impact
with when or origination validation was
configured in on your routers and were
you concerned about that when you rolled
these things out and what is your advice
to others as they go through this
deployment scheme Adam let's start with
you sure I mean it was definitely a
concern you know we didn't see kind of
any impact performance wise in our lab
testing and then we you know test
started testing in production on those
five devices that was beer we didn't
really see you know anything there
either and we monitored pretty
extensively for 3-4 weeks before looking
to you know kind of continue rolling out
our deployment but by and large you know
we just didn't really notice anything
negatively one way or the other so my
advice would be is you know try it out
make sure things look good on your
platform but generally speaking it's you
know the deployment has been pretty
pretty smooth and pretty straightforward
okay great çf about you and someone is
muting me and unmuting me all the time
yes that's why I know we also tested
this in lab person we didn't really see
any issues what was interesting was this
spring when more and more of our
customers started enabling this and we
could see some interesting thing on some
of our bgp sessions that we know so is
as we tested this for some time we
some of the smaller bugs that are not
something you should care about
if you run up-to-date software but some
of our customers apparently don't do
that and what we can see there is a lot
more route refresh being received on VDP
sessions actually consuming a fair bit
of CPU usage on our routers but so far
we've been able to cope with that yeah
ok ok excellent
Nimrod what about you um so obviously we
were concerned about performance when
when we tested we didn't see anything in
the lab and and we still don't see
anything concerning in production I'll
also mention that the Doug Montgomery
over at NIST has done some testing on on
some of the sorts of things I'm not sure
if all of this data is published or not
but you've done some work where they
they tested with you know full tables of
rows for everything fully a fully signed
table you know a 50 % table 75 % table
different combinations of amounts of
sign prefixes just to see how it would
affect the platforms and any really from
what I understand and had noticed
negligible impact on on that so you know
even as the number of rollers continues
bro I don't expect that we're going to
see ok excellent excellent
um so what rpki a validation software
you are y'all using and how did they
implemented maintained and do you have
redundancy and monitoring configured
Adam let's start with you sure we are
using four validator and auto and and go
basically we've got a free validator set
ups you know redundancy was a big
concern of ours so you know we basically
trying to deploy these in a way that was
redundant
in all manners there you know our
validators are in different locations
globally they all run different you know
validation software the validation or
the validators are running on different
hardware and different vendors we even
use different operating systems but our
goal with definitely to deploy without a
single point of failure which i think we
did a pretty thorough job of and yes so
far things have been look pretty good
absolutely that sounds great what about
UCS sames being area so that was a major
concern for us as well especially what
we saw in testing in the beginning where
there were really only the right
relators available and the pro rata
nature actually got stable but we
decided to not only offer or offer but
have validate your stats are of
different types different software but
also spread them out geographically so
all our Raptors connect to all of our
validators spread out over the world
which makes a litte bit more redundant I
would say as well and we are running
right now with only RPG elements I'm
from OpenBSD together with go fer for
the RTR function and browse nature with
included RTR supports we used to run
extract PGI but rolled that back just a
month ago one thing that we monitor is
also the output of all of the validator
to make sure that they are in sync with
one another because there is some
discussion in the community of how you
should interpret our c4 for invalid
certificates and other things that make
the develop aegis on the market actually
output different things as well and in
the comparisons then between the
network's you could say okay but they
think lamented RPG I but for some reason
I see a few invalids well there is a
reason for that
yeah yeah actually you bring up really
good point CF and that is there's there
some things within the standards that
need to be as sort of clarify a bit
especially with CR ELLs expiry etc that
have seen and is definitely brings up
interpretations or things that different
vendors have done it's a good point
Nimrod what about you we take the same
approach
you know multiple geographic locations
multiple vendors of relying party
software right now we're we're still
running the right degree and as well as
route Nader horizon on the west what's
coming if it's it's valid to make a
change and we also have have some
monitoring in place where we check the
what the routers see from those relying
party and make sure that we have a
consistent view from all of those from
every instance of the relying party
software some need for any vendors that
might be listening be great to have an
easier way to get to lemon tree for that
first no screen scraping oddly great
well thank you so much so let's go back
let's go to the provisioning site we
talked about the validation sites go but
on actually great rows within your own
networks and which solution are you guys
using and which regional registries are
you touching and what do you prefer
so Adam let's start with you sure you
know we've got IP space with you know
all the our IRS except maybe lack knit
so you know we've we've been creating
rows for our space in our own space with
each of those right now it's being done
manually we admittedly just don't have
that much IP address space that's ours
you know the originated I think and
that's been that's worked out for us I
think you know the process there it's
obviously a little bit different between
the different are hours but by and large
it's you know not overly complicated or
anything like that so it's been pretty
straightforward there as well okay so
yeah yeah we've gone with the hosted
solution have that both right Aaron and
APNIC offers right now at least then
same thing as I'm weird Tier one we
don't ordinate that much IP space we've
had a few customers where we have
delegated our own IP space to where we
had to go through and sort out four
to create robust but it's mostly gone
very well actually
okay and M rod what about you though
I haven't been directly involved with
creating any of the roads but we do have
somewhere with a sign for parts of our
IP space my networks a little bit
different I guess we have I'm sure one
transit provider but I also have a lot
of my own I my consumer and wireless
site so we do have some of our row
assign for that I look to a time at some
point in the future where it's all been
on the hosted solutions primarily with
their in I look to a time in the future
where we'll have a delegated setup that
great with our you know customer
provisioning tools and where we'll have
be able to delegate to a customer and
have them log in and essentially our
hosted order delegate to them as but
that'll be a fairly significant project
of itself excellent excellent excellent
so I have a question that's a regarding
your software in terms of actually
dealing with repositories going back to
third akia validating the routes and
that is what happens if one of the
repositories we need to gather your RPI
information is not available
what what what is your what is your
strategy in dealing with that so Adam
what do you guys do
yeah right now basically if that were to
happen we you know would potentially
just be accepting about you know from
from those missing you know once there's
a you know other approaches there I mean
you know we're looking at the end ripper
things all the time but that's that's
what we're having with us today we just
accepted so you feel open which is great
CF what about you yeah we essentially
have this same set up we feel open
we will just accept imbalance for the
repository that's not available but we
do stagger the refreshes or updates on
our validators so we if a repository
goes down we will directly have those
still on our boundaries to row us for up
to one hour at least
okay okay in them rod what about you so
I think carl fredrik looted to some of
this earlier there's some discussion in
the community about how to handle some
of those things and like you said the
standards need to be clarified a little
bit on how those situations could handle
from what I understand the validators
themselves keep things in cash or some
period of time and and they'll use
whatever the most recent information
they have for until I'm not sure exactly
what it said what it does and it may
vary from from guide from platform to
platform and and then and then
eventually it'll no time out and will it
okay I'll open s go through whether
things like you probably heard John
Byrne say on Monday Spock when he's
talking about art he also entered the
talk with some of the things within the
orange region and one of the things that
we've done is we any of the horse I have
been created within the hosted solution
on are actually propagated to the
repositories within five minutes what do
you guys think about that is that
appropriate sort of time for it in terms
of Adam yeah
sorry there's yeah feedback from someone
yeah I would say you know obviously
instant is always better but you know in
a perfect world but you know five
minutes to me seems reasonable
okay okay okay huh CF
yeah I don't have anything against Dutch
okay Nimrod
yeah there's been a lot of discussion
about that and in the past I think it's
I think it needs to be recognized that
that rpki doesn't propagate at the speed
of eg P it's not it's not routing
information it's a sideband it's
something a little bit different and I
think what we had before where it
updated well four times a day whatever
it was that that's probably a little bit
too long a lot too long maybe and you
know five minutes is pretty good it
makes things work it lets us set a
pretty reasonable propagation time from
time the user puts something in to it
gets published in in Aaron's database
when the caches fetch it and then it
propagates the routers so you know we
can reasonably expect propagation within
an hour or so okay okay so one of the
things that's kind of interesting about
this and and it was actually it was
there was a discussion about this at ITF
a while back and we're starting to move
into future phases and one of the things
that's interesting about this is
somewhat analogous to DNS where there's
a DNS change there's a notification Nate
made to the secondaries that replicate
that information from the primary master
and Dinah's parlance to say hey look my
contents of my zone have changed please
get this now do we need some sort of
mechanism that says hey look there's
some change that's occurred there's a
new Rohit that's been added or there's
been one that's been changed do we need
to have the sort of a more sort of near
real-time update feature built into our
PGI or do we think that the period
period of five minutes as some sort of
number is good enough Adam what do you
think yeah like I said I think you know
whatever possible
you know instant is always good that
being said I do think five minutes is
reasonable and from an operation
standpoint you know but the difference
between five minutes and near instance
or near instant you know may not be that
big of an issue certainly in certain
circle
chances it potentially could be but I
think by and large probably okay okay
okay Carl yeah the same it's entirely
okay
in Nimrod I think as long as we manage
those expectations and and recognize
like I said it's it isn't routing
information it doesn't propagate but
it's pretty close it's pretty good we
just have to know where that line is and
and know what to expect
I think it's perfectly reasonable
timeframe okay excellent excellent
excellent
um so rpki only does deals protects with
origin validation those are other things
that we need to deal with in the routing
to infrastructure to secure what sort of
things do you think are important and
what sort of things you think are
working I an IETF like a sba for example
if that's useful and finally if a ASPA
is useful what do people think about
actually registering and letting people
see their peers so Adam let's start with
you sure you know I think path
validation is very interesting you know
obviously we're here right now we've got
origin covered but not full path so I
think that's you know something worth
looking at
you know there's potential implications
there but definitely think it's very
interesting I think ASPA is definitely
interesting against you know and it's in
the early stages but you know in terms
of publishing you know the peers and
then concern on that you know as a
transit free tier one you can see all my
adjacencies in the routing table so I
personally don't have a problem with it
but I can definitely see why some might
fair enough
yes I think it's something that is
needed because if you look at the
quality of the different IR or databases
that we are dependent on today some
change is needed and we're talking about
authoritative or and it can be
authorized whatever records we need some
way of making sure that no one can just
register around
entry and led be and everyone will
accept it we need this as well but one
step at a time
excellent thank you in them right um I'm
a big fan of the the ideas that are
being worked on especially SVA I think
that the concept makes a lot of sense
you know it's Lincoln said is it's
really it needs some work get
implemented but that should be really
really interesting to do as far as the
you know the publication of information
that's the same thing in the routing
table the the whole purpose of this is
to be able to cryptographically verify
things that are in the routing tables so
just just because we published it in an
RPI you know it doesn't make it any more
well-known than what we see the routing
table and a capable excellent thank you
so with that those were the last of the
prepared questions and I'm gonna turn it
over to John Kristoff to bring up what
the audience has been asking about very
good there's there's a handful of
questions we gotta try to squeeze in
short amount of time that we have mark
you asked a lot of questions and you had
to expect this one of the questions that
came in it wasn't provoked by me or
solicited but essentially it's this is
is there any plane changes to the our
our PA so it's part one it's actually
two part question to the rest of the
panel members is are all of you using
the air Intel or not
so go ahead mark you so the the best way
of getting that answer is talking to
John Curran our president CEO he talked
on Monday and he's more than willing to
his email address as well no and you're
more than welcome to reach out to so
that is sort of the answer to the first
question and the rest is up to the rest
of the participants I would imagine Adam
sir yeah the your muted atom but the
narrow it's maybe just a quick yes or no
if you guys use their family not sorry
audio yes we use the the all the jobs
from the are ours yes numerous and we do
validate on the air as well yes
yeah we use all the pals from all depth
are Alex okay terrific thank you um next
question but specifically for foreign
abroad what are the key barriers to
enabling rpki filtering on customers
there are potentially some enhancements
that could address those barriers um I
think it's internal things primarily we
have a fairly diverse customer edge
different platforms and play and just so
far it's been a lot of work to to
prioritize that and we haven't gotten
there we we also have some pretty good
route filters that we already prefix
list bass track
well filters on all of our customer
edges that depend on that have served us
pretty well so far it's neither one is a
complete solution and but that that's
one of the things that's it's made it
difficult and then you know so we like
having that as packet filter that prefix
list rather place and they're just
having the diversity on that edge on
some other platforms makes it
difficulties aren't we a technical issue
in our lead
I already bacon good thank you very much
next question is for those of you on the
panel it's probably exclude you broke on
this one is if you're rejecting routes
have you looked at what you're rejecting
is there any pattern to trends to what
you're rejecting the most
yeah I would say yeah we've definitely
kept close tabs on what we're rejecting
both in terms of prefixes and the
traffic associated with those prefixes
and you know I mean there's certain
networks that have more in balance than
others but I would say by and large from
our observation that hasn't been a
pattern or you know I can't say you know
the vast majority come from one source
type thing it's kind of in a spread but
like you know Nimrod said earlier I do I
was surprised at the low how low the
levels of impacted traffic open that
they were okay I take sound throws in a
group answer next question is currently
there's about 130,000 Roiz this person
telling me I'm not true but the number
has no bound were the baton is very high
but someone could come along in tomorrow
and double that number or create a
significant amount of just aggregation
any concerns from either Aaron or the
operators if that would happen
there are some suggestions in the
community what to do with host base for
us so you could essentially create a row
up for a specific host and if you look
at the ipv6 base you could do that for
every host address within its last 48
and that will generate a considerable
amount oh well we've been told right now
is that there are some protection
mechanism within the RIR
publishing tools so that that won't
happen but otherwise the way for us to
securely manage our routers is to
essentially not let anything figure or
more specific than what we would accept
on our customers sessions through the
validator as well meaning that we're
only accepting slash twenty fours ipv4
from our customers we don't need to
accept any rora that it's more specific
than a session for this goes aside with
also our tbh having to function and
that's a totally separate discussion but
yeah it's directly a problem but we've
been ashore for now okay thanks very
much
next question if all's
called Tier one ISPs work implement
origin validation what's the benefit for
the customers behind them enterprises
content providers and so on diplomat
rpki origin validation so are you soon
you're you're saying you're at the
question is what are they down streams
to actually do validation themselves and
and I'll admit they you know we buy by
having all of the tier ones doing organ
validation we really take a significant
bite out of the problem because you know
all of those routes are propagating
through through one or more of us you
know I didn't and so if we're doing that
validation then then yes or downstreams
definitely reap those benefits that said
there it doesn't it's not that difficult
as we kind of walk through to get this
going and to be able to do validations
on your own and you know it's yeah it's
great that we're doing it but there's
there's not really a whole lot of reason
that that larger enterprises are no
larger networks non-jew ones should be
doing shouldn't be doing it all so
everybody and do it thank you brain next
questions comes presumably someone from
both small maybe midsize isp interested
in the validator lying party best
practices what's the impact of a
validator being down or unreachable and
is second part of the question is would
you recommend or is advisable or is
acceptable to run the validator and you
know the cloud provider so there's
there's been some some discussion about
some of those kinds of things as well
the impact of not having a validator
being reachable has been like we said
it's actually kind of similar to the
repository not being available you know
you're just not getting information from
that
one validator and the way they way the
systems work as long as you're receiving
that information from any one validator
you have that protection so the idea
there would be to build that diversity
you have multiple instances so that you
don't have that single point of failure
the question of running the validator
and loud provider is a little bit
different because that that goes to a
matter of trust you know you trust that
your connectivity to that cloud provider
and then you haven't done that the
crypto validations on your platform
locally so are you trusting them to have
done that validation on your behalf
it's it's possible to do it it's a good
idea that you have to make that decision
what's right for your organization these
validators are not very heavy it doesn't
take very much VM to on it the ones that
we're running are pretty skinny and they
it's it's not yeah they work pretty well
you can you can do it have to figure out
what's what's right for your
organization okay it's taking your voice
and I'm afraid we still have lots of
questions in the queue but we're
beginning to trespass on the time of the
the upcoming presentation so we're gonna
have to end it here thank you all on
behalf of the program committee I know
if you had anything closing the same
mark but when it comes to the panelists
yeah I just want to thank you thank the
panelists and the audience for listening
in and and hopefully this helps
encourage you to adopt our PTI as a
first step of many steps that we need to
take to secure routing infrastructure so
thank you very much thanks everyone the
next session will begin shortly
[Music]