Hey
[Music]
you
so hi everyone I would like to introduce
you to our next speaker
ronbo Nika her own is distinguished
engineer at juniper and he's here to
talk to us about fast reroute on IP
networks really all yours
thank you good evening good night good
morning good afternoon whatever time
zone you're in and today we're gonna
talk a little bit about IP fast reroute
now IP feet fast reroute has evolved
through three stages at first there was
link free alternates LFA then remote
link free alternates are LFA and finally
topology independent loop free
alternates TI LFA we're gonna step
through each of them but first let's
talk about a little bit about what the
problem is let's say for a minute you
have a link failure in your network well
for some small period of time you're
going to be dropping packets while the
IGP turns the nodes on either side of
the link failure are gonna have to
advertise the link failure it's got that
information propagates through your IGP
domain everybody rican recomputes their
best path to everywhere else and then
things go back to normal now and this is
called the convergence period and
connected e connectivity isn't restored
until the IGP converges now how long
does that take
well it depends on the size of your
network the size of your IGP domains um
the speed that your processors running
out if you're lucky
it might be milliseconds and nobody'll
care if you're less like likely seconds
and maybe users will start to notice
that if they're gaming or if they're
doing IP telephony and if it's really
bad it might be tens of seconds and
users will definitely notice that so we
have this idea of IP fast reroute IP
fast reroute protect some resource
either a link or a node and it computes
a repair path around that protected
resource when the protected resource
fails the node just upset upstream of
the failed resource
shifts traffic to the repair path so
that connectivity is preserved during
the IGP convergence period anyhow that
may have sounded like so much
gobbledygook so I'll give you a concrete
example let's say for a minute r2
calculates its least cost Ralph to r7
that's gonna go go through R to R 5 now
if R 2 R 5 breaks are two is gonna
blackhole traffic destined for our seven
and this black holing may persist for a
while um certainly r2 has to install new
routes to r7 but maybe other nodes also
have to do that before the ITP Rican
verges so for some small period of time
we're going to have black holing and
that's going to be called the
convergence period now we need two other
words in our vocabulary um one is pre
convergence state r2 is in a pre
convergence state regarding r7 from the
time our two r5 breaks until it installs
a new route to r7 so what's the pre
convergence time it's the time between
the break till the time our two gets a
new route to r7 then there's a post
convergence state once that new route is
installed our two enters a post
convergence State
now there are three fast reroute
solutions they've evolved over time l fa
re l fa and e IL fa there are some
things that all three solutions have in
common and there are some things that
all three solutions make all three
solutions different what they have in
common is each of them has something
called a point of local repair the point
of local repair is just upstream of the
protected resource it notices that the
protected resource is broken first the
other thing they all have in common is
something called a repair node the point
of local repoint of local repair the PLR
wants to get traffic to the repair node
during the convergence period because
the repair node is guaranteed to have a
path to the ultimate destination so the
PLR may not be able to use it best path
to get to the destination but if it can
get traffic to the repair node the
repair node can get at the rest of the
way now what are the differences between
LF a RL fa and TI l fa well the biggest
difference is how fussy they are about
selecting a repair node in LFA the
repair node must be directly connected
to the PLR and it must meet two other
criteria that we'll talk about later but
the good thing is you don't need a
tunnel to get to it and it gives you
pretty good coverage in most network
well in many network topologies LFA is
good enough to give you fast reroute but
and some network topologies LFA will not
give you fast reroute that's why we say
it's a good coverage as opposed to you
know 100% coverage now our LFA has less
suvir's restrictions on rev repair node
selection there are more nodes that can
be the repair node and the reason why as
the repair node does not need to be
directly connected to the PLR if the PLR
can reach the repair node over a tunnel
that follows the pre convergence IGP
least cost path that repair node is good
enough so thus of the restriction on
selecting a repair node is less severe
you do need a tunnel to get to it and
you get better coverage than LFA but
still you don't get TI LFA then finally
we have apology independent LFA it has
the least severe restrictions on repair
note selection in fact you're guaranteed
that there will be a repair node
available again you need a tunnel to get
to it and in particular you need a
segment routing tunnel the difference
between the tunnel you used in our LFA
and the one you use in TI LFA the tunnel
in our LFA follows the pre convergence
IGP best cost path least cost path the
tunnels that you use in TI LFA can
follow any path that you want and it
gives you the best coverage it gives you
100% coverage so there's guaranteed to
be a repair note available so let's take
a little look what we're going to do is
take a look at all three fast reroute
solutions LFA or LFA and di LFA we're
going to take a look at a reference to
Paulo G and take a look at first our
repair node is selected and how we use
it then we're going to tweak the
topology a little bit to show you a
topology in which in this case LFA does
not work and we'll go on to our LFA do
the same exercise and we'll tweak the
topology a little bit and show you a
topology in which neither LFA nor our
LFA will give you coverage and then
we'll go on to TI LFA and show you how
it gives you 100% coverage so let's talk
about LFA first
LFA preserve
connectivity during the conjure up that
LFA preserves connectivity during
convergence by pre computing and
installing a backup route to the
destination when the primary route
becomes unusable traffic shifts to the
backup route
so let's go through an example and the
example topology r2 calculates its least
cost path to our seven and that least
cost path traverses the link between r2
and r5 that's the link that's
highlighted in yellow it also identifies
a repair node and in this case the
repair node is r3 so let's say for a
moment that r2 fails if r2 can get
traffic destined for r7 to r3 it has a
guarantee that r3 has a path to r7 and
things will just work now
Oh what what do we do before the break
well r2 calculates its least cost paths
2r v r7 through r5 it identifies a least
cost path to the repair node through r2
r3 and it installs that path as a backup
to our seven so we need a couple pieces
of terminology here first is PLR in this
example r2 is the PLR it is the node
just upstream of the protected link and
it will detect the break on the
protected link first it also identifies
the repair node in this case r3 now what
are the requirements to be a repair node
well first and foremost the repair node
has to be directly connected to the PLR
second it has to satisfy the loop three
criteria this means with r3 is in its
pre convergence state before it noticed
notices that are two r5 has gone down
its least cost path to r7 must not go
back through r2
it turns out that's exactly the
situation here our threes least-cost
path to r7 has a metric of one two four
six whereas if it went back through r2
the metric would be one five seven so
our threes least cost path to r7 is not
back through r2 you can see why you
wouldn't want it to go back to r2 r3
sent the back pack it back to r2 r2
would just send it back to r3 and you'd
have a routing loop the next criteria is
the downstream criteria that is the IGP
metric from the repair node to the
ultimate destination has to be less than
the IGP metric from the PLR to the
ultimate destination and that kind of
makes sense the repair node has to be
closer to the destination and the PLR so
what happens after the break r2 notices
that link are two r5 is broken
it sends traffic destined for our r7 to
r3 r3 forwards the packet the rest of
the way to our seven and it gets there
continuity is preserved during the break
and when the IGP rican verges now our
two's least-cost path to r7 will also be
through r3 now I'm going to tweak the
IGP a little bit and the last slide the
IGP metric of r3 r4 was one now I'm
going to tweak it up to three well now
our three is no longer a repair node for
our two and the reason why the metric
between our three and our seven going
through our for our 6r8 is three four
five six seven eight
well the metric going back through r2 is
one five seven
so if r2 tried to send a packet destined
for r7 to r3 r3 would just send it right
back to our two you'd have a routing
loop and that would be worse than black
holing so what we're seeing is the basic
limitation of just plain old LFA in some
network topologies there is no repair
node so in this particular network
topology LFA cannot protect link are two
or five with respect to destination r7
so this brings us to remote LFA how do
we get around this problem
well our LFA addresses LFA him
limitations by allowing some nodes to
serve as repair nodes even if they're
not directly connected to the PLR so
what does that mean in LFA the only
possible repair node was r3 now
other nodes can serve as the repair node
but you need to build a tunnel from the
PLR to the repair node and that tunnel
will follow the least-cost the pre
convergence least cost path from the PLR
to the repair node
so let's take a look at the exact same
topology we had a couple slides back
this is the topology in which LFA would
not work because you know the metric
between r3 and r4 had been elevated to
three so again our LFA is protecting
link R 2 R 5 that's the link highlighted
in yellow are two calculates its least
cost path to r7 and it's still through R
2 R 5 and it installs that as the
primary now r2 identifies a repair node
this time R 3 is not the repair node R 4
is um and you'll notice our 4 isn't
directly connected to R to the PLR and
the repair node aren't directly
connected so R 2 has to create a tunnel
to the repair node and this tunnel
follows the IGP least cost path from the
PLR to the repair node and then it
installs that tunnel of the PLR our two
installs that tunnel as a backup route
to r7 now what are the requirements for
a repair node this part of the talk is
gonna sound a little scary because I'm
going to start throwing P's and Q's
around but it's really not that complex
so try to hang with me the repair node
has to be in the PQ space now what's the
PQ space the PQ space is the
intersection of the PLR SP space and the
destinations Q space so we're going to
define two things the PLR is going to
have a set of four errors in the and the
P space the destination is going to have
a set of routers in the queue space and
any node that is in both sets is in the
PQ space now what is in the plra P space
the PLR SP space contains nodes that it
can reach in its pre converging state
without traversing the protected link so
in this example are two in its pre
convergence State can reach R 3 R 4 R 6
and r8
um along the pre-computed along the
least-cost path without traversing the
protected link you'll notice that it
can't reach our five our five is not in
our twos peace pace and the reason why
is our twos least-cost path to our five
is through our to our five and that's
the protected link so it's just not
there now the next thing we have to
understand is the destinations queue
space what's that the destinations queue
space contains the nodes that uh that
can reach the destination and their pre
converging state without protecting the
without traversing the protected link
and in that space we have our five r4 r5
r6 r7 and r8 um you'll see that our
three isn't in that space if the
destination wanted to reach our three it
would go through the protected link so
now we're looking for nodes that are in
both the P and the Q space and the
intersection is our for our six and our
eight
so our for our six and r8 are all
candidates for being the repair node and
in this case we pick our four is the
repair node the reason why is it's
closest to our two also it's going to
illustrate a nice little point in a
minute so what happens after the break
um the link breaks and becomes unusable
our to start sending traffic destined
for r7 through the backup route that is
to our for our four releases packets
from the tunnel and sends it to r7 now
let's take a look at our four is passed
to r7 you'll see that it has two week
will cost multi paths one goes through
our six and r8 the other goes through r6
and r5 and both are leveraged because
this is just an IP packet and it's going
to do the load balancing the way IP does
now let's talk about node protection for
a while the difference between link
protection and node protection is what
is protected and the previous slide you
saw the link between r2 and r5
highlighted in yellow that meant we were
worried about it breaking now our five
is highlighted in yellow so what does
that mean
when r2 detects link are two or five is
down it assumes that the reason for that
outage is that r5 itself is down
and if r5 itself is down all of the
links connected to our five are also
down so in the case of node protection
r2 not only wants to avoid link are two
r5 but it needs to avoid our v r6 and
our v r7 all of the nodes connected to
our five so what does it do um again it
calculates its least cost path through
our to r5 then it identifies a repair
node but this time it can't identify our
four because if our four with a repair
node and the traffic were released at
our for our six would send it across the
equal cost multi path and you you
traverse r5 so in this case there is
only one candidate to be the repair node
that's our eight so instead of building
a tunnel from R to R for this time we
build a tunnel from R 1 to R 8 when the
link breaks packets go along that tunnel
r 8 the repair node releases packets
from the tunnel and r8 Ford's it along
the one and only path to r7 and that's
through our eight or seven now in node
protection what are the requirement what
are the requirements to be a repair node
um the repair node has to be in PQ space
that is it still has to be in the
intersection of the PLR SP space in the
destinations Q space um here's the
difference the PLR SP space contains
nodes that it can reach in its pre
converging state without traversing the
protected node so
um here the P space is R 3 R 4 R 6 + r8
the destinations q space contains nodes
that it can reach of the destination in
their brief convergence state without
traversing the protected node and here
only seven or eight are in the queue
space and this is because of that IPC
ecmp so here only r8 is a candidate for
the PQ space so we're starting to feel
pretty secure now we think that we have
well things well in hand you know using
tunnels you expand the number of
candidates you have has repair nodes and
you get better coverage but you don't
get 100% coverage here I've tweaked the
IGP um metric on this link one more time
first time you saw the metric it was set
to one second time you saw it it was set
to three this time it's set to seven um
and this example again r2 protects LFA
protects the link r2 are five and the
IGP metric associated with our four hour
six has been cranked up to seven now our
two SP space only uh contains only node
r3 um
because the IGP metric from R 3 to R 4
is so high that path through R 3
basically is the least cost path to know
where's the least cost path to almost
every place is through the broken link R
2 R 5 so the P space has only R 3 in it
the Q space still contains r2 r4 and r5
and the PQ space is empty so in this
topology r2 can't find a repair node for
r7 and you just can't get 100% 100%
coverage in in this topology now really
the problem is in our LFA the repair
tunnel the tunnel that connects the PLR
to the repair node follows the pre
convergence IGP least cost path wouldn't
it be nice if you could have a repair
tunnel that's traffic engineered it
follows any path you like so now the P
space gets very large in fact the P
space would include every node in the in
the domain and this is exactly what you
get with TI LF a topology independent
loop free alternates
okay um we already talked about our
elephant limitations the fact that you
can't get a repair note for all you
can't get a repair note for all
typologies so let's talk about how tal
fa works in this application TI LFA is
protecting our two or five again the
same link again our two calculates the
least cost path to our seven and it's
going through our to our five so it
installs that as its primary link now it
identifies a repair tunnel and in this
case
can pick our four is the repair tunnel
because so long as our two can get the
packet past our three into our for our
four can release the packet from the
tunnel and it will get the rest of the
way to our seven notice that this repair
tunnel doesn't follow the least-cost
path from our to to our for the least
cost path from r2 to r4 is through r5
and r6 across the broken link so this is
a traffic engineered repair tunnel um
the way this repair tunnel works is r2
pushes an SR MPLS label onto a stack and
forwards the packet to r3 r3 pops that
label off and that label is an
instruction the instruction says for
this packet along the length r3 r4 send
it to our for whether or not that is the
least cost path to r4 and that solves
your problem now you can deliver the
packet to r4 which is a perfectly good
repair node um even though our three is
not on the least-cost path from R 2 to R
4 now P are two installs this tunnel as
a backup route and you'll see that it
gets used with the link brakes
now what are the reason uh what are the
requirements for a repair nord when
we're doing PIL F a link protection well
the repair node has to reside in the
destination nodes Q space that's to say
the destined no destination node can
reach it and it's pre convergent state
without traversing of the protecting a
protected link so nodes four or five six
seven and eight are all in sevens Q
space um
notice there's no real requirement about
P space because because this is a
traffic engineered tunnel r2 can reach
every single note on this router under
than this topology
without traversing r2 are five now in
this case we choose our four because
it's the closest to the PLR
so what happens after the link after the
link breaks are to realizes the links
broken um so would start sending pack
packets along the backup path it pushes
labeled 1010 Ford's the packet to r3 r3
pops the label forwards the packet to
our for our for sends it the rest of the
way along the path and again our six
leverages that a CMP between our five
between our six and our seven so there's
one path through our five and other
through our a and our six will use those
now
let's talk about node protection we also
have node protection in TI l fa and TI l
fa here the link isn't protected it
snowed r5 that's protected so when are
to realizes that the link to r5 is
broken it assumes that the reason for
this is that our v is broken and all of
the links that are 5 connects to are
also broken so now you do not want r6 to
be exercising that ecmp to r7 you don't
want it sending traffic to our 5 so your
choice of repair tunnels changes you
don't want to use our four as a repair
tunnel because it would send traffic to
our 6 that would leverage the ecmp you
don't want to use our of 6 as a repair
tunnel as it would leverage the ecmp
you want to use our 8 as the repair
tunnel so what does this repair tunnel
look like well our two creates a repair
tunnel to the repair node node the
repair tunnel has an outgoing PLR
interface that's the interface to r3 and
it has a list of adjacency segments MPLA
that it has a repair list and the
adjacency segment 10 10 that begins on
10th r3 and ends on r4 so what what
happens in this r2 pushes the label 2010
and then the label 10 10 and forwards
the packet to r3 r3 pops the label 10 10
and that label causes it to Ford the
packet to r4 r r4
you
forwards the packet all the way to our
sex and it does this because of label
2020 our eight receives the packet pop
pops label 2020 and forwards the packet
the rest of the way so what you see here
is this repair tunnel the Green Line it
didn't follow the ITP least-cost path
from R 2 to R 4 um but it was traffic
engineered in such a way that it pushed
past the the the nodes that would have
otherwise had to go through a node
protection what are the requirements for
the repair node the repair node must
reside in the destinations cube space
same as before and that means the
destination has to be able to reach the
repair node what in its pre convergent
state without traversing the protected
link so our sevinor and r8 are in the
queue space r4 and r6 aren't in the
queue space because of the ecmp to r7
and in this case we chose our 8 as the
repair node ELR we could have actually
chosen r7 itself as the repair node
and here's an example of what happens
after the break this is exactly what I
talked about a couple slides back are
two pushes to labels on the packet and
sends it through the repair tunnel to RA
so wrapping up with some conclusions TI
LFA is a fairly simple mechanism that
can protect all nodes and links in all
network topologies and for this reason
we say that T il FA provides 100%
coverage TI LFA is powerful enough to
the motivate network operators to deploy
SR there are many network operators who
want their traffic to traverse the
least-cost path from source source to
destination they don't want to do any
traffic engineering at all what they do
want FR r and fr are gives them 100%
coverage in any network topology so they
deploy segment routing not because they
want the traffic engineer their normal
traffic but because they want the
traffic engineer their repair paths well
that's it and I'll open to questions now
thank you very much Ron now we have
three questions for you so far if
anybody else wants to get a question
real quick please submit it now I'll get
to it of your time so the first question
is while doing segment routing traffic
engineering if the explicit note is
failed does TI LFA have a mechanism to
protect the node failure okay so first
let's make sure I understand the
question the protected node is the
endpoint of AV prefix Ted hood said the
protected node appears to be down I
think the answer is that the behavior is
configurable one possible behavior as
you drop the packet because you cannot
get to the protected notice down another
is that you just go to the next node I'm
gonna have to check on that and see if
our implementation actually does both
what I believe the behavior should be
configurable all right the next question
is for the LFA flavors each node has to
compute LFA for every other node in the
network yes it did not know that there's
not that computation loads get very
large yes it is computationally
expensive and to reduce the expense
there are some optimizations you might
pick a repair node that is suboptimal
but good enough to reduce the amount of
up optimization there are other things
that you can do even in a fairly
complicated network we found that we can
do good enough computations pretty
quickly alright and next question is
what is your opinion about the future of
protecting srte policies by TI LFA on
transit nodes okay protecting TI LFA
policies on transit nodes let's say and
we are talking about in SRM pls it says
srte policies by okay in that case we're
probably talking about SRM pls and yes
it can be done on a transit node
let's say well first of all TI LFA is
all about prefix and node segments let's
say you're in the middle of a node
segment and you realize the link is down
and you need a way to get to the segment
endpoint um it's exactly as it was
described in there and the slides what
you do is push a few more labels that
get you to the repair node and once you
know the repair node might be a segment
endpoint that might be a node on the
path to the segment endpoint but neither
event you're gonna get there and the
repair path the the labels that
represent the repair path will go away
and you'll continue routing the packet
on its merry way to the segment endpoint
all right thank you very much I do
apologize to all the questions that we
have for another time but sure Ron would
be perfectly happy to talk to you and I
list or by some other mechanism please
feel free don't you know yeah again
thank you very much and that concludes
our current session the next talk is the
5g QuickStart
[Music]
you