greetings people in front of the chaos
to West stage welcome to the next talk
maybe you have the time to just fragment
a little bit as you know from the other
talks this by the way is what is this ah
self organized sessions so if you have a
topic or kink or something you really
really want to talk about feel free
contact me or my team actually the team
and me we do have a few slots and we are
looking forward to set you up give you a
little stage for your project and
everything then
the next talk is about bisque it is a
decentralized Bitcoin exchange and the
man to my right who is a little stressed
has an a great name
his name is Chris beams like laser beams
it's gonna be a good talk amazing I love
that okay hello everybody so we're gonna
talk about bisque one moment there we go
I'm gonna talk about bisque which is a
decentralized Bitcoin exchange that's me
I'm a co-founder of the project along
with Manfred carer who's in the audience
here today as well let's say a little
bit about what bisque is first bisque is
a decentralized peer-to-peer Bitcoin
exchange it's best described as follows
in terms of its major component parts
which is one bisque is a cross-platform
desktop application it allows anybody to
buy and sell Bitcoin in exchange for
national currencies right that's
something that not many exchanges do
that are decentralized for national
currencies and other crypto currencies
to bisque is a trading protocol and it
enables individuals to exchange directly
with one another over the Internet
eliminating the need for trusted third
parties to be in the middle of exchange
transactions third bisque is the
peer-to-peer network formed by all of
these biscuits all these bisque clients
working together connecting with each
other
implementing the bisque trading protocol
with one another the bisque network is
fully peer-to-peer in that it requires
no centrally controlled servers and it
has no central points of failure so
bisque is a desktop application a
trading protocol and appear to peer
network that all work together to form a
decentralized Bitcoin exchange bisque is
a GPL license so it's free software free
software for free people
so let's talk about why we built it why
does this exist our mission is to
provide a secure private and censorship
resistant way to exchange Bitcoin for
national currencies and other
cryptocurrencies when we say secure
we're talking about the safety of your
funds today most Bitcoin exchanges that
you use are centralized that requires
people to store their bitcoins on
centralized services servers putting
those bitcoins at risk and even if
you're doing this just for some short
amount of time just as long as it takes
to trade and then withdraw your funds
thousands of people are doing that at
the same time and that creates extreme
incentives for those servers to be
hacked and for those bitcoins to be
stolen and this is exactly what happens
time and time again the beatings have
and will continue so long as people
continue to do it wrong right
this is antithetical to the way Bitcoin
works these hacks are tens of thousands
of dollars worth of Bitcoin hundreds of
thousands sometimes hundreds of millions
of dollars worth of Bitcoin like in the
very famous case of Mount GOx
incidentally not incidentally not
coincidentally bisques first prototype
showed up just a few weeks after mount
cox failure so security right privacy
when we say private we're talking about
users ability to control access to their
own information so today most of those
same centralized exchanges require users
to divulge personally identifying
information in order to set up an
account and then they in turn link that
data link that data about users about
you with your trading activity this
practice creates extreme risks - in that
your personal details and sensitive
financial information can be stolen
leaked or otherwise used against your
own best interests we don't have to look
any further than recent news right you
know not Bitcoin related but we probably
have all heard about Equifax literally
half of all of the people in the United
State
more than half of the adults being you
know doxed right 143 million people's
personal data very sensitive personal
data being being hacked at Equifax right
literally every single yahoo account was
hacked recently and this one
people who know Bitcoin will know well
you know the IRS the financial agency in
the u.s. came to coinbase a couple of
years ago and said basically we'd like
all of your data about all of your users
and that's not good for them it's not
good for users right so secure private
censorship resistant so when we say
censorship resistant we're referring to
users ability to voluntarily trade with
one another without interference from
any third party today
centralized Bitcoin exchanges are highly
susceptible to that censorship by their
nature they have to operate in one legal
jurisdiction or another that puts them
at risk of being fined or shut down if
they don't comply with the laws and
rules of that jurisdiction which may
include and usually do include
restrictions on who can trade what can
be traded and almost always include
requirements to collect personal
information as I described above so
these are bank secrecy laws any money
laundering laws no your customer laws
these are almost ubiquitous in this
means that when you're signing up for
these centralized exchanges to exchange
Bitcoin you're having to give copies of
your passport your electricity bill all
kinds of sensitive information that does
you no good to share so and again we
have to don't have to look any further
than you know recent news and in Bitcoin
this year many people have probably are
probably familiar with the stories of
China shutting down banning exchanges
all kinds of madness right so so
governments can do this they can they
will this is the kind of censorship that
we're talking about and this is why we
built this the way that we built it
right the only way to achieve all of
these properties I'm talking about
secure private and censorship resistant
is to be decentralized right we don't
build things decentralized just to do it
that's way harder than building things
centralized right this is all for a
reason
so let's talk about how bisque works
here it is in a nutshell let's just
imagine a scenario you want to buy some
Bitcoin right and you want to do it in
exchange for euros let's say so in this
terminology you're a buyer of Bitcoin
looking for a seller of Bitcoin who will
accept your euros as payments so to
complete such a trade using bisque you'd
follow a series of steps similar to the
following first you download it right so
you go to our website you download
bisque you install it and you'd run it
just like any other application that
you'd run on your on your desktop right
the second thing is you configure bisque
with your euro payment account details
now this might look antithetical to what
I just said here you are typing in
personal information information about
your bank accounts well keep in mind
this information isn't going anywhere
this lives locally only in bisque until
the time that you choose to take a trade
with some particular County counterparty
then and only then is this information
shared with that counterparty so that
you to purely peer-to-peer can settle
that trade with one another so the third
thing is that you'd then go look through
bisques offer book and you'd see well
what existing offers are out there it's
a sell Bitcoin you want to buy it so
who's who's out there that already wants
to sell and maybe you find an offer that
you like and if you don't find an offer
that you like then you could create your
own but in this scenario let's imagine
that we take someone's existing offer to
sell okay so you take it and you agree
in this case to by 0.1 BTC write 0.1
bitcoins from the seller in exchange for
about 1200 of your own euros the next
steps are that bisque is going to
orchestrate or coordinate the process of
you the buyer and your counterparty the
seller working together to go through a
manual process right bisque is
integrating with essentially a legacy
set of systems
see banking systems if you like to think
about it that way and they're not very
modern it's not easy to automate sending
euros through a banking system means
you're gonna have to log into your
banking website and click buttons right
so bisque is gonna help orchestrate that
process but bisque isn't going to do it
itself so this is what we mean when we
say that payments happen out of band
right or out of system from bisque
but bisque helps orchestrate it so you
can see that process here waiting for
blockchain confirmation that's going to
be your deposit transaction with Bitcoin
the Bitcoin being traded and your
security deposits from both buyer and
seller we'll talk more about that in a
second so check that's done you maybe
wait ten minutes for that to start
payments so that's bisque telling you
the buyer go to your banking website log
in and send 1200 euros to this I
bandwidth this first and last name
you've gotten just enough information
about your counterparty to settle this
trade right so you do that and then you
wait right because banks are slow much
much much slower than blockchain so much
much slower than Bitcoin right might
take depending on the payment method it
might take an hour or a day or even a
few days for say a say per transfer like
we're talking about here okay and then
the next thing is that the seller does
receive your your payments and on the
sellers side in their bisque client they
click a button that says I received the
payment right then on your side you're
gonna see a notification from disk
saying okay
the trade is complete the seller got the
funds you two have worked together to
release the Bitcoin to you the buyer
we'll talk a little bit more about how
that happens in a second and the trade
is finished and you can withdraw those
bitcoins to a different wallet or you
can leave it in bisque bisque is also a
complete wallet so that's an overview of
the process but let's break that down a
little bit and talk about how trading
with bisque is is different than other
forms of trading Bitcoin so the first
thing is that there's no automatic order
matching right when you use a
centralized exchange you typically say I
want to buy this much Bitcoin
and it instantly instantly happens your
account is credited with that Bitcoin
the fiat side of your accounts that that
exchange is debited for that amount and
the reason that that's possible is
because of automatic order matching that
centralized service is providing a lot
of value right centralized Bitcoin
exchanges are really convenient and
really nice but they're doing that
because they're managing that that offer
book or that order book in a centralized
way so bisk doesn't work that way right
it's purely peer-to-peer you're looking
for some particular persons offer to
sell or they're gonna take your offer to
buy or whatever it is so no automatic
order matching the best protocol like I
mentioned coordinates out-of-band fiat
payments so like I said you're gonna
have to go log into your banking website
or whatever other payment method you two
have agreed on and ultimately settlement
like what it takes to complete the trade
that's what I mean by settlement it
takes longer with bisque that's
different but in return the trade-off
that you're making is that it's a far
more secure far more private and far
more censorship resistant way to
complete that trade so if that's
attractive to you you would want to use
bisque right if you're a day trader
who's trading 5 10 15 20 times a day
bisque wouldn't be a very friendly
platform for you you would want to use
something centralized probably but if
you're trying to get in or trying to get
out of Bitcoin if you're trying to get
into Bitcoin for the first time say
right this would be a very attractive
platform for people who are privacy
conscious okay so how does bisque
actually fulfill these things how does
this keep your funds secure well the
first is that bisque is entirely
non-custodial what does that mean it
means we never ever hold on to your
funds this is like the prime directive
this is like rule number one in Bitcoin
if you don't have the keys you don't
have the Bitcoin right you never ever
ever give your bitcoin away to somebody
else to a trusted third party so bisque
doesn't violate that centralized
exchanges do bisque respects this
important part of sort of bitcoins
philosophy if bitcoins motto is be your
own bank then bisques motto is be your
own exchange
right and that means you've got to hold
on to your funds the whole time and
never is it in our control right the
second thing is security deposits from
both buyer and seller so both buyer and
seller are going to put in a little bit
of Bitcoin in addition to the Bitcoin
actually being traded as a way of
ensuring that if something that nobody
acts badly right we can talk more about
that in a second to those security
deposits along with the Bitcoin being
traded or locked away in a multi
signature transaction on the Bitcoin
blockchain which some will have heard of
that might be new to people but if
you're familiar with the idea of escrow
like when you buy a house you make this
very expensive purchase and you don't
trust the person that you're buying the
house from to just hold the hundreds of
thousands of euros so you put that with
an escrow company usually right a
trusted third party well one thing that
blockchain technology and Bitcoin in
particular makes possible that wasn't
really possible before is the idea of
trustless escrow so we put that we
bisque helps coordinating putting the
Bitcoin being traded and those security
deposits away in a so-called deposit
transaction that requires multiple
signatures signatures from you the buyer
and the seller in order to spend that
Bitcoin out so that that those funds
those that deposit transaction is going
to remain locked away in that multi-sig
transaction until the seller clicks that
button that says I got I got the euros
and when he clicks that button the two
bits clients are going to work together
to sign out that deposit transaction
that's a little technical right but the
point is your funds are never in the
control of a third party the only place
that they're ever living is either in
your bist clients or safely locked away
on the Bitcoin blockchain the final
thing is that this concludes a
decentralized arbitration system as well
right it's one thing to design a system
like this you know so far we've gone
through the happy path right what what
it looks like when it goes well but what
happens if a mistake was made along the
way what if what if you as the buyer
sent the wrong amount to the seller or
you
you accidentally wrote the wrong name in
the payment details or you sent it to
the wrong I banner you sent it too late
or you never sent it at all right what
if the seller never clicks that button
that says I got your money even though
you sent the money right so all kinds of
mistakes can happen and of course there
can also be bad actors in a system like
this so these are the kinds of things
that no amount of code can really solve
so we have to have human arbitration in
a system like this and that's why
biscayne incorporates a complete
decentralized arbitration system as well
to handle disputes okay so that's how
bisque helps keep your funds secure
right how does bisque help keep your
data private well the first thing is
that there's no registration there's no
identity verification like I explained
before you won't have to be sending
anybody photos of your passport with
bisque second is that every bisque
application every client is a tor hidden
service so for most people most people
probably haven't run out tor hidden
service probably a disproportionately
large number of people here have but
most people will never actually
experience running a tor hidden service
but with bisque it's just out of the box
box it works right and there's no
central servers or databases that we're
maintaining that record any data we
couldn't record it if we tried because
everything is quite private again it's
just between you and your counterparty
when you agree to settle a trade with
each other in order to take a trade with
each other okay so how does bisque help
you resist censorship right or how is
bisque censorship resistant well the
first thing is that we're dealing with a
fully decentralized even a fully
distributed peer-to-peer network right
again every single person on the best
network is running that clients so
that's a fully distributed peer-to-peer
network and that's on its own pretty
hard to shut down right that's the
nature of of these kinds of networks the
second thing is that bisque inherits in
a way tors
own censorship resistant resistance
right because everybody's running a tor
hidden service running on top of tor we
inherit all the benefits of
you inherit all the benefits of that and
the third thing is that bisque isn't
structured as a company or other kind of
legal entity it's not a foundation it's
not a fair I know it's none of that
it's just code so bisque is just code
that individual people are choosing to
run and we know by precedent from things
like BitTorrent say that's pretty hard
to shut down so far code isn't illegal
right and it's up to all of us to keep
it that way and the way we keep it that
way is by claiming our rights and
running code like this so where are we
right what's the current status of this
it's been in production since April of
2016 we've been developing it like I
said since basically just after Mount
GOx failed so that's already almost four
years in development it took about two
two and a half years to develop and test
it completely before we were comfortable
going live on bitcoins main net or the
main Bitcoin blockchain but we did that
in April of 2016 so that's about 20
months ago as I speak and there there
are you just looking at that's the
monthly charts of you know how much
Bitcoin moved through the network and
there's 20 bars there right so 20 months
of Biskind production so far and during
that time we've processed thousands of
trades worth millions of dollars of
Bitcoin rights or the dollar value of
Bitcoin if you measure it that way and
we've had no downtime and we've had no
major incidents so bisk is still small
very small by comparison to the biggest
centralized exchanges out there in the
world but we've been growing steadily
and this chart is showing you again the
US dollar value of all the Bitcoin
that's moved through the exchange at the
current you know exchange rate for
Bitcoin to US dollars so if you look at
the left side there in April of 2016 we
did about $30,000 worth of Bitcoin
trading otherwise known as nothing by
comparison to big exchanges right but
you see that trend line moving through
it we
doubled that that volume about every
three and a half to four months since
April of 2016 and that's you know if
that's actually an exponential curve and
we've been tracking to that curve pretty
well this chart that you're looking at
is up-to-date as of September this is
the chart from the last two months so
the fully accurate chart this last month
was a pretty wild ride we went from
doing about you know $500,000 months to
doing $500,000 days all of a sudden and
that's due to a few reasons but the
biggest reason is just everything that's
been going on in Bitcoin lands so if you
follow this space you've probably heard
about how most if not all of the major
centralized exchanges have just been
totally overwhelmed by you know the the
influx of new users and so on just
crumbling under the under the load of
you know even even shutting down new
user accounts and so on turning people
away well we got a little a little taste
of that fortunately we didn't shut it
shut anything down we didn't turn
anybody away we were actually able to do
quite a bit of trading even though it
was pretty intense and so so let's talk
about how bisque is funded right how do
we keep this whole thing running it's
free software right like you know both
free as in beer and free as in speech
you can just download and run bisque and
obviously it's you know a GPL licensed
but actually trading on this does cost
something right so we charge trading
fees and where those trading fees go are
directly to the arbitrator's right so
one way to think about what you're
paying for when you pay to trade on
bisque is you're paying for the security
that those arbitrators provide even if
the arbitrator doesn't have anything to
do with that particular trade even if
your trade is a kind of happy path trade
you never would have engaged in that
trade in the first place if you didn't
have the reassurance knowing that
there's an arbitrator there if something
does go wrong so that's the kind of
value model behind our trading fees and
those fees have averaged about one
Bitcoin per month and
up until this last month or so that
wasn't enough to pay the bills over the
last month the price has gone up so high
that actually could start to pay the
bills but primarily it's been funded out
of pocket you know we've been growing
and and and making a bit more money as
we go but it hasn't been enough maybe
we're starting to turn that corner now
but the problem is that there's been no
decentralized way to compensate all the
other contributors that that do all of
the other things with bisque right all
of the coding all of the you know
monitoring I or C and Reddit and you
know updating documentation and all of
the things that aren't arbitration
there's been no clear way to compensate
those those contributors in a
decentralized way and I'm mentioning
that here because I'm going to talk in a
moment about the bisque Dow right so
more on that in a moment but these are
some of the issues that we're currently
dealing with and then we've designed
solutions to but that are in the process
of being rolled out so that's funding
right so how is this governed
how has bisque been governed so far
right again this is all changing right
now but up until very recently it's been
a small team of contributors it's been
centralized maintenance arbitrate excuse
me administration and operation what
does that mean it just means that small
group of developers and contributors are
the ones that are responsible for all
the code changes and so on the founders
have primarily been the key
decision-makers right and there's just a
couple of founders so that's already
quite a bit of centralization right
these are all risks when it comes to
censorship resistance right when you
have centralization of decision-making
and funding and so on that makes you
weak with regard to censorship
resistance so that's why it's so
important for us to solve this problem
and so you can think about it this way
right bisques technology is
decentralized really quite well
decentralized but bisques governance
hasn't been so far this bisques
government governance is largely largely
been centralized
so where are we in the mission that I
talked about earlier then I said our
mission is to is to provide secure
private censorship resistance way you
know to exchange Bitcoin for for
national and crypto currencies well I
think it's roughly safe to check the box
on secure and private right this is
never perfect it can always be better
but we think we've done a pretty good
job of that certainly better than the
alternatives that are out there but with
regard to censorship resistance like I
say there's work to be done so the the
peer-to-peer network over tor right that
goes a long way towards censorship
resistance that's great but
decentralized funding up until very
recently we hadn't made a lot of
progress in that and decentralized
governance we hadn't made a lot of
progress in that so what we need now and
what we're up to now is continued
trading volume growth right if a growing
number of people don't continue to use
bisk
then it'll probably never become
economically viable right it'll always
be a very tiny just open source project
kind of struggling to get by but the
good news is you've seen that trend line
it seems to be going pretty well the
second thing and this is really the most
important thing especially to an
audience like this is to scale up
contributions right scale up the group
of people that are contributing to bisk
working on bisk working with us through
github and you know sort of all of the
normal state-of-the-art tools in order
to obviously improve bisk but to help
continuing fostering that growth right
the bisque that we have today wouldn't
be able to scale up 10x 100x right if
for no other reason then we only have a
handful of arbitrators right now so we
need more people who can do arbitration
for example in order to really really
scale up you know to kind of the level
anything near centralized exchanges like
we know them today we need a
decentralized compensation model to
incentivize all those other contributors
that I just talked about and we need a
decentralized responsibility model
to avoid censorship right so if there's
just one or two heads to cut off then
there's a decent risk that they will be
cut off but if there's a whole bunch of
people that are responsible for you know
all the pieces and parts of what it
means to operate and administer and
maintain bisque and its network then
that's a whole lot harder to shutdown so
we have under the DAO right which I'm
going to explain in just a moment our
governance becomes decentralized -
that's the idea so what is the bisque
Dao how many people have heard of this
term Dao yeah okay that's like
approaching 1/2 for those that don't
know it stands for decentralized
autonomous organization and this is this
is an emerging concept in the in the
kind of crypto space right you can think
of it as what happens to the idea of
corporations when you have things like
cryptocurrency in the mix we start to
see a kind of new economic entity start
to show up corporations we're and we're
an innovation three or four hundred
years ago we may now have a new kind of
innovation in how to organize ourselves
and how to structure ourselves to work
together effectively and the idea of a
Dao is the kind of leading set of ideas
around that so this talk that I'm giving
here is a modified version of a longer
talk that I gave some months ago in in
Prague and so there's a number of slides
here that I'm going to move through
pretty quickly because I want to make
sure that there's time for for questions
and we just have about 10 more minutes
but for those that are interested right
you've now seen the overview of bisk why
it exists what it's for a little bit
about how it feels to use it what I'm
going to talk about now is a very quick
overview of the Dow it'll be a little
bit like kind of breakneck pace but if
you want to find out more there will be
a link at the end of this to a paper
that we call phase zero a plan for
bootstrapping the BIST down if you want
to dig into that that's a that's a great
read and you can find out all about it
and then you can come come talk to us
about it and hopefully contribute and
participate but in any case how this Dow
works is we introduce a new token
and we call bsq which is kind of like
our name B is Q's disks name but BS Q is
a token that's designed to facilitate a
transfer of value from traders ie users
of the platform people who find bisque
valuable bisque bsq is designed to
transfer value from traders who use
bisque to the contributors who are
maintaining it and the way that bisque
works that bsq works is that the 25
Bitcoin that supporters have donated to
the project since its inception right
four years ago we distribute those 25
Bitcoin to all of the past contributors
by cutting up the Bitcoin into tiny
pieces
a thousand Satoshi's large it's a very
small amounts of Bitcoin and the way the
math works out there is we turn 25
Bitcoin into 2.5 million bsq we then
distribute those two point five million
bsq to all of the past contributors like
I say whoever helped bisque you know
come into existence and and be the
project that it is today this this
process is called this idea of bsq it's
a colored coin and some of me some may
have heard of this that's very different
than the tokens and kind of ICO stuff
that we see today so commonly a colored
coin in the colored coin on top of
Bitcoin actually is Bitcoin but with
additional validation rules additional
things being possible with that coin so
again I won't go into a lot of detail
but it's very important to say that this
is not an ICO there is no crowd sale
there is no pre mind there is no
crowdfunding none of that stuff we
simply don't need it so again it's a
token designed to facilitate a transfer
of value between the traders who use
bisque and the contributors who maintain
it and I'll just very quickly click
through this again I want to be able to
take questions let's see the main
problem is
that the flow of funds goes only to
arbitrators like I talked about and
there's no way to compensate
contributors in a decentralized way
right now so that's where bsq comes in
and we have five functions or utilities
of this token and the first one is
trading right people can trade bsq like
if you're you know you can trade it for
dollars or euros or what or Bitcoin
right on bisque of course that's where
you can trade it the second function is
spending it
people spend bsq on trading fees right
so as I explained before you pay in
Bitcoin today for trading fees as we
enable this functionality you'll be able
to pay for those same trading fees at a
discounted rate with bsq which gives
traders an incentive to hold on to it or
it's a or to buy it in the first place
the third function is earning right so
contributors submit what we call
compensation requests for a given amount
of bsq to compensate them for whatever
they did that month and the fourth
function is voting so people who already
have bsq use that bsq as a kind of
voting chip that's the fourth function
of the token and they use that voting to
green-light
or to reject compensation requests so
stakeholders decide who gets new bsq and
the fifth function is bonding so for
roles in the Dow that are inherently
high trust right something like an
arbitrator that's a very high trust role
a bad actor arbitrator could wreak
terrible havoc on bisque and its network
so we have so the fifth function of BS Q
is that high trust roles can bond in BS
q can put up a very large amount of BS q
and that BS q can be confiscated if that
arbitrators say or other kind of bonded
contributor trusted role if they act
badly
okay so again a whole lot here that I'm
moving very quickly through that you can
find it all in the paper and I'll skip
the bid on issuance and destruction even
though it's my favorite slide in this
whole thing no time to talk about it
okay so let me leave it at that you can
find again all of this is in the paper
this is adapted directly from the paper
that I mentioned and let me just go to
this last slide where you can find out
more so we're bisk underscore network on
twitter i'm c-beams on twitter and of
course you can download it if you want
to join us in slack come hang out talk
to us about anything you like there's an
there's a link for that the phase zero
paper is that link so just bisque dot
Network slash phase - zero and of course
we're on github at bisque - network so
that's I think we have five maybe ten
minutes five minutes okay yeah so booth
the first what's with
ken users to find their own settlement
times like four SEPA for example you
have about eight business days of
reversal risk and I saw like on your
example like five days of settlement
time which is not enough to excluded
reversal risk yeah so the the I think
the question is about how long is the
kind of window for settling a trade no
but I can actually sit in my offer as a
seller can you set it yes No
yeah so so in the if you if you caught
it in the in the slide that I was
showing for say portrayed x' there's a
number of days that you have right to
settle the trade that's fixed so the
seller can't specify that but it's fixed
at you know five days or whatever it is
simply because that's what we found
works well over time the internal CPA
regulations say it's eight days business
days yeah yeah yeah we're not following
that it's a pragmatic approach where
we're saying if we set it at this many
days we never have problems if we
started having problems then we'd extend
it so yeah
thank you I have a couple of questions
so yeah I didn't really understand if
you do crypto to crypto as well we do
yeah so so I focused on talking about
crypto Fiat right or a Bitcoin to u.s.
dollars Bitcoin the Euro that kind of
that kind of trading because that's
really the core of Bitcoin like the
really the core of the mission is to
give people there has to be one good
on-ramp into Bitcoin from the fiat world
and that really doesn't exist today that
the only thing you can do is go to a
Satoshi square or have a friend or a
family member who already has Bitcoin if
you do that if you do something like in
person like that then you can have a
reasonably good sort of privacy and
security profile in that initial trade
to get into Bitcoin but there has been
no good way to do that online and so
that's really why bisque exists but once
we had done that then it was pretty easy
to add in crypto to crypto trading as
well because if you think about it like
I said payment settling the payment
happens out-of-band right so you're
going to your bank website and so on
well that's for a Bitcoin to euro trade
well if you want to do a Bitcoin to
Manero trade Manero is really just a
different payment method right so you're
gonna settle the Monaro side outside
out-of-band from disk as well so that's
kind of a good way to think about it but
the the constraint there is that one
side of every trade is Bitcoin so you
know go I had someone asked me today
about doing a you know an ether to doge
doge coin trade on bisque and that's not
supported it would be a two-step process
right to go from doge to bitcoin bitcoin
to ether or something like that okay so
if i wanted to sell some PRC 20 token i
cannot just go and list it there unless
I accept fiat no well so there's two
things so if you wanted to sell an ER C
20 toke and if the question is is that
already a listed token on bisque the
tokens anybody who issues a pull request
okay so you have to issue a correct pull
request and will always merge it so
anybody can add a token and people do
that all the time so that's it yeah okay
as a seller is there a way for me to
automate confirmations through some kind
of API from my bank if I'm selling like
larger volumes so I don't have to go and
confirm manually in bisque that yes I
receive the money to my account is there
some way so we so this does have an API
that can automate a lot of things but
there's not we don't have we don't have
a second you gotta take the mic away
from there man but we don't have we
don't have you know sort of like
bindings into all the different banks
and stuff like that again mostly they
don't have api's to do it but even if
they do we don't have that support that
could be something that somebody
contributes for banks that do support
automated access but we don't have it
yet anybody else yeah
hey great talk question you in your
paper you use the term bonding it says
is it some kind of stake mechanism the
term
bonding bonding yeah is it some kind of
stake or is it something else or so yeah
so the question is when I use the word
bonding with bsq for these high trust
roles under the bisque Dow do I mean
like steak or staking or having
something at stake that's that's another
term in the industry that people use is
staking yes I mean the same thing
we call it bonding because there's a
long history of you know say plumbers
guild well you know bonded plumbers
right or bonded taxi drivers or whatever
it is that's a common term of art and
the second thing is it's a reserved word
for us because we have stakeholders
people who hold bsq are our stakeholders
so we didn't want to confuse
stakeholders with staking yeah same
thing though okay thank you very much
I'll be around at the Bitcoin table so
happy to answer questions
Chris beam I'm so sorry Chris beam
season Perl I'm so sorry - no more
questions out of time the next talk
starts in five minutes but where can all
these wonderful people find you and
touch you with more questions yeah so
biscuit network is a website disk
underscore network on Twitter and I'll
be at the bitcoin table pretty much all
conference so okay guys you know
Thanks