see for okay ladies and gentlemen
welcome back to the Kaos West stage this
is here it's the stage for
self-organized sessions and I'm amazing
beautiful smart great people whole talks
here such as these two and it is my
honor and pleasure to leave the stage to
Astro and Moffat osh thank you I am
Astro
this talk will include a demonstration
but also some rambling about political
developments but first let us break the
ice for JavaScript the web is a really
good platform to me because all the
specifications and documentation are
freely available
you just press URLs to people they don't
have to run your binary code without a
sandbox and nowadays it's almost
everywhere we have a screen the web is
everywhere and I bet for any of you
hardly they goes by where you do not use
the web and then there's JavaScript a
language that is belittled by many of
you but it has somewhat improved with
ACMA script 6 and although it's
dynamically typed there are type
checkers like flow there are super sets
of the languages like typescript and
dart my only sorrow point is built to
change that wonder the JavaScript for
you into some chrome compressed single
JavaScript fire that you can deploy on
your web server they are hard to figure
out they're hard to keep up with but
there are no js' an electron we don't
need a tool chain because you don't
deliver code to clients you run locally
and well then you lose the EE the
advantages of the web but you can still
use the same code base as you use on the
web the same
and JavaScript usage got very different
with the advent of nodejs and electron
you've got modularization modulation
means every tiny bit of functionality is
a reusable package a so-called
module on the NPM denote package manager
where you may know the extreme cases
like the infamous left pet incident the
effects of modularization consolidation
of functionality with clear boundaries
clean interfaces and no blood it may
look bloated to you when it pulls in all
those dependencies but it's actually an
advantage and the graphic you can see
here is module accounts comm which
compares module systems of several
languages and the NPM ecosystem is by
far the largest now if you take a look
at this javascript word
I discovered stuff that I find very much
under represented and that is peer to
peer functionality yeah some of the some
of the most active projects some
examples like secure scalable which is a
social networking service which is
entirely decentralized and they've got
an interesting approach they have a
per-user blockchain where your proof of
authority is a public key and public key
cryptography also means to get private
messaging for free I just read on so
secure scuttlebutt that there will be a
safe organization tomorrow and now I
give over to Marvin Tosh the author of
peer flicks a dot Project member and
author to 623 modules on NPM Hey yeah
thank you
I'm Evan Tosh it's actually 324 now
because I just published one an hour ago
so it's pretty cool
now I think a really interesting point
about modulation and
on NPM especially with the peer-to-peer
community and notice that we have a
bunch of different peer-to-peer projects
in node did that project which I'm
working on there's scuttlebutt a lot of
IP faces on NPM also is that since we
come from a culture of very high
materialization there's a huge net of
shared dependencies that are all small
packages so you in the list here that
Astro has picked up I have a thing like
the multicast units module that is so
heavily used by so many projects that I
hate it gets around a hundred thousand
hours per day and so you have all these
competing projects which basically peer
to peer cut projects are at Atlas
essence competing with each other
because their projects tend to compete
in the same space but they're all
reusing properties 60 70 % of their
module graph by using small single-use
reproducible modules so that's super
exciting the one I'm working on the most
is that project which is on there some
Linux tool here cool which is that each
peer network for sharing a lot series of
data it's basically a iteration and it
turned a m-- to do much more real-time
sharing so unlike ipfs it's more based
on on real-time sharing so you have a
set of files you want to share and you
want to share them over time and you
want to share updates to them in a very
efficient and nearly instant matter but
still having a peer-to-peer system and I
used to work a lot with bit turned like
Esther said I used to have a project
called peer flex which is a streaming
pattern client and since both of these
projects are heavily materialized we
were able to reuse a lot of dependencies
like the bad projects reusing the same
TV as a split turn this and using
modulation strategy we split things down
into small JavaScript modules is very
easy to like just pick the ones you want
I'll give it back to Esther announced oh
you can talk about other cool projects
yeah Leslie this was a web torrent web
torrent is a very nice BitTorrent
implementation because it's very modular
now BitTorrent is the most popular
peer-to-peer protocol on the internet
but what web torrent also brings is
capabilities to run in the browser and
you may ask yourself p2p in the browser
yes that is available today with the web
RTC stack which brings voice over P to
the browser and forwards over P you need
low latency so the s p2p functionality
web torrent can use that for data
distribution why is this great the trend
is in a bad situation let me show you
turn to logo the trend is in a bad
situation especially here in Germany
where I'm from you are liable for all
the actions of the Internet users of
your internet connections of your
internet connection if you ever get
caught with copyright infringement you
have to pay a thousand euro fine by some
evil lawyers the effect is that there's
not only no open Wi-Fi in Germany
there's also no has also effectively
could peer-to-peer file-sharing here
no one torrents anymore except over
Virtual Private Networks - - or
third-party countries now this is
motivation for me to run a torrent site
to show that this is no illegal
technology PHP is actually much better
you get data integrity for free because
you need to verify what you get from
random peers you get offline capability
for free because what you download is on
your computer and most importantly in
contrast to classic line server systems
the more downloaders they are the faster
it gets for everyone so this is actual
democratization of means of media
distribution or broadcasting and
actually the term broadcasting has been
coined in the combination of BitTorrent
and podcast feeds
and these podcast feeds are also my
source of legal content but in those
five and a half years now the single pet
pot catcher has gained BitTorrent
support and a legal lack of file-sharing
habits is a problem for me because no
one has a BitTorrent client installed
anymore now if I have Wi-Fi I can
demonstrate it to you in Hollis
just waiting for some linux magic to
have him here there we go now is the
website you can download the torrent
file like you could in the past five
years but as of this year I added web
trend it was really easy and you can now
click Play and web torrent us everything
to just add a media element and enable
streaming playback of course it takes a
while to buffer I'm having like 12
megabytes over Wi-Fi here that's not
possible
the trick is that I have another browser
on this computer running a local host
seeding the fire no manual setup just
peer-to-peer and it actually should
start to play really soon yes and
because it's so hard to programmatically
feed media data to a multimedia element
the web tour and people have taken
precautions that streaming is also
possible and it's really great now back
to the slides
mm-hmm
looking office yes ready to go please
hold for some Linux magic again there
you go
now alhasan germany has gotten somewhat
lifted this year but uncertainty
persists you shouldn't run an open Wi-Fi
here without a VPN and no one would
anyway because there's just no culture
of running open Wi-Fi and what's worse
there are other problems at the door net
neutrality is melting away for example
there is a this telecom stream on offer
it's currently a free add-on that you
can that you can book to your mobile
data service by Deutsche Telekom and it
means that these services get zero rated
they don't count into your into your
traffic volume and this is now free but
of course they are monetization plans
behind this cheaply rated tariffs for
the masses who just want YouTube and
SoundCloud and costly fret rates for us
power users if you look into other
countries like Portugal this has gotten
much further no one of these users would
willingly download on my service any
more I tried to apply to the German
telecom with my veteran service but the
telecom can't recognize my traffic
because technology is way better than
classic client-to-server and now I am at
a disadvantage and I will take action
against that but my warning is if such
schemes get widespread the internet will
die for us power users we like to secure
copy with our service just like we use
YouTube download and why is this
happening in the first place because
there's too much centralism on the
Internet
that's why I'm telling you don't let the
internet become television 2.0 where you
have many receivers many recipients but
very few senders white spreads
peer-to-peer deployment means no one
will put products and companies at its
disadvantage without a large public
outcry
make every user a power user just don't
develop exactly for or against bad loss
because then you could be accused of
willfulness just implement what the
Internet allows for and then you have an
existing project which can be which
can't be positioned as being at
disadvantage and that is that is one way
of hindering these lawmaking efforts
that break the internet so please put
more fear into your apps put in your
peer to peer into your websites thank
you
do we have time for questions they are
any conditions message yes we do
dear audience time for quest Oh we
started beginning right at the front
it's not so much a question it's more a
comment the example you have in Portugal
I have to comment on it because I'm from
Portugal I started a digital rights
organization there and we're going to
tackle that pretty soon right now I have
other actions that take all our time but
net neutrality is going to be one of our
big fights ok but now back to other
topics
you mentioned peer-to-peer and
JavaScript
curiously did not mention zero net do
you know the project what do you think
about it
did you say Sarah net yes yeah I know
Sarah it's it's a cool project I think I
mean so when we talk about peer-to-peer
and JavaScript we talk about multiple
things at once we talk about the browser
we talk about node.js we talk about
electron something like zero net as a
mass adoption thing I mean it's not
gonna hit the browser anytime soon so
you know we need multiple strategies
right why do you think the browser
anytime soon because it has to be
installed first yeah so just like
anything that has that install dialog is
just gonna have a an asset drop off and
use the adoption compared to a normal
website for I'm not saying it's like it
doesn't say anything bad about the
project it's just that in order to
deploy something fast we need to stuff
that works in the browser now if you
access it through a proxy but you cannot
control it so that's just it you can
still access it decentralize Lee but
it's not your nodes
yeah so the project is cool and solving
a lot of really hard peer-to-peer things
like a connectivity and I'm sure you
know as you know yours run by it will
get more and more adaptive because it's
a really cool project and all helped a
lot but you know we kind of need both
things still
thank you the audience more questions
hi do you still need stunning servers if
because we were talking about web RTC in
my in my experience it tries hard at
doing like not hole punching but if it
can't get it to work its gonna use
Google service Google service and they
say yeah done and turn service ok yes
sir we're about to see it's building so
the protocol itself is kind of complex
and and you know kind of a massive thing
I personally wish it was much more
low-level and we just had a UDP type
stack in the browser so we can implement
our own you can actually do stun between
peers in a peer-to-peer fashion also if
you have one introductory peer it's just
way more complicated which is why nobody
does it but you could could in theory
for Rip Torn they could implement an
extension for this for the stream that
will allow an own PA between two other
peers to track as a stun server because
it's just a matter of having you have to
route a couple of messages if they can
in fact connect peer to peer but there
are are cases where firewalls will just
shut everything down and you need a high
server I think it's called right yeah I
server for doing tunneling that in that
sense and in that case you need a
centralized endpoint thank you some more
questions from the audience
well then thank you very much again one
last question as usual if any questions
arise where do we find you in order to
talk about the whole thing a little bit
more well I'm almost total and secure
skala but yes I'm on IRC I mean on
freenode I mean a dead Channel and I'm
also roaming around so just being me
there we also have that there's a dead
session happening at 8:00 tonight us in
the in the wiki so come find me there
cool guys thank you very much
[Applause]