good morning party people at the Kaos
West stage this is day four and this is
a self-organized session we had great
fun the last three days to do so
presenting your stuff
we will go on doing this today - thank
you for the pasty yesterday and cleaning
everything up there was amazing and
Matty will now have an introduction is
it not yeah it's an introduction about
scuttlebutt so please an applause for
Matty cool so hi I'm Mikey I'm coming
from the progress bar hackerspace from
Bratislava and I will today we will try
introduce you scatter bot and so it will
be scattered but what addition and my
questions will be the which the failure
what's your favorite tool for you are
using for the decent communication maybe
hands up if you are using already
something ok so I will maybe skip it
because I see that party was hard
yesterday so ok so the console bot is
based on the all the off-grid concepts
how uses the information how its shared
and doesn't count on the digital surface
of the all protocols what we used so far
today and it's designed like it should
work even on the mesh networks and work
like even between the direct - not books
or direct to devices like mobile phones
or dialogue to satellites right so and
the core of the scatter bot is like the
secure gossip which produce your message
which is signed by you so it can be
changed when it's best over to someone
else
so and the whole cattle boat meaning is
like the sea slang for the gossip right
and it must be invented like exchanging
your gossips about your co-workers at
your pirate ship okay thanks at they are
Bochy Tara - so sorry
so yeah when you are using the out great
communications you are literally not on
the internet right so to be short the
scatter pod is all about it not embrace
the objectivity and doesn't have any
kind of singleton sign consensus because
there is no need to consensus let's fork
your discussions and continue in other
treat every person who used the
scuttlebutt have their own view of the
network so we just share the common
informations but there is no objectivity
on the social network as we know
nowadays social networks and you are
building the networks by your local
trust so you will bring your friends to
the network and this doesn't work like
the IRC or some kind of the forums where
every people see the same yeah so the
major thing about this couple is that
you don't have any kind of the outer
editors so you are your own outer et and
you just trust yourself so it's a based
on your good decisions you make and you
links you click right so viewers of
scammers and yes so some up there is no
global Singleton's so there is like
nothing like single ledger or single
computer or a single file system and the
people don't need to agree what they see
right so ok going for some technicals so
as every person will sign up to the sky
Bob locally it will be generated the key
pair and it's their cryptographic name
is their public key and that's it right
so and every message you produce it will
append to your personal let's say the
blockchain and that's what you are doing
on the scatter plot every time when you
post a message or create some kind of
the post right and you will be just
joining these messages together using
the miracle trees the principles of the
scatter plot is is about the
subjectivities so if I say the CCC is
great you could not agree or if I say
there has been some situations or base
equations around the CCC I could or
could not agree right so there is also
the against consensus so if the CCC will
make some kind of statement other
persons in the room could refuse the
statement and made their own right there
is also the free speech and free
listening on the scatter boat so
everything it's what was being post
there it could be like passed over and
could be published on other nodes right
so it's literally nobody can stop you
and as the part of the dog fooding
is that scatter bodies being used by
their own developers for using is a
primary communication tool for the inter
daily life right and best principle is
the uncapturable that nobody have total
control all over it right
like the tor tor project have some kind
of board which decides what to do and
how they act and how they produce their
think over it right
so there is the identity is your public
key not laser and there is your
subjective name or like it's called the
pet names so anyone can assign you your
different pet name
yep and it's all in Toth so skip skip to
be quick so yes in the yeah when you
produce your messages you creating your
cig chain and creating some sequence
number of your messages let's say and
you are connecting to each other like
some kind of the secure ledger so and
you don't have some that kind of the
proof of work so when you try to modify
your published already sick chain you
will just broke your identity and your
identity will be not consistent anymore
so there is also some parts there should
be probably could be implemented there
some kind of deniability as well so yep
okay I can tell you that some técnicos
about the how message looks like you
have their signature you have their
public key your content of the previous
message has been linked the sequence
number of the some kind of the post in
the channel and time stamp and sign and
some blob for rich media so this is how
it looks
and you may see their dairy you have the
outer their sequence number time step
hash yet the algorithms for the crypto
could be changed anytime and that's it
and this the part of the content is
being like the flexible and beings now
extended for some kind of the
motivations but you don't need to accept
moderation parameters as well and I will
get back later to it so there's like
three basics signals using the at for
feeds the percent for the messages and
amp for the blobs and you have also some
tech and end of the each of these links
which will tell you what kind of the
crypto is being used that could be like
replaced any time this is like some
further crypto you are using for entity
the Purves ete keepers and for the your
messages you are using the private books
and secret I think there is the double
secret or for not sure right now because
it was the change lightly and you are
using the content as link link for the
messages yep the great thing about the
the scuttlebutt is that are using the
secure the gossip so anyone can pass
over your gossip but it couldn't be
changed right so and it's
cryptographically verifiable that it was
saved by you right okay here is the
another great feature of the scuttlebutt
is that when you choose the person who
you will start the flow you
automatically your scuttlebutt instance
will start replicating and anyone else
who will start follow you will also have
changed to see the feeds you are
replicating to them
okay let's cut about using our souls DHT
for the sharing the peers so if I will
connect to your peer I will get some
diary of your peers and stories you have
and I will look up for the persons I
follow and I will download the part of
the content from you and will replicate
it to the next person I will met in the
future and the great thing about the
scuttle boat is that you can use it like
offline and handle over it on some USB
or SD card to someone else so it could
be like used the sneaker nets and could
be used without internet yay
[Music]
okay this is the pretty complicated but
it's easy to understate understable that
as you named someone on the network it
could be really different how you will
see when someone else follow you so you
will interpret the network differently
for each person will follow the next
person after you write so it could be
modified and every person who will come
through you you will see the network
like you interpreted to them so you also
can change the network to sum up that
the schedule would have no Singleton's
is saying that the single sensor
Singleton's have the problem that they
don't meet the the architecture and the
concept of mmm designs of the whole
usage
[Music]
and okay and as cattle bodies using the
miracle trees you can literally just
replicate only your friends or your maid
which participate it's that kind of the
discussion so if you have like the few
time to replicate it from the Mars you
only replicate the part of the
discussion and you can read it offline
as well afterwards and yay clicker stops
works great so oh so this thing doesn't
work the turret the turret editor so
okay so now
so okay yeah okay thanks so I will sum
up for the applications there are some
real-world to use each already so yeah
next slide or maybe next slide
yeah so the people behind the scatter
will start embracing the get to place it
in back to the decentralized environment
and you can literally use the get SSB
which is the replicated get over your
friends so and this is encrypted by
native and it works like some common
brands there is also the Catering's
which you can create some events it's
pretty experimental for now there is the
in development mobile app for exploring
the scatter bot treats as is getting on
there is the decentralized Fermin
centralized Sound Cloud which used like
the vector and magnetic for sharing the
blobs with the music there is a chess
there is the application for having four
books you read
there is the also blogging platform
because the lot of posts in the scatter
bots are quite long and recently there
someone released the tail net which is
the Skillshare network and here is some
real numbers from the network so there
is like this measurement is using like
two weeks window base the conductivity
of the users and average activity is
somewhere between 80 and 100 users daily
so so some technical things you can also
configure in your scuttlebutt instance
how many people you want to replicate
and use the numbers number and how
number of hops you want to see in the
network you will be replicated - and
yeah and you can also use the hardcore
mode to turn off the public replication
okay and if you want to start using this
cattle boat right now you can head over
to the github SS b c and patchwork
patchwork slash releases and download
the application open the scuttlebutt pop
servers urls and wait for the initial
sequence of some few sig chains and some
go some channels and introduce yourself
at the channel new people okay I think
that's it so if you will be on this
cattle boat you can maybe follow me if
you go there and maybe see you there so
thanks if you have questions I know it
with time it's okay 12 minutes so any
questions questions from the audience
a great talk thanks thanks
can you configure your scuttlebutt
client to just replicate specific people
so I mean maybe I don't want to just
replicate what people have there because
maybe it's not legal in my country and
so on and so on
or can I say okay I trust these people
to not post stuff which can get me into
trouble
maybe I'm seen in the code and it's not
like in the it's not configurable right
now but yes you can make it a pull
request and yeah it's possible yeah so
it's yeah buddies are in the scatterplot
this is mean to be not to be censored
any anyhow right so it's up to how you
make it right so and that there are also
free some viewports of the scuttle both
instances as well so and they don't
break each other but the content you
will see will be quite different so yeah
but that's the nature of the scatter
boat Thanks
more questions
is there is there some kind of
possibility to generate private groups
or private subnets of this scuttlebutt
yes
by default the subjectivity would use
been used on the scatter bodies that
what they have been told in this stage
doesn't collide what have been told in
other room right so if nobody will leak
from other room or like that both ways
it's totally separate still then so yeah
and the great about is this cattle
bodies using the miracle trees so the
every discussion have the the content
hash of the discussions so if you don't
follow any of person from the next room
you are not in your probably not will
not see the content right so how it
works okay but as soon as someone from
my group leaks content to another group
it's out in the oh yeah we would be it
could be seen said yeah now there is
also some row Java running the scatter
body instances as well and they are not
connected to I yeah I see some post but
for me is not reachable because I don't
know the people from row Java personally
and there is also some Venice was
scheduled runnings as well more
questions
okay what yeah then as usual my last
question where do we find you here on in
Congress if you want to talk to me I I
think you can find me through the wiki
okay so I'm there and yeah I know the
tweeter so cool thank you very much for
your amazing talk Thanks
[Applause]