okay party people at the Kaos West stage
here is the next talk it's a very nice
talk actually performed by this great
and beautiful Michael he will talk about
the man zero hot wear wallet so we're
gonna have actually some very nice
pictures live pictures from a camera
taken from this hardware it's gonna be
absolutely amazing I'm hyped please Mike
go ahead
great thank you no no yeah well let's
get started I'm quite happy to follow
the mobile wallet which was given by m29
what's his name again anyway we're gonna
be talking mostly about hardware wallets
and in particular Manero Hardware shown
showcasing the wallets that we have
produced so far prototypes this is so
this is a very very sparse description
that I've put up here just to explain
what the project is about to answer the
questions that people people typically
have so this is what okay
got cut off at the bottom if you don't
mind we won't have a slide deck okay
I'm quite lazy so I don't like making
slides and this is online so whoever
wants to review it as we're talking can
just go to this URL go spin comm paste
EPM BK it's a public a public a what is
it called a public etherpad or ghost bad
or whatever and that's all that we're
gonna have it's gonna be quite fast this
is my name by the way Michael Schlow
from benifits you can call me Michael
just like it says right there and I go
by ms VB usually online when it's IRC or
when we're chatting or or something like
that so just like so many other other
more narrow groups like Cove reor the
Monaro software we do our communication
mostly in IRC channels so you might have
Mineiro - ccc for the planning for this
event you might have mo narrow - dev for
the development and we also have mo
narrow - hardware which looks like this
- hardware so you get the idea that's
the IRC channel anytime you have a
question you want to pop in to this
channel then you might get an answer
depending on which time zone you're
living in anyway so we can start with a
bit of history because the hardware
project has not been around too long
officially it's been around since the
1st of October it kind of started at Def
Con last year what last year no 2017
this year's Def Con in July in Las Vegas
that's where there was a monaro party
quite nice one high up on a hotel in a
hotel room and I was meeting with a few
other people we decided to group into a
hardware division so to say and so to
speak and create something a pilot
project that would become the Monaro
Hardware wallet a lot of people believe
that when eras is missing their own
hardware wallet so that's where it all
began and that's kind of the beginning
of the project and the history now the
particular project were working on the
hardware wallet should last six months
until we're able to provide a design and
what that means is that we're not we're
not planning to release a firmware
that's full-featured and stable we're
not planning to release an enclosure or
a case if you'd rather you know plastic
or aluminum or whatever it is we're not
planning to release quite a lot of
things we're focusing really right on to
the the circuits the PCB the printed
circuit board and and the hardware
design itself so figuring out if we want
to put an ePaper inside if we want to
have a battery
if we want to have a charging circuit if
we want to use a particular MCU all of
these decisions we'd like to reach
consensus on them and produce a design
before the six month risks the the six
month end of the project which should be
at the end of March and where does that
take us it takes us right to about the
1st of April but this is not a pissant
olive oil this is no joke
we probably will finish by then we're on
track and and tie on time so far and I
believe that there is a CCC event that
Easter heck it's about that time
I think it's gonna be in votes Berg this
year so if you're all there inverts Berg
for Easter Egg you may see our release
party at least we're planning to do that
that means that at the end of March if
we're on time we will have a more narrow
Hardware wallet design and I do have
some prototypes here to show because as
we're creating the design we need to
test and so we produce we produce boards
but I do need to back up because I
didn't mention that the project started
at Def Con in Las Vegas and that we
talked a little bit about what other
things you could do with hardware and
Manero is quite ambitious in a lot of
ways so we might be producing for
example some years some month whenever
ATM machines payment processors
specialized cards smart cards that
actually operate as wallets or something
else or as security devices or as
signature verifiers or you can use them
to log into what I don't know an SSH
server or something a lot of other
hardware wallets can already do that but
I'm just trying to point out that we may
not only be making a wallet so we just
took care of that took care of that this
is what you have to do when you have no
slides right and we took care of that
right now I guess we can take a look at
what everybody wants to see so my camera
is not so good I hope you can see this
so this is kind of what we may end up
with the form factor and let me see if I
can make this better here yeah that's
okay I think anyway so this is kind of
what we want to end up with this is not
a more narrow project you probably
recognize this some of you folks right
this is a node MCU so this is actually
very different than anything we're
planning to produce this is a
general-purpose computer but it's about
the same size and format if you can make
a conclusion for it it has some holes
has some connectivity we'll probably
only use USB this has a lot of RF you
can see the antenna there as well god
this laser does not do the job anyway
and this is kind of an example of what
we may end up with so that was so that
was the other hardware and there's
another yet another example of other
hardware here I think I'll this time I
will put a white piece of paper
underneath
so that might be a bit easier to see
with a paper I think I don't anyway so
this is another piece of hardware which
we created in in the Monaro hardware lab
but it's not a wallet there we
government yes so so what we have here
is a it's basically I call it a crypto
shield because all it does is provide
crypto features to just about anything
that it can connect with this can be
connected to an Arduino Raspberry Pi
anything with GPIO with GPIO and I
squared C connectors so that's an
interface that's used on this I squared
C and the laser won't do the job but you
can see this it's you can see the secure
elements here in the middle and what a
secure element does is it basically
offers you a lot of cryptography a lot
of crypto acceleration in hardware and
some features basically lock down the
the appliance in altogether it it avoids
the problem of reading secret keys out
because you can blow fuses that are
internal to the chips and then the
secret key can never be read out again
these kind of things so this is what
we're experimenting with and using these
kind of devices this is not a Manero
device but it's something similar
I'll go right ahead and show the first
generation of Monera wallet that we have
this was this a couple months old
already like I said the project is is
intended to to end after six months so
so we're almost halfway through and this
one is a couple months old
there's a lot of glitter oh fudge it if
I stand right here then it looks okay
anyway so this is the very bottom this
is the bottom of the PCB that's why you
don't see very many components you can
see some passives these are resistors I
believe know these are capacitors and
some other things but this is the bottom
so let's turn it over and take a look at
the parts that are the cool parts are on
top and if I do this is kind of how it
will be used all right
so this is how we this is how this is
one version one variant of how the
hardware wallet will look it has a has a
MCU in the middle it has some some input
and output some buttons we might add one
or not has a LCD or LED in this case and
of course it has a very important logo
therefore the Monaro hardware wall so if
you are looking around for the
programming interface this we have JTAG
on here and this is a very sleek and and
very nice what are they called
I forgot the name of it but I'm pretty
nice connector here one point two seven
millimeter spacing and we've got a micro
USB there for power and data like I said
we're doing most of the communication
through USB as so many other hardware
wallets are anyway so this was our first
generation the it's quite large if you
want to compare size this is a
BeagleBone black so that's the size of a
BeagleBone black which is similar to the
size of a what Raspberry Pi or something
do you like me go boom black so we have
some fans not of the more narrow
hardware but well okay of other hardware
so this is the one okay this is so this
is this is a size and the form factor
that we're kind of looking at for a
developer edition so we're already
considering having more than one more
narrow Hardware wallet one for the
developers which appreciate large
connectors and maybe micro USB which is
easier to work with and on top of that
if you know anything about side channel
attacks and analysis glitching and clock
based attacks CPA correlation power
analysis all these kind of things
there's really cheap device it helps you
do this analysis called the chip
whisperer and it's just chip whisper has
a what a accessory board that accepts a
you
Oh format PCB and that's exactly the
format that we chose to use here so we
can just drop this into a chip whisper
and do analysis directly without doing
any wiring at all and that's why we're
going to keep this form factor the way
it is this is going to be locked down in
code and and this is our developer
edition so we'll get wild and crazy on
the developer edition we probably won't
consider a lot of use cases that for
example border agent border crossings
and so on okay well we'll do that it's
in firmware and but this is more of a
consumer feature for us so moving on to
where are we anyway
okay we're on we run more narrow
hardware we can X this one out now we're
on one narrow hardware and right so what
is the current state of Manero hardware
here is our panel ization of the
consumer edition I can't even fit it in
there I mean can you kind of see that
maybe I should just do this so this is a
panel of hardware wallets there's ten
Hardware wallets on there and this is
what we get back from the printer and
then once we receive this we either hand
solder it one by one or we slip it into
a pick-and-place machine after
stenciling a solder on there I apologize
that I can't show all of the steps well
I I didn't bring my taking place machine
with me in this suitcase they're rather
large anyway but this is kind of what it
looks like close up let's see if I can
let's see if I can block off the glare
stand just right you see that cool gold
I just think that's excellent anyway the
things look kind of okay and this is the
consumer edition it's a lot smaller as
you can tell there's still JTAG on there
even though it's a consumer edition
that's slanted row
and you can see where the buttons are
gonna come on there those those are
those those two blocks there and then at
the top that's where we solder on a
plastic header for the screen and in the
middle you can't see the laser can you
but anyway in the middle is the the part
that's the most important part it says
MCU the microcontroller unit and after
we solder everything on there it looks
like this so right I can even put two of
them on there actually I can't do that
well you get the idea and yeah that's
another thing that we sometimes have to
do we had sometimes have to create our
own test harness and debug cables so I
made this special electro wonk about
four days ago because I had some
problems with the USBC connector USBC
connectors are real pain if you're if
you're developing hardware and you're
considering going to us PC yes do it but
plan on spending a lot of time getting
that right you a USB a micro USB or mini
USB all these old standards that are
about a year old you just need to get
four contacts right you need the two
data and then the power and the ground I
mean there's five contacts I think but
you only need to get four of them right
with the USBC connectors you need 24
contacts and they're smaller so it's
just ridiculously difficult to get that
perfect when you're soldering underneath
the chip and anyway that's why I made
this electoral wonk that you see there
and on the end of the electro wonk if
you're curious that's how it looks I
just kind of stripped the wires in order
to test so that's a little anecdote but
here you can kind of see the difference
the bottom row that's before they're
populated the wallets are populated with
the ICS with chips and and components
and the top is where it's populated you
can even see the plastic headers where
the screens pop in maybe I should kind
of slant that
hey that's pretty cool I like the
slanting action there and so what does a
screen look like when you what that's I
mean I'm not gonna plug it in but that's
kind of how they look the whole idea
what these plastic headers are not
elegant like this one this one has a
soldered on a soldered on screen you can
tell from the you can tell from the FPC
that the fine pitch connector here
that's soldered on it's much more
elegant and it's flat it lays flat and
it's nice but we can't use those when
we're doing testing we're trying to send
devices out so people can produce
firmware for them or test or give
opinions feedback and so on and if we
just keep sending devices out with the
the screen soldered on first of all that
means a lot more hand soldering for us
real pain and second of all we're
spending on extra screens that people
already have so the answer to that we
think is to just purchase these purchase
these screens that are mounted onto a
PCB and they have pins and then we just
pop those on the wallet and the next
wealth that we send out that that same
tester we don't send a new screen out
they just use their old one so that's
kind of the idea all right and so that's
kind of how it looks you can probably
tell the one in the middle there I
started desoldering parts from it
because there was a loop of some kind
somewhere it was I could tell that
ground was connected to power over the
USB circuit so I just started debugging
and that's kind of how it looks when you
get things wrong and then I guess I
could show these two which are actually
working and that's kind of how finished
prototypes look I mean sometimes we we
decide to slant the screen you know for
like a Ferrari red slanted you know
spoiler look that's really really cool
or sometimes we just do it like that
that's a little easier you can get
underneath the screen and pushed you
know push things around and connect
leads
so this USB see connectors not everybody
has a USBC cable and that's why that's
why there's these adapters if you look
carefully well it's not gonna work but
it's actually a USBC to to USB what be
micro so that's what we're sending out
now to Monaro community in order to test
and get feedback I guess I can probably
do a demo before we get into questions
right and so I'm not sure which one I'll
demo I guess I will do this one and what
do I need I need some power
there we go
all right
I don't know
that's I've got to stand in the right
place so yeah the problem with LED
screens and focusing on cameras you can
tell what the problem is right there is
no focus problem because you can see the
text on the PCB it's just impossible to
read what it says I can read it myself
it says Mona's or motifs or HW Hardware
wallet by DFU so this is the first
firmware that we produced ourselves and
we're able to program the board over DFU
or device firmware update which is not
sure if it's a standard but it's a
typical procedure that that you use if
you want to avoid JTAG programming and
kind of more esoteric swd or things like
that so it's much easier you can do
everything with a USB cable and that's
why we kind of celebrated by yeah by
printing that onto the screen and that's
almost the only thing it does I mean it
doesn't seem like a lot but just getting
the toolchain right and the programming
and the DFU and so on believe me that
that's quite a test
to celebrate we did that and then we do
have two buttons so let's see if you can
see that when that when I push the one
button let me see work I can't see where
I'm pushing there it is so if I pushed
there so now when I push the button I'm
gonna read it again it says left button
and if I push the other button says
guess what right button left button
right button left button right button if
I push them both yeah I don't know if
the I don't know if the BeagleBone black
can do that by the way it's really so
let's see what happens if I push them
both what do you think will happen do
you think it'll crash the board okay
let's see I'm gonna push them both oh
okay the last one that went down is the
one that gets the split no it's the it's
a left one
well it didn't start a fire so I'm happy
about that anyway so that's kind of as
far as we've gotten with the firmware oh
yes and we're gonna keep working on the
firmware but like I said before a
priority is on the hardware design right
so right I can just keep yeah I can I
can do the same thing with these smaller
Ferrari style
I made them read because it's kind of
the holiday season Rio red I don't know
does that make sense
but yeah there's plenty of styles and
colors we can choose
I'm the if I can show all of them you
know if you want to see any of these
others working you just need to come
back to the more narrow stand because
it's kind of repetitive so we'll get
back to here and we finished that so
what most people ask when we're talking
about this winter online or or I don't
know just in general kind of the five
top questions are why should there be
another Hardware wallet because there
are others there's like keep key okay so
I'm not sure if Kiki will be with us in
another year it looks a maybe I don't
want to say anything bad but I haven't
seen too much development there there
are some answers to the question why
another wallet the trouble with that is
you need to line up a group of 20
individuals and ask them that same
question you will get about 15 different
answers or groups of answers and after
you do that you will finally have a good
overview of why the world doesn't need
another wallet and why the world does
need another wallet so it's really I'm
gonna avoid the question from that for
now there's I assume that the same
answers that applied as the second
hardware wallet came in existence apply
for this situation just as well there
are many more than two hardware wallets
at this time and as long as they all
diverge from features and I don't know
operational models price freedom
open-source or not these kind of things
I think is just fine that there
differences that we have a flourishing
ecosystem of hardware as well as
software I I can't imagine anybody
saying we should have only one or two
crypto currencies right this is bad that
we have a flourishing ecosystem of
cryptocurrency technology based on
blockchain and with various types of
software and that's kind of a same
answer that I would provide but that's
just me I'm just one person don't trust
me but that's my answer to why another
wallet and speaking of differences and
diverging features so we we will have
something but we integrated USBC before
there was any other hardware wallet
design that that incorporated USB see
for example that's just one example if
we put an ePaper display in which means
that you can still read the the public
address or the public you know the
public information of a person of an
individual's wallet even when it's
disconnected from USB even when the
battery's dead so that would be a
feature we're kind of fighting with
features like that because sometimes
somebody wants to turn off all
information and how would they do that
if the battery's dead
and the ePaper is continuing to display
it but you get the idea there's quite a
lot of features that are yet to be
integrated into other hardware wallets
on the market and so that's kind of what
differentiate differentiates the Monaro
hardware wallet from other contenders
lots of people want to buy one or they
want to get in line to buy one are these
kind of questions
no sorry
there's no way to buy one but maybe
after we have a design after Easter hegh
and if you pay attention maybe talk to
Manero folks they can point you in the
right direction
even before then if you want to test or
help out or contribute in any way
looking at documentation making photos
and uploading to a blog or plugging in
your JTAG programmer to see if it works
etc you're probably way up on the list
to receive a prototype device in the
mail if you provide your mail address
which is a big problem we have in Manero
nobody wants to do that
so anyway so that's about the trouble
with purchasing and what if I lose it so
these are the kind of questions we get
sometimes which are based on firmware
and features that are in the software or
the host software running on a computer
or the type of USB cable or these kind
of things that don't apply too much to
the hardware design so obviously if you
lose your hardware wallet then you will
have the same ease of recovery or
problems of loss as any other hardware
while they basically all offer some kind
of backup feature and security system
where you're in control of your data
even if you lose a hardware wallet but
this and many other similar questions
depend on a firmware being established
and and well tested and available we
don't have that so it's hard or almost
impossible to answer these type of
questions you can still ask them I don't
mind we can you know we can we can find
the answers together right and then how
do I participate if I really like this
idea we're very open group everything is
open source even the process so the
project plan the the disclaimer which is
a legal document which basically says
yes I want to receive a wallet in the
post or something all of that stuff the
members list we have about 30 members in
our group everything is is out in the
open and we have never signed an NDA and
don't plan to in fact it's a requirement
not to do so NDA's a non non-disclosure
agreement we have no secret processes or
secret decisions or secret meetings
anything like that
no secret contracts so if you like that
idea I mean that's kind of a unique
thing and the hardware market in general
and and wallets as well then the
question becomes how do I participate
and I can answer that pretty easily
because if you well let's get rid of
this discover here so this is gonna be
hard to read I think it's kind of small
right but I'll read it to you in fact
I'll put this in fact you don't you
don't have to write that down because
it's in the ether pad
if you just got this URL right at the
very top the second one down that's
where that's where we have our taiga
system which is a project management
system it's not only open-source but you
can actually own the data and have it in
your internal infrastructure that's what
Manero kind of likes when Aero doesn't
like when there's a slack type of system
where maybe or maybe you do own the data
or maybe you don't but it's not inside
your control right so this is in the
control of a corporate group somewhere
in the world with a group of servers
that follow a type of policy anyway so
taiga is better in that sense if you
like self control over your project and
that's what you do and that's what we've
got here here's some projects for
example m20 for 9:50 i think is his name
and the nice fellow that very bright
fellow that showed off the mobile wallet
he has a project here as well I think
it's probably where is it must be here
okay well I don't see it but um it's
here as well and like here's the the
project that we have for planning this
event and our table back over there the
34 c3 and this is a the project that I'm
talking about now the RFC Hardware
wallet one design so I'm just gonna
click on that and that brings me to well
you get the idea this is how it looks
and then this is the timeline this is
kind of what a chronological order of
what's been happening this is a great
way to to get familiar with the with the
development side of things so here's a
person who just signed on he's a he's
gonna do mechanical engineering wants to
at least mechanical engineers they're
kind of responsible for enclosures so
they'll probably be making designs oh
you know I forgot to show that we do
have a half design of a mechanical
enclosure see that nice acrylic there if
I just block the light off you can see
that
so that's kind of half of an enclosure
that's a very start of an enclosure
anyway so we're getting started on that
to just because it's not a requirement
doesn't mean we're not interested so
this is another thing that's not a
requirement is RF or radio frequency
interfaces none of I won't say none I
think most or maybe none of us like the
idea of having radio frequency involved
in Hardware wallets is it's just too
yucky I mean okay theoretically you can
lock it down is be secure I know so
what we're still experimenting with that
for a number of reasons we might be
forced into using a chip that has an RF
interface Bluetooth and NFC and if we do
that then we'll probably make use of the
NFC mostly so that you can have a a
wallet - wallet protocol where you know
you're tapping another device and
receiving an address a public address or
you want to pay your friend so you tap
your two devices together and that's how
each device knows you know what to send
and what to receive when would you want
that if you want to avoid optical
character recognition in QR codes if you
realize that there's cameras all over
the room then you don't really want to
hold your phone out or something with a
QR code piece of paper or something you
might be able to use an NFC circuit in
that case to avoid detection if that's
what if you'd like to remain anonymous I
mean it's not the perfect method because
there's there's there's plenty of ways
to defeat that as well but is this
another another option those are
features that we're looking at another
thing we're looking at if you take a
look at the left hand corner it says
ledger blue port so we're always
interested in porting designs from other
contenders and then mixing it up and
then taking some portions of their
design putting 10% of the treasure in
putting 10% of the ledger and maybe
putting 50 or 60% of our own ideas in
and then we're moving 20% of those
mixing it up like that or shift devices
as an excellent wallet called the what
is it called the bit box right that's
kind of cool it has very unique stuff on
there like a capacitive touch element
and a cut-through board LED that's very
bright
I like it a lot it has an SDHC card so
everyone is a bit different and we're
we're thinking about borrowing or
contributing you know this inner this
very interactive method of working with
these groups and yeah sharing features
so that's what we're doing here with the
ledger for example then we've got a
person came on as a tester another
revision of the of that port here's a
person who was working on logos more
boring stuff probably project planning
from me so this is what we saw before I
mentioned how cool that gold looks it
costs a bit more to put gold on there
that's real gold by the way it's a real
gold but you know I mean we're more
narrow right it's worth it isn't it you
have to do it if you're more narrow
yeah the next board it'll be a different
color I don't know what do you think
this is what I need I need to figure out
the color of the next prototype board I
mean it can be green it it can't be red
because it's not Christmas anymore
but it could be like black it could be
green blue yeah orange is not available
yellow you like yellow yellow is
available Oh yellow for Easter like eggs
okay right oh by the way the guy that
likes black BeagleBone blacks he's not
here anymore
he got really bored I think and so yeah
this is what the panels look like when
we get them from the printer we put some
other freebies in the in the holiday
packages those are cygnets which are
made by another excellent hardware group
they basically just sign what is a sigma
2 I've actually forgotten I haven't put
one together yet to say it has anybody
bought or assembled a signet I believe
yeah they sign things so they do some
cryptography so this is the programming
portion we're doing this with a
flyswatter 2 which is also open
not sure if it's open so it's hardware
but they're very open open people they
have
they make their own stuff and it's
rather rather good you can see it says
JTAG debugger there then we have a logo
there and more board examples and this
is kind of what we thought it might look
like for the holiday send-off of
prototypes blah blah blah so that's kind
of answering the question how do I get
started whoops which is here how do I
participate now to make it even easier I
mean there's all kinds of stuff there's
a wiki here you can kind of take a look
at the documentation the requirements
are here we have a set of requirements
if you want to get familiar with the
project more we we've been interviewed
by journalists on a number of occasions
really cool designs there I love this
picture this bull with a blue print in
the background and it and a microscope
oh I just love that yeah and and our
good friend an animal who is the the
chief covert developer he kind of got us
started in this and made all of the
personal connections in in Def Con in
Las Vegas last year this year so that's
kind of the first interview that we had
with a journalist he was on board and
kind of hanging out that's why he's part
of the picture there yeah these are the
requirements I mean it's kind of a long
document some of these things might be a
bit boring what functional requirements
like obviously we're gonna take five
volt power from USB we're we're gonna
have a three volt battery housing this
is this could be coming handy if we if
we use a very low powered MCU for a
detailer dopper ation of some sort with
a reduced functional yeah reduce
features but we can detailer we can no
longer have USB and the thing is still
working so there's some I'm not gonna go
through this but you know you can get
you get the idea that there are some
well-documented requirements there so
and here's the program I was talking
about where you can receive a device and
test it and give your opinion you can
say this is really not as good as a
blackberry
beagle bone black I'd rather have a
Raspberry Pi anyway and yeah if you do
decide that this is for you you just
need to read this part alright and it
basically involves saying yes I want
I've read the disclaimer and I then I
live here and you should send me a board
and then you sign it in any way you want
in fact it tells you how to sign it
using the Monaro software here somewhere
I find that really really cool wait a
minute
how does I how do I sign it somewhere it
shows you yeah I can't find it now
yeah but the Monaro software can be used
to sign generic text I mean we all know
that this is possible from the Bitcoin
client as well it's it's no it's not
yeah it's it's easy to do but I just
find that a very elegant method all
right so say that you want to get in
touch with us you don't know how or you
don't
so there's a button here at the very
bottom that says meet up I don't know
why it says meet up but if you click on
that then another window opens and
you're sent to the matter most channel
this is actually bridged to IRC so if
you don't have an IRC client if you
don't know what IRC is you don't like it
or whatever then you can use this and
this is similar to slack but it is it's
an in-house type of thing where you
don't lose control over your data right
so we prefer that I think and yeah you
have to be signed in to get this screen
you need an account but it's quite easy
to set up the account it's about one
minute procedure and the way I saw that
is by going here and clicking on meetup
right and there's all these other things
you can see who's on the team for
example blah blah blah there I am I'm
Michael and online I'm ms VB there's a
there's the issues bug reporting the
wiki there's a kind of a sprint type of
hour I'm sorry I'm agile methodology
type of project planning here so for
example there's a technical
familiarization sprint and then it loads
that and you just kind of check out the
tasks that are involved some of these
are are finished some are still improv
so here I had to order trial components
for example you get the idea
there's epochs I don't even know what an
epoch is and then back to the timeline
so that's some how you get involved in
the project or how you learn more about
it regardless of if you want to get
involved or not and I think we're done
whoops stay stay stay stay
yeah so that was how do I participate
and if anybody has new questions or if
you have a request if you want to see a
another device start working or
something else then off to you there's a
question there thank you hey Michael
there was a nice talk I love the clothes
on pictures of the of your hardware is
it okay if I as usual ask three
questions first or do you want to really
want to go ahead now let's go with you
guys questions first meet me right there
if you want to ask a question on stage
you can but you will be on screen and on
the Internet just wait a second
we do have time there's no rush
here I'll pass this you can pass us
around take a look I can't get past the
speakers but if someone comes up I just
have actually I have more than two I
think I have three Hey
thanks Michael for to talk just want to
know from like the chip design if this
is like monaro
only or if this supports all crypto
notes
coins yeah that's a good question so the
the optimist the optimistic perspective
that I would like to offer is that
anybody can code to support more than
just one arrow
there's another one that's a
first-generation the green one is the
first generation so I would hope that
whoever had an interest in Z cash would
try to find a way to pack that into the
program storage and then run it from the
bootloader and see what happens in so
many cases you can just basically take
code from a JIT hub repository and
that's three-quarters of everything you
need to do to port a competing
cryptocurrency onto for example a mining
rig or a hardware wallet I mean there
are some problems that that do impede
from making this crossover Manero has
some very unique crypto algorithms like
for example we don't use the SEK P 256 K
1 curve which is what's used in elliptic
curve digital signature algorithm or
ECDSA we use a different one so that one
that I just mentioned the SEK P the SEK
256 p1 that's what's used by e thorium
by light point by Bitcoin by I think
almost everything I mean you guys are
pros so you can correct me if I'm wrong
but if there's maybe a hundred different
crypto currencies then maybe 90 or 95 of
them use exactly that curve that
elliptic curve now Manero uses a
different one which is called IDI 255
1/9 as well as curve 255 1/9 so the one
is a Montgomery curve and the other is a
edwards curve they're basically very
very different then the Bitcoin and the
others so you're kind of stuck with that
if we choose for example a secure
element that can only support that or
that's going to that's going to be one
thing that's difficult to two people
porting other cryptocurrencies on the
other hand it it's probably not the case
that we restrict our secure element to
just that one curve so who knows another
thing that I'd like to mention a lot of
hardware wallets are trying to do
everything at once
they're packing in all kinds of
cryptocurrencies into a single into
signal application I think that's fine
but it kind of gets wild and crazy and
especially if you have limited yeah
thank you
yes let's get excited so especially if
you have limited program storage which
is 512 Kbytes on these FCU's you can't
do very much with that so if you have
rings signatures and confidential
transactions and stuff like that
happening inside and programmed onto on
that MCU it might be pretty challenging
to to implement other types of
cryptocurrency models based on other
elliptic curves on top of that I would
say go for it and I hope you do it will
be very supportive in in that we will
try to overestimate I'm sorry should
that should I say underestimate uh yeah
I should wheel we're gonna underestimate
the resources required for implementing
a hardware wallet so hopefully you all
and me and everybody will have more than
we need in order to put another
cryptocurrency inside thank you so is
the hardware free lossless a lossless
open source is it fluffs yes it is it
follows the CERN license which is very
common for hardware projects and I've
actually forgotten if well because we
don't have an official firmware and host
software portion in this project we have
not defined software licenses we've only
defined Hardware licenses and they're
fully open source if you read this
certain license it has a it has a poison
pill it has all the stuff that you
really like to see in an open source
license
thanks for the talk I have a question
more about software you haven't spoken a
lot about it but who is writing the
firmware for for this hardware and how
is that projects can you repeat that who
is writing in the farmer for this
hardware so there are a few people doing
that at least I think the best answer to
that is is that there is no firmware
component to the project so if we have
firmware in this case it's a it's it's
to allow us to test you know just that
left button right button so we don't
have an official firmware group there is
a set of people three or four I believe
in that list of team members and they
have a roll set to them that's not
mechanical engineering it's not design
its firmware it's coding I think that's
what we call it I think you're asking a
different question though you don't want
to know if there's team members that
have a rule set to coding you'd like to
know where maybe the the JIT hub
repository is and how this proceeding
right no I was thinking what's the state
is off the software side I mean you have
to have Hardware first but to have
something working you need the software
side as well so was that that was my
question what's the status of that
yeah the status is that it's on our
minds that we know we agree with you
that we need software and firmware after
the hardware is done and we also know
that there's there's some disagreement
as well at how much firmware and
software we need up front in order to
produce a valid and good hardware design
do we need to have these efforts going
in parallel for example and we really
haven't reached a decision on that but
first of all in our JIT hub repository
which is under the Monaro - project I
won't mention it ok I'll mention it's
called Sakura but this name is gonna
change anyway so under that sub
directory there is a a sub sub directory
that's firmware and so it will go in
there and if you're wondering well why
don't we start with a firmware why I
have
we finished enough firmware consider
that most contending groups that are
producing hardware wallets they're doing
this with five or ten team members
they're well financed they have a list
of customers and they still cannot
produce and begin taking orders for a
new generation of hardware without
working for two years some most group
need two years between the time that
they start consistence eaving a new
design and they're actually ready to
send that order off to Shenzhen or
wherever whoever's doing the assembly
and printing we're trying to do this in
a very kind of CCC chaotic manner very
loosely coupled loosely structured in
six months so there's no room in there
to actually do the firmware and the
enclosure and the modding and a lot of
other things so that's kind of a sloppy
answer but and there's another abstract
answer as well that whoever gets on IRC
and says I know exactly how to code
firmware and I can I can provide what
ten files it you know and we can do a
nice hello world type of flappy birds
thing on there just to show that
everything's working right and we can
integrate portions of the open source
code from other projects and I can help
with that that's kind of what we need
and that would accelerate development of
firmware as well but we're focusing on
hardware and that's why we don't have
features that are typical of a hardware
wallet at this time we've only been
working on it for about two months two
and a half months
it's over there
thanks Megan for the talk I'm curious
about the history of the project from a
social community perspective can you
tell a little bit how the project went
from an initial idea to a current group
of a large group fairly large group of
contributors and testers yeah yeah it's
um I kind of intentionally short cut the
history portion because it's it doesn't
interest that many people so one thing
that's worth mentioning though is that
before I came on at Def Con in July
there were other people working on
firmware adaptations of Manero source
code for existing hardware wallets and
these came kind of pretty close to
producing something usable for Manero
and they died off in the end or
something happened where it just didn't
work out so that's kind of the
prehistoric existence of a hominid or a
hardware wallet for us the community and
so so I guess I was the first team went
member to come on and and the few people
that I had met in DEFCON yeah you can
read the article it's actually inside
there's endo genic and Ani mole fluffy
pony they kind of they know their way
around the project very well and they
were very encouraging about my idea to
do something with hardware and then a
wallet would be the perfect place to
start and I just came from the black hat
a black hat workshop where I'd produced
my own hardware
I showed it actually the the board the
one with the secure elements so I was
really enthusiastic that's kind of the
start for me of the project and once it
got traction in the community and a lot
of people there was incredible there's a
lot of hate talk on reddit we got past
that we got we got past a lot of
a lot of I don't know boundaries and
things in order to kind of get the idea
that the community agreed that we should
have a hardware wallet that the manera
community controlled and owned because
there's a copyright on all documents it
says them copyright the Monaro project
year so that's kind of the history and
the and the cultural development if
you'd like of the project is that does
that answer your question
yep thank you in what sense and what we
growl in what regards to hardware
wallets add value to Manero to the use
case how would it benefit the value of
Manero yeah so how will a hardware
wallet add value to the Monaro
community ecosystem technology in
general right so some people don't know
this but Monaro is more a project than
anything else it's not only a
cryptocurrency it's not just something
on a ticker that you'll see that that's
you know a value that you can exchange
it's actually a collection of projects
so what we have which I'm quite excited
about it's called Calvary which is a
generic and on an anonymous a ssin layer
similar to tor we've got things like
open alias which is also under the
umbrella of Manero which allows you to
exchange addresses without those crazy
long numbers or optical recognized QR
codes which are captured by cameras or
anything else you just know they're the
email address of your friend and that's
their addresses their XM or Manero
address as well and there's all these
different projects is a number of them
and they all add up just a bit of value
it this is kind of this is the way I see
things that a lot of these people they
have different reasons for starting and
and maintaining their projects but each
of these projects strengthens the
ecosystem as a whole right so what you
end up with is a higher valued
technology in general so you have these
developers that are very well known
they're writing the the daemon the
servers and the
Alliance and they deserve a lot of
praise but what we also have around a
people writing books ebooks what
hardware wallets and I think that they
intrinsically add value to the whole
technology I see that point but I would
like to question you though to like give
us a concrete example where you could
imagine a hardware wallet being of value
right on the market on the street here
at our club what could it be where would
your project your hardware based project
add value um okay
not sure if I understand the question
it's not a bounce of a price no no it's
only about use case how would I imagine
it being used out there right
well I this could be that I could
possibly rephrase a question how do
hardware wallets of any kind protect the
value of a person's virtual wallet of
this virtual currency right because you
can have brain wallets you can have all
kinds of different wallets why does
there have to be something with silicon
parts a two-factor authentication like
Google Authenticator deaths right it's
quite secure already so why would I want
to add to that well I mean two-factor
authentication without a token that you
actually owned it's physical is kind of
hard to imagine right so you have to
have some hardware to make two-factor
work and this is the same type of model
that makes a hardware wallet of any kind
protect and secure a wallet in general
so without that hardware you still have
a wallet it can be a paper wallet that
gets burned if your house burns down you
can get a bank you know bank vault and
then they have control over your
hardware you see the point but a
hardware wallet kind of adds value in
the sense that it's another it's another
type of protection that you can choose
to use in securing your hardware wallet
I think that it's if you're a super
person a superwoman or a Superman then
you have a mobile wallet and you have a
hardware wallet and you have a brain
wallet and you have a paper wallet and
you have a
dusty'll and you have all of these
different things okay that's actually
the best situation because if anything
fails I mean you can argue about it
because it actually increases the attack
vector as well but so this is the
arrangement that you can choose from if
hardware wallets don't exist then we do
lose value in general not just in Manero
but everywhere because you have less
choice and they do play an important
role in securing Hardware just as
two-factor authentication tokens
whatever they are play a role in
securing you know your access control to
whatever server software and you didn't
ask the question but I'll answer it
anyway so some people like to know this
kind of goes along the lines of the can
I buy one one of the requirements is to
make this technology real cheap real
nice on the pocketbook so you can you
can you can you can order one or
assemble one yourself you can pay for
one just experiment and you can pay for
six you can buy six of them I mean if
some of the hardware wallets on the
market they cost about 300 euros and
they kind of they do one thing well they
protect your wallet they do the same
thing as the cheaper ones so we're
considering figuring out a way to have
hardware wallets be produced and go on
to the market so that you can pay 10 or
20 euros for one so maybe less if we get
a sponsor on board you know you can you
can buy five or ten of them for me
that's the essential point of your pitch
there and that the the current devices
cost about 300 euros and you're about to
lower the costs 100 fold 10 fold I don't
know somewhere between that right that's
nice that's nice thats value of course
yeah it's nice for some people most of
the people in the hardware wallet market
they're making a lot of money right now
because their technologies is it's so
expensive
you know we're actually very good
friends with with a competition we
travel out to Prague we travel to Sweden
I'm sorry to Switzerland to Surrey we'll
probably make a trip to Paris all these
places producing wallets and I've talked
to people on the phone and even other
wallet technology like open dime it's
it's just very nice to interact with
them because they're very friendly
people and most are pretty supportive I
mean they lock their technology down
there is no hardware wallet available
for purchase or anything that has a pure
open-source model where they open-source
and everything's free all the
documentation the procedures the the the
project plan the roadmap and so on there
is no other so but so we all we respect
that as well we don't we don't go out to
Turek and say hey you know your
schematic I mean it's it's probably
defective because why other why would
you otherwise lock it down and close it
you know we don't do that we we're
friends and yeah anyway so I can't
remember what question I'm answering
yeah probably blabbing is probably time
to close this off isn't it any other
questions okay give it up for Michael
one more time thank you very much thank
you from the depth of my heart because
you grilled him very very good better
than I could ever do in the hot chair
and if you want to know more about
Manero there are ten about ten or twelve
features that are very easy to learn
about you just have to walk back to the
table there you get this poster we have
enough for you you can take one home and
it's really very well made don't you
think say yes yes I absolutely love it
Michael ten ten reasons okay so people
were wondering sometimes we pass around
chocklit just pass it on
people bring food here I don't know them
sometimes sometimes they're my friends
that's how we do it here in the CCC also
thank you for bringing back all the
hardware is this all the hardware this
is very friendly I love this friendly
community this is a last reminder we
have one more talk later on what does it
say
something about networking scalability
and privacy it's gonna be right here we
still have some free slots if you have a
presentation or topic or something
that's your just your personal kink
contact me or the team we are more than
thankful to give you a stage we have
cameras and audio and you get all the
files to take home and to show your
friends everybody wants to hold a talk
on the Congress right so you can do this
here thank you and see you later