and
the
I also with my country tis Trevor Chiam
from the freedom of the press foundation
founder the freedom of the press
foundation
he's going to be here he will Sulekha
some questions from Twitter that
that you guys have submitted and I guess
is it a good time to remind
people and the press is not a press
conference all the questions
we're going to ask every later come from
our attendees and hopefully they'll be
questions that you're interested in as
well
on please just follow our our guidelines
and everything will be cool
arm and that's on oh yes almost forgot
we have a third panelist will be joining
us
from Russia wanna shower
wanna my real heroes and I think many
people in this room many people in our
community
many people in america Edward snowden
welcome the
the
now
yeah
the
there had helping compatible guys some
had a little bit of trouble here in the
stage but I think I can you dance
microphone
I wanna start out by saying to dan
ellsberg
thank you for everything you've done for
all your service both
in the government and outside government
everything you did for us
as a nation as a society you have given
us you have given so many so much and
told us the truth
about what our government is doing at a
time when the truth is very hard to get
and I have to say I i actually out
I watched a documentary about your life
as I was grappling with these issues
myself
and deter had a deep impact
really shaped my paintings to thank you
for everything
head to I see you've changed since I
last saw you
hike I have to tell you
you don't have to do that for this
audience the well luckily I've
I've got plenty black t-shirts but I do
not have to keep Alexander granddad G
I'll say this for Def Con
so
up I'm gonna try to stay largely on the
way and that these guys cock but I think
there's a few
topics said would like to cover and
to start with I was hoping dan could
describe
on when it felt like the first time you
heard about Edward snowden
on his feelings on hearing his name
and seeing what he had given the world's
and
if his feelings have changed since then
and how he's
he's grown to feel about everson
I can tell you exactly what I shall
hope actually which had not been
great supply for me recently when I saw
this
name in this conference I had mixed
feelings about it
I'll my my feelings of hope
go up and down or I haven't been too
high and no question
I'll I felt though when cell
when Chelsea Manning was revealed I use
to
night you says Conway how how often do
you need a pentagon papers which is a
massive
disclosure that is unequivocal documents
that really shows in one document
doesn't do it as as it knows
and mando they can say well we change
that
the next day that was just some
particular on a little Department
some low-level person originators from
so what you really need is a massive
stuff as in the pentagon papers
the chose know this is what they said
the next day and the day after that near
was the official policy
and so forth and I waited forty years
to hear that and so I was pretty much
losing hope that there would be anybody
inside
who was willing to risk
his freedom his life for her life
freedom to put out what needed to be put
out because I if you put on a lot of
stuff
and I want to get into this with you ed
its technically
you have to be something a specialist to
put on a lot of stuff com
not be identified shell I was feeling
not hopeful it'll come in just three
years after Manning
come snow themselves no question I
thought it is possible
and a in fact I N you once told me
that I you hoped among other things to
show
that one could do this and be successful
and i i'd be interested to hear actually
from you
watcher measure I there's no question in
my mind you have been successful
but what you had in mind when you wanted
to show that people could do this
because after all you are on the country
et cetera well
so then there's a lot of things to
address that I mean that that's a big
topic but you said something I want to
response you first which was you kinda
touched on technology you talked about
how people recently
RR specialists there you specialist
skills
together information is tremendously
important to the public but we've been
denied access
to and they're able to publish that
getting around the world
arm before anyone's able to stop before
their original story
before they're able to basically shot
public
out are the room government you know
this one died or sauce from our
democracy and the keep me there
is that up technology
empowers this is something we seen again
and again people forget yes
because they think about only modern
times the only weathered the recent
samples I think about meeting meaning
now
other people who all in the same sort
for but they forget the technology
actually
in a few people forget about the snack
that
you were you know you know in a garage
with Xerox
she you know a copy machine might not
seem like a killer app to a lot of
people
with that enable you get this back to
the pool
and the same xerox machine negating that
gave us
same is done in the the former associate
why and
what that tells me and what i think is
important for our society
and I don't just mean I mean around the
world is to recognize
the technology empowers individuals
it empowers Boysen how's democracy in we
didn't earn $1 million into a movie
or a woman into world more in as
fundamentally change the way that we
relate to our government
and more importantly the way our
government relates to
us you know they say when people feared
when the government fears people we mobs
we have new we have freedom and I think
that's very true
and we see that more MORE when the
government has been
left Sweden doc even when we have
whistleblowers
who come up and see the great interest
to bring things public
are people like will be times through
arm at Loomis I'll
who end up giving you know these guys
get pole out of the shower naked at
gunpoint
from the things their lives who is
their discredited you know he said
disgruntled
there's these these broad campaigns
brought against them it
they didn't hands heart evidence
they did everything right thing
witnesses in this industry bear
mishap again something very important
happened
are a lot of people haven't seen washing
hostesses anymore
are I former State Department official
who
has basically said I'm he's bound by
classification he had to get the
articles ruled by government to redact
any classified information
were deposited with the washington post
lani basically said
executive order 12 triple which is one
of the sons
Ortiz which allows the United States
intercept basically
communications the current overseas is
being used
to collect incredible a mouse a
communications not just on people around
the world not just listens everywhere
it specifically on Americans which is
precisely with United States government
said
and this is this is the kind of thing
that's dates
illustrated because what he revealed was
explosive
should be on the front page of every
newspaper but instead it's an opinion
article
on one newspaper because there's not
clear irrefutable
evidence that brings the president to
the whole brings
the Congress to you know the press and
says
we have to have a national conversation
where the public is given back
it see stable government and we as a
society
are given the opportunity site where the
lines should be drawn
not a few officials are sitting behind
closed doors and I think that
is a new power
the technology has given us over the
last 100 years
that is increasing in frequency straight
man to
and if we paint with
with and responsibility to use
appropriately to
police ourselves the way our technology
grows and not sleep
law into new protocols into the usages
into new applications for these things
we really think about the implications
output in you know our cities in our
your sneakers and washing machines and
you buy at the grocery store
we will have not dystopian future but
we'll
am a democracy in which citizens
around the world in every country are in
power regardless the policies and their
government and we at the very minimum
will know the truth about world in the
truth our government and it will not be
able to be hidden from us and more
on so add you mentioned
to SA whistleblowers who came before you
Thomas trackers in the front row here
and a bill Binnie who spoke at the lil
last hope two years ago
on and of course on here since daniel
ellsberg most
famous whistleblower in US history were
you aware of their stories
I am prior on to what you did on how
familiar
were you with the pentagon papers and
dan ellsberg
and did you learn any lessons from them
and are there lessons future
whistleblowers can can learn from you
I absolutely i mean i
I follow this closely I think every in
the towns can you did because we're
people forget
is that you know we in public we see the
stories they come on the news you know I
the Justice Department president all
talking heads they say these guys and
bad guys this
wrist country this you know spies have
been charging the Espionage Act a
a they did that when you wouldn't happen
when you look bad
the government to used in their case
particularly as Thomas true
which eventually collapse I and the drop
Jack John
and basically agreed to call it a day
are
you gotta remember that inside the
intelligence community trumpet
these things they're holding these guys
up at as examples to say look
if you say what's going on stuff online
even years even if you doing it for the
right reasons even if you do it the
right call
there will be Rep russians know they
they talk about internal channels mama
these guys used intern chance and they
people like thomas strentz ended up
getting and I and this is something that
I
paid very close attention I'm a great
deal on and I think
it reminds us that you know that the
founding fathers they didn't
height a revolution have a right to
sort by internal process the Supreme
Court this you know some internal secret
policy
is not democracy and that's not checks
and bans
thats your person if we're gonna have
the Moxie
we're gonna have and right enlightened
citizens if we're going to be able to
action baugh
that you know consent the car we have to
know what song has not least the broad
outlines the Parsons
and we can't have the government shut us
now from every action
you know that they do now that doesn't
mean you need to know the name
every single spring it's hard it's out
there and detailed
every particular operation against
factory and more
we have he front as americans
and members of the global no the broad
outlines a
on policies that have a significant
impact on our lives
and I think that's something that the
Tom direction have dude
so damn i text questions for you on
oftentimes I its biggest critics
often invoke your name and
they invoke it in a positive way and try
to contrast what you did
with whatever did but can you talk about
that a little bit how does that make you
feel
and you agree with and you disagree with
them to the most recent was actually
Secretary of State John Kerry
who said that that you are a hero but hi
ed was
was not and sell you spend on elder
well this bullshit in a way started with
like Obama I'll ran
somebody actually took the occasion to
ask him about Manning
I N here in San Francisco concede here
country and San Francisco I and said
Well
didn't Chelsea Manning them Bradley do
exactly what else for did
you know and with with well I could
answer that very strange what he said
was
on ellsberg's material was classified in
a different manner
well that was true in a way
whatever what as I mentioned earlier
everything that Manning put I was secret
or less
and everything I put always top-secret
that was the difference
and to I think the person asking the
question didn't pursue their
a and of course in your case
arm will I'll come back to that but in
your case higher than top secret you
know
communications intelligence stuff which
I would earlier have said
arm didn't deserve to be put out and
tell you see what it says
and then you see it's evidence of
criminality and should not be
subject to criminal prosecution for
revealing it even though it years
higher than top secret so since then
that was with Manning
and I found them 13 2010 that thanks to
Manning and now do you
I'm getting more favorable publicity in
forty years
forty haha because suddenly
people who we're all for putting me in
prison for life before
now realize that I was really a very
good guy I was the
I was the good whistleblower control
I'm I'm totally of course rejected this
from the beginning then I
didn't want to be a forreal for showing
a battery
to people that I totally admire doing on
an identified with
because the inlets leakers
whistleblowers
and I appreciate the mall ones who put
on information that should have been on
their anonymous I don't know their names
on the wall
but the difference here %uh to me with
Manning and you was that each showed
very clearly
as I had felt for years ago a
willingness to put out enough material
that was gonna see your really be
serious but is in prison for life
when when I read that Manning it said
relationship to agree in Lommel
the wrong guy to confide in that
he was willing to go to prison for life
or even be executed
I said to myself I have waited forty
years to hear somebody say that
that's the way I feel forty years ago
and
it's taken this long but so I filled
immediately and identification with him
obviously in your case in Manning's case
in my case
we all have different backgrounds were
different in in many ways but we have
the same access
interestingly not comparable comparable
and rub
different kinds of things soul
identified
with them and I couldn't bear to hear me
getting good press
on from the secretary saying from on
their on the grounds that
my motives were different and go for
example you mention you have some
specific sir
well ellsberg just put out information
that was historical
you know are three years old at the
at the most recent well that's because I
didn't have for most recent
I if if I had had the current
documents I would not have bothered to
put out history
mine high-interest was not in setting
the record straight my interest was in
ending an ongoing war
helping to end an ongoing war and for
that I would much prefer
to put out current documents which a
at that moment didn't have access to
very few people daily in the government
even in the white house. he was a big
secret what nixon was really up to
including nuclear threats and I hope
that my documents would show a pattern
that extended into the present
and I failed are hardly anybody was
willing to extrapolate
and say well ellsberg shown that four
previous presidents
live in the same way escalated in the
same way made the same kinda secret
threats
are truman Eisenhower Kennedy and
Johnson but it ended with those who
attended before nixon
so I thought maybe they'll figure out
that maybe the current president
is doing the same Knoll it took
documents
and I didn't have that so for years I've
been saying
to people it's gonna be with documents
even though the increases the risk
well people know that basically but they
were willing to take the risk I'm sorry
to say
and I'm could do in announcing show them
Manning came out with his
I'll millions haha hundreds of thousands
actually
cables and then you with documents
and it's like Mordechai Vanunu in Israel
with photographs
that Israel had up a nuclear program and
even an h-bomb
that they weren't willing to admit and
it took those documents which took the
risk
so what i'm saying is a I saw right away
without having met you without having
that Manning that
this is someone who I identify with
and at the same time new heroes she said
well as my feeling
I'll heard Snowden's well I have a new
hero
now and so thank you
and
providing would actually follow up on
that I think there's a really important
want there that wasn't no hasn't been
real well
addressed and media and that was you
said you acted
you not to reveal specific in yeah but
end the war the basically correct
seniors policies that were costing lives
costing us the future of our country
critical home
work needs to be changed where we can
step back soon one
enjoy better society and I think people
need to remember that
these these a the stories that are being
published by Jim
posts the journalists working together
editors institutions to really analyze
whether these things
are in public interest whether they can
benefit
us Society tomorrow and one published
since they were just
you know gossip or they don't have this
just haitian on with me. since the
stories
we Dean we not home Lawrence or the new
truth
are all about the fact that I
all over communes are being intercepted
elected in license or automatic
and that means that all OVR years or
of Hallmark's russians or associations
who talked to who me
cool off we had all these things
are not supported to the officials to
the Parsons
of are a few a a few guys behind closed
doors
I and we don't know %ah we can hold into
they don't to us they don't even answer
to the whole bottle
homes their own 8 members in congress
the cop gennady
get full breed on these intelligence
programs and interest in
are the intelligence community the
intelligence committees the response
overseas problems are these guys who
have access to class on
mention Dame receive more
month from actually all every single
members committee
receives money from a top 20
intelligence are
companies United States and they also
receive more
money from these companies than any
other members and cons I in fact
a single one up these %uh congressman
his
his name's Dutch Ruppersberger received
over 350 brain
from D's companies along that's not
always as donations that's just from the
stop on
so when we think about the revelations
when we think about the fact that we've
learned
what's going on we have an ability to be
we have the ability to correct
this fall reach up when we have the
ability the protest
unconstitutional activities never should
have begun we
also have a broader I civic
understanding of how our government
works
we see the most senior officials and
government didn't lie
under oath and making false statements
to Congress noble
James clapper but not just congress not
just a lot more
there are the ones that didn't get as
much attention for example
the Department justice general the
United States
he'd long to the Supreme Court twice
in writing and it was in the New York
Times
well you know this and become the front
page news that you know persists
and we respond to but it was a direct
revolution that came out on the
newspaper
on June's was when we found that people
had anticipated
are to dial back because its technical
terms it's important what happened
is the government was using war
was so its to collect evidence
to justify war applications for warmth
serving
that's a violation about the fourth and
the system in
for people who keep school are and
what's interesting is
they didn't report this to the court's
and he didn't report this to the fans
but then they later told the Supreme
Court that they were and it turned out
that was untrue
if we don't know these kind of things
we don't know are gone we have to be
able to know not just what governments
do but holy
act in order to decide how close the
wounds from my sons
if we didn't have whistleblowers like
you like Tom Brady my everybody else has
come forward
minutes whilst we would have a blast
open less for you must Campbell side
and because of that I think it's worth
taking risks to do this
any its it's not just watching
you know that this scandal is what easy
the scandals what's happening every day
unconstitutional at least they're still
turn right now
the fact that we looking at arm present
want things that can talk about a lot
he's have pics this the fact that a the
most
the least controversial I in terms of do
we can
does this chin is sections yell
and section 213 Patriot Act
basically says the hay we can collect
call records Madacy records from
everyone regardless of whether they are
suspected and crime
in wrong and we have yet
you know what does that do why are they
doing this ones that
because the imprint communications right
they don't get anything this is just
this is just the signaling it's like
we're par
private acts the me who you talk to
when it happened where was that not
I the exact contact what was said
schools
so encryption protects the content but
we forget about
Association and that's what this is
about these programs like section 2
en masse general is not about serving
you
it's not about serving me it's about
supreme
us colette it's about watching the comp
in
for everybody in the country and on a
global scale
this is basically a big data program
which provides the raw data
and then be analyzed seeking seltzer I
can be subjected to rules for
for I it says everything you do
is being analyzed it's being we it's
being
mention and that's without regard to
whether or not
you've done anything wrong are so when
people say
you why does this matter well why do I
care know washington doubles
couch it's because again we think about
this in terms of the fourth
it's in unreasonable singe because
there's nothing to just up to
happened batsman Britain's were the due
process
she's on the system where the government
is basically saying
we're gonna use warrantless surveillance
to collect evidence to then secretly
used to get a warm
or the first time in shins
our freedom tools she right Congress
shall make no
law abridging the freedom prospects
or write to us she the to enjoy the
company
whoever we want if
you what are your rights from moment you
lost them for a lifetime
and that's why this matters is because
it happened and we didn't know
your whole in the post-september 11th
period we had programs
up on stones the correct doctor internet
meta-data
or home in meta data it was screen
on massive he robust dataset
that allows us to look at connections I
and action programmatically
in Los up everybody every polls
all the time and I think that's not good
that's
momentum unamerican thing and I think We
the People
you the people you miss one right now
have both means and capability
to help deal a better future by encoding
our rights into the programs and phone
calls on which means life every day
and that's what a lot of my future work
is going to be involved in and I hope
you'll join me read in the press every
other organization
in making that
so I should mention both dan ellsberg
and now it's known are on frequent press
foundation's board of directors in
we really want to make it our call to
help journals and sources and everyone
can act in a way they can be
protected on from the government size
when
and essentially protect our right to
privacy
and free speech and sell I think
that brings me to my next question for
ed
and this comes from mom one of the asked
own questions on Twitter
is what specifically can designers and
developers
and others working in technology start
to do to make things better
better in are there specific examples
out there that you would like to see
people follow
so when i when i wanna talk about this
it's always difficult because it is
entirely dependent on the threat model
or the individual was offered
you know I gam gam home has a different
set of priorities
then somebody who's working I to report
on the now seasons deeply irresponsible
government and Fort
she I and so generally when I talk about
this lesson
as encryption Persian Persian because
it's an important
first step that denies the government
access to anything more to the grievance
suspicion
which is drawn from Association but when
we talk about how we
it's the stuff for the future we gotta
realize that Association
is often home he doesn't ended action it
starts in
friction because you don't think about
the links
slim the signals that are happening when
I'm emailed you
we gonna can read content the
communication medical
you know why I'm way the government I
who was at work on Thursday
Central Intelligence Agency and the
National Security Agency where the FBI
who works on programs which would be
deeply embarrassing governor
wire--the contacting someone at the
freemen prestige on the Washington Post
The New York Times
and so the tools like securing drop
which are good because their last year
mix round networks locked or
on to this work obviously don't direct
network path but we gotta think about
the fact that today if people are
connecting through phone that's not
super helpful because the phone for
example sees that
you're connecting to toward it seems
you're toward user
on a good example this really bad
example in terms of sex is this recent
American spy was discovered in germ not
he was apparently
alleged in the newspapers spying for the
United States against German
hi he then I guess wasn't satisfied with
with what was going on
so he said hey I'm in shock myself to
what I think are the russians because he
got it email
gene great perhaps I need any help
with the Russian embassy and Asia hey on
saw some doctors he said
oh yeah sure sure and he sent them three
class products
arm now this is an email I don't know
whether it's a and kryptonite for
has women covered in detail with the key
is
I yeah for sure it was on this and
the communication I in this case german
counterintelligence
his mom although he's actual alleged
spot his knowledge
over injures he's interested in money
arm
is a the fact that when he did this
he was the only one who had access to
these documents whose
out of the office at the time took the
day off the Sensei again you know we're
not talking about the most
missed getting on or with this is the
kind of thing you have to worry
in terms of how do governments
I discovered the Raptors
and the same techniques they use to
discover Sly's
to you stepper germs arm
you know that arise in case I and the
rose in case
on both of these are journalists in the
United States where for example
are the government was trying to get a
chance rise in New York Times reports
reveal
source or they were subpoenaing
I AP reporter we all the songs
I all the phones in their office to say
who from the government
all the Associated Press these are
Association
since they didn't get the content of the
calls but they were trying to figure out
what's going on
when we think about how we nixon's
problematic we think about things in
terms of protocols we need to have
for causes a resistant to traffic
analysis be happened
basically even if they're some level
performance Lt see can't look at
differences in for example Skype
conversations and tell which shot from
were
was spoken I'm based on packet size
the signals the so-and-so were on
you also need to use some sort mixed
route some sort shared infrastructure
that die forces
that individual connection from the
individual
origination and that's the heart problem
it's all things were
a performance a performance respect me
toward is a really good job combat tours
all cities
the only person you DP are men and a lot
of things like that
but I this is this is something that's
that's better
really get down and have everybody get
into
sore red somebody pitches and I'm and
young people community whether that's
clear
whether that's a mailing list each year
it's the pure remarked that time do
these things
6 need people to attack these systems
we need people to work with adversaries
on all
so we can fix them and there's also the
user experience
issue for example GPG is reposted pretty
reliable
on encryption unfortunately it's damn
near unused
and he are its fine too comfortable with
command line it's fine if you're good
key management but again game game at
the home is never going to be able to do
that
sort we need encryption
makes routing need are non attributed
communications arm or on attributable
even access URL for example that's
available to people
which easy it's transparent and that's
why
cool on that we can use not just here in
the United States but around the world
is again this is a global prop I the
National Security Agency the FBI
these guys love way because we've got
the biggest budget 100 most rest
but we're only the sparks remarkable
last this is going to be a lot worse
words there and we have to do you know
the grad students in the world
have to be thinking about what they can
do to fix this
anything can have a shared arms need to
think about
how are so worst people
on or going to try this for and Brent
your system not just damage individuals
but today image governments to shield
themselves from
oversight and accountability and what
can you
what do you know what can you think up
to help shield us from and the
techniques wrong with my imagination
at Duke a couple
thing
okay help people were taking notes your
honor I in the darkness
her tech texting on the suggestion
he's giving you your much earlier orders
a good
up they know this stuff just for her
I'll just two things to meet me
gotta like like your have to take this
off but may have to say
with Mike with my hearing problem the
reverberation
earlier before these was such that I
missed a lot I'm sorry I look forward
scenery broadening our on this on the
web I missed a lot of work
say I'm sorry to say but now I can with
this
not when I'm talking
two things we've been talking a lot
about your
people out here helping
sources extreme importance
helping sources anonymously and without
being a tribunal
get there information to journalists to
this story true germs
this entry into the public and congress
very possibly
I'll for example with the overhearing
that we just heard about Kanal feinstein
by CIA I it's a it's real trick to get
this stuff
even to the Intelligence Committee which
kind of a black hole for information
anyway
but I can't get it to them without the
CIA knowing
there is also the problem there isn't
going directly after journalists and if
you're sick this is what I was thinking
if you are successful in inspiring the
people here
to dis to find way for software
the they can really use you know with
even is
I'm not even on Twitter for example
at my age it's enough to be on Gmail
so easy to use
van they need right now when they can
find resources and shut them off
that gives you your government control
pressure a government person is simply
authorized information from the
government whether it's classified or
not
they put out a lot of information is
classified because it supports
their programs and their their
reputation what not so most
leaks a classified information are
actually
authorized by an agency or a high
official winner but supposing it becomes
possible now for that
handful whistleblowers really to get the
information
then they would wanna go after the
byline journalist who prints
now so far they have not done that the
they accept the idea that the public
will go along with prosecutions have
officials
who signed a nondisclosure agreement as
I did
or you did are and without
really thinking at the fact that that
that agreement is not
subject in corporations are also under
criminal prosecution drew
punishment by prison 100 subject to a
lot of other things like ostracism
your job which is enough to keep people
Simon anyway
but supposing now that gets harder to do
when they can't shut off all the sources
they haven't yet going against the
freedom of the press idea by directly
prosecuting journalists
assigns they have kept on I guess you're
always time for the grand jury going
with the threat basically that they're
gonna go after him on the grounds that
he's not a real journalist
something like that mean between person
but
a actually of course as you know when I
know the people
signs didn't do anything that could
possibly really be
prosecuted the question also done by the
New York Times and by the Guardian by
the driver
which they're reluctant to go after its
my
opinion I'm I'm putting this to you but
my opinion
that that lies next on the ground
that supposed journalist called michael
kinsley
I accused bring greenwald and Peter King
is done the same and I think
a number of others and that is you guys
you journalists
are aiding and abetting a a crime
a criminal with the assumption being
from the beginning
it still leaking is criminally meyer et
seq questions to
whether it should be regarded as
constitutional to regard us
as criminals but if you do unequivocally
regard as a scramble
and people like you then the logic
the people who are helping them get the
information to the public
are indeed helping for sure that's what
they are doing
but aiding and abetting is a legal term
and it has to do with the crime and
perpetrating
with David Gregory a on ass cream or
you know in so far as you are aiding and
abetting
his its shaky thing in so far as your
why should you not be punished
so missing you I was really thinking I
didn't bring it up before
to accept that the giving the
information is unequivocally cripple
unequivocally from is I think the first
step almost surely
to going along with kinsley and Gregory
and so many others
aiding and abetting rather helping
publishing is also
criminal seems logical normal are
and they will go there will go after
that
as well so I know is that something you
thought about her
no I mean it's it's a really complex
are topic and i'm taking
when we talk about whether or not the
government begins going
after journalists this is the real
sticking point for me because
in terms all my political loss has the
latest technology here
is I would say almost all minutes
on when of
when we think about three small we need
to think about software
mean that express are freedom but also
defended
are governments remind the same
technologies
the doc the same standards the use the
same
and this happens World War so the
solution to that
I when you ask me is
whether or not the united states
government can manage to
behave itself to restrain itself against
violent
Constitution against bring suits against
journalist against
limiting the freedom press other
governments will make different
decisions
and if we want to live in a better more
online world what we need to do is we
need to remove
those capabilities from the government's
by
enshrine our rights into our means
by denying them those buildings at least
on a massive
on hard-luck occasional can't pitches
Road
every mobile phone never competed out
that works gonna
call any of our research an end up on
you now burge Ars Technica or any one of
these other sites
arm and this can be post-mortem them out
this can be reused
repurpose their find out didn't respect
mom
but governments can still pursue their
legitimate needs
from law enforcement for intelligence
collection on a targeted basis by use
those your days only when they are the
least intrusive
and sensual means getting intelligence
that they require
but it's worth a shot not doing this on
a broad social level when the target
every journalist the top every music see
and this is this is the way I think in
the future
me to focus more more toward how we do
this
and when you talk about journalists like
David Gregory like michael kinsley after
the onset he had
follow that story michael kinsley Arden
basically that was not a place
journalists
to decide what the public should and
should not now isn't a misquote was
that decision as to what we the public
should know must
ultimately be lined up
some people can are but it's a
the key there is that East Dr
representing class
interests and we need to recognize them
as the class like
these germs who are basically
reflexively
going to protect policies
that are working against the public
interest should not be trusted to inform
us right need to mark their names and
remember what the right now
it's helpful that we get all these
different views now they
you participate in the event option for
most mean that more
ideas but at the same time when it's
being done
to actually limited when they're saying
these people shouldn't
make these people should be able to
publish stands
this news should never means we watch
out
because that not ever benefit public
that's making
our society that government institutions
necessarily less
now I mean it's a challenge second
or on in terms of class interested can
we talk about her
Texas and passions holes Julius Ainge
we at one point where is that hackers
world sis
sisson world night anybody out there who
you know
posts on Stack Overflow the Stack
Exchange Inc
arm you guys are parked technical lead
right if you mean her of poor work a
is or hoops were even opened ET now
have a few even for clinics you know are
hmm you're in advocate
that is going to help us move forward
in shifting the middle ground of
technical literacy for the National
right along young people like are they
understand how technology works to
extend
but this is important to him they don't
know what we're doing
right they don't know where the canoe
owns they don't know
I have network works arm they trusted
devices to hang
we all any of us no even the slightest
have a city beauty to help educate
rounds just like the rise of course is
right we have an obligation
to teach people around us how to read
and write
we have to teach people in our society
how iraq
society with our technology safe
reliable in a way that serves the
interests of all of us not just a select
few who don't wanna high priest
technology no matter how good that is
for us
because its best in the world on and
unclear
I I think
go ahead and start no see I was very
struck twice something you said in
Vanity Fair
quarter which is that everyone image
I thought I was restricted everyone a
vision I believe this is absolutely true
has known things that were wrong
saw things has seen things that were
wrong should be known that should be
exposed
and as you put it we have turned our
eyes away
because we were intimidated and I
happened you were speaking of yourself
speaking myself are come back to that
but I i believe that through every human
on earth that there are times when the
bite their tongues
they keep their mouth shut because to
reveal it would
would destroy would lose a relationship
or a given very private matters
or a job or career whatever
and it kept and then you said a then you
said
but there comes a time you know when the
in level with him humanity or the
wrongness
is so great that you have to cross over
that line is he said he said I crossed
over that mine
now to to tell true now
I thought when I read that that's edward
smiled
who get that and that's chelsea manager
and how many others
when you said there comes a time when
you very generally
I'll cross over that line and tell the
truth even at cost
to relationships to your boss to your
friends to your
everything else most people I have to
say
never do reach that mine may never reach
a point
when they decide to take a risk other
own status in their own relationships
and their own shop can attest to that is
that many of them have been tested on
things like
the continuation of a wrongful war of
thousands applies hundreds of thousands
in the case of tobacco
they said 500,000 lives
a year bossed by tobacco look at GM
right now the handful but you know
striking where they deliberately covered
up covered up is
is not only me in the how many people
the tram
know that lives were being lost in
people were being injured and who spoke
I'll
nobody don't think so are tobacco
to people her leg one thing that I hope
from you premier example is that more
people will be inspired
to take even significant risks in other
words were talking when I am
the whole group here about lowering the
risks for people
and that's undoubtedly essential but in
the end
there will always be a risk as you say
an point problems and so forth and the
willingness to take that risk
for civilians is very rare
I it was a as you may know was bismarck
20 people who said
civil courage she owns invented that
phrase signal-caller
the is very I think courage on the
battlefield
is the very common in our country are
perfect country
and at that point uses civil courage is
another matter
very rare its willingness to risk now as
I said before Manning and before you
I virtually give I i have to say it
almost given up on it
and you're showing an example now
Manning didn't get the
art gallery attention but he didn't get
the
affecting this country except as I said
earlier for getting our troops home from
Iraq
that you did and why because I think
in Manning's case he was showing what we
were doing to
other people in the third world for
others
model and you
and i three in my case
with the effect because it had millions
of Vietnamese that were being killed
wrongly every one of them is wrong
when I read the pentagon papers in real
life that from the
for the first time that the very
beginning we were supporting a French
colonial re-conquest to the country
which I thought of it
on american weather was illegal
internationally or not
I'm sure every death in vietnam
as being unjustified homicide
and to me that was murder mash
murder and I couldn't be prouder that
anymore watching well
the american people didn't respond I'm
sorry to say on the whole
sharper people in audiences like this to
the mass murder
but there were 58,000 Americans in the
process of dying them
see and in your case again it wasn't so
much directly dime
but what was being done to us in people
are are objecting to that
so I think we have to have a different
standard a new show the possible even
your colleagues initially as you said
agree with you many of them this is
wrong it shouldn't be happening
but I have a mortgage I have a marriage
I have you know this in their
children to go to college and that was
enough
even though all were talking about this
massive
you know intrusion which is a is a new
world basically the people need to know
about
soap it shouldn't be only you I would
hope that some of your colleagues who
I would suspect let me give you a little
PC experience from my experience
if you were in the room with your former
colleagues now
I would expect them to leave them
that they would not be in touch with you
if you can tell me that the former
colleague from NASA
hasn't anyway communicated with you to
save did the right thing or in any way
help it I would guess there was zero on
that that was my experience at the RAND
Corporation
you lose every friend you have who who
has a clear it sets from that's all your
friends
so liked you're not made of sugar as you
Sean
a you can you can deal with that guy I
for you say yesterday it was in the
paper if I mean change in guantanamo
I can live with that well that didn't
surprise me that that's the
that's the person I find you to be that
was not surprised it's pretty unusual
statement
you know after orgasm well let's make it
a little less unusual
I'll you win in the Special Forces try
to get there
and your legs broken so forth golden
I used my marine training in vietnam is
a civilian
I marine company commander in peacetime
and so a user training in vietnam so I
saw combat I work with troops in combat
there you see current physical courage
every minute every day a people
same doing the job was trying to say the
conference room
the kind of courage is marvelous I
marine one set on cock at terroir
uncommon you would remain
uncommon courage was a common virtue
okay right
when you're doing it for the boss for
the commander in chief with the applause
appear country even if you don't get the
approach most of it is anonymous
but you know they would approve you with
a new ever
what they were doing in a they would
hold you accountable with you didn't do
it
we should have a different standard than
we do for civilian officials
and not just official you know one of
them regarded himself as an official but
a middle-level person
you shouldn't be simply that you were
the extraordinary hero that we thank
it should be that we should ask the
question of those other people
hi me do you think you could keep this
secret that long
keep it totally keep your miles a lot of
blood is road because people better
times
and swallow their whistles and dry
didn't speak out
and it's time I think that we not
prosecute them but tell them
that is not the way to preserve
democracy you were not
fulfilling your oath and I'll just him
by saying
people ask as I you is the Patriot
or trader you know that's the headline
in all these things
Edwards no patriot air that drives me
nuts the very thought you know
that people could regard he was a
traitor the ignorance
up the media and the congresspeople and
the other hand the interviewers
grace that question offends me is an
American think think
that it can be traitorous to tell the
truth to your fellow
countrymen what
to standard I would like to see said I'm
sure the standard I would like to thank
known was the one person in the fucking
NASA get what he absolutely should have
done how many people should have done
what you did
the killed healthy man
confidence about country when it came
out I see it now
I'll pp interpreter we all took the same
old
to uphold and defend the Constitution
have already said
the people who violated all the time
thousands are people who
who are against it like changing some
other when it comes to
proving that poll no one
in the US military services up to the
commander in chief
has fulfilled her oath
to defend and support the Constitution
like Chelsea Manning
and no one in the US executive branch in
any branch
his filled your oath the oath to uphold
support the Constitution
as well as you so thank you
that's hot I would harm
I'm still politically very modern
you know I think it's funny very first
time
I I met gland removed sort
the lead journalist talk to in hong kong
he called me a wrap
and that was a surprise me because that
was the first time I'd ever been home
decal
but he didn't mean it that way he called
you work
set against arrest a poet
radical action radical action right on
with his I think there are so many
people throughout the government
throughout the country we're trying to
do the right thing as you said
there is this this burden this
compulsion
this are operation inertia
where they feel you know they
we talked about its new office are
people who saw this as well
who agreed this was wrong who were
disturbed by and
who felt we needed to do something but
at the same time we all have a sense
we all have more we all have lives we
all have things we want to do things we
want you
and you did you did too right
why I mean I'll of Hawaii everybody you
know I i don't have to say I love my
friend
mom but you put a person's risk and I i
mean
the highest possible on when I walked
out of the office from
why on last day was that
I would never make it out on your mom
but I accepted that has I knew that
as you said earlier we all have to win
it the
level incivility inhumanity you can see
and do nothing about and when you cross
that line
you have to do something but at the same
time we can't
we can judge people too harshly
for human nature people have a different
analysis a different weighting
risk at least for me are what's
important forces not
and then between able in power I don't
wanna take
negative stance judging them and saying
you didn't do what you're supposed to do
you didn't do which use more will do
even if that is the case
I think a min from an engineer's
perspective no how
can we its how can the people
in this room reduce the costs action
how can the people in this room how can
people around the world who can
n machine what's happened the last year
what
thoughts %um about how we can make sure
we get the truth what our government
spending
that we have a seat at the table with
government regardless
how to 410 government regardless of what
their response will be
because when they do something wrong we
will now
and they don't know who told the world
and
critical misses the point this is not
about in this is not about you know one
thing how
welcome this is about time when
governments real
its that when they do on wall
things when they do on Constitution
things were when they do things that are
entirely legal
comprehensively in more we will find out
about
that will change war that will change
the way we
because the problem today is when you
bring
you know I case when the system we have
today
is I secret agencies
operating under secret policies secret
interoperation
interpretations loss overseen by secret
courts
rusty words 35 use have said no
only 13 times out 35,000
when s the way it comes and you know
they're overseen by the
congressman we're gonna pockets stuffed
home a lot of times like these
intelligence contracting companies are
what
the government has done when we look at
this anyone other steps
isolation fact that it takes 10 years to
get this for dinner
open chords at the supreme court's that
the secret war
when we look at what that is and
isolation any step it might look like
you know clever morning by the cup but
when we look at Copper
it comprehensively one he is is the
government has developed
and expunge the Copperhead provides
basically the room
passable to our constitution the escaped
the sandbox our democracy and they're
basically
using to change are built rights
without mercy and we will go what is the
bill right say
brutus I miss all well for a moment
still there but in reality it's gone
something completely different happen
beyond behind-the-scenes
and we can't allow that and the only way
we can stop that from being
retrospective action where we go back to
investigate and try to figure out
who did something wrong who we should
hold to account is we have to make sure
we stop it
work at only way that's going to happen
is we have transparency
we have accountability to the senior
officials who popped up in the first
place
and
well very good
are I for civil let me say I
I agree I understand what you're saying
don't condemn these people working on
that is the important thing
but you when I are talking we're having
a real discussion here because we do
have a somewhat different focus
and I happen to think that both
approaches are important
when we think actually
when I I keep mentioning is forty years
between nineteen 73 with my trial ended
in 2000
13 when you came out
for years or 71 2010 so for
I in fact came to feel that I was
apparently just asking too much
that somehow you
you keep saying you know everybody has a
limit
and what I was seeing was no
a few people have government and most of
them have
note that by the way as you said there's
no question at all times
there are people in the system who are
criticizing
were raising questions were even using
this is
wrong or what not up to a point as you
did
before you know you went all the way and
talk to other people
what their limit is going outside going
outside channels going to the public
going that moment
doesn't get across the taking a risk
even complaining or criticizing
some and the they may even lose our jobs
as result
I eventually but they get another job as
long as they haven't broken that promise
to keep their mouth shut about anything
see they can get another job they can be
trusted the
they will stay inside the system like
dreadful and wait
during the Vietnam War but they don't
I'm
so I i come to feel nobody apparently
know what it can do this I don't know or
it so necessary in it so obvious
the price %uh not doing it the price the
government achieving
total control total control I love
the embarrassing things in the plans are
going to
is Vietnam War and the Iraq war
the approach to climate we've had right
along
the nuclear weapons policies which are
incredibly reckless shame shame
Lee reckless that have gone on without
exposure from people inside
they don't have a limits or something
met you in Manning did show me
there are some people out there I've
always felt that they were more
who had the capability to cross that
line then we were seeing
and that you know the advantage and your
approach
is to make it less dangerous less risky
and I agree that's the central and can
be done and the people in this very room
are contributing to that encamped richer
as we
we were speaking last time you and me I
have
being not a technologist less optimism
about technology
then you have you know infinitely more
about it than I do but
I'm more than twice the age you are and
the future of Titanic's let's say is
is in my mind even though I that was
before me but
on the challenger for example and I
don't put my
I it's hard for me to believe that all
these people together
will make the process of telling
embarrassing things about
the government which is exactly what the
public needs to know to hold them
accountable to have an influence on
policy
that that can be made totally riskless
I think that there were there will
remain a risk of some kind and I think
that hurts and I don't think we're ever
you probably agree with that yeah
there's never going to be a holy
risk-free in but we can do is we can
mitigate
yep in britain trying to get a little
bit more available a little bit less
painful
ago arm and yup its
want to get one for your permission this
is crucial it's crucial that they do
that what you're saying is crucial
but i just want to put in a word for the
what I've been saying here
which is the hope that people like like
you
any other speaking out here timed recon
just one reader
and the other who have spoken the truth
that people can be inspired other
that they will be more
whistleblowing in there has been even
given
risk and you know I was
handed him here we were coming in a
thing from expose fact which is a poster
that is I'll appearing in in Washington
right now
and it has a with my picture and has a
big headline
saying don't do what I did because
are I E for years
didn't want to talk about people I
talked about civil disobedience in the
need to do in connection with nuclear
things in order
gotten arrested more than a few times
over and i won people generally did not
have
access to classified information so I
wasn't talking to people who
had their taxes journey they won't let
me talk to them
and the anyway getting audience here and
so
I didn't want to say you should be
whistleblowers
because it sounded too much like saying
do what i do. in that same self
self-promoting and then I thought it was
a
with the recording on that poster a new
way to put it
don't you way to war
his started don't wait till thousands
more have died
before you tell the truth with documents
and it doesn't say it on the sign but he
said even at personal cost
even interpersonal risk that people
should see
yes you're not in prison but you are an
exile
and probably I have to say I see very
sadly I think
indefinitely I don't do not see this
congress
and a in any future president to this
one
changing the law and they should
rescinding paragraph Eve 18 USC 793
which should be rescinded as
unconstitutional I don't think that's
going to happen
and that means you couldn't come back
and have a fair trial
ever I that I really foresee in this
country
I'll in other countries that they may
change our laws that's in process the
following a public interest defence
and allowing an argument but I and I
would love to see that in this country
but I don't see it happening so that
means you have a fellow
for many people that could be a negative
well look
he did it and picture telling us to do
can come back to his own country
what the fact is you shold first of all
you're not in prison
if you came back here as you know and I
know
you would not be able to talk to the
public
make your case to the public the way
carry and
weaken ever juju Henry actually said
make your case to the public which
actually affects the legal
all ship you would be in an isolation
cell like Chelsea manning up for two and
a half months
but for the rest of your life I believe
from the moment you
you were arrested so you could not make
your case the way you can
in are going for the whole world right
now so it's essential
it was I said this reason it is
essential for you to be out of the
country
when you major revelations was another
difference people said well dan ellsberg
say
faces for all the whole thing altogether
but you could I was able to speak
demonstrations the interviews everything
as you're doing now from outside the
country
inside the country even while the FBI
was looking for me I was on walter
cronkite
in the evening I even using an
undisclosed location
in Cambridge we've gotten very excited
an internal here either I am the the
FBI's with 30 the world
and I'm on evening news well you are too
but you had to be out of the country and
was essential that the people hear from
you
so what I'm saying people can look at
him saying
here is a guy who understood that it was
worth taking a risk
worth risking in even sacrificing
personal relationships
on so great you're her father was able
to go to Russia and see you but you know
if you if you're in a situation so not
so much you know
so Chelsea Manning has never been
interview
by reporters from the time she was
arrested in kuwait into
no reporter has been able to see her
face to face
and talk to her will you have the you
would have the same
prospect and it's worth it
you did the right thing I don't even
have to ask you whether you regret
paying this price I can't even imagine
you know wouldn't hurt you
I never met a person who went to prison
against the draft
against the war and all other who
inspired me to give the Pentagon Papers
I don't know why I'm whoever told me
they were granted 23
years in prison thanks man so that's an
example
it has to be seen yes lower the risks
also get the message out it's worth
taking the risk awards with a lives may
be at stake
in our democracy in your case is that
state thank you
and one their their couple things I
could
saying on that just real quickly because
I I think we're running down on time
but the we had an extra twenty minutes L
ok keep talking we can go to a
we got a 50 okay
arm there's a lot
I'll one of the things which you touch
on patriotism
a little better and I think everybody in
this room
would agree you know most most the time
people who attend her conferences are
marks last my but geena Petri
doesn't move you know obedience
to putting aside
your obligations to your people to your
country
for the benefit of your government is
the office
pic is oaths to it or
I want most dangerous & Co Roces things
a person to greet you in society and
culture around what we
require I'll what we should
which are oaths now
its my like our Constitution she didn't
want us to stand up for our Constitution
say
you guys this is most ridiculous shit I
have ever seen you know you're smiling
everybody in the country and everybody
world you not even bothered
querer real means your secret arm
you not only brings
now initially expect us
to do that if they expect us to stay
site
in the face extraordinary masses
widespread violations of the
Constitution
they shouldn't ask us to take the oath
first place you know because the nazis
are there is there something else
you mention their moms actually a really
short work members are completely lost I
was thinking
year Swiper you're too young tender to
your
I a lifetime
means law yes things like that will do
that I guess
child on the Internet but really it's
how we come together
we fix the problem right we we know what
we have but the key is you talk about
the way things are
you talked about the system we have
today you talked about the
proclivities almost use or protect their
own interests to the detriment
up the people to the detriment of their
own homes to the judgment
themselves the second come because
comfort is a tremendous
you know more than when we talk about
hun captures in on the Internet
home it sounds stupid but we loved ones
you know the the mean a lot to us
but the key is when we talk about
government
saldovar you know again a attacking the
hypervisor
our democracy getting out there and you
know it it's changing domain
the boundaries our rights without
telling us about
if they can do it to the fourth in the
system and they can do in
right you may say I'll X
don't care about spun recommend spying
on me its gonna
right when you see when you see
not just the Prince's but the wrongs
that are in here you initial make
apartments
okay these are rights that are in here
my nature
these are writes that long to human
condition he's a rights third
deepened up and the kids were peeled
back in time you never did it was that
it's gonna get worse arm the founding
father said
people yet the government desert
newspeople
aren't willing to stand up people
willing to take yes
to reveal long even if it means they
have to burn their own life
their families you know their their
children
descent and everybody after us the
values that they hold dear will
disappear
world and we all inability to push back
against
we all have you to contribute you know
in that the open source movement is a
great example of this
but it's not limited a problem its
no politics is the way we miss the way
we talk to our hearts
when we talk Orton's we have the ability
to build
and more almost there just society every
and even technologies dangerous and
destabilizing
when we don't think about when this
before when we think about increase in
robot is a she workforce
the fact we have young people who have
tremendous
student debt never been result that's
not dischargeable
bankruptcy proceedings thanks government
without arm
we have a new class that our intentions
I in a very new and modern way that's
for corrosive
to the sort to Gallatin deals
that we as Americans aspired whole
and if we don't take chains don't take
risks to push back and say more
we have a place missus we have in place
in this world
you guys them are not gonna represent
public's interest you can represent who
you can represent
you can represent class interests
exclusive to the detriment
the left or that coochie in that seat
we're going to bill new site Ranjan
and thanks to the same technology that's
lead us in many ways we are now in power
in New its you know when we when we talk
about all these things will talk about
massive
announce when we talk about the fact
that you know
we've got its famous inquisitors in
history it said give me six lines
written by the hand at the most honest
man must find something to hang him with
no we're not talking about and positions
from medieval times were talking about
Keith Alexander
not and its up to us to change that
because we can revoke
that homes on we can try democratic
BodySpace
now if they say you're gonna exclude you
on that day
if we're going to exclude you from those
discussions if we're gonna
play games like they're doing the UK
when the past are
an extraordinary expansion span one
spouse just last week
under the guise emergency law when
they've been ignoring the emergency last
year
arm we have not just
the capability but we haven't
obligation to push back against
to Creekside what
so easily with government which
questions
so we'll have about two minutes left I'm
do each if you want to take a minute
to on address each other or
address the audience
we we really do agree fundamentally your
because you talk about
talk about bypassing the people who
don't take risks in the government
building a new technology I just wanna
say that
to will take risks in other words people
as we know from Aaron Swartz's we know
from the others
who've gone down here basically
German him the other the and Tom Drake
who tried to do this
and very gerd we be in for
tried within channels dual there is risk
even if you don't get prosecuted
if you can so people will have to be
willing in all the serbs even here
even here it will people take risk
possible you remember
tundra yesterday just what we talk about
it you when I talk a lot about the
Constitution
and rights jewel that's not
in the end that's not the beginning in
and up the problem here
after all the Constitution or thrice
slavery
for a long time the Fugitive Slave Act
was upheld by the Supreme Court
and the people who violated that a great
risk we're doing the right thing
rosa parks are refused to sit together
for mercy
she was violating in in Montgomery
Alabama she was driving along urban
upheld by the Alabama Supreme Court
if thats modern oxymoron sometime but
the
on the fact was once civil disobedience
was mister if they change the law
or I should say if the Supreme Court up
holes for the first time
it's never addressed this question the
espionage her with its strict liability
with its no public interest no not
without any the changes that are
necessary in if they are poll that and
say its constitution we would've lost
pretty much over First Amendment
and without the first commander in the
fourth amendment and other things
and that will have to be violated at
that point
will have to be civil disobedience at
that point in the supreme court will
said
5 a.m. maybe more maybe six will have
its constitutional to allow for
government solely by
him down and one journalist will live
with that michael kinsley and David
Gregory will take their handouts
are with with no problem allow the the
government
to have the last word as to whether
something should be redacted or not
they'll still be newspapers as in China
but the fact is we will have lost the
independent branches
we don't have much in congress now or in
the courts
but something with will have lost the
ability to rebuild their
and the affect will be say more
unnecessary wrongful wars handle
so more climate deprivation and so forth
so we need more people like you was I
keep saying
many others but also people who were
less courageous if I may say but who are
willing to take
some risk and to discover that there are
limits
to what they will put up with that in
this audience and Amin
government and they will quickly find if
they ask that question that there are
limits
and I should be willing to take a risk
they'll discover what I
discovered in 1969 the government is
gone
beyond those limits for me and they have
to be explored
and with that I think we'll be right
there
will be hard to find the limit if you
start asking yourself whether there is a
limit
mother should go across a edge in any
closing thoughts
at are just real quickly
look around everybody
whose in this from
run and recognize that weaker broad
cross-section
people who are thinking about these
issues working on these issues affect
issues there are people from the NSA in
this one
right now you know they they pay travel
hostile conferences in
my min people who go and read a little
ports in the share
everybody else go to different tracks
they make sure they see all the fun
starts
arm put the keys even for you got to
work for the NSA who were in the room
much longer to do I'm not telling you
what to believe in
you know and its okay if you can it's
okay if you disagree with me
it's okay for everybody you know
to look at this because we have to
decide how we feel
right we gotta stop honking that what's
on the news
is the gospel truth once she says behind
dunno
poem is exactly the right answer what I
say something that you hear a lot of I
could be totally fall she
you gotta figure out what you believe in
in Staines word you have to stand
for you now and whether I'm a good guy
weatherman whether I'm here or whether a
traitor
none of that matters criticizing he
I think about what matters in issues
run think about the world you want to
learn nanoparticles
I could ask you to do one thing thank
you to everybody
on and thank you panels for everything
the
thank you
the I can hear the whistle really well
the
I can you have even better
thank you
the
and
and really don't know what does not the
and you know what to do when this
happens
okay our hands are gonna be hurting for
a few days but it was worth it
thank you at Snowden thank you Daniel
Ellsberg thank you trevor Tam thank you
attendees for making this such an
amazing experience
I think it really made history today our
schedule is a bit late so
things are going to be one hour behind
one hour delivered a change
so we're going to try and start the the
next auction of three tracks
as close to four o'clock as possible
please
file orderly into whatever direction you
wish to file an arm
I had and continue being responsible and
on
and have a lot of fun alright
will season