rules
up love
and with us all of it now but
I'm quality you go back up
justifiable their you
it up was
really up marvelous
him I especially a availability is
learn a lot now you know we r hey higher
road before good up but in other words
well sorry have I don't say to keep
ourselves from the
warblers trend I'm unita
all ourselves to a higher ethical
standards so yeah well
their ground rules up
for as much logic only up
he heard under partial
her up look but there exists the
possibility of breaking love you
and it gave Europe
on by the front door well you know there
is a possibility
bring a and then you have a locksmith
wish generally of
money and Yahoo or month satellite
I and you only get lost you know what
all these on the table the
are purchased and used for the express
purpose
love or passing day is that you no
longer
for a while us yeah yeah I don't say
anything
yeah their way see what and
I so
dole up scared people
alright every fun
are I'll lot a secular basically
about school buses that are not working
prather
and my but what is fire yeah you're
silly
at and I have the light will enable I
could wipe all your firewall rules way
you know there is new real attack that
once
something a little after size you know
the right
God or other your home or intended yeah
I S
causes so you know it by
what years old with light and buzzer
henry's able to avoid listening to a
phone conversation well inside the
building
you know that security implications of
them
and so really is with good at it all
your hard work to your superior network
infrastructure
from yeah side of things really just
gets
undermined by the guy going home depot
and binder physical security hardware
because visible security really is but
the trunk are it doesn't matter
%uh Monday yes one of those exactly
but uses your goals it happens
maybe long so yeah really is
it's just you know a fight the blaster
systems it's already game or I could
pull off a hard drive second-lowest
something directly to your computer it
just
you know that is the trump card so
because you're kinda
matters little bit too um so
always will also look like this in the
you know some sort of container
but they look like that in Tylenol or
a problem like this all lots even though
they look
you know fairly different from the
outside on on the inside they're pretty
much identical
so that he sexually with a look like is
here
you have a X your house in the long run
this is the interior
or the plug the thing that I actually
wrote it since I N
get the key way here which is the way
that he goes then
the kelly also typically has come up a
little warnings here
and all these really do is they serve to
where they serve
I the purpose of preventing Aqeel one
system
from being inserted into another sister
right so get a sliding door
you know totally can't insert into a
quick set or record
so who is like this open we can see the
interior the cylinder
we can see the pen staggered because
that is made with three parts
a spring a driver been and keep them
some people may refer to as the top and
bottom pin hole or try to get away from
that
because especially you go over to europe
and they're not meant to like this
they're mounted like that so you're
referring to the top and bottom
containing very different things
people but from here so this is the
driver been detected the driver
much trouble the worst rather keep it
think that's the key done this here
service in the same day real life long I
wanna you know
same thing the other house in La Feria
that intercourse flooding
get the can stack and the spring driver
waukegan yeah so as far as how this loss
operate you know if you're just to try
to turn the cylinder
so how does look here here and I'm just
gonna get this
and just trying to turn he obviously
doesn't turn I
her so what's preventing that well it's
just
you know these kids are physically
preventing
that lock cylinder plucked from turn we
call a binding action
so but we insert the property
it raises the spins that cup to form
what we call a share lying there
what's your line is when the separation
between
the driver been and keep in lineup with
separation between the house and the law
adequate minimal are the pluggable when
the separations lineup
well look at that point that you're
right there and there's nothing he now
looks older
rotating solo case at exactly
other have a place in the bath which
actually a loss along no
again rosa her lifelong
he wasn't raised but not great
sure will have their what the share
owners and graded
the locks overturns roe case and opens
so question oh there's more than just a
single penny stock companies lost like
to hope so
I typically especially among the feel
cheaper american
lot packet loss
you only really how the variation on the
ski pants here all these
driver panzer process there and so
course the sizes love these keep them
score late what we call the believe the
key or the clue to the key
so if you wanna see how it works you
know that he goes in
these pins right along this period he
when he is fully inserted
shell informs alway cost of its own
what that chillin forms well again
nothing appealing law concerning
an opening so does
Sophia the in crafting
looks like they're both of the balloon
sorry that
bad at all
but alright XLVI incorrectly
presence the second cut right here as a
little bit too low
and so it'll be buying on just the tip
love that better and I there and that's
enough to prevent the loss column for an
opening
over to our same thing the protein
binding like keeping their
is this Luther on don't have any
questions about how long operates
okay so now what that mean ol kinda
Howell
you know a lot worse we can look at
actually
exploiting you know certain liabilities
are what nunn
especially picking la copa so we're
trying to imagine the inside the
cylinder
you know same here you know I want to
create a la cry I want to compete with
Ashleigh
quick set one up and so you know I trial
along design diagram in AutoCAD or
whatever bye prefer you know SolidWorks
sir
computer aided design program is I okay
you know I'm a place to manufacture has
made goes okay we'll
watercolors on go oranges
you know with I did crated in you make
it right
well tolerances are essential you know
how old
consistent things are to come off the
assembly line
so you know you could have even if
you're a mean with say a
diameter one milliliter you could have
been coming off the assembly line at 0.9
millimeters for one but 10 years you
have that parents
right and of course the higher haunches
their use your views are much more
sensitive
a machine which really factors that
process
you go okay well you know if you want to
use a higher tolerance is this law is
going to cost a lot of money on go on to
compete with
he'll play in fact that one of her for
well you know
then we have to start keeping the
process you know using a little bit
less precise machines using materials
that there's been no holes
feel or what not you know we'd make it
out cheaper materials like brasser maybe
even sing
as you keep making this whole month
I if you're trying to mount another
perfect will law
you know all these pitfalls will be
exactly circular right along its
management center line
and you apply a light turning pressure
all in fact that you buy it at the same
time right well
it actually is not the case because %uh
these you know
cheap enough the manufacturer partners
and even matter fact and professions
um know this is all other maple
impossible so if we look at this this is
a brand new law clerk to pressure the
package
and can see that it's some sort DeBary
mechanism
at the top of the voters polls and you
know this is introducing
these inconsistency is reason to fashion
a perfectionist
at these pins that bin Laden cutter 10
you can see there past infancy there's
little imperfections not casting process
there
I miss even go down to you know how
often
do you replace girl Italian right is
every time it really goes in a little
bit where the heart of gold
and it makes the next rule very very
slightly different
through and so you know there could be
other a
operations like is to be slightly
overweight in shape a little bit of a
long as much as race airline
but well as add up to is when I apply a
light turning pressure
this owner only one these bills taxes by
anyone hire
I'm kinda thing that is like the honest
one out you know say if I had
her 3 p.m. right here in this one back
here this one is here and this one here
well you know if you draw a straight
line this on buying first on that one
not one right so that
letter said this is Karla add up to make
blocking possible it's kinda like
you've all seen like the hacker movies
where they go up and put the lights up
against Norton
the numbers fly by goes okay cracking
cracking
into next want 4
well you know those of you who are more
secure specials
you probably realize that passwords and
door locks in one hour
not like crap like that I notes you take
the whole hospital whole thing with the
whole thing but
looking how it works like packing
worsened movies we only really working
on one part this
solar a one-time so to just see the
general process
I mean first we apply a lettering better
and then we internally the whole paper
halftime inner know your preferred
lifting cool and we're just going to let
this can stack up
and so I will be talking about a few
things that you may
you know feel or see or hear even
I'm don't be afraid when going past them
that you're not feeling is that
this is just you know this is why long
Uniqlo actors
right is your cut train your fingers to
feel these things
and so what will actually happen is when
this gets its share
this plot will rotate a very slight
amount will rotate enough to form a
little look here
for this keepin' to have a restful her
sorry
ever been to address book on the keypad
will then be free to follow
downer you never got to tell the tale
right so
you know how this happened to basically
is on to the next higher
and so when we actually will get taken
as
and we apply veterans pressurized
are cutting tool apply attention
pressure that trying pressure
and you can see here that was the
binding to of course we don't know this
summer's going in
your traffic flow but we're going in
with her
look back here kinda feeling around
again it may not be immediately
perceptible to you
but the bike has docked actually
slightly
different a little bit harder to live
because think about it I mean
fraction as we added the whole process
you'd house unlocked wants to go this
way
and the coral of the one so this way and
they're just you know
their actively percy against both sides
that
the I'm fictional whole process makes a
little harder to lift
but again don't be afraid if you're not
actually feeling that you're first
starting out
so essentially just repeat that process
hunting for that bind
pin all throughout this lock and tell
opens up its
and lots of things hold so a 100
questions on a
him alright so to go
a little bit more interesting details
here is about you know how things
actually and work and what not
what we're talking about here is was
called Liberty picking or single parent
dating
on this is generally the thing you want
to try to practice with
you know this is the things that is much
for school base its
as you will get better and better it
will be a look pic higher and higher
costs the looks like this
and there is another technique though
hold rating
and this is usually worse you know the
tools to how little squiggle
or some sort of all shape that isn't
you're just a single
litter or single thing and basically
those are rick's
so how Redfin works it's a much more
look based activity
we inserted into all a pleasure to
pressure only just going here first
correcting around me a very angles
kinda moving up and down hopefully by
luck expect ok
as the thing about repeated if it's
going to work it's definitely going to
work
relatively quickly right I am
and so it is a much more lot basic
happens the lace
which is why a lot of people to start
all really you know take to rate
because he was working I cannot the
marksman but
before other thing you'll find a
breaking is especially when you get into
the
a you know more difficult levels a loss
I'm especially getting to you know
security plans and
Parihar what up really becomes much less
effective
I mean in competitions so the first
thing I i try because you know it's
gonna work is work going to work quickly
I'm but singleton picking is really
nothing wanna practice to get to the
higher
you know work that Olympic
so a little bit on tension for usage so
first off you know I love people well
I should do senators I'm here I we talk
about a few things that
you know I find work for most people
don't be afraid if it doesn't work for
you
block witness although passing in trying
different things and find out what works
for you
so what i'm talking about things but
feel free to try different ways
BC 52 they work for you awesome users
but this curve you know gives you a
little bit of a starting off point
so generally I don't want attention with
my phone because I find I get a little
bit less control over that
and so generally I want to use my little
pointer finger here
know here I prolly still looking like
this because I find that when you pick
with your finger up here you have you
know
a little bit I less control over its so
by answer this like that you know here
I have much less control over the
variability up that tension pressure
than I do
you know much more out here so I can
recommend kinda stretch it out there
are still not quite there because you
notice the finger straying away
which generalizes obvious I know you're
putting way too much pressure on
attention
it really is not require much I'm
I'm in fact if I just have a locking up
and I have a property well I the term
really really doesn't
and so really it's just I a quiet too
you know
roughly about half the amount press
download laptop keyboards
iron you know imagine the way to three
butterflies the end of the year
more visual learner it really does not
require much though
in fact you'll probably find that we're
passing picking you know it takes a
while that long but he took it block
try to get a little bit later per
attention pressure on
and you may even have your cock pic I'm
so like I said it's very obvious when
you know your fingers for train white
you take your figure a way has line
across
finger at the very clear indication is
in a bit too much trash
pressure so
a there are two main considerations when
you insert essential into the
tool are so it's the clock the first
thing is you don't put all the way at
the bottom
is if we put all that bottom well
you know this piece the middle here will
essentially be
running up against the house in lockers
and no I picture the whole process
and make things a bit more difficult to
were to take over
secondly you want how you know another
room up here to be able to insert
essential and
you know maneuver around busy don't have
that's room
well by have I tend to like this
you know I have no room to go anywhere
little actually manipulate
the individual yes so they're those main
considerations
I'll there's I you know
what people have tools for free to share
I think I may have some for public use
as well
I have a number lock so here they want
to start with they have numbers on them
%uh those numbers indicate how many
planes within the Saunders so
seizing one for example will have just
wanted and everyone sort of like that
keep on going to go to and what not I'm
one thing about the
the one can lock actually why was it
about this
is more similar things feel good because
it doesn't require much dick gets off
and I just a potential
answer like that let that thing open it
up
and of pixel
and so really my eyes no real challenge
you'll be able to pick it opened
revealing it's just the big thing is
is learning how things feel so first of
turning insert sexual inside look
weekend is think this law takes say I
hope it
and it feels like so what we're feeling
here says there's no tension pressure on
their
is just the pressure in the spring
pushing down right now
so this is kinda more how a.m.
non-binding Penn Hills
now we can take turns into old inserted
into the lock
apply a light rain pressure and that is
all I want him back in like we know that
is the buttons that right
and so this is kinda hello feels when
you're working at the plant in stock
there and then you get that sack up pick
this year
and enter nope so
feel free to trial local laws out there
and
if you have questions let me know thanks
bird
on
your