all right welcome back for this next
talk we've got Alyssa Miller and that is
the the coolest most awesome stylize
[Music]
like beginning to a slide deck that I've
seen that is that is awesome I love how
it looks embossed like it looks it looks
raised like it was stamped out like a
license plate that is super cool can I
say stupid PowerPoint tricks you know
[Laughter]
yes so this is I think there's a really
interesting one I'm glad we got a talk
like this that you submitted something
like this you know I think we've seen a
lot of fraudulent stuff in the years but
but very few that like viscerally
physically give you chills when you see
them in action
and deep fakes are are super creepy I
think most people will agree so yeah if
you're well we're one minute away I
think we should wait until 3 o'clock
just uh just to be fair okay you know
we've been bang on starting right on
time throughout this so I don't I don't
want to start one early and somebody
that might miss something but yeah
thanks for coming to talk at I believe
you you're not oh man look at the guitar
collection in the background alright we
if we were super early we'd have all
kinds of stuff to talk about I've I've
actually been playing guitar and bass in
between presenting people here well it
is three o'clock and if you're all ready
to go I will turn it over I am all set
take it away Alyssa
you
all right well welcome everybody my name
is Alyssa Miller and you have joined me
and the rest of the folks here for
losing our reality deep fakes changing
the face of attacks so if we've not met
before let me tell you a little bit
about myself first
first of all foremost I am a hacker and
a researcher I have been a hacker all my
life I bought my first computer when I
was 12
taught myself how to program in basic
quickly learned asynchronous modem
communications and started playing
around with a service that unless you're
old like me you might not have even
heard of prodigy before so yeah I've
been doing this pretty much my whole
life
I'm also an application security
advocate for a company called sneak if
you haven't heard of us I can talk to
you about that some other time you'll
have all sorts of contact information
for me later I'm also an author and a
blogger so I do have my website I'll
give you the link to that where I keep
my blog I'm currently working on a book
that will be released in preview form
fairly shortly a guide on helping people
start their career in information
security so kind of goes along with our
last talk a little bit and then finally
I'm also speaking of our last talk
you've met one of my co-hosts from the
uncommon journey Colima stodgy is
another so we do host that podcast and
itsp magazine so today I want to take
you guys on a journey and it's a journey
of sight and sound and I want to begin
by asking you to take just a moment and
look around you you might be sitting at
a desk watching this you might be on a
couch just notice the things that you
see around you take a deep breath in
what do you smell what sense are
floating in the air right now
what do you hear what sounds are around
when we perceive
the world around us we use our five
senses everything that we know
everything we've based science off of
everything that we understand about this
world is based on our five senses but
what I'm here to talk to you about today
is the fact that attackers now have the
ability to attack those very senses that
we use to perceive the world around us
and this is the new attack paradigm of
deep fakes so when I talk about deep
fakes let let's discuss really briefly
what it is that I'm actually referring
to when I talk about deep fakes I'm
talking about any form of artificial
media that's created using deep learning
neural networks now it might come in the
form of still images as you see in the
upper right it could come in the form of
audio or as most of us who are who ever
ever heard of defects before probably
what you've seen our videos like this
one of Steve Buscemi at the Golden Globe
Awards only that's not Steve Buscemi
wearing a dress I'm sorry
so we you may have seen some of this
media before ultra-realistic very
difficult to tell that it's fake other
than clearly that's not Steve Buscemi's
body but these are all created using
deep learning neural networks now deep
fakes began as a research project back
in 2017 a paper was released detailing
how researchers were able to create this
type of media using these deep learning
neural networks and you know where most
promising technology seems to take its
foothold first the porn industry jumped
all over this they realized that they
could use this technology to take the
faces of popular celebrities and place
them on the bodies of the actresses in
their porn videos so you see images here
of women like Natalie Portman or gal
gadot or Emma Watson and Natalie Dormer
who are just some of the many
celebrities who have been subject to
this in fact there are websites now
where you can go and for a fee you can
actually request videos with your
favorite celebrities in them but of
course that wasn't where things stopped
and it wasn't too long after that point
that people started to realize we could
leverage this in politics and we could
start to manipulate the political
discourse in countries around the globe
by making phony videos sure some of them
are sad tires some are meant to be a
little more damaging you see a few of
them here another example you may be
aware of from 2018 was a video that
surfaced of Barack Obama giving an
address from his office and saying some
less than complimentary things about
then president-elect Trump your problem
was it wasn't Barack Obama saying those
things it was actually comedian Jordan
Peele who had created this video and had
deep faked Barack Obama and so these are
some of the things that have been talked
about in the media have been talked
about indeed amongst politicians about
the threat of deep fake but deep fakes
go further and the threats that they
present are far more right wide-ranging
one of the areas that we don't hear as
much about is where deep fakes can be
leveraged for social engineering a
terrific example of this comes to us
from the UK where the CEO of a large
Energy Corporation was duped into
transferring 200 million euros to
attackers now how did they do it well
they created deep fake audio of the
president of the parent company
instructing the CEO to make this wire
transfer and the CEO fell for it in fact
they came back a second time and tried
to do it again thankfully the CEO
learned his lesson and the second time
that came around at least he picked up
on it pretty quick and realized ok this
is not the president that I'm talking to
and this is abnormal behavior for him to
be requesting
but the fact of the matter is the
attackers were successful and they made
off with over 200 million euros we talk
about pornography well there's also this
idea of revenge porn and if you're not
familiar with this term typically where
this term is leveraged is when we talk
about people who have shared nude photos
selfies whatever with a partner or they
below their partner to take such photos
or video of themselves and then after
the relationship ends for whatever
reason that partner decides to get
revenge on them and releases those video
images to the web well now we have the
case where that video or those still
images don't even have to exist where
potentially a disgruntled partner or
ex-partner could create this type of
media and release that to the Internet
and while it's not real it could still
be just as embarrassing just as damning
or even worse because it could present
scenarios that never actually occurred
but what about the business world I
mentioned that social engineering
approach before what about some other
threats against business what about
using deep fakes to extort high-profile
business leaders now I show the the
example here okay Jeff Bezos has not
denied the real nature of any of the
images and videos that were used to
extort him but do those videos do those
images does that media have to be real
in order to have potential threat to a
high-ranking CEO
it only has to be believed long enough
for it to have a negative impact on that
organization or on that CEO or on that
high-profile business leader to have a
damaging and lasting impact on their
marriage this is a real threat this is
something that we face today with
high-profile business leaders around the
globe we've all you may have already
seen videos of Elon Musk's face being
put on the body of a baby now yeah
that's that's pretty innocuous but it
wouldn't take really much additional
effort to create more damning video of
him in other compromising situations
speaking of Elon Musk what about this
concept I like to introduce called
outsider trading so if you're familiar
with insider trading it's when people
with insider knowledge of the inner
workings of an organization use that
sensitive information to profit and to
bolster their their stock portfolios
they may know that there's bad news on
the horizon and so they sell off their
stock in advance or they know that an
upcoming development is going to cause a
significant stock increase and they
might buy up that stock knowing that
it's about to increase in price well
consider this scenario since I have my
my friend Elan up here at the moment I
consider Tesla's getting ready to launch
their next model call it the Model Q and
the night before Elan is all set to go
on stage and have his big launch and
he's gonna you know smash windows with
sledgehammers or whatever he chooses to
do this time video surfaces of him in a
meeting with stockholders sharing
information about problems that exist
with the line or you know something
that's going to cause a delay in the
launch or cause problems or delays of
backlogs in and delivery of these
vehicles well what's going to happen to
that stock naturally it's going to
plummet
that's a deep fake video released by an
attacker they could make use of this
situation they could plan this situation
short that stock buying it up while it's
depressed and then when it recovers
after news of the deep fake surfaces and
the launch goes as expected they sell
off those stocks this is a real threat
that exists today that could easily be
exploited by attackers so if I can
manipulate a large organization like
Tesla and and manipulate their stock
prices such to my own benefit what about
entire markets could I manipulate the
entire automotive market with just a few
well-placed
deep fake videos and if I could
manipulate a market what about the
entire economy of a small nation
so as I said before everything we know
about the world around us comes from
what we're able to perceive with our
five senses
but how do we define reality when we
can't trust those five senses this is
the paradigm of attack that deep fakes
have opened for attackers now how do we
create these deep base how our attackers
creating such convincing video well I
told you it all begins with neural
networks deep learning neural networks
that we call Gans Gans stands for
generative adversarial network if you
break that down the name it actually
describes exactly what they do they're
generative they're going to create
something their adversarial in the sense
that there are actually two neural
networks that operate within again there
is what we call the generator which is
responsible for creating content and
then there's the discriminator which is
responsible for assessing that content
as to how real it appears
now we train both sides of the scan with
a training set and this training set
typically is a set of still images a
large number often times but not always
and we're seeing increasingly fewer
number of still images needed in order
to properly train these scans we then
feed the generator the target media so
the target media is the video we create
that has an actor that we want to
replace in that video with our subject
and the generators going to take that
video and frame by frame it's going to
attempt to replace that actors face with
that of our subject the discriminator
then takes a look at those images and
says yeah either these are a very good
representation or no I can detect that
that's fake when the discriminator
detects that they're fake it sends it
back to the generator and it updates the
generator and we're gonna see more how
that works in just a moment the first
step in creating a deep fake however is
that that training that I mentioned and
in order to do the training we first
need that set of training images and to
get those training images I have to
normalize them through a process we call
extraction and the extraction is
literally taking each image and they
could be still images like this pulled
from a video they could be still images
found on the web and using facial
detection algorithms it detects and maps
out the face so you see 68 points of
facial recognition being mapped out here
those landmarks are studied by the GAM
and you also see the green box which is
the alignment that is this particular
algorithm aligning the face determining
what direction the face is facing if you
will how its oriented to the screen but
it's not enough just to identify it we
then have to normalize it in terms of
size and resolution so what we see is
that these algorithms will then take
that image take a fixed square around
that face region that it's recognized
and reduce that
to a specific resolution or in some
cases if it has to would increase it in
this case you see 254 by 254 pixels and
that is the standard training set image
that we're going to work from so the
entire training is based off of that
standardized image size and shape and
we'll see a little bit later why that
becomes important but so now when we go
into training what we're going to do is
we are ultimately feeding those images
to a two part system within the
generator the first part is this encoder
and what the encoder attempts to do is
take those images and represent them in
what we call just a model and that model
is nothing more than a a numeric way to
represent all the aspects of that face
that we need to capture in order to
recreate a face so the encoder writes
that to our model it then passes it to a
decoder and what the decoder is going to
attempt to do is the decoder is just
going to attempt to recreate that face
from no information other one than
what's include encompassed in that model
so it creates this new image that's an
attempt to recreate the original image
and then it passes it to the
discriminator the discriminator looks at
that and says how good or bad a job it's
done in recreating that face and it
expresses that value in terms of what we
call loss so loss is really just how
well did the decoder do in creating that
image it then updates the model that the
encoder is using it updates what we call
the weights and I'm not going to get
into all the inner workings of how
neural network models work but just know
that the weights are how the model
adjusts itself and continues to get
better and better so the discriminator
updates those weights constantly making
the encoder better and better and so
this process runs in what we call the
trainee and so in the training now this
is a process that can take 24-48 even up
to a 22 24 48 hours even up to a week
and what we're doing in that process was
were actually training two sets of
images the first
is our target the face that we want to
replace in the video the second is the
subject or the person whose face we want
to insert into the video so here you're
seeing images from a project that I
worked on where I was simply replacing
myself with Alyssa Milano
now I take those two sets of training
images and I actually pass them to the
same encoder so now that encoders trying
to build a model that not only
mathematically represents my face but
also represents Alyssa Milano's face so
it's it's more generalized and it's able
to represent the aspects of either of
our faces then that model it it creates
is used by two decoders decoder a is
going to try to recreate my face decoder
B is going to try to recreate Alyssa
Milano's face and in that process we're
constantly improving that model and
generalized generalizing it to recognize
both our faces and to be able to
recreate them reliably when that
training is done we now move into
conversion this is where we actually
create the video frame by frame I'm
going to take that video or those images
of me and I'm going to pass them to the
encoder so the encoder is now going to
take those images represent them in the
model but now we're going to pass them
to decoder be so decoder B just knows it
has this generalized model and it's got
to try to create Alyssa Milano from that
and that's exactly what it does and the
end result is my head with Alyssa
Milano's face this is the traditional
process for creating deep fakes now 48
hours 72 hours a week to do training may
sound a little onerous it can be and
indeed it takes some powerful GPUs to be
able to do that if you're trying to do
it on a CPU can take even longer with
our apps out there that help with us the
one that I've been using and is most
commonly seen these days is one called
face swap it it's a GUI interface it's
super easy to use its built-in cut and
Python makes the whole process a lot
simpler
but it can be made even simpler still
with this website called deep fakes web
deep fake swipe you just upload some
training images a video a training video
as well and it will generate a video for
you now I can tell you I've tried that I
paid for it it is there is a cost
associated with it the results weren't
great I gave them very good training
material and it took them about I think
six or eight hours to create the video
back and it wasn't very convincing but
it's there and you can create some if
you're not looking for something to try
to fool somebody if you're looking more
to do something satirical it's great for
that you know another application that
was built a while back called fake app
is the the blue icon here
that one's kind of disappeared from the
market you can still find github repos
that claim to have the original source
code although I wouldn't trust them
because most have been found to contain
different forms of malware and other
nastiness you probably don't want to
mess with so I really wouldn't trust
that one the final one I mentioned here
is this app that was released last year
called deep nude deep nudes whole
purpose was to take still images of
women and supposedly show you what they
looked like undressed now the reality is
those images it was creating were just
deep fakes where they took the face from
the image you provided and they deep
faked it on top of the picture of a
naked woman that thankfully that app
only lasted a week as you can imagine
there was a lot of backlash to something
like that and the author pulled it from
availability very quickly some people
again claimed to still have the original
apks for it I would be really careful if
you'd go pursuing those because again
they're typically filled with malware
and other nasty things you probably
don't want to put on your phone but
defect technology is getting better some
of you may have seen a recent article
where people are talking about how
somebody created basically real-time
deep fake of Elon Musk within their zoom
session and indeed there is a zoom
plugin now that can create almost
real-time deep fake images
you can replace your face in your zoo
meeting with pretty much anybody you
want how is it doing this
well it's using a different approach so
instead of mapping out all these
landmarks and doing all this training
and trying to create a model specific to
a particular face it's taken that idea
of a generalized model up another level
and it's really tried to create this
very generalized model that you can see
third from the left here of just how to
detect a face in general and create a
deep fake from it now the results right
now not terribly convincing there's a
lot of visual artifacts that you can
tell it was deep faked lots of
distortions and things but it is
bringing us one step closer to the point
where we can create real time deep fakes
so
how do we even tell what's real and fake
anymore well researchers have been doing
a lot of work on how do we detect deep
face and I'm going to share with you
just some of the methodologies that
they've been using the first that was
looked at quite a bit were just very
obvious visual artifacts that were part
of a deep fake so remember I mentioned
that whole idea of using these
normalized images that are sized to have
specific size and shape early on gans
weren't really good with applying those
images when the face shapes didn't match
and as you can see here that red arrow
on the right hand side points to some of
that visual distortion that occurs near
the eyes when Nicolas Cage's face is put
on top of Elon Musk's head so this is a
case where just simply the Gann and some
of the image processing behind the
scenes that were used just made some
errors and they resulted in visual
distortions and these artifacts were
easily detected by ganz even of course
your eyes could detect this sort of
thing but it didn't take long ganz have
gotten better and better their use of
different imaging techniques in order to
place faces and them ask them off and to
to blur transitions so that things fit
better have gotten considerably better
over time and in a very short amount of
time I might add so researchers moved on
in 2018 in June of 2018 researchers at
University at Albany State University of
New York released a research paper
discussing how they had done studies
where they found that blinking was not
appropriately replicated in deep fake
videos and so by analyzing the rate at
which people blanked the number of
blinks per minute they could accurately
identify deep fakes and there are a lot
of reasons for this and in part because
training sets typically didn't include
pictures of people with their eyes
closed but within two months of the
release of that paper we started seeing
deep fakes coming out where I blinking
was being addressed more realistically
within the videos research continue to
look at it they're now studying the rate
of blink the so both the velocity of how
fast the eyelids move and the direction
in which the eyelids move things like
that to still detect but of course every
time our detection techniques get better
so do the gans that produce these images
another issue that comes up and this
again is related to those standardized
imaging is this idea of warping and
again those same researchers at SU NY
released another paper this time in May
of 2019 where they started looking at
the problem of warping as it pertains to
physical facial characteristics as well
as the issues of resolution so remember
I talked about having you know images
that are 256 pixels square so in a 1080p
image like this it works well if the
subject is far away so we see Sharon
Stone here with deeps again Steve
Buscemi's face I don't know why he's so
popular to be inserted into these videos
but he is and from far away it looks
quite realistic but later in this same
scene when the camera zooms in on her
face and suddenly
that Gann has to apply a small image to
a much larger region we see the issues
you can see the difference in resolution
between the facial region and other
areas of this frame her hair her
shoulders her blouse you also see if you
look at the left cheek some very obvious
distortion in the shadows and the shape
of that cheek these are things that
again gans are very easily able to
detect and so researchers have been able
to do this with fair accuracy but again
as these models improve and they use
larger and larger training sets I've
seen training plugins now that go up to
512 pixels by 512 pixels if you think
about that in terms of an HD frame set
the 1920 by 1080 that's that's a
considerable amount of sizes for a
facial region if we're talking 512
pixels so we're going to continue to see
that get better and better researchers
know this so they've continued looking
at things they're now looking at this
idea of behavioral analytics and in this
case they're not looking for visual
technical issues or artifacts instead
they're actually looking at the facial
expressions and different facial
characteristics of the speaker in
context of the the content that's being
delivered so researchers combined at
Berkeley and USC release this research
in the latter half of 2019 and if you
look what they're taking a look at is
this first row of pictures of Barack
Obama still images from a talk that he
gave this was a case where he was
delivering a very gentle and caring
message he was trying to appear very
empathetic and as a result you see his
eyebrows are raised his eyes are very
open he has a very soft overall
appearance he seems very caring the next
row down however was Barack Obama
delivering
a stern warning to North Korea and there
you see his eyebrows furrow a lot his
eyes are more focused and angry looking
over all his face you see more of the
lines around his mouth because of the
serious message that he's delivering
initially when they released this
researcher this research the researchers
reported a 95 percent accuracy rate they
expect that to be 99 percent accurate by
the time the political season rolls
around this year in the US so that's
great when we're talking high profile
individuals but what about somebody for
whom we can't build that big behavioral
analytics model for because there's just
simply not that much material it doesn't
work so some other researchers at
Cornell University are looking at how
can we prevent deep fakes from being
created at all and they've leveraged
this idea of adversarial perturbations
and what this is is it simply noise
that's visually in detectable to the
human eye that they insert into images
that actually can can wreak havoc on
those facial recognition algorithms that
deep fake generation relies on so the
first role you see images that are
untreated and you see from the green box
that the facial recognition is easily
able to detect the faces here in the
second role you see what happens after
they insert that noise suddenly there's
numerous faces being detected and none
of them are actually accurate to the
face that appears in those frames and
then of course that bottom row is you
can see that's the actual noise that was
inserted into each of these images now
this is promising technology but again
it's not realistic to think that we can
go out there and for every person in the
world take their images that are on the
internet and replace them with images
that are so treated this is long term
maybe it's something we can do at the
camera level but it's not realistic to
think we're going to get there anytime
soon
and indeed there's already research
being done into how to improve those
facial recognition algorithms to get
around this so it's great that we're
focusing our research on all these
technological innovations that can
detect deep fakes but the fact of the
matter is deep fakes are not a
technological problem at all deep fakes
are misinformation and the reality my
friends is that misinformation is a
human problem misinformation is a human
problem we've been dealing with for
decades for centuries even in human
problems require human solutions how do
we go about addressing misinformation
that's the key to combating deep fakes
the problems with misinformation if you
followed misinformation in terms of
politics or in terms of yo cold war-era
attempts at propaganda the biggest issue
with misinformation is that it tends to
be very sticky and what do I mean by
sticky
well misinformation is designed to play
off of our existing thoughts beliefs and
perceptions it uses our current
prejudices our current perception of the
world to tell a story that we're already
happy to believe we almost want to
believe it and for that reason when we
perceive that misinformation our minds
do this incredible thing they build this
logic map and they insert that
misinformation into that logic map
because it just matches up to the things
we already know and so it just fills a
point in this logic map of how we get
from evidence a to conclusion B and so
it's embedded it fills those gaps it
gives us that evidence to support
conclusions that we already wanted to
make
as a result it is exceptionally
difficult to remove that information
once it's there in somebody's mind and
this is the struggle of propaganda this
is the struggle struggle of
misinformation this is the struggle when
we try to undo the effects of
brainwashing which when we talk about
misinformation yeah that's not an
exaggeration it does go to that level so
what do we do to debunk this
misinformation
for starters we need to put the
awareness out there that this
misinformation exists at a macro level
it's just awareness that deep fakes are
thing and we see the media doing that
today I'm giving this talk today April
Wright is another person who gives us a
talk about a lot of the threats around
deep fix it's getting attention from
researchers we see researchers doing all
this work to produce different detection
capabilities we see social media outlets
like Facebook working with Microsoft and
Amazon to create million-dollar
challenges for researchers to produce
detection techniques so we're starting
to understand that this is the
capability and that's what we need and
more specifically when deep fake videos
surface we need to get that information
out there as well the second key is
repetition those messages need to be
repeated over and over and over again it
needs to be something that is culturally
aware throughout our entire society we
need that ability that awareness to
recognize that there are things that we
used to trust that we can't trust
anymore our standard of evidence has
gone up we used to look at video
evidence as kind of the gold standard if
you will if it was on video we knew it
to be real that's why we have so many
surveillance cameras that's why we see
video evidence used in courtrooms being
used to such a strong powerful degree
deep fakes threaten all of that and we
need people to be aware of that we need
to make people aware and repeat it over
and over again that they have to
question the things that they're seeing
the things that they're hearing the
step is the part that often gets missed
and that is we have to take that
truthful narrative and use it in a way
that we can replace that misinformation
in that logic chain in the person's
brain so what that means is we have to
understand how that propaganda how that
misinformation was constructed to play
off of specific prejudices specific
beliefs specific value sets and we have
to craft our truthful narrative in a way
that plays to that so when we think
about what I talked about in terms of
the threats to businesses business has
to start looking at misinformation as
another incident it should be part of
our instant response plan we should have
those strategies in place for how we
become aware of it how we respond to it
how we work with the media to get that
truthful narrative out there to replace
the mythical narrative that's been
injected into the minds of those who
already we're set to believe because
maybe they weren't real happy with our
company or they they're just looking for
a reason to believe that corporate
America did something terrible
or that our high-ranking officials did
something terrible so that is the lesson
to be learned here from a business
perspective start looking at how you can
build this into your incident response
plan and treat misinformation as an
incident the good news is it's there are
some positive intentions
there are positive uses for this
technology and in fact many people have
questioned why did researchers ever
create this in the first place how could
this have ever been a good thing well
despite or in addition to rather the
fuehrer lot the feel theoretical let's
try that again the theoretical
improvements in deep learning overall
some of that idealistic academic sense
there are real-world applications where
we've already seen the use of this
technology why having Star Wars fans out
there and betting I do see Rob one
remember grand moff tarkin making a
return appearance even though the actors
dead remember a young Princess Leia
showing up yeah that was deep fake
technology that made that possible now
there are ethical concerns here of
course the good news from a Hollywood
perspective is Hollywood actually seems
to be taking those ethical concerns into
consideration they spoke to Carrie
Fisher before her death and got her
permission to create this in fact Carrie
Fisher was really excited that they
would be able to create this video of
her and her younger days and make it
more consistent in the movie they also
went to the actor and I apologize I
always forget his name who played Grand
Moff Tarkin and they did get permission
from his estate from his family to use
his likeness in the movie but this isn't
the only place where we're seeing it
used Ganz the technology behind deface
are being leveraged in medical imaging
recent studies have shown that Ganz can
more accurately detect tumors at a far
earlier stage than doctors better still
they can predict with amazing accuracy
what the growth of that tumor will be
again far exceeding the capabilities of
even the best cancer specialists out
there today so this is really promising
because
this is something that can help inform
better treatment options less of the you
know try it and phrase sort of approach
that sometimes is still a reality when
we think about cancer treatments today
and we're starting to see other research
being done around this to even expand
the usage beyond just tumor detection
medical imaging will improve
but it's not just medical imaging there
are other cases in health care space
where we're seeing this used we're
seeing augmented reality start to grow
in terms of telehealth options and what
you see here is an augmented reality
based telehealth solution that uses deep
fake generated video of a doctor that
doctor that this person is looking at
doesn't even exist that's not even a
real person
but it's a doctor's image that was
constructed by again to maximize the the
friendly nature the inviting nature of
that doctor's face the goal here being
that people will be more apt to open up
and to more openly share information
about their current health situation by
a telehealth that's important if we
think about the current situation we're
in right now with COBIT and the number
of us who are having to to use
telehealth options today to speak with
our doctors making people more
comfortable in those situations and more
able to accurately Express to their
doctors what's going on is crucial then
finally we've seen political application
now you could argue and there is
discussion for sure about the ethics
behind this and whether this is really a
good thing I look at it and I think it's
very innovative at minimum and I
actually think it's a good idea this is
a politician from the country of India
and in his district he represents a
constituency of people that span twelve
different languages if you know anything
about India there are numerous numerous
dialects that are spoken across the
country so he doesn't speak all 12 of
those dialects so he created an address
to reach out to his people he then had
that address
deep faked both audio and video to make
it appear as though he were delivering
that same address in each of those 12
different languages that make up his
constituency he was widely popular as a
result people were very excited to hear
one of their leaders expressing a
message in their natives tongues
something many of them had never
witnessed before this was truly
groundbreaking and I think we'll see
more of that that's to me that's a
positive use because it's it there was
nothing dishonest about it he didn't
suggest for a moment
that you know he was speaking in all
these other languages it was it was made
known that this was how this was created
but it was just a way for him to more
directly connect to his people so as I
start to wrap up here we're just about
out of time I want to leave you with
this quote this quote is from Yuri
basmanov he's a former KGB agent and
this was him discussing the mass
brainwashing techniques of the former
Soviet Union back in 1984 they called it
their ideological subversion program and
this goes to the heart of the problem
with misinformation when we can no
longer trust the information around us
and we don't trust our own senses we
start to make decisions that no longer
are in our own best interests that is
the breakdown of so many systems that
our society is built on so it's
important that we be aware of this it's
important that we focus on the human
solutions to how we combat deep fakes
some other materials for you really
quickly a hashtag project deep fake if
you follow that on Twitter or LinkedIn
you can see some of the results of the
projects I've been working on I do have
a system here with some dedicated GPUs
that I have been doing some deep fake
work with seeing just how realistic I
could get those videos to be you can see
some early results that Alyssa Milano
video that I created if you go to that
youtube link I also have a link to these
slides they're available both in sked
for this conference but also if you'd
rather you can use that link to go get
them from github they're available to
you I'm happy to share those if those
are at all helpful to you additionally
some references for you all the
different studies that I have cited in
this talk today if those are useful to
you by all means please go ahead and
check those out as well a lot of great
reading some of it gets pretty deep into
some machine learning concepts so I will
warn you it can get kind of dry just be
aware of that as well and then finally
I open invitation to continue the
conversation I love the reason I get out
and I speak at conferences like this the
reason I work as an advocate is because
I love sharing ideas and hearing other
people's ideas I love to have my ideas
challenged to challenge yours if there's
knowledge that I have that I can help
you know you with things that you're
working on please feel free to reach out
my twitter handle is up there my DMS are
always open my LinkedIn if you'd rather
address me there that's fine too and a
link to my website as promised and then
finally on behalf of my employer myself
and besides Knoxville just a great big
thank you all I really appreciate your
time and attention today with that if
there are any questions I think we're
happy to take those at this time
ya know like almost down to the second
timing there that's that's perfect and I
think we do have some questions I I had
one just off the top of my head I think
one of my biggest concerns especially
talking about you know using this
technology for manipulation the media
game is all about exclusives and
scooping and getting it out there as
quickly as possible like how how could
we ever pump the brakes on that kind of
thing or educate them to the point to
where they can they can not be fooled by
this I mean already with the amount of
media that exists out there that intends
to be fake in the first place
posing as real media now we got to worry
about the real media getting getting
duped what are your thoughts there so
yeah so it's twofold right you've got
the first of all there's the media who
wants to do a good job and you know
their problems there they're the ones
that are being addressed right now in
part by different research like I
mentioned the challenge at Facebook
Microsoft and Amazon are doing part of
their goal there is to release that not
only just for social media but to the
greater media community as a whole so
they can authenticate videos and things
before running with a news story you
know I think the media is also already
kind of gotten the message that they're
going to be you need to do even more
than that
though and really authenticate the
source of videos authenticate the story
through other means as well before they
just go and run with it now the media
that doesn't care if it's real or not
and we can all think of a few examples
I'm sure the best example of that is the
Nancy Pelosi video all right that wasn't
even a deep fake that was just
manipulated to slow it down but even
after news came out that that was fake
we saw multiple right-wing news sources
releasing that video claiming it to be
true
you know countless millions of people in
their audience rishe airing that content
claiming it to be true and believing
that it was true so that becomes the
harder issue and that's where
you know some of the greater aspects of
trying to fight misinformation in
general where social media is now taking
and sometimes removing that media and so
forth that's gonna have to continue to
accelerate the other challenge we have
though honestly is that there's some
gray area here that social media is
struggling with where is that line
between free speech and acceptable you
know use of these different videos to
create satire versus what violates
copyrights and privacy laws
there's definitely legislation needed
here unfortunately lawmakers right now
are only focused on election security
there nothing can be on that and so
there's a lot of work to be done there
as well yeah definitely it's and just
let you know and in the the discord is
having a great time with this but I'm
gonna have steve buscemi nightmares
tonight I know I keep seeing that if
that's like the third time now it's
passed by in my peripheral vision I've
seen that that that one in particular is
horrible I don't know why he's such a
popular subject for deep face it just
everybody liked him and Nicolas Cage
there that one looks like him he's just
it's he's just has a very unique like
quirky look which is why I get so much
work in Hollywood right I guess yeah so
yeah I think we had some other questions
here let me see what I've got somebody
asking how many covered 19 related fakes
have you found you know honestly I
haven't seen a deep fake yet from that
and I'm actually surprised like I've
been kind of watching for like dr. Fauci
to show up somewhere deep fake like you
know saying some nasty stuff about the
president or something like that but
surprisingly there hasn't been as much
lately I don't know what's kind of toned
that down but yeah I haven't it's please
let me know if someone sees some because
I would definitely be interested in
knowing about that
so somebody's asking they're interested
in how the noise is applied to live
images in order to prevent faking so
it's basically like a summation so if
you take the you're taking two images
you layer them together and you apply it
and if you got down to if you were like
so say you were gonna do it in Photoshop
you would literally take two layers and
just by applying I'm trying to think all
the mask works exactly I apologize but
it's basically a max masking technique
where those pixels that aren't that
static gray in that you saw that was the
static gray is added just to make them
more visible but the way they're at it
is it's it's just individual adjustments
to those pixels it's it's a slight
change in coloration and in I believe
it's if you're taught if the parents are
you talking RGB or CMYK as to how
exactly that that gets adjusted but yeah
they it's just taking that and applying
it over top so I think the follow-up
question to this and I think I know the
answer the answer is probably going to
be yes is whether or not like major
social media you know services can apply
that as you upload that's what they're
talking about doing the research on it
is still not complete but I think that's
yeah as you read through some of the
follow ups to the study that was one of
the suggestions and I know you know
Facebook at least had uh released some
commentary about the possibility of
doing exactly that that's the hope the
issue comes in to you would also have to
do it with video and that's where it
becomes a little more difficult because
a lot of the training right now like
when I did mine for in Face Swap I used
video and I just I had it extract still
images from video for the training set
and so you know in that case you would
have to have every frame at 30 frames a
second or 60 frames a second apply that
to it and I that could get pretty
time-consuming
yeah and I it sounds a lot like we're
getting started in a game of leapfrog
and like like techniques to prevent it
you know like very similar to what we've
seen with malware and other stuff where
like it takes them takes us six months
to come up with a defense and a day for
them to figure out a way around it yeah
well and the worst thing here is when
you think about how Gans work where you
have kind of that the detector if you
will that that discriminator network
it's already making the attackers better
because it's doing that instantly as
part of that training so a lot of the
techniques as you build those into you
know we build these detection techniques
well people take those they build them
into the discriminators and now that
just updates the generators model to
account for those additional elements
and so that's you know you're right it's
a constant cycle of attackers making the
defenders better and the defenders
making the attackers better and it just
happens at a faster pace now because
we're talking machine learning yeah all
right looking for other questions here I
don't think we have any more I think
that's it definitely a great
conversation in the in track one on that
and if you want to check that out later
it's it's there's a lot well maybe I
don't know if there's a way to turn off
the images as you browse it skip the
skip the doubled-up steve buscemi eyes
and mouth one yeah yes yeah all right
that that was awesome I appreciate it
thanks for bringing such an awesome talk
and excellent delivery and we've got
plenty of time before the the next
speaker here all right I appreciate it
thanks again everybody so much thank you