hello everyone this is Hardy Couric
first a quick check can you see my
screen and can you hear me out
we're all good okay all right so good
after everyone and thanks for having me
here I'm really excited to be here
presenting on this topic which is near
and dear to my heart which is navigating
their web security Ernie with OS per Sam
software assurance maturity model and
one of the core members of Austin
project first of all I want to thank
besides Knoxville for scheduling this
atlas for me this is the first online
event that I've been attending I'm sure
the same thing for many of you hopefully
I'll get what you come to Knoxville next
year before we dive deep into the topic
I want to share my professional journey
line so just let's spend two minutes on
Who am I
so I signed my career as a software
engineer and I got introduced to
security when I was doing my master's in
complete science at unity of Florida my
very first professional exposure to
security was when I was Adele and I was
asked to kind of build a hickory and pen
testing team from there I got an
opportunity to bootstrap EMC spark
security program after that I led
various product information security
teams at companies like Intuit Amazon
and Splunk I'm also on an advisory board
for a few security and data privacy
startups as well as the nonprofit trade
organization called CompTIA which many
of you might be familiar with pompeii
shoes IT security certifications such as
security plus and size Atlas but
throughout my career I also contributed
to industry through safe code
publications science top 25 programming
errors CBS s 3.0 and besom since version
1.1 1.0 so for those of you who might
not be familiar with besom besom is
another so physically maturity model
which is descriptive in nature
it was developed originally by acetyl by
interviewing six independent software
vendors from safe code founding member
companies and EMP was one of them that
is how I contributed to be sim a besom
is more of a descriptive model versus
prescriptive model like Sam and by that
what I mean is this him helps you
compare with other secure organizations
and which organization is performing
which security activity at which level
that is what it helps to describe
I started contributing to OS Sam some
around 2016 and have been one of the
core members of La Stampa logic since
then
you
so before we start the talk just wanted
to get some legal stuff out of the way
I'm not speaking on behalf of my current
or previous employers nor am I here as a
representative of my current or previous
employers my opinions are solely my own
and do not reflect those of my current
or previous employers
you
so quick agenda was Sam I'm sure like
some of you might have our used or asked
them in the past some of you might be
very new to watch them so I wanted to
spend some time for those of the folks
who are new to us
Sam giving them introduction on who is
awesome what is awesome why do we need a
model like was them an overall project
history and background
Sam version 2 has been launched recently
in about February this year so also
wanted to quickly go over the highlights
of what changes we made in version 2 or
version 1.5 and last we will discuss how
to apply Sam in your particular
organization my goal is to make sure
that you walk away with enough knowledge
to start applying Sam in your
organization starting Monday and in the
end I'll open up for a few questions or
feedback if you already are using Sam
and if you have some feedback we can
open up for that or if you are new and
if you want to start using it if you're
any questions we'll leave some room for
that
you
so if you are in one of these 15 plus
different roles then this particular
talk is very useful to you and as I
mentioned you will be able to walk away
with knowledge that you can apply to
your organization and this is our like
just representation of our target
audience but mainly ba stamp is geared
towards everybody who is involved in
building and securing products
so first of all without them
Sam is the result of hard work of the
contributors around the globe over the
past three years this group represents
different geographies companies of
various sizes consulting and product
development as well as academia as a
result wast time is very versatile and
can be applied in companies of various
sizes across the globe there are many
times during the design and construction
of osm when we were having debates and
it always was very helpful to get
diverse perspective from this group of
new Jews because many times when we were
discussing about certain language to use
certain metrics certain guidelines
it was always helpful to understand the
perspective from somebody from South
America somebody from New Zealand
somebody from different parts of United
States as well as somebody from Europe
so this has helped us neutralized the
language for them and also oral model
where we wanted to make it so useful and
so versatile so that anybody and
everybody across the globe as well as
all different types of companies can use
it be it small a little startup or big
corporation
so what is awesome what Sam is one of
the flagship projects and flagship
status is given to projects with
strategic importance to both laws and
application security in general
om is one of those projects I believe
there are about fifteen or sixteen of
all the us projects they have received
the status and what then is one of those
projects
om is the framework of Software
Assurance that provides effective and
measurable way for all types of
organizations to analyze and improve
their software security posture that is
tailored to their specific risk that
particular organization is facing and
the key thing is one size doesn't fit
all so you really need to look at your
organization's risk and your own
maturity level when you start applying
osm fam is full of useful resources that
does help in evaluating your
organization's current security
practices providing recommendations or
suggestions for growing and maturing
those practices providing a way to
demonstrate concrete improvements over a
period of time and defining and
measuring security activities throughout
the software development lifecycle one
of the big benefits of Sam is that it is
vendor agnostic Sam can be done in-house
or you could have one of the several
application security consulting firms
help you with the assessment and
creation of plants and watermarks
you
so one of the key thing about osm is
also it's very versatile and it can be
used across different types of
organizations who are using different
types of methodology beat agile
waterfall or DevOps so why do we need a
model like watch them
lately if you see there is a quest to
increase speed across all different
types of organizations and many times
security might be perceived as more of a
hindrance in accomplishing this goal of
increasing speed
at the same time due to this increased
pressure of increased speed many
organizations are growing in complexity
with increased number of texts texts
various organizational structures growth
of open source software and various
deployment models beat cloud based model
on frame model multi platform model as
well as responsive design
the result almost 75% of the monopolies
these days our application related
to standardize security activities in
such complex software environment we
need a model like what SEM
so why was them
the most that can be expected from any
model is that it can supply useful
approximation to reality all models are
wrong some models are useful change or
box a George box is one of the great
statistical minds of 20th century and I
think one of the key thing over here is
as he says all models are wrong in some
models are useful why is that because we
all understand that there is no you know
each organization is has its own
challenges it has its own risk profile
and its own maturity level
as a result there are no two
organizations which are same if they are
same our life would have been much more
easier it would have been more like a
cookiecutter approach if you go from
organization to organization but reality
is different the point is that you
cannot find a model that will exactly
describe the reality there are too many
variables and most of the models are
built mainly in the academic world and
we live in the real world but you can
have a model that is close enough to be
useful and that is what Sam Sann is that
model which is close enough to be useful
but not exactly representing your
particular organization
Sam was defined with that type of
flexibility in versatility in mind so
that it can be utilized by polarizations
of various sizes with different types of
complexities and organizations employing
different types of development models be
it a gel water form or DevOps
in addition this model can be applied
throughout your organization or a single
line of business or individual project
within the organization
now let's look at some of the core
principles of spam
when Sam was designed we had at least
this four core principles in mind
first an organization's behavior changes
slowly over time
changes need to be smaller and iterative
to really take hold and make a
difference second there is no single
recipe that works for all different
organizations Sam is built with that in
mind and supports organization building
a program that is tailored to the risk
profile culture and maturity they have
in that particular organization
part the guidance related to security
activities must be prescriptive solution
must provide enough details for non
security people
because there are many security
initiatives which fail due to poor
details lack of communication or invalid
assumptions
or all the subsets of the program will
be based on being this model being
simple
well defined
and miserable
now for those of you who might be new to
Sam let's look at the project history so
Sam is not a brand new project was
project or at least even before there's
a history before even it came to us
the first version of Sam was developed
by independent software secret
consultant named Kovac Chandra under the
name of open Sam
and it was the first job was made
possible through funding from 45
software
after a number of years it was kind of
being stagnant from like somewhere on
2009 till 2015 a small group go out
together at was and work together to
breathe some life into this dead project
or not dead body but it was connected
project and San became awesome project
so it is no longer open Sam it is now
considered awesome but this is the
history like it started as an open Sam
project back in 2009
the ocean first version after it came
under was umbrella was version 1.1
it expanded and restructure its
predecessor into four complementary
resources
core document that describes the course
and model
how to guide that explains how to apply
this model which Start Guide to help
accelerate learning and eruption and the
most important one is the toolbox which
is kind of like a spreadsheet that voids
simple automation for detect election
matrix and graphs
back in 2000 1700s them came up with a
new version 1.5
version 1.5 incorporates refinement of
the scoring model to provide more
granularity to the scoring in assessment
the applying more model has been
designed to have Sam Assessors and
organizations avoid the awkward
discussion on whether to mark answer yes
or no when it is honestly something in
between and show incremental
improvements
we just launched Sam put ATO in February
2020 where we have changed the
measurement model one more time and this
time with aim to as qualitative
measurement to represent how well an
organization is performing the security
practice because in 1.5 we definitely
added a lot more granularity but it was
still missing
the key element of a qualitative
measurement and that was one of the key
feedback that we received across the
globe from Sam practitioners
so that is why one of the key things
that we wanted to change was this
particular aspect of the assessment and
measurement
now let's look at the maturity levels
and the assessment score at a very high
level
so at very high level therefore maturity
levels zero one two and three at level
zero particular practices completely
unfulfilled at level one security
practices perform but in an ad hoc
fashion
at level 2 security practices perform
with increased efficiency and
effectiveness
and at the highest level which is level
three security practices perform with
mastery at scale across the organization
not everyone needs to make level 3 in
all the areas this is one of the
mistakes that I've seen many of the new
organizations make they try clean for
level 3 in all different areas and that
is actually honestly not the boost good
use of your limited resources
the goal is not to max out on each
practice security practice in each area
what the target machua should be for
your organization is largely up to you
depending on the business drivers and
the risk your particular organization is
facing
so in version 1.5 we had modified the
scoring model to provide multiple choice
answers to allow for more accurate
assessment previously in Sam and most of
the models the questions we're like yes
and no which is great from like more of
academic perspective but in real world
as we all know the answer many times
lies in between the two let's take one
example so looking at Sam 1.5
if you are doing the assessment if you
are trying to answer the question on
education and guidance practice are
those involved in software development
process given role specific security
training and guidance that's the
question that you as an Assessor is
trying to assess
you know you have trained some of the
developers and would like to train some
project managers and cue engineers
but given the situation how do you
answer yes or no
now this is the dilemma if you answer no
you get no credit it looks like you
aren't working on it but actually you
are and if you answer yes you may get
full credit and may have issues down the
road when you are trying to ask for
training budget for other roles such as
project managers and QA engineers
because the - forces you already did
this particular activity and that was
the challenge in the previous model 1.5
with the new model you can answer
something like some or at least half so
I meant in version 1.0 and 1.1 in 1.5 we
added this new granularity levels where
you can add some or at least half and
get the partial credit but also have the
ability to show improvements in your
score when you finish the initiative to
train the other rules with the new model
we also change the wording to many and
most and not all
and these rationale behind that as well
in practice there's always some activity
which will not be performed for small
group of applications for the right
reasons for example if you know that
some service is retiring in near future
well you may not want to spend your
precious resources in getting add a
particular application in compliance and
you can still get the full credit
because that work application is going
to retire anyway very soon so that is
why we also change to artists we propose
menu our most and not all because in
real world accomplishing all is kind of
a tall task and it's almost like that
long tail of like you know last few
applications takes you forever so that
is where we want it to be more pragmatic
and wanted to provide this flexibility
now before we look at Sam Porto wanted
to spend some time on introducing to the
folks who are new to Sam in version 1.5
so at the highest level
Sam version 1.5
is defining four critical business
functions in each business function the
category of activities related to nuts
and bolts bolts of software development
practice that your organization might be
following for each particular business
function Sam defined three security
practices each security practice is an
area of security activities that build
assurance for that particular business
function for each secret practice and
define three different levels of
maturity as objectives and each level
within a secured practice is
characterized by successively more
sophisticated objective activities as
well as more stringent success metrics
than its previous level
so this is SEM 1.5 at high level
now one would ask what are the
motivations behind a new more new
version for this model so there are five
main motivations first is aligning with
the most recent development
methodologies such as agile and DevOps
and when we wanted to do that our goal
was to make it software development
methodology agnostic
because version 1.5 and its predecessors
look more suitable for waterfall direct
mythology even though it was not meant
to be so we kind of collected feedback
from sand practitioners across the globe
and we realized that it's missing key
aspects of guidance in terms of how to
securely build and deploy software
specially since eh series part of agile
and eros mythology
second motivation is to improve the
measurement even though Sam 1.5 address
the feedback about different granularity
levels it still did not address equation
how well an activity is being performed
thus needing some qualitative
measurement
the third motivation is to avoid orphan
and unrelated activities in different
maturity levels there are quite a few
security activities in version 1.5 and
its predecessors were defined such that
it lacked consistent theme across
different levels of maturity within a
security package which also resulted in
few orphan activities
such as scores I mean if you look at
version 1.5 their security practice
called course code signing and there's
literally no consistent theme in the
same security practice and across
different maturity levels
and also there is no similar activity
yet
mature level one and mature level three
so it was kinda like created more like
orphan activity
the fourth motivation was
arranging maturity levels in order of
increasing difficulties so this was
another shortcoming of previous Sam
versions it was sometimes possible that
some of the security activities at high
level very in fact a little bit easier
to implement compared to security
activities at the lower level now it was
one-way intuitive like you know if you
look at material level it's one would
assume that as you go higher in the
level of maturity the implementation
cost should be higher but that was not
the case so we had to fix that one as
well
the last but not least was Sam
production process itself it was slow
and waterfalls resulting in major
overhaul of work every time we needed to
release new version just recently in
fact Sam itself Sam project itself is on
th any itself that's a great progress
and that was also one of the motivation
behind the second version of Sam
now let's look at the same framework for
version 2.0
the sample dotto at very high level and
the area highlighted are changes from
version 1.5 which we'll call in few more
minutes sampled Auto is defined in three
levels again at highest level Sam
defines five critical business functions
versus four in version 1.5 and each
business function is the category of
activities related to nuts and bolts of
software development in your
organization
for each business function Sam defines
three security practices each degree
practice is an aerial security related
activities that build assurance for that
particular business function and for
each security package again Sam defines
three maturity level as objectives
with insecurity practice is
characterized by successively more
sophisticated objective and more
stringent success metrics than the
previous levels and overall as you
increase the level of maturity you
should expect higher cost of
implementation as I mentioned earlier
this is one of the area we fix in
version 2.0
if you look at the framework you can see
that governance is more focused on
program itself looking at more strategic
elements such as strategy and metrics
policy and compliance education and
guidance
we have renamed construction business
function to design business function
into dot o and introduce the new
business function called implementation
design implementation verification and
operations together cover the core of a
software development lifecycle
high level design is focused on three
things threat assessment security
requirements and security architecture
or secure architecture
intention is focused on secure build
secure deployment and defect management
and we are going to spend a little more
time on this particular business
function a little bit later
verification is more focused on
architecture analysis requirements
driven testing and security testing so
these are more like testing and
verification of this model
last but not least is operations which
is focused on incident detection and
management and environment management
where the apps live on
so at high level this is Sam Boudreau
framework
now let's take a closer look at security
practices in this new framework
if security practice is divided into two
streams stream a and stream beach
the purpose of the streeams is to align
and link the activities within the
practice or different maturity levels
each stream has an objective to be reach
and this objective can be reached in
increasing levels of maturity this way
we ensure that there are no orphan
activities that seem only relevant on a
single maturity level like for instance
I mentioned code signing in version 1.5
let's take a closer look at one of the
security practices which is the
requirement student testing under
verification business function to
understand this screen concept a little
bit more so requirements testing
security practice is divided into two
streams the stream a control
verification and stream B misuse or
abuse testing
this dreams aligned and linked
activities in the practice or different
maturity levels as you can see
eastream has an objective to be reached
and this objective can be reaching
increasing levels of maturity
anystream also provides that consistent
theme across three different maturity
levels
as I mentioned earlier the key changes
in this particular model are
imitation business function under which
secure build and secure deployment are
the key practices which are more years
towards DevOps and agile practices so
let's take a look a little bit closer
look at this particular security
practices
so secure bill
this practice focuses on creating
consistently repeated repeatable secure
build process and accounting for
security of application dependencies as
I mentioned earlier in today's complex
world there are a lot of organizations a
lot of developers they use third-party
open source libraries and some other
dependencies so it was important to
include that particular aspect in coming
up with the new model
the secure bill practice emphasises the
importance of building software in
standardized and repeatable manner and
of doing so using secure components
including third-party software
dependencies as you can see the first
stream which is Bill crosses focusing on
removing any subjectivity from the build
process by striving for full automation
at level 3 and automated bill pipeline
can include additional automated
security checks such as fast and as to
gain further assurance and flag security
regressions early by failing the bill
for example now I'm not recommending
that tomorrow everybody should start
failing to build based on SAS and as
result because there's a lot of work
need to happen before back such as you
need to remove false positives you need
to remove noise from some of these tools
because most of these tools they have
some level of noise that they introduce
once you remove that noise and then you
have full confidence that the issues
identified by these tools they are high
confidence high fidelity issues then you
could reach to that level and that is
the reason that that particular aspect
is as metric level 3
the second stream which is software
dependencies how is the prevalence of
software dependencies in modern
applications it aims to identify them
and track the security status in order
to contain the impact of the insecurity
on other ways secure application the
most advanced form it applies similar to
each extra software dependencies as to
the application itself and there are few
pools available and there are a couple
of very good towards projects in this
particular aspect so for stream B this
was dependency check and was dependency
crack are the two main tool which are
available from us to help with that
particular stream
now let's look at the next stream which
is secure deployment on stream so next
if you practice which is secure
deployment
this particular practice focuses on
automatically securing deployments to a
production environment and all required
secrets one of the finest ease in
believing secure software is ensuring
that the security and integrity of
develop applications are not compromised
during the deployment
- this add this practices first stream
which is deployment process focuses on
removing manual error by automating the
deployment process as much as possible
and making its success contingent upon
the outcomes of integrated security
verification checks it also forces
separation of duties by making
adequately trained non developers
responsible for deployment
some organizations they have only
certain developers who are more in
DevOps roles they are responsible for
deployment
the second stream which is secrets
management goes beyond the mechanisms of
deployment and focuses on protecting the
privacy and integrity of sensitive data
such as passwords tokens and other
secrets required for applications to
operate in production environments
in simplest form suitable production
secrets are moved from repositories and
configuration files into adequately
manage digital roles in more advanced
forms secrets are dynamically generated
and deployment time and routine
processes detect and mitigate the
presence of any unprotected secrets in
the environment and I am NOT here to
recommend any particular tool but there
are some tools available some of them
are open-source tools some of them are
build by various companies so you can
look at those tools to accomplish this
particular objective
now this slide I'm not going to dwell on
this slide too much because I already
have covered some of these suspects
during the motivations behind the new
version but this is a quick summary of
key changes that we introduced in Sam
version 2.0 I want to focus on the last
bullet which is on the measurement so
the difference between SEM 1.5 and to
auto is also on measurement
1.5 focus mainly on coverage based
measurement the 2.0 version focuses on
qualitative aspects in addition to
coverage business measurement
so after looking at all the changes that
we introduced in Porto as well as
introducing this overall model to folks
who are new let's spend some time on how
do you apply this model to your
particular ization
as I mentioned each organization is very
unique in its own aspects especially
their risk profiles and their existing
level of maturity so it is very
important to start with preparation and
preparation goes beyond just doing the
assessment so preparation I'll talk
about preparation a little bit more in
detail in the next slide but at high
level typical rollout approach for Sam
includes six different phases
the first phase is prepare phase then
assessment
during the target defining the plant
implementation and rollout and this
curve again goes back to assessment thus
creating more of a cyclic process or
cyclic and continuous change improvement
process
so let's look at the first phase which
is the prepare phase
preface in my mind is the most critical
phase called success of Sam application
your particular organization
it consists of four activities the first
one is to define the scope so before
even you start to implementing Sam you
have to determine you want to apply Sam
to the whole organization a particular
business unit or some particular
applications or projects
the reason for that is the scope really
determines the amount of work it needs
to be done as well as what kind of
buying you need to receive so that is
what leads to the second one where once
you identify the scope of your
implementation you can identify the key
stakeholders and they vary from sport to
score because if you want to roll out
some Sam across your whole organization
you need to get buying from much higher
levels of leadership courses if you are
confining your scope to just particular
business unit then you need to take
buy-in from that particular business
units leadership team and if you are
doing it on that worker one particular
application or project then you just
have to get buying from that project
lead
but the key thing is once you define the
scope you need to get critical buying
from the leadership team
once you get the buy-in you need to
start spreading the world and do the
evangelization because that way you will
get lot more broader support
as part of preparation please review the
resources that we provided as part of
same version protocol guide for maturity
levels and defines objectives benefits
activities assessment questions quality
criteria success metrics and the cost
I was shown one example here so if you
look at this guide it's pretty
self-explanatory and as I mentioned
earlier that this guide has been created
with group of volunteers across the
globe who work at companies of different
sizes as well as academia so the
language is very neutral and it's very
self explanatory
spend some time in starting this guide
so you understand how to use them
after that you start doing the
assessment
in order to do the assessment you need
to start conducting interviews with key
stakeholders to evaluate the current
security practices
here we recommend the in person approach
versus emails this way you can explain
the key intent behind any activity and
clarify any potential doubts they may
have
there are three ways in which you can
perform an assessment
the lightweight assessment there is a
detail assessment and there is in a
hybrid assessment
lightweight assessment is simply
interviewing key stakeholders and
recording their response
during detailed assessment you asked for
evidence for performance and quality of
each activity being performed in the
hybrid assessment model you asked for
evidence only on a need basis for some
of the activities and not all of the
activities and at least from the most of
the practitioners and practitioners the
assessment takes a good amount of time
like it depending on your organization
or the scope that you choose
it may take somewhere between oh one
hour to two to three hours
it really depends on what scope you are
trying to cover
so the most particular approach is the
hybrid assessment
now once you record the responses from
the key stakeholders and look at the
evidence
you can assign maturity levels using the
Sam spreadsheet that we poured it
you
one of the key thing about this Sam
spirit will curl a bit more in detail in
the next slide is how we have come up
with combined coverage based
measurements as well as quality based
measurement as I mentioned each degree
package needs to be assessed on those to
access coverage as well as quality so
let's look at the example of spreadsheet
or the worksheet that we have built for
version 2 Auto
as you can see in the previous version
we just had the question for example if
this was an assessment for 1.5 it would
have been the question new test
applications for correct functioning of
standard security controls now in
version 2.0 the way we have added this
quality criteria are clubbed together
with the question so if you say no for
any of this quality criteria or if you
do not meet any of the quality criteria
the answer for the question should
simply be no you cannot have yes if you
do not meet the quality criteria that is
how we added the second dimension of
measurement in this particular
assessment and the key goal here was we
a lot of debate when we are deciding on
this one and we went back to this some
of these sandport principles and one of
the core principle is simplicity so as a
result we decided to add quality
criteria for each question this way time
to complete an assessment did not
significantly increase with sample dotto
and this was the key thing which helped
us guide in making this decision because
we did not want to create this very long
and laborious activity that is why we
added simplicity and we added this
quality criteria to the existing
question which was aim to cover the
coverage
all mature score for the security
practice is calculated by taking the
average of maturity level one between
stream a and screen B and adding that
the level of maturity at level two and
level three and once you add all of this
you come up with the rating for that
basically practice
once you finish the assessment
you need to define the target as per
business drivers and the risk profile
for your organization now the most
important thing over here is to estimate
the cost so on average it takes about
five to ten percent higher cost for
every level of maturity when you try to
increase every level of maturity it
takes about five to ten percent higher
costs we do not have concrete data but
this is based on most of the Sam
petitioners feedback this is the rough
estimate so you need to keep that cost
in mind as well and this costs again
varies from organization to organization
there is profile as well as the existing
level of maturity so keep that in mind
once you set the target you can define
the plant and in order to do that first
you need to determine the chain schedule
as per the upcoming release and develop
and update roadmap plan for the next
four or five phases now this phase wise
approach is also good for from the
change management perspective and what
we recommend is no less than three
phases and no more than five phases to
roll out Sam
we also recommend that you start with
the most impactful security practices
such as training in awareness and site
assessment in the first phase
once plan is defined start the
implementation
implement activities using sample auto
guide that we have worded as part of the
resources leverage other Sam projects
Sam aspires to be an umbrella project of
all samples so always projects and what
it means is what Sam project can map
back to one of these Sam business
functions and security practice so we
want to have this mapping done as part
of future directions
and here are some of the example or
voice projects and how they map back to
various same business functions and
security practices so as you can see
some of the worst projects edges was top
ten that can map to multiples and
business functions and not just one
business function
after implementation we need to create
and update scorecards on regular
interval by capturing scores from before
and after an iteration of assurance
program build out and communicate this
progress to the management the key thing
over here is communication and again
this phases they have lost somewhere
between three months to 12 months 1215
months so it again depends on the scope
of roll-off the phase can be can last
about 3 months or it can last up to 12
months as well but the key thing is you
need to communicate the progress to the
senior management on regular intervals
now here are some of the available
resources which have to get you started
using Sampo all these resources are
linked to our Sam to our G website so if
you forget everything
just remember one website over time dot
o-r-g all the resources are linked to
that particular website so loo visit
that website
and one more thing sand benchmark
initiative so what is sem benchmark
initiative
it helps answer the question how do I
compare to other organizations
if you remember we discussed on others
operations maturity framework earlier
during this talk called vision same
benchmark initiative is inspired by
vision be seen does really good job at
providing comparison with other secure
auditions the goal of this project is to
collect most comprehensive data set
related to all organization maturity of
application also physical programs
this data should come from both
self-assessing organizations and
consultancies that perform third-party
assessments
we understand privacy is key here
because many organization may not want
to reveal their level of maturity or
immaturity to rest of the world keeping
that in mind or data collection process
will be anonymous and we will make sure
that privacy is always at the forefront
when we collect this data
you
so before finishing this talk just quick
highlight on what is the future for Sam
so Sam will continue like the previous
version we are able to have smaller and
faster iterative versions version 2.1
2.3 so on so forth in fact we just
embarked on ch CD ourself
the second one as I mentioned earlier is
the references to otherwise projects
because we envision Sam being more of an
umbrella project under us and all of us
project can map back to one of the Sam
business functions so we will definitely
provide more references to other wise
projects
and last but not least is it's a very
aspirational goal of making this
assessment and roadmap creation more of
an online process that would really help
design this to match the moon more
modern software applications itself
currently if you can see you have to
download some of these resources such as
the spreadsheet which would call it
worksheet to do the assessment and
create road maps eventually we aspire to
make all of these things through online
assessment and online road map creation
templates
having said that I the key call for
action here is to start using Sam
Stemper Auto and somebody says proof of
the pudding is in trying it so I really
asked everybody over here to start using
Sam 2.2 and if you have any question you
can always reach out to me and others
Sam volunteers and also you can reach
out to us for any feedback you might
have
thank you
Thank You Hardy we will go into a short
break and then we will be right back
with Ryan tick thank you