all right thanks everyone thanks for
showing up uh let's get started here
I'm Tony Ruchi and here's a little bit
of background on me
maybe all heard me talk before
I'm a retired counterintelligence
special agent and I kind of grew up in
the intelligence community running
computer crimes investigations for a
good part of my career and retired in
2004 went out to work at Oak Ridge
National Lab and 2011 we recruited to go
out to Reno Nevada to go build some data
centers out there and after we stood
them up I stepped away and began
starting some companies in the
commercial space out there well I found
very quickly that a lot of folks are you
know focused on keep the lights on and
the day-to-day operations and one of the
things that they used to ask me about
all the time is hey can you come out and
and give us a look you know kind of a
walk down our stack and give us a
security look another set of eyes and so
that really stood up a couple of sectors
of business for me and and you know as a
result I kind of transitioned a lot of
that military training in the government
space into commercial sector and
especially these days with ransomware
and data breach is kind of running off
the charts it's one of those things that
I mean it's not going away while a lot
of people have been out of work there's
many of us in the InfoSec community and
especially the incident responders side
of it would have been you know busier
than ever so let's get right into it and
take a look kind of what you know
everybody has their their media sources
and the news that you look at these days
and you know people think about when
they have the security education
awareness they start talking about their
email really focusing on your email and
watch the links and your email your
bedded email but you know one of the
things that's transitioning has been
transitioning for a while is you know
where do you read your news you're
either reading it online or your
portable or your mobile devices and that
type of thing but in a lot of cases we
were reading it online and watching you
know web-based news and you know how
easy is that to manipulate that traffic
especially if somebody's in close
proximity to you do like a minute man in
the middle attack and be able to
manipulate that traffic and put
something there in the headlines that's
attractive to you and I know you're
gonna click on it if it's if it's
something that's relevant to you so
everybody has their own media of choice
for social media some people like to
watch videos you're watching you know
your news through very specific apps if
you've got children in school you might
have an app that's provided by the
school and the staff a lot of cases
everybody's ordering from online
services these days so you know you're
waiting for that next package coming in
for Amazon it's pretty simplistic to
create that link and put it in your put
it in a message to you and there's a
good chance you're going to click that
and if you that mobile device happens to
be connected to your domain then then
it's game over in a lot of cases it's
just like clicking that email link
within those environments so just a an
age we equate ransomware to the corona
virus in your network you have to ask
yourself a few questions is your network
really ready for a ransomware attack I
guess the real question is can you
recover your network from a ransomware
attacks especially if you're the
defender yourself you know one of the
challenges being able to defend that and
recover it we always ask one of the
first questions that I always ask well
first two questions when I get called
out on an incident is you know do you
have in bet in onboard IT staff or they
outsource and what your recovery
strategy look like do you have a
recovery plan and your are you able to
recover you know you know a lot of cases
they don't really know if they can
recover because they've never exercised
it so we ask them have you ever actually
your cyber incident response plan then
that's when you get the sucking teeth in
a lot of cases you know it's either the
answer is going to be no or yeah we're
kind of building in that direction but
yeah we really haven't haven't gotten
there yet yeah we're working on that
well it's too late when you're you're
still working on that and the reality is
in a lot of cases they don't even know
what the hell it is and then that's the
day that you know that you're probably
going to be negotiating with somebody if
down the road if they have been
compromised with ransomware so that's
one of those types of you know moments
and it's the aha moment you know early
on now one of these to consider is the
type of ransomware that's compromised
the network as well because there's a
few families of ransomware that I've
dealt with and just since Thanksgiving
I've dealt with about six or seven cases
specifically and on three occasions
phobos ransomware which comes under the
Dharma family is one of those unique
varieties of ransomware where it has a
nasty habit a favorable habit for us of
failing midstream and so it doesn't do
full encryption it doesn't continuous
the overwrite the data that it's deleted
so as it encrypts the the top layer of
the files you can in a lot of cases go
in and do like a forensics recovery if
you've overwritten data or view deleted
data in the past and trying to recover
that data from the from the raw drive
and and I'll talk about that a bit and
I'm gonna kind of mix two different
cases I know I know in the bio there I
said that I was going to talk about a
specific case but I'm going to talk
about two of them one was with regards
to to Phobos and and then another one
here that is pretty unique in and of
itself here that we'll talk about
but that's something I always consider
and we'll talk about recovery in just a
little bit but for those attackers out
there you know some are much more
disciplined and they have their attack
Keim's and then you know they do this as
a business you know ransomware as a
service is out there
well ransomware as a service heads-up
dashboards and command control centers
they can be purchased for you know four
hundred dollars anybody can go out there
in the dark net and you know purchase
Philadelphia and if you're familiar with
any kind of sales management or CMS
dashboards is very Salesforce like you
know you can track who you've who your
victims are you can build your attack
platforms you can attack specific type
of systems you can keep track of them
globally where they are and it gives you
a lot of heads-up information in there
one of the things with regards to
Philadelphia and a few others I think
it's pretty interesting that there's the
the give mercy button there if you look
at it down the bottom about about seven
o'clock so somebody gives you a good
enough story to the attacker they're
gonna be able to you know just go ahead
and hit that button and give you your
decryption keys back or send you to a
link where you can download those keys
so that's it's kind of feature-rich
right if you might say Joe Cruz another
c2 here that is been in the news and
it's been used quite a bit lately
and it just has a few more features than
Philadelphia but it's just a
straightforward navigation you can just
walk right down it's very intuitive you
don't have a have have to have a lot of
skill or training in it that's the scary
thing is because a lot of these folks
who are hidden companies especially on
the small to medium scale they don't
have a lot of training and so if they
screw something up in your network or if
you piss them off or they get pissed off
themselves just out of out of pure
anxiety they walk away and you're not
getting your data back if you've got no
way to recover yourself and so it's
extremely important to manage the
conversation and we'll talk about that
and
pretty good detail just a second there's
a few more shots of Joker ooh kind of
look at there's the victims list there
it gives you a nice heads-up display of
your victims themselves and then hey
there's my reporting page so I can see
who has what and how I want to report
that activity out maybe I've got a
report to my seniors because I'm I'm
just a field agent out there and I need
to keep on task right I'm tier I'm tier
one and then here's your attack builder
if you want to go ahead and build a
campaign it's just like if you you know
if you have like the know before or fish
me or whatever those other you know
campaign builders are it's the same type
of thing you build your campaigns of
attack against your your targets so you
have to think about you know kind of
your your victim management and do's and
dont's they're you know when I get
called out for an instant response and
somebody calls up and it's usually the
first conversation is is extreme they're
in stream peril and this is the worst
day in a company's life in a lot of
cases because they've invested you know
so much and they're keeping their
business you know operating or making it
successful and and then now all of a
sudden they just watched everything go
sideways overnight they come in after a
long weekend a long holiday and that's
usually when those calls come in over
Thanksgiving Christmas New Year's fourth
of July or whatever that long holiday
might be that's when these things seem
to happen but you know remember that
whenever you're negotiating with an
attacker or any of the conversations
you're acting on the behalf of your
clients so you can't have a
holier-than-thou type of attitude and
you need to to make sure that you know
if the client doesn't already have a
Bitcoin account you may already have one
if you're an intersect professional and
you may already have one day you may you
know be willing to offer up you know the
the account to to do the transaction but
in some cases it's a
liability and they don't want that they
want they we've got to keep it
maintaining within our our own sector so
we've got to build the count themselves
so that's something very important we'll
talk about the account itself because
you don't you stand up a Bitcoin account
overnight and you don't just stand up at
a count tonight and then throw money in
it this afternoon and then expect to
transact you know fifty thousand dollars
tomorrow it doesn't work that way in
most cases and in some cases you're
going to get these ransom notes says you
have 48 hours to respond and act and
move money and you know that's that's an
indicator for you whether or not you're
dealing with the mature organization or
you know some script kiddie out there
who may have just downloaded and and
spent you know his allowance on a four
hundred all a piece of software lets you
kind of look through that we're gonna
walk through each one of these here but
it's important that you pay attention to
these and I'm going to have this whole
slide deck available to you at the end
as well I'll drop it in my my instance
there but no matter what goes what
happens with with the engagement one of
the questions it's always asked from the
client is you know alright so if I pay
this we're definitely getting our keys
back right and the answer is you know
maybe maybe not these days in most of
the cases that I worked it's it's high
probability that it's upwards of you
know mid 90s percent that you're getting
the credentials back or the decryption
keys back in whatever form that is this
day it's almost like they have a Yelp
you know in the underworld where they
they've got to keep up their Yelp rating
because you know when you do your
research and you find out who it is
who may be attacking you you kind of
know whether or not you're going to get
them back by the time you you pull that
trigger but we'll talk about that as we
kind of roll along here so getting back
to the Bitcoin account set up you know
is a few folks who've already s you know
you know setting up
Bitcoin account you know am i setting up
an individual account or my city setting
up a business account does it make a
difference
it does because the way you set it up
allows you to move money quicker and you
have forms of identity that you can
provide that you can validate yourself
you know the pure essence of you know
cryptocurrency is the anonymity in a lot
of cases but in these tape types of
incidents you're not going to have all
that at that level of anonymity if you
need to set it up quickly because you
need to perform provide you know some
form of federal ID or something like
that a lot of cases depending on you
know which service you decide to set up
an account and so those are things
they're all taking consideration and
I've got a little bit coin 101 that I'm
going to add to the deck there at the
end of it along with these right here as
well but yeah you pick your your
exchange of choice you know coin base is
an example there put them things that
you can do you can put credit card you
know attach that to the account and you
can move money almost immediately but
you can only move a little bit of money
at a time and you have to kind of build
the trust with them and you have to you
can level up if you will I'll show that
next slide but it's important to point
out but if you do bank transfers yeah I
can move a whole lot of money with the
bank transfer fifty thousand dollars I
can move that tonight but that money is
going to sit there just like if I moved
fifty thousand dollars into a bank
account I really can't touch it for you
know five six seven eight nine days
depending on where that is and wouldn't
you know it as soon as you start a talk
like this that's when the phone rings I
think the phone of the dogs in most
cases but so those are things that you
need to take time and research and and
and help educate them as well because
the levelling up is extremely important
a lot of cases you're dealing with you
know maybe they have been hit with a you
know a - Bitcoin ransom or something
like that and you can negotiate those
things down
but you know in some cases you know
you're dealing with you know you know a
million dollars and that that might be
extremely challenging in a lot of cases
so those are things that to take it in
consideration and so you can see by the
time you level up into level 3 which
which may take a bit of time so you know
you can encourage them to use your
account or use a another organization's
account that already has one or if
you've got a pre relationship with them
already and that's something that
they're concerned about have that
conversation now say hey you might want
to go ahead and set up an account and
just move some money back and forth and
then begin stablishing the bona fides
with with that exchange that way if the
time does come because you know it's
quite quite possible that their time is
going to come and then it all boils down
to how fast they can move it to be able
to respond and keep those numbers down I
guess the big takeaway there is is at
the end we already reinforced that a few
times so here's an example of the faux
beau splash screen and it's on the info
text file that's just dropped usually in
the C driver or somewhere in the route
and it's dropped in a bunch of different
places on a machine once it's been
compromised
but you know kind of walking through
that tells you a lot because most cases
you're gonna see this just as a copy and
paste template and they'll just change
the header information their primary
secondary email and the reference ID
it's it's their reference ID and you
descend it's a it's a dash and then then
you're usually a four to six digit
reference ID and that's you as the
victim and that's that's what you put in
all the headers back to the emails back
to them so it gives you a little bit
instruction there and here's some your
proof of life opportunity here they're
already telling you hey we want to show
you that we can decrypt your data you
it's important to make sure that you
leverage that and take advantage of that
if a time comes when you had that
conversation with them that
you want to go ahead and send them a
couple of mundane files that have been
encrypted first to prove them prove to
you that they can compromise are that
they can decrypt those files and return
those to you and then this is an
important statement here about how to
obtain the bitcoins this is where you
can really determine the maturity in a
lot of cases of the organization and you
can tell whether or not they're seasoned
they know what they're doing
the verbage in here is very
straightforward and standard they won't
try to rush you they won't try to throw
any idle threats in here but this is one
of those ones that they those those
blocks right here where they'll throw in
there that you've only got 48 hours to
stand up a Bitcoin account and money
needs to be there or you know we're
gonna start doubling it every every 24
hours after that you know no delays and
I'll try to throw all the the anxiety
and stress on you that's what really
flips people out but that's also an
indicator that somebody's really doesn't
know what they're doing because they
don't realize and take time to sit back
and think the other indicator is
secondary communications while you've
got a couple of email accounts up there
that you can use and leverage you also
have a jabber client in here and I'll
show you the jet or the another
communications client and the other
splash screen here in a second but that
is more useful than the email because
email you're dealing with time zones and
things like that all the time and you're
not going to get a whole lot of sleep
while you're doing this because you have
to operate on their time zones in most
cases to maximize your communication and
you don't want to let communications lag
and you don't want to let let them go to
sleep because they're dealing with lots
of lots of victims at a time and you
don't want them to put you at the bottom
of their priority stack once you finally
do get your act together and you you are
ready to transact funds on behalf of a
client and the last one air is just you
know I think it's kind of cute in here
they're giving you little heads up a
little security awareness on how not to
damage further damage your files
one of the interesting things a lot of
cases you're able to take those files
off of a hard drive and drop them onto a
virtual space and and still recover them
so it's kind of a moot point but it is
pretty interesting now here's a bit
Paymer splash screen and it's a little
bit different because when you hit the
screen and it pops up it shows you
exactly what you are gonna owe them
coming back to the phobos you'll notice
in there you don't know how much euro
you owe them yet you won't the clock
really won't start ticking for you until
you reach out to one of those email
addresses up top and you tell them eh I
got this on my computer and it said to
reach out to you how much do I owe ya or
you know what what do I need to do you
know you kind of play it dumb and we'll
talk about that in the back-and-forth
and the messaging but bitpay Murs one
where it it shows you exactly how much
they're demanding right up front it
gives you their wallet information it
shows you your reference ID you put that
in an email to them you go out to their
wallet you can verify that that wallet
is active and they're just waiting for
you to drop money in there in this
instance here they're asking for ten
Bitcoin and here's my contact email so
you can also email me or you can use
that chat in the very bottom right
corner on that first half of the pane
that proves to be probably the most
effective form of communications that
you'll you'll use emails are great but
the online chat is extremely useful in
these cases especially when you get an
idea of you know the time differential
are they four hours six hours in front
of you you know when when do they answer
the first time usually and when's the
last time you hear from you can start
putting that association matrix together
as to where they might be regionally and
then you can pull a lot of it out of
there out of their vernacular as well
for me I like this you know keep a lot
of screens heads up on my machine when
I'm having any kind of conversation even
if I'm just having conversation with
them so I want to make sure like VPNs
not
down not down and using encrypted
browsers a good idea obviously and it
just creates another layer of protection
for you because here I'm using my
machine I might be at home or I might be
on client side at my hotel or wherever
that might be but I don't want to give
away any kind of detail about me if I
don't have to any needles machines and
so you know keeping up their blockchain
I like to look at their their wallet as
well to see if they're also receiving
transactions elsewhere are they getting
a whole lot of money running in there
and all of a sudden you know they're
only looking for a few bitcoins for me
but I'm watching you know a hundred and
fifty bitcoins transact through this
wallet a day you know these folks don't
need my money but how bad does the
client need their data back and those
types of things and so or you know are
they asking me for one Bitcoin and I
don't watch any money transact that
there's there's two reasons why either
they're you know they stood that wallet
up today and you can you can verify you
know when it was stood up and you know
if they're smart they're only using one
wallet per victim and they spin up
another wallet for each one of their
victims but they might be dealing with
you know twenty or thirty victims in any
given time so you know again it all
depends and every one of them seems to
be a little bit different then I have a
working browser in there where I can do
some you know heads up research without
having to jump screens and things like
that around there so when you send out
in that phobos message and you send that
email back out to them you get that
first response back and it tells them
that that's what it tells you hey I
decrypted all your files you need to pay
1.8 bitcoins in this instance here this
was just a couple months ago where that
was about twelve thousand dollars at the
time at the current exchange rate twelve
thousand sixty three dollars I think it
was is what it was and and then it gives
you all the instructions all the way
down the line in the very bottom you can
see the email that I sent to them is
very
bored very professional remember it's a
business transaction it's its business
to them you don't need to play games you
don't want to you know use a lot of
slang and and and street slang and
things like that and try to you know
Google leach speak because that's not
who you're dealing with in most cases
you know you want to do some research on
you know in the background you've got
somebody in your team that's either
yourself or somebody else who's skilled
in forensics you want to be able to
start pulling some data off of there
looking at you know indicators of
compromise and see what you're dealing
with and make sure that you actually do
have you know a specific family or a
variety of ransomware as opposed to
having a false indicator or somebody
just is playing games with you and has
messed around with your machine and then
drops you know and index file in there
like that which has happened in the past
and it really scares the hell out of
people so you're looking at and and it's
very clear when you drop them into
places like virustotal
or you can go to you know any run and
you can drop one of those executables or
even the binary into a Windows machine
and watch that thing spin up and watch
you know what happens it's a great
demonstration platform and you can do
this if you don't have your own
capabilities in your own environment or
you're anxious about doing that and
spinning up a virtual machine and
watching it blow up you or you can do
that yourself right there online and
drop it into an environment like that so
it's a great resource to have bookmarked
so that was you know coming back to that
business transaction that was my email
back to them is you know you spin up
either fire mail proton whatever you
know any kind of account a burner
account that you can use for that
instance and you know I'm I'm one of
them for that that sake of that
discussion remember the first
conversation you have with that client
is going to be you know there's
absolutely no way that I'm
hanging a ransom on here so we got to do
everything that we can do well when you
start running down that whole chain of
events with them and you say look do you
have any way of being able to recover
that data do you have any backups local
do you have them in the cloud is there
any possible way and you've exhausted
all those resources then you start
having that math conversation with the
you know the the c-suite of how much
would it cost you to reconstitute and
rebuild all of that critical data that
you lost because you don't need
everything you just need the critical
nuggets how much would it cost you and
if that number is more than what that
ransom is then you start having to have
that next conversation with well it
might be logistically you know and
economically better for you to maybe pay
that take your chances and recover that
data that we scrub it we carve it off
and then we blow up all your instances
of your active environment that was
compromised and the replace drives or
machines that they're you know
completely dead in the water and that
type of thing so you had those
conversations but you know it takes you
back to this point here when okay you
grow on through that entire exercise yes
it is necessary for us to to go ahead
and do that we received that response
back from them and now the clock starts
ticking when you're dealing with
something like Phobos where you've now
learned the destiny and how much it's
going to cost then you go back to them
is this something you can deal with it's
it's almost like going to a flea market
you can almost always ask for half at a
minimum and in most cases as long as
you're keeping that conversation alive I
like to play the you know poor country
boy type of conversation with a lot of
them and and you know we're just you'll
see some of my conversation here we're
just a poor rural school we're just
trying to look out for the kids and that
type of thing so you know but as you as
you get down to the the conversation
here you know you say well alright we're
thinking about it I've talked to the
leadership in the meantime you want to
keep the
conversational I'm now the clock is
tickin with him so this is the time that
you want to go ahead and throw them some
files and you send them some file that
doesn't have any kind of critical data
in it you don't want to send them your
password lists and now I can get into
all my systems because the IT guy you
know is AWOL but you want to you want to
send them those files and then they're
gonna send them back to you in most
cases yeah they send you a link and I
like this one here because this is a
pretty interesting password that they
chose they believe in strong passwords
you know we always kid get around you
know when we find some some you know
botnets out there or something like that
they don't even protect the botnets
themselves and they've got a default
password in their infrastructure a lot
of times but when they choose a password
like that maybe they thought we were
just the poor bumpkin company at the
time but I don't think that's the case
you'll see in a moment so goes back to
the don't play games with them you know
here's there's one instance where yeah
I'm just telling them we're a small you
know management company and this is
where they were asking for 1.8 you know
Bitcoin which is $12,000 and they did
have a rule with their board members
that the general manager could not allow
I could not spend anything more than 55
thousand dollars without calling
together a board board meeting in for
them to vote to vote on it and so rather
than having to call up an emergency
board meeting to go through that whole
thing he's like hey let's go ahead and
just put that back to them and offer it
up and see what they say and so when we
did that they did say hey yeah you know
what we'll take fifty five hundred
dollars is the least amount that we can
take and you know and then you start
going off from there and you can see I
tried playing the whole you know poor us
you know look at our small handful of
employees here we're a small development
they rely on us to be up and operating
and you know kind of play the old and
come on do it for the kids and I even
through the kovat in there
but yeah we still
ended up now on the other side this is
one where I may have taken a little bit
of a heavy hand with them and saying hey
you know it's unfortunate you make it
you've mistaken us for a large
corporation yes maybe wasn't the right
way to go well it clearly wasn't the
right way to go we're at rule school and
they did hit a school district was a
pretty big school district and you can
see the rest of it I won't read it to
your verbatim but you know I tried
playing it down hey we're just real
small we just want to make sure that we
focus on the kids in this rule town and
their response back was an email with an
attachment that had the financials from
the previous year you know let them know
look I was in your system I know how
much your budget is I know how much your
expenditures were and it's just a drop
in the bucket for what I'm asking you
here and we did end up negotiating it
down there yeah they asked for 10 and
they agreed on three I went back to him
after we got that message back and I
said hey can we please discuss it and
this is where we're in that chat window
and you catch them online you just keep
it going back and forth with them and
you know I said hey you said to reach
out to you discuss the price and I'm
still kind of played that we're still
small and he was just very
matter-of-fact so what's your offer yeah
I don't care about all the sob story
what's your offer and you know this is
what I stalled for a little bit more
time with them and say hey I can't make
a legitimate offer without going to the
board he said so discuss it and then you
know do it well we were rolling into the
4th of July weekend at that at that time
so he said all right you've got until
Monday so we did buy a little bit more
time in that instance and one of the
things important is to keep that
conversation alive so every day I sent
them at least two messages just to let
them know hey just to let you know we're
still working it and I'm waiting on the
board and hopefully they're they're
gonna be able to find everybody and pull
them all together and we're gonna get a
decision even sooner than we had
expected and so
kind of kept that going and finally I
told him I said hey I've been offered a
grant approved to offer you one Bitcoin
and still trying to beg and plead and
you have to swallow your pride in a lot
of cases because you're you know here I
have a grown man trying to beg and plead
for mercy and you feel like you know
geez I feel like I'm just you know
cowering down to them in a lot of cases
but remember you're doing this on behalf
of an entire community or whoever that
that client is at the time and so you
can see the response back and forth in
there one of the things that I'd ask and
it's not captured on this is can you can
you take a smaller amount right now and
give us the encryption keys for just a
few of the machines because it's really
important we get payroll and that hold
nine yards and then you can you know
when we can get the rest of the money we
can pay out the rest of it then you
could give us another key to give us the
rest of data that's where he was
explaining now it's it's one key to
crypts everything so it's it's a
one-and-done kind of deal so you can see
how that went and then
it's important not to make promises you
can't keep you can't say that yep okay
Monday I'm gonna move this money and
it's going to definitely happen on that
day it's you know I'm gonna try we're
gonna we're gonna attempt it I always
use the kind of the the soft messaging
the passive voice that this is my first
time hey we don't do this very often you
know we don't we don't have a Bitcoin
account I don't even know what bitcoin
is before this all happened
and you know we finally got the money in
the account but it was being delayed
because it was a new count stood up and
then you know so I asked him just to try
to keep the conversation alive is this
common and yeah so this is kind of
coming back to the the other case where
we'll do our best to move that money
just kind of keeping it you know passive
but at the same time it's not me doing
this it's us as a collective team
because I'm representing a large you
know organization and so it's not just
me they didn't just hit a single person
and that way they'd understand that
they're not just dealing with one person
I don't have decision-making authority
and so I always try to put it in that
way
versus I you know you hit me you you you
put me in this predicament it's it's us
and we type of thing so you get to the
point where you've been watching your
heads-up display and you you finally
transact that money it drops into their
account you watch their wallet transact
the funds and then it populates with you
know whatever the the volume was this is
a response that you get with the bid
Paymer which is pretty interesting and
comical from an investigator perspective
because at the end of the day they're
trying to help you protect your network
further down the road they try to tell
you that they don't intend to come back
or something like that but they give you
a little security awareness but they
also teach you how to
the tool itself but the interesting
piece is very end I've highlighted it
there they point you to Jim shavers Mimi
Katz
blogpost back in 2016 defending against
mini cats and so when you click on that
you end up jumping to Jim's page there
which is pretty interesting many of us
have read it over the years but you know
they're they're kind of giving you an
exit security awareness breathing hey
knuckleheads here's how I here's how I
did it in a lot of cases you know we
find that that phobos's attack vector is
through 3389 with open RDP and that's
where you know it's extremely important
to stress that the folks you know hey
look this is this is how we we see that
they got in and it's important to be
able to capture you know a lot of that
perimeter information like the logs and
all that traffic like that because one
of the questions that the board members
or any investors or any of the SI
squeezer gasps was this an inside job or
if somebody hit us from the outside how
did they get in what happened and they
want to know the full forensic story of
what happened and did anything
exfiltrate my perimeter and and that's
you know where you can or you can't
answer the question depending on what
available information you have because
the last act that attacker is going to
do before they exit rate your system is
they're going to delete any logs and
they're gonna pick up all the crumbs
that they can on the way out and so they
delete a lot of those logs and in a lot
of cases because your encrypted and your
your full disk encryption now in a lot
of cases you don't have the ability to
recover that so it's hit and miss and
especially if they you know are hit you
at your edge and you didn't have a an
independent firewall not a cases a lot
of these small to medium-sized
businesses it's not the case yeah I had
a server and it had some firewall
logging up my printers got firewall on
its off it's probably okay right you can
see where they're standing so it's
extremely important to be able to pull
that forensics information for them to
be able to do that analysis to say you
can't say to your investors that nothing
left our perimeter so that transitions
you know to the type of conversation
when they go public and it's extremely
important for them to be transparent
with regards to what's happened and the
last thing they want to do is lie
intentionally you know withholding some
that information because we all know
that that first report is always wrong
and it's just you know what's that
second report going to hold is it going
to be a hundred eighty degrees on that
story this is this is just kind of
Toni's joy in all this as a hunter and
an investigator I like to know where
this money is going I try to chase that
money as long as I can after the
transaction has been made that's part of
why I keep that wallet up because you
can chase the trail to a certain degree
you can see in this instance here where
our wallet makes the payment to the
attacker and then the attacker starts
breaking that up right away and he
starts carving that money up and he's
break it into the you know 2.2 4 then
0.75 and then each of those start
running down their trails and they're
either paying out or they're washing it
a little bit of both but they'll start
you know kind of laundering or blending
that money so that it's obfuscated a
little bit deeper in case Secret Service
or anybody else is trying to track them
hard but in most cases they're paying
out anybody that's on their team and
that's usually that smaller bucket on
there where they're they're paying
people out and then you can chase those
trails down as far as you go and then
you finally lose track of them so it's
difficult at best and there's a lot of
folks who just you know when you when
you lock on to a wallet they want you to
throw them the wallet and they'll do all
that in the background you can't eat up
your time you know hunting and chasing
that down the road but here's kind of a
blow-up if you couldn't see it very well
on your screen of that larger
transaction and that larger slice as
they were beginning to blow it out so
once you've got your money transacted
and you got
the keys now then you start depending on
the type of decryption tools that you
ransomware that you have you begin
decrypting it your conversation with the
attacker in a lot of cases isn't over
you have to maintain coms with them
because in some instances you receive a
file you download it and you executed on
the encrypted files or the machine and
you're done you're done conversation
with conversation with them in the case
of Phobos that's not the case you end up
having to run and I'll kind of walk you
through you run the tool on the
respective drive
hey you just you know scroll to the
drive and you're either looking at a a
directory or you're just doing a full
disk itself and drop it in here and
you're scanning it and then what it does
is it drops the hash back to you well
let me back up here and you email that
hash back to the attacker and then they
send you another hash for the decryption
and you pick that hash up at their drop
site and then once you receive that hash
you drop it back into the tool and then
you decrypt that specific instance in
that machine every machine has its own
unique signature that you have to do so
if you've got an entire instance and a
company that's got a hundred machines
you're doing this transaction with
Phobos a hundred times so that's why
it's important to segment out a where's
my critical day is just my my financial
server is in my core server do I need to
hit all of my end-user machines you know
do I have the ability to do that do I
care
so you really have to have those
conversations because that can really be
time-consuming because once you let that
conversation die for you know a half a
day or a day they're gone and they're
not coming back they've already got
their money there's no priority for them
to you know make sure that you're taking
care of cleaning house it's speaking of
cleaning house
you know once you've gone into that
server
you pull off of that you know or that
machine that's got that critical data
it's interesting a lot of times to see
what is left there and which artifacts
are are left behind and what value add
or gifts they gave you and you can see
in this instance here there's a variant
of a Bitcoin miner that's you know left
in there even after all of the
ransomware is removed through the
Decrypter so it leaves a bit there and
that's why we always had that
conversation with well I've decrypted it
I'm back to operations thanks a lot guys
go away it's not that you now you've got
to go ahead and and scrub that pertinent
data off and then you're starting over
with fresh drives in some instances it's
time to refresh your hardware as well
because that was legacy Hardware anyway
it's that time to go ahead if you're
going to go through that effort let's
just go ahead and you know build out new
instances or let's just you know migrate
you to the cloud or wherever that might
be depending on your deployment but you
know it's important to reach in there
and clean that up and blow up those
machines if they've got a little bit of
a disciplined capability in there I talk
like this wouldn't be valuable unless
you know kind of what do we see in the
horizon you know ransomware is gonna
continue to grow it's not going away
anytime soon you know regardless of what
you heard back in 2018 when they said eh
2019 it's gonna start fading away then
you had that little downturn it's almost
like the corona right it's it's gonna
downturn then it's probably gonna come
back up for a lot of folks in some areas
because they're getting out ahead of
themselves well you know we're already
seeing a lot of the the fireless attacks
out there where you're not clicking on a
PDF that sent to you an email it's
happening with those apps that I talked
to you up front about and then you're
also seeing instances where some of the
teams are saying look you know if you
play games and you refuse to pay then
we're gonna dump your data
out there in public domain and so daxing
your victims is extremely important for
the the victims out there to understand
when they ask that question you know
well did they excellent rate anything
it's highly likely that they have
excellent rated that data from your
network already because they wouldn't be
able to Doc's you if that's not the case
so and it's going to get bigger and
bigger they're they're already targeting
you know large financial institutions
and and hospitals especially in these
critical times it's pathetic to see
those types of things but I've dealt
with three cases alone just over the the
period that we've been you know quasi
quarantined and that's not always the
case when you're doing something like
this but the fact the matter is it's
going to get worse before it gets better
and you know you're already seeing
instances you know even prior to the the
new year of people dumping people's
creds and and access to their machines
as well as their internals out there I
think last week there was a there was an
instance where an Israeli group dumped a
bunch of folks well is that your end of
speech timer no that was that was mine
yeah that was that was mine no I put my
little heads up to myself over here so
let it run over trying to be respectful
of rush hour I know anybody got drive
home to the refrigerator yeah yeah
pretty much I already made my way there
so I'll leave you with this you know if
there's you know there's always those
lists of here are the top things you
need to be doing really we're all doing
MFA we all should be thinking about it
if you're not but the reality is if
there's one thing that a company needs
to invest their money in is three to one
resilient backup recovery strategy and
and practice practice practice give the
confidence to the IT teams even when
they've got an effective solution in
place if they haven't practiced that
there's an extreme amount of anxiety
when they push that button the first
time and if you've been there you can
speak to it it's it's extremely anxious
for those those folks out there
everything
else in there is traditional you know
administrative housekeeping good
networking security and and taking care
of business but with that I'll let you
guys get back to lay Tony I've got we've
got one question on the line for you
have you had cases where you have made
negotiations sent the payment and then
receive nothing from the attacker how do
you avoid the risk or at least
communicate it to the client the risk
that they might pay and not get anything
that's that's a great question and it's
an upfront conversation because as soon
as you start having that conversation
with them that okay you know we've we've
determined that we can't recover your
data you don't have any backups there's
no way to rebuild this that's very
unique
you know one-off data and there's no
other way to get it back unless you
reach out to who your attacker was and
try to try to do this their question is
usually alright so if I pay this no
matter what the price is I'm guaranteed
I'm going to get it back and the answer
is always you can't guarantee anything
in that and so you have to make sure
it's very clear them and they're not
trying to hold you liable for that as
well it's a huge risk you do see all
over the press a lot of instances where
they're not paid out but I'll tell you
I've done this for for quite a while and
it's in the mid 90s you know low to mid
90s that they're paying out and so it
does happen but it's a very rare
occasion these days that was more you
know three four years ago and you can
usually tell by the time you get to that
point that you're ready to transact
funds if you're dealing with somebody
who's mature organization or a kitty who
downloaded a piece of software and we
have one other question just curious
have you dealt with an issue where the
entire network and shared device were
encrypted yes yeah and so that's those
instances where you know you're not
spinning anything up and and and that's
you know one of the conversations we
have with a lot of folks on there as
when we do assessments and pen tests is
you know the make sure that your your
backup and storage is not binded to your
domain in a lot of those cases because
it's crawling the domain or any of those
domain attachments are are being
encrypted as well even when you push
them up into your your off-site storage
and we're seeing those so you know in
some some cases that's kind of comical
because you'll see in and you know were
the last pen test report that we got was
that we got gigged on it because it
wasn't we didn't have it bound well it's
it's actually a good thing these days
because it's it's giving you kind of a
gap in in some instances but that's
where you start rolling into the RA
let's find those critical machines and
let's try to do a forensic recovery of
those machines just like we might try to
you know do a disaster recovery for a
drive that's crashed it looks like we
have someone put in one more question
they're an inquisitive folk so when is
it better to refuse the payment or is it
never a good option
you're talking about refuse life use to
pay the ransom so yeah that's a great
topic of discussion it really it turns
into a heated discussion so if you
remember about November of last year a
bunch of Mayors all across the country
and to date I think it's well over a
hundred there's something different
mayor's around the country have put
together this letter and they signed the
letter saying there we will not pay
ransom we're under any circumstances and
I shout out to the mayor of a couple of
cities that I do business with regularly
and I said good luck with that because I
know what your network looks like and
you're gonna fail hard when it comes
time to address that because if you
can't recover and you and I talked to
these these IT guys a lot of times and I
go man we think we have it but we
haven't exercise it well let's sit down
and exercise it you've got to have the
confidence and ability to recover that
and your IT team has to have the
confidence in themselves and and to just
arbitrarily say there's absolutely no
way that we're gonna pay it you know
it's you tongue in cheek you just have
to say good luck with that because it's
you have to be willing to have that
conversation you know at least ask if if
you've got no other option because what
are you gonna do and Tony the masses are
asking for your slide deck yeah I'm
gonna drop my slide deck on the on the
link on the B sides talk there so on the
schedule so I'll drop that in there
shortly afterwards here perfect well
thanks for coming out with you guys
thank you guys for joining on the talk
here and hope you enjoyed it and don't
hesitate to reach out