yep so sorry ryan i don't know you but i
i know travis is
is one of our most neighborly hackers
in the uh community and um always
interest is
interested to see what he's talking
about if it's gonna be
radios or watches or watches with radios
or studebakers
i see we've already at least do the
bakers today we've ticked off the
studebaker box
real quick we got studebakers we got
cats
moisture studebakers and more cats yeah
we got one cat picture that includes a
studebaker
excellent every combination let's see
how many we can hit
all right it's it's five o'clock uh you
might as well uh
go ahead and take it away i don't see
any reason to wait
all right so um the
lecture we'll be sharing with you today
is based on a paper
that ryan and i wrote a few years back
um
the concept is that um many of you have
done a little bit of reverse engineering
and you would like to do more reverse
engineering
of uh things and
the skills that it takes to reverse
engineer an
embedded system really aren't that
different
from the skills that are necessary to
reverse engineer like a desktop
application or a game
um so
today we're going to discuss the fancy
tricks that
take what might be seen as a hardware
problem
and converting
that hardware problem into a software
problem that is then
easy to solve on a desktop with modern
tooling and
a nice environment uh sound good
everybody
um so i keep forgetting that there's no
audience
feedback in this so ryan is going to
sort of
play the part of the audience and
interrupt me if i skip over something or
fail
to express it properly this is
yeah feel free to send in those
all right so um reverse engineering
embedded systems is like uh loads of fun
on its own but at the end of the day
you're just looking
at numbers and figuring out what the
code does so what you really want
is a worthy project at the end of it
that proves that your time wasn't wasted
um one of the the first of these that
was pretty cool is an open source
project
called rockbox i believe this debuted in
2002.
um the idea was that they wrote their
own mp3
mp3 player application and then reverse
engineered
commercial mp3 player hardware in order
to port this application to run on it so
you can run this on an ipod you can run
this
on pretty much any of the
popular mp3 player hardware from 15
years ago back when
uh people collected mp3s
um another nifty result of revised
engineering
is a project that i started back when i
lived in new york or the godless north
as we call it a knoxville
this project is called mv380 tools it's
reverse engineered its patches
against a commercial
push push-to-talk two-way radio that can
be applied
against the manufacturer firmware so the
patches are written in c
they then change the behavior of the
commercial
from where the hardware was designed for
allowing you
to add such things as um like a phone
book
of amateur radio operators that are
registered with the protocol
you can enable promiscuous mode you can
also dump out the memory and
dump raw packets off of the air in order
to reverse engineer the settings
of a commercial network
and more recently hudson has been
playing around with this thing which is
a cpap machine that he's attempting to
firm our patch
into being a respirator
in all of these you need to begin by
understanding the architecture that
you're working with
then you need to dump a firmware image
load the firmware image into reverse
engineering tool
and then read it and annotate it until
you can understand what it does
so we're going to begin by taking the
architecture at a high level and then
we're going to jump into some details
um it's impossible to learn how to
reverse engineer a new uh
architecture in just one hour so what
you should be trying to remember from
this
are the nifty tricks that make the
reverse engineering easier
or the things that might block you and
how to get
beyond them and if you remember some
high-level details
about the architecture and its quirks
that would be good too
uh ryan you want to take this one and
begin
um like the the high level of what an
embedded arm
ship is sure
yeah so an embedded arm chip there's a
few examples that you see
here a common one that stm32 is a small
microcontroller the nrf51
is from nordic it's uh has an rf core in
it
and there's many other examples and in
arm
keep in mind that uh you have typically
32-bit
registers but your instructions could be
32-bit or it could be 16-bit if you're
in thumb mode
and i think that one of the the um
most notable things here to keep in mind
as your reverse engineering arm
is figuring out which context you're in
and figuring out how to follow as we
jump between contexts and we'll cover
that later
we're not talking about chips that have
support for legacy classic arm
instructions
these chips are notably small in size
and when we mean small and we look at
their
memory maps you'll see it's less than a
mega flash
less than 128 kilobytes from a very
small ram as well
so this helps keep the code size that we
have to look at smaller
but also means that the developers are
going to be playing tricks for code
optimization
and the code can run from sram but it
usually runs
in place from flash memory you'll only
find it running from sram when it's
a temporary patch or when it needs
to load a small driver to rewrite flash
memory
and for that reason can't be executing
from flash memory at the same time
the registers are different than in x86
or md64
in that um someone put some
thought into what the hell they should
be and decided to give them
meaningful names instead of
conglomerates of all the backward
compatibility history of the platform of
the 1970s
r15 is what you think of as the
instruction pointer in an x86
we call it a program counter or a pc in
risk ships
but it's the same thing r14
is the link register 13 is the stack
pointer
and then your local variables sit
between
r4 and r12 and it's the child's
responsibility to restore these before
returning to the parent
while registers 0 to 3 hold parameters
and return values and any time you call
another function
the child can clobber those and not fix
them on the return
the program counter is always on when
you're in thumb two mode
and if it were ever even that would mean
that you were executing in the classic
arm mode
with 32-bit wide instructions in thumb
tune mode your instructions can be
either 16 or 32 bits wide
and you have very little memory so the
high bits
of your program counter are pretty much
always consistent
and the same and point to flash memory
they can point to sram but in almost any
code that you look at they'll be running
consistently from inside of flash
now i said that there were two
instruction sets you've got arm and you
have thumb two
arm is optional in the smaller chips
but anything that's a little bit older
or a little bit
larger older as in like uh game boy or
game boy color
uh game boy advance um
i'm actually not entirely sure about the
game boy first generation the game boy
advance can definitely run both
instruction sets
and again it's the least significant bit
of
the program counter that tells you which
instruction set you're
executing so on the machines that can do
both
if you jump to an odd address you get
the thumb two interpretation
of the function that begins one byte
before
the pointer that you're going to if it's
an even address
you don't use the thumb two instruction
site you use the arm instruction set
and they did this so that you could
freely jump back and forth
between these different instruction sets
within one single program produced by a
single compiler
without the uh
without breaking compatibility and
function pointers
um r14 is the link register
you can think about this as the um
the return pointer on the call stack in
x86
except that in arm and in thumb and
power pc
and many other risk instruction sets
the instead of the the parent pushing
the return pointer onto the stack as it
calls the child
it's the child's responsibility to save
the link register before calling your
grandchild
so if you have a leaf function that you
call a leave function is a function that
has no children of its own
then um you branch to that function and
it can
do its work and return without ever
writing to the step
as long as it doesn't need to save
registers or call another child
or anything and because
this value gets thrown right back into
the program counter
on thumb two it will also always be odd
r13 is the stack pointer it is
always even it is always 32-bit aligned
and just like in x86 your stack grows
down
um the differences in the stack behavior
are
generally in that the sac is sort of
manually managed
when you do a call that doesn't directly
change the sac it's the child's
responsibility to save things after it
arrives
now the local variables are also
the responsibility of the child to
restore so
when you have a sum2 function
you'll see it begin by pushing the
link register and some of the local
variables
onto the call stack and then at the end
it pops them back off and if you read
through the function you'll see that
those
are the same registers that it changes
by overriding
the requirement is that the state be
restored
as long as it goes back to what it was
the child can do whatever the hell it
wants with them
registers zero to three are used for the
parameters and the return values
um our zero is the first one by the
calling convention and it also contains
the 32-bit word that you might return if
you return a 64-bit word
then you will also use r1
and you're under no responsibility to
preserve
the other parameters so the the trial
function can clobber any of these that
it wants to
and if the parent expects it to be the
same it's it's responsibility to save it
onto the call stack before branching to
the child
but you're going to come here for a
description
of the uh the number of registers
their names and stuff um you wanted to
know how you could get code and begin
working with it
so there are a couple of different ways
to
to get the firmware um the easiest of
course
is a firmware update um
brian when you're trying to mess with
something what what fraction of the time
do you get the firmware for free just by
looking at an update or executable
or the vendors i'd say yeah
i'd say uh you get lucky on that about
80 percent of the time
it's uh you know you can just
um sometimes i mean not handed off but
you know yeah get it out of like a
you know application download that goes
through the smartphone and you can sniff
on the wire or something right
yeah uh for bluetooth you'll have to do
chip extraction
for bluetooth devices in particular um
android has excellent support for
logging bluetooth to disk
which you can then replay in wireshark
in order to
capture the firmware update as it goes
up there
um another way of grabbing it
is through jtag which is a debugging
protocol that's very often
unlocked and if jtag is unlocked then
you can connect a debugger
and dump an image out there's also a rom
boot loader which can be either locked
or unlocked
if it's unlocked you just read it out
through the serial port
um but if if jtag or the wrong
bootloader are locked
there are still options so
for a specific example the stm32f0
family is rather popular
um it has a vulnerability in its
jtag implementation which i believe was
first documented
at using 2017.
the vulnerability is that when you
attach
jtag to the spm32f0
flash memory is disconnected from the
cpu core
and the memory bus the idea here is that
if you think that there is
a functionality problem with your device
you're free to connect a debugger
to check for that but you're not allowed
to read the code out of it that you
would need to copy the device
or to reverse engineer it
there's a minor problem here which is
that sram is still exposed
because it's not disconnected but the
major problem
that was presented used in exclude is
that
when you attach jtag
flash is disconnected one cycle too late
so your jk debugger can
uh dump out a single word per connection
and by repeatedly reconnecting and
resetting the device
the jtag debugger can dump out all the
firmware
the nrf51 is another popular
jtag there's another popular
embedded arm chip with radio support
this is the
one of the first bluetooth ships that
supported bluetooth low energy
and was nice to program
um there's similar there's a similar
situation here
in that jtag was supposed to be able to
connect to the chip
without being able to dump out all of
code when the device is locked
the vulnerability here is that you're
still allowed to single step the cpu
and you're still allowed to
um view its registers you can read them
and you can write them
um you're just not allowed to do the
extra memory yourself
so what they did was uh with chris brush
did
in 2015 was he found an instruction that
loads the um
the word in memory at the address that's
in register zero it takes that word and
it loads it into register one
um and after he finds that instruction
he can then loop through this
instruction while changing the value of
register zero
in order to dump all of the firmware out
the jtech port
even though the chip is locked
and once you have the firmware you can
unlock the chip
or replace it with a new chip right in
the firmware
and continue debugging with full
privileges
there are also bugs in uh master on boot
loaders
um i used to love writing exploits for
these
because when you find a vulnerability in
a mask rom
and you exploit it you generally have an
expert live
and ryan how long do they live
they they never go away these are the
best ones have you ever seen one patched
i think somebody passed one once by
ripping everything out of the field and
pushing out all new chips but
it's just not uh not something people
like to do
so the cost of patching this is that you
need to
begin manufacturing new chips of every
affected item
in the family which requires the mask
revision
so you're looking at about a minimum of
a quarter million dollars
per unique model number in the family
so in the case of stm32
they would need to do this separately
for the stm32f407
and 417 and 207 and 217
and so on so the these bugs live a very
very long time
they're the sort of thing where when you
um when you find one as a defender
there's not much that you can do about
it certainly can't upgrade anything in
the field
and if you have the decision to burn
your warehouse into the ground and
remanufacture the chips from scratch
over a security bug you generally choose
not to do it
when i'm hunting for a bootloader
vulnerability
this is one of my favorite tricks that
would never work on a pc
um on a pc you have something called a
guard page at uh
address zero and the purpose of the
guard page
is that if you ever have a null pointer
meaning that the pointer is zero
and you try to read from address zero
the guard page will trap
and inform the operating system and the
operating system will kill your process
and the reason for that is that very
often you forget to initialize something
or you try to allocate a buffer when
you're out of memory or any number of
things
and you're stuck
on embedded systems it works differently
um
this code here the the print data
function that i've thrown together that
just prints
uh the bytes at a location in
hexadecimal
um this will dump the beginning of your
firmware image if you call it
for thumb length and for address equals
zero
on many embedded arm chips because
quite a few of them will locate whatever
memory you booted from to address zero
meaning that when you dereference a null
pointer you get the beginning of your
code
so if you can ever find a place either
in the application
or in the bootloader where you can trick
it into sending you
uh data from the device's own memory at
address zero
you have a firmware
this brings us to the concept of um
what is in memory at which location
this is the memory map from
the pocket gtfo article that ryan and i
published
uh it was illustrated by angela martini
and you know the
the only advantage of doing this lecture
remotely is that you can read some of
the
uh the items on this list
the um is being
that memory is sort of arranged into 512
megabyte regions
and that you've got a full 32-bit
address space
so four gigabytes of memory that can
possibly be addressed
for a microcontroller with one megabyte
of flash
and 192 kilobytes of ram
here's the and travis maybe just
covered for people how if they don't
have a poc or gtfo article to reference
the memory map
they might find that in documentation
oh yes so this is always in either the
data sheet
or the programmer's guide which is
sometimes called a family guide
it will be unique to your chip or at
least to the chip's family
and it will um it will tell you
um which pointer goes to which location
if you're so unlucky that you do not
have documentation
for this or it's not in the data sheets
you'll find it in the linking scripts
and if you don't have the linking
scripts freely available from
the manufacturer you can very often find
them included with commercial c
compilots
and since you're not trying to do you're
not trying to use the compiler you're
just trying to read its header files
it's very often not restricted by the
compiler's license enforcement
when you look into the list you'll see
that
everything is sort of organized by the
most significant bits
of the of the address
in this table here we're only looking at
the most significant byte
if um if that byte is c0
we know that we're looking at mask from
this is the wrong boot loader that is
physically baked into the chip that
cannot be patched or changed
if the first part is before
zero we know that this is in the i o
region
and that the um the thing being pointed
to
is something like a counter or a timer
or a serial port that it interfaces with
the outside world from the cpu core
if the first pipe is twenty and
hexadecimal we know that it's
s gram and if it's 10 in hexadecimal we
know that it's tightly coupled round
which on this particular chip happens to
be slightly faster but is not executable
and the vast majority of the pointers
that you see when taking the firmware
apart will begin with zero eight which
means that they're in flash memory
which can't be freely written simply by
writing to an address
like the other memories can but it is
directly executable
and it's where the majority of our code
runs
and then on this chip the stm32f4 series
if the first byte is a zero that alias
to whichever memory we booted from which
is probably either the mask rom or flash
but the hardware does allow booting from
sram for development purposes
so let's take a look at some pointers um
20 again from our list above
20 is in f ram so
the first pointer is to
srm this is like a global variable
perhaps
the second and the third pointers those
are both
odd and they both begin with zero eight
zero eight tells me that they are in
um that they're in flash memory
but they're being odd the least
significant bit being off by one
tells me that these are either very
strange pointers
to a byte offset which exists for rather
rare
or far more likely they're odd because
their code
and their thumb two code because
remember this ship
cannot run the classic 32-bit wide arm
instruction set
it's unable to
have code and even addresses so every
function pointer that you find will be
odd
and then this last one uh four zero zero
two
three c zero zero
that's in the i o region which we know
because it begins with
uh 40 and hexadecimal and there are
header files
for this chip that define
all of the i o addresses this happens to
be the flash control register so
whatever function
contains this pointer
that function is interacting with
flash memory it might be writing it or
it might be
um locking the chip
we can then search for these numbers in
order to find all of the functions that
involve flash memory
or all of the functions that involve a
particular serial port
and by doing that we can then narrow
down
the code to the individual function that
we care about
um ryan i've been hugging the mic would
you care to talk about the interrupt
vector table
and what it means sure i can go through
that um
let's see actually travis why don't you
start and i'll jump in on the next one
that'll work so the interrupt vector
table begins
at the very beginning of an arm from our
image
when you get a firmware image you don't
get a exe
file or an elf file like you would in
windows or in linux
instead you very often get just a blob
of bytes
and you need to figure out where those
bytes need to be loaded
and you also need to figure out inside
of memory
where the basic functions are
this table begins with the initial
stack pointer which is a really cool
thing kind of unique to microcontrollers
because it means that
from the very instant the program begins
running
it has a functioning call stack
yeah so that's that's r13
yes and that means that your reset
vector which is the entry point for your
code
your reset vector can be written in c
and you don't need
any custom assembly language to write
the beginning of your
kernel on an arm
cortex m firmware image
so these are the beginning bytes
of a real firmware image for
um a cortex m3 chip
you see that address zero we have
um these four bytes in hexadecimal we
have 30 14
0 0 20. and
because this is a little ending in
architecture we read them backward
so the first 32-bit word in memory is 2
0 0 14 30.
the 2 0 is an sram and that's our stack
pointer
and the value after that reading the
next four bytes backward
if you follow along is zero eight zero
zero four one two one
well the zero eight the most significant
byte tells us
that it's in flash memory and q1
the least significant byte is odd which
tells us that it's thumb code
so when we decode these we get first
the initial fact pointer which tells us
which piece of ram
the firmware is using
and then we get a bunch of interrupt
handler addresses beginning with the
entry point of the program
and continuing on to other events like
receiving a byte
on a serial port or um
having the nmi tin or non-maskable
interrupt
uh attacks and
we can work on the component pieces of
the firmware
in order to um in order to confirm
that we have it loaded to the right
location
so the next step uh the one that you've
been waiting for is actually loading
this into ida pro
or binary ninja or guidra
or vadara 2 and doing something with it
when you go through this and the concept
go ahead trash
oh sorry sorry when you um
when you open the file in ida um it sees
this as a bunch of bikes and it doesn't
really know
the instruction set or the loading
location or any of those details
so you need to help it out a little bit
the first thing that you need to do is
change the processor type manually to
arm little engine
arm at some point did make big endian
machines
and even machines that can switch back
and forth between big engine and little
indian mode
but these days it'll be rather rare for
you to find the beginning firmware
so you choose little indian and then in
processor options
um you have all of these fancy uh
variants of the instruction set but arm
is pretty good about keeping them
backward compatible
so about the only thing that you need to
do for these images
is mark that the architecture does not
support
32-bit wide instructions
and then ida is going to ask you um
for the memory organization and if you
remember that memory map
that i showed you earlier this is where
you present the memory map to item
so we do need a ram section
or code that tries to read and write ram
won't properly decompile
and we also won't be able to track the
global variables and we definitely need
a rom
stacker but ida defaults both of these
to being at address zero
and uh the ram to not even being of any
size
so we correct it by two methods the
first
uh the easy one is the ram we know
from the data sheet where ram begins and
how large it is
here i begin ram at um
the address with a high bite of 20
because that's what i found in the
memory map of the data sheet and i set
the size to 128 kilobytes because that's
also
the value that i find in the data sheet
the rom
i load to a strange address it's
zero eight zero zero and then um c
thousand and the reason why i do that
is because in this particular device
there are two
kernels and the first sits at the very
beginning of flash memory
and acts as a sort of recovery
bootloader to start the second one
and the offset for the second one i had
to find
uh by reading that first bootloader's
code
so now that i know that it begins
just 48 kilobytes further in memory
than i then the documentation
says i can apply that in ida and have
everything loaded at the correct
location
and there's one more thing that you'll
need to do or
ida will give you total garbage for your
results
which is that um when ida loads
an arm image it's a little bit confused
about the instruction set
because um on the arm architecture you
have two different instruction sets and
you can freely jump between them
so you need to use alt g
and set the t value to be one
when you do this you then told it that
you want
a code 16 section instead of a code 32
section
and from that point on the disassembly
will be correct and then you can begin
exploring
and marking up your functions
at the very beginning it knows nothing
about it
so you see code 32 as your organization
everything is at the correct loading
address
and the bytes are correct but ida
doesn't know where
any functions begin so the first thing
that you do
is you type alt g and set t equals one
in the dialog
to change code 32 to code 16.
the next thing that you do is you use
the d key to mark
these data bytes as being
data words
so once we mark all of them up as 32-bit
words we find
the internal table and it's very large
it's more than a page in this
architecture
and each of these 32-bit addresses after
the first one
is a valid interrupt handler that the
cpu will jump to when the right event
happens
we can then use this for a sanity check
if we made a mistake at this point or up
to this point
if our alignment is off if our
configuration is wrong
there are tales that can let us know
that we're about to waste our time by
reverse engineering gobbledygook and let
us sort of
uh step back a minute and and take a
second look
the first thing to check is that some of
the
instructions are only two bytes wide
implying that we're properly in thumb
mode
the other thing to check is that any
function which is apparent
meaning that it calls another function
should begin by pushing
the at least the link register and maybe
some other registers
and also at the end of that function it
should pop those
back um off of the stack
and into the registers that came from
before returning
we should also check that every target
of a branch and link instruction which
is how function calls work
that every function call is to a
reasonable address
meaning that when you look at the
address that it's targeting
you find the entry point of another
valid function
this one isn't as
[Music]
as useful as you would expect it to be
because the branch and link
instruction is relative in thumb to
meaning that if i've loaded my image to
the wrong address
function calls will still work and we'll
still
jump to the correct address because
they inherit the um the same mistake as
our loading
and then at the end of the function
after
the after the program counter
is restored and the function goes back
to its parent
we will either find another function or
some has something called a constant
pool
and the constant pool is used instead of
where x86 would use immediate values so
in x86
you can have an instruction that
contains a 32-bit word inside of it
in thumb 2 the longest instruction is
only 32 bits so there's no room for that
constant to fit so instead you point it
you point relatively to the end of your
function
where you have a list of all the 32-bit
values you might want to load
and it can be fetched from there
this is an example of a thumb 2
instruction it's
a short one i use this one during a
sanity check
the purpose of this function is just to
make sure that everything is loaded
right
we see that at the very beginning it
pushes
register 4 and the link register to the
call stack
at the very end it pops register 4 and
the program counter off of it
this is a neat way to cheaply return
because in
popping the value from the what was the
link register at the time
the function entered back into the
program counter
it can skip restoring that we also see
a bl instruction in the middle which
calls another
function within the program jumping
there
i find a valid function which tells me
that this is correctly loaded
when you have your image and you begin
to understand it
you're generally trying to do it for um
for some reason
one reason might be to change the
firmware on the physical device
but another useful thing that you might
want to do is
extract a library from the physical
device
so that you can run it on your desktop
this is especially true
if the library is proprietary or if you
can't um
you can't purchase the copy so
this radio the titera md380 has a
proprietary audio codec
called ambi plus two
and the um
if you want md plus two there's an open
source decoder
but there is nothing open source that
will encode the audio
instead you're supposed to purchase a
dongle that plugs into the serial port
it's supposed to send
your audio samples out the serial port
and then get back the compressed packets
so what you can do instead which is i
explained
in uh hypocrisy tfo 13 5
is you can take the firmware image that
you now
understand because you reverse
engineered pieces of it
and you can re-link it to be
a linux arm executable
you can then compile your own speed code
to run against that library
and the end result is that you have um
a unix command line tool that is able to
call the proprietary library functions
of the physical radio and because it has
the correct code and it has the correct
ram
everything is in the correct position
and everything still works
these are the uh
gcc 9 commands to actually perform
the linking the um
the gist of it is that i'm telling it to
load the
firmware image where the firmware would
go
at zero eight zero
c000 so this leaves experiment.img
as our firmware where the firmware
should go
and then what this does is this loads
ram.bin
into memory where the ram should go
and i also give it um section names
so that my linker can provide pointers
for this back
to my main function
and when i link all of this together
i can then um
i can then call into these functions so
the first thing that i do is i make
a function pointer to the same firmware
address
as i found a function that does nothing
but return
and what this piece if it does is it it
makes that
function pointer and then it calls it
and if it doesn't crash
that means that it has called into the
firmware and successfully returned
if it crashes it might be because the
page is not executable
or it might be because of another
mistake along the way
after i have a very short function
working
i can then take a much more complicated
function
uh mba decode wave this
is the function that takes a compressed
amde audio packet as the radio would
receive over the air
and it decodes it into a wave buffer
that will be played
out the sound card of the radio and this
is how you receive digital audio
and hear it as a voice that you
understand
now um you can see from my comments that
i don't really understand
what all of the parameters of this
function do
um i know that a5 and a4 are always zero
so i just make them zero
um the buffer
is uh i think a temporary buffer and i
use the one that was already loaded into
ram on the device
because there might be um tables that
are required
and then also a7 is always the same
address
inside of sram at
2001 1224
i just repeat that same address
from what i see in the disassembled
firmware
i don't actually know what it means or
what's located there and i don't have to
because as far as that function is
concerned everything that it expects in
flash memory is at the correct address
and everything that it expects in ram is
at the correct address
so if i call it with the same parameters
it performs the same functions
this audio codec happens to have a copy
protection mechanism
which i didn't notice when i first
emulated it
because in my emulation the copy
protection check had already
passed so by running the firmware image
that i've dumped out of the real radio
and the frame that i've dumped out of
the real radio it's almost
like i've paused the running program
inside of the physical hardware and then
migrated it
into a unix process and continue time
off from there
[Music]
part of the weirdness of this function
is that uh
in in amd you have two time slots so you
have to call the decoder twice
and only once it will work so i just
double that up
but the end result is that i have an arm
linux executable
which runs perfectly fine under qmo
so it doesn't matter that my desktop is
an intel xeon or whatever
um which is then able to call back into
the firmware
if i were doing this for a commercial
project instead of a hobby project
or if i were more diligent in the
quality control for my how
for my hobby projects i could use this
to write
unit tests and integration tests to know
that my understanding
of the meaning of the firmware and the
locations of the functions were correct
there are some other nifty tricks that
you should know um
when you're reverse engineering desktop
software
um we've worked our way to a point in
the world where
most new software
uses
utf-8
and there are some exceptions like if
you're looking at very old software you
might find
um a national standard
or if you're looking at windows software
you might find
unicode 16 instead of etf8
in firmware for arm
it's surprising what you'll very often
find um
the chinese standard called gb2312
so sometimes when you're looking through
a firmware image for a device
that has a free display in chinese
but not in english um
and you run springs on it you look for
unicode strings and you find none of it
you will still find gd231 two strings
if you try that and you can then run
them through google translate
and use those strings to understand the
meaning of the
code involved
i have a github project that that dumps
these strings because the standard tools
don't seem to
like that format magic constants are
also useful
in the case of reverse engineering the
radio firmware
there was um support in the protocol
for um like an emergency
shouting mode where every radio that
hears the message will decode it
you use this if you need to address
everybody on the network
even though some of them might not be
configured to receive you
by searching for the address
that you send that audio to i was able
to find the functions
that control whether the radio plays
incoming audio or not
um which allowed me to make promiscuous
mode to decode
all all incoming audio you can also
search for masks
in this particular protocol addresses
are three bytes long instead of four
or eight or 16 or whatever else you
would want so by searching
for zero zero ffff
i could find all of the masking
operations that were trying to drop
off the extra byte that was not a part
of the address
and that allowed me to locate large
parts of the networking style
you can also hunt for reference code so
um in my case i was attempting to
reverse engineer
a device which locked its own firmware
and i needed to find the function
that locked the firmware in order to
disable it
to do that i i looked at the
manufacturer's reference design
and they provided this example function
which was used exactly with no
modification
by the radio vendor it was um statically
linked into the firmware image
so i could look at what assembly code
was generated by compiling this
and then i could search for everything
similar and by clicking i was able to
find the correct function in very little
time
you can also automate a lot of the
the dredge work of
sorting through the image and
identifying things
so one very useful thing to do is to
realize that most functions are targets
of a branch only construction
and um the only exceptions to that
in a normal application will be um
functions that are called by pointer
where you will find
a copy of the function pointer either in
flash or sram
and interrupt handlers which are in the
internet handler table
so if you run through memory
and you find every branch in link
instruction
and then look at its target and then you
instruct your disassembly tool
through an item python script or
the scripting for whatever other tool
you're using
you can automatically identify all of
those functions and then
um then begin working with the entry
points all known
or even instruct i to decompile the
entire image and then search through it
as c code without having to look at the
assembly
and when
the vendor releases a firmware update
and you would like to stay up to date
with that firmware
but you've written your patches against
an older firmer image
um you need some way to automatically
port
because if you do all of this by hand
then you forget why you did certain
things or why
um you patched out certain functions and
it becomes difficult to maintain
instead it would be nice if all of your
patching were performed
in c in the style of replacing a
function of a particular name
and the names you could apply to one
version of the firmware and
automatically move
to future versions so
if you're trying to do this between
let's say adobe pdf reader on spark
and modern mac os
um that becomes a hard problem because
you have
different compilers different
instruction sets different major
versions
um and they're very smart people who
work on those problems and get results
in them
in my case i'm interested in getting an
answer immediately
with a couple pages of c code so
the way that i do this is that i realize
that um
embedded developers usually use the same
version of the compiler
they don't update their compiler
frequently
like um like a desktop linux user might
and when you're using the same compiler
to compile different
versions of the same firmware most of
the functions don't change at all
and those that do change um
those that do change are usually for
the small feature that gets fixed
they're not necessarily the same
function that you might want to
hook
so you're usually looking at the exact
same assembly code linked to a new
address
and when it's linked to a new address
the
targets of the bl instructions
which means branch and link which is the
thumb version of a function call those
change but nothing else changes
so we can do this trick where um
you can compare how similar two
functions are
by stepping through every 16-bit word
in the function with a being the word in
the first function and b
being the word in the second function
and if a equals b
then great they're identical and you can
move on if they don't equal
each other but they both have a most
significant nibble
of f meaning both of them have their
most significant four bits set
then that that 16-bit word
is part of a branch and link instruction
and it doesn't
matter that it changed because it's
expected to during location
so this lets you come up with a very
very short c function
that will race through large firmware
images
and directly compare their functions in
order to identify which ones are
equivalent
so that you can import your symbol names
if you'd like an example of this there's
a
code in the symbols directory of the
md380 tools project
um we've gone over a lot in this lecture
i
hope that you picked up some nifty
tricks that you'll use in your own
projects
i do not expect you to remember every
detail
and i certainly wouldn't if i watched it
myself
but it's the nifty tricks that save you
when you're blocked
or that allow you to um
to hack something that you might
otherwise get stuck on
that are the valuable things that i look
for in these lectures
if anyone wants to have reference
material for this polka gtfo
11 11 6 has the
full article that some of this content
came from so you can also look at that
if you want reference
howdy hey so i'm uh
sent out a query for questions uh one
question we got
was um what modern devices have the
cortex
m in it and i was just doing some
noodling
uh while while you all were talking and
i found that ifixit
is a pretty good place to find what
chips are and what things since they do
tear downs and they
verbally you know they write out what
chips they find and identify the chips
oh yeah their tear downs are great they
also show you like
um which tiny ribbon cable you're most
likely to screw up when you
open the device yeah yeah this thing
will tear
if you if you pull that screen off yep
um yeah so i found out like uh some of
those hoverboards use them the apple tv
uses them ipod touch sixth generation
uh the pebble watches smart watches
use them so in the apple tv this won't
be the main cpu this will be
off on the side so it's in the
they they use it both in the main unit
and inside the remote
controller does it have a chip name it's
for the rf4ce travis in that one
i believe
yeah so a lot of these that that's a
great point engine right a lot of these
will be in
uh you'll often find these families in
smart remotes so
uh i don't know specifically if it's the
m3 and them but you know think of any
remote that you're pushing your
your uh yeah i'm pretty sure they're
actually empty-based
that you push and do voice to tell your
tv what you want to do for example
whether that's a tv an apple product or
a third party
um typically these are integrated into
some of those radio chipsets
or based on this architecture and if you
have uh
if you have like a small consumer device
with an lcd screen
but that clearly isn't as powerful as
android
um it's quite likely one of the
higher-end gore-tex-iron chips
cool yeah yeah it's what it looks like
with a few devices here
the oculus rift multiple versions of the
oculus rift also use it
and the uh second generation nest
so yeah that was that was pretty cool i
was trying to think like how would i
even find that because
you know manufacturers usually don't
publicize
that you know what chips are using for
what things
and i realized i fix it uh that's what
they specialize in
so the manufacturer won't publicize it
but
very often you can find out which chips
they use from their fcc filing
yeah yeah we see a lot of leaks come
from that
before devices come out sometimes
well very cool um
yes so i'm i'm not seeing any questions
so thank you thank you both very much
for the talk and
um yeah there's uh there's definitely
some
discussion going on on the on the
discord
which has been fun to have