finally working
yeah this is his last year yeah I'll
so get
okay about so nice
yeah I'm yeshiva does both
peco one-issue yeah this is over
everything yeah as a postdoc overheat
in my group me fingers the problem
I'm getting really good passers yeah one
that
so us are affecting its heavy heart yeah
phone Wednesday I have that was lost all
to tell you why I think it's gonna be
very the
imagine that you have the luxury up
starting from zero not having to be
compatible with OSA
how'd you do it right now bus very
clever
and 12 see someone to work with me on
the strong
and iPhone hacer sixties for those of
you who are
possibly I'm using you get that call
peco and since then
I have managed to exact same I
combat be funded from day that European
users basketball so that you have some
can somehow be
that baby but yet my peers and a half
back to you
action mine it for me to be able to pay
someone fact that you wanted me to
figure that out your life or the said
Joe at my job now is to ensure the best
possible people
for building a team that you make yes
and he's not just going to be 15 I'll
security software experts give
this out yeah yesterday
fashion design Experimental Psychology
30 human beings
as opposed to just and didn't love you
yes
keeping get hardware yeah
for also my love yes the students there
are no that
so it worked what you're going to do
Easter truth I for I've got some more
that good
get it 30 people and see how do people
react because
sangria human beings are different
platforms for us yeah how they work
is not just thinking about what happens
to us I your
you're still earth even though you are
no way from just yeah
does that work we think would be a great
idea doesn't actually work
we've reviewed we that he's a and we
you know humidity to just pay attention
to a that as working
good yeah he got that my
could be good for they've yeah hopefully
you know that would have something that
you we'd be happy at the youth and
when I gave to you last year my vision
about peco
is not really look I expected with the
red yet is just a starting point then I
hello I would be proved wrong said the
this is all rushed
let in learning what was right you can
be the most def so
I would for bites works for real people
as
that sunny Arora thaw is that
at Jul I before we go your Fisher
more is over year yeah that other than
your behavior
is yeah the figure out what they gave
you last year
this first both fishing 40 the form that
I would
nasa you know is for security software
processes occur before
this yes yeah do not make a dent in the
universe
might improve the lives of anyone who
have to remember
with office today reaching at billions
plus
you yeah want to talk in person were
gamers yeah possibility for your own
work you can be
orthopedic this yeah yeah
acts tell me what you think the greatest
challenges
offer go and how you dress in
you how to address the issues on this
team and
for the next month thank you very much
that's my
tremors slather commercial going on
as well because II for my sins I had a
good share
be set workshop are reserved for insider
threat
since a substantial proportion of people
here fracking the password finder their
company
yeah I decided
maybe something that you have an
expertise and yes I sincerely
share and I we r vigorous it before but
very insecure
my buddy yeah Pat because i've seen
but then you're looking for academic
paper smoke for security presentations
well we will listen to anything is also
according to the shore
short babe resume people sesno's about
we haven't been
got a call from colesville and birthday
and
any suggestions for interesting stuff
yes
but I was wondering about you
Michael position because it does so
mister you like
from you for the bolsa
you but it's portable stoves limb or or
will you accept full
a oxygen I
yeah I know I'm
if is the result of these Google with a
what you want to get all the money is it
isn't a
came around publication and theoretical
understanding you need to be a little
slow cooker group I'll see you
if you love here I important for among
others
does not have a a I'd also its
to to apply or we got me it was the old
what was up at nightline is to produce
some that at me I go back
I started off by saying that I'm think
it would be very good
to get rid of toxins maybe even if we
believe ego that
I have in mind or something even better
that would saying goes
still very difficult for these things
even when it exists to display sponsors
and I'll I'm a save your life at 185
likes this now having said that I
believe that bosses are tired
both for me to be people that first year
you want to save money
%uh us share the speed and that's
important
as the number of things with which we
have direct deposit
grows and grows and grows and grows will
have to say but that just doesn't work
no matter how much we have invested
five-year deal subsequently more
maybe what you know may want to be in
five years maybe drive years time
at someone who their hands on their next
so I will start now
thinking about work could be something
it would be great
if we you were a bit just like the whole
slavery which we got right now I think
we got okay
I don't wanna I don't have something
that is demonstrably working
except for the computer on which is
being one and so
I want yes for the rear working through
that it could be a guy who preferred
understand yes our C if you wanted but
with every other
from you can cite the stuff we have
tried to give me everything does were
so I do want people who are yet have a
good building things
doing stuff furriers I'm I have you want
to hurt both of us
I'm raise the money you know it's always
easier to get
more money you've got the meeting today
so we that
behind me I get going your shake the
habit other
and is to save you from this guy to make
it used to be with me or something that
at you this is look I already have
funding for but I hope to expand his
group to something more
I son las vegas Vic Country externally
without being my employees
that's also something that and course
would be interested in
to 77 up the army easy by me
for my intellectual property ok another
about anything over Ethernet
so is going to be quite easier work with
me on that
as the Sun statements yeah Elijah
was born two stand
I'll I am always here undereducated
here got no exception is over there are
some that are most often
yeah
performer it was like that so nice so I
was kinda wondering because it also is a
very specific position
yeah it was ok but what what the is
there for the rest of us come we've got
a few
do you want those who hustle me yeah
experience pack up and I'll buy yes i
hack
yes that yes I for one in the world
yeah do these you everything right
and have a surprising number of reasons
I know that you have issues and gets
upset about something then
halfway through you know one or two
years in says actually the thing I don't
like to do
is some BS and I want to leave them
isn't
freedom to pursue the thing that they
think they're gonna
something that knows I'm gonna have to
figure something at the end is a need to
be able to
to some house in here there reason air
users direction on the work on that
little bit more this time
focus he said things get Cs for those of
us were injured austere
alright dude I like 22nd summary of what
because yes alright okay at
executive summary upbeat of rosters
either
right air users were gone
and said pass rushers a hardware device
it also took a few almost nothing as
long as you show us what about sports
server ratso yeah down to seven seconds
second myself as a whole the device that
you have constructed from
at moments on paper of and that will
also take a cute
I against anything as long as a surprise
why the support
Press so is something something else
Somfy are something you have this is
going to be something you have
effect on me and Greg Hastings it for a
fight that
on with my phone last year an Android
phone I don't want it to be part of the
Android phone this is also mentioned
today
and because the your Android phone runs
a number of other things
I know what these other things to be
near all my credentials
so I want to dedicate devices yeah with
talk about his cousin okay
here though okay
no yeah talking about two hours talks
about sourcing
dog Friday right
three