so let's give it up for me hello thanks
everybody I'm gonna stumble over here
again with that said before I begin and
I want to read a statement that I've
prepared so with that said I should be
in LA today speaking at another InfoSec
comments instead I took today off flew
all the way out here to st. Louis and
I'm speaking at an impost that
conference I did submit this talk on
behalf of myself independent of my
employer who happens to be here today as
a sponsor so I apologize to my employers
in advance let's see so with that said
the statements today are on my own
behalf
not on my employer
are we getting feedback on that mic all
right and we turn this one off so first
lesson of today's talk is about
microphone management all right
can y'all hear me now no feedback still
a little bit of feedback all right so
with that said you guys see the
disclaimer here there is a little bit of
bad language
it's nothing graphic or anything all
right so also it won't hurt my feelings
if you walk out this wouldn't be the
first and won't be the last so with that
said let's see
I would like to shake this thang show-me
con CFP Review Board for approving this
talk and I also apologize for what you
all are about to hear also if you're
still listening to this then thank you
for coming and specifically coming to
this talk I'm not gonna be discussing
anything new or groundbreaking this is
just old stuff this is stuff that you
see in your environments to this day so
my goal here for today is really to fill
the your attention for the allotted time
to make you laugh a couple of times and
maybe you'll learn a thing or two that's
really the goal here today so with that
said I've got about a 40 45 minute talk
and I've got 63 slides and the slides
about are it's about a one gig
PowerPoint presentation so with that
we'll get started
Oh last thing today happens to be my
birthday so yeah so I will be at the bar
at the end of tonight if anybody wants
to buy me a drink alright so let's get
started this is talk is confessions of
really bad systems administrators we're
gonna kind of learn from the mistakes of
me and many of my peers so I was
mentioning this earlier I'm basically
committing like career hari-kari on
stage so this either is going to be very
successful or I don't know the real
title of today's talk is really
confessions of a shitty sis admins
there's a theme here and hopefully
you'll kind of see where we're going
here so a little bit about myself I work
for
cyber-ark software I have the coolest
job in the entire company I'm not a
sales guy I'm not a tech guy I simply
help people so I'm helping partners I'm
helping existing customers guys internal
into our team
I've run what's called our office of
programs I really have no clue what it
is but my job is generally I just help
people for a living I have a degree from
the University of Texas in Arlington
Texas home of the Mavericks if you're
not familiar with UTA we have an
undefeated football team since 1976
pretty awesome right you know about 1976
the nation's Bicentennial that also
happen to be the same year we got rid of
our football program all right I also
have a bunch of IT security
certifications on big fan of
certification I think it's a good way to
get your foot in the door in the
industry I also run the subreddit for
the CISSP subreddit so if you have
questions about getting an info SEC this
I'm always around to help and answer
your questions I am a really active
member of the InfoSec community in
Dallas Texas so Dallas Fort Worth if
you're not familiar has a kick-ass
community we between like Dallas hackers
association in TX ESG o day all day
please school DC - one for Issa is e
squared I mean the list literally goes
on and on and I'm really happy to say
I'm part of this really active and
vibrant community I personally am on
known as in the community as the travel
hacker now I'm not like chris Roberts
hacking your plans out of the sky or
anything what we've me and my wife do is
though we get really really cheap
airfare and travel all over the world
for like a shoestring budget let's see I
went to Australia for 11 days I think we
spent $3,500 for that total we did a
Easter Island for again nothing nine
days for cost like 1,100 and just
recently like literally like 48 hours
ago I just got back from Liberia Costa
Rica we spent five days there and
including food airfare lodging at this
resort I think we pay
700 bucks for the four of us so if you
want to learn more about travel hacking
I'll be more than happy to talk to you
about that later but more than anything
beyond all that I was a former shitty
sysadmin all right so before I even buy
was a shitty sysadmin I was just shitty
helpdesk agent and this really where I
learned a lot of the mistakes and the
Phil pause that I've made in my career
and hopefully you've seen these in the
past and hopefully won't commit these
again so this talk is unlike a lot of
the ones you've seen previously these
are kind of little visual cues that will
help me spur my memory and then tell you
some more stories okay so let's start
talking about helpdesk and the where we
started making our mistakes and that's
in the password I remember this very
clearly it was November 2004 George Bush
had just defeated John Kerry in the
election and the first password that we
were supposed to give out to Orion users
when we reset their password was close
now remember this is the fall of 2004 so
what would our password potentially be
fall 2004 you see the problem is is that
seasons change roughly around the same
time and it is your 90-day password
policy so I guarantee and that
organization where I was working there
still passwords out that are probably
like summer 2019 so again if you're an
attacker trying to spray an organization
using these default passwords was the
first thing I made as far as mistakes
now you've probably seen something
similar this in your social media you
know find out your Star Wars Sith name
or whatever by entering this celery of
information sharing it with your peers
you don't realize you're sharing all
this secret password reset information
potentially so just be aware of your
online presence along that same lines if
you know ed SCOTUS he literally wrote
the book on pentesting he has a great
story about disclosing sort of password
information he did it was talking about
a pen test where they just owned the
hell out of this superintendent of a
school district the way they positioned
it was they wrote an
interview as a schoolchild interviewing
the superintendent as if they were
writing a report so some of the
questions were what were your parents
names what was your first pet name
things like that and this guy totally
just spilled the beans so be careful of
what you're exposing to the public in
whatever you're doing
this is a kind of on the same lines of
password questions these these aren't
really security issues but I had to
share it with you where I worked at a
long time ago
we allowed our end users to create their
own secret questions and some of them
were just awesome so here's just one of
them this one guy was really cute and he
decided to play that he was hard of
hearing so we had to make the person on
the other end to repeat the question
over and over again starting really
quiet until the point where basically
their addition yelling the question so
what was a good question that would just
really make a datacenter just die
laughing well this was what it was
who's your daddy so the person was like
what I'm sorry I don't hear and so the
person the helpdesk person was basically
screaming because your daddy before the
end of the day and the answer was me now
this is another one this guy wasn't just
real creep but I swear this is this
really is the his question the question
that he came up was what are you wearing
right now and yeah but it gets even
better and I swear I by the way if you
haven't figured this out I'd love stupid
just an animated ug animated gifs and
memes okay so that's basically what this
whole presentation is so I found a Jeff
and it was the best one because it
literally was his answer all right so
the answer the question is is weren't
you wearing right now that is totally
inappropriate so that was actually as an
answer so anyway but the point here is
is that you need to be careful of the
questions that you're disclosing if
they're easily being able to disclose
probably not good security questions all
right so I'm gonna move forward to
actual real confessions and things where
I see security being prevalent here the
first is the concept of TLS three-letter
acronyms
if y'all familiar with that right it's
we're in security we it's all about TAS
the first one I want to introduce is the
topic of an SLA does anybody know what
an SLA is service level agreement right
this is the metric in which contracts
are defined if you don't meet your
la then you haven't done your job right
well when I was in helpdesk
we were measured by another TLA this
one's called an f CR anybody know what f
CR is first call resolution that's
exactly right
as a support desk person just picking up
the phone I was expected to resolve
every call that I came across to a
certain threshold what percentage do you
think average run-of-the-mill support
desk person should maintain 25 good good
number
anybody else 40 you know when when I was
doing this RFC our ratio was 90% we had
to close 90 percent of our calls the
first time they call so think about this
from a social engineering perspective if
I don't get the answer I want from the
person on the end of the phone I had the
longer I keep them on the line the less
their Ser rate drops so you really the
person supporting you really wants to
get the call done as quickly as possible
so if it doesn't work you just call back
and the chances are getting what you
want as a social engineer it's pretty
good so again knowing that the end user
this the support agent has to maintain
this like high threshold of call
frequency presents some security risk in
lieu of operations all right so this is
really where I started losing my taste
for Humanity and progressed up the ranks
of a helpdesk I went from helpdesk 1 to
2 to team lead and ultimately I became a
sysadmin this is really where I think we
learned a lot of our security mistakes I
became that the master to prod really
who controlled the keys to the kingdom
right and this is where I was introduced
to the three envelopes that have saved
my career time and time again I'm gonna
teach you this strategy over the course
of today's talk and hopefully this will
save your careers as well all right what
you see in a lot of IT organizations is
there's lots of players in them in the
in the organization and we all have a
common view of systems administrators
yeah we're not too highly looked upon
except for maybe ourselves right you'll
see that you know that we're not highly
looked upon because we have certain
things that we value above all others
and if you're not familiar with xkcd
these guys make amazing comics and
they're so true to life in this one
right here we're talking about a
sysadmin what do they give it what do
they care about its uptime right it's
all about uptime when it comes to
systems administrators now we're all
security professionals here I hope you
all are familiar with it the CIA triad
come on let's let's all say it together
it's confidentiality integrity
availability right when it comes to
systems administration not security they
operate on a whole different triad all
right
y'all familiar with the AAA triad nobody
all about availability availability
availability availability that's what
they're concerned about and so my point
here is is as systems administrators
people think of us as you know we know
all the answers we're the technical
folks but in all honesty we're really
just treading water we're trying to keep
our head above the ground and just keep
the systems running however the hell we
do it right so when you saw my intro
slide you saw my my hacker handle it's a
Rainmaker and I'm not really that fond
of it but I really believe that the best
hacker handles are given not chosen and
that one was actually bestowed upon me
most people think the Rainmaker that's
like money money dollar dollar whatever
no it's more the traditional term the
the Native American rain dance to save
the day and the my VP at the time gave
me the term and a Rainmaker and I never
went away
basically we to date I did a datacenter
move and our whole network did not come
over like it was supposed to production
now it is across the board and somehow I
got it up and working
thus I got the term Rainmaker I have no
idea what the hell I did to get it up
it's running online but hey but that's
why all the names stuck so one of the
lessons learned today is when you're
making changes on a production
environment don't do multiple ones at
the same time because you can't
attribute one to actually correcting the
issue make changes very scientifically
ok all right so let's get started and
start talking about some of the security
mistakes that we made
that I've seen and have done in the past
if you look at my LinkedIn you can
probably see a couple of the companies
and we fixed these problems since then
but for example I used to work for a
very large chain of restaurants and we
had to go our grand opening we were
doing the whole ribbon cutting for the
Chamber of Commerce and the problem was
is there was only one wireless network
that riderless network was reserved for
the point-of-sale for our servers and
for our corporate IT network
unfortunately this the owner of the
company one-a-day public facing Wi-Fi
for our customers so when you only have
budget for one what do you do
you shouldn't expose it to the end-users
right that's exactly what we did so I
hate to say that but there's situations
where we cut corners for the sake of
operations we had to give it a open to
the users thank god another buddy
breached it before we actually corrected
the problem but again it's cutting
corners and that's really what's the the
crux of the problem here which leads me
to kind of some other things we were
gonna talk about circumventing of
controls all right you see that just
because you have a control in place
doesn't mean people are actually using
it and this is really prevalent when we
start talking about systems
administrators because we're the ones
installing those sorts of things we know
exactly how to circumvent them and so
again these are some of the mistakes
that I've seen done and done some of
these myself I mentioned earlier
November of 2004 this was also the same
time that World of Warcraft they you
know the the vanilla version went live
that was that was the big one right it
is anybody gonna play the new vanilla
version that's coming out or has it
already come out August okay
well I'm totally gonna be into that so
look me up later but the problem is is
back in 2004 I was working the night
shift and well I needed to do my molding
for more than the multicore 40 man raids
so what do you do when you're working
the night shift you bring your laptop
into work yeah that's the sort of the
circumventing of controls either that
were talking about what we've seen in
or common terms now we've done you know
Hardware filtering is is rather than
bringing hardware and data into
organizations we're seeing users take
data out quite often our security
controls are so harsh that it's
preventing our end users to do their job
and so they're taking their data and
they're maybe chained only get out
through Skype or slacks so people can
they can access their files and their
personal devices circumvent any sort of
caz B's and things like that so just be
aware that you know maybe these controls
are maybe too powerful and that's
introducing even more risk this one here
this one was a fun one company decided
to get wise and install content
monitoring so you know seeing what our
employees are doing they also allowed
outbound SSH so a simple sysadmin who
doesn't want the company to know what
they're doing can create and outbound
socks proxy to their AWS instance or
raspberry pi at home and completely
circumvent the filtering from your
company these are the sort of things
that your sis admissions are doing
because we're giving them admin access
to do you know whatever on their own
personal on their their assets on their
computer so again probably the people
that are installing these controls are
also the same ones that are
circumventing them another one this one
was pretty funny I hate my keys I am the
most forgetful person I tell people that
I have the short-term memory of a
goldfish and it's probably true I forget
my keys with my key fob all the time and
so what we would end up doing is because
of network segmentation we would allow
for multi-factor to access our PCI
environment at the time rather than
having to use my key fob to give it and
I happen to also be the VMware admin so
we just jump on vCenter get console
access completely circumventing the MFA
those are some of the controls that we
got to talk about and that's what we
have to do is watch and monitor our
systems admins because they're gints are
committing the controls we put in
another one here is we're lazy
that's how why we got into technology so
all machines can do the work for us many
a time have I set a job off and walked
away with the computer unlocked that
that happens more than
then I would like to admit in the past
so what we ended up doing was we created
a distribution list called donut and I
love this and this is such a simple
thing because it game if I as the
process if you happen to find a machine
that's unlocked and you're able to send
an email from that user to this
distribution list they're obligated to
bring Donuts in the next day yes if
you've ever wanted to see a grown man
clear three cubes in like rapid
succession to get to his unlocked
computer that's how to do it so what the
also here you can see from our lazy
sysadmin is you know the machines
unlocked this is something that again I
now that I'm I've learned and you know
recovered from my mistakes I used to let
vendors come into my network
unencumbered we might monitor them for a
little bit you know set up a go to my PC
session so they could get into the
systems but was the sysadmin actually
watching him now it's probably having a
smoke break or talking to Sally in
accounting the point being is is I
wasn't watching our vendors and our
third parties accessing our systems and
just exposing our organization to who
knows what same thing is applicable with
us well they target their breach came
from an external vendor so be exposing
our vendors to our network unsecured Lea
is not entirely the best also this one
you see that the forest and the tree
here right this kind of teaches me our
Tala tells me about responding to alerts
one of my jobs previously was a tripwire
responder and responding to the alerts
that came in and there were just so many
so what did we do because we had just so
many alerts we just ignored the hallo
that the problem is you can't see the
forest through the trees we were
tripping over ourselves so pay attention
to the alerts tune them down because
otherwise you're just getting a bunch of
crap and there's no value in it so - and
you're tuned your logs and make sure
let's move forward I think this video
will play I don't know if the audio will
but you can probably get the gist of
this anybody watch Saturday Night Live
anybody know who this is Nick burns your
company's computer guy so in the process
of being assist admin not only was i
jegg a gigantic asshole to my customers
like Nick
you'll notice that Knicks logging on to
the machine on behalf of the user
remember mmm yeah what he's doing is and
the circumstance is you know putting in
his own password potentially and so now
that I've learned about this what he
should have done is after you know
messing with Jennifer's computer here
rebooting making sure that you know
Nick's MIT credentials aren't stored in
memory so the point here is is be nice
to end-users and if you're going to log
onto a machine make sure that again
you're the ntlm to memory or I'm sorry
ntlm V to hash is stored in memory so
hypothetically saying Jennifer's machine
got like a keylogger or a ram scraper if
I go over her machine login to a machine
well now my creds are in her memory
exposing it so be aware of that all
right moving forward passwords you see
this is a password recycling here and
then an island of trash in the
background because that's what we're
doing here when we recycle passwords
it's trash there's a couple stories
around this one let's start here I have
an organization that I consult with and
they use the same password across
multiple different platforms what does
that mean exactly well it's an ad
account it's a very very highly
privileged account but it's running an
application running several service
accounts it's also running hard coded in
several different automated scripts it's
also running in their Linux environment
as well facilitating some ad bridging in
some processes the point being is is
this one a privileged account is bound
to like six different applications and
processes so let's say we Institute a
password policy where that password gets
rotated you know what happens nothing
there gets an exemption in your audit
policy and that password has never
changed what really needs to happen is
we need to make our credential
single-use making sure that they're
located and used for a single purpose
and a single purpose alone another story
I want to tell here - anybody know what
this movie says kangaroo jack it's a
terrible movie but this guy he was the
sysadmin that ran our UNIX team and this
was his icon on our I am client so this
reminds me of what he did
so compliance mandates in certain
organizations require you to rotate your
passwords and so this guy got smart he
got really smart he decided to send a
batch job that changed the password
across the enterprise so man main
maintaining the compliance but what he
didn't tell they come auditor was he
just ran that exact same batch job again
and reset the password right back to the
original so the says the password change
right on the logs auditors happy right
but did the password actually change now
did security change oh the point being
is quit reusing your passwords it's
really really a bad thing which leads me
to a really important point about
compliance compliance is a low watermark
when it comes to security it is the
minimum viable product across the board
however this is also probably the
biggest carrot on a stick for
organizations if you haven't followed
hermit hacker this is a personal friend
of mine and a really good guy and he
told me that using compliance as that
carrot on a stick
as far as motivating businesses to spend
money on technical and computer security
controls is how to go about doing it so
tying compliance to your your security
controls goes a very very long way so
I've shared with you a couple of the
mistakes that I have made I've
definitely made a few I'm gonna share
with you some mistakes that other people
have made okay we'll start outside of
the worlds of systems administration see
if you can pick up on this one anybody
know this this one all right let's let's
watch Kanye over here you don't need
audio for this one all right so take a
look at what he's doing he's showing
President Trump the new explain one I
believe oh you already saw it all right
hold on so he's showing the president
right here he he calls it a gift I'm
still stuck on Jeff it's Jeff for me I
show of hands is it Jeff gif oh did you
suck now but take a look zero zero zero
zero is his password and so that really
kind of shows me about default passwords
yes alright so this is a real confession
I actually had a system that I
maintained and I was the junior admin
and I was told to change the password
and my senior admin said no we can't
change the password we have to keep it
at the default I was like why it's like
so the vendor can get in when they need
to okay what the hell are you talking
about like much like dr. Phil here it's
just like one of those brain farts so
when it comes to passwords I need to
make a very good clear point guilfoyle
says it better than me if you're not
familiar with Silicon Valley I highly
highly recommend this show it's more
like what does they say it's not like
social engineering it's more like
natural selection right this is not
hacking here don't post your passwords
on notepad sticky notes things like that
here's just a couple of the ones that I
found over the course of just visiting
clients and even more important if
you're gonna be on TV
holy cow do not put passwords in your
workplace all right worse yet just if
you're gonna be on TV don't have it done
on your work site be away from around
your machines maintain that clean desk
policy but yeah these are all just
people that have had passwords just
exposed because they left them on TV
crazy stuff right alright so let's talk
about Miss configuration if you think
about it there's more security incidents
due to Miss configuration than there are
security vulnerabilities there's way
more people installing applications than
actually developing them and so what
you're seeing here is Gartner says are
really good that 99 percent of cloud
security failures will be the customers
fault by 2023 it's not the s3 that's
that's compromised it's the
configuration settings so we have to
make sure that we're doing our
deployments we're doing our work
diligently otherwise we're exposing our
applications to undue risk all right so
again it's their configuration that's
really the the scary part alright now
who here is familiar with truffle log
this is a really cool tool that I want
to show a problem that many developers
make on a daily basis and it's a hard
coding your credentials into scripts
this is a just freely available tool up
on a github and what it does is it
recursively searches through the
commit histories of github submissions
what that does is you know if you put
your password in clear-text
by accident you make a change you submit
it if you don't remove it from your
revision history it's still just as good
there so I want to show you a couple
things before I begin and show you this
it's a true - case here all right so
this is github just from this morning
you can actually just search for
keywords and it will show you the most
recently indexed accounts and you can
see these are people's secret keys just
right out here and get up huh yes oh
sorry I'm not showing my screen thank
you let me a duplicate my screen here do
you do all right let's see here yep so
here's the github right here you can see
that this is just indexed recently and
people's secret keys are just exposed in
clear text here and if you want to
automate the finding of that this is
really where truffle hog is very helpful
so I created a script to make this a
little easier today let me see your si
desktop truffle hog - and I wanted to
show you this idiot that put all this
open light his SSH keys passwords all of
this stuff is in this morons github repo
I mean take a look at this all right
I'll scroll up here so you can see a
couple SSH keys private keys come on
scroll up damn it there we go
so yeah there's a secret there this is
all in one single github repo don't
worry these this is my github repo so
it's they're not actual real passwords
so yeah tough yeah it's not you're not
finding real passwords so but my point
is is that you know developers easily
put passwords in their scripts their
source code and it's very easy for an
attacker to find it all right so I'm
gonna switch back into presenter mode
and here let's see all right
Oh No
that's the last time I'm leaving the
screen here so we're good there all
right so there's all right all right so
let's keep moving forward we got mr. t
here talking about April Fool's this
this is a real story that happened in
one of my organizations well we had a
web developer that was let go and he was
not too happy about it so as one of the
last things he did before leaving the
organization was a planet a time bomb on
the e-commerce site so at some
predetermined time when he was long gone
lives like nine months after he loved
the time mom executed it just happened
to coincide with April Fool's so what
happened was is it was actually fairly
benign logic bomb it basically was a
JavaScript that inverted the screen so
it looked like you were looking at
everything upside down happened like I
said on April Fool's so what happened
was is the company played it off like it
was an April Fool's joke but in reality
InfoSec was running around with their
heads cut off freaking out so I thought
that was an interesting one nothing
really came about it but again this just
shows where you know potential risks
exist in your in your processes this one
here this was a good one I had a client
of mine that we were doing an assessment
of their privileged accounts what
cyber-ark does we work on privileged
accounts security so your most important
passwords like domain admin accounts
need to be managed really aggressively
and we found this domain admin account
it was a systems admin account that was
running a service and it wasn't just a
regular domain admin account it was the
guy in the room that was well I was
given the presentation too and let me
real quote him word for word I said I
think he said I'm not calling you a liar
I just don't believe a word you just
fucking said yeah that really makes you
scared right so I did what any rational
human being would do and when I showed
him that
fact that he was using his own account
to run this service I handed him the
HDMI controller and said let's log on to
the box and take a look oh it was
amazing within like ten seconds this guy
turns bright red redder than the guy
shirt in the back and it was awesome
he said I'm so sorry but the point is is
this guy was running you know service
accounts with his own admin account in
the event that these service accounts
are running that meant that those
credentials are stored in memory so in
the event that that machine was
compromised an attacker would have
access to his domain admin account
pretty scary stuff right now this is one
that I shouldn't have to tell you but
I'm gonna do it anyway you shouldn't be
surfing inappropriate content at work
right this goes this is a great story
because I get I get to shut somebody
down hard so on my one time I was
managing our sand storage and we were
about to put a
my Gration so we're cleaning up data and
I found a treasure trove of
inappropriate content what happened was
is one of the people on our team had a
really weird fetish but I digress he
happened to be storing all of it in his
My Documents folder on his corporate
issued laptop what he also didn't know
was that in My Documents folder was
being replicated back to our standard
for document retention purposes so what
he was into was getting synchronized
back to the files here we happened to
terminate that a couple years ago but
the data was still there and it was
still being backed up on a regular basis
which is how I discovered it so this was
the cool part so he accused me of
planting this you know contraband on in
his file share so be that he actually
started before me I was like okay bro
let's do this pick a day any day pick
one before I even started and let's
restore that file so he's no longer
there and I was so yeah
but my point being is is it I'm not
trying to can't shame anybody just keep
that stuff off your per your work
machine do that in your own time right
all right so I'm gonna kind of segue
into some things that we want to talk
about words that you shouldn't be using
in a professional context these are
things that I've seen people use some of
these are not a little mean they're not
bad but again I would advise you to try
to use different words ping ping in the
context of Technology is a beacon
waiting for a response in the terms of
business it doesn't necessarily mean
that it's morphing you say if you pink
somebody in accounting it's a lot
different than pinging somebody in
networking right they don't quite get it
all right another thing is is the term
to be honest I hate this term because
this implies at times you may not be
honest so just don't use this word you
know just again try not to use that
another one the the concept of burning
the ships that you know that's the hell
or high water we there's no going back
you guys familiar with where this term
originated from the conquistador days of
like seventeen sixteen hundred's
Coronado made it to the new world and
burned his ships so that the the his
soldiers had no recourse but to discover
the new land
you know what that never actually
happened there was no burning of ships
rather than burning of the ships
Coronado actually scuttled the ships he
programmatically broke down the timber
and the linen and all the resources of
the boats that's just stupid
so do things smart okay another term
that I want to talk about today is the
term brand jacking this is some
marketing mumbo jumbo it's the same
things that we've heard of time and time
again it's fishing right let's call a
spade a spade and not use divergent
terms because it all means the same
thing this is fishing another term that
really really gets me this grinds my
gears is the term open the kimono
anybody heard this one I don't like this
one this one you we see c-suite
executives just within the last couple
of years using this term this is a
reference to the historical times of
Japan where the geishas would you know
open their kimonos as a show of exposing
their naked bodies that's not the
intention of today's c-suites using this
term it's more of being transparent
honest and open with your transactions
without knowing the historical
connotations this really changes the
context of this phrase not only is this
sexist but it's racist and so again in
my opinion just best not use these sorts
of terms in the context of a business
discussion right another one that I
really want to talk on and I think this
is a really good opportunity to talk
about this is using the term hacking in
relative to criminal actions you know
what there's a lot of hackers in this
room today and none of you well I hope
none of you are legitimate criminals
hacking is not a crime you know this is
how we're finding these flaws and along
with the whole concept of the hacker and
the hoodie and the with the face mask
these aren't hackers then you want to
talk about what real hackers look like
these are real hackers well they may not
be this is a this is not a real person
calm these are just computer-generated
people these are the criminals that we
need to be protecting not against these
sorts of folks you know so you've kind
of shared with you a bunch of the
terrible things that I've seen in my
past as a systems administrator I want
to share with you a couple of things
that are actually good things that you
can take away one was just using common
sense being able to really protect an
organization from ransomware somebody in
accounting really shouldn't be running
you know bash shell scripts or you know
VB ship scripts so disassociating that
type of extension to something like
WordPad and so is just a really easy way
to go about doing that and yes that is a
base64 Easter Egg there so another thing
that you can do is changing the default
installation path just going from C to D
what does that do from a security
perspective a lot of the script kiddie
tools are looking for default
installation path default registry
values things like that and so by just
deviating even something as small as
that you can actually break some of
these automated scripts now let's be
honest if we got an apt in the house and
they're actually doing byte by byte you
know file by file scans this
gonna help but if we're talking about
some script kiddie stuff yes this will
help also from a systems administration
perspective this will actually by
breaking out your OS volumes and your
data volumes will actually shrink your
data backups too so it's a win-win
another thing is is that the personal
relationships in being in a career of a
systems administrator you can see these
are some guys I used to work with at
fossil that are now we've gone our
separate ways but you know I still run
across these guys as clients I'm not
gonna tell you where but this is a
government facility I mean that's crazy
right there's a these are my two best
friends we used to work together between
the three of us we have 17 girls yeah I
know there's like no y chromosomes that
were produced at all but these are some
of my best friends that I wouldn't have
had if I didn't have a career as a
systems administrator and then we
wouldn't have the awkward hugs from
Jason - so by the way if you haven't got
a chance
Jason's do want to talk later tomorrow I
believe and it's gonna rock your socks
off so I want to give credit to him and
also if you can see we can have fun on
the job - anybody seen American Psycho
yes so you get that reference right
there feed me a stray cat yeah so I
changed all the payroll systems to say
feed me a straight cat for a day just
because I wanted to so I've kind of
talked about you know being a shitty
Systems Administrator I really do
believe that the shittiest of systems
administrator can also become one of the
best security professionals because
again we've made these mistakes we know
how the corners have been cut we know
where the skeletons are buried and so
this kind of allows me to segue into how
to get into info second how to get into
security I get a question a week online
from people and so one of the questions
I really get a lot is is you know the
concept of should you go for experience
or should you go for a certification I
kind of believe in both I mentioned that
you know I'm an adamant fan of is
c-squared a conte ia and all the
different certifications there's a
method to it anybody know who this guy
is here Dave Ramsey I love Dave Dave got
me out of 60 grand in debt it's all
based on this concept of the debt
snowball and
taking the small bed debts and rolling
them into the next one and once you get
that paid off you go to the next one I
highly encourage you if you're in any
sort of fiscal debt take a look at
Dave's course it's worth its weight in
gold but if you apply it to the concepts
of certifications in IT it just makes it
even more sense so this is how I started
I started with an A+ security we want
the security plus and these build off of
each other so again the harder that gets
the you've already kind of maintained
the baseline from the previous
certification so I went from the SSCP to
the CISSP and then there's all these
different other ones that you can get
now this is just a handful of governing
bodies there's so many other different
ones but you can do these are the ones
that really go into the the crusader
defensive style now if you want to go
into more of a Red Team offensive
certification track there's also a
different certification track you can do
as well these are just a handful but if
you really want to hone your dark wizard
skills definitely go down the route of a
couple of these certifications OSC P and
OSCE in particular really good ones but
there's a problem with certifications
they're only as good as the the paper
that they're printed on so if you're
going to get any of these certifications
know what the hell you're talking about
and demonstrate that okay so in lieu of
doing a QA today I wanted to kind of
make this an opportunity to kind of have
you share with me and the rest of the
people today a couple of your
confessions a couple of these stories of
mishaps that you may have done in your
career and lessons learned from that so
if you don't mind if you've got to kind
of share with the share with the class I
think show anybody want to just show you
AG share with us serve right here up in
the front
tell me of one of your confessions here
if you if we have to if nobody else
volunteers then yes you do
[Music]
password zero one very complex okay oh
no way so you're saying this rogue
accounts started jacking in with
accounts no oh no so let me get this
straight you kick off this automated
script that's supposed to disable a few
accounts what ends up happening when you
run the script and what did it really do
[Music]
so you shut down everything in the
production domain by accident from
running the script yeah we need yeah
thank you
and question are you still at the time
were you still employed after this event
Wow that's even more impressive right on
right on for the sake of the time I'm
gonna uh
show of hands anybody other stories real
quick you'll want to share with the
class one more back here yes sir yes on
that same note don't take WebEx calls in
the men's room I purposely flush
multiple times just to spite you when
you do that okay thank you guys for your
for your confessions if you may I want
to share with you a couple others that
were submitted to me online before we
kind of conclude today's talk this one's
a pretty good one anybody know what you
name s does on a Linux system anybody it
simply just checks the machine name
properties of the remote system right
okay very simple command that says Evans
do day to day all the time right anybody
know what that same command does on a
Solaris system now rename the host yeah
I can do with some damage
I mean moving forward how many of you
all have done this alright so show
everybody's done then these are mistakes
we all make right very quick easy fix to
this simply and I've started doing this
to my junior admins I put this in their
profile and it has fixed so many
unnecessary deletions in your
organization so again just making simple
fixes to correct that I saw somebody
raise their hand earlier in the back did
you all have one more story you wanted
to say no yes Wow
be careful of the commands you run very
scary scary story there I got a couple
other ones this one was given to one of
my buddies and a DHA they used to run a
they did remote support for restaurants
and they had their credit card
processing available via dial-up modem
and so this ingenious young professional
decided again this is a long time ago
maintain a password list and decided to
put it up on Geocities because nobody
would ever go to this unlisted website
right well funny enough there's this
thing called wayback machine
that password list which has never
changed still works I swear to God so I
mean this is some scary stuff we're
talking about another really really good
story came to me from my friends at
fuzzy snuggly duck if you're not
familiar with them look them up they're
awesome incident folks this is a really
good story about how to properly handle
an incident in this circumstance we have
a database table that was compromised by
an attacker attacker got into the
network who was able to take X fill this
data but not just X fill the data the
attacker decided to be smart and
basically planted their own canary back
in and replaced one of the records in
the database table so eventually the
attackers were found in both sexes finds
the the event and alerts the end users
hey urines
your data was compromised and we are
we're on top of it right so the problem
is that also ended up notifying the
attacker because he caught her up did
the data oh it gets better than that so
again so InfoSec has now sent an email
and they're you know company letterhead
proper formatting you know telling them
that hey you been breached so what's an
attacker gonna do use that same
letterhead just spam the hell out of
just the same people that he just pwned
so what the attacker ended up doing was
said hey yeah you're right we have been
compromised in order for payroll to be
successfully done you're going to need
to log into your this phishing site and
give us your admin passwords so not only
did they steal the data they also fished
the attacker afterwards so all right so
I've got a couple of things before I
conclude and so again to make sure that
you actually respond to me I'm going to
bribe you none of this like small stuff
I got a real full-size candy here so I
told you there was going to be a quiz
later all right
SLA all right I can't hear y'all so I'm
just gonna throw stuff okay by the way
I'm so thankful there's no projectors
like up here because if you've never
seen a guy had a 4k projector with the
like a Hershey bar it's not pretty so
personal experience confession there so
here we go all right
service-level germane FCR yes good job
CIA all right
AAA all right let's see if I'm get a
spiral on this one I just wanted to put
this in there so all right so again
wrapping up guys just a couple of things
too before I finish you know prioritize
your security over operations that's
it's an important thing don't cut
corners it's kind of important the fact
is is that the systems administrators
these are the people that we're trusting
to install these solutions they're
probably the people that are
circumventing them so let's watch our
Watchers right
be aware that you know just because the
application may be secure
maybe the installation itself isn't so
be aware that misconfigurations are you
know in jeopardy as well and the fact of
the matter is is vs. admins we're humans
too we're lazy we make mistakes
there's errors that happen risk is
everywhere learn from the mistakes that
you've learned from today from myself
the people here as well and the people
that shared with online the confessions
so again hopefully you won't make the
same mistakes this kind of leads to me
back to the three envelopes story that I
told you at the very beginning when I
first started at my very first sysadmin
job I got three envelopes in my my desk
drawer from the previous systems
administrator and said hey this is what
you need if something really goes awry
and you just don't know what to do open
one of these envelopes and it will
really help you out so the first one
when the production system went down I
didn't know what to do I was about to
lose my job so I decided to finally get
that envelope I open it up and blame the
previous assignment cycle that's all
Sean's fault you know what it actually
worked it actually kept me back I got my
job at all good so about nine months
later same thing happens again
production goes down again things are
going crazy I have to go back to the
drawer I pull out the envelope I open it
says blame the vendor so that's what I
did work like a charm about six months
later the same thing happened again so
again going back to my trusty envelope I
open it up it says prepare three
envelopes yes so that concludes my talk
thank you so much everyone I appreciate
it