we like to save the best for the last if
you've come to show me con at any time
you have seen this guy I met Jason 10
years ago my mentor Ralph fetch from
India introduced me to him years ago
I've had the honor of speaking in
Iceland and Romania all over the world
and one of the coolest things about it
is Jason's there and when we start doing
our con I was always like I can't it
finally have a friend in my town and not
necessarily like oh I'll see him Romania
in November which I'll see you in
Romania in November if you don't know
who Jason is I'm going to give you his
nice little bio but Jason is he's gotta
let you know who he is
so Jason E Street is the author of
dissecting the Hat the forbidden network
from sonorus I can't ever say that
cinder s I don't care either I don't
even know creator of dissecting hack
he's spoken at Def Con he is actually
one of the main people that helps ensure
that Def Con keeps going on derbycon
yukon and several other cons his life
story can be found under Jason E Street
that's Jay AYSO in East Street he's a
highly carbonated speaker who's taking
Pizza Pizza Hut all over the world from
Beijing to Brazil he does not expect a
need up by you to still be reading us
this far but if they are please note
Jason was chosen F times Person of the
Year 2006 please give it up for my
friend and colleague Jason E Street
and that's literally toast legit you can
google TIME's Person of the Year for
2006 and you'll see the cover which it
says you so if you were around in 2006
congratulations
it's like TIME's Person of the Year 2006
how are we doing it's like I still don't
know what time zone I'm in but I've been
assured its central so we'll just go
with that this is the talk I own the I
Pony not basically it's the things that
I love to do I love for my victims
targets clients to to do when I'm
robbing them and three things that I
hate for them to do when I'm robbing
them because it makes it harder for me
to rob them it's like ah there we go
it's like perfect example for a nice
offer it's like see you in Vegas
DC 8:01 party awesome so you notice how
that doesn't even faze me it's just
life's weird right so a little bit about
me is just all you need to know is that
I do social social engineering security
awareness engagements physical
compromise you can see some of that done
on National Geographic it's like you see
me in the news but more importantly you
see me in your server room on your
surveillance footage in the lower
left-hand corner it's like those are
actual footage videos or pictures for me
robbing things that's actually a
computer that I took from a teller and
Beirut just walked in didn't even say
hello unplug the computer while they
were doing business beside me and then
walked out
that was a finding by the way it's like
that wasn't reported as a finding so so
that's what I do
it's like but I also like to educate
it's like that's the key thing I like to
do it's like red teaming or penetration
testing whatever you want to call it
whatever you think makes it sound cooler
what you do is like it's one basic
function your job is to educate the blue
team the defenders the client to make
them better secure at the end of the day
it's like if you go in and you break
into something and it's like and you
like I went in I pushed him in the face
and no plan finding you know you've
wasted their time your job there is to
defend your job is there is to help
protect the defenders and make the
defenders better that's all red team's
do is to make the client better and you
see so many different variations of that
you know it's like I hear I've go to so
many conferences and I see all these
people talk about like all these obscure
and high-tech very very sophisticated
attacks and I'm like those are cool but
can I just walk in off the street and
just like you know grab their server
it's like I don't know how to do a
sequel injection that'll give me the
drop to database it's like that sounds
difficult and complicated I just walk in
the server and I take the hard drive
where the database is and I walk out
with it it's a little bit easier for me
it's like you know for each their own so
it's like we hear about all these
high-level attacks but we're not talking
about some of the basic low-level stuff
that gets everybody it's like and when
red teams come in they do a disservice
to their clients because they go in and
saying oh we went through the ceiling
panel and stuff you know and we use some
freon gas to open up the motion sensor
and it's like two roped in it's like
that we took a picture of a from a jelly
belly and stuff you know I was able to
fool the biometric thing and get into
like that and then the clients like
thank goodness we're safe because that's
like a high level I mean you were like
ninjas aside we don't have to work
that's not our threat model we don't
have to worry about that it's like so
we're cool it's like y'all guys were
like awesome you are ninjas it's like
weird
threat models not ninjas or
nation-states it's like it's a whole
East nation-states
but still it's like we don't to worry
about that it's like so what I try to do
is I try to remove all of that it's like
I go in and say I never been in this
building before I didn't know who the
manager of the people were I walked in
on the first minute within 2 minutes and
22 seconds I'm now behind your teller
line and I have full access to
everything in your bank that's a problem
it's like they don't have any answer for
that because you can't just walk that
away it's like you can't just want this
so that's why I like to do it the easy
way
it's like it's not that I can't do it
see I've had to do some jobs where it's
a little bit more sophisticated than
that not by much okay but it's a little
bit more but it's like I like to do the
most basic so it's like there's no
defense for it and then we have another
problem in information security and
that's what we need it's like what we're
trying to build you know your executive
management it's like the picture on the
last light that's what we need build
that protect us it's like anyway sure we
can do that it's like what's our budget
well we can afford what's on the right
okay we need what's on the left but we
can afford what's on the right do your
best
lose your job if you don't it's like but
do your best right it's like that's what
we have to deal with it's like so I want
to give some basic advice it's like I
mean every accuses me of being basic
anyway but it's like I want to give some
basic advice on what we can do to better
protect ourselves that you can take back
today to help with and so one of the
things that I love more than anything
else that I cherish beyond all measure
is employees not empowered or educated
to question the unusual that gets me
every single time into a building into a
site into a server room into the
computer into a network and into the
jackpot it's like I was on and again and
I tell you it's like and what I mean by
that is there's nothing worse there's
than a false sense of security right I
think so it's like everybody thinks it's
like everything's to protect and I'm
like no no it's like there is something
worse than that it's like it's like not
no security but that false sense of
security it's like that's what the
problem is people going in and thinking
that oh you got to go through there's
physical guards at our doors
we've got RFID badges it's like we got
can secure two areas it's like so if
someone's inside there they must be
trusted and so therefore when I come in
with a clipboard or it can work shirt
saying I needed something I'm trusted I
must be okay no I'm never okay it's like
but people act that way I was on a job
in January it was a very secure facility
it's like I had a I dressed in the
jacket so it's like and I dressed a
little bit like the rest of the
everybody and so I came in and I told
him like hey I'm with IT we're checking
the USB rights on your computers because
you shouldn't be charging your phones or
devices from the computer you should be
charging the devices from the outlet so
we're doing this USB rights to make sure
that that can happen and I have a cable
an iPhone lightning charger cable there
is no phone attached to this cable it is
just the cable and I plug it into their
computer and then I pull this detonator
out of my jacket and I swear to goodness
it looks just like a debtor little
square box a little light and then aunt
Anna and I didn't have to pull it out
but I did it for a fact because I wanted
to get caught I wanted them to question
it I pulled out the detonator I didn't
say boo okay I was tempted but I did not
okay so and it's like and all of a
sudden notepad pops up on their screen
it automagically Tikes out test
completed successfully thank you for
your cooperation
smiley face emoji and I'm like okay cool
the test of us is thank you very much
for your cooperation it's like I'll do
that eight people in the same area no
one questioned me how my table
activated their notepad I go back
because I do like I said I do security
awareness engagements it's like I don't
just it's not useful if they're not
educated they're not understanding right
then and there on that day when the
impact is still fresh that something
went wrong so I go back to them after
the engagement is over and I go back to
each person and I question them say did
you find anyone
just a teeny just keeping it and it's
like yeah yeah now that you mention it
it's like I thought it was a little
weird it's like but I didn't want I
didn't want to feel like I didn't want
to interrupt it's like I didn't want to
like cause any problems like no call
submitting trouble it's like that's okay
it's like caused a ruckus some guy just
came and plug the cable in and somehow
your notepad activated that's sketchy AF
you should be talking to somebody okay
so it's like so that's what we need to
do we need to empower our users that
it's okay for them to question when
something unusual happens you are not
having every day of your job weird
things like that happening it's like and
if you are check yourself you may be on
lady sitcom but if you're not it's like
it's like then you need to question and
you need to contact security
you need to let them know hey this was
really weird what's happening one of the
things I hate it's like I'm not talking
about this guy technically but it's like
is open lobbies faces I mean let's face
time I don't know this is what the CIA
lobby looks like because trust me if I
ever visit its gonna be going through
the back door with the bag over my head
it's like I'm pretty sure it's like I'm
on a lot of lists for some reason all
right so I know exactly why but but so
public faces are well monitored highly
visible I hate those kind of spaces it
is so hard to loiter in those spaces
it's so hard to case to place in those
spaces it's so hard to not be getting
attention in those kind of spaces so I
was a this is no past November I was in
Moscow it's like I'm reading the faces
so I know where the feds are okay good
Gotham and
I was a asked to visit because firsties
headquarters because I think his Percy's
a friend of mine and yes I'm now on
another list I'm sure but but so I was
invited I was in Moscow so I decided to
go and visit the headquarters and I am
telling you as soon as I walked in the
door it's like it was like it was an
open environment but there's this nice
couch there and I'm one of those guys
it's like when they even when I'm not on
the clock that I can't go off the clock
you know I still gotta think like what
could I do here to cause destruction you
know it's like it's just a habit okay
I don't actively cause the described
destruction I don't actively go and do
the bad things but I can't help thinking
about it right so I decided instead of
just going straight to the reception
Stefan's checking it's like I'm just
gonna sit down and check it out and see
what see what the layout is you know sex
I think that'd be cool it's like man as
soon as my butt touched leather on that
on that couch this big security guy I'm
pretty sure his name was Ivan you know
just walks over he's like excuse me
comrade couldn't he didn't say comrade
but you know it's like uh how can I help
you today it's like do you need to
register with someone or you do you have
an appointment
very polite okay but when your muscles
have muscles you're allowed to be polite
and no matter which way you want to do
it okay right it's like I mean he was
literally wearing these these black
trousers and this shirt that was like
either two times too small or if muscles
four times too big for it I don't know
which but it's like but he was very
polite and he guided me he was so
helpful and guided me straight to the
receptionist desk so I could check in
and validate that I was supposed to be
there in the first place and that my
friends is exactly how you do it it's
like there was no confrontation there
was no obvious like you know I've been
being distressed or there was something
that I can complain about it was like he
was doing it as a service like I'm
helping you it's like I'm trying to be
nice but at the same time letting me
know
mother you ain't getting away with this
it's like you need to kill register it's
like and that's how your buildings are
supposed to be it's like that's how your
lobbies are supposed to be it's like
they're supposed to be where people are
registering and then waiting for the but
they're not just loitering they should
be registered and accounted
for as soon as they get into your
facility so you can account for where
they are at all times so that was well
done on the I on their part and it's
like it was a really cool tour was like
really nice facility so I'm gonna get
out of that because I'm probably in more
trouble one of the things I love is no
ingress filtering or internal monitoring
and we got to talk about fails it's like
I can't help but add the TSA because
they provide so much examples of bad for
me
and then this one it gives it a TSA a
just missed mock weapons more than
seventy percent of the time
seventy percent of time you had one job
right tonight and I bet you their main
excuse is gonna be it's like yeah but no
four ounces a toothpaste made it past
did it so there it's on okay the
battle-axe and the bachelors may be okay
but no four ounces the toothpaste that's
a line we're not gonna cross so that's
one of our biggest problems is that
we're having our people it's like we're
building the security we're thinking
like let's make sure our firewalls
blocking all activity coming out or
going in make sure that we've got that
hardened perimeter but then when it
comes about you know outbound traffic
any any no monitoring because you know
it's trusted it's coming from inside
coming from inside the house okay
how do you not watched me horror movies
ever right and more so now than ever
your attacks your actual point of
ingress is that compromised machine in
the counting it's like that's been
compromised and now using the controls
that you put in place to then connect to
the command and control and compromise
your internal network and then I mean
look at Sony it's like seriously I mean
not most of the movies lately but still
the come
they lost over one terabyte of data
during their breach how do you miss one
terabyte of data leaving your network to
Paraguay it's like it wherever it went
that's a little odd right just a little
bit I mean even from a network
standpoint I mean what did they do the
network guys go see all that traffic
leaving the line oh we need to increase
the bandwidth on this it's like there
seems to be a lot of traffic why why
wasn't security looking that going maybe
we should check that out Bob you know is
like has never really released you know
one terabyte of data going to South
America maybe we should check into that
you should be monitoring and fielding
your no one should be able to connect
outside that network unless it's from a
policy procedure that backs it up on the
firewall rule it's like I one of the pay
lives that I use on my Bosch bunny
because I don't do I don't do
compromises I don't do exploits I do
security awareness things one of my
security awareness things is basically I
hope I plug in the Bosch money it opens
up command prompt it types in telnet to
Towell blinky lights Titan l and all of
a sudden in the command prompt you see
Star Wars and ASCII it's like playing
animated it's like through your telnet
which is really sort of cool except for
the fact you should not have telnet
going to the Netherlands it's like on
your accountants computer correct
am I crazy well yes I am crazy but still
is that that's crazy
why is your accountant that allowed to
go telnet to the Netherlands and why
isn't there someone at my desk when I'm
there within five minutes asking that
question because there's no proper
egress filtering we're not monitoring
what's leaving our network we're so
concerned about what's coming in it's
like you're so busy trying to build the
walls it's like we got to build a wall
make it bigger
China apt is gonna pay for
it's like well guess why it's like
they're going over that and then they're
just walking out the front door and
we're letting them because we're not
monitoring what's leaving our doors
we're just so busy trying to barricade
them so one of the things I really hate
it's like not not not sneakers I'm not
hating on sneakers sneakers it's a good
movie though don't start getting flame
wars on me but dual factor
authentication that's a problem it's
like to get to deal with right it's like
because I love doors that are just like
it'll just open up or the pin pads those
are nice it's like but when you put an
RFID or a hid badge which I could easily
clone with the proc smart or a boss
cloner it's like that's awesome but then
you put that pesky peek keypad there and
I'm like mother it's like that's not
cool that's not playing fair I'm trying
to rob you all nice and stuff and you're
being difficult it's like you know
where's the fun in that well for me
anyway right it's like and so I have to
give you one of the same story that I
did about the cable back in January they
did something very cool and mean to me
it's like I took all the time all the
time in trouble to sneak into their
facility going through the freight
elevator and they had a security pad and
card in the freight elevator entrance
lobby so it's like they created their
own little Lobby inside that couldn't I
couldn't get in I mean it took me 13
minutes and act like I was on the phone
till an employee let me in but I got in
and I'm like ah so I'm in the section
I'm like I'm getting ice cream right and
so until I decided to leave that one
section they owned the whole floor they
own two floors in this building so I get
to the glass door and I'm like it's like
oh that's a I can't go anywhere else but
this section you have to badge into each
part of the buildings floor even though
you're it's the same company they still
leave segmented the actual floor what
the actual you know that's not cool I
mean it was cool because I was able to
steal someone's badge
they left there on their desk it's like
and then get in but at first I panicked
that wasn't nice it's like so but then
they segment but they segmented it and
it took multi-factor authentication I
love people that I've done so many
different banks and gone into their main
headquarters and it's like anju me to do
million dollar wire transfers it's not a
simple process
that's some serious business right it's
like they need to protect that stuff you
need a protector ID you need to own that
identity that you did that so that you
have you a USB keys you have a key that
you have to plug into the computer has
there ever been a time I have not found
a USB key already connected to the
computer when I came in to steal it it's
like the answer is no it's like every
single effing time it's like if it's not
on the computer that's okay don't panic
open up the middle drawer right there
it's like so you've got to make sure
that you have two-factor authentication
but you got to make sure that it's an
actual two-factor it's like you gotta
make sure that's actually going to
actually be used in a secure way it's
like so but those are the things that
that really pisses me off it's like I do
have a problem with that now the next
thing it's like I love people that don't
follow established procedures everybody
says we have a procedure against that or
that's against company policy it's like
oh I know it is it's like but here I am
right it's like and this is a great
story about sorry for everybody that's
in the Air Force you know sorry hashtag
sorry not sorry
but uh this was actually on Ellis Air
Force Base in Nevada it's like two
civilians somehow breached an Air Force
Base and were found only when one of
them told the airmen she'd been
kidnapped her attacker grabbed her put
her in the car and just started driving
it's like we're leaving it's like here's
a good road well I'm gonna like you know
hide this I've got to find a place to
ditch her and like you
and hide the body it's like well here's
this an abandoned area so it seems
pretty the band and let me just drive in
didn't stop at the gate the guard didn't
go that's odd
that car it was a civilian car didn't
check in seems legit it's like let's not
bother reporting that it's like and then
the guy got on the base then he realized
oh wait I made a horrible decision
you've made several by that point buddy
it's like and so it starts trying to
drive around and was able to stop she
was able to get out and escape at that
moment and was able to talk to the
guards it's like and notify them the
fact that it's like I think someone
broke a procedure here or two I don't
think she said that it's like but that's
what happened and it's like you got
established procedures it's like for a
reason security has procedures for a
reason another good story that I have to
say because it's really funny once again
at the expense at the Air Force it's
like I have nothing it's the Air Force
it's like I I make fun of everybody
equally but it's like there was this one
where back during the Cold War a Russian
agent drove up onto a u.s. airbase in
Germany he then proceeded to walk up to
a plane that had a missile attached to
it he detached the missile it's like put
it in a wheelbarrow I don't know if he
stole the wheelbarrow too but I really
hope he did ok it's like put it in a
wheelbarrow willed it to his Mercedes
it's like we're in Germany after all
right he put it in the backseat I
attached a red flag to the tip because
it was sticking out of the window and
German laws are German laws okay it's
like and drove home to his apartment
disassembled the missile it's like and
mailed every piece back to Mother Russia
and I mean the the German metal system
is impeccable it's like every piece got
back there ok it was like it was just
insane I think there were some policies
that weren't enforced there either it's
like your policies aren't good unless
people know that you're going to enforce
them your policies are not good unless
your executives own up to them
are part of them and are responsible for
them as well it's like if your
executives don't have to follow your
policies congratulations you have no
policies it's like if your executives
are exempt from your security procedures
guess what you have no security
procedures you have a wish list that's
like that the the chumps use okay and
then other people go well I report to
that guy so I don't have to follow those
either and then those people go why
report to that guy who reports to that
guy who reports to that guy so I don't
have to follow them either and the only
one that fallen on this like you know ed
and stuff you know in the mailroom go on
oh well at least I got my steak we're on
halal these policies you know it's like
that's not gonna work out well for you
okay you have to make sure your policies
and procedures are there they're
enforced and people are aware of them
you have to make sure that happens
because if they don't understand that
and they don't believe that they have to
follow those policies then you've got
really not much of anything now this was
sort of my education part a ramp part of
there and it's like you're asking
yourselves like what exactly is the
point of this it's like what one of the
part is to educate it's like to tell you
about some of the things that I like
about that but now I want you to know
some of the questions you should be
asking your work area your space your
employers your enterprise your wherever
you're working or whoever pays you a
paycheck it's like here are some
questions you need to take back to your
users and to your security team it's
like here's some questions it's fruit
for you
like for one really inside of threats
which one fits the bill do you really
understand what an insider threat is is
it really just a it's a really just the
the malicious actor like Robert hands
wouldn't say and and I like the feds
going right now why is he always picking
us it's like this put me off the list
then maybe okay it's like so it's like
so maybe it's a malicious insider threat
or let's be honest sometimes it's just
stupidity like on the right it's like
and I love this fact it's like on the
right the TSA devolves willingly for an
article all the print for their keys so
you can make duplicates of them now
that's sort of bad because that opens up
all your luggage all your secured
devices can now be opened up by anybody
a luggage handler anywhere around the
world because they can 3d print those
things when asked about it and accused
about like how dare you what what are
you doing the government the same
government who wants the keys to all
your mobile devices for your encryption
keys when well that's not really a
security practice we don't really care
it's like too bad that the keys are out
there but you know that's not our
problem sure I want you to have my
encryption keys now yes that instills me
with so much confidence it's like so
that is a threat vector
those are both insider threats one was
malicious one was actively trying to
destroy your network trying to do damage
to your company the other one just did
it by accident if your company goes out
of business because of one or the other
does it really matter which one it was
you should be preparing and protecting
for both and also if you're going to do
that it's like you need to understand
it's like when that threat happens how
you respond to this I call this the fail
burrito I added this slide this morning
at 6:30 something it's like I don't know
if you're aware of
Border Patrol have a employee a
contractor who against company policy
and procedures copied over 500 gigs of
data off the Homeland Security's
computer network which was against their
policy and what do they do they put it
on their network which was then breached
and then downloaded and the Homeland
Security you know being the wonderful
responsive government entities they are
set out a thing going I send out a press
release going like we're not going to
divulge who it is but we're talking to
omens like we scanned the dark web and
I'm sure that when when marketing heard
this like they skin their she's always
kind of it sounds cool just leave it
that way okay it's like we scanned the
dark web it's like we found no traces
everybody's safe don't worry nothing to
see here and the documents they release
it on the metadata showed exactly what
company was so good job on that one and
then Justin Cox here was like able to go
really he's getting the dark web that
sounds like a great idea let me try oh
look here's the 500 gigs of data you
said that you scan the dark web for I
found it within five minutes maybe you
should look into that I mean I call this
the fail burrito because you put a
little bit of fail here and then you add
some more fail you wrap it up and fail
and it's like whatever you do just look
at it don't eat it because you're gonna
get sick okay but it's like that's what
they did and it's like so thank you
border control and homeland security for
once again providing us what we're not
supposed to do on anything so that's an
issue right there it's like that's an
issue because that's once again your
data and what's gonna happen well those
contractors are going to learn a lesson
those contractors are going to frickin
pay the penalties they're gonna have to
deal with the repercussions that I'm
joking that they're fine it's like
they're still doing business with them
there's like they're like don't do that
again and they're good it's like that's
what's going on right now so yay one of
the other things you do how do you ask
for an identification who do you ask and
how do you ask which one of these people
would you ask for identification the
answer is all of them it's like I do it
a little trick question because the
security guard actually has a badge but
you still ask for everybody it's like
that's who you ask
it's like you make sure from the CEO to
the guy in the mailroom they should all
have identification and they should all
be asked for it it's like I remember I
did a security awareness training class
for all new hires at this one online
Bank and a week after one of the classes
the owner not just well I think he was a
CEO too
he may not bother he was the only on
that in place right he was trying to get
into the second floor where our
datacenter was and he didn't have his
badge an employee literally only there
for about a week and a half saw him
coming and he was like sir you can't
come in here it's like you don't have
your badge I need to escort you to the
to the front office it's like do you
know what that owner did is that people
take fire it's like that owner went like
that's a very good response it's like
let's go up there and let's make sure
that we take care of this it's like goes
up to the front desk got a visitor's
badge it's like until he could get his
other badge and then left and got that
guy's name to us so we could properly
thank him for a job well done how many
other people tried to get an exception
to that rule how many other people in
that company thought it was okay not to
have their badge zero because the owner
lived up to the policy and the
procedures and took them seriously so
the guy who owns a company is going to
live by those rules by Godley everybody
else's right that's the way it works so
what do your employees think a password
manager is please tell me because I'm
literally legit curious what point in
history it's like it had to be like in
the 60s or 70s that someone looked at
their keyboard and when hmm that's a
good place to put a password I don't
think no one's ever going to look under
there I'll just put my little toast
another of the keyboard will be fine
it's like I mean how many people have
done that how many people have looked
under a keyboard and found a password
and then course
this is how many people voted under a
keyboard and found a password yes
that's why we drink right it's like
that's one of the educators I'm sure
it's like it's like so what we need to
do is like so I've got a great this Cup
there's no blinky lights involved in
this it's great for security awareness
and your team can do it right now
set up a schedule for for it so you
cover every single company branch
outpost whatever off this and floor
throughout the year it's like no matter
how long it takes it's like how many's
but just pick one floor a day or a week
or a quarter whichever is easier for you
to do it's like and have your security
team go through that floor and look
under every single keyboard you're going
to be depressed at first a lot okay
you're gonna be depressed a lot at first
it's like but do you know what you've
done you showed them that you're real
you showed them that someone is looking
someone is it trying to make sure that
the policies are in forth and you work
even if you don't find anything you're
gonna find something okay
you're still making a valid effort to
show people like hey I'm with
information security and you look under
your keyboard we're doing a password
sweep for security okay thank you very
much sorry to interrupt it's like and
you go through that the whole way that
right there is an invaluable security
awareness engagement for your users and
that didn't cost you a dime except for a
little bit of time it's like I'm a poet
I know it don't worry it's like so
that's what you need to do start
creating that kind of rigorous
inspection and let people know that
those passwords are serious go and do a
tutorials how many of your users know
that the spacebar is a valid network
login character the spacebar that is the
best key on the keyboard because I don't
write passwords anymore passwords are so
2010 right I do pass phrases I figured
write the effing Ilia
now you know it's like I got the space
character I guess they are it's like it
was the best of times it was the worst a
time exclamation point time I've got a 1
instead of an eye and a 3 instead of an
e it's like lit that's elite hacker
speak right there poetry it's like you
know it's also uncrackable win win show
them that they can use the space bar
show them what a good passphrase looks
like show them how they can use their
song lyrics or their favorite movie
quotes as a passphrase on their
different systems and servers and then
on a post-it note they just write Gmail
Terminator 3 as long as it's not I'll be
back don't use Arnold Schwarzenegger
quotes cuz they're always like to the
chopper I'll be back they're very short
okay it's like it's like so so get them
to like some some better quotes from
different movies it's like you know a
little bit longer quotes a little better
senior song lyrics okay let's face it if
it's like you know Gmail Rick Astley we
know it's never gonna give you up it's
like so it's like tell them to make a
little bit more obscure yes I just
record show me con so that's one of the
key things that you have to do it's like
educate your users on how to be better
at it and and and give them that and
empower them with that education so
they're like okay I'll start using pass
phrases because what happens when you
make them use a special character and a
lowercase character and and a number and
it's like an you know what they write
really complex really you know eight
character twelve character passwords
that they have no way of remembering so
they put it down the post-it note and
put it into your keyboard it's a vicious
cycle people we need to break it so show
them how to do passphrases show them how
that helps and makes it more effective
now another thing is what does your
social media profile really say about
you it's like there's been a big debate
on the the the Twitterverse lately about
people using employee social media
profiles against them it's like my whole
take on that
huh it's like I'm not supposed to use
one of the biggest gold mines in the
history because people might think I'm a
bad person I'm trying to rob you we've
established the fact that I'm a bad
person way long ago okay
bad people are looking at social media
profile I'm not going to go in and
create an account and make a
relationship with the person and tell
them that I want to marry them and go on
for six months until we start playing
the wedding and they go surprise it was
a fish I just wanted your accounting
information sorry you just booked that
thing to Aruba
we're not going okay that's a little
extreme okay but I am going to use my
fake accounts to go in and peruse
Facebook in LinkedIn and Twitter and I
am going to use that information to
gather as much information as your
employees are willfully putting out
there to the public to the public not to
like friends I'm not accepting your
friend requests it's like I did get a
guy on LinkedIn to endorse me I was a 23
year old female redhead who just had
finished going getting my CPA and I was
an accountant and so it was really
wonderful it's like an he endorsed me
for my tax information and my accounting
experience they gave me a lot of good
endorsements it's like and I got a lot
of good compromise so it's a win-win
situation for everybody but I don't
usually go and do the involvement I'm
using those to gather information there
was one particular teller or I don't
know if they were even a teller it's
like there was someone in a bank branch
and they literally had on a public
profile
I was not friends with him and trust me
after that talk I will never be friends
with him it's like I said I could show I
had a screenshot of showing the ad
friend button
I was not their friend so publicly to
the world they had their phone number
and their home address available on
their about page on Facebook profile
this is a time in America where people
are still being kidnapped held overnight
to open up the bank that
morning to be robbed and the next slide
that I showed was a picture of their
house I'm not creepy okay I didn't
actually go to their house take a
picture okay it was Google Streetview
it's like but I showed that picture and
people were upset mad disappointed in me
I mean I get that a lot so it was okay
but it's like but still it was very
upsetting and I'm like you don't think
bad guys are doing this this is what bad
guys do they do bad guy things it's like
the only difference between me doing
this and all the other people that are
doing this right now is with me you get
a report
you're being pen tested at this moment
you're just not getting the report
that's what you pay for when you're
getting a pen test you're not paying for
the actual attack and all the other
stuff you're you're getting paid for
that report at the end of the time that
tells you how to fix the issues because
there's like five other people in
Paraguay testing the same exact thing
and it's like no offense to any
Paraguayans but it's like I just like
saying Paraguay so it's like so that's
one of the issues that you have is that
you've got to watch out and you got to
make sure your employees know by being
an employee they couldn't be in a target
they have to be suspicious of who's
trying to friend them it's like who's
trying to look at their profile who's
trying to connect to them on LinkedIn if
they ask them questions or they send
them unusual quizzes I literally saw
this one quiz the top 25 things about
you and I'm like that's interesting it's
like oh let me look at these questions
oh these are the top 25 password reset
questions for email servers and banks
it's like what a co-inky-dink
right it's like all those things like
you know what Game of Thrones character
you are it's like who cares about that
now right but it's like it's like what
Marvel here
it's like what's this what it all those
things are mining your information it's
like you don't know where it's going
okay
everybody wants to be Tyrion Lannister
everybody's iron man it's like it's just
it's what it is so it's like so stop
trying to answer those now another thing
is one that sorry I hate picking on
these people a little this thing is one
of the leading causes of compromise but
did your employees really take it
seriously that's another thing that was
just recently on Twitter it's like I'm
on Twitter way too much obviously it's
like and but that's one of the problems
is that one company was trying to sue
their employee for doing a phishing
attack and I'm like for the first time
no that's not cool it's like but I'm one
of those guys if your employee keeps
clicking on malicious links after you've
reacted them after you told them what
the threats were and they still doing
that then why aren't you firing that
employee for doing it if you have a
delivery driver that keeps wrecking your
van do you keep that delivery driver on
the payroll and that's just like the
50,000 dollar vehicle you've got
employees cost you 300 million dollars
maybe you want to look into some you
know corrective measures so in this
attack target over 300 million dollars
how did that start phishing email I mean
I mean trust me the CEO of the HVAC
company was quick to say we were a
victim of apt apt goddess what is apt
stand for no that's what they tell the
board and that's what they tell their
shareholders apt stands for adequate
fishing technique that's what apt stands
for they tell the other stuff to their
board members okay because they want to
get out of it and make it not their
fault but nine times out of ten that's
what Starr did was a phishing and if
that's what started if you know that
there is a problem in your production
line that one of your robot
that is assembly your car is every once
in a while not bolting down properly one
of the parts in the engine so every
third car that you put out there blows
up and kills your drivers would you fix
that I mean either your general motors
in the 70s but would you fix that now
okay stop too soon it's like it's like
my bad they literally waited for 13
people to die but okay whatever it's
like I'm the bad guy it's like so you
would try to fix that we know that
fishing is an attack vector that is
being used regularly we know that your
employees are being targeted if your
employees don't consider it part of
their job to be cautious with opening
emails then you're failing your client
your users and your executives you're
failing them not them failing the
company we keep trying to get technology
to protect the users against themselves
instead of getting our users properly
trained to protect the technology that's
what happens they're your best asset
stop treating them like a liability and
start treating them like you're part of
the team and let them be aware that
they're part of the team because that's
what they've never not been part of your
team so we need to get that going we
need to get that I mean and it's a
broken record and it's like a horse I'm
gonna keep on kicking and a windmill I'm
gonna keep tilting at sue me not really
I don't have any lawyers I'm very bad at
business okay so what metrics do you
have that helps to justify your budget
and your actions I've had three
conversations on two continents just in
the last two weeks about this subject
it's like about budget how do I get
upper management to buy into this
process and I'm like how are you showing
what you do it's like that well that
gets there it's a constant well of
course they consider your call center
the better you do the less Stacy it's
like I love going at the end of the year
stuff you know you go to your boss like
hey have you noticed nothing really bad
happened to our network we didn't get
briefed nothing will if you
two million dollars it's like I'll make
sure nothing happens next year it's like
it's like a mafia you know mafiosos
Italy it's got really lights businesses
hate to have something happen to it you
know give me a couple of hundred
thousand more you can make sure that it
doesn't happen I'm just saying you know
it's like that would be bad
it's like and I'm very bad at Italian
mafiosos but still that's a bad thing so
give them numbers how many fire do you
log the hits on your firewall they're
coming in the answer is yes it's like an
what do you do with them you discard
them every 30 months like every every
other company does in the world right
because he wants to read through them
but the record how many hits come in put
that moat in an excel sheet and you got
a number
you got a metric it's like but Jason
that doesn't make sense who character
not really going to look at they want to
see numbers give them numbers how many
ideas that works you get coming through
the day well we haven't probably turned
your ID yes I know you haven't properly
to the dry Diaz everybody here knows you
haven't properly tuned your IDs that's
not a secret but it's numbers that you
can use how many spam emails get through
your email gateway will Jason that's our
business we don't care
those are numbers use them get those
metrics how many machines do you have in
your network
we don't really know you better ethic
find out soon okay because that's just
bad that's besides the point that's not
even part of this talk I'm going on a
rant you need to find out how many
machines are in your network okay
because if the guy in Paraguay knows how
many machines you have and you don't you
have one extra machine you really need
to be worried about okay that's all I'm
saying no how many machines are on your
network because sometimes they have the
habit of increasing by one and you're
going to have a very bad
day so track how many machines you have
track how many of them are patched
properly and put that in a report and
that report when you first get it is
going to suck really bad because now
there's gonna be you know attached you
know actual responsibility we hate that
okay but then things start getting
better and you get to start showing
improvement and then at the end of the
year you go to the executive and you say
hey you see how our metrics improved and
we're trying to get better on this and
we're on task when we're trying to
increase that we're going to need a
patch management solution and we're
going to need an asset management
tracker and we're gonna need these other
things to help make sure that we're
running smoothly we're actually gonna be
able to do this increase it's like can
we get a budget for that and they're
gonna look at the numbers and their act
like they're gonna read them it's a new
pie chart so that you're good it's like
okay yeah we can do that it's like we
need to get that done that sounds like a
good idea it's like yeah so that's how
you do that so and one of the last
things it's like I'm gonna say is
educate and power users can you ever
have enough for that
the answer is no always make sure your
employees feel empowered to say
something's wrong I don't know who that
person is I need to report them it's
like I don't know where this email came
from it looks suspicious I need to
report it December 7th 1941 Pearl Harbor
that morning a person manning the radar
station one of the first radar stations
in the world and this was at a time when
the world was at war and this was a Navy
base or an Arras it was an Air Force
Base or Navy base Navy okay so I'm
picking on the Navy this time so there
we go
so it's like so on a Navy base Pearl
Harbor it's like the person manning the
radar station sees planes coming from an
abnormal vector from an unusual
direction and they do their job they
report it to their next thing next in
command
they've got sir it's like we've got
planes coming in from the unusual
what do we do do you know what that
person said person looked at it knowing
that we the world was at war knowing
that they were a military installation
seeing a whole bunch of planes coming in
and their immediate reaction was that's
probably our training planes you just
disregard spoiler alert it was not the
training planes and it's like
everybody's like Jason thanks for
bringing down the whole room now but
it's like a debbie downer it's a we're
doing so well the wolf is like war so no
but that's one of the things it's like
because they did not human actions are
always going to be this seems bad I
don't want it to be that give me another
alternative to it and I'll buy it you
had to get your employees off that you
have to get your employees to be
suspicious not to be paranoid not to
every time they get an email like this
is trap what's going home you know it's
like no I don't want them tackling the
FedEx guy okay
it's like because sometimes that might
be me okay and I'm fragile i bruise
easily okay but they at least need to
report they at least need to report
those suspicious activities they need to
have a chain of command if you're if you
don't have an extension or an email
address that every single one of your
employees know to report you don't have
a security program how are they going to
report that I'd literally remember one
time I'm in Amman Jordan and I'm robbing
this Bank and the managers frantically
telling me I told this story many times
I know but it's still pertinent I was
plugging in a USB Drive and she's
telling me it's like sorry you can't
plug that in and I'm like you're right I
shouldn't be plugging this in it's like
you should talk to someone I should I
know I'm supposed to be doing that but
if you don't know I'm should be doing
that well then you should definitely
tell someone I'm doing that it's like
five machines because she didn't know
who
oh she did not know what to do if I
would have gone in with the ski mask in
the shotgun I would have had a very bad
day because they are trained for that
they weren't trained for a guy with this
a suit and a USB Drive please answer
that until my busy it's like so you tell
them that you show them how they need to
act how they need to be suspicious and
not just like saying oh it's got to be
this way it's got to be this person
I mean someone I've had I think I know
that least three different enterprises
that I have pictures of me up on their
stock go on warning if this guy shows up
it's like you know call the collar cops
it's like and I'm like well done you've
protected your facility against me all
the other thousands of people coming
after you fair game but I'm not gonna
I'm not getting in it's like so you've
got to make sure that they understand
just be suspicious it's like just ask
questions don't take everything for
granted to that person supposed to be
there or that person is really from IT
plugging in a cable to check the USB
writes on your mobile device charging
policy it's like let them question