this guy god I met this guy in Tampa
they go b-sides they go your granny know
and then they go you're gonna keynote
with Kevin Johnson I'm like are you
kidding me oh I kind of fell in love
with this guy keep cuddles well I always
want to say about Kevin is Kevin's a
friendly competitor and he goes no he's
not he is a wonderful colleague I can't
we had a love fest earlier today we're
going to get teary we love each other to
death
Kevin is one of my idols in this
industry he's been around forever he was
an instructor for years calling me old I
got as much gray hair almost as you he
was just for men he's been he's been
running secure ideas for the past we
nine years in August nine years they
come back year after year we keep having
them I every year I go I don't not gonna
have Kevin that I go I I have to have
Kevin it's it's my it's my hit this year
we've had two Kevin Johnson's the other
Kevin Johnson refers to himself as the
other Kevin Johnson and we always say no
you're our Kevin Johnson this is the
other yeah without further ado please
put your hands together for mr.
professionally evil Kevin Johnson man
so talking about the real Kevin Johnson
who spoke yesterday I'm sitting at my
booth and a gentleman walks up to me and
he said he was being helpful right he's
like don't you speak in five minutes and
I had a moment of panic like oh do
i luckily
Larry who is sitting at the booth with
me he's one of my guys he's like no
Kevin you don't that's the other Kevin
Johnson is like but I'm the other Kevin
Johnson
so I'm Kevin I've been Kevin for 46
years I've been Kevin Johnson for 18
less than that you do the math I'm lazy
so we're going to talk today about
something that is near and dear to my
heart this is something that matters a
lot to me and I hope that you enjoy the
ride but if you don't then you just are
wrong so we're gonna talk about how we
can fix the and I'm gonna use a phrase
now that you're all gonna laugh at
because it sounds like a marketing
phrase but the skills gap that we keep
hearing about right and while I don't
believe that most of the information we
have about the skills gap is true I
believe most of it is marketing crap
from companies that want to sell more
training I do believe that we have some
problems with filling positions we have
some problems with filling positions
with people who are not only qualified
but are actually good people I and one
of the reasons for this in my opinion is
that it's so important is the job that
we do is critical for the future and I
don't mean that to blow smoke up your
rear I mean that because it's it's true
I have two daughters and you'll hear
about my kids if you haven't already I
love my daughters and currently they
still like me
my understanding is as they get older
that will
and then I hope that it then changes
back is my understanding but I love my
two daughters are awesome my wife is
amazing and having kids I just got lucky
they're beautiful kids so they can't be
mine Brenna when she was nine and I've
talked about this on this stage before
Brenna when she was nine had her
identity stolen she was treated at the
local Wolfson's Children's Hospital
which was wonderful they dealt with us
the family and her amazingly and then
about three months after she was in the
hospital they were breached and they
lost the medical data and information
about all of their patients and I part
of me is furious I will acknowledge the
fact that if I ever find the person who
breached Wolfson's and stole my
daughter's data I will probably forget
the ethical part of my title and so but
I got to have a conversation with my
nine-year-old daughter about the fact
that for the rest of her life she was
gonna have to deal with identity theft
that you can google search her social
security number today right and that's a
problem and I and I feel like one of the
main reasons we have that problem is is
that too many organizations either don't
understand why security is important and
or they can't find people who are
willing to fix the problems we see too
many talks I was having a conversation
with a gentleman earlier we see too many
talks about people who stand up here and
talk about I hacked this and I'm awesome
but they don't really talk about this is
how we fix it right and this is what we
do to make it better
okay we also see way too much
information about cool hacks yet as
somebody else said to me this morning
MSO eight oh six seven is still in the
wild and for the people who don't know
vo eight is the year the patch was
released right that patch is almost
older than my kids that's a problem
and we still see it and we can all sit
here and clap ourselves on the back for
being cool hack sores or we can actually
go fix stuff and that's what I want us
to do I want us to fix it and I talked
about this and I used the title the
great explainer because of Richard
Fineman and I never met Richard Fineman
I wish I had he was a physicist way
smarter than I am I'm not that smart I'm
an idiot I barely made it out of high
school I fake it right I I do what I
need to do to make it work but Richard
Fineman if you ever listened to his
presentations his classes if you ever
listen to interviews with him one of the
main things he talks about is how
critical it is for us to share the
knowledge we have that we have to make
other people better because they know us
we have to raise the water line for
everybody so that we float the boats
higher right that's our job that's our
main being when I die which I hope is a
long long time away from now but I will
say every birthday gets closer right
when I die I hope that what people say
about me other than the fact I'm fat and
lazy and funny-looking is that people
learned from me even if all they learned
is what not to do right that's my goal
I am also a greedy capitalist my goals
be protested by the Occupy movement but
that's a different goal pup tents in my
cul-de-sac or something before we really
get started let me tell you a little bit
about myself I'm given like I said I'm a
nerd I am such a nerd I've said this
before but I'm such a nerd that the
bully who used to take my lunch money
still does but he makes a damn good
Subway sandwich
I am the CEO or head nerd of secure
ideas we are a consulting firm right
we're pen testers what does that mean
and why does it impact you guys
it means we're hackers the majority of
what we do for a living and this is
important because of the way I look at
things is break into companies who gave
us permission steal oh sorry steal
stuff by the way pg-13 okay we go with
that we steal stuff and then we show
them how we did it so they can fix the
problems and the reason I mention this
is because it affects my perspective
it's way I talk about things right some
people are getting oh my god did you see
the animal facts breach oh my god yeah I
know
oh my god did you see the speech it was
awesome I mean it wasn't awesome for
them and it wasn't awesome for all but
oh my god was awesome I like this stuff
I nerd out on security right okay so
that's me I'm also Alliance faculty
member I that's kind of fun they have
the world's most concededly named
service ask an expert I always laugh
right they'll get us on those calls like
Kevin will be your expert today like oh
damn I gotta live up to that now I have
a speaker and author I do courses I
taught and wrote the courseware for SANS
Institute I've taught at blackhat
derbycon I like to say that I'm an
international speaker because I taught a
class in Australia once in Canada a few
times right I'm like the Jacksonville
International Airport we have one flight
to Bahamas I told that joke get a
Jacksonville Chamber event this dude got
really pissed he's like we are - at
International Airport I'm like no you're
not
like yes we are I'm like okay great one
question if you can answer with anything
other than Atlanta I will agree you're
an International Airport
where's customs guy you know Sam right
wTF is my project I started that 10
years ago whole bunch of other things
and I'm a nerd
my wife says the the thing I'm about to
talk about is I'm the nerdiest thing
I've ever done I pointed out to her
lychee maybe when I was 26
she doesn't know but I am a member of
the 501st Legion we are a Star Wars
costuming group twelve thousand members
or sixteen thousand members strong
worldwide we build screen accurate Star
Wars costumes and then we wear them to
raise money for charity right I want to
say last year we raised something like
14 million dollars worldwide right so I
thank you but that wasn't me I just want
to be very clear that wasn't me I'm just
one of the nerds in a Darth Vader
costume right that's and I get to do
cool things like go to hospitals and
cheer up kids and and stuff like that so
like for example the picture the Veda
there is me that was an event where they
brought in two or three hundred blind
kids and we let them feel the costumes
so they knew what the characters look
like I'm crying in that helmet right
that's what I get to do I'm building a
Jew baka right now I've been building
Chewbacca for five years and I'm about a
month from being done I am so excited I
will admit that there is wookie hair
everywhere in my house I when I got here
two nights ago not last night night
before I pulled my clothes out of the
suitcase and wookie hair came out with
it so and for the people who don't know
Whoopie hair is just weave hair I own 26
pounds of weave at my house which I
believe is more weave hair than anybody
should own so the best part is once I
finished costume I have to go to a
hairstylist and wear it and have them
me I just want to walk in to Supercuts
that way really I'm here for a haircut
good okay so one last thing about me I
have a sense of humor
please note you might have misheard me I
did not say I have a good sense of humor
I said I have a sense of humor I my
favorite joke which was my favorite joke
last year it's still my favorite joke do
you know why Walmart wasn't hacked
they're not a target exactly I got to
introduce like the C ISO of Walmart at
an event and he wouldn't shake my hand
after I told that joke I said you
weren't hat I thought you had a good
side of the joke
so the last thing I want to point out
and this is my sales pitch for the day
okay time to and after I give you my
sales pitch you'll recognize I'm a sucky
salesperson one if you are a veteran
active duty military or first responder
almost all of our training is free for
you all you have to do is ask we'll give
you a coupon code no no no that's not
don't applaud me I'm not the veteran I
have bad lungs I do say veteran though
because this veterinarian wrote me I
used to say vets if you're a vet and
this guy wrote me and I'll be honest
have you been polite about it I would
have given him the coupon code but he
wrote rude he's like well you probably
won't give it to me because I'm a
veterinarian Mike you're right no that's
the first one second sales pitch if you
are a non-profit charity our services
are free please note I did not say our
services are free for six months I did
not say some of our services are free
our services are free for as long as we
offer the service you have to be an
approved nonprofit charity to be clear
what I mean by approved is I approve you
it's a pretty simple rule don't be a
dick charity Westboro Baptist Church the
people who protest military funerals
they are a federally recognized
nonprofit charity right
that's my sales pitch for the day we're
talking about the problems we're going
to talk about the shoulders of giants
and then how do we move forward
the first problem we have as an industry
we have a skills gap I know I know
marketing but it's true
we have trouble finding people who know
about security we have trouble finding
people who know how to fix the problem I
want to point out that I have quoted two
different articles here from the same
source that are five years apart I think
my only before I suck at math we've had
the skills gap for as long as I remember
Allen Power has been ranting about it at
Congress and now if I was a good guy I
like him but he's been beating the same
drum forever we suck at finding people
who know stuff and the other part of
this slide in my opinion tells you why
we suck at finding people who know this
stuff because what I did is I went out
to a number of training sources last
night because I wanted to get the most
up-to-date information I also wrote my
presentation last night but I wanted to
get the most updated information to take
a six day class and certification is
seven thousand three hundred and seventy
nine dollars who the hell can afford
that I can't and I run a successful
security consulting firm there's no way
and that's not just one source I want to
be very clear
right all of the major training sources
for information security training is
multiples of thousands of dollars to get
in the door we're talking three five and
six day courses posting four five six
seven thousand dollars oh and you got a
travel there right I can't do that I get
calls daily emails daily from people I
want to learn what you do no you don't
okay you do it's awesome I love what I
do I really do love what I do
right how many other people get to say
so I was sitting at work today and I
stole million dollars from a company
it's fun right but how do we learn this
stuff if every single place we go all I
want to do is take money from us and
lots of money I've been raining about
this for years I refer to it my hashtag
because I found out some millennial told
me I needed to have a hashtag so I
created one affordable training because
the reality is training has to be
affordable because if it's not
affordable we can't do it and I'm not
getting political here right we're not
gonna talk about free college and all
that kind and I'm not saying free
college is a bad idea I didn't go to
college I don't know if college is a
good idea right but if we can't afford
to learn it if we can't go to a good
place where we can trust the information
because that's the thing I'm going to
talk about in a second the next slide is
the fact that so many of the source of
information we have that aren't $7,000
are wrong
I saw this article being shared I shot
skipping ahead but I saw this article
being shared on Twitter by lots of
people I respect and it was a blog post
about md5 hashes and I went to the blog
post and the entire description
conversation was about
how to decrypt md5 hashes laughing is
the right reaction to that because you
can't decrypt md5 hashes it's why
they're called one-way hashes it's in
the damn name and I read the article and
I want to be clear I want to be good I
didn't put the article up on a slide
because I want to embarrass the person
who wrote it because I look I don't I'm
a mean guy I am import records and not
divorce court I'm called an asshole
you gotta mention it wasn't divorce
court cuz I'm assuming that happens a
lot in divorce court the defense
attorney I was doing some work shutting
a company down because they were running
those scams you have a virus and the
defense attorney called me an asshole in
the deposition and I don't know what to
say because I was under oath so I said
yes I am I think when I testified the
judge said hey wait maybe you're the
asshole aren't you yes your honor
I don't know what to say to that couple
months I'm testifying for the Department
of Justice on that same case so I'll be
a federally Court recognized asshole I
think this is a con accomplishment right
like it doesn't help arguments with my
wife though cuz she can call me an
asshole and I can't argue it but so but
we I'm not a nice person is what it
boils down to but I didn't want to
embarrass this guy and I go and I look
at the blog and the blog has some really
good information and it has some really
shitty information and then I realize
with the screenshots the person has is
that the tool set the person was using
and I don't know whether that person
wrote the tool set or they use somebody
right like I don't know but the tool set
referred to it as decrypting md5 hashes
I went out I've seen documentation from
major companies that teach information
wrong hell for years Microsoft gave bad
information in their documentation now
Oracle has taken over that title
we teach people badly right how many
people here have gone to college for
computer science how many people here in
college were taught security techniques
and requirements and whatever I'll point
out for the people who don't notice lots
of hands went up for the first question
and I think I saw four hands for the
second question right we're not teaching
it I go into a high school because one
of the things we do at secure ideas is
that we try to push education as a
matter of fact we push it so hard
I own a six-day web pentesting course
that we can't say what it was written
for because that's wrong but you can
look at my resume and we open source the
entire 6 day course
just over a year and a half ago that's
how important we think education is
right and I'm not gonna say that
information is right I'd like to believe
it was right I wrote it and I'm a genius
but we want to make sure the data is out
there another problem we have that
didn't flip I'll walk over here and flip
it no now it flips do you see that it
knew I was coming it waited now to slip
a lot the other problem we have is what
do we teach right I get asked all the
time how do I become you how do I get a
job like you and I I say up here most
people don't even know the path and the
pun is totally intended so the IT nerds
in the room get it I hope because way
too many security people I talk to don't
know how to manage a window system they
don't know how to install software they
know how to pen test right they
downloaded Kali or samurai WTF and they
ran some tools and then they got a job
right I read the threads I won and have
moderated mailing lists and forums and
boards of conversation and I see the
questions right
downloaded this software and I I uh I
don't know how to install it
double-click on it do I double click
with the mouse I've taught classes on
web pentesting where I have literally
had to have a facilitator sit next to a
student so that when they got to the
exercise and the first step in the
exercise was open Firefox the
facilitator could reach over and double
click on the Firefox icon on the desktop
because the person didn't know how to do
that and I was morally bound to not
describe in the exercise steps how to
double click on Firefox and you think
I'm exaggerating we hear all the time
right
yeah I saw it on Twitter just last week
and ranted about it
SMS is insecure so we should remove all
SMS two-factor from our accounts at
least a hundred InfoSec professionals
shared that tidbit last week really we
should remove SMS 2 factor because SMS
is insecure did you recommend another
option no I don't know don't get me
wrong I'm not argue I'm not saying up
here I don't want anybody walking out
here going Kevin's a moron he said SMS
is secure
no I didn't but I will tell you that SMS
two-factor authentication is more secure
than no two-factor authentication right
but we don't understand that well enough
as a community the other problem we have
is where do we go to get into this right
how do I go from being that high school
student or that college kid to be a pen
tester I want to be very clear in my
opinion and since I have the microphone
I'm right
that is not a single step and we talk to
people all the time right hey I'm in
college right now I'd like to be hired
by secure ideas as a penetration tester
my answer is well that's nice too like
it's important to have goals you're not
gonna meet that one because in my
opinion and I will point out that while
it's not I'm right because I have the
mic it's I'm right because I do the
hiring it's secure ideas owners
privilege if you want to be a senior
security consultant secure ideas you
have to have a decade of experience as
an IT admin or a developer because I
don't give a about your ability to
pen test
I don't these people come to me and
they're like oh I wrote a buffer
overflow yeah so did my 9 year old cuz
she read an article on the Internet and
I don't mean to downplay the difficulty
of writing a buffer overflow what I do
mean to downplay why that's so
important what we're supposed to know
how to do is to understand how that
buffer overflow impacts the business
we're consulting for which is why I want
you to have 10 years of experience as an
IT person I want you to know what it's
like to be up at 3 a.m.
fixing the server that you broke let's
admit it
[Music]
and having to fix it by the next morning
I want you to know what it's like to set
up a majordomo mail list yes I'm old
subscribe yourself to it to test it send
the test email sip it worked go home
come back the next day to two and a half
million emails in your inbox because you
were the idiot that subscribed the list
server to the listserv thank you yeah I
found out how many messages it took to
crash exchange but uh right and the
reason I want you to know that is not
just because I want another story to
laugh at you about I do but because I
want you to understand the impact your
recommendation as a security person has
on the business I see it all the time
because I'll tell you one of my jobs we
have this service called SAS tow where
we do advisory for companies and we we
work with developers and things like
that so we read a lot of other companies
pen test reports and let me tell you
right now many many people are morons
writing reports I'm not even gonna argue
the putting your logo on an SS report
does not make it a pen test because if
you think that you're too dumb to learn
but I will argue that telling an
organization that has sequel injection
in their login field how their
clickjacking implementation is not good
enough means you don't understand how
applications work you don't understand
risk you don't understand and that's a
problem right and I'm not claiming I do
I've been a moron for longer than ever
and every day I realize how dumb I
actually am when I got involved in in IT
to become a security person when I
decided I wanted to be a security person
I literally sat down and wrote
a list of the ten things I needed to
know and I'm not a list person but I
wrote down the ten things I needed to
know to call myself an information
security person and I learned one of the
10 and I had a list of 23 things I
needed to learn and I learned one of the
things and I had a list of 45 items I
needed to learn I'm now at a point where
the list is so big I had to buy a new
hard drive okay
I like I like Google Drive because they
haven't limited my list I know less now
percentage-wise than I knew then because
now I know a whole bunch of the I
don't even know I didn't know which
scares me even more because tomorrow
I'll learn four more things I didn't
even need to know I needed to know it's
scary and awesome because I like
learning right the other problem we see
is how do you how do you get a skill set
how do you prove I'm a pen tester right
I know a way hack Amazon works for kevin
Mitnick okay it wasn't Amazon because it
was in like the 30s but uh I might be
exaggerating slightly I do that with
scum right oh yeah I said it
and I've said it before I will talk
about that next do the ethics bullet
right we have to learn and we have to
have a safe place to learn and one of
the things that a lot of people do is I
always capture the flags and I want to
be clear I don't have a problem with
capture the flags that are set up
correctly and authorized okay but I will
tell you that most of the capture the
flag is environments I've looked at
aren't actually relevant to the real
world okay and that's a challenge to
improve them not to bash them but you
need a place to practice
that's why samurai WTF exists it's why
things like the cyber ranges exist I
think it's a good idea to go
get information about environments you
can play with work with your local
schools work with your local companies
if you're not in a security company
let's say you work it Express Scripts
I'm just gonna pick on them because they
were mentioned as one of the sponsors if
I was Express Scripts
and I want to be clear I have no idea if
they do this or not if I was them I
would take one of our development
environments and I would set it up in a
way to allow our people to practice and
test and and learn how to hack it there
in the company set aside build a rules
of engagement all that kind of stuff but
what you're gonna do is you're gonna
build up skillset safely right guess
where you're gonna be able to use that
skill set at your company
now some people recommend bug bounties
I don't not as a place to learn once
you've learned if you want to go out and
join bug bounty programs to practice
that's fine but I don't recommend
learning how to pen test on somebody
else's bug bounty and the reason I say
that is because more than likely you're
going to go out of scope for what the
bug bounty is because you're learning
okay
it's not negative I'm not bashing you
just that's what happens we see it too
often okay and so we got to do it
the other thing we have to do is we have
to learn ethics we as an industry spend
too much time put in people like kevin
Mitnick and chris Roberts up on
pedestals right and we look at these
people saying hey there's three oh my
god he flew a plane sideways right and
we put them on stage we have people who
stand up on stage and talk about the
illegal stuff they did and we all
applaud and cheer them and they go to
the next conference what we should be
doing and I'd like to believe I do but I
can't claim for myself but I believe
what we should be doing is advocating
for people doing things responsibly
people who are working to improve things
because I'll tell you right now if we
don't start being
ethically we're gonna get this shutdown
right and too often I see and I I'm not
talking about this conference because
you all of course are 100 percent
ethical but I go to way too many
conferences where the elevator is broken
by the second day of the conference
because some idiot thought it'd be fun
to play with it or the screens are
messed up or there's 27 extra ATMs that
weren't there at the beginning of the
conference right hey you know what I'm
talking about right we have to really
think about the ethics now I want to
point out that I said ethics not
legalities because there are things that
are legal I don't consider ethical and
we can have that debate if you want and
I won't claim that I don't break my own
ethics because I'll tell you right now
you mess with either of my daughters or
my wife although my ethics just became
really flexible I wouldn't need that
because I love that and I'm not a big
strong guy who can beat your ass
but right and I want to be very clear
that one of the reasons this is so
important to me is because I'm where I
am today because I got to stand on the
shoulders of amazing people and I hope
to be the set of shoulders other people
can stand on and I've put some of the
people that matter to me up here of
course there is a picture of both of my
daughters that's on purpose all right
they're not that young anymore but I've
got people Jason who's my business
partner Jason is amazing I can't tell
you the number of times I go to Jason
and say hey what do you think about this
idea and he centers me he focuses me on
what the right thing to do is people
like Mike poor who I worked for it in
guardians and I grew as a consultant as
a man as a person because of Mike's
leadership
his ability to talk about what was okay
to do and you've got people like James
fields who I worked with at Blue Cross
where I really feel like every single
time I talked to him I left the
conversation a better person I want
every one of us to have that impact on
everybody we interact with if I have a
conversation with you I want to walk
away better I want to walk away smarter
I want to walk away knowing more I will
admit that if you have a conversation
with me
you will leave knowing more even if all
you leave with is knowing more that you
don't ever want to talk to me again that
is more right sorry but this is what we
got to do this is how we need to fix
this right we have to be like these
people right the last person up there
that you may not recognize his Alban
Johnson he's the founder of the 501st
legion right and that's our to Katie
Alvin's daughter was sick she died and
she wanted in our two unit to watch over
her when she was sick and in the
hospital and the astromech builders
built our to Katie and so she now
travels the world raising money for a
variety of charities is why they're up
there right but we have to look at what
we do we have to look at how we interact
and and I've got to be honest and tell
you that very many times I fail at that
I look back at my day and I remember
that conversation I had with a Comcast
person and how many times I use those
words that I won't repeat now
comcast has more recordings of me
cursing at people than anybody else
should but they deserved it but I think
back to how I interact with people I
think back how I interacted with the
customers I think about how I talked to
people outside and there are days where
I look back on it and I'm ashamed of
what I did and what I said and how I
worked and I think to myself I got to do
better and there are days if I may say
so myself that I look back on and I
think man I'm really happy with me today
I did good I helped people I felt like I
taught people I feel better about me and
my goal in life is for that second day
to happen way more often than the first
day but the thing we have to remember
and this is something I've struggled
with for years is it failing one time
isn't a sign of failure it's failing to
get up and be do better the next time
and I'm gonna fail again I'll tell you
right now there's a good chance that on
the way to the airport
somebody's gonna piss me off
because it's the summer and all the
people who don't know how to travel or
traveling just take off your damn shoes
I don't have to do that anymore anxiety
is a pre-check but now we have the
people who don't know they're not
supposed to take off their shoes in that
line I don't understand why that
irritates me as much as it does put them
back on but I tried right
and my goal is for you to try the same
way yourself so what do we do
I've talked about it a lot I've talked
about the problem I've rambled on said
some stupid jokes I'll say some more
stupid jokes we have time I'm full of
stupid jokes
for lots of things my eyes are brown so
what do we do in my opinion the way we
fix this okay and this is huge
I admit that right I have outlined four
thousand different things that are wrong
I might be exaggerating slightly I've
talked about the fact that our education
system is failing us right we are
teaching people how to use Java applets
in college and then beating them up when
they use Java applets on our stuff
except for Cisco because for some reason
they get away with it why do we accept
that from John Cisco I don't understand
that's it separated or you as you know
how you can tell it recognized at Cisco
admins workstation there's 13 different
versions of Java running for the various
two right yeah damn it I love those
machines because I can hack them better
but
we we've I've outlined that we have an
education problem I've outlined that we
have a price problem we have a skills
gap whatever we want to call it we got
to come up with a better name because
skills gap has become the same thing as
like zero day protection have you seen
that marketing flaw zero day protection
now I know at the market at the vendor
meant they meant they would protect you
before you knew the vulnerability
existed but in my head zero day
protection a zero day
right oh no I'm sorry negative day
protection is what they refer to it as
zero day is a vulnerability exists and
we don't have a patch right we all agree
on that definition so a negative day in
my book is the vulnerability doesn't
exist I'm here to announce security as
new product it's negative day protection
it's an agentless software list
controlled there's not even a dashboard
we guarantee that we will protect all of
your systems from vulnerabilities that
don't exist right done that's kind of
like the PCI counsel saying that no PCI
compliant organization has ever been
breached have you heard that do you know
why they can honestly say that because
being breached makes you out of
compliance with PCI like it's automatic
so they can absolutely say if you are
compliant you weren't breached semantics
it's so much fun I should have been a
marketing guy no I shouldn't have been a
marketing guy I mean the wrong person to
put in front of a group and say hey buy
our stuff but because I'm the birds like
you wanna buy our stuff this you do you
don't know maybe you do I don't know but
we've also talked about how do we build
this up and in my answer my opinion
the answer is mentoring now I talked to
somebody earlier and he said and I agree
with him that the term mentoring is
overused way too much he's right we
talked about it but we don't really
define it
your job your job every person in this
room job is to mentor other people I'd
like you to be formal but informal
mentoring is just as important you
should constantly be teaching people
stuff you should constantly be answering
questions you should constantly be
learning yourself so that you can what I
like to see and what we recommend quite
often and what we help implement quite
often is mentoring programs where we
will take a security team and we will
have the mentor the IT people the
developers the QA people the project
management people we have them teach
them and show them and guide them into
what security means because it ties to
what I said earlier that the way to make
sure somebody has the right skill set is
to give them a background in building
things in making things in supporting
things if I can go to my developers and
show them what security means and help
guide them at building out a secure
product right the next time I need
somebody on my security team I have this
staff already I have the people that I
know that not only do they know what I
want them to know because I showed them
but they already work with me even if I
don't pull them into my team even if I
just continue to work with them as part
of the development team or the QA team
or the project management team or the
management team they will do better at
security and we see this I want to be
blunt we have a product we sell I'm not
trying to sell you I am I'm always
trying to sell but we have a product we
sell called SATA the strategic
application security training and
advisory program it's literally a
program where we mentor your development
staff we mentor your security staff on
an ongoing basis right now don't get me
wrong as a greedy capitalist I will tell
you come sign up pay us we'll do it
but there's nothing patentable Todd not
sure if that's a real word but let's go
with it right for this mentoring program
anybody can do it you sit there and you
work with people what we do and I'm
describing our product because I believe
it's the right way to do it I'm also
going to describe it in enough detail
you need to do it yourself and not buy
it from us okay
I'd rather you buy it from us but first
every two weeks there's an hour to to
our live session where we sit down with
whatever people are able to sign in and
we teach them various topics of security
so today we'll talk about using
parameterize queries and sequel
injection and blah blah blah blah blah
right tomorrow next week or two weeks
from now we'll talk about how to work
within a web app firewall and why it
doesn't solve all the problems and how
to tune it and what-have-you right
two weeks from then we'll talk about I
am and it's two fact right whatever okay
then the rest of the time one those
sessions are recorded and my answer to
you and I know many people don't like
this I don't like being recorded okay
but when you do a learning session
record it and the reason you should
record it is one you should review it so
that you verify how you do it that you
did the right thing that you can improve
yourself two by recording it allows
people to review it at their own pace
right so that helps second you have
regular open office hours where a person
who knows what they're doing that's
critical is available to hold somebody's
hand as they're doing something
themselves whether it's hey we got this
report from Barrett code and we don't
understand what this finding means or
hey we have this new thing we're
implementing and we're not sure if we're
doing it correctly or hey we're doing
this test this is we're building a unit
test and we need help making sure it's
right whatever it is you have open up
ten hours end you have a regular
communication path outside of those open
office hours we use slack
we have a slot channel that the people
who have subscribed sign in to and we
give them and we guarantee them a
response time of like I think it's 20
minutes you don't have to do the
guarantee we're a paid service so we
have to do an SLA right but you want to
make sure that you don't desert whatever
communication channel you built like a
lot of people I see they'll do it by
email if you have a question to email me
and I'll answer your question and then
they just get busy and they ignore the
emails right or they think I'll get to
that later I do that I regularly will
see an email in the morning and think to
myself okay I'm ready to know something
I'll work with this this afternoon and
then what happens is like 3 o'clock in
the morning call dammit I gotta get that
eat right like so don't do that ok and
then make sure that the other direction
works as well so as I'm talking to these
developers about how we test stuff for
them we do screen shares as we're pen
testing so that they can see what we're
testing how we're testing it right
things like that at the same time we
regularly talk to them about the
technologies they're evaluating we talk
to them about the technologies there oh
you're using vagrant now oh you're using
Crippen idiots oh you're using em
whatever mustard seed libraries or
whatever I made that one up probably
exists but right oh we're using Gatsby
oh cool I've not used Gatsby yet let me
look at that look at write whatever okay
you should be learning as much from them
as they're learning from you if you're
not in applications fine
mentors the helpdesk person who has a
dream of being a I'm gonna say
full-blown IT person I hoped as people
our IT people but we're without this
person work with the asset management
person work with the project manager who
has to evaluate whether or not that
project can go forward and we can use it
or what have you because way too often
we ignore the business side in these
learning engagements we focus on the
Nerds why because we talked to her it's
fine right we relate to the nerve
but I'll tell you right now that project
manager she was going to determine
whether you get budget next year right
that branch manager district manager
that you eighty person whatever title
you want to come up with one of the best
pen testers I ever worked with one of
the best pen testers I ever worked with
was from the help desk and her job
before she was on the help desk where
she was a hostess at a restaurant right
and she was one of the best pen testers
I ever worked with and the reason she
was one of the best pet investors in my
opinion other than the fact she was a
genius but it was also because and this
sounds weird but the four or five years
or whatever it was that she was a
hostess standing in front of the public
telling they had to wait for their
dinner she learned how to interact with
people way better than I can write it
says she knew how to talk to people and
not get them angry and give them
information but they weren't gonna like
hearing because let me tell you right
now your company's been working on that
application that they're deploying next
week for six years and you're about to
tell them that the underlying framework
they developed is insecure you're not
going to be popular at the next change
control meeting right been there done
that I have the t-shirt right they learn
how to talk to people that's what we
have to do we have to mentor we have to
show people how we do this so I've
outlined how we do it and I want to be
very clear the way we do it very little
cost and I don't mean very little cost
to the customer it is very little cost I
want to say it's 1,500 to $3,500 a month
depending on how many people you put
through the program right and the reason
I point that out is we are a consulting
firm the only reason every two weeks I'm
able to pay payroll is because people
hire me we are a cash flow business we
don't have venture capital
we're not a unicorn we're not IPO it the
only way I pay payroll every two weeks
is people hire me if I can afford to
have somebody full-time mentoring people
at a subscription rate of a $1,500 a
month you can do it inside your
organization just as cheaply right
seriously it's not expensive to help
people there is a cost one of the costs
is your time and your time is valuable
what is it
86,400 seconds a year a day or whatever
it is right and every second you waste
I'm not gonna sing I sing horrible I
sing so bad my grandfather had to leave
church when I was a kid because he was
laughing I have no skills you should see
me dance I only do it in a Star Wars
costume and it's funny gomorian guard
right do this help people work with
people if you have questions I'm at the
end of my time I believe I believe but
if you have questions please feel free
to chat them out I'll answer them into
the future if you want to build a
mentoring program yourself yes obviously
hire me I'll do it but if you want to
build a mentoring program yourself if
you need help designing and guiding your
organization to do what I believe you
should do call me because I do believe
that I have been blessed beyond what I
deserve and it is my responsibility to
help other people succeed that's what I
want okay thank you very much for your
time
[Applause]
I start off real quick there
you