model and so I want to set the stage so
that when you see that you aren't taken
aback because it is going to be a slight
change of pace and a topic but it came
out of the research that I did for this
main talk so I want to introduce it and
then I want to get feedback from you all
so talk to me afterwards DM me do
whatever tell me it's a terrible idea
come it's the best idea ever I am gonna
put it forward because I want feedback
rate so let's get started you know the
background I do red teaming the key
thing for me that motivates me to talk
is I'm anti nihilism anti security
theater anti wasted time and more
importantly I am Pro risk-based security
and what I mean by that is I believe
that risk can be identified I believe it
can be it can be measured and that I
believe it can be handled in any number
of ways that we manage risk I am against
the whole sky is always falling
mentality that we often have in this
industry and so that's why I speak
that's why I teach is because I want
this to be a positive experience and I
think we can make a positive difference
as on the side I love Islay whiskies I
just put that up there so that if you
enjoy the top feel free to buy me a shot
of Eileen whisky if you dislike the talk
and you see me drinking some you can
slap it out of my hand and I'll know
that you did it enjoy it just make sure
it's not a glass cup or something that
could get that could get hairy quickly
so let's talk about why you should have
a red team first and then we'll walk it
back a little bit and we'll talk about
why it shouldn't be special so you know
the first thing you'll notice there are
a lot of caveats in this talk and this
first slide is no different is the red
team isn't for everybody if you're still
getting wrecked you know in the pen test
in the first 24 hours you don't need a
red team you probably don't even need
pen testing
that point you need you need a base
security program but let's say you move
past that and you're not getting rekt in
in your standard pen test anymore you
have a sock or blue team that needs to
be challenged that needs to involve red
team's are great for doing that because
they can simulate what they're actually
going to see and it can help them
improve their their time to detection it
can fine-tune their processes and they
can simulate what you what attackers are
actually gonna do against you over a
long over a long term period of time you
especially need a red team if there are
full apts in your threat model and you
can use these to justify the security
decisions that you're already making and
asking for but people are saying no to
you you bring in the red team you say
look look what happens when we don't
have this or when we don't do this or
when we don't have these policies in
place and people say okay we understand
now so you know oftentimes red team's
want to be special so I come from a
penetration testing background and I
know pen testers we think we're special
we think we're the hotness because we're
often treated like we are and so we can
go to our heads we dislike using
corporate anything we think we're above
it we want to manage our own
infrastructure because we do specialized
things and we can avoid oversight and
accountability because we are managing
our own stuff and sometimes we think
we're unhackable and the rules don't
apply to us and so you know one thing
that one thing that I want to start out
with is is some stories I have to hear
that I'm allowed to talk about I always
want more so the first one was talking
to some folks at AWS and they have seen
groups that do penetration testing
consulting see they're taught their
infrastructure compromised and used to
attack their clients and so if that
client sees attack traffic
coming from those AWS instances they are
able to differentiate between is and an
actual attacker or is it the Consulting
Group another one that I really like is
I was talking to someone at a major
manage security service provider and
they had an incident happen and they
went and investigated that incident and
it turns out that there was a pen test
group who had added a new domain admin
to the to the domain but what they had
done is they had used a leet-speak
version of the company's name and so
what the MSSP was able to do was to go
look through all of their other clients
domains and identify every single place
this consult this consultancy had been
and it turned out they were using a
similarly speak password and so we know
that pin testers can get lazy and pen
testers often the ones that are going
into red teams eventually and so we need
to protect against ourselves and what we
know is some of our our own kind of own
bad behavior that we can fall into so
first thing I want to ask is who here
has ever stood up you know to take him
down a rule on a firewall because they
needed to do testing and then forgot to
re-enable that firewall rule when they
were done ok so yeah ok a few people
here and everybody else is lying you
know anybody that's never touched the
firewall and I've never got it right the
first time and it's always been right
and how many people here can tell me
unequivocally that any system that they
manage that they're responsible for is
currently not compromised has never been
compromised
they've never clicked an email they
shouldn't have and they currently are
not putting their organization at risk
in any way anybody want to raise their
hand trust me you will get hired on the
spot if you raise your hand if you are
telling the truth at you raise your hand
you
are the best person here to talk to who
here has ever asked of their blue team
or if they do consulting why don't they
just do this why don't they just
implement a privileged access manager
why don't they just you know remove
local admin off of all the systems
anybody ever say why don't they just do
that in their head or out loud I'm just
thinking yeah so I'm going to talk about
why that idea of why don't they just is
one of the the most detrimental things
for our industry so these are the
reasons why I think that your red team
shouldn't be special is that shadow IT
happens hackers can get hacked and then
there's a lack of empathy that can come
from all of that so you'll remember that
I said at the beginning of my talk that
I'm gonna be talking about something
else called the Red King maturity model
and this is where I'm going to just
quickly introduce it like I said I don't
want it to be jarring the first time I
gave this talk I saw all these confused
looks so I'm gonna preface it a lot of
thing I'm gonna talk about this you'll
also notice that it's the darker blue
between the other slide so that's your
that's your key to know that I'm talking
about the red key maturity model and
this came out of the research I did for
this talk and it's really about helping
organizations identify what is right for
them should they be having penetration
testing should they be having red
teaming should they have to be having
full-blown adversarial simulations all
the time so there's a spectrum of what
you need as an organization and a great
question that somebody asks when I first
postulated this was what should drive
that testing should it be the
organizational preparedness such as how
built-out is the sock how developed as
the IR team or should it be the threats
in the threat model do they actually
have a PPS and so I'll answer those
that's an interesting question that I'll
answer a bit later so now notice the
color is changing we're back into the
the main talk so the first reason why I
don't believe
that red team should be as special as I
think they are is shadow IT so that
happens when red teams or penetration
testing teams manage their own
infrastructure they you know they spin
it up for their their c2 management or
for their fishing engagements whatever
it might be and they're often just given
free rein to do that in AWS digital
ocean or wherever it is and there's not
any oversight there's no auditing or
logging of what's happening of who's
doing what I can tell you that I've
worked with or been at multiple
penetration testing outfits where we
have the same path where we all use the
same password to log into a system that
we test from while we're out there on
our closeout calls telling folks you
should be using all this complicated
password rotation software as doing that
for you we're all logging into the same
fishing server using the same username
and password with with no
non-repudiation over time you have
configuration drift as you have to open
up firewall rules to allow you know
maybe specific types of c2 traffic back
because there's there's weird outbound
rules on the on the organization that
you're attacking or internally if you're
doing internal testing and so you can
get configuration drift over time where
and you forget to go back and modify and
put those into a more secure state and
in the end red teams aren't IT
departments I have an offensive guy I
will admit to you that they're mostess
admins can are better sysadmin than I am
I can find they're the few things that
they do wrong and make turn those into a
whole incident but that doesn't mean
that I can do their day-to-day job nor
should I try I should work on owning my
offensive skills because red team's
can't they can't test and help with
remediation and continue to hone their
skills and build new infrastructure and
maintain that new infrastructure and do
security monitoring on that
infrastructure once they've set it up
and whatever else you can think of that
a red team needs to do that's a lot and
that's what we're currently asking when
we don't put parameter
around how red teams should operate when
it comes to managing their own
infrastructure or the fact that we're
even letting them manage the majority of
their own infrastructure so who believes
that by being a good hacker that also
means you're a good defender cool okay
oh we got one back there calculator so I
I do believe that in the you know where
we're headed we do need to have
defenders that are better at doing
offensive stuff so we need sock analysts
who when they put out a new new rule or
a new playbook they're able to go test
it themselves they're not depending on
the red team to get to it three months
down the line so we need blue team
members that have offensive offensive
capabilities and we also need offensive
folks to understand how the defensive
folks are thinking that makes them
better at their job and so but as it
stands now being a good hacker does not
automatically make you a good defender
it can be difficult if there isn't a
division of systems that are being used
to tell is somebody testing or are or is
their account actually compromised so if
you have a tester who uses one single
laptop maybe that laptop has a VM on it
with the corporate image that they use
to check your email and all of that if
that whole system is compromised can you
confidently as a blue team say that that
you can notice when the activity that
they do off of that asset differs from
the activity that they do for their
day-to-day so the testing activity that
they do can you confidently say that you
can identify when that starts to look
malicious because they already do kind
of both of those things and then there's
there's this mentality that comes from
all this so when you're constantly doing
mic drop pen tests when you're
constantly delivering the bad news you
aren't used to having bad news come to
you you don't want to be told that
you're doing it wrong you can you can
get a little conceited
your skills and so this mentality that
comes out of out of having attackers or
offensive minded folks who aren't ever
checked by the organization leads to a
lack of empathy and I know it because
I've been there so this is me speaking
from personal experience how many times
I've said the term just do this and I
have no context of what that
organization is going through even
though I do internal red teaming now
it's just now that I understand how
cumbersome a corporate asset is when you
have to you know login to privileged
access manager just to get a password to
get into a proxy to try to get outbound
and you still get blocked going to a
site that you have to do for your job
and your system runs you know slow as
all get-out because it's running three
different types of any virus that aren't
actually achieving their goal once
you've experienced that you can start to
have an empathy when you say just do
this just turn on this new feature just
buy this new type of software because
you yourself are going to have to deal
with the consequences of that so when
you have to deal with the consequence
you think twice about what you recommend
and you think of more creative ways of
implementing solutions to the problems
that you identify so we need to balance
security with usability also when it
comes to things such as building out the
infrastructure you you have to interface
with the various groups whether it's
getting a new subnet for yourself
because you want to be isolated from the
rest of the network to do testing but
you don't want to go out to AWS and do
that you want to keep it internal you
excuse me sorry my brain just skipped a
beat there so if you have to do
something like that if you have to get a
VPN stood up for your your team so that
you can test from the various parts of
the world that you might be in where you
might be on site for an engagement but
you still need to potentially be
monitoring stuff
another location so you can facilitate
that using something like a VPN you have
to work with the VPN team if you need
the blue team to not monitor the
outbound traffic that you have coming
out of your subnet because you don't
want them to notice your activity before
you actually do it against the rest of
the organization you have to work with
them all of that requires you to build
relationships and all of those
relationships are critical when it comes
to getting things remediated and so if
you the only time you're ever talking to
folks is when you're telling them that
their baby is ugly they're gonna hate
you
but if you can if you are having to work
with them and build those relationships
when you tell them that you're their
baby is ugly they're gonna take it a lot
better and you're already gonna have
that that rapport built and so in the
end I think red team's really need to
take their own medication their own
medicine medication sounds a little too
clinical thanked their own medicine cool
so let's talk about solutions and what's
not the answer is to say well there's
this weird guy and the security
conference I went to once and he was
like you're not special stop thinking
you're special so here's a corporate
asset just like everybody else
go forth and test they're not a admin on
that box that can't even stall VMware
they can't do anything and you're
telling them to go test that is a recipe
for disaster
they aren't thinking anything done and
they're not going to provide you with
any reasonable result the other option
is is also the kind of other extreme is
also not a good option like well there
was a strange guy this conference and he
said you shouldn't use a corporate asset
so here's a shiny new MacBook and spend
if anything you want at AWS I won't we
won't worry about it show us you're
worse also not set up for success based
on everything else that I I hope I've
made clear throughout this talk so far
and then this last one is should we
should all know that it's bad but you
know we still see it pretty often in our
industry so what is a good approach so
I'm going to talk about good
approaches from a general standpoint and
then from a technical standpoint so
first have red team's lead by example if
you are as a red team recommending and
pushing your organization to doing
things like infrastructure as code so
that it can be auditable then the
infrastructure that you stand up should
be infrastructure as code you should be
already leading the way with using
things like terraform or docker or
whatever your whatever you're doing that
you want to see the rest the
organization do you can be that example
and you will need you will need
exceptions like I said you can't just
give somebody a corporate asset and
expect them to do their work their
offensive work so there are gonna be
exceptions which they'll talk about
I do recommend keeping data on internal
infrastructure I put that in quotes
because some people will be like what
about if we're hybrid and use all these
cloud words and stuff like I don't care
whatever you consider your internal
infrastructure keep it on that and then
one thing that I love is work to allow
current risk owners to keep owning that
risk so when it comes to for example
having a VPN for your Red Team if
there's already a team inside your
organization that builds VPNs manages
them and and is owns the risk of having
that that exposure let them keep owning
that the last thing I want is somebody
yelling at me because I did something
wrong I might be like well knows the VPN
guys they gave us the VPN they said it
was all good then I can I don't have to
worry about dealing with any fallout if
something goes wrong because I have
these different groups that have already
thought about it and decided if they
they're gonna own that risk so from a
technical standpoint Institute
principles of least common mechanism so
this is where we started to get into
exceptions so most folks at our
organization they have one laptop if you
have a red team they should probably
have two they should have a
a set that they do all of their email
and there I am and all that on and then
they should have a testing laptop where
their corporate credentials never touch
that thing maybe they have a specific
testing domain account if they ever need
to start from a point of assumed domain
compromised at whatever level and you
give them that user so if you suddenly
start to see that testing account going
into places that has never been or in
areas of the network that are not
currently in scope for an assessment
then that can raise a red flag but if
you were to have given them the
corporate you say use your corporate
account to do everything then you aren't
going to be able to differentiate as a
blue team between when they're doing
offensive testing then if that account
is actually compromised mediated data
transfer so because you have these two
separate context you need a way of
getting things like screenshots packet
captures whatever it might be between
the more risky context of the of the
testing asset and the corporate asset
and the corporate kind of context so
using something like secure email or box
or some type of file transfer system
where you can log and monitor how data
is going from one context to another so
something in the middle not just letting
them use the USBs and drag them to drag
that stuff back and forth and then apply
principles of least privilege so you
know on your on their testing laptops
well first off you know any number of
times I've been on an engagement and
I've said well you shouldn't have
everybody being a local admin the same
should go for testers on your on their
testing laptops they should have the
ability to be admin but their default
user should be a low privilege user and
they they know the admin password so
when it's time to install stuff do you
know put a network card in for misko's
mode they have the ability to do that
but from the get-go they're starting at
a lower
context in case there is compromised in
case they download some exploit and they
don't review it carefully enough and it
ends up popping their box along with the
box that they're trying to pop during
the assessment so hopefully these good
ideas have good outcomes in the general
good stuff that will come from it is as
a red team you'll better understand
infrastructure policies and procedures
when you understand the the massive
mountains that folks have to climb to
get soar an infrastructure in place
you'll start to understand where folks
are likely to try to circumvent those
and this could be can be some of the
first areas that you look when you're
performing an assessment you will start
to build relationships with the blue
team and with the other more defensive
and management aspects of the
organization so when it comes time to
ask them to remediate something you're
already you're already friends you
already see yourself as being on the
same team again what I love offloading
risk to other folks that aren't me that
isn't my team really like that and then
you might notice a theme just for good
measure I throw it in again you build
relationships because I think security
is really about building relationships
so that you you can you see yourself as
the same team and not as an antagonistic
relationship where you're always trying
to one-up each other technically this is
part of a defense-in-depth strategy
we're always recommending that to the
folks that we're consulting with or to
our blue team's if we're internal so we
should be performing defense in depth
when you start differentiating between
these these contexts of testing versus
regular activity it lets you utilize the
corporate apparatus to log monitor and
differentiate between malicious and and
good and good activity and in the end it
lets red teams do what they do best
focus on doing offensive stuff that
wants to manage their infrastructure
they don't have to worry about risk they
just get to hack stuff and as a
Kaymer that is my utopia of having less
meetings less dealing with my
infrastructure and I just get to just
get the poem babe that would be the
ideal future so you'll notice it's dark
blue so I'm gonna talk real quick about
an idea that came out of this research
the red team maturity model so this is
how I see a progression of the types of
testing that an organization can have
you know you start with third party
penetration testing maybe it becomes
more it becomes more continuous more
repetitive and then you get a internal
penetration testing team and then maybe
that turns into an internal red team and
then that red team can then turn into
something that's doing ongoing atmos
aerial threat simulations so I use these
as the indicators to help you identify
where you are in that progression so
what is your saw capability what are the
skill sets of the people that you have
in the offensive capabilities at your
organization what is what do you do you
have the ability to have threat Intel
you know I see folks who want to do red
teaming but they have no threat Intel so
folks are just scouring the news and be
like oh this is a cool hat let's see if
my organization is vulnerable to this
that's not an efficient way that doesn't
help your blue team build defenses
against known threats so you need to
have threat Intel that you can feed to
the red team so they can do accurate and
realistic testing so here's an example
of looking at based on your sock
capabilities what where you might fall
within the maturity model so you know if
you're just doing third party
penetration testing you might not have a
sock at this point and that's okay but
as you start to do continuous third
party penetration testing it should
become a function of IP it might still
be unform alized
and people at least know who to call
when they see certain things go wrong
and then let's jump all
down to a red team your socks absolutely
needs to have good coverage throughout
the organization there's no point in
having a red team delete hats
if the sock can't go back and be like
well we didn't catch it
but we could have if we knew what to
look for and here are some of the things
that we can look forward because we have
the logs we we have the auditing and all
of that in place it also makes the red
team it lets them do more complex
engagements so they can actually test
play books and how the sock responds
they can even use how response is done
to further their attacks there there
have been engagements that I am familiar
with where folks actually caused an
incident to get an IR team involved and
they somehow get themselves to be that
IR team and then they further their
attack that way they use the playbook to
elevate privilege and so unless you have
a playbook in place for the various
types of instance that you might have
then it doesn't the red team can't go as
far and can't continue to test those and
so this is an example of how you can
mature based on where your sock is and
it one more example
to give you an idea of that is the types
of testing that you might see at these
different stages so you know when you
have those first few stages you have a
lot of is scanning based it's overt it's
loud and fast and these are just your
general pen tests and your general
assessment when I was doing consulting
before I went internal I would have I
would have folks who were getting a pen
test done once a year for we had a scope
of one week maybe two if we were lucky
saying hey we want you to stimulate an
apt we want you to go low and slow I
know you understand you have it because
one week and I have to first get
familiar with your entire network as to
identify where the goods are because you
refused to tell me even though we only
have one week and you want me to be as
stealthy as possible
so understanding where you sit here is
important for the type of testing
that you asked asked for and so if
you're still just doing one pin test you
know a year then you probably don't want
somebody trying to go low and slow you
want them to have breadth of their
findings as you start to get to an
internal red team those exercises should
be informed by threat Intel you
shouldn't just be doing the latest
greatest hack you should be saying okay
we have these known adversaries and we
can map them to this you know maybe
you're using a tack or something like
that we can map them these TTP's over to
attack and we will take those and we'll
try to use them ourselves
as a red team to attack our organization
and so yeah so this is this is an
example again all these slides will be
available on my github or they are
they've been there for a little bit now
if you want to go look at it in more
detail so I told you that I had a really
good question asked of me when I when I
first came out with this idea of the Red
Team maturity model and they asked why
tie the maturity model to preparedness
so how prepared is the stock have
repaired his threat Intel instead of
actual threats because if they have a
pts in their environment shouldn't they
be actually simulating a PT's yeah they
should but they aren't ready we we have
so many organizations that are behind
where they need to be and so what that
means is they need to level up quickly
they need to make those investments so
that they can get to internal red
teaming they can get to internal
adversary simulations so I kind of went
back and forth when I was first coming
up with this and saying how do you
measure where you need to be and I do
believe right now at least it needs to
be based on the preparedness so you
aren't just as a red team you are just
wrecking the blue team pointing fingers
laughing and then doing that over and
over again because you aren't starting
out with kind of the basic things that
they need to be overly catch and the
basic responses that they need to have
so you'll notice it's back to regular
blue I'm gonna wrap it up so this idea
that red team shouldn't be special is
probably not popular among operators you
know I'm an operator myself I know I
like to feel special
I like to do you know headshot pin tests
those type of things and I don't want to
do anything that's going to kind of tie
my hands a little bit but we need to
take our own medicine and we need to
start to build relationships with the
folks that we have to work with to make
our organizations better and so some
things I hope to do in the future is map
this the Red Team maturity model to
attacks because attack is the hotness
right now and I think that could help
kind of push it if you have ideas for
the Red Team maturity model other ways
that I haven't even thought of that I
could I can better recommend to help
folks understand where they are along
that spectrum of the type of testing
they need to have please come talk to me
I'm by no means that we're the be-all
end-all of this type of thought and so I
depend on a community of folks who know
more about certain things that I haven't
learned yet so please come talk to me
this is my information VM stay open and
this is where you'll find this
presentation along with some other ones
I've given any questions yes right yeah
so so the question is is there a level
zero to this for example if you still
have XP with already P exposed to the
Internet you know do you even need
scanning and so answer to that is yes
there is but I want to focus on the
maturity model on offensively like
whatever offensive stuff do you need and
I would argue that before that you need
somebody to come in and help start to
build a security program do things like
vulnerable
management if your pen test is your
vulnerability management program then
your vulnerability management program is
way more expensive than it needs to be
the the license for any number of
scanners even if it's you can only put
it on one box you can't get like some
cloud scanner or whatever with agents
deployed across your network if even it
was just on one laptop that you have to
maintain that's less expensive than
buying a pen test that's going to just
run a scanner against you and then wreck
you and point fingers and laugh so I do
I do think there absolutely is a level
zero so so that's it that's a great
question and another thing that you kind
of said it makes me think is is when we
I don't know if actually want to call it
a maturity model I'm thinking about
making it more like mist in the sense of
of you can kind of choose where you land
throughout all these different parts of
it because I think instead of it
because I don't want folks to have a
goal of getting to adversary simulations
because some organizations never need to
do that if you if you run a small you
know local business you might you might
only need to go up to you know
continuous third party penetration
testing and I want folks to feel like
that's okay based on based on the
threats in the throught model so I have
to find a way of doing that better and
if anybody has feedback always I really
welcome that yeah any other questions
yes
[Music]
yeah thank you for that and so yeah so
the comment was that it can be difficult
if you will feel like they have to go
zero to 100 and they can throw their
hands up and then feel disheartened and
I really don't want that I want folks to
to always have hope as you know I try to
be a positive person when it comes to
this work and so doing anything that can
help folks see a see a positive future
it's something that I want to contribute
to so thank you for that any other
questions
thank you everybody