my math right that makes August older
than Bitcoin I have no idea what that
means
it's not as profitable as Bitcoin but I
thought was important to mention
okay so what's what's the problem that
August tries to solve right like what
why would you use it why does it even
exist so the core problem is that
there's lots of situations where you
want to edit configuration files
programmatically meaning you're writing
scripts via the bash script or some
Python code Ruby code C code what have
you and as part of that you need to
fiddle some configuration settings
somewhere and as an example if you look
at at this little problem here yeah sshd
config you want to turn off root logins
and you're like yeah stand back I know
regular expressions I know saved and
yeah you come up with this which works
great until you realize that the number
of spaces before the yes could be
variable right some people Pratap's
there some people put five spaces there
doesn't work
sorry before the advances nights
and so yeah you come up with a slightly
more complicated sane thing to catch
that case then you realize Oh besides
yes and no you know there's a bunch more
options that people can set with the
permits route login you want to get rid
of all of them so 10 minutes later
you're at this beauty here and you're
like wow we're done right everything
works you do a little prep just to check
and then this happens right like some
and that's that's not a small annoying
problems that yeah that you encounter
when you do that and if you have to do
enough of those it gets really really
annoying so in a way you can think of
Argos as as a repository of yeah all the
knowledge that you have to have all
these stupid little things you need to
know when you want to do something like
yeah changing the route locking
configuration for now at the core of the
problem or what makes this it's really
really interesting is that there's a
bazillion different file file formats
for configuration files you can look at
that as saw the pointless creativity and
at first I sort of looked at it that way
too but there's also yeah configuration
files are user interface in way right
and and they have a mouth feel to them
you're not going to get confused whether
you're editing the httpd.conf or the
nginx
config right like they give the whole
thing a certain feel and so preserving
these configuration files and just
dealing with them as they are it's
really really important to August like
we're not going to go and say oh we'll
just start over everybody change that
evens or other programs that read
configuration because we have this
awesome store that makes much easier to
programmatically change things we have
to live in the world that exists in that
that reality of all these different file
formats is part of that reality another
thing when you when you write code that
needs to fill the configuration files
easy-easy trap to fall into if you think
about it for a moment they're like oh
this is really easy I know exactly how
I'm going to break this down and parse
the file into the data structure that I
can't change the really hard part is
actually making changes cause not just
because of all the hitch cases I had in
that example but also because you need
to you need to preserve a lot of
unimportant detail like people get
really grumpy if you strip out the
comments just because you use they used
your tool to make some small change
people are really attached to the
formatting of their files that's
something that turns up in back reports
when we get that wrong a lot of times
okay there's a long-standing debate in
the contract management world whether
you should even try to to modify
configuration files or whether you
should not just manage files
yeah wholesale like and whenever you
need to make a change you change a
template or the golden copy you have in
source control and that 10 just copy it
Howard I'm not going to get into that
debate I just want to note that there's
there's a lot of cases where that's just
not feasible one example is for example
the let's encrypt folks they they have a
little client that downloads an SSL
certificate for which for your web
server but also edits the configuration
of your web server to have it you know
to have all your virtual hosts use the
new certificate that you just download
it and so they can't go and just yeah
right over your httpd.conf right they
need to go in there and find the exact
places where it defined virtual hosts
and then switch their configuration to
use the let's encrypt is a sale
certificate and they actually use
obvious for fiddling with the hackey for
the Apache config ok so how does it work
as I said yeah we handle configuration
files the way they are yeah there's no
needs to have like special annotations
in them right you don't have to have
comments in them that say don't change
this is managed or something like that
you can totally make changes with augeas
then go back edit the file with VI
changed with Auggie's again that's
that's totally fine and yeah one one
important point of our user steps that
it parts these files into the data
structure and we use the same data
structure for everything that's somebody
or listen obviously that's the thing
with the tree yeah it's exactly that's
that's the tree like you know when we
parse file parse it into into a tree now
talk a little bit more about what the
tree looks like in a minute
I already talked about how how people
get really really grumpy when you screw
up so the unimportant stuff alright if
you're just adding an alias in it see
hosts if it's a hostess all of a sudden
reorder and has no comments anymore
people like that very much
okay and so I hope you're enjoying this
vintage mm I think 9 slide this is what
you can do with OpenOffice from back
then yeah so this is the way to the way
August works is think of the blue box is
the library that gives you an API when
you when you start using it you say load
a bunch of files and what that does is
that the library reads the files you
want to to want to manage and it uses
something called the lens that's this
green thing here to turn this file into
a tree right this might be its host's
here and this might be actually conflict
won't have to and then you use the API
to make changes to this tree you can
find things in there it's actually got a
pretty powerful query language built in
that sort of close to X 1/2 I don't know
how many fans expanse we have in here
but for these things is actually useful
but yeah so you make change to the tree
and then you say yeah
save save my changes and that's where
the lenses get involved again yeah you
take the part of the tree for it's your
host send it through the lens and that
produces an updated file and so these
lenses are other thing that sort of
encodes the knowledge we have about each
file format that yeah you have to have a
different one for each file format and
that's you know one of the things that
I've heard people say it's like yeah Oh
audience would love to use it but I
don't really know how to write lenses
and I've heard it's really hard in
general at this point that's probably
the yeah ten years on part of the talk
you don't have to write lenses like yeah
what you know about lens is after
listening to me for the last two minutes
is about as much as they need to know to
use all yes I
did a little graph off the number of
different file form or I didn't change
the title of the spine this is really
different file formats that bit obvious
can deal with really early on this is
like me writing about ten of them and
then puffin per saw I didn't know it is
here showed up and he did a tremendous
amount of work just on the lenses and it
really helped both wrote a ton of them
and helped a lot of people write their
own lenses and get them in and get them
in shape that we could ship them as part
of the distribution so right now we're
at a little over 200 lenses we do 200
different file formats that audience can
deal with
I think the curve is tapered tapering
off exactly because this isn't good is
it because we're because we at the point
where August out of the box knows enough
about most file formats so this is going
to be interesting
I don't know the video camping cycling
in and out I can try to her yeah
okay I just have to talk reading really
fast before the picture goes away again
yeah so if you yeah how can you use
fogginess but what you need to do to use
it first off it's as I said it's a sea
library the the writing agency was not
fun but sort of solid on purpose because
I want to make Argos usable from as many
languages as possible and see sort of
the lingua franca there we have language
bindings for pretty much anything you
can think of the thing I'm really sad
that's missing is in tactile so if
anybody here feels like they want to
contribute in Turkel bindings for yes so
let me do that the other way you'll
encounter Hajus in the wild is in in
configuration management system systems
quite a few of them have some form of
audio support built in and yeah I hope
you realize what I'm doing with the
slide right like if you're configuration
management system does not include
support for audience it's not top-shelf
so you might want to complain about it
okay so the easiest way to get started
is something called arc tool it's a
little command-line tool and if you run
help it prints out all the commands it
knows the the intent behind are two
listed to really just let you explore
how arias deals with files what the tree
looks like search thinks in the tree
make changes before you incorporate that
into your your programs it's really
mostly meant as a tool to get familiar
with the API and get it feel for it
although some people have started using
that in scripts it's not it's not ideal
for scripts because some of the output
is not great for for processing
afterwards and when somebody complained
to me late last year about that fact
that our two lists are not really useful
in bash scripts I started thinking about
what could we do to make the feder
I didn't go all the way to another
command-line tool to make changes but I
figured yeah because all just puts a lot
of structure onto text files and you can
query that structure it would also be
really useful to have a tool to just
query yeah the way all you sees things
without making changes and so I wrote
this thing called arc match if you want
to play with it it's really new in in
110:1 and I just released that maybe a
couple of weeks ago so it hasn't really
hit all the distros yet but if you want
to play with it there's a docker
container elude our flash arc match that
you can pull and that has everything in
it and you can play around with it a
little bit and just to give you a feel
for both how arc match works and how
August sees the world a simple example
is sort of the NFS exports file to find
things in there it's not entirely
trivial it's simple but not entirely
trivial because you can have on each
line you can have any number of
definitions for exports so that makes it
a little awkward to deal with in crap or
things like that but it's still simple
enough that I can talk about it here
getting myself and so the first thing
you can do is you could just say lock
match yeah it's the experts it just
prints out the tree yeah that's the tree
that the lens is generated for for that
file and you can think of this tree
almost like a file system it's very
similar to how a file system is
organized with a few important
exceptions one is one of them is that
siblings in the tree can have the same
name so this door one and dirt two
they're really two different nodes in
the tree and they're both called dirt
the one and two is just there to help
you see that they're two different
things similarly like client has an
option one and option two but they're
really just called option and
the one into is just there to to this
distinguish them the other difference
from a file system is that even
directories can have content associated
with them in August that's called the
value like each node in the tree
consists of a label and a value
so they're both has some some content
associated with it but also has children
and the experts lens how it how it
structures things is like each of those
three entries is basically one line from
from its exports and for each client
definitions you get one of these client
things right this client one here and a
line two and that it breaks that into
you know whatever the network
specification is for that and the
options so one simple thing you can do
is just print out all all the clients
that you're exporting anything to like
just give me a list of the things that
I'm exporting stuff to and you know with
with ARC match the important thing here
is that you say I want to match der
slash client that means go through the
tree look at every turn owed then go to
a client node and that's the thing I'm
talking about and then when we say exact
it just looks at that one note and not
the stuff underneath it are matched by
default would print everything that
you're matching in underneath it the
exact says just that note and then only
value says only print the value of the
note I don't care about the path how I
get there and so yeah that gives you a
list of the things it's the expert you
can of course restrict that to just one
export here and that's the only change
that you have to make is put this slash
slash home into brackets year now you're
saying what I want to match is the der
node that has smash home in it and then
the client for that so there's there's
lots of I mean yeah I could already talk
for an hour about these these matches
they're called path expressions and
they're they're the XPath stuff I
mentioned earlier
probably talked for an hour about yeah
lots of things really cool things you
can do with it one of the things you
might want to do is I know is this
legible in the back I just realized that
the red is probably not great one thing
you might want to do is just print me
all the directories that I'm exporting
where at least one client doesn't have
route swap set right so there's a sanity
check to what I'm doing so yeah we want
to print it snaps no clue because it's
exporting something without root squash
we want to bring prince nash home the
first client has root squash set but the
second one doesn't and temp is okay and
pop is also not okay we only look at it
root squash not all squash and yeah
that's the sort of the arc match
expression you would use for that i
don't want to go too much into too much
detail how that works if you have
questions i wasn't happy to explain that
later okay
so how can you get involved if you're
yeah if you're looking at this and
you're like cool and if you try plate
with it a little bit and yeah you want
to do things that in my mind that the
most important thing that August is
missing right now is sorry organize
documentation there is a lot of
documentation but it's sort of it's
growing that's another side effect of it
being around for ten years it's not well
organized it's sort of hard to find what
you need if anybody feels like yeah like
riding and doing stuff like that
I would love I've been looking at it
book to do that but haven't gotten very
far would be really awesome to get some
help there yeah other things the yeah I
said we have a ton of language bindings
they all could use some love if it if
it's just to make regular releases in
some cases you know they could be
changed to be a little more idiomatic
for the target target language right
rather than just being a straight up
here's a C API and you can call
like and then the Ruby bindings we added
throwing exceptions and stuff like that
which is just closer to how Ruby people
want to use it yeah the other band
findings could use some love with her
too of course there's always room to
write more lenses we're never going to
run out of configuration file formats
that somebody has come up and or just
can't cover yet and then if you if you
want a really big project yeah there's
been over the years as there's been
people who've tried and made some
headway the very first person that
that's right there was one of my
favorite problems ran into that during
the build but while you compile audience
it creates directory called aux and on
Windows you can't do that like Windows
just blows up because that's your
whatever serial device is something like
that but there's there's more work to do
there I mean Argos uses POSIX API you
need to find ways to around them on
Windows or yeah go to the back tracker
there's tons of like little box and yeah
okay here's the website the website has
a quick tour that I highly recommend if
you want to learn how to use it better
it just walks you through some simple
simple examples of making changes to
files with arias and there's also links
to the mailing list and source code the
github repo it's alright and that's all
other questions
the question is is it a except besides
just showing the value is it able to set
the value August underneath yes in art
with our tool you can do that you can
change values and then save the file
I wrote arcmap specifically just for
reading things like art maps right now
it doesn't give you a way to say things
but that might be an interesting
addition to it sorry
yeah yes
yeah yes so yeah the question is is
about using something like augment in
scripts to make changes
I've loosely thought
you
yes
yeah so the question is not how does
August know which lens to use and what
format to expect and there's actually a
lot less magic then then you might think
it's just like when you write a lens you
also say how this applies to files that
match the following gloves like yeah
like cello shell gloves that that's
something you have with the lens and so
my example - your only work because the
lens actually has a little statement in
it that says this lens works for the for
the file / ET c / exports this weighs -
if you have an exports file it's
somewhere else this ways to say use this
exports lens even though you don't know
about that but sort of for the default
locations yeah or just just knows
automatically
yeah yeah but yeah so yeah this is the
computer science part of the talk
Yammer is outside the realm of what what
audience can do because August is
restricted to so initially August was
restricted to regular languages like any
file format that you can describe with a
regular language at some point because
Apache I added support for for
context-free languages but the Amal is
is at least context-sensitive because of
all the this spacing thing this ways
around that if you have a special lexer
you can turn your Yambol into a
context-free language but yeah none of
that is in and they said there is a
Yammer lens but it is really restricted
to yes order one one day that's right
like it that doesn't it with
Invitational nested things
yeah so the question is what about files
for the country guitar yeah with the
configurations spread out across
multiple files like a doggie directory
and August's very consciously focuses
just on the file level that there was
another saw the design decision I made
early on is that I don't want to have
more than just syntax transformation to
things I don't want to get into any sort
of semantic thing there was actually
somebody on the mailing list with some
I've shied away from us or the include
statements in a lot of configuration
file formats say you know you can
include some files and you know August
doesn't even understand that yet
but yeah I might have that but yeah it's
it's it's very much focused on sort of
individual files and everything beyond
that is sort of application logic from
our users point yes
you
yeah so is it possible to write a Python
or like a pure Python part of August and
some people have also asked what about
app you or go portal or yes it's
definitely possible it's sort of a
matter of time there is there's a lot of
fairly complicated stuff going on behind
the scenes like I wouldn't be keen to do
that I think you're looking at it at
least six months to a year for doing
that that's like yeah I mean for the
language geeks here this there's an
early pass or in there and there's lots
of fun fun stuff in there
so I would rather for like the ansible
problem and I would look at whether you
can statically link stuff and just copy
that over like just instead have a
little binary stop or something like
that link link obvious in statically and
then just