okay so it's 12 noon we'll start so our
next talk will be about the
well-renowned project VLC by the founder
and president of the Vidal an
association with an organization please
welcome John that is games hello yes
please comments it's okay sassette you
please come and sit
don't stay don't set up in the end so as
often I come and talk about the some
updates about the villain project and
mostly PLC and I'm going to speak about
what's going to happen next so for those
who don't know I think that's getting
less and less people in this room I'm
the president of a non-profit and I've
been working on VLC since since my left
basically and so we're going to speak
about VLC um just a few slides about VLC
0 which is going to be released on to
Tuesday and Holy Thursday for the the
time we do all the building for those
who don't know just a few slides about
what the did we finally put on VLC
sweet oh I believe I come like for the
last three or four years in will do that
in 3.0 and and it's going to ship next
whatever and of course he didn't but
actually now we are the release
candidate 8 or 9 so it's actually
happening and sorry the packaging the
good distributions so 2.2 was Weatherwax
was a very stable release which helped
us to get a lot of work on schedule
because people were not bitching too
much about this table 1 which allowed us
to do a lot of stuff but see when you
look at it it's quite old we it
in 2015 so three years later we're going
to actually work on we had around 200
million downloads on our websites of
course outside the distribution and
outside all the corporate environments
so let's give you a good idea of the
desktop size of VLC on Windows and Mac
which is good not that many regressions
the biggest issue we had is was
of course 4k and UHD coming well coming
soon HEV C is almost dead Thank You 81
so speed at yo just a few numbers and
ideas we're talking about 18,000 commits
on VLC cool around 3000 for each of the
mobile ports which is Android iOS and
uwp which is quite big it was of course
too long to come but it's a very strong
release and the reason why it took so
much time was we are going to finally
have one release for all the platforms
and with the same name same number right
so many of our users don't understand
because it's of course illogical that
the version on iOS is 2.8 dot 5 and the
version on Apple TV is 1.1 and on droid
is a 2.5 something I mean no one
understand anything so we're moving to a
way that the first number is actually
the core version so next version is
going to be VLC 4 and so on and the
mobile ports and can have different
release games but at least for the users
they understand that the big number is
the support of formats and codecs which
is what most of people care about so
that's why it took us a long time mostly
because with mobile and with 4k and 8k
and so we needed to have hardware
decoding by default and getting that was
quite difficult as our old months mentor
told us man copies murder
so in VLC speed of 0 on all the
platforms we got zero copy decoding and
displaying like so we are now finally
the architecture is finally done so that
we can just bypass a pass from the
decoder to the filters to the V output
just a reference to the frame and so we
don't have many copies and it's so
everyone is happy or almost the results
are quite good and we get 4k on the
iPads we get 8k on the Galaxy Note so we
can have 8k 60fps decoding on the phone
just a normal high-end Android phone the
lies the last i7 the last two versions
also gets you 8k with VLC we have less
CPU consumption and GPU consumption than
movies and MP CHC so we we have some
very good results um
we support 360 vo you care that about so
much because we are in the future like
3d but mostly some important part is
that we support now network shares so
you can actually go and browse you DLNA
UPnP your samba shares you whatever your
ftp we even have SFTP support for the
few people who do that but also that
means and that was quite difficult
because we had to have password
management so now we integrate we use
your koala tour you leave secret or your
windows singing because we don't want
your password inside VLC because of
course this is going to crash and you're
going to get your secrets licked so we
don't do that but we had to do a lot of
integration for that as I said common
code base we now support 10 bits and 12
bits of course 12 it is there is no
display but we support some kind of HDR
using lipless able from the MPD project
which means that we can do tone mapping
correctly for once a Vittorio is going
to be happy for once but if you have a
Windows machine with a correct driver
and the correct moon and the correct
cable and the correct green then you can
get maybe some crappy you HD HD are
correctly bathroom um it's going to work
someday on other platforms a poorly on
droid first we spend a lot of time ozone
HDMI pass-through for long time VLC was
not able to do anything else than DTS
and Dolby bathroom for audio and that
was very problematic for everyone using
VLC as HTTP T so that's fixed because we
finally destroyed the stupid
architecture we had then a lot of new
formats a lot of work on the other that
if streaming because no one wants that a
lot of support on subtitles so we
support ttml a SMC or you had talked
before we even support webvtt which get
got us a CSS engine in VLC yeah
we are so happy about that where people
if you are on you
my default now we're using OpenGL on
Linux and we have a experimental Whalen
support it's of course not perfect but
that probably because of Whalen well I'm
going to pretend and not as and also we
have a new and we have also a new
subtitle rendering stack don't buy you
Syrian developer I already talked about
that refer to my talk last year which
gave us some yes some support of this
language that you all recognize as my
yell I am the one who did not please
take extra lessons but yeah we have a
full text rendering engine that is not
cute that is not gtk okay row that is on
VLC so because it is quite technical
crowd we've done quite a bit of work on
the DLC one of the main reason is that
libby else is actually the api we use
for the mobile ports so we finally I did
a lot of function
demo of
directly that was a bit
of course when my quest 10.7 and on twit
from 2.3 and iOS 107
so that's very large and this is the
last version where we suppose we are
going to support all those platforms 3.0
is going to be a kind of LTS by LTS I
mean just back parts of security issues
because we won't bent in it correctly
I'm afraid but still they will get at
least security based release is
supposedly Tuesday and on your stores
and so on on Thursday when when we
update about website and we finish all
the bids and test them so cool 3.0 is
there what's after VR there is a lot of
people who talk about VR and there is a
lot of formats every camera is doing
something different every headset is
doing something different smooth of the
VR apps are using a 500 megabyte
download of unity and so on and they're
all quite shitty and if you just want to
just look at it it's very difficult so
instead of 0 we supported all the 360
playback on your with your touch with
your mouse with your keyboard with your
with your clicker and so that's just
normal ones and of course we had a new
3d my sonic audio renderer
sima also talks about that but then some
people actually wants to play some hmd
and there is still the question of how
do we support 3d in VLC which so far
we've not on so yes so we're going to
work on open HMG integration so we're
going to have in the main VLC and in a
very simple way so it's not going to
make you your VLC each one
didn't
raise one Holly baby could I finally
merge the MVC support Anton please yeah
good luck I know but also we're going to
have a kind of mode that is called
virtual Sierra which is basically you
have your 2d screen inside the kind of
sky map and so you look like Zoe in a in
a movie Sierra the good thing that is
going to be a minimal integration quite
simple and it's not going to change much
on the wheel seat the change is in
mostly on the OpenGL video output and
then we are going to work on integration
for unreal and unity using the same API
Lib on FBO passing that we use to do the
cui demo so after v vr we're going to do
VLC 4.0 called Auto chic Auto slick is a
vampire
photograph I believe please refer to the
whole disco this world books if you need
what are we going to do in their new
video architecture new input and
playlist media library integration and
UI and popping back platforms so video
output um we discussed about that
actually yesterday we're going to
rewrite most of the video output of VLC
because now basically we are using a
kind of pool model where you asking the
hardware what you can support and then
we go back upstream to to reconfigure
everything back to the decoder and put
the converter that was because most of
the time the hardware was really shitty
and we limited frame buffers or xvideo
now that almost everyone has OpenGL and
direct3d 11 we're doing going to do the
other way around which is pushing
pushing the frame from the decoder up to
there and in the end with hopefully some
magic with shaders and libel osebo we're
going to get it better which means
rewrites most of the video outputs in
VLC which means also poly dropping some
of them which we can do because we
dropping platforms the outreach
recycling so that you don't have this
very annoying effect when you move from
one video to another one that sometimes
the video output close it shouldn't
happen but still it happens when we'll
have that it's going to be easier
support for 3d and VR well that's not
that difficult to do side-by-side in
OpenGL
and probably more HDR because there will
be two new different formats of each of
this here or maybe three or four and
then people are going to ask for SDR to
HDR support and so on and so on and
probably a video filter API in the PLC
finally let me premised us Thank You
Jaime he doesn't know about that yet
input manager we're going to rewrite the
input because now in VLC the audio
output and the video output are owned by
the playlist which allows you to get
smooth transition of course it's not
smooth because it's not done well
between one input to the next one so we
are going to split the playlist and the
input manager which is going to the
input manager is going to own the audio
output the video output the stream
output and this one is the one who is
going to manage the input and it's going
to know the next input it's going to
simplify a lot of playlists and this
might give us some gapless playback in
VLC or even like crossfading Wow for
those people who care but also it's
going to simplify it a lot of code
because now the playlist of you'll see
the vlm of ELC the media player of the
Libi LC are doing different stuff and so
everything is going to be at the same
place which means we write of the
playlist we are going to drop the
current playlist which allows trees and
we are going to have a very simple flat
playlist and this one will have like a
1:1 relationship within input manager
media library we are going to do to
integrate a media library the one that
we having on Android on the desktop so
small details
it's C++ in SQLite it's going to be
quite simple we are never going to look
like Cody it's not the goal but and for
most people who use our correctly VLC
which is double-click from Nautilus or
dolphin it won't change anything right
this will not be activated when you need
but for the people who need it then they
will just double click especially on
Windows
where there is a lot of requests for
audio playlists and media how it's going
to look I have no idea yet but the idea
is to keep it quite fast what is fast as
possible so it's not going to be like a
Maybach
which brings us to a new UI this is the
current VLC version for Windows Tour UWP
this doesn't mean it's going to look
like that it just means that we should
do something better for the media
library integration in a playlist so if
you have inputs or ideas please share
them if you are designer or if you have
like strong opinions on how it should
look if you care about the fight between
gnome and KDE and Waylon about
client-side decoration and DWD please
also give me your input oh yes I forgot
in the input we are going to rewrite the
way the timestamp are going to be
managed because now when you play back
with VLC after the d-max are between the
d-max and decoders if we write all the
timestamps to be closer to your output
which means that if you concur then
basically you're because all your
time some talk gone this is going to be
a big change we'll do the first part in
VLC for and the next part in the next
version and the final part in the
version after but this is going to be
quite important to get frame accuracy
and correct transcoding
so as I said we're going to drop
platforms Windows XP and Vista the
Chinese people are not going to be happy
about that
I'm sorry about them but the problem is
that we still have 8 percent of our
traffic on vidalin dog that is coming
from XP and that is actually increasing
yeah Mac OS 10 standard seven eight nine
are going to be dropped like most of the
others I think we kept it more longer
than most other bigger even projects on
Linux I think OpenGL is going to be
required like there won't be any other
way around
sorry guys and from on the way we are
going finally to drop on to a 2.2 and
2.3 and scribble do and so on and for
iOS same iOS seven eight are gone so
what's after that um I we have to fund
research project the first one is VLC GS
and when I mean VLC GS I'm actually
meaning VLC and not like oh I'm going to
wrap around a few HTML this API and that
is possible because of webassembly
coming soon it's a kind of
like
ts in HLS in JavaScript in order to
Remax it in mp4 to
the browsers don't respect correctly the
mp4 stack and the mp4 specification so
the idea is to get VLC running directly
inside the web browsers and that's
possible with web assembly and threats
currently we did a work on that we have
something working on Firefox with a SMGs
and pthread so not with web assembly
because webassembly doesn't support
threads yet
it's going to come last June and I wish
I wanted I wanted to give you a demo but
I can't give you a demo because I
upgraded my Firefox and they did disable
shared a red buffers because of the
spekt spective security issue but if you
look at my talk that was recorded at
what was it at forms you could see the
demo and I can give you the pages for
the people who care we managed to play
normal WMV video you know the white life
video the one from Windows so I really
show that it's not possible that it's
decoded by the web browser and actually
works fine even on my machine
720p h.264 was easy and we were talking
enough like everything done in a SMGs
right so no SMD Gs nothing else will it
go on yeah probably some people from
chrome said that they were open to
discussing of having their hardware
decoding exposed directly and as we were
outputting with WebGL and of clean
surfaces that was actually quite
performance the problem is mostly audio
output because if anyone has tried Web
Audio sorry about that it's completely
insane
they basically know where to have like
just a little simple sink and give PCM
and get the information back from how
much has actually been playback like any
other audio API you have like awesome 3d
filters in web audios and amazing
filters and so on but the basic is not
there so we'll see another project we're
working on is unboxing one of the reason
force unboxing is that basically VLC and
other multimedia frameworks have so much
in it right
and so one of the good way is to put
everything inside the Sun box right but
if you do that then VLC is going to ask
for access to your graphic card which
means basically Canon mode it's going to
give you access to your audio and so on
and so on and in the end you check all
the boxes from the sandbox which means
basically your Sun box is useless
we don't need GPS but I'm sure with some
mp4 craziness where we need a map of the
location of the filming it will be
required so this is difficult
um what we're looking at is doing the
kind of things that home did which is
having the access the DMACC serve and
the decoder and different processes and
do shared memory sharing in a
cross-platform way yeah I see some
people are laughing it's going to be
difficult if people have ideas it would
be very nice we have a demo of that
which is just based on on on on P trace
and about in threads yes I know my time
is up and as Christoph says and that's
good because I finished any questions
any question I have a mic don't be
afraid do you want five more minutes
which ya which HDR formats you support
now i mean p q HL g so the question was
which HDR formats right so far and i
mean in a normal way of HDR the only way
we support that is windows 10 and that
is only HDR 10 when we do two mapping
with HDR 10 its limited to the placebo
it's doing a now HDR 10 it should be
able to do HDR 10 plus and i think h LG
should be easy to do if you I don't know
exactly but if you know if you want you
can ask Ian he will tell you but
basically I still mapping it's easy
right the problem is when you're not
into a mapping is that you need to
actually discuss that on the HTML link
which we don't have access to so you
need the driver support and that's so
far only on Windows 10 and annoyed and
only on selected devices on Android so
so far it's very annoying
yes us to be able to find feel see on
the f-droid repository and last week I
didn't see it anymore it said something
in f-droid project yes they don't want
to build it because it's too difficult
I'm sorry guys but we had them we gave
them Dockers we build it on Jenkins they
could pull it we help them to get a
special way of like we go help them they
don't want it because it's too difficult
because it's it breaks so much but I
mean it's a distribution that doesn't
want to distribute what can I do right
we we check we check that VLC is using
the less least amount of permissions we
need we drop them down in the last
release we have no trackers nothing so
we you like really clean it's not like
Firefox issue on our phone I thought
they just want to build it and their
only solution is oh you could do a
repository yeah but then the user needs
to go and click and add the reposition
no one is going to do that I don't I I
don't know what I can do more I can even
give them like versions that are built
on the hilly speed boat but not signed
so they can check and sign where their
own keys if they want so far they just
like No so sorry sweetie pie it's
working on Raspberry Pi that's user
interface has some some problems did you
find some some better solutions because
usually the output when you are using
the hardware acceleration then you have
less space so on Raspberry Pi we I think
we fixed the map and mal acceleration
hardware acceleration and video output
display it's quite difficult to build
for husband a PI to be honest but there
is a there is a it should work now
correctly but the problem you're
referring is a problem between cute and
mal fighting against each other and so
we've been starting to look at that with
two
community member and we'll probably the
backbone that fostered a job but I don't
think the big issue is fixed
especially in fullscreen when you have
the something about it thank you today
thank you if you have any other
questions I'm around follow the cones
and there is a booth where you have big
price to win in the second level of K