hello everybody my name is Raphael I
work at Oslo Nia which is a small French
company specialised in GIS application
and open source open source tools so I
will present a work about back shearing
station analyzes this work has been done
by Daniel Gao which is one of my
colleague me so to introduce my speech
you certainly know what is a shared back
services so this picture comes from Lyon
in France so you in large cities you
might want to do some little travel
within the city and you might need some
some transportation mode so shared bike
is a good solution easy to use and the
great question France where is all the
available bikes at stations or if you
have a bike are they available station
to to rubber drop off your bike so
that's this kind of question that we we
try to do transfer and we we did some
some analysis by using some machine
learning application so the first
question we wanted to transfer is the
the fact that a bike sharing station can
be classified in terms of the way user
used them so maybe there are some
similar patterns between between
stations and we also we are also focused
on the building of complete data
framework a complete data pipeline from
open data so you can gather some such
data and open portal so from totals to
all made API for example and by store
store of data or by apply some
treatments and that's this complete
framework we were interested in so in
this presentation I will present you
what is the data we we used then for 2 &
3 awesome proof of concepts of the types
of analysis we can under with such data
and to finish the presentation I will
show you a short API a little a PA API
sorry that we developed so just to begin
we we talked about geospatial data we
are interested in how bag sharing
station works so we can recover we can
gather this data on a public portal so
for example we walked with the data of
Leon and the data of Bordeaux to French
cities so it could seem a little bit
rough but such data are not so
complicated to to handle because we just
have some station IDs some types time
stamps and at each time stamp for each
station we have a number of available
back station a number of available bike
and the sum of these two can't quench it
is is normally equal to the number of
station of spots of the stations so we
also have some station which doesn't
work
so in this such an example we can see
that there are no available station and
not
variable bike on the second line so that
means that the station is closed and in
our studios we just manipulate this kind
of data sets of a data frame how we
handle this data so we work with Python
and to build our data pipeline we use
Luigi which is a fighting library
dedicated to that applied line building
so the the fact was to get the data on
the portals so the data was on Jason and
Jason format on XML format we we were
able to find some shape files too and
the objective was to store this data in
base and who applied some treatments and
machine learning treatments to to them
so the first application with the first
anneli analysis that we did with the
data was to classify back sharing
station in terms of the utilization so
we have some stations that are not so
well used
we have station that are very used on
the reading other one that are very used
on the morning and so on so we we wanted
to know how this can work how a system
in the city I can walk when I talk about
time theory so its availability bike
time series and we have some example for
example in green through a one day we
can see a station so on the beginning of
the day there are a lot of bikes
available at the station and on the
evening it's the opposite we have
so in orange and blue another example
and this work was inspired from a
similar work done for Dublin City by
James
Lauro and the results of such a
clustering was this kind of figure so we
have four groups of station these
results of Lille the city of Liam and we
find we found one cluster which gather
all the station that's where a lot of
blacks are on during the day but not
during the night so that's the blue
cluster there is an opposite cluster in
red where a lot of bikes are on the
station during the nights but not during
the day so we can see that it means
different situation in blue it's
probably a place where people live or
walk sorry and in red it's where people
live so they take the dough back on the
morning and go with the bike where they
live and on the evening they they are
take back the back the bike and set it
in the the place dolly in purple we have
another crystal which represents station
where people can go out Sunday evening
for example so place neo to restaurants
or bars and so on and we can to make it
more clear we can set all the station
with this clustering representation so
it's the city of Lyon and I don't know
if somebody in this in the in the room
know
knows Liam so we have the I will begin
with the purple circle so the place
where we we go out on the evening so
it's the city center with all the
restaurants and bar and so on we have
the place where we walk in blue so it's
the business business neighbourhood with
the the main station we have the
universities on the on the top of the
graph and all the red points it's mainly
a place where people live so with a lot
of residential area so that's it for the
first the first example of application
then after that we try to predict the
availability of bikes ads shared by
excitation so what we know in such
situations so we know the dates the time
of the day we know all many bike they
are at the station but the question we
want to answer is omitted bike bikes
will will be there on the station in the
next hour so it means that we will use
supervised learning to use the
availability in the available
information to predict a new information
and we can verify our prediction because
we have the data in so we use the method
which is called eg boost so I won't
enter into the detail of the method
method but to be to be as simple as
possible exists is it's a decision tree
emitted so we we use this decision trees
and
gradient gradient method so the why we
want to to predict is the availability
probability of finding a bike at the
next hour and the information we have so
X things variables or the hour so the
time of the day the day so in the week
is it a Monday is it a Tuesday and so on
and the available bikes at the current
hour so just to show you some some
picture of the proof of concept on the
top you have the prediction of the model
on the bottom you have the ground truth
so we we don't we won't go into the
detail but we can see that's even if
it's small the blue points are really
similar in the in the two graphs and the
red ones as well so when it's blue it
means that in one hour there will be
lots of bikes at the station and when
it's red it means that it will be hard
to find bikes so it's a synthetic scale
between 0 & 1 and what is interesting
that if we plot the arrow on the left
you can see that there are not so much
station where the model is not good so
we have just two station maybe on the on
the left which indicates that the model
is not able to to predict the good
amounts of bikes there so we didn't
really work on the on the features we
won't we didn't try to improve the
definition of feature two to get a
better error
indicator but it could be a possibility
too to get a better result so to finish
the presentation I can show you a little
demo of our app API so that's on the
Internet
click on this link and this API has been
developed with flask so it's a REST API
we have the two cities so Bordeaux and
Leo we can imagine to to gather more
data for more cities to add them to the
API various project on github I will
give you the address at the end and
there is the documentation so it's not
really a documentation it's more a way
to to to get some data in JSON format we
can try a little demo so we have one
table and we can try to gather some that
data so maybe by indicating at the dates
so we add data
so the data was from September or August
from a two-sentence oh sorry we can get
three three days of data we can focus
only on again an ideas for the IDS of
the bike sharing station so it's a it's
a trial I'm not sure yes well I don't
know the idea of the station by heart
but that's the idea and if you you you
can so execute the the the request and
get all the data in the JSON format so
maybe I will have another example after
but that's the global ID with that with
this request tool we have graphic
graphical parts for the API so we can
represent all the station in real and
involved and get the station name for
example this one is Tolstoy Allen we
have a list of station and all the
transaction so we can also click on the
station to add some more information
about the the station so for example
this station is tahula term so this
station is located on the city centre we
have some information we have the daily
profile so it's a station where people
go on the the evening there are a lot of
bikes on the evening and we have also
the daily profile for Monday Tuesday and
so on
we have some time series for the last
day and we have the last week if we if
we want and the last transaction and so
for example we are on we are the 3rd of
February we still gets data every 5 or
10 minutes and so the IP API is able to
to represent this this recent data so
what I mean by transaction is a
transaction is when someone take a bike
or a drop of a bike to the station so
this is the gated project it's called
Jatin Shia I don't know why it maybe
it's Japanese
it's my product that's named give this
name so I where I was not so confident
in my ability to to show you the API is
I prepared some some screenshots so just
this shot I didn't show you this chart
it's the the amount of transit
transaction for the most the most used
station and we can see that the two
station that are the most used are near
to the the train station gap are you so
that's a little indication of how the
network is working and that's it's so in
conclusion I hope I was able to show you
that with a simple geospatial data we
can do some some interesting stuff with
with machine running so we try to build
complete data pipeline with Python and
widget we did a little API that's if
you're interested in
can complete this visit API and our
objective is to do online learning so
the little example I show you so we
train an examples method and clustering
algorithm for only one week of data with
only one week of data one objective
could be to to train our algorithm
online so with new data we get better
training and have something which is of
a good quality either even with a new
raw data so thank you for attention you
have the address of the little project
there you can also go to the blog of
Australia to have some information there
are some blog articles which are talking
about this project and we can you can
also send us email if you're interesting
so thank you for your attention
[Applause]
maybe there are some question
you are talking about our API or the
geospatial so no no it's it's R&D
project it could be an objective the
city of Lee
oh yeah exactly
so we use you know it is open open
geospatial data okay you just have to go
on these websites okay and gather the
data so the data are in Jeff do Jason
formats okay yeah yeah every five
minutes or so on we just build a cron
job okay be together that Irene five
minutes I mean store them into our
database one day
yeah it's a typical day yeah we just mix
every types of days yes oh that's our
choice if you we tried we show the Limu
results which is good the results in
Bordeaux it is not so interesting so
okay it depends on how the city is
organized yeah
certainly but we didn't check yeah but
it could be interesting too I guess
maybe we can continue to ask question
yeah but if if you want and after your
question yeah okay so you have a
question
the question the question is about
missing data we just gather the data we
have a cron job which recover the data
every 5 or 10 minutes and we do not have
any alerting tool which we say us a
warning there are missing data we just
consider them a posteriori after
gathering the death I am not sure about
that I it's not me that did this this
job but I guess the missing that are the
missing station are dropped from the STD
yeah of course I would say that this
this job could be generalized to to
everything if you have the the the same
pattern of data that's the same data so
it's geospatial data you have a
continuous data gathering process and
it's just that we didn't check the 1880
and so we just were focused on bike
sharing station because we did some work
about transportation how transportation
is organized within a C but without we
know that it could be possible not yet
we were just at the proof-of-concept
step one perspective could be to you
know to to give the give this API or
give propose the API to to the service
provider because I don't know the the
added value of such a thing it's a way
to reformulate the data so maybe could
be interesting for us but the question
was not really not yet
Oh
yeah
mm not so not so well but we did not we
did not use post GIS for this Chile
everything was done with patent so we
use we use Wiggly which is a data
pipeline builder which we use psychic
law for machine learning stuff we use
volume which is a library to to build
some maps and it's just a way to
represent information on maps but the
only database related part of the
project was the the the data storage
no no operation was done on data through
PostgreSQL on all pouches
it could be yeah of course that's a good
question
as you as you said this kind of new
actor without stations it it generates
different results question and we are
out of scopes
maybe we I don't know exactly how it
works if you have a kind of transaction
when you drop you your bike as well
okay
in the same area yeah yeah it's it's a
different problem because we do not have
the station availability question but
you can imagine some some you know it's
not really this kind of application but
some sort of save traveling salesman
problem maybe to find the bike which is
the nearest bike of you but yeah it's
it's definitely a different problem yeah
but it could be very interesting to to
work on there is there are incentives
yeah