it's crazy I like saw that the other day
I'm like what is this what is this new
software so thank you for your
introduction and Sobell starts right off
with two questions first a west her to
talk yesterday about the Electra is the
salmon okay right Sofia thank you and
who has her other collector before this
talk yesterday so also someone okay oh
they actually are no perfect okay so
yeah I will directly dive in also as you
all know reliable editing of
configuration files is not so easy or
not always so easy
and this is not only a problem which is
faced by configuration management but
it's also a problem faced by
applications themselves in the moment I
wanted to integration and access other
configuration files they are basically
they have basically the same problem as
configuration management has focus of
electrolysis is wider than only to be
used by a configuration management
because of this but in this talk
configuration management will be the
main focus
so yeah as you heard in the talk before
example appears cannot access some files
like Yammer and yeah and as you know
there are many incapabilities between
the different platforms so the idea and
the long-term goal of Elektra is to
integrate the technologies as they are
so we have a lot of brilliant passes and
validators out there which are waiting
to be used and and the main goal is that
configuration management and other tools
should use exactly the same passes as
the applications to do and so electro
also introduces specification language I
cannot go into detail during this talk
but so things that can be done in this
configure in the specification languages
you can specify which options are there
you can document them you can specify
which defaults are there so if I remove
the option what what does this actually
mean if no option is there and so on and
so on so all this information which is
actually needed for doing configuration
management should be in this
specification so that's the long term
goal of Elektra so and what also can be
done because of this you can also patch
through so for example if you have here
a configuration management tool we will
see this later then you can patch this
through to some specific file for
example using the ideas parser and doing
something so you can decide which parts
of the configuration maps to to which
parts of the configuration files ok so
to enter this high-level overview of
this in technology technology
integration can be used for this for
configuration management and and the
board is quite well defined so Elektra
is
- which runs on the nodes and the
distribution between the nodes happens
within the configuration management
tools so Elektra that doesn't bother
about this about this deployment but it
bothered about how the configuration
works only on the individual nodes and
the focus in the talk will be will be
puppet but actually you could use a
lecture with any configuration
management tool as so I will talk today
about not only one tool about Elektra
this will be the first part but also
about puppet Electra which is basically
which is the second project using
Electra so let us start what Electra is
so electro is the small fast library it
doesn't have any dependencies but it has
many plugins and these plugins have
dependencies it does not introduce the
demons that doesn't introduce any
security problem and its main
abstraction we need for this talk today
is the key value abstraction which is
the common structure amongst all
configuration files and there any
configuration file soon Texas map able
to keep Lu pairs and yeah with this
abstraction in place you do not have to
care about the concrete syntax which is
in use so here we have example so the
same configuration is expressed in in E
and also a little bit more verbose in
XML and these are some
[Music]
different parcels which are available in
Elektra today so they are also applied
some bindings available so especially
relevant is Ruby binding which we will
use later for our puppet integration
there are currently more than 80 plugins
available within Electra a lot of them
involved in how to manipulate
configuration files others for example
can check configuration for validity and
others for example can encrypt values
within configuration files or can do
completely different stuff there are a
packages available for Electra in in
various distributions and it's already
used widely preparatory in proprietary
software and for example I hear some
examples but from the beginning for of
Electra the goal was to be used by the
floss ecosystems so I'm here to push
this a little bit forward and there was
a lot of positive response in the talk
yesterday so I'm looking forward to see
many more applications electrified soon
ok so the second part will be this
puppet Electra module so it basically
adds two resource types in within puppet
they are called cardi B key and car B
mount and what they achieve can be shown
here so we have this compiled catalog
which is distributed to
notes and the puppet agent then uses the
lip electric aura and this carbon mount
we saw Stipe defines this mapping so we
add new they have newer kind of
identifiers which are called the keys
and we can map these keys with with
concrete files on the disk and with
concrete formats for example I was in
here so that's the car to be mount
abstractions of this mapping here and
then we have the car be key which can
manipulate individual values within
these files so these are the two main
abstractions and the main idea in the
puppet Electra is to have configuration
settings as first car citizen so that we
are not manipulating conky a complete
configuration files but we go down to
individual configuration settings and
the goal of the project is to bring all
features from Lib Electra to puppet so
all the Apostles Electra has the error
messages that are provided by Electra
and so on so how does it work
so the karabük here so as you know in
puppet you need here and unique
identifier and luckily Electra exactly
has this unique identifier every key in
from Electra is a unique identifier for
concrete configuration setting so we
directly write it here and
before automatically fulfill a puppet a
property with it then we have to send
that so that we can ensure that
something's present and then we can set
an work group name so here we actually
edit the Samba configuration and set the
specific workgroup so it's as simple as
that that's so and of course I saw
Electra does not manipulate any other
settings so they complete the rest of
the Samba configuration stays completely
untouched and if you want to be sure
that some well is not there so it should
be the default then we can ensure its
absence okay so yeah the the larger goal
of Electra has already said is that
application developers directly use
Electra and in this case nothing needs
to be done we would just write to this
part and December configuration file
would be edited yes of course we have to
bootstrap to get to this situation
and so if applications do not already
use Electra we can unmount them and for
this year amounts the sample
configuration file so we say at this
electro key we want to have this
configuration file present and here we
can specify a list of electro plugins to
do so okay and yeah we can even go
further and we can also add a
specification because in an electorate
also a specification language included
and they can also written down directly
in pop art for example here we can
define simple checks for example a type
we shorten some range which is actually
than not part of the configuration file
but it will end up in our in a
specification namespace of Elektra and
here this is more than imperative puppet
code can do because we can also a have
local checks so these checks have local
on the note when before writing out the
configuration for example we can check
if a file exists in a trivial way ok so
it's even more comfort possible because
it's tiresome to manually encode this
configuration constraints and we also
have a lot of implicit checks some
plugins already know how the data that
data look like
and here's one of the strengths of
Elektra for example are from from how
hosts file looked like we automatically
know which parts are IP for for
addresses and P for 6 addresses and how
canonical host names look like and if
you use the hosts plugin as done here
the card amount at a host plugging the
host plug-in actually recommends global
network so that's not really necessary
to write it down it's only here to see
the larger picture then more that more
than one a plug-in is involved to do
this and and then we get a complete a
check for that we only write when it
hosts file so if we have here an invalid
IP address if this master putress is
invalid we will get a validation on the
know would get address info
be invoked and it actually check of for
this operating system if this appeared
rest can be successfully resolved and
otherwise you get an error message from
what get address info assess about their
P address and again the long-term goal
is that application they have a lot of
us because they know best what
configuration actually expect should
write the specification and it's really
simple because also the specifications
in key value pairs will simply say this
is an ipv4 address and and basically you
have already encoded all the information
we need to know so what we actually want
we want to go beyond deaf ops so okay of
course it's nice if you have a group of
developers and operations working
together but it's it's not always
possible and the longer-term goal is
that we have a common language to speak
between developers and operations so
that we can communicate and more
efficiently what we expect as well it
configuration okay so the last part will
be a case and a user study where this
puppet leap Electra was used and first
we have done a case study and in the
case study we basically set up the whole
infrastructure of Lib Electra so there's
this web server than documentation
server many DNS then alliances and so on
and also a complete build server
continuous integration and so on and all
these parts were realized with puppet
lip elektra some of these applications
started to use
electra then it's of course quite
trivial to apply a puppet leap Electra
in two cases so pianets
was the one who implemented the puppet
leap Electra and did this case at the
user study and he also implemented for
example to ruby black ins which parson
tried configuration files k then a
little bit more information about the
user study with it
so we had four puppet tasks in three
different variants and the puppet asked
were non-trivial so you have to
manipulate different configuration files
in different ways and the focus was on
configuration file editing and we
compared the usability between canopy
key the one puppet provider talked
before then obvious in settings and host
and and we also did time measurements so
the setup was quite sophisticated and an
robust also participated in the study
and for example David who will have the
next talk also helped us a lot and also
participated with the Salas thank you a
lot for that
and and and
system you really saw that there was a
lot of effort invested and are doing
this set up we measured how long editing
of configuration files needed and in the
first our task we had a host file
editing like shown here and in the
second part we had modified Samba
configuration and as you so here this
are the medium where Leo said this is a
boxplot so if this person till 25 or 75
and these are the outliers here so this
already gives a quite a clearer picture
but we also used statistics to show if
there's the significance and the end it
actually was so the host is technique
significantly faster than Electra so it
actually pays off even with Electra to
write dedicated resource types when the
image settings was on par with Electra
but as you know in the settings is not
generic it only works for in it and for
maintenance tasks it was not adhere
conclusion we also asked about the
usability of the systems and yeah so so
we we asked in a questionnaire to rate
the usability of the systems for this
best and to what is burst and also here
the specialized host plug-in was was
liked most and in the second in the
settings and puppet Electra our second
past best use
okay so at the moment we have a usable
solution as shown is the complete live
electro punk rock infrastructure works
with this and for example which puppet
for and Debian stretch we have a very
reliable solution but in in other
systems for example the the Ruby
interpreter not of the system but
another one is used and here a ruby gem
would help which does not exist at the
moment and so it is still maintained so
payin heart is still still decreed to
maintain it and I'm also a common Tina
but it would be create to have help and
bring this tool forward yeah then there
is this multi key support so Electra by
itself has transactional support for
configuration files so you can make a
large change of many configuration files
and Electra make sure either at all
configuration files are changed or
nothing happens but in the current
implementation every KDP key in makes
and
individual invoke within Electra and
yeah but for some plugins like obvious
you can't go five if you need a single
if if this is separated to move the key
support would be great and we hope to
the problem was in actually implementing
it in a puppet provider and we hope that
there's a better support from puppet
yeah but maybe we hear something about
in the next talk so here a picture of
some of the people working on electrons
so this is beyond hot did the work I
could not come here and unfortunately
Thomas is here with all wait afterwards
outset so if you want some t-shirts
stickers and want to talk with me I will
be outside afterward so this is a more
complete list of people currently
working on electron on many topics I
can't go into the details of this so
yeah yeah here you can find the purpose
lip Elektra and and here you can find
Electra and we also have all the data we
level of this user study and yeah so are
there any questions
yeah
okay so the question was if I have this
validation already in the in the
application and let's say if if there's
some way to export it to a lecture
without defining on it in two places
and yeah that's a really good question
and and the goal of a lecture is to have
it own it at one place and the current
solution of electrodes that that if you
have already specified in the Electra
you can generate the code you need in
the application so Electra has also a
code generator where you can put
everything within the application yeah
so thank you
and yet I think it's in a private repo
currently because we think the data of
the persons participating at the puppet
show him in this puppet control and the
stock see I think that's currently in
the same repo and we cannot publish it
because it has non animist person theta
but but on request we can separate it
and give you the so please drop in
emails I think it's a good idea are
there some other questions
so see you outside