thanks Francesca um so hi my name is
Matt Bostick I am a platform engineer
working for cloud fair in London I'm
interested in distributed systems in
performance and until September I was
studying a master's in computer science
at night school for the last two years
which was hard but super interesting so
today I want to talk to you about
building and designing a distributed
datastore which I did as part of my
Master's final project so this won't be
a talk about stuff I'm working on at
work it's really a personal project I'm
the the project is called timbala
that's the logo that's actually the
second logo because logos are important
and it was original Athens TV so if you
see references to Athens dB
that's why and so Tim Bala is a
distributed time series database or will
would be if it was finished did she beat
the system is a huge topic I won't be
able to explain everything during this
talk but hopefully you'll be able to
take something away
subscribe to broad torque and I'm gonna
talk really about how I approach the
problem so it's more about the design of
building a system like this and doing
that and go rather than going into like
very deep technical details so just a
disclaimer Tim bar is not
production-ready
so please please don't use it for
anything you care about in production so
what is distributor why am I talking
about distributed systems well a
distributed system is a system where you
essentially have coordination between
networked computers and this is how our
Wikipedia defines it and I think the
coordination part is is really important
and it's really hard as we'll find out
so why why distributed why why do we
need a distributed system well first of
all we want to survive the failure of
individual servers so if an individual
server dies we want the system to keep
working and we also want to be able to
add more servers to meet demand so we
have this it's a distributed time-series
database if we have lots of users
sending metrics we want to be able to
scale up the number of servers to cope
with that demand
so although otherwise known as
horizontal scaling
so there's a great list of fallacies
edition' be computing that came out of
sun microsystems I think it's got some
great things in here like the network is
reliable if you're running a distributed
system that tells you that the network
must be reliable for the system to work
be be very distrustful of it so this
kind of thing makes building distributed
systems interesting and so the use case
for timbala
was to create a durable on long term
storage system for metrics and so I've
worked a lot with Prometheus and really
what I wanted was a place to store my
Prometheus metrics over a long period of
time say five to ten years and it was
important that it this system could
store multidimensional metrics so
metrics defined using labels or tags and
it also must be also capable of storing
more metrics than could be accommodated
by a single commodity server so why not
just use the cloud right everyone's
using the cloud you know you could just
use like s3 put your data in there well
first of all it wouldn't make for a very
good masters project so that was what
the first thing but also sometimes you
want to run stuff on-premise maybe for
because you don't want to run your data
you don't want to put your data in the
cloud and you have an off data that you
need a system that can handle a lot a
reasonable amount of data but maybe it's
not so much data that you want to run a
system like say Hadoop or safe which are
big complex systems and can be can be
difficult to operate so the other the
other use case I had in mind was I
needed this system needed to be highly
performance so it needs to be able to
ingest a lot of metrics very quickly and
I also wanted to be really easy to
operate I think this is really important
with distributed systems that you have
to bear in mind how they're going to be
operated in production so being able to
see what is happening in the system at
any point in time was really important
so what are the requirements so well
first of all the system needs to be able
to shard the data so it needs to be able
to store more data than can fit in a
single node and by shorting I mean
essentially spreading data across
multiple sir
by splitting it up into chunks it also
the system also needed to replicate data
so we wanted to make copies of data in
case a single node dies we would still
have a copy of the data on on one of the
other servers I mentioned throughput so
the system needs to be highly available
for data ingestion specifically so I
focused on high availability for the
right path because when you're reading
data when you're querying the system a
human can always retire you want to
avoid that if at all possible
but if worst comes to worst they can do
that if you're ingestion if you're your
right path is not available then your
your the data that you need to ingest is
going to start backing up you're gonna
have back pressure and then when you try
to catch up you need to ingest your
normal your normal traffic plus the
traffic that is backlogged as well so we
want to try and avoid that and really
make sure that they're the right path is
is as available as possible and
operational simplicity so it needs to be
simple to operate maintain I wanted to
keep the number of configuration open
options to a minimum so less less things
to tune which hopefully would translate
to less things to get wrong and also add
good instrumentation so logging metrics
and tracing so that you can see if a
certain client hit a given server which
other servers that requests had to
traverse through to be able to serve a
request and the other requirement I had
was interoperability with Prometheus so
I mentioned the original use case I had
in mind for this was to store Prometheus
data long-term so I wanted to reuse
Prometheus best the best features which
is the query language and its data model
and also it has API is already defined
so I didn't want to have to redesign
those api's when when I could reuse
those so that helps me to focus the
project and it allowed me to focus
really on the distributed part of the
system which was the part that was most
interesting for this project so it's
easy to think about distributed systems
if you have a really small amount of
data because you know you could just put
it on
and it's not really distributed system
so I think it helps to kind of at least
have a target to work with in terms of
numbers so I just looked at CloudFlare
is open T STP insulation this is where
we keep metrics for long-term storage
currently and every 2017 we're storing
700,000 data points per second so
700,000 metrics observations ingested
per second and 70 million unique time
series and those are multi-dimensional
metrics so 70 million uni unique metrics
so this kind of gave me a goal
I knew I wasn't going to achieve this
for my Master's project but at least
helped me to think about what the
constraints of the system would be and
how I need to design it so how do you
build a distributed system like where do
you start you have all these servers
talking to each other like it seems like
really complex and difficult so I had a
hard time coming up with an MB MVP and I
didn't have a lot of time to build this
cuz I need to do it on evenings so I
started thinking about ingestion versus
querying so the read in the right path
so it was one of the first places I
started and then I thought well how can
I also reduce the scope of what I need
to do well we're using third-party code
wherever possible so reason those
Prometheus libraries was one of the most
beneficial decisions in the project and
so I reused the poem QL query library so
I didn't need to reinvent my own query
engine and I reused the IPA code as well
so the so the system would be API
compatible with Prometheus so any
existing integrations would would work
with it so I came up some milestones the
first one was to just get the system
working on a single node so no
coordination no communication between
servers but just be able to store data
on a single server and then query it
back out afterwards and then the next
milestone was to actually get the
service talking to each other start
sorting the data across the nodes
replicating the data so that we have
enough copies to survive single node
failures and then also look at
rebalancing data between between servers
so that we can recover from from server
loss so and then there are other things
I want to do if I could take this beyond
a minimum viable product so one of those
things was read repairs so that's the
ability to as you're reading data
you can see if a given server is missing
some data I basically tell it hey you're
missing data you should you should have
a copy of this so that was one thing
hinted handoff is the ability to store
data on behalf of another node in the
system so that if that nodes down you
can basically hold on to its data until
it comes back up and then send that data
across to it and then the other thing I
wanted to look at was an activity
entropy which is a fancy way of saying
having a background process that runs
and tries to detect missing data in data
that you might not read very frequently
so with repair read repair only works
for data that you're reading and with
metrics you're often reading just very
recent data so active and active anti
entropy would allow you to repair data
that is maybe further back in time but I
was pretty sure I wouldn't be able to
finish that for this project so I was
like okay this is cool this is really
exciting I'm gonna like start reading
like research and papers and this was
really cool like I've read all these
things about Numa and writes
amplification and how to work with SSDs
and em up and hashing all this kind of
stuff
and it was super interesting but like
yeah this there's so much to work with
here and I needed to start small and
needs to get something working so like
let's ignore that for now so back to the
essentials so what did I need to think
about for the system to work well the
service needs to be able to talk to each
other need to to to coordinate Peter
Bergen wrote a blog post about his
system for ingesting logs called ok log
and that was really influential to me in
terms of framing the problem in terms of
coordination between servers and then
indexing how do you know where your data
is stored in the system how do you store
the data on disk how do you know which
nodes should be in the cluster and when
you know which nodes should be in the
cluster how do you decide where to send
the data between them and then finally
how will the system fail because it will
fail at some point so to try to
understand the problem more let's let's
consider some of the traits or
assumptions we can make about time
series data so the first one I made was
the data once ingested will be immutable
so basically their data would be append
only so there would be no worry - no
need to worry about updates to the data
so we don't have to worry about
like updating a row essentially in a
relational database or the date having
to manage multiple versions of the same
data so that helps relax some of the
requirements because it makes it we
don't have to worry about managing all
those versions and so the other thing
about metrics is the data types can be
really simple so time series can include
events but in this case I was just focus
on numbers and numbers can compress
really well prometheus
to two point two point oh and a bar F
uses a variant of the gorilla
compression algorithm from Facebook and
this uses double Delta compression for
64-bit floats so it takes the difference
between the two numbers and then it
takes the difference between that
difference and it uses that to compress
the data and if you're interested the
the gorilla paper explains how that
works
so the other thing to bear in mind with
time series data bay time series data is
the tension between the rate reading the
right patterns and this is really
important when thinking about how to
design the system so you essentially
have continuous writes across the
majority of your individual time series
so in the case of CloudFlare for example
we had 70 million unique time series we
might have maybe 40 million of those
time series being rich written to within
the last five minutes so you have a lot
of updates across a broad range of data
but then when you're reading back from
the system you're often reading for a
given time range of data so you have
this tension between the right path
which is touching many different time
series and the read path where you're
going across time so that was something
that was difficult to there's one of the
most interesting properties of storing
time series data and now if fabián from
the Prometheus project goes into this in
more detail in his blog post so I looked
up I was like okay what exists currently
I won't go into that into detail now but
the main thing I drew from these
existing systems was the idea of storing
data in columns so column the data
stores and from Amazon's dynamo paper
the idea of using consistent hashing to
determine where to place they turn in
the system
so I mentioned coordination and
coordination being able to think about
the system in terms of coordination was
really helpful and the thing I realized
was if I wanted to support a high
throughput on ingestion I wanted to keep
coordination to an absolute minimum
because that would help reduce the
complexity of the system and and all as
a result make it more reliable and also
avoid coordination bottlenecks because
those bottlenecks could be couldn't be a
bottleneck for the for the ingestion
throughput so the other thing was to
know which which servers were part of
the cluster at any given time so I could
just do this statically I could just
tell each server what other services it
exists but that's gonna be kind of
painful especially if you had a lot of
nodes and also I needed to know if a
node when a node fails so being able to
detect a node failure so for that is the
member list library this is used by
Hoshi Corp Cerf and also console it's a
if the goal it's a goal I brie eases the
swim gossip protocol and by gossip
protocol I mean that the service talked
to each other using UDP and they
synchronize their state with each other
using UDP and then occasionally they
have a TCP mechanism for reliably
synchronizing their state and they talk
to each other and basically tell each
other they they still exist and so even
has some really nice properties one of
them is that you can detect if a node is
still alive even if you can't access it
directly so the nodes can snitch on each
other on each other and you can
indirectly detect if a server is still
alive so that worked really well the
membership library was member list
library was really easy to integrate
Peter Berger and also uses this in okay
log and it was a lot easier than I
thought to get this up and running so
that was really really good to use
so indexing how do you find the data
quickly like you have all these nodes in
the cluster where do you know where your
data is so I could use a centralized
index and I've worked with the raft
protocol before I anew bit about
consensus and I started thinking like
I'm sure I need consensus for the system
and then I thought about it I thought
well actually probably only need
consensus if I have a centralized index
and using a centralized index you have a
consistent view of
what should exist in the system at any
one time but to do that you need to be
able to coordinate between servers so
that you can decide what that
centralized index should be and that's
likely to become a bottleneck high
ingestion volumes so I wanted to try and
avoid that if possible so the other
thing you could do is just use a local
index in have each server know about
what it stores itself the big
disadvantage to this is that if you lose
data you don't really know exactly what
you've lost because if you've lost the
index along with your data then you
don't know what you've lost but maybe
maybe we could work with this maybe we
could do something so like dynamo
cassandra and react they all use this
idea of constant consistent hashing to
determine where data should go so I
started looking at that and so I was
looking at data placement and how we how
we place dates are on the different
servers so consistent hashing is
essentially a way of placing items into
buckets and hashing is just a way of
using maths to put items into pockets
and consistent hashing aims to keep the
disruption to a minimum when the number
of buckets changes and so in our system
that translates to when the number of
nodes in the cluster changes then we
want to keep the the disruption to a
minimum and we want the amount of data
that is displaced when all the servers
to keep to stay to a minimum as well so
in this example if we have five nodes in
a cluster and one node fails we should
only only a fifth of the data should
have to move to another node assuming
that we're not able to replace that node
immediately so I looked into consistent
hashing algorithms there's a decision
record on the github repository for this
project that goes into more detail and
I'll show these slides afterwards
basically the first one I looked at was
the Karger algorithm and then and then I
kept iterating in and worked on looked
at jump ash I'd encourage you to look at
the of link to the papers here I won't
explain them in detail right now cuz I
don't have the time but I'll just show
you the the jump past implementation
which i think is super elegant jump ash
is an improvement over the column
algorithm because it uses less memory
and it's a lot faster another thing I
really like about
is it that stood out to me was that it
uses this magic constant which is a
64-bit congruence or random number
generator and it uses this magic
constant to to make this faster so
daemon risky has an implementation of
this and like this is the this is the
whole jump hash algorithm so the other
thing I needed to figure out was well
the hash function that's that I using
consistent hashing needs a partition key
so I need just figure out what that
partition key could be and the choice of
partition key could have a big impact on
how many nodes you have to query when
you're querying data and also how many
nodes are ingesting data at any one
point in time so again I went into a lot
I've gone into detail on the github
repository for how to choose this but
what to include in this was a critical
decision in the system and we need to
store three copies of each shard of each
copy of data so I achieved this by
prepending the replica number two the
partition key so then I was like okay
well I know like where to put the data
and how to index it but like how do i
how do I store it on disk and I started
looking at different kind of structures
different libraries I'd like to started
working with Roxie B and really I mean
storage is really hard and I could have
spent I mean this could have been a
project in itself
and luckily around the same time Fabian
and the Prometheus team were working on
this TST B library and I thought well
I'm already integrating with heavily
with Prometheus so why not just use this
library so the the interfaces for this
library were really clean to use and the
conclusion I got from this was a good
program programmers or lazy programmers
constructively so because if you can
reuse something then why build it
yourself so I solved the on disk storage
problem by using an existing library so
this is the architecture that I came up
with so no centralized index to keep the
ingestion throughput high so the only
shared state is a node metadata each
node in the system has its has the same
role and any
no oneno can receive data and any node
can be queried as well so what about
testing well I found that integration
tests were the most useful because I
could quickly iterate on the system
without having to worry about breaking
my unit tests and so integration tests
I had unit tests as well but integration
tests really gave me the most the most
value so for the unit tests one thing I
looked at is how is how even is the data
distribution across the nodes in the
cluster so I wanted to make sure that no
single node we're storing more data than
the others and also are all replicas of
the data stored on separate nodes so if
I store three copies of the data I want
to make sure they don't all end up on
the same node so I wrote unit tests to
do this and with little histograms and
you can build histones like this using
the in using the go testing library
really simply just repeating a character
and I used the standard deviation to
measure what the what the distribution
was between nodes and I used the the go
sub tests to test to test this against
different numbers of replicas and
different numbers of nodes in the
cluster and this was really helpful
because when I changed when I changed
the consistent hashing algorithm I could
actually see the difference and see the
improvement in balance when I switch to
jump ash so the other thing I looked at
was data displacement so if I remove a
node how much data has to move and this
helped me find a book about because I
was I was sorting the list of nodes
alphabetically cuz I figured that would
make it more deterministic and
determinism is a good thing but in this
case it didn't actually help because it
worked against the jump hash the way
that jump hash works and in the in the
jump hash paper it says that the main
limitation is the buckets must be
numbered sequentially and I was treating
I was treating them as names of servers
rather than just numbers of pockets so
my conclusion was that each node in the
cluster needed to remember which in
which order it joined the cluster
the other kind of sensor wrote war
acceptance tests and I did these by
executing the the binary itself and that
allowed me to do things like test if my
command line flags were still working
and I also did things like test if I
look for certain canary metrics to make
sure I hadn't forgot to register metrics
but also other things like can I query
can I can I find the result of 1+1 and
can I query data out of the system I
mentioned the integration test is being
the most effective there wasn't
crossover between these in the
acceptance tests but they they were by
far but the the integration test focused
more on the integration with other
services such as Prometheus and I
actually had Prometheus writing data
into the system and then I was able to
query back out again to make sure that
that worked and I when I queried it back
out I would use the official Prometheus
client library so I could be sure that
my system worked with both the
Prometheus server and the official
client libraries and I use docker
compose for this for portability it was
really easy to get set up and I had the
docker compose integration test running
in Travis CI for every every pull
request and this actually worked really
well so I'd highly recommend this I also
set up a benchmarking framework so I
could see how the system is working as
it's running and not allowed me to do
things like graph my throughput and also
CPU usage usage and memory and again I
used the benchmarking framework was was
harness was in using docker compose I'll
just go through these I use PDF to help
determine where I could speed things up
I think that's been covered and like to
talk in more detail so I was just skip
through that and the last thing I want
to say is that I what I think a chance
to do this but I really wanted to do it
is in failure injection in in with
docker compose you can use failure
injection to test how your how you
distributed system manages with failure
so you can have a privileged container
that can stop nodes in the cluster
inject packet loss latency and that
allows you to see how well the gossip
protocol works
and how well the system copes with
failure so our conclusions I think the
greatest challenge in this writing
distributed systems is anticipating how
that will fail and how they lose data
the implementation is already hardened
itself but it's even harder to figure
out how they're going to fail and the
other conclusion I took away is make
sure you understand the trade-offs that
your production systems are making
because they are they are making
trade-offs and finally use get used app
it's awesome so thank you so much to Sam
and the other contributors to DEP and if
you're interested in reading more all
the all the links are up here and I'll
share the slides on on the FOSDEM site
afterwards thank you before we do the QA
before we do the QA I want those two
people that are taking care of the doors
to go to the doors so do not leave yet
just let you go to that door and Marcelo
can you go to that door Oh perfect okay
because otherwise gonna be a chaos in a
minute because there's a huge amount of
people outside already now you're gonna
start repairing and in the meanwhile we
have the QA thank you any questions oh
yeah
so the question was what tools that I
used to benchmark the system so I wrote
a little tool that would generate load
it generated random metrics using a seed
so that they would be generated
deterministically and the benchmarks run
in doc campos so i'd i'd spend up three
nodes of the cluster generate metrics
ingest those and then i'd see how they
performed in prometheus yes
so I'm not sure I fully understood the
question but I think it was Kaji did the
system provide one interface to query
all of the metrics no so this I mean
this system is designed to stand alone
so it's it integrates with Prometheus
but you could use it without Prometheus
it just it implements all the Prometheus
API is essentially the majority any
other questions thank you
[Applause]