we started in two minutes for the
recording live stream but yeah I
introduced try go walking 4-bit lab that
will talk about Stoker Cuba needs
integration testing so very interesting
subject okay hello everyone and I see
that the rooms also thanks for coming to
listen to my talk my name is Greg Osby
zone and I work at gate lab as a senior
developer focusing mostly on the CI
seedy area but also on test automation
so some of you probably have never heard
about get up so get up is the solution
that is very similar to github but in
the open core model which means that we
have a github Community Edition which is
a free software free open-source
software that you can install on your
server so today I would like to tell you
about building an end-to-end integration
testing framework okay I will do my best
okay I'll do my best
an integration testing framework called
github QA so end-to-end testing is a
strategy used to check whether your
software works as expected from start to
finish we can also use end-to-end
testing to check whether deployment
process or installation process is okay
for example
especially when you distribute some kind
of a package like Debian package or
docker image what we do what we do at
gate lab so we needed a end-to-end
integration testing framework we because
we had some major problems in the past
with users not being able to install get
lab users not being able to update
github we had some broken major features
like pushing to get up
we had also some broken deployments to
get lab comm with cost us a lot of
trouble so we knew that we are going to
need end-to-end testing framework
and in good luck we are using merge will
request workflow which means that we
have at depend on code review but code
review is also not a silver bullet
because sometimes contracts between
interfaces are not clearly visible in
the code so in the past we had a merge
sequence which was basically one-liner
reviewed by a few senior developers and
no one was able to spot the bug in the
code so before that we'll probably need
to build an end-to-end integration
testing framework we discussed our goals
and we decided that we need to make it
possible to run tests in the CIE CD
environment to automate testing we also
decide that we need to test installation
process the deployment process that we
want to make it easy to locally
reproduce failures and with that and
that we also want to run tests against
aging production or any other
installation like on-premises
installation these were our goals but
our ultimate goal was to make it
possible to run end-to-end tests in
merge request to catch bugs before even
merging them to a stable branch or
master branch we knew that we're going
to use continuous integration to
automate testing and continuous
integration is a software development
practice where you wear code is
integrated frequently and were quite
lucky because we had our own integrated
github CI CD solution that's an
integrated product you can use that
whenever you push code to github to see
continuous integration feedback in merge
requests it's a free open-source
software part of the github community
edition as well so a few notes about
github CI CD logo in the in the middle
it's a github instance when we describe
github CIC architecture we refer to
github instance as a coordinator the
satellites around our github runners and
you can add a runner to the project you
can have multiple runners and runners
are going to
all coordinators API in order to pick
builds process them and dimension would
push changes a push will result to the
merge request github runner also
supports workflow with work clothes with
brain tests with Dockers so end-to-end
testing is a great use case for using
containers we knew that we want to cover
scenarios like updating get lab from
latest major version to current version
or using github CRI to test github CI so
we wanted a test scenario where we could
start the container with gait lab
register runner and see pipelines being
processed correctly but how to do that
how to design sort of framework like
that so in github one of our core values
is iteration so we decided that we are
going to trust iteration again and with
that and that we need to start very
simple so we created a separate project
called github QA we decided to use Ruby
capybara WebKit and r-spec tools because
these were tools that get labs
developers were already familiar with
and we created our first and to end
integration testing scenario as you can
see it's very simple we have a main page
that we are using to sign in using
credential credentials and then we
expect to see text signing successfully
on a page so this is pretty simple and
page main is our first page object and
page object it's not a new pattern where
page objects is a widely used pattern in
end-to-end testing page objects are very
useful to abstract away things that you
can do on a page and later you can also
build some features on top of page
objects as you can see our page main
page object is plain old Ruby object
mixing mixing capybara DSL and using
capybara to fill in forms click buttons
and
check if there's some content on the
page we also added github CI
configuration file to run into an
integration test on every good push it's
also but it was also quite simple you
can see that we install some
dependencies like WebKit that we have
only one test job for testing gitlab
Community Edition using a feature called
services so we use services to start
container with github ze latest version
we export some environment variable and
then we just call a spec with capybara
which is testing github from the
container
later we'll refine our CI configuration
file it looks a little different
differently right now we are not using
services well we actually use docker in
docker cell service and being QA is a
wrapper around docker so we knew that
end-to-end testing is not really fast
and that we eventually will need to
heavily paralyze our pipelines so we
decided to design the tool in a way that
it's quite easy to paralyze tests so we
knew that we that tests have to be
idempotent and isolated but it's quite
easy to do that when you are actually
testing a stateful application so we
used feature in get lab called sub drops
so whenever we put up a gate lab to a
test harness we create a new sub group
and then we also create a separate
project for every test example which is
not particularly fast but because we can
paralyze everything and this is
something that we can actually optimize
later we decided to stick to this
approach in the next iterations we added
some page objects we implement new test
and then we encountered first major
problem like both I'm taking almost two
hours to build get lab package and
docker image that we later wanted to
test so before that maybe
we can run tests against nightly built
in 95 lines but feature like pipeline
schedules was missing also other
features that we could use like multi
project pipelines or multi-level
container registry images were missing
but we were lucky again because we could
build features that we needed to test
github so we started building features
but first we had to solve a problem of
merging gitlab community edition to get
good luck Enterprise Edition because
merge was happening once week which
caused fragile tests problem so there
are multiple definitions for fragile
tests my definition is that you have
fragile tests when your tests are not
able to adapt to changes in your
codebase so whenever you change
something in the codebase you constantly
need to update tests so imagine a
scenario like when some developer
changes a page layout in gate lock and
because we have a good documentation he
or she goes to the github QA project to
update patch object so we can test
github CI community edition but because
of the weekly c2e
emerge github Enterprise Edition was
instantly outdated and we had to wait
entire week before the next merge being
done so we decided to resolve the
problem by moving all instant test
scenarios to see e and te repositories
and from that point all our page objects
are living in exactly the same
repository like views and selectors that
page objects depend on our so we also
change the responsibility of the github
to a project which I told you was a
separate project and now it's test
environment orchestration tool week Emma
fie that it ended now available on
rubygems for everyone to use it also to
test their own instance in order to make
github QA
life easier we also had to dr. eyes our
test harness and then after a few more
iteration our building did a great job
with reducing the build time down to 20
minutes we are now merging people up
committee addition to Enterprise Edition
every three hours and this is an
automated process it's not really
relevant and important for github way
right now because after we move test
scenarios to see nte Enterprise Edition
logging behind is not a huge problem
anymore but it's much easier to develop
features when these two projects are
synchronized then we build some features
like pipeline schedules manual actions
and blocking manual actions multi-level
container registry post race and we
found a workaround for missing feature
called multi project pipelines and we
are now working on making it and making
it a first-class feature in gridlock
and then again imagine a scenario like
when a team of front-end developers
decides to rebuild a top navigation bar
in github like it's something that we
actually did have a release ago but they
don't know that there is a QA
subdirectory in the project holding all
the page objects we have so they forget
forgot to update page objects so how to
solve that problem we decided to solve
it by making it possible to couple every
page object with views and selectors
from the project and this is not a
perfect solution we're aware of that
it was kind of 20% after a third 80%
result solution for us and it would be
obviously much better to a certain
elements existence on generated page but
this is something that we plan to work
in the next iteration so but this
solution works for now works for us
pretty well now because whenever someone
pushes a code to github with views being
change or selectors
we have the job that verifies the
contract between page objects and views
that page object depends on in the
continuous integration so it's instantly
visible for developer that github QA is
not synchronized with the code that have
been changed we also decided to make it
easier for developers to contribute and
we designed the concept like give lab QA
factories this is this concept is very
similar to factory bot formerly known as
a factory girl project known for a lot
of Ruby on Rails developers so whenever
you design a factory you make it part it
is possible to add dependencies like
project factory depends on a group being
fabricated before fabricating project so
whenever in the code someone wants to
fabricate project but there is no
explicit explicit group assigned to the
factory we fabricate all the
dependencies including group for the
project and then we manage to add manual
action and with that change we are
checked our ultimate goal of bringing
github QA to merge requests so now
whenever someone clicks package queue a
manual action all the get upgrade tests
this code in a merge request from start
to finish and obviously because manual
actions are in github are optional which
means that this stage has been skipped
it's still possible to merge a merge
request without running end to end test
for your changes but we have this
feature called blocking manual actions
when when you make action blocking it's
not possible to merge Ameriquest until
action succeeds so now our github QA
process looks like this in the CEO an or
a II project someone figures QA action
QA action starts a brand new pipeline in
github omnibus project Clapham use
project is responsible for building gait
lab packages building with docker images
and pushing them to the registry and
also omnibus later triggers pipeline the
github to a project github QA pulls
images from the container registry
orchestrates test environment and runs
end-to-end tests against test
environment later we propagate pipeline
status upstream directly into the merge
request to make it possible for
developers to see the steps and now live
demo so I know that people at
conferences love live demos there are so
many things that can go wrong so so
let's hope that's going to work this
time so I'm going to open a new console
I'm going to make this text a little
bigger okay I think it's visible bigger
okay I think it's okay the second one as
you can see I have no containers running
now and now let's try executing comment
like get lab QA test instance in which
seee okay let's see what happens okay so
let's go up as you can see we add them
to pull docker image from docker hub
then we create a docker network and then
we start get lab with docker run because
it's the first run it will take a few
minutes for get up to configure itself
so it's happening here we have get la
pomme news project built in to get up
and it's omnibus doing its work here
yeah so I can show another thing that
might be interesting as you can see we
have test instance in which seee and now
let's go to our slide number 14 and you
can see
I think it's visible that in the CI
environment we have pretty much the same
comment and actually get lab - QA
comment is a wrapper around being away
so we are running exactly the same
comment in the continuous integration
like we can run locally using github QA
gem this is a common line interface that
comes from the gem that's available
Rubick gems
so let's go down to the bottom of the
build log it's taking a few minutes for
github QA to start get lab get lab needs
to configure itself so whenever we
trigger a package to a manual action in
mercy Quest the argument to the
developed way C stands for Community
Edition obviously but we can pass a new
URL to the image in the registry here
which means that we can test any image
we get lab this way ok so we are now
starting all the services a daughter in
the container as you can see that github
QA is now waiting for get up to start
and now I can go to my browser and enter
an address like get lab c e
nightly test yeah and i should be able
to log in to get lab as you can see we
have no projects and because our spec
suit is randomized our spec we decided
to run tests for creating an issue which
means that an issue should probably have
dependency for a project so we should be
able to see that here after refreshing a
few times
is the first one so we need to create
all these subgroups for them for the
github QA and give up Kwai sandbox
top-level group as well so it can take a
few seconds I think it should be already
here no not yet
maybe this is one of these things that
can go wrong
[Laughter]
let's wait till tomorrow yeah
okay let's maybe go to groups we have a
sound box created we have test name
space creator no project here yet
oh we have a project so next we have
text test for sacred variables we have
quite a few tests here but I want to
wait until r-spec select tests for
creating a new pipeline okay now we have
tests for the IP I creating camera quest
so we should see a project with a merge
request we have security variables so
now as I said we have all the tests
isolated and bind important and because
we create a separate project for every
test example these tests are completely
decoupled and isolated yes that's that's
that's why yes it was telling you about
parallelization right so we can paralyze
the statute and it will eventually run
much faster okay okay so we have now
test for CI CD pipelines so we are
pulling get lap runner we are running
and registering it and we are pushing
get lap CI why am L as you can see it
should be there so you can see that we
have pipelines running
we have pipeline with all the jobs one
job managed to succeed we have echo okay
job succeeded and yeah that's it so we
are now using get lab CI to test get lab
CI and we are using docker in
actually in docker so it can be quite
complex but it works okay so let's go
back to the slides okay so a few lessons
learned first lesson that we learned
that there is no silver bullet in
end-to-end testing because how you
end-to-end test your software heavily
depends on how you manage to shape
processes around deployment development
installation process so there's this
great paper by Fred Brooks about
essential complexity and accidental
complexity and that there is no silver
bullet in software engineering so I
think that is very relevant for
end-to-end testing because essential
complexity is you know a deciding factor
in how your end-to-end testing framework
is going going to look like another
another lesson learned is that testing
shows the presence not the absence of
bugs which in other words means that you
won't catch bugs in code that you don't
have tests nervous for so this is a
great quote by Edgar the Dijkstra who is
believed to be a great grandfather of
modern software development and testing
and I think that's that's true and that
we will eventually eat something more at
git lab to test github so I personally
believe that canary deployments on
kubernetes are a great huge thing being
able to incrementally roll out your
changes to your users using tools like
exceptions monitoring performance
monitoring security testing to guide you
until up to 100%
roll out is a huge thing and at github
we heavily bet on the kubernetes and we
are building a lot of features into
github to make testing gitlab easier and
because we are building features it'll
get love our users can also use this
rotary so
imagine a scenario when you can you need
test your software then you can feature
test your software then you can build a
package test it with a tool like github
QA and then start incremental rollout
guided by techniques like performance
monitoring exceptions monitoring and
security testing for example until you
reach 100% rollout and only then you
click a merge button in a merge sequence
because only using this strategy we'll
be able to know that your feature is
production ready before merging into the
stable or master branch I know that a
few companies are doing that already and
at github we are building a lot of
features to make this workflow possible
it might take us a few months together
to be able to test github this way but
we'll eventually probably gather and
we'll also build a lot of features that
other people can use so I believe that
products quality is not only a perfect
code products qualities a combination of
users happiness developers happiness
product managers happiness and company
well-being and I would like to end this
talk with a nice quote from Tom DeMarco
product quality is a function of how
much it changes world for the better
and I believe that github strives for
changing the world for the better
that's all thank you
questions well we are using so the
question is are we doing any testing
with real browsers so good luck QA uses
Google Chrome browser in a headless mode
took click you know stuff in the gate
lab we can also disable headless mode
and we can see in the real time what's
happening and how github create
navigates through the gate lab two
different types now only Google Chrome a
but now well it's a start it's the first
iteration right yes
future okay so the future despite of the
workflow with Mirchi quest that i
described to you is that we are now
working on cloud native helm chart to
make it possible to deploy get lab to
kubernetes and we are also going to use
home with github query because as i said
we also want to test deployment and the
installation process and currently we
are building a big monolithic docker
image which were testing we've developed
way but eventually we will have a stable
helm chart that will also use to create
a test environment and will need to run
github query against that this kind of
test environment that answer your
question okay thanks
yes we have Dockers running into Dockers
well this is quite complex so currently
we are using docker engine in the CIA
environment all our files are being
processed inside the docker so in order
to make the workflow the same locally
and in the CIA environment we have to
use docker in docker in the CI
environment doctoring docker is a
service so
well I'm not sure if I understand the
question okay so let's let's meet after
a talk so but I will try to explain
maybe I managed to get it right so in
github way we use docker in docker but
the architecture is quite complex github
QA is responsible for starting container
with github or multiple containers for
example in the test scenario where we
test get lab geo which is Enterprise
Edition feature so we need multiple
containers with good luck but we also
need to start container with instance
test scenario which we built whenever we
talk a new version of github or whenever
we build github we also build a
corresponding integration test docker
container so in order to make it
possible to execute test we linked
containers together but also inside the
container with test we have docker
available which we do by mounting socket
in the in the in the container so I'm
not sure if this answer is question yes
we also do that
well it is because in the CI environment
this is full the doctor in docker using
privilege mode but in the in the local
workflow
this is the single docker engine okay
now currently we only do click driven
testing so whenever we want to create a
project or something like this we click
our wafer get lab to create a project
group and all the things we're thinking
about making possible to use the API to
speed up the process a little but
currently we are only testing API so we
are not using API to create resources
our gait lab quick factories depend on
only page objects currently yes of
course we have you need to test we have
integration tests we have feature tests
and integration tests on top of the
testing program pyranose right so we
have a test scenario using get lab QA
which is going to start container with
previous version mount some volumes
share them and after the after stopping
the previous container we use the same
volume use to start the new one and the
code inside the container is responsible
for updating gate lock no we don't we
don't use proceeded data okay yes
that we want to express we don't know
well not really usually users that
encounter bugs submit issues with the
description and we have in our issue
tracker something like ten thousands of
issues which huge part of these are bags
its which is perfectly normal in that
project in that scale but yeah so did
lab clay is still in early development
phase we would learn to make it easier
to write tests to use domain-specific
language and stuff like that but as you
told you we plan to iterate and yeah
and that's it well yes of course we when
we design github Kawai we had to make it
possible to fail the CI pipeline
whenever developed we encounters an
Engram integration problem and we do
that so we we check for example exit
status of the docker engine binary right
we also whenever we encounter exception
on the page we also failed the pipeline
so we we had to incorporate a lot of
techniques like this into the get
upgrade
okay so I think that that's all thank
you very much for listening I really
appreciate you coming thanks again
[Applause]