hi everyone my name is Yuri benzylic and
I am an in-house counsel in a Volvo we
are from slack eeeh and I'm really glad
to be here with you today some notes at
the beginning we are overwhelmed we are
working on an identity management system
which is open-source but it's obvious
because otherwise we probably wouldn't
be here but we truly are confessors of
an open-source approach and in the next
next 2 minutes I will show you why I
consider identity management system to
be an appropriate solution for the gdpr
and disclaimer at the beginning these
are my own views at and this is not to
be considered as legal advice let's look
what this presentation is going to be
about first we will look whether the
privacy is important or not then I will
show you the reasons that led to the
gdpr in my opinion after I we will look
at steps you need to take to achieve
compliance and finally I will show you
how we deal with the GDP are using our
identity management system now we have
that out of the way
so who here thinks the privacy is
important well I do too
but I don't have such feeling about the
behavior and the activity of many people
online this day these days especially
the young people doesn't really seem to
care they tend to provide their set
their personal data to service provider
every time he requires it and with no
real consideration I have heard a really
interesting view on the matter from an
attorney of privacy advocate of Edward
Snowden a journalist called
when Greenwald who spoke about how
people think about their privacy he
spoke about the former CEO of Google
Eric Schmidt who said that if you have
something you don't want other people to
know maybe you shouldn't be doing it in
first place
and that is the opinion of people who
say the privacy doesn't matter but they
don't actually believe it and the way
you know they don't believe it is that
with their actions they take all kinds
of steps to prevent and to safeguard a
privacy they put passwords on all their
accounts and they lock themselves in
bathrooms because everyone needs to
protect his own realm maybe you have
noticed when this CEO of Google Eric
Schmidt ordered Google employees not to
talk to CNN magazine interviewers after
CNET published an article full of
personal information about Eric Schmidt
and his family all of the information
obtained through Google searches and
using other Google products this speaker
gangrena also did an interesting or
rather ridiculous experiment including
all the people he met who claimed the
privacy didn't matter to them because
they had nothing to hide
every time you heard it he took out his
pen wrote down an email address and
wanted them to send him passwords to all
their email accounts not just two
official ones but to all of them he just
wanted to throw through what they were
doing online and if they were not bad
people there was nothing to hide it
would expect there wasn't any email on
this account it was left the real
resides in the end and the reason behind
it is that we as the human beings even
those of us who in words the exclaimed
the importance of privacy instinctively
understand the profound importance of it
it is known that the humor human are
social animals it's been known for
thousands of years on the one hand we
need an attention of other people this
is why social media are so successful
recently but on the other hand it is
truly essential to fulfill our nature as
human beings is to have a place where we
can go and hide from judgmental eyes of
other people because everyone has things
to hide and this is why I consider the
privacy to be important
and by seeing the importance of privacy
we may understand the importance of the
gdpr even though the gdpr looks like a
bunch of onerous duties for the data
controller but how often do we hear
about information leakage compromising
of confidential data and other data
breaches and still the vast majority of
people doesn't bear in mind the threats
and what is more the consequences of
data breaches you is not only losing
money you may lose respect reputation
trust and in the end wall online
identity so what is the GD P R I don't
think there is anyone who hasn't heard
about the GD P R in the last year but
just in case there was someone who
hasn't heard about it I will tell you
what it is even though the GD P R was
published more than two years ago nobody
really seemed to care at the beginning
and now I feel the GD P Armenia is
raging in the corporate area I realized
the seriousness of the situation when I
heard an advertisement on GDP our
solution at our regional Eastern
Slovakia radio for better understanding
and imagination why the GD P R is just
inevitable and natural outcome of
current cyber environment we must say it
has his own history and it's been coming
for years the discussion started more
than six years ago and Commission
Council and Parliament took part in
debate all of them required to make many
compromises to achieve result in the
form of joint proposal of European
deregulation GDP our general data
protection regulation GDP our being a
regulation means it's direct obligatory
nature to the Member States before the
GDP are there was a Data Protection
Directive something like a framework for
data protection but it was mandatory for
all Member States
to enact the specific elect this
old-fashioned fractured approach was
causing many ambiguities for the
companies operating in an international
environment the measure sufficient in
one jurisdictions jurisdiction strictly
were not enough in another country
therefore the companies needed to make
many alterations and modifications and
it raised costs heavily this costs
definitely weren't effective so the
harmonization was desperately needed the
GDP our deals with all layers of data
protection there are principles to be
maintained and there are rights of data
subjects to give effective but the tool
for achieving compliance isn't strictly
prescribed or defined the solution is up
to data controller to choose the right
one for achieving compliance within his
organization and this feature makes the
GDP our dynamic law what is unusual
because law by its nature is your
usually strict and rigorous and the data
protection by design and by default by
virtue of the article 25 of the GD P R
makes it a dynamic enactment main
reasons why the gdp gdp r had to be
enacted sooner rather than later even
though many fought to postpone its
effective date are in my opinion these
for advancing technology the rise of
technology has never been at such level
at as it is nowadays and there are many
use in which the personal data might be
misused there is business with personal
data big data analyzes companies and
profiling companies you know big data
analyzes is a process x mining large
sets of data to uncover patterns
correlations and customer preferences
with one main target to sell more this
company's trade with personal data and
it means even more risk for personal
data to be abused another reason is that
data protection laws are archived in
comparison
to the technology what if in fact it is
one of the main features of law and it
is needed force for legal certainty but
the gdpr makes a step forward to make it
a dynamic enactment and finally
harmonization as I said there was live
there were different laws in all Member
States and it was causing problems with
interpretation so the gdpr aims to
resolve these problems and to harmonize
this branch of law so this is the
background but the most important
question is how to become compliant this
is the most difficult question and I
might disappoint many of you but I doubt
there already is a conclusive answer
I've been working with the gdpr
regularly for more than half a year
studying it writing in Verilog attending
conferences supporting our technical
team I have even been on an individual
session and our national DPA and with
every answer I was looking for three new
questions arose a few days ago a good
friend of mine called and asked me hey
dude have you heard about the QPR or
something I said do you mean the gdpr
well maybe something with the data
protection well I may know a bit about
it but I realized there might be a
problem with explanation he is an
advocate with no technical background a
really good one but he hasn't read the
world gdpr and he just expected me to
recommend him a complete solution which
I unfortunately didn't have the gdpr is
so complex and has so many requirements
that I can think about one tool to
overcome it all mm for this small to
mid-size solar company it was enough to
implement internal direct directive have
the company protects personal data in
fact you didn't even have you didn't
even respect its provision unless there
was a data breach nobody cared and this
is going to change with the GDP are the
data protection will
to be adopted into daily operations this
is the main change DPR brings and it's a
it's an accountability so far the DPA
could come to your office and start
auditing have you protect personal data
actually they would be looking for your
fault but now with the GD P are
effective you will have to manifest the
measures you use to protect personal
data if your company is big enough and
process large amounts of personal data
you will probably need a team to
implement gdpr project
the combines could be achieved only as a
cooperation of all subjects who come in
touch with personal data first thing you
need to do at the beginning you will
have to realize support from key
stakeholders within your organization
and make the privacy the priority then
you will need to assign the team the
thing I would choose would consist of a
lawyer to interpret doula information
security officer to design and implement
measures into internal systems and also
some people to help with data mapping it
would be probably HR specialists and
some financial officers for the person
in charge of a gdpr project I would
strongly recommend he ensures that he
has three pillars to build on people to
implement solution and to put the Data
Protection into daily operations then we
will need the money actually the
solutions are quiet expensive but you
may use you may save some resourcing
using open source products while I'm not
saying it would be for free and time one
of the crucial assets because an average
time for implementing gdpr solution in
mid-sized solar company was
approximately 10 months including both
technical side and documentation
these are the steps you need to take to
achieve compliance first data mapping
you have to know where the personal data
are being stored and processed between
your organization to be able to protect
it then you will need a good data
governance because it must be able to do
various operations with the data or like
handling subject access requests or
approving the accountability you must
also be able to identify the data
categorize it or in some cases to carry
out the data protection impact
assessment the data safety will be
usually understood as as an encryption
and it will be the choice of the most
controllers and the you will have to
take into account the state of the art
and the nature of processing to ensure
privacy by design and you should choose
the opt-in style for processing the data
to ensure privacy by default there are
many rights of data subjects and you
have to give effect to all of them so I
will give you some brief information
some important tips what you should do
and you should give the data subjects
the information all the information you
have actually you should keep it simple
and don't use legalese you know this
archive language of old lawyers who are
now facing the extinction but you should
make it really intelligible so the data
subjects would be able to understand it
and you must also show all the data you
are processing and you have to inform
later subjects about their rights about
all the rights they have then you should
give a control to data subjects over the
data
you should be able to provide them
access to the data and to show them what
data were processing how when and how we
protect it then there is also a
brand-new data portability law there
data portability right that should
enable moving personal data between
controllers at data subjects wheel you
should also be prepared to modify the
data as the data subjects have right for
the rectification and you should be able
to stop processing the data whenever the
data subject wants it because the other
subjects have a right to object to
processing and finally you should there
is data minimization principle it is one
of the most the one of the core
principle of the gdpr and so you should
gather and keep only necessary
information you should choose lawful
basis really carefully carefully and you
should choose the purpose for your
processing really carefully because once
it's run out you can't hold the data any
longer and you should also be prepared
to delete completely the data when the
data subject uses his right to be
forgotten so how about the solution
there will be enormous demand for
solutions for sure leading software
companies and law firms are in the race
to present their solutions as soon as we
have read through the gdpr
we realized that is what we can do that
is what Identity Management can do or
you have to have the lawful basis to
process personal data and you should be
able to demonstrate demonstrate these
lawful basis there are several kinds of
lawful basis like consent
performance of a contract complying with
legal obligation or to protect vital
interest of data subjects or to purse of
personal related to data subject and you
should keep and you should be able to
keep and manage the data and identity
management software are excellent record
peepers identity data are being
monitored and managed by the IDM systems
there are there is data and metadata
therefore the IDM systems know what
happened when it happened and how it
happened for every existing account in
IBM system there must be a reason why
this account exists and the reason for
existence of the account who would be
the lawful basis for processing let's
look at the technical side very briefly
lawful basis for processing would be
modeled as an assignment the target of
this assignment would be a data
protection scope which will be modeled
as a specific type overall and all the
legal details would be specified in this
role in this data protection scope and
lawful basis will be activated by
creating an assignment to this specific
role so this could automatically trigger
the provisioning of all accounts and it
works also in the other way so if the
lawful basis expires it means the data
would the account would be automatically
de provisioned there are many things
many things that the identity management
solution could do you can do manage
concern because there are require there
are strict requirements for constant it
must be grand or worried and you may
manage it really granule with using
identity management you can also solve
request for
rectifications and request for the
Ovation so dealing with the right to be
forgotten and it should be really good
tool for the data protection officer for
accountability because it has really
good data mapping usage and at the end I
will show you the screens from the from
the solutions it's not a really good
readable but there is a card for data
protection and all the information
necessary to comply with legal
obligation will be specified here and
you can manage all connected systems
with with identity management system and
there are lawful basis for any map you
might be able to see all the lawful
basis for every account in this tool so
that's all
[Applause]
thank you so let's open up the floor for
questions yes
I don't hear you Internet Protocol I am
NOT a technician so if the Internet
Protocol is GDP are combined I can
answer it I not a technician no for
automated processing and for databases
for filing systems it is if the if it is
for if the GDP are is applicable for the
paper yes yes for databases for every
filing system and it might be a paper
database also
however how could you do what so what
they're connected there are systems
connected okay how could you be
completely compliant with the gdpr I
said that the toe isn't strictly
described or prescribed and that I can't
even think about one tool to overcome it
all but this will be this door handle
some crucial situations with connected
systems