so from one Michael to the next this is
Michael chroma vice president of
technology architecture carbonyl and
he's going to talk about how we can
convert our open source projects a
profitable to profitable business not
only in the financial way given up last
fall Michael thank you very much I'd
like to start with a big big thank you
for all the event organizers it's really
amazing it's it's I don't know my fourth
or fifth time it paused them and it's
every year really amazing so big
applause for a husband thank you so
let's start off this whole talk is not
going to be about political correctness
not whatsoever that's the fun thing when
you're also in a business world you
don't have to be but you will see that
not only business guys have to be
politically correct also in communities
they often don't need to so this talk is
really can be offending to some people I
know many of these people so they won't
have a big issue with it yeah where mine
I am my name is Michael I live now a
long time in Germany I'm an open source
guy enthusiast I I've committed codes to
many projects asterisk Linux kernel
VirtualBox many others I really truly
believe in the values of open source
software or generally the free and open
source movement so don't get me wrong
you can also check it up in the big
Internet
so but many of the statements that you
will see today will be a little bit
contrary and that's absolutely
intentional because it's a little bit
also what I want to try to make is a
wake-up call because in general most
free and open source fundamentalists the
relief that they are mutually exclusive
to business and there are many counter
examples I'm sure you know many of them
but my before
Michael was bringing out quite some nice
things in terms of funding and how you
can actually deal with it and and yeah I
I just try to show you my view of the
things as you realize I'm I just kept in
force ajita which is which unfortunately
got ill there's going to be a reference
later to her so I think she liked it
first of all we want to start off with
definitions these are the oxford
dictionary definitions of what a
community is and what a businesses so
the community is is traditionally just a
group of people living either in the
same place or having a common
characteristic pattern and businesses
while businesses just have the intention
of earning money right regular
occupation profession or trade as it's
in a definition it's not just a person
it must just not be a physical person
but it can also be a natural person like
an organization corporation whatsoever
so when you take two quotes from to
hopefully not unknown men to you
one being Richard Stallman and one being
Steve Jobs you could in my opinion
interchange them not saying that Richard
Stallman would say the same than Steve
Jobs but I think also Richard in the
meanwhile realizes that things can
really be done by a single man and these
are two men which really did a lot of
things one more in the open source world
one more in the communication and
electronics world but both had an impact
both made something real big and yeah
which it is one of the guys why we're
basically also here today but this
general mass perception of community and
business to each other especially from
the view of fundamentalists is this that
a community is always the good ones and
business is always a bad ones just think
of all the battles that we have with
large corporations such as Microsoft
which we're yeah they're just evil they
want to make money and who cares about
them and we just want to be free we want
to be open we want to share data that's
all true but the thing is is look at a
company like Microsoft now they open
source key core technologies of them not
all of them and maybe they'll get there
I don't know but for certainty
corporation is also nothing else but a
community maybe with slight different
visions may with slight different you
know tools or ways to do it but just
saying that a business is money driven
and there are the evil guys that just
doesn't work and most people think it's
either either a dictatorship in the
worst case or maybe a monarchy because
you have yeah your traditional King and
that's it
but even in the community world not
every community is the same as the other
some have really moral intentions they
want to do something pretty good they
want to protect your data they want to
make sure that you can use things in a
free way you have the transparency
obviously you want to know what's what
the computer is doing essentially you
don't want to get ads for something that
you don't ask for so these every
community has has has its own goals
essentially and as in any case
communities as corporations they just
also do it in all some products they
want to try a solution to a problem
so GPG is a good example GPG tries to
protect your data from prying eyes
alright so you can encrypt you can
decrypt you can share you can you know
just deal with your data in a way where
you think this is the data that I want
to see protected this is nothing of
anyone else's business
some communities unfortunately do lack a
vision they have some ideas they think
of yeah we want to go there we want to
go there but in the end they just always
hunt the next iteration yeah they fix
hundred bugs they move on to the next
one this happens especially to projects
and I want to give a good example
space walk for example raise your hands
if you know what space walk is not too
many so space walk is actually the core
backend upstream component from Red Hat
Red Hat satellite five which is used as
a conflict management and update and
patch management solution space work was
is really a cool product no matter what
I personally at least loved it
but they don't have any vision anymore
because they our I have to correct
myself because Red Hat has decided to
say like well spacewalk is okay but we
just you know make Foreman and puppet
and whatsoever we we make our new set of
like six and that's where actually the
company they decided all we have a
different direction but spacewalk is
still not dead but they don't have a
vision anymore so any community needs a
vision where do I want to be in a
certain amount of years also is also a
little bit from a definitions point this
here is the kernel 4.9 based on the
contributions that have been made to the
linux kernel from
individuals with their yeah employer
basically so when you look at this you
will see Lennar oh yeah is it's a great
organization especially when you when
you take a whole device world into but
also intel is contributing a lot and
many others open source organization and
close source or your organization's in
fact you i don't think you see them here
even and I'm also not a Microsoft Amboy
but Microsoft has also contributed hack
a lot of code into the Linux kernel of
course it's helping their own business
but that's the way it is so don't miss
precept a community with a project
that's also what's happening very often
especially in a Linux world this is
actually a little bit outdated but this
is from great crow Hartman officially
from yeah what they brought up in a
Linux Foundation how much single
individuals especially in the large
project or the largest project
open-source project like the Linux
kernel has to do so we can thank all
these guys in doing such a great job
Greg Hartmann without him
the car wouldn't look as it does now so
but in the end the reality about a
community and the businesses they both
share the same general idea if you're
part of the Liberal office team you
might envision and say like I want to
make sure that everyone has free access
to an office suite and actually I want
to make that product so good that there
is no one else that this is the main
project because everyone who puts his
time even if it's like you don't often
get paid for what you do but just in
that case extremely want to want to see
that this is really moving forward so
you sort of have a vision for what this
community moves towards - and also
that's one of the reasons why a project
you know there are many projects that
are evaluated for its activity for
example half a year or something didn't
happen good example I can give you here
is open change open change had the best
intentions possible they had as a goal
to say we want to implement the DC RPC
protocol for Microsoft in an open source
way and get rid of exchange altogether
the goal was nice but the backing of it
was horrible indeed with one guy only
leaving literally the project died
unfortunately because that's not what
change is about an open source is about
so in very short words community and
businesses have quite similar ideas of
how they want to move forward and it's
nothing bad I mean look at the Linux
kernel there is no question and as a
number of millions of devices that are
on the planet the Linux kernel is
dominating the world and it's good it's
really good and we do want it in any
case so looking at those based on our in
a comparison the community and the
businesses the community or communities
in general have ethical purpose they
want to do things in a better way than
others
they want to do it in an open and a
liberal transparent way all the things
that I just mentioned but there are also
communities that also are profit
oriented right so profit oriented let's
take a foundation for example if a
foundation wouldn't work sort of profit
oriented well then they could not afford
all the things that are they are doing
maybe also paying once in a while a
developer or you know just making sure
he has the travel expenses compensated
and whatsoever so at some point the
profit is not really like they get cash
out someone but they use their profit to
grow the project and that's a good thing
also community there are many many many
people who are very politically touched
especially in open source free and open
source movement world people say and
there was a great talk from Richard
Richard from openSUSE who really said
well not every community has to be a
democracy and that's good so I will
bring up some examples where you can
actually see that point even even
doubled also in this comparison
businesses businesses are always very
focused on intellectual property
obviously because they invested into it
now there are main companies you have
people that take money put it into an
organization to pay the bills to pay
people developers to pay infrastructure
to to do all that stuff and yeah
communities often get this by by by
donors and and whatsoever so the thing
is from how they are acting it's
obviously not exactly the same but they
have quite some important similarities
so let's take a stupid example I admit
but I just love it at first then this
event as I just started my talk off it
is a really community-based project and
it's now yeah 20 years and I hope it
will be the next hundred years because
this is really great and the spirit is
awesome and when you get when I get a
water you pay one year old and that's
good because
every every to honor you pay actually
gets into the donation and makes sure
that the infrastructure here is paid and
that we have yeah all the all the cool
stuff that we have here power and so on
you get my point
let's take a stupid other example which
is very recent red had bought for 250
million a company which essentially had
free software open source so who knows
about this murder or about this purchase
hands up see a lot of people do that's
great because this is exactly also what
communities are about they are worth
something because there are people
behind it and people that make a
difference
this technology is important towards red
hat and red hat is also an open source
company everything that they do is
really open source I give you an example
when you take red hat enterprise
virtualization for example but in Red
Hat Enterprise virtualization it is it's
about product for a red head at the time
and what they did is they just thrown
out the windows server and just replaced
it by rewriting everything based on over
so it's an example of business and
community working really well together
redditor has the interest because there
are shareholders behind there they want
to make sure that you that that's yeah
they can pay everything and but they do
it in a more much more ethical way that
just fits so if you translate you are 50
million and two water bubbles just
imagine how fast and would look next
year okay so I also want to give you a
little bit more practical example of
what we've been doing Capano
is something that you earliest could
have heard of two and a half years ago
because we as Capano we were formerly a
company called suratha they had multiple
reasons and I really know what I'm
talking about because zurafa was a
company that had a tagline that said
best open-source exchange drop-in
replacement and that was yeah that was
the truth it was great but we were in
open court company open court company
says we
have about 90% or xx percent on open
source code and the rest you have to pay
for our bill was actually delivering a
real choice for business customers so
business customers tend to have money
right so we didn't to be very honest and
really much care about community in
general we had some we had some a lot of
partners and stay brought in their
things but we reviewed them and
everything and so on you know the game
but in the end what are we now we're
100% open source not one line of code is
closed
the only implementation of open source
market back in in Walt that's from us
and we now strive for higher goals and
these higher goals we want to see
working together with a community these
higher goals are not how can I say just
making more business customers because
then we could have stayed as we are our
goal is is to make something better than
a product that we originally wanted to
replace that's why work better than a
Microsoft Outlook replacement the thing
is so Rafa had a past of over 10 years
he's 10 years we had one product that we
wanted to challenge and that was
Microsoft Outlook that's email contacts
tasks notes and calendar this product
though is just staying as it is from a
feature set it doesn't really change
much but we as human beings we've
changed a lot
we do have web meetings now we do have a
lot of requirements in terms of document
management and so on and when we would
have stayed with Outlook like other
projects also stick to their thing just
forever and ever till the end of time
well then the project will get
irrelevant at some point and our thing
is is providing a real choice for
business customers and anyone else so
the benefit to the community is you can
run a raspberry pie run your Capano have
fun with it we don't care about it but
when it comes to the business world if
you say like hey I want to I want to
have a supported environment I need
clustering whatever and I want the
cluster set up by someone who really
knows what
doing no matter what then you have a
company behind there because there are
people professionals that get salaries
paid and that have a great time in this
community because nothing else is also a
company it's a community to make things
work in a better way so from a community
perspective there's nothing better to
achieve to get downstream in the
distribution to spread the word to make
it available to all of them this is the
example of Capano it's an open Sousa
it's going to be in Debian 10 it's going
to be a noble tool and also one of the
things that I want to bring up and
that's one strong thing that Michael
before me also brought up don't look at
your community as that's only the it's
the best in the world and no one else
next to me because that simply doesn't
work there are more liberal persons that
say hey you know what we're actually
doing a little bit similarities like
this whole I mean by aura tea is good
right dr. Alex yeah Alex tea and so on
it's good but when it comes to common
ground sometimes it would be nice to you
know reach over the aisle and just ask
hey guys how are you doing that let's do
it together
let's maybe make it and this project
happen and that's what we did a scope on
a core when we open sourced
we just said like yeah we're not open
sourcing all the stuff to be honest we
actually rewrote a lot of our components
but we also took a lot of external
dependencies into account on software
that we base on so when you see a look
at this Coverity graft and you will see
it at that point in time we thought like
hmmm let's take the external
dependencies into account and our
so-called Coverity score which covers
the defects of hundred thousand lines of
code or how many defects there are
enough in each hundred thousand lines of
code then we had a quite horrible score
compared to the average average of how
many defects are generally in open
source but then we started to say like
well ok that's the way we go
so we also fix that software a good
example is G soap also good examples my
spell and that's how
also a community can help you seen that
on a Linux kernel and you also see it
for example with us when you as a
company have a have a goal or you as a
community have a goal you can also take
all these dependencies into account but
you should not could so your
worldview just have to have this
comparison this area a business can be
ethical as well we did everything out
the source and we recommend everyone
even even big players already realized
that it's the best way to go we can have
morally good intentions social
environment whatsoever yes we want to be
also able to pay salaries and and
hosting and whatsoever and generally if
you if you run a company in a good way
then you're not doing it like a
dictatorship or a monarchy people
especially the fundamentalists live like
the practice of I don't want to get told
what I have to do real company doesn't
work that way a real true free and open
source thinking company doesn't do so my
point about going back to free and open
source software I really recommend that
you forget anything about democracy in
open source world to be honest that
simply well it works but it works badly
and I can give you proof of it and I
think you will agree on that this is one
of the political correctness things
please note the stock replaces love what
you do every day and Aunt Betty loved
when you did this and I have to say it's
good that he did that because it was a
wake-up call to the media which was
actually the recipient of this photo
Nvidia had the idea of we have to
protect our intellectual property we
don't want other competitors to just
take our code and make better GPUs and
whatsoever so my thing is this is
clearly the unmatched top guy he's the
king of Linux and no one I will get to
the back to that also later no one will
challenge that for many reasons and we
have someone like
- basically the prince of linux if you
can call it that way he's the guy who's
making sure that we have a stable kernel
he's the maintainer of the stable
branches so all in all together to
summarize the Linux kernel yes it is as
ethical as it gets free code a free
platform to run your applications no
matter where you are it's as transparent
as it gets it costs no money you can run
it anywhere have fun with it so tomorrow
we'll good intentions as well as well
are there as well yeah for the social
part there's a cool movie called anger
management Lina's watch that you'll have
fun it's non profit I already mentioned
and the most important part about any
community and company in my opinion at
least and I'm doing this now for quite
long time is really do it merit-based
I know a community like libera offers
for example can say like you know anyone
is at the same level because the reality
and the truth is not everyone is when
you get started on a project and you
want to grow into it of course you can
start at the absolute top at the
absolute bottom level and just say hey
maybe I do a little bit translation
every bit helps it's important no matter
what but certain projects have had quite
some interesting developments by just
giving the wrong people the right credit
and that's quite important because also
a community also community based project
should always go by what the merit is of
that each person from the business side
well you won't find many free and open
source projects that get that much
funding and it's good that way but
there's also a big but who has ever
attended Linux column hands up please
okay recommendation please do Linux kana
is really recommended and there is a
t-shirt well there has been I don't know
how it's this year or last year but many
years before hence there was a
fun t-shirt actually and there's a lot
of truth with it and said 2013 the year
of the Linux desktop 2014 the year of
the Linux desktop
guess what 2015 the same so the
reality is Linux is awesome it runs on
every desktop but it's not used on every
desktop and that is a pity and there's a
great blog post that I want to recommend
you from one of the gnome guys where why
hasn't the year of the Linux desktop
happened yet and you will bring up quite
some valid points
and one of them is this fragmentation
gnome in itself is a great project KDE
is a great project like lxd there are
great desktops that are available for
the linux world but they are fragmented
some work there
some don't work then we had some change
from X org you know this is seriously
when you want to have mass adoption
please we all know that we want to have
as a normal user when we want to bring a
laptop to someone and say hey try Linux
and he says like yeah ok Linux is not
equals Linux yes that's true and choice
is good but give it a good default we
and this is where I'm getting very
politically incorrect we have some great
standard called l FS l FS is it is
really it defines standards for common
usage within Linux it's amazing how many
don't
how many distributions don't give a
about l FS and that's where we have
fragmentation we have fragmentation
applications we have fragmentation
desktops we have fragmentation of usage
because everyone thinks he can do it
better and some of us some of us really
take changes look at what a boon to did
with with unity they realized hmm
we made maybe a mistake we should really
go back to the norm and they did and I
think we can learn from that step we
should try to unite more and stop
fragmenting everything because this is
where the real power of free and open
source movement comes from we can agree
to disagree on certain areas and we can
make things configurable we can make
them available on different premises No
what but I really and to be honest I see
this now for 20 years I am really pissed
off about that and I thank you really
much for this chance to bring this up
because this is not only my opinion when
you when you talk to many of the leaders
in open source areas I just had a talk
today from someone from Postgres he says
like you know what I built up my
business based on Postgres and the
community just doesn't understand what I
tried to tell them he's trying it really
hard but it just doesn't work so every
good open-source project needs good
marketing and needs good structure and
it doesn't have to be democracy stop
requesting that everything has to be a
base democracy because you're hurting
your own project so as good marketeer
this is the stack of Capano that's it
thank you
[Applause]
any questions oh yeah it works questions
raise your hand we'll make sure
microphone spawns in front of you oh
sorry I didn't see you
okay first thank you for this speech I
would like to ask you how big companies
affect standards and in turn how they
affect the communities which implement
these standards to be honest I have not
understood you well can you repeat
please how big companies affect the
standards and how these standards
effects let's say the software we are
building because for example when you
are talking about open abis you always
find the big fish something like okay no
Microsoft could brought that stuff
you're more under standard ization part
as far as I understand you okay so for
from the standardization point I must
say that even the big players have
learned about it if you take protocols
like DC RPC that was invented like 25
years ago they made it closed obviously
at the time and they've realized that
that they benefit actually when people
can interoperate with their stuff so
actually the the big corporations
generally from at least what I see have
adapted that they realize actually we
can make more business if we're open and
let just the others integrate we just
have to go merit-based we have to make
our products better than that and at
some point when you look at the desktop
stack as I as I used that as a basis
they're like big gnome DFS and gnome BFS
too and incompatible changes back and
forth there's a good reason why let us
say said we don't make user space
incompatible changes and that's a good
that's really good this is one in my
opinion perfectly executed open-source
project but there are many others like
rocket chat and so on but let's take
Microsoft for example they're one of
their latest developments is the
Microsoft graph API completely
transparent completely not the same as
it was before because they just say hey
if you want to use our API just use it
have fun with it it's actually the same
mentality as free and open source
projects run but the reality is is that
especially in an open source world this
is not happening often enough there are
enough examples of that you know there's
like in chat upstairs 10 solutions now
for chat ups the one is better the one
is worse it's all started from from
slack which is a good product but then
all kinds of new products showed up and
they all say hey I have a bigger sorry
not politically correct I have a better
be a bigger dick than you that's
essentially the reality in the project
sorry we have to stop the Q&A ROG here
the next speaker is in the line I'll be
around at the Cabana booth yeah thank
you thank you for the talk
and thank you for the insight
[Applause]