I'm Alex Angie and I will be talking
about um component which is our vision
of the secure mobile platform but why do
we need this anyways it's always a bit
hard to keep up with all the security
incidents incidents that that happened
and originally I plan to use as a
motivating example something from last
year where Google keep tracking your
location and sending it to its service
even though you had location disabled
but then last week I came came across
this news from a German newspaper which
said that the German Federal Police is
able to monitor you on your messaging
your whatsapp traffic for example or any
other messenger for that matter and how
do they do that are they able to break
the crypto as we as you may or may not
know on decrypted and current messengers
is pretty strong and they're the
protocols have verified partly and so on
no they do not have broken the Crypt or
anything um they get your messages
before they get encrypted and after they
have been decrypted for the other way
and that's a problem if your platform
actually so they install the throw and
horse on your mobile phone and get the
messages even though you're doing and do
encryption and apparently that's a
problem and we can talk what our ideas
are what you do about this so first I
will tell you a bit about the challenges
we have and why these these smartphones
are so problematic when it comes to
security and and strong strong
encryption then we talk about our
objectives in the project and I will
tell you what we are using which
technologies we are using what the on
what the architecture of a trusted
system should look like and it's another
interesting question - also on get the
throw in horse problem in under control
how can we implement a high assurance a
trustworthy platform so it really that's
what we want to do and cannot be hacked
and it's all a bit about
our platform is looking like or what we
plan for the future and of course there
what the current state is it and what we
do in the future so there are actually a
couple of problematic three big issues
in the smartphone platforms one thing is
at the hardware level and this is really
nasty as the isolation between the radio
networks you are using on be dead Wi-Fi
Bluetooth or even though the the radio
network they are not very well isolated
and so it is possible that an attacker
that's on the radio network that has for
example set up a fake base station or
Sega set up a fake hot spot he can bring
your device under control and
subsequently actually do what what if
what the police and also malicious
hackers are doing on get access to your
data there are a couple in all of these
examples are from the last year there
are a couple of incidents that
demonstrate here that this is an issue
for example the pro pone arm weakness
last year where someone which allowed an
attacker to get your application process
under control from from a Wi-Fi network
so without any interaction no clicking
some malicious link or opening email you
you're not supposed to open it's really
like a passive attack and then your
phone gets hacked another like Samba
listy is a blue blue born a something
comparable to this but over bluetooth
you can't even have your Bluetooth
disabled and your device not in this
coverable mode doesn't matter so unless
you have patches for this someone could
take control over over your device
without your interactions and lastly
that's also a hardware issue the
basement processor which is the one
that's actually talking to the radio
network has had to say the same issues
in the past and I also was some
something with wow I out subsets I
believe in the last year
which is comparable and could be
exploited from the Radio Network that's
obviously not good but there's more to
come you may have heard of the stage
fright vulnerability that was something
that came up in July 2015
[Music]
millions of devices were affected by
that and it was as simple as sending you
some media content like a video stream
and that would then um allow an exploit
it would would be able to exploit the
media server which is the central thing
that that's all the media decoding in
Android and take control over over your
device because this has rather high
privileges I did some some calculations
or I I got the figures because I was
wondering is that is that resolved
meanwhile um so that was 2015 when when
state fight was was in the media I was
was a hot topic but since then as you
can see in the graphics the the number
of critical bugs actually has not really
declined so it's it's sometimes only
only a handful or one or two bucks but
sometimes we also have ten or twenty
bucks per month that effect is not
immediate subsystem and can potentially
be used to get your system under control
so this is another big issue and all by
sending you something like a picture or
video something that you probably get
every day there are these other leads
third class of privacy issues
um so privacy leaks the Android platform
is not really built for keeping your
private of your data private because
private information is called is
considered the oil of the of the new
digital age so people want to get your
data of course there were several
incidents it's often last year like the
one I mentioned Google was tracking you
even throw your hat um the location
service disabled
they're worse for example that thing
with that keyboard that would send um
the suggestions you had in your you in
your address book into the cloud and
then that was a back but and it could
end up in a different person's keyboard
when you're suddenly had contact
information of of someone else in your
as I suggest in your keyboard so
apparently the current platforms do not
do very well when it comes to keeping
you your information really private the
only question is and I have answered
this that for myself
would you really do your banking
application with that kind of platform
given that it's rather fragile and there
are so so big attack surfaces so we want
to do something about that with the
component project firstly of course it's
it's open source you would have expected
that it's gonna be a platform for mobile
devices and the goal is to run
unmodified Android apps on a completely
new on a completely new operating system
but with high trust worthiness so
eliminating all the issues or hopefully
most of the issues that I've just
mentioned firstly we want to prevent we
we want to protect applications from
getting compromised we want to confine
applications so they cannot a bug in one
application cannot influence another
application or the whole system and for
and thirdly the user should remain in
control so that no one can decide to for
example fitted location information into
the cloud without the user really
knowing that or he will be in able to
switch that off so
but why our current systems so
problematic actually why do we see all
these issues so what we see here is a
typical typical overview of a monolithic
system and the problem here is that we
have large like that we have large
portions large monolithic kernel
portions like the Linux kernel and they
they implement complex features and so
when one app at one for example uses
that media framework that we have here
or the kernel this belongs to its
trusted computing base that means all
that needs to be correct for the
application to work correctly and if
there's a bug in any of these million of
lines of codes then this can also affect
other applications if they share one of
these big monolithic blocks and the
consequences is that the probability
that we have some bug that can be
exploited and has a has an impact on
other applications is rather high
because these are the trusted computing
base is so high and the chance for four
critical errors the issue now is we
cannot really avoid that complexity
because media decoding is a complex
process networking is a complex process
but we can manage it cleverly and for
this we use the G note OS framework
which is another open source project and
it has the nice property that has a
recursive system structure which
facilitates a small trusted computing
base so if you see that tree here
there's a root which is the parent of
all the other processes as you might
might know it and this parent has
control of all its typos is it this will
typically be a micro code which only
this resource control in separation in
the system and the parent can need to
create everything out of its own
resources and has to full control so it
can also again remove the resources and
so we can start building a on a
recursive system structure where every
other child where every child all
makes up such a such a tree and again
has control about the subtrees this
allows for a small trusted computing
basis if you see that orange um
that orange application here the trusted
computing base is only what a horse in
the tree and maybe services that are
used and we can even reduce further to
trusted computing base so the create
application for example could implement
some very complex functionality like a
whole network stack or a driver but if
we have another application that trusted
wrapper for example does encryption
transparently that we do not need to
trust that that Network stack because
packets are the packets are encrypted
before they are sent out and so this is
outside of all trusted computing base
GNote supports a number of interfaces
for legacy apps also for example a
virtual machine environment where I can
run complete PC operating systems you
can run QT apps POSIX apps also in their
save device and environment for reusing
existing Linux device drivers if you
want to know more this the microcode def
rooms where they're the creators of
GNote are around so now when we have
these these components that that make up
the trusted computing base there's a
second question how do we make sure they
do the right thing
for this um we use spark which is
another open source technology this is a
language that's made for building on
high integrity applications it has a
strong type system which helps a lot I
mean it's it's designed the language is
designed for avoiding errors and what's
what's in particular nice it has a
formal contract so you can define this
you find invariants and pre-imposed
conditions I have a spark example to
come on the right and as you can see
there's their signal analysis tool that
that checks the checks the these
invariants and in line 11 for example
you see that something is wrong this
function is supposed to do to calculate
the absolute the absolute number of
something that's passed in their integer
access passed in and what we do is if X
is greater than zero we return it if X
is below zero then we return minus X so
that's something that probably most of
you would think it's a correct absolute
function that that calculates an
absolute value but if you're on the spot
tools they say okay here's something
wrong because if you put in that minus
two billion something number then this
is an error and the reason is that in to
compliment representation and we just
that the range of negative numbers is
higher than the range of positive
numbers so we cannot represent such a
large positive number and that the tools
catch and you come as they're in the
command as the comment suggests if we
say okay X must not be on that small we
can add a precondition that then
prevents us from putting so small values
into that function and so we can the
tools catch that issue you're flexible
in what how deep the verification goes
you can only do data flow analysis and
catch issues where we're in
uninitialized variables are used and so
on and you can can go down to really
prove to really prove the absence of
runtime errors so you get no exceptions
and to it do not do out of area in the
in indexes and such kind of things if
you want to learn more about spark on
this room where
there will also be talks on spark okay
let's put that together what do we want
to do with with these technologies this
is an example um that we have built to
get rid of these these hardware network
related issues so I told you that an
attacker chem can attack your phone via
the via the radio network because the
the basement processor may have a flaw
and then the isolation between base bed
and application process or is not strong
a partly per shared memory and so once
in the basement process or also the
application processor can be accessed
and what we have done is using the
genome framework you don't see all the
components here right now it's
abstracted away we have the G note code
framework it's running on a microkernel
called Nova and on top of that we build
a spark component which is denoted as
firewall here and what it does it's
connected to a virtual machine running
Andrew it running in a version of
Android and all the communication
between that Android and a second device
which is also running Android which is
running a standard Android phone
distribution that does actually
implement the communication with the
radio that's how it looks like so really
on the right side there's the on their
signal based system um you have two
virtualized Android on the right side
you can really interact with it and it's
connected by a USB um with a with the
phone that's actually only running the
basement software and in between this is
a lot we know what you see all the
messages between basement and
application project processor get
filtered and validated in a spark
component so that if someone would send
a message that exploits for example and
a buffer overflow on this would get
mitigated that this message was would
just get thought so that
on the right side the virtualized
Android is protected from any attack
from from the left side and of course as
they're connected by USB
there's no direct connection anyways
okay another thing that I was mentioning
is that you have little control over
[Music]
over what what's going on your system
someone can an attacker could just take
for example an app that's sending all
your contact information to the internet
we want to do something about that too
by using resource filters that is the
app system in Android typically is very
cost great
so it's an all-or-nothing thing you
can't an app a permission to get your
contacts and it get can get all the
contacts if you don't ground it the
permission then it may malfunction or
crash completely and when it has the
permission it can do actually everything
that that's associated with that
permission and when you think back to
that to that spark component we built
for the basement firewall you can think
of this same concept for Android
applications and the permission so our
vision is to put a filter in between the
end of it app and the rest of the system
and so it's possible to precisely track
precisely track what the applications
are doing and then enforce the user
policy that's far more powerful than
what's possible on Android right now
okay so our general goal in the end and
we are only under on the way right now
is in contrast to what you get suggested
typically you don't have to update very
often because the the security is
enforced by trusted components where we
have proven that they do the right thing
you may also
in the future or the platform click on
any link that you like because it cannot
do harm to all this to this overall
system and of course you should be able
and in our vision to install any
arbitrary apps from any App Store
without any problems of course using
cellular cellular Wi-Fi and Bluetooth
net but should not be a security issue
as it is today and of course I don't
know who whether you have an anti-virus
but it shouldn't be necessary and it
shouldn't be there too because it
increases your attack service anyway and
of course the vision is that you should
be able to do sensitive tasks like
banking or controlling in the industrial
system on on the platform right now we
have Android as I said running in a in a
virtual environment so a complete
Android it's also not running on a phone
yet so it's we the system is running on
a on a PC right now but the ocean is to
really bring it on the phone and to port
the Android runtime which we are
currently working on on to on to the
genome platform directly so we can run
unmodified Android apps with all the
without all the rest of the Android and
with with tight controls who trusts
components in the future for this we
need to create such a push between these
two worlds the the Android world Android
runtime and the general system and of
course we want to build more of these
protocol wrappers that we have done for
the bay for the basement processors so
you can also um have trusted in trusted
wrappers for Bluetooth Wi-Fi and so on
and of course we we need to bring this
on a real telephone so it's actually
usually it was usable on a device um
everything we built is open source as I
mentioned under a GPL um we develop it
publicly so if you want to get the touch
I'll try it out you can do this one funk
it up yeah
and if you wanna get in touch with us or
have questions or suggestions then send
us an email thank you are there any
questions
[Applause]
[Music]
yeah
yeah so the questions yeah so the
question if I get this right the
question was if you can do more
fine-grain policies than the Android
coalition system and for example deliver
random data instead of real contexts how
would we solve the problem of the user
making the right decisions was that the
question we do not have a solution there
there are other systems like xposed
framework which try to solve that but
honestly frankly we are under how to
really do the technical control of of
these things level and that would be an
open question actually one could think
that an application can only read out
context that it has written in there
itself and it bigotech somehow but we
don't have a full concept of that so far