alright it started so simple I'm going
to take you through a little bit of
background to tell you a little bit of
history of the project where we are now
where things are going so first of all
this herb container be it's been
mentioned least couple times so far
today as we've been in here so container
be showed up around the same time that
the open container initiative was formed
to the OCI Runcie has been mentioned
here several times already this morning
to 12 so run see is that executor the
implementation of OC house runs about
and so at the point that doctor decided
to to use from C container he was
created as a simple kind of management
supervisor on top of the run seed
processes then later that year it was
announced that that they're gay would
expand to be more of a core you know
full fully functional container run
funding to use separate from docker
announced announced late December 2016
do what we call continuing 100 we
differentiate that with the old
container he fall out the 0.2 branch and
then in March last year based on
promises made the announcement that was
contributed
a positive computing foundation the same
foundation under which kubernetes and
other five major projects sit and then
by December witches against a little
over a month ago via nose our full
version one release so that's not there
so that kind of gives you a quick flavor
of where we've been obviously you can
find out a lot more on our getting on
project page as we all know stars are
the gold standard by which you decide a
project worthy no that's not that
important but we've got a broad base of
contributors and and we've actually made
it come a point release this one that uh
and we'll talk to that so first of all
it might be helpful just to stop for a
minute and say you know why continue 101
I was the initial little kind of
supervisor for run seed not sufficient
why did we need to create this larger
kind of a core container runtime
well it really continued that spin-out
that began with us beyond run seed
I don't know how many people who use
docker three or four years ago was a
single binary you can pop it on a living
system that was statically linked and
you had your in this builder you have
the diamond and under clients all in one
thing which was kind of nice for me
usability standpoint but not so nice for
using docker in different ways obviously
as kubernetes should have I've seen in
other use cases
doctor is a lot of the project
that valuable for the broader ecosystem
so container he was going to the next
step of that that we got to come with a
stack
you've got Rossi as an executor of the
spec that runs on spec we've got
container B as this poor runtime without
the sort of docker twist on how things
are done whether that's never being
volume management so good day to me
provide that place if you're not
interested in doctors kind of ecosystem
but you can still have a catana
runtime so the things like kubernetes
through the CR CR I can rely on
container me and how to use the full
topper engine and other cloud providers
other use cases I can use that and then
of course you know combining that with
donating the code and outside of docker
was valuable to get more mcgraw
collaboration just seeing it as another
part of doctors products so container B
you know you might look at it and think
well is this just a cut-down doctor is
it just a smaller version of the big
chopper engine no actually it have been
a lot of ways they used the learnings of
those first two or three years of the
dominant runtime to kind of rethink some
of the things that were done some of the
things that work done as well as we
would have liked to have seen and so
really there's a set of technical goals
that maybe is Gerren see from the api
that we would immediately start with
everything being fully based around this
the I suppose image back to the runtimes
back the focus would be stability and
performance
not so much in features and do releases
and so have this well defined for our
base function and then each part of
container main would be full
couple of image pauses and runtime with
all potentially the pluggable and
reusable
even without the rest of the container
be and so there's a basic architecture
in twenty minutes I obviously can't be
done into all these areas we're going to
look at the couple that are making of
interest but effectively each of these
is engineer pc g RB c-- service with an
api obviously they'd all have the
metadata of storage so contain metadata
image references to two blobs for your
layers of your container file system
snapshot drivers amount to what in dr
recall the broth draw diversity prime
Novoa ofs are over layered place mapper
those are snapshot airs in the container
pete world and obviously that links to a
runtime
where you can pass through those yep and
run the container via run see we also
developed a rich go long very so again a
container be is not necessarily the best
thing for replacing their use of for
example the doctor client but for
embedding it's actually very powerful
feedback so far on the api is you know
that's highly usable easy is I've given
a few talks on it as well the and find
online about how quickly can write you
know sixty seventy eighty line client
and pull images start containers
pause containers
and town so you can check that out these
slides will be online you don't need to
break these is down so let's just talk
through a few pieces of the
architectures of snapshot I mentioned
are similar to what dr. Paul's Rock
robbers Tonya root file system is
translated from the set of blobs into a
running image that's all handled within
the snapshot to understand the
simplicity of snapshot errors it might
be useful to think about how dr. dealt
with the graph driver that dealt with
layers about a layer store or the
contact address ability of how how you
assemble like an image called a book to
or alcohol and above that or where it
was a referenceable image store that had
the mapping from main images and the
problem was not nothing to me these
components but there were a lot of
interconnections between these
components have made a heart to write it
and graph driver without making a lot of
modifications throughout doctor
so revisiting that when we design
container bead was to have a much more
simple snapshot or interface that the
metadata store would basically be this
intermediary between my set of layers
things I'm downloaded from the registry
and my runtime maneet's
they follow root filesystem and so we
can actually look at the snapshot our
interface is very simple again we don't
have plug two to deep dive into how that
operates but the nice thing about snaps
are is that this hands in to set amounts
and so there's no more deep bitter
linking between the graph driver all the
way up to how a runtime sees sees that
players and so this makes it very simple
to ask around see to run my container I
just handed a listen balance without
straight from the snap Trotter and once
he can assemble those about them and I'm
off and running so again the much
smaller interface Minh ground grabbers
or simple relationships and this
external sound lights like the one I
just talked about but you can actually
play with with our simple CTR tool which
is the client for potato B I can list
now chop and do them in three four and I
can even tell it to hand me that sent
amounts and I can actually mounted you
know in Linux and start playing with my
file system directly from the command
line that actually running a container
so those are that's one value Larry
Orcutt and he took the things we learned
from dr. and actually improved running a
container again I'm hit this briefly
again getting that list amounts and
those yeah configuration so those are
the two pieces of information I need bas
system and config those services can
depend that any supported runtimes and
so whether he is run C which is the
default Linux run time Microsoft is
working on their windows containers on
Windows and Linux potatoes on Windows
runtimes through their ship obviously
can replace run scene with hybrid on
stage or in some clear containers and
again because of this this decoupled
architecture these pieces over here
don't have to know about that runtime
any OCI
implementing runtime will be able to
take that information and run
entertainer in that environment in that
environment I mentioned the API and I'm
going to skip through these terms
quickly so we have run out of time for
kind of wrapping up but the CTR tool
obviously has a simple command
push-pull run start create you can see
on the right that's saying saying
actions in encode form using the
standard eco API client it's again I
connect to the demon I pull an image I
can then run that image by creating a
task and starting it again you can do
the same thing with the c-care command
web tool fill a task again obviously you
get the picture that the client
operation to do these and also a nice
going the eye for embedding these
capabilities within your own application
there's also ways to customize another
CI configuration so we've provided a
nerdy API a lot of wit bumpers so this
has with post namespace I want to start
a container but I want to join the pin
namespace in the host for example in
this case so again these wit humpers
either you can use them as we provided
them or write your own
to do that same say you want to be
container B and make a doctor like full
run fun obviously you can create with
hoppers to do volume support specialized
networking so again this ways to
customize mother's day like config as
you process it through your client I
want to talk briefly about releases I
mentioned that are $1 release you know
in December and coupon
and often we spent a lot of time
defining a release process that was one
of the complaints about docker
especially as it was used as the runtime
underneath kubernetes about breaking
changes moving too quickly and so the
key points at the release process we are
using semper major releases have a
support horizon that includes backward
fixes until that support Mirage them is
over and so already since December we've
done the two point releases and we back
ported many fixes out of master which is
leading toward our 1.1 release and so
again we're very focused on support and
bug fixes all the way through support
horizon not forcing people to have to go
to the export release the next point
release it does should include the
Windows capabilities for a container run
kind of support the Microsoft is working
on and again all the stability and back
backward compatibility guarantees are
provided for in the document as it's
clearly stated saying oh you know the
CTR tool versus the GU API versus the
GRDC and in which things are supported
for what time frame and it looks like
this if you go to the document what's it
look like there's a project again as I
mentioned we have a lot of contributors
especially joining the CNC out and other
groups have gotten involved obviously
doctors still strongly involved from
their use case as a part of the docker
engine staff it may be interesting to
see the Tesla's and
or contributor that's only because the
doctor employee left doctor didn't join
Tesla he's still very involved in the
project I think this is going to be any
container be running in your Tesla
vehicle and he comes soon yeah so as I
mentioned it we're part of the CNC I
know they're interesting news is that
the movie project governance has changed
I don't know if anyone cares much about
open source governance there was a lot
of sort of a sticking point of a doctor
having a beol model caught up on a lot
of their projects we change that last
year and now have the mobi technical
steering committee that oversees all the
movie projects including container D on
that TFC as well as five other companies
are represented on the TSP and so we're
excited to see that there's definitely
growing number of triggers to the
project more than just a limited set of
companies so obviously this is part of
doctor staff you've heard about PRI
container B in a few talks already in
this room there's been an experimental
combination of swarm container B so
again think of dr. and dr. swarm mode as
kind of the doctor ain't official
release you could take container medium
storm kit which is an open source moving
project and they should create their own
swarm mode without any of kind of
doctoring products Lily's been built in
don't let me go through those but
they're using to Tanabe and then this
week just about four days ago at cloud
foundry runs on community proposed
switching from seed and container B to
get rid of something
that they've added around the garden
container runtime for Cloud Foundry so
we're excited to see them
he used container be the Apache open
with syphilis project as using dr. today
but that's planning on switching to
container the other folks at puppet are
lead to have been contributing to
container B and we go to see that use
case was growing in the future last
couple slides just begin a visual on
kubernetes today with the dr. Jim each
one of these each one of these steps in
the stack means another v80 procedure
API code layer says as you can see it's
fairly need today for couplets in the
CRI dr. Chynn to the doctor and in the
container need to run see these here are
high container B project has just merged
in dark into our github codebase and
we're planning to have them as a plugin
so this will be a single binary
container B plus the CRI so obviously
you can see a lot of hops will be
reduced and we've been spending a lot of
time even creating a lightweight year
and C protocol for the shin that's a
memory and it definitely is much faster
so we hope that this will build
definitely a better staff for kubernetes
view so they could continue run con for
performance memory use etc
stability and everything else if you go
to custody - Arthur Cooper name is the
hard way you can actually deploy today
and try to scare on container B you can
do the limits pip can't I make all good
mothers for run on our measles here our
container D and get a I sowed with
patanty kubernetes 1.9 cloth and
and try it out today so again I've
talked through this kind of the
takeaways we hope that that container he
gets broad usage of the core content
runtime for the doctor community for
kubernetes open with Cloud Foundry we've
been doing a ton of stress testing we
have a 24/7 and stress running with
statistics and data that hopefully will
keep a container name of we're still
building ability guarantees like I
talked about our release process and bug
fix back ports so if you're interested
there's ways to contribute there's
plenty of documentation out there
there's room for contributors and these
slides are outlawed in this building
link+
18 CTR be and the Apatow if you have
questions on Twitter email me it's been
a github and a finger on tongue yeah we
are yeah by up ii yeah everybody
which means no questions and welcome to
make this week