okay Pokemon C alpha C don't so I did
talk today and I forgot there was
capital for English and French
there was an Aurora like give office and
I didn't know there was a capital in in
English when you when you put English
speaker and French speaker you need a
capital I rounded today okay so I will
try to to talk about about this trace
and basically I am a French we knew to
develop our Whiterun teacher I am a CTO
for a French company working on party on
embedded systems it's quite a big
company in open source but we have about
70 people working on embedded systems
it's called a smiley CS right is the
reason main companies here C is the
department and I were to book several
books about the medical enix and the
last one in absorb a key in French is
embedded Linux and the last one is was
available in the end of between the last
year for Christmas if you wait people
you can offer out my book
so what is the ex race is the official
trailer for the Linux kernel there was a
vote to assign the winner the first one
one of the first one was LTT what tell
TT was not mainline I don't think his
main line today
so f tracer is a variable since two
point six point three thirty one and its
main mostly developed by Steven roasted
from reddit and Steven or left reddit
some months ago is walking for memoir
today and it is the developer of the
entity which is quite close to to waste
waste because you need to measure other
some problems with reality so they are
also feature for tracing you can trace
of course you can trace finger functions
you can trace events and latency it's
not a debugger but it so it's a kind of
profiler
so as I say the debug application with
we left was basically a debugger it's a
very binding most of standard
distribution for example my on my boon
to you can you can use a straight I will
show you and it's based on demographics
you if you want to activate if you
compile your calnet by yourself and
activate a trace or exactly right if you
want to you are you have to access to
counteracting trestles so for example
you have to mount even if it's not done
you have to mount the debugger FS on
ciske under debug and on Siskel and
Ebert you have an entry tracing and you
have to access as route and you can see
all the files the virtual fight to
access the web trace system so there are
some important files are are put in in
volume as a trust which is the result of
extras available events and available
trestles
and very important fight is a tracing
gun which is a switch for activating or
deactivating F trace and this is on my
open - it is default to one so you
should put not to the current Reza
otherwise you will trust everything and
you will get commodore c XG 64 inside of
a pc it's a code for first even worse
that i'm not to tell so the procedure is
quite simple you set a trot song and the
filter for example wake your party you
in every dressing you run a program for
example AG bench which is a program to
to generate load on the system you
disable the dressing and you can get the
result
so result for example - a thing max the
latency i will say but there is a lose a
solution if you use an embedded system
to to run the tracer on this of course
on the system and to send the data to a
remote PC for example because it's of
course it generates big files and so for
example if I use the octo and or balut
on a recipe Rider the file system is
quite small and so the files can't video
can be on the file system except on the
boot partition because it's bigger on
the fat the fat partition I don't know
why but it's figure so you it's better
to send to send off I to to the PC there
is an example another example for
example you want to - to trust the
function of a simple driver you set
function graph for function function
graph is much better because it set a
graph of a CC like graph
you said the future you try some neither
the function of my driver 3 you trace
and you you know - - for French is like
a foo and bar for us and
the story of Toto are very famous famous
in different so you send something to
the driver and you you can get you can
get the result from the forms of trust
so if we have time I can show you two to
up both s trust and Trust to to to sue
the two way of debugging the system
so someone slide only on the basic
internals it's based on it's a bit
surprising but it is based on em count
it's a GCC port failure just like in
userspace but not really the same when
you comply with - PG will you
you generate a call to an count at the
beginning of the function right so there
is lots of overhead overhead doctor
there is a complex complex system
embedded in the Linux kernel to replace
the uncrowned who not inscription there
is a program to to record the clouds etc
etc make it work very nice but is based
on em count and AM count is very old
it's it was available in UNIX before in
XIII we not know it was on UNIX or
already so there is a reference
conference from for Steven from Steven
about about the subject so real-time
programming mostly is based on Toyotas
products tasks you can use for example
POSIX timer for software time such as
time up create time your set time which
will generate those young and the senior
is not real time really real time not a
real time but it's software time if you
want to use other real time and it
better results you can use a local and
asleep instead for example we we will
see a test with PMT at the end on the
Raspberry Pi you can you can get GPIO
and
with the microscope actually in a small
oscilloscope and you can measure all the
system logins and she sees all agencies
so this is this is on a big urban black
with one millisecond period its adult
system quite adult system one
millisecond is not so so short but if
you start from some tasks you will be
you will get this result which is not
very nice
all rights with adventure tool from the
RT test package so if you want to test
events and we all time with extras there
is a one way to use the schedule a cup
event so you set not to the current
roster oh it's not actually not the same
dressing way we have trusting sou you
put the schedule a cup to set event you
activate the trace you start an example
cyclic test which which is an example of
the after test package we generate some
some threads with priority etc it's just
like this I can show you some demo okay
like 'fuck test
okay take each on the PC so you will see
the worst case on the on the on the
right in a microseconds it's a so it's
just a periodic task with one my
Michigan child okay so it's quite simple
to use
if you got tired of slushies because
it's a it's a bit boring to to to do
echo echo echo cetera and cut you have a
trustee and you command which is in text
mode and return it's a contribution to
the project and there is a counter shock
which is based on gtk it should be based
on cute in the future because Steven
will walk on a tree and where you walk
on upgrading the kernel shock at full
time you say so well so it's a good idea
because general shock is not that sub
stable and I don't like GUI so what
trustee MDU you use or record and report
record to record and report to display
well and you create by default we create
at rest of that file you can create use
the remote server access in listen on a
PC for example you trust the MD design
with a number of port and on the target
on the number that system you you say to
to send the data to the PC with them
with the same program to tree simply
record my - II schedule a cup and you
will see if you if you report on the PC
it's much better to do that on on the PC
and the file is on the PC I you play the
file and you can you can you can check
there is a one milliseconds difference
between each event
well it's only text mode so you have to
do best better things for for marketing
people for example okay coming
communication people anything you want
or your mother-in-law or anything so for
the text mode you have to extract data
you can use the new plot and you have
static wizards but the new plot is very
powerful counter shock is dynamic and
interactive but
so DUI and is not that stable as I say
it should be involved by her by Stephen
and their there are lots of lots of
Bouton's in the Colonel shaki and I it's
written so it's quite strange some
sometimes it works so it works but I
don't well it works but I don't
understand what is the research between
two two tries for you to be stranger or
something like that so very complicated
which lot of scholars so we select the
right CPU and you can drag you with
these Mouse
of course it's for demos which doesn't
work out okay
the best okay okay you will see well
well so yeah you can see you can get the
values value so there is a okay I will I
don't like it but it's fine for free
should be better in the future
okay so I did it in the interest to do
today just add to slide the god kind of
shock if you can see you can see the
time stop here and the next one with the
next the next event you will see the
timestamp is updated about one
millisecond okay it's nice because it's
interactive but I will show that another
way to walk with us to us I will test
free entirety on Raspberry Pi with the
one millisecond diode another one but
it's it's it's it's a program to
generate activity on the GPIO so there
are two reactions the first one used on
physics timer and senior's seek alum
senior and the second one is based on
nano sleep so you can load the Raspberry
Pi with the flipping only thing you want
and there is separate small way to test
it the first one we call the event with
real-time program but in schedule other
so with no prior static priority okay
the second one use a sketchy foe with a
high priority priority so you can set
the priority of a program on Linux by
using C ashati it's much better than
writing the code inside the program
I did realize this do years ago so you
say sched fifo F and 99 for priority and
the last one you test you do the temp
the same test with real-time program
okay and you compare the result with a
group good new plot so the sketch before
with the time now is awful you have a
line yeah but with the kind of cloud
around it's not a cloud it's okay this
is not the point
this is legenda okay because every time
I show the picture everybody is saying
why is the why the point is it's
religion okay the second test its scale
author but with clock clock the no-slip
is not real time but see it's not that
bad
okay because there is no senior and the
third one is a pre-emptive with sched
fifo and i priority so it's a little
best
okay
so I can't show you maybe I can show you
some 10 minutes left okay for example
how to use f trace directly so C's
Yarnell do you
so on ctrl do you have lots of tracing
subsystem for example you can trace the
there should be a USB you can tracer you
will be transfer etc it's not only for
us for us of course
so tracing one
get current Rosser
okay good fiction graphic your interest
so I don't remember no but it's better
always great okay I will I will insert
it's always the same example
okay so it's it's a very simple driver
which reads reads the data put it in a
buffer and we send data see you might
arbitrage
okay
so I would set the filter
okay so you have a lot the new functions
so I put my tripod
okay
okay because it's it's it's to to take
the ten minutes
you know but it's for sure actually
Tracy MV is nice for tracing events
right this is my opinion
Tracy MV is fight for racing events when
you want to record data but I think /
this is better to to to trace to trace
the driver just to show the function
call exit row this is my opinion this is
not the same way to use of trust so if
you if you write to talk again it works
on me with Toto in France okay you will
see
I forgot to activate the tracer no it's
mine
okay so i'm i put the I put the function
function graph thruster so it's there is
a time for the time of deletion if I if
I change the thruster to to function it
would be different
okay but it's white quite the same you
have the color and it's called Why Why
is it by the VFS the white etc and so
now you can you can display the content
of the to the file and
okay okay
okay so it's it's interesting if you are
the driver and you want to check the
time stamp for folder calling okay
so I if you have actually you can you
can put markers in industry there are
lots of possibilities I focus on real
time lots of what you can put markers
inside your code and you can see the
marker is called traits marker F stress
marker you can do the marker and then
you will see the Bakke I know I have
some slightly bulky if you want just to
just to see it's it's in French but you
which would be fine - it's for follows
students
yeah no it's not this one
TTFN trace you can well you can do some
some things as you can use a twist
finger for example in your in your
driver and oh sorry and then you you
will see the the message in the
interpreter so it's a very interesting
and in your film featuring grass you
will see it either comment and you can
you can add it you can use a trust
marker and for example in the use of
space code you can write to the marker
fight the script or before nano after
nano and then you will see the commands
in the intersection graph so you can add
some things and to help to see what
happens in the camera
ing ITT Angie oh this is LT TNG it's a
bit complicated actually when we began
to work on on the real-time as I do with
my company which was called open wide
we started with delta T energy because
if truss was not a variable for abuse
for for the planes for testing the
planes and we switched to x-rays because
LT TNG was very complicated complicated
it's not mainline so you have to to take
one reaction of the kernel with one -
another module etc it's much better to
use main range functionalities because
it works on all platforms it's always
the same interface
well it's but I think it's much better
but LT TNG was fine but it was a bit
difficult to set set up as you can see
on the picture the priority but if it is
real-time the priority is static
to drop because of the consumption of
the Tracy yeah can can you can you drop
the service because of strong context to
context context constraint
you mean real we got the gift race or
well you can do anything you want you
but actually when you start f tres you
start the x-rays with it's not a program
with zest race it's a problem with the
common liner well when you when you
start the common with with the specific
priority
this coven so when you this is a static
priority but if you want to to modify
the priority you should set this setting
of the priority inside the program if
you want to change it but with CRT it's
for starting your program with a static
priority but you can of course you can
you can write the program it is not a
program with a straight it's a program
it's a problem with with the program
itself if I or I don't understand your
question
no no I don't think so if if there is a
modification of the priority of a thread
inside the program
after us we will twice it in without any
problem I don't know I know I extended
bit PS but I didn't use it so my cancer
and so to the question web traces you
can trace you can trace or use of speech
program who is used by using transfer
codes which mostly is used for for
tracing in general functions and events
in real time events okay thank you
[Applause]