[Applause]
and no oh my this is gonna be fun
alright I am Sam and this is deaf deep
dive so by day I am an engineer at
stripe and then like the rest of the
time performing dad I am working on
package management for go so we're gonna
dive into depth which is this so who's
who sort of depth first of all see this
that that makes me very happy
all right that was not everyone though
so we're gonna we're gonna no quick
overview thing here I'm not gonna do
like the full history the full full
history of package management forgo it
is quite a story but we are at this
point now where we have dep github.com
slash going slashed up which is the
official experiments tool official
experiment is a very carefully chosen
phrase there's actually going to be a
pile more information coming out very
soon about what the tool chains that the
official go tool chains dependency
management work is gonna look like but i
don't wanna get into that right now
bottom line dep is still the official
experiment it is recommended that you
move along to this that you migrate to
this there will be another migration
process to the tool chain of the future
but will be easier from to go from depth
so if you've got existing projects you
should migrate yeah so that is strongly
opinionated about workflow in a way that
is you know common for for for go
tooling so i'm gonna try to get through
in this teeny little window of time that
we have are these these two basic things
how to use that day to day and then at
least a little bit of information about
how dep works and why most of this this
is a product of like a month and a half
of writing or so but with the last
release that came out two weeks ago we
put up the stock site which now has a
ton of documentation it does not yet
complete and the headers are terrible
the formatting is awful i have people
come and help me with my Terrell
CSS but there is just a ton of
information about using DEP and most of
what I'm going to go over here is
actually covered there so you can you
know play along at home as well later
but that pass fundamentally three
commands Stepan it's depinger and dep
status and we're only really gonna talk
about the first two here DEP status sort
of reports the state of things there's
not as much to explore there definite is
for setting up a new project a new a new
go project it can also try to convert
existing projects does pretty well at
this we have we have importers for a
bunch of different projects but I'm
gonna start the demo here and it'll be
fun because I got to do this think of
the microphones if I can balance it and
then talk at it like this will this work
nope yeah great okay so there - thank
thank you thank you alright so we're
gonna go to I'm gonna pop it on my go
path and go to make a new directory here
I'm hoping that everyone is familiar
with go path again we don't don't quite
have enough time to explain how all that
works today but I'm inside my go path
I'm just gonna go to a demo directory
and I'm gonna run a simple definite the
results of that definite is it creates I
can just do this it creates a go package
tamil file hiko package that lock file
and a vendor file there will be more but
[Music]
yeah so the go package that tamil file
does a couple things one it defines the
project's route that does as to where
the chief effects there one is that so
everything inside of of your your go
path is its
import path is determined by its
position relative to the root of the go
path so because I just went into a
directory called demo it means that the
route import path for the project that I
created there is demo it also has sort
of get like behavior where you can run
DEP commands from anywhere underneath
that directory and it will root find it
we'll walk back up until it finds a go
package Tom will file until Deb finds
that go back that's homophile and we use
that and say hey this is the root of
this project and all my operations will
correspond to the to this project
Deb does not like protests if you napped
if you nest go Packers dot Tamil files
but it is not at all designed to work
with nested projects that's quite
intentional so go back into Tamil is
mostly hand edited and it contains rules
we have some simple examples of that Wow
I forgot it's an BIM again all right so
the basic things that were that we're
doing in a go package that Tamil file
are we're saying these are the rules for
how we want this project to be to be
treated not gonna explore all these
again lots and lots and lots of
documentation online but mostly what
we're saying is one like these are the
versions that are acceptable for my
dependencies to this required thing sort
of lets you add the real the primary use
case for required is oh I want to pull
in some I need to pull and you know the
the binary for some dependency that I
have that I used to like run go generate
or something like that like proto buffer
or message packer or something you can
actually point required to main packages
in a way that you cannot import main
packages legally and when you do that
DEP will pretend like it's one of your
dependencies and it will make sure that
has all of its dependencies and you can
version control your supporting tools in
this way and guarantee that their
behavior is consistent ignored let's you
pretend that a certain import path
doesn't exist you can just black hole it
this is also very useful for some of the
weird rough edges that that the people
sometimes run into but the big thing
here is constraints we're gonna say hey
for some project I want to only use you
know I I want I want to use version 1.0
point O or greater in this case we have
what's called an implicit carrots
unless you put in equals at the
beginning like that then we interpreted
as saying anything from one point 0.02
to point 0.0 it's December thing and
then in our last release we also added
pruning automatically pruning is a
system which will figure out which
actual files you need for your builds
and it will automatically remove
anything that you don't need from your
vendor directory no muss no fuss so
that's great I don't really care go away
all right yeah so the go back is a
tumble contains rules the other Pisco
package that lock I'm not gonna pull it
up because it's empty right now the
cofactors that lock is strictly machine
generated whereas it is expected that
most of the time you're gonna end up
updating the go package that's home all
by hand it is a transitively complete
picture of your entire dependency graph
and contains a mutable references like
it commits sha wands for example that
means that your go Packers dot lock file
represents the reproducible build for
your project by having this file you are
guaranteed that anyone else your CI
system or any other person collaborating
with can get exactly the same version
that you were working on when you you
know generated that file and checked it
in both the tunnel and the log file
should be checked in it's the
expectation definite can also try to do
conversions as I mentioned before it's
automatic behavior is if you run
definite inside of an existing project
then it will try to read in the meta
data from that project and convert it to
the equivalent in depth land so we have
support for seven oh man we have support
for seven different types of tools at
the moment and we do reasonably well
with these we have not we have we've
really locked these down pretty well we
did not get many reports anymore in fact
I don't think I've seen a report of like
hey this obviously converted something
wrong from this this other project there
are some things that we cannot honor for
example go vendor go vendors model says
that you can have different packages
from the same repository at different
versions DEP does not allow that DEP
says it is one version for the entire
repository so that we do not create a
fractal of combined versions that no one
ever anticipated but that can make
definite a little bit hard to get over
if you're converting an existing project
there might be some things which don't
quite fit into the EPS model but once
you get over that hump things tend to be
a lot easier and again the migration
process extensively documented on the on
the dock site so not really worth
showing here because it would be just
DEP in it and then it figures out a
whole bunch of things and then you're
done and yeah less less less explanatory
than anything else you can also try
gopath if you want if you don't use an
existing tool then DEP can read off of
your go path to see what versions of all
the dependencies your project has
cording your go path and then use that
to populate those go back there's a
tunnel and go package down lock files
bottom line though is that once you get
out of this definite process you are
like free and ready to go and and use
DEP for real for normal which means
using DEP ensure because this is all you
do all day every day with that this is
the one command there are two sort of
additional modes for it for the obvious
things like say DEP ensure add so we're
going to do this real quick I'm gonna
add I'm gonna go and add package errors
because that's one that people know the
other Wi-Fi does
make a dummy mango file which is just
imports the fun package and all right
and it's done so this gave us an error
message but if we look now at our go
package that lock file we can see that
we've got get up the calm slash package
slash errors and it's yeah it's been
it's been pulled in and we also can see
that it is in our vendor directory so
only thing that they actually have there
[Music]
so yeah
deputy red is the the convenient
shortcut that most people are used to
and I'm gonna get to the sort of
underlying model in a second and why it
works this way and why we get this error
here but dep ensure ad is is gonna be a
familiar thing for folks who are used to
like running a get command say hey i
want to add a dependency to my project
so something we added because it's a
little out of its a little out of sync
with the way that that normally works
but you can run it it'll pull in
additional dependency you can also
specify multiple dependencies you can
definitely add as many individual
packages as you want but the expectation
here is that you are going to specify
the route of a repository you're not
saying I want to add github coms last
package slash errors slash something
it's the roof that's what you're adding
when you want to go and update then
which is our next command you can run
dep ensure - update to update all
current dependencies or just one or two
if you weren't without in the arguments
just step ensure update which i'll do i
guess i'll have no effects because
oh yeah we added this right so I have to
explain them all all right
most dependency management tools they
have the separate file right like
package a JSON and NPM or gem file and
that is the authoritative list of the
dependencies that you actually have in
your project this is go we decided not
to do things that way sort of more
consistent with go get DEP is built
around the idea that what actually
dictates whether or not something needs
to be in your project is the import
statements in your project there's no
work that you have to do of like oh I
added the new import over here now I
have to go and update a file to say that
that you know dependency exists that
information is available it's statically
analyzable very quickly so we pull it
out of the files it also means that when
you remove dependencies there's no
bookkeeping to do you pull out the
import and it's no longer you pulled an
import and if that was the last instance
of an import for a given package you run
a depinger command and it will just go
away but try a definition or update
again there we go
so no effect on our go pack is a lot
because packagers was already at the
latest version that was allowed by the
constraint that we specified this is a
key concept with update what update
actually does is it looks at the version
your go Packers Tamil the constraint
specified in your go packers Tamil
which here is V zero seven zero with
some pleasant carrot oh oh man not
having screen real estate is hard so it
looks at the the the version that's
allowed and you go back to that time
when we'll get the latest one so if say
they were to release a zero seven two
then if you were to run DEP ensure -
update then they would go ahead and
update to 0.7 0.2 but because we already
have the latest allowed step interrupt
it doesn't do anything in general it is
preferred that you target specific
dependencies for update running a global
update I mean you know maybe do it to
sort of test it and try it but if you're
having any difficulty at all
sticking with sticking with just one or
two will really help isolate variables
with what's going on this is one of the
the nastier problems that people ended
up having with gliders glide did not
allow you to say I want to update just
this dependency of that dependency you'd
have to instead update everything and
especially for a project like kubernetes
which tried to move to glide for a
little while they had a lot of issues of
that the underlying thing that's going
on though is is the the key idea of DEP
ensure oh right now I've got like six
minutes so I got to get to the model
right quick okay the reason that the
command is called DEP ensure like this
is this is a weird name for a command
right this is strange people look at
this like what are we talking about
ensure the key behind ensure is not I
want to take just one tiny little atomic
step I want to just add a dependency or
I want to just remove a dependency or or
update one instead it is the phrase is
something like hey DAP please ensure for
me that all of my dependencies are
satisfied that all my constraints are
satisfied that all of the constraints of
my dependencies on other dependencies
are satisfied that everything works out
and is safe and sane and then with a
command like - adder - update it's also
do this little bit of extra work on the
side but instead of giving you a bunch
of commands that you know lets you sort
of work yourself into an intermediate
and kind of incoherent state DEP always
tries to return you back to a sort of
known good State that we think of as
being in sync and this is why there's
there's no manual bookkeeping this is
all based on this idea that we have of a
relationship a functional relationship
between the different components in the
system we have our actual project
sources and the imports in our project
we have rules in our NGO package that
Tamil we combine those together we run
them through solving algorithm which
gives us back our NGO package that LOC
are reproducible file that describes the
whole build and then we use that in turn
to populate the source of our
dependencies in our vendor directory and
we can actually see that at work in in a
nifty little way here so there's a
hidden command called DEP hash inputs
and if you look at the output here it
should look familiar
so this is telling us that we have some
constraints these are what's declared in
our NGO package Tamil we have one
declared on package errors and then
that's the actual constraint SVC is an
indicator that it's a semantic version
type that's alright I think you know
then we also have this this imports
requirements list these the actual
things that we import in our project if
I go and I modify something
[Music]
so I added the one additional imports
then hey look it shows up there and I
can run a DEP insure DEP test is just
it's it's a test repository for DAP
imagine that and then we'll see that in
go package that lock there's depth test
so I just added a dependency without
actually using - add just a highlight
that - add is actually mostly sort of
convenient syntactic sugar the goal of
that design and there are still some
hiccups in there is that you should be
able to just sort of stay in the context
of your editor add import statements
like you're used to doing and then just
run DEP ensure and it doesn't matter if
you've only added one or fifty it will
pull all of them in and resolve all of
them together it keeps it brings you
back to known good state it makes your
project brings everything into sync
now here's a fun little trick so
somebody shout out the name of a
directory that would normally be ignored
by goal list vendor test data okay I'll
use test data alright so
to be the last thing alright so I just
created a test data directory now this
is normally ignored by go list you can
see that with that's the one that I
wanted yeah so it's not sure when I
asked Oh listens like oh that test data
directory doesn't exist this is thermal
test database or normal uh no behavior
there so if I run that past inputs then
we see that also that import that I
added there does not show up this is
what we want we don't want that pulling
imports out of our test data if we
should happen to have you know Jacko
files in there however if I do this
little thing
please work please work Oh didn't work
work - tested earlier so we to do that
right did I put a difference
no that should yep all right
well when I tested it earlier it worked
hang on
yeah okay not working right now don't
know why it's not working right now but
I actually I may have done it wrong
wrong well the thing that actually does
work I promise when I'm not screwing
something up on stage in a live demo is
that Deb is smart about seeing because
it is not technically illegal to import
things and test data and I know you're
thinking why would you do that and my
question to you would be why does a
protobuf repository do that because
there is a real protobuf repository that
actually imports something in test data
from not inside of test data but
whatever it is
Deb is smart enough to follow these
these import path chains through
projects and and ya know when it should
actually include those things it would
then normally if I'm not messing it up
yeah it would normally pull that one and
see that one I'm out of time now right
one minute all right let's pull in
client go from kubernetes that's let's
do that why nots let's see we can do oh
yeah
I want to say this work or not did I
spell it right I spot it right right
that's kubernetes it looks good okay
alright and there's a sub package that I
wanted to use out of this one which one
was it let's see oh yeah
traffic and gets one so so Depp is slow
right now they're actually this this
this is a nice demonstration there there
are a bunch of pending performance
improvements that were able to put in
but in a different talk actually the the
dock Oh talk that I gave I talked about
how Depp is really sort of based around
functional design principles this idea
of functional relationships between
states and similar to a similar to a
functional language it relies on its
designed to run immutability in a way
that allows us to take aggressive
advantage of caching yeah traffic
doesn't exist I forgot the name of the
package oh well but yeah we we it's
designed around these functional
principles but hasn't yet implemented
the caching routines we're on that next
thank you awesome
you actually have Q&A time but we're
setting these up so I actually have a
question I know but I have the mic so so
yes so my question is should you or
should you not submit the van der
dependencies to github I need that
that is your choice we recommend that
you commit both your GOPAC Ossama and
your go Packers don't lock files other
tools might say you do different things
with your lock file depending on whether
you're like a library or an app we don't
make a distinction you are just a go
project no matter how many binary know
what I remain packages you do or you
don't
but your vendor directory is up to you
the only effect of committing your
vendor directory is that if you are like
a pure library and you commit your
vendor directory then you can give your
depends a headache folks depending on
your library if they are not also using
DEP but if they're using depth then
they're fine question over there
so he asked why it is that when running
definite some of the dependencies going
to the NGO package that's homophile but
like to see your versus some but not all
okay right so at the moment constraint
directives only function on your sorry
on your direct dependencies not in your
transitive dependencies so it's pulled
outs so this is doing a conversion from
some existing tool oh this is just on a
new project
what is it adding constraints for so
you're running it on the running on an
existing project of some kind okay okay
yes so it's basically trying to do its
best guest job of saying these are a
sane set of dependencies or same set of
constraints before the current
dependencies you have based on the the
current state of the world that we could
infer definite is a best-guess basis
it's not intended to be precise it's
intended to get you most of the way
there you'll probably have to tweak
after running it a little bit depending
on the complexity of the project other
questions yes
so we fundamentally can't solve that
problem that yes sorry Eric asked how we
handle aliases the fact that there are
different sort of routes to a package we
fundamentally can't do anything about
that the only I'm done I'm set okay we
found in the can't do anything about it
like it's it's kind of a deep problem
and in the way that go is structured the
fact that import comments exists as
we've got one point for that allow
packages to say I must be imported at
this import path helps a lot
some also future changes that I've been
discussing with Russ for a while may
also help a lot with that too
but basically there are two separate
things and we don't know that they're
the same it's the same as basically any
other tool ok I'll be outside if anybody
has questions - thank you
[Applause]