hello I so now John and Christian will
talk about surf so the stage is yours
all right thank you very much good
afternoon everybody and welcome to our
talk on distributed file storage and
multi-tenant clouds using set of s my
name is Kristin Frieda I'm working as a
software engineer at Red Hat obviously
and with me is hello my name is John
spray
I'm also an engineer at Red Hat's I'm
the former maintainer of CFS and the
current maintainer of the set manager
demon all right so in this presentation
we want to give you a brief overview
about the key components that we are
using to expose actually shared file
systems within an OpenStack cloud we're
going to introduce it to OpenStack
Manila and we will continue or John will
continue with the Ceph FS native driver
implementation next will be some
information about is the NFS Ganesha
driver which is used lately and has some
improvements about the native or using
the native set of s driver directly and
at the end of the talk we are going to
give you an outlook on the future work
that is happening right now with the
upcoming open stare Queens release and
beyond the Queen's release so before we
talk about the components that we are
using let's quickly recap you too late
what's the challenge that we actually
try to solve here so what we want to do
is we want to enable tenants or admin
administrators of boudreaux machines to
expose or to use a shared file system
across their virtual machines at the
same time we want to be we want this
shared file system to be 10 and aware
meanings that we don't have like a
single global shared file system for all
the machines running there but only to a
subset of the machines and another
subset of machines from a different
tenant are not able to access of course
data from 1 to 10 and a for example the
whole deployment should be self managed
meaning that the tenant administrator
from tenant a for example can set up
create shares
the lead shares for their users and the
arbiter machines and the operator of the
underlying OpenStack cloud and the
storage Baggins don't need to interact
directly or need to set up the different
file systems for the administrators as
an operator of this cloud I want to be
able to reuse my actors to work well
hopefully I want to be able to reuse my
actually available storage back-end
system so for example if I have already
set running that exposed block storage I
don't want to add another
software-defined storage I want to reuse
this existing storage form a shared file
systems so how do we solve that actually
we're using three different projects to
solve this issue or this challenge first
we have OpenStack Manila OpenStack
Manila is the OpenStack shared file
system service we're going to use staff
as the software-defined storage solution
backing up your OpenStack cloud and
we're going to use NFS Ganesha which is
a freely available NFS server
implementation so let's have a look at
OpenStack Manila the OpenStack Molina is
the OpenStack OpenStack shared file
system service it actually exposes a
bunch of well one API that your users
and administrators of virtual machines
connected are used to request of shared
file system shares delete shares create
new shares stuff like that so as a
tenant administrator that want to use a
shared file system you send a request to
the Manila API in the Manila API in the
background there's a second service
called Manila shared service which
actually talks directly to your storage
cluster and the storage clusters and
exposes for example IP address where you
can mount this chat filesystem and at
the end of this the tenant administrator
would get back an address and IP address
for example that you can use then and
your guest VM to actually mount this
created share and finally your guest VM
is talking directly to the storage
back-end now this support existing
one enough for different back-end
drivers quite a few proba teri drivers
that are well supported by their vendors
there are some generic drivers for
open-source implementations but under
the additional staff of s there was no
real production-ready open source drive
available meaning for example that you
have stuff like highly availability
services running them so set up as
editors well features and with services
it's now possible to run really a
production loud using OpenStack Manila
with a completely open source cloud
deployment OpenStack deployment so ZFS
is actually distributed POSIX file
systems that is built on top of
liberators and raiders the technologies
that actually makes f or itself SEF
itself is probably is already well-known
for example for its block storage
service using ratos block devices radius
block devices are often used together
without mistakes in there
to expose volumes for your virtual
machines running an OpenStack and it
also exposes objects services called
using the radius gateway rgw exposing an
s3 and object and an Swift comfortable
API implementation so the OpenStack
foundation is actually doing surveys
twice a year typically before the
OpenStack summits and it turned out that
most people more than 50% of the
operators actually want to use CFS as
they are back-end for their Manila
service and there's a good reason for
this as I mentioned early on most of the
times when you have or a yourself
cluster running cinder you might want to
reuse this one right you want to use
only a singer and software-defined
storage within your cloud and this drive
actually is a demand to to use set of s
with in Manila so before John is taking
over and giving you a more detailed view
on services
I want to explain a few key terms that
we are using during this presentation
when we actually deploy OpenStack clouds
with in Red Hat for our customers at
reddit we're using a concept or we're
using a tool called triple Ocho below
actually means OpenStack on OpenStack
and we have a so called under cloud
which is basically a management node and
this management nodes then deploys and
so-called over cloud this over cloud is
shown here for example we have a bunch
of controller nodes that for example
expose API services not only Manila but
let's say Keystone as well the Nova API
and so on and so forth the controller
nodes are also running a distributed
mariadb cluster and other services as
well of course we have some compute
nodes where your virtual machines are
running on later on and we have some
storage nodes there is well we are
supposing or setting up actually a few
different networks by deploying an over
cloud and we have public networks that
for example expose the IP I services to
the users this is also called a control
plane and we have some private network
networking networks that we are using
for example for the storage traffic in
the background and these are typically
called data plane networks and a private
and normally not seen by for example I
shouldn't be seen by the guest VMs
actually alright that's that I think
John's going to tell you a bit more
about service
so the native driver for Manila is the
simplest thing that we have at the
moment it's been in OpenStack for a
while now and it acts as the basis for
what's coming in future releases when we
say native in this context we
you
in
very good performance because all of the
gas PM's can talk to all of the Earth's
T's and the South cluster that gives
them a scale out level of bandwidth that
means there are only limited by the
bandwidth of their own network interface
so if you want to get 10 gigabits or 40
gigabits or whatever of storage into a
virtual machine in an openstack cloud
this is where you can do it it's fairly
simple to deploy from the point of view
of the person deploying the cloud itself
because you're not deploying any extra
protocol gateways or anything like that
if you're running OpenStack on a fully
open source platform the chances are you
already have a safe cluster that you're
using for RBD images via cinder so you
can use the same underlying safe cluster
with a single large set of s file system
and expose that as Manila volumes the
way we implement the concept of a manila
volume in the cipher personated driver
is simply as a directory so suffice goes
a little bit further than what's
required by POSIX in terms of what it
provides you it gives you her sub
directory quotas and per sub directory
usage data that lets you do an
impression of a particular directory
being its own file system so when you
type DF on one of these sub tree mounts
you're getting that per sub tree usage
information and the quota is being
enforced to that level so that when
somebody asks for a ten gigabytes manila
volume what we're really giving them is
a directory with a 10 gigabyte quota
there's a link there to a presentation
from CERN who are using this driver at
some scale already so here's the network
diagram and the important part of this
is the red section at the top where we
have the safe storage network that's
connected to all of the backing storage
servers the vo SDS which typically would
be separate from the networks that you
exposed to your client workloads and the
reason for that is that SEF is it has
some security built in it does have its
own crypt
and authentication and so on but that's
not designed for use in public it's not
the kind of thing you would expose
directly to the Internet
and it's not the kind of thing you would
usually exposed to untrusted client
workloads that somebody brought to you
and asked her on your cloud so 10 and a
and 10 and B here are just both
connected to the same network so they
can potentially interfere with each
other somewhat and they can certainly
run the risk of interfering with the
underlying safe cluster the upshot of
that is that you would only use the safe
native driver if you trust your
workplace and that is the case for quite
a lot of OpenStack users as it turns out
to begin with I expected this driver to
have very little uptake because it has
this drawback but we've had a bunch of
people using it because it turns out a
lot of people using OpenStack are just
using it as a way to automate their
infrastructure for their own work
clothes and for those people the
security caveat is acceptable so to
recap the pros here are the performance
it's shown itself to be popular with
users the implementation is is very
simple it's just a directory that
somebody's mounting and I didn't mention
a che
but that's because there's nothing to it
the safe cluster already provides high
availability in itself there's no extra
effort needed to make this solution a
che when it's used by manila clients in
an open stack environment and the
downside to emphasize again is that we
are giving musa PM's direct access to
the storage network which is certainly
not a best practice and is only
acceptable if you can justify it based
on how much you trust your applications
the other slight downside is that the
clients running inside the Nova VMs need
the Ceph software installs to mount the
Ceph filesystem so the set client is in
the Linux kernel and so this isn't
massively onerous but it means that when
you deploy your your clients if there's
a new version of seth coming out you
need to worry about things happen
inside you'll know the vamps so again
only works if you have a good a very
good relationship with whoever is
running your applications and whoever is
building those VMs so having talked
about what's wrong with the native
driver
I'll pass back to Christian for the
current work all right
thanks John so because of these
drawbacks the engineers were actually
looking into a different way how to
expose the shared fire systems to the
users and what has been implemented is
actually an F aspect service that
exposes o that actually uses a set of
SNS to have a fast driver and exposes
the shared file systems to the guest VMs
using NFS services this is completed
will be completely integrated with the
upcoming album stack Queens release
which is coming out in a few weeks and
I'm giving you a little bit more detail
how this works
so first of all we're using NFS Ganesha
Ganesha is a user space NFS server
supporting multiple NFS versions and
build on a very or using a very modular
architecture using pluggable file system
abstraction layers and these file system
abstraction layers already include
different open source
fire sir fascia shares for example
cluster of s GPFS lastra and set of s
Kanishka makes it possible to actually
dynamically export and update the
configuration without actually
restarting the service itself so when
you add a new share to to the Ganesha
server you don't need to restart it you
just send a signal using the D bus
protocol and it will update and export
the new service for example it has also
some some metadata metadata cache
implemented and included so even if so
when you're using NFS to access a shared
file system not all your requests need
to go to the underlying storage back-end
but some of them are already cached
so how does it look like when you want
to use the set of SNFs implementation
your tenant is for example using the
horizon web interface or the manila
command line interface and sending a
request to the manila api service so
minute manila api services and talking
directly and natively first to the
storage cluster running surf FS and
returning a directory pass next as
manila service will update and send the
information to the universe Ganesha
gateway which itself mounts this
directory pass locally an exposed C NFS
service using the NFS protocol itself so
at the end of the day the administrator
has an IP address with an NFS service
that you can mount on your guest VMs now
this is how all happening on the control
plane let's have a look at the data
plane so on the data plane it looks now
a little bit different because your
clients are no longer talking directly
to the staff of s demons or the surf
demons but only talking to the ganesha
in a fest gateway this has some benefits
of course because we can better isolate
traffic from each other and as John
mentioned the drawbacks that we have
when using set FS directly are no longer
come into play here that it adds
actually well a kind of men in the
middle here in the data path so you need
to need to run the Ganesha service in an
H a mode highly available mode otherwise
it would become a single point of
failure so what we're doing here when we
set up on OpenStack deployment using
triple L we're running pacemaker to
enable or to run Ganesha and an
active/passive mode
if we look at the again at the network
level we now create a new network for
just for the NFS traffic itself and the
tenants are no longer directly
connecting to the Ceph network but to
the NFS network and ganesha has also
connected to this NFS network so you
might wonder actually if those tenants
use the same in a fast network to access
the data services you might see traffic
from atop each other well Manila
actually triggers or creates OpenStack
Neutron security rules to isolate
traffic between different tenants from
each other as I mentioned we are running
pacemaker on the controller nodes within
our Trello deployed environment so
there's a concept within triple L called
composable roads in composable roads
actually make it possible that you for
example define a set of nodes that are
running specific services and it might
be well it would be a nice idea to
actually run the few standalone notes
just for the Ganesha services and with
their own pacemaker cluster however the
pacemaker cluster at the moment is tied
to the controller nodes because it's
also controlling other services as well
so we can't easily remove or move the
pacemaker service to a different node so
pacemaker needs to run on the controller
nodes and because of that Ganesha itself
needs to run another controller nodes
and for example needs to restart the
Ganesha container finishes running
container rights in newer releases with
an openstack triplet oil was in trouble
Oh needs to restart it on a different
note
[Music]
so to summarize what are the benefits
using the CFS NFS Drive implementation
we have better security because we can
actually isolate the user virtual
machines from the set of ethnic step
network and its demons we already have
familiar NFS semantics that are included
in most guest operating systems which
isn't for some guests or for some
operators pretty important because you
can for example add safe drivers to your
pet sematary guest system and but
instead NFS itself is widely supported
already out of the box we have some pass
separation in the backend storage system
and by using OpenStack Neutron network
policies we can actually enable or
enforce ZZ back-end traffic is isolated
from tenant to tenant and that gives us
the possibility to run it more in the
open in a public cloud environment
compared to for example a private cloud
deployment where you can trust your
little machines but there are also some
drawbacks here so as I mentioned Ganesha
as a man-in-the-middle now in the data
path and your guests are no longer
directly to the h AE enabled or H a
Ready Set cluster but to the only to the
Ganesha service so what we would like to
do is actually we would like to run s
would be a trunk Anisha and an
active-active mode all run for example
ganesha in a way that we spawn a
separate ganesha instance for every
tenant so instead of setting up a singer
ganesha service when we deploy the
OpenStack cloud we could well we could
actually do start a Ganesha service
third power tenant on-demand and by
doing so we would increase the
performance that we get out of this
total service and not exposing like a
single point of failure because you only
have a single commercial service running
and was that sad I'm giving over to John
again
was give me giving you an odd look on
what comes next so it's fairly clear
that we've got the native driver that
gives you great performance and
simplicity but has a big security
problem and the NFS driver which is much
easier to use and much more generally
applicable but has some innate
limitations in terms of performance
naturally we want to build a scale out
manifest solution the way we want to do
that is to have a tighter integration
between Seth and Ganesha pacemaker and
chorus Inc are very useful tools for h.a
up to a certain scale but we envisage
that in the future we're gonna have NFS
daemons that need to scale out
potentially as far as scales out so
potentially up to hundredths and we'll
also want to have Ganesha demons that
are created on a perk tenant or per
share basis so have a much larger volume
of these than pacemaker chorus Inc will
be able to handle SEF fortunately
already has lots of general-purpose bits
for keeping its own services running so
we intend to put a wrapper around NFS
Ganesha and run it in a way that it's
slaved to the South cluster that should
also make it simpler to deploy because
there's no extra configuration to do for
chorusing pacemaker and also easier to
use for users in general of SAP so
whether you're running with Manila or
any other environment we can potentially
give you a single command that both
creates the filesystem and configures
the skill map NFS on top of it
kubernetes comes in here as well so
there are a number of efforts ongoing at
the moment to bring SEF into kubernetes
environments and not only to provide the
storage to applications running those
environments but also to take advantage
of what people at ease can do
to run our services to keep our services
up scale them and so on and that will
apply to NFS kanesha
so when Seth wants to create a new
Ganesha demon it will ask kubernetes to
do that for it whether your application
is based on kubernetes or not so even if
you're on a traditional OpenStack cloud
you would still probably be using
kubernetes behind the scenes if you
wanted to surf cluster that could
provide this kind of capability for you
so here's a diagram of what that
solution looks like Manila is still
there in the top left and it's calling
down to in the MGR there is the Ceph
manager daemon it's one of the demons in
a south cluster and it asks the manager
to create and delete shares for it and
on Manila's behalf the manager calls out
to the bottom there to kubernetes and
asks it to create these pods that
contain a new service that we intend to
create called
NFS GW which is a sort of analog to rtw
the Raiders gateway but it's doing NFS
and those pods would be the the data
path for the user applications UC Korea
is mentioned at the bottom left of that
diagram as well that's about the network
configuration that goes with this so as
well as creating NFS daemons / tenant we
will also need to be doing network
configuration / tenant to give them the
right level of isolation that's very
much an emerging area in kubernetes
traditionally kubernetes pods only had
one IP and that was all you got but
things are moving fairly quickly in
kubernetes and we imagine that things
like these storage containers will be a
sort of early adopter of the new
improved stuff that's going to be out
there in communities
so this is the sort of third revision of
that same basic diagram but this time
you can see ten and a and ten and B are
both talking to their own Ganesha
they're not sharing anything at all
anymore they're fully isolated which is
kind of what we wanted to begin with so
this isn't trivial and it's not all just
planning making a scale out Ganesha
cluster on top of SEPA fest has some
challenges running it to begin with is
very easy you can download Ganesha and
do this today it's a shared file system
you can put multiple front ends in front
of it and that's all fine but when a
failover happens we need a little bit
more stuff happening here
so NFS clients have some state with
their NFS server but the NFS server is
also a separate client that creates a
fair bit of complication in terms of
what order you restart services in when
a failover happens but also at war
points you have to put the NFS services
into what they call grace so when you
put an NFS demon into into grace it
means that it's not gonna let any
clients take any any new locks or access
any new files until two failed daemon
that we're currently replacing has come
back and that's to prevent locks getting
stolen and provide the right semantics
for the user application it's quite an
obscure aspect of implementing NFS that
most people aren't familiar with but it
becomes very important once you start
doing active actor NFS and scaling it
out especially when you're putting it on
top of another system which is doing its
own AJ underneath in this case Seth even
further out MDS is in safe clusters the
metadata servers are themselves a scale
out cluster so we'll want to scale out
the MDS at the same time we scale out
the MPS daemons to let you do things
like small file workloads efficiently
NFS delegations will speed up these
workloads a lot for certain applications
that don't want to keep doing lots of
round trips all the way down to the
south cluster that allows the so a
delegation allows the safe cluster to
say to the NFS demons okay you manage
this file for the moment you don't have
to ask me to do more accesses to it
PNF s parallel NFS everybody's been
waiting years p NFS
it might still happen one day in the
context of seth what that might look
like is putting a little lightweight
demon in front of each of the OSDs
that allows pmf s traffic to go through
it and what that would mean would be
that an individual NFS client even when
going via NFS rather than surface native
protocol would be able to get the full
bandwidth of the cluster and finally
there's the use of this outside of
OpenStack
so Manila is a fairly separable thing
from OpenStack
it will be interesting to see to what
extent Manila gets reused in other
environments but also to what extent the
components that we're building here to
support Manila get wrapped up in other
environments so much of the same stuff
for somebody else in Manila they'll also
want in
kubernetes or any other container
orchestrated environment so we
anticipate this stuff that we're
building into SEF and unsafe for Manila
showing up in other frameworks as well
that's all I've got
thanks very much for your attention any
questions
I did not so you're asking about
Kerberos which I didn't mention and
that's because that's a general-purpose
NFS aspect and it doesn't change if you
ETF so whatever Kerberos support exists
in your NFS demon will still exist when
you're running on safe I'm not an expert
on the aspect
so I think the question is what I'm
running NFS on top of CFS and both of
them are doing sub mounts sub directory
mounts how are we tracking the metadata
beneath that so the metadata inside SEF
is completely unchanged you can mount
the overall filesystem that's storing
these volumes and you will see all of
the volumes as sub directories and you
can even read and write to them safely
at the same time because our whole
concept of a volume is this sort of sham
where really it's just a directory we
don't have to really make any changes at
all and how the metadata is stored on
the backend yes
it's it's still in service yes sir sorry
the question was yeah sorry I forgot to
repeat the question there it was will
the NFS demon still run on separate us
all they run directly on SEF or the
underlying Raiders and the answer is it
still Sapir us just with a more nicely
packaged NFS solution on top of it
that's one question here
right so the question is why are we
doing file systems and not block devices
it's for workloads that require a shared
file system so if you have a workload
that requires storage which is only
accessed by one VM at once then a block
device works well but if you want a file
system that will be accessed at the same
time by many different nodes then Manila
is what you want so cinder cinder is
still great for a single single node
access and Manila is primarily for
people who want shared file systems
access by many notes at once one last
question
[Music]
I'm sorry icon Hey
I'm sorry that the question was when
deploying the the Queen's version of all
of this with the NFS solution and does
it require any special dependencies of
configuration especially on the network
side so whether the Queen's release and
will be fully integrated on the triple
our site so when you deploy a nova cloud
using the Red Hat's triple o then it
will be fully integrated already you
just need to enable it during the deploy
time so when you're familiar with with
triple o you have a bunch of environment
tires that for example set various items
networking stuff like that and with the
Queen's release it will be as simple as
like just adding an additional included
environment fire and that will spawn up
and well deploys again azure services
and other services so you can just use
it basically out of the box that's the
ID okay okay I think that's it thanks
everyone