yep there we go numbering is good thank
you very much for coming cool wow this
is this is a awesome audience oh yeah
I'm Richard I'm the chairman of the
openSUSE project so I've been actually
contributing to openSUSE for about well
12 years as long as the project's been
around and some genius thought I should
be in charge
and actually I'm gonna talk about how
the distribution project specifically
but I think most open-source projects
out there seem to have forgotten why we
have governance why we have a project in
the first place and talk a little bit
about some of the consequences that
we're actually facing in the real world
with our projects and yeah how we might
want to change and rethink actually what
we're doing when it comes to keeping it
yet keeping our project running how
we're governing them so you know
ultimately answering the question does
governance matter and when talking about
governance it's it's it's quite easy to
talk about you know the leadership the
guy in charge the guy at the top you
know and obviously the you know a
certain person at the top of any food
chain can have a significant influence
or maybe not such an influence but but
yeah does does have an impact on on how
the organization below works thinks
about things talks about things and then
also talking with other people and other
organizations but really at the heart of
it it shouldn't be about the person at
the top the question of projects
governance or organization and and how
it actually works should all be about
the influence that any one individual
can have any new person joining the
project any one person in that can they
you know be be this sort of pebble just
disturbing the entire ocean of a whole
distribution or the entire open source
ecosystem at large and it's this kind of
thought of you know can is there the
power of one in openSUSE is what really
got me thinking on this topic of do we
meet that test that any person can can
join and really influence where the
product is going
and of course when I was thinking of
that I was looking at all these other
projects and got me thinking of you know
just how does everybody else do it and I
kind of realized that the situation's
way WAY Messier and way nasties and I
was expecting and and not nearly as free
O's and open as I was hoping it to be in
you know open source ecosystem and so
sort of when thinking about this I
realized I wanted to sort of talk about
which who does the project serve really
what is the point of an open source
project what is the point of an open the
distribution project and why did what
who does the project itself serve who
did it who is it meant to benefit and
the first time I asked is to most people
they answer you know we're here for the
users you know we're doing something to
give software to the users and the more
I thought about it the more a tweet I
thought that's totally effing wrong it
is our projects do not exist to benefit
the users and in fact what me you know I
say we I think they'd and if you
disagree with me I'd say then we they
should not benefit the users the project
should exist to benefit the people
working in the project the software that
we produce yes that's integrity for the
users but that's the product that's the
end result the governance the structure
the methods the policies the processes
every decision we make as a project
about how we're going to organize
ourselves as a project should be
orientated to serve the needs of the
people in that project as soon as you
forget that and start focusing on the
end users and start feeding that into
the the organizations that the project
projects time and time again they lose
their way they lose focus they lose
their they lose that purpose and you end
up with yeah you know distributions are
try and solve everything for everybody
and then no one uses it because it
doesn't do the thing they want to do
have done so it really yeah it really
has to exist to provide a collective
benefit to your maintain is to
tribute is to your volunteers because if
it doesn't provide a collective benefit
you're not going to have any maintenance
you're not going to have any country
there's no one's going to bother joining
your project and yeah it this does
require a bit of a mindset change for
some projects some people do you know
really stick to the mentality of sort of
users first but the project has to be
there for its contributors and I'm now
going to stop using the word
contributors because language matters
and that this framing matters you know
when you talk about contributors they're
just kind of tendency to especially as a
leader of a distribution project you
know it kind of comes with an
implication of it's my project and
you're just contributing to it you know
I don't like that kind of hidden meaning
behind it often gets kind of labeled
with the thing of the contributor you
know there's you know sort of suggestion
of a contributor doesn't really have
ownership of the end result
they're just contributing to the end
result and secondly on the other
opposite side you know with with
language you know maintain is quite
often comes with a you know an opposite
connotation
we're just maintaining it we're just
keeping it where it is or it's ours it's
mine ultimately no matter what anybody
in your project is doing doesn't matter
if they're you know helping with the art
work who are helping with ideas of
dealing with you know support formed or
whatever they're all volunteers
I would contest every single person in
an open-source project is a volunteer
either literally they're doing it in
their spare time and totally voluntarily
but even when dealing with open-source
projects where corporations are involved
ultimately the corporation is there
voluntarily they can always give us
where and the people working in those
corporations are there voluntarily
unless you can give me an example of an
open-source company that has slave labor
but there shouldn't be and I really hope
there isn't
so if soon as you start free realizing
that and thinking in those terms and
realizing every single person in your
project is a volunteer a lot of these
weird questions about how should we yeah
how should we deal with this doubt and
how should
deal with this idea you know how should
we organize our yeah yeah leadership
committees and technical groups and that
kind of thing suddenly becomes a lot
easier to actually answer and totally
changes the context in how you approach
these problems because ultimately you
the kind of underlying bill of this
they're they're volunteers if you're not
again not dealing with the needs of your
volunteers they can walk away and when
they do walk away your project suffers
for it and I just brushed it all back
there we go then this is kind of yeah
sums up with this quote to you know
we're we're here doing Linux doing
distributions you know it's free but the
project you know the work you are doing
for the project isn't free it's valuable
it's beneficial and so you know we have
to have the project constructed in a way
that it somewhat in its own reward and
it caters there so that that project is
providing a value add to that
contributor to that volunteer and yet if
you look at so many of our projects
what's the first thing we do when it
comes to structuring them and organizing
them and having some kind of governance
we have a committee and starting without
the distribution but just Apache and
this is Apache HTTP D but this is
actually true so so every single Apache
project in this you know every Apache
project has their their working group in
it at the top which you know all major
changes must be voted on any Apache
developer can vote on any Apache working
groups changes which is nice however
only the active maintain is for that
active working group are the ones that
their vote is actually binding so you
know basically if you want to get any
change into a patchy httpd you have to
be friends with you know at least three
of the maintainer there but on the flip
side because you know they're trying to
be very equal opportunities and they're
open there anybody can veto anything so
basically if you're a new guy trying to
contribute to Apache you really are
gonna have a hard time you know unless
you're surprisingly lucky and this isn't
necessarily a bad thing it works very
for them I think I would actually say it
works very well for the majority of
apaches projects because most of ever
patchi's projects are somewhat narrow in
focus and narrow in scope and therefore
you know having a narrow decision making
model has certain benefits you can you
know theoretically get changes to bother
really quickly but then having a look at
the border ecosystem how many different
web servers do we now have in you know
in the linux ecosystem you know nginx
and the like all competing with apache
because apache doesn't do it the way
they think should be done why couldn't
nginx
get their lightweight unis into the
Apache HTTP project well because this
decision-making model it will never get
past this kind of committee process you
know they're thinking in their way doing
things their way
and they've structured their entire
decision-making an acceptance model in a
way that reinforces the status quo
you know Debian does this a kind of a
lot as well but you know and lots of
other projects do it's not necessarily a
bad thing but people when we're deciding
on governance models for our projects we
really should be thinking about the
impact that has on where can this
project go you know long term how come
it change happy to be sustainable how
revolutionary can it be you know with
this model there isn't going to be some
massive fundamental world changing
rewrite of Apache unless you know
they're really those guys over there
really smoking something nice and that
might be a good thing but it does mean
that over time things are likely to
stagnate things are likely to slow down
things are likely to get harder and then
that's how projects decline
that's how projects go away and then we
need new projects to come up and stand
up there but does it have to be that way
could we you know to do a sister have a
sustainable project the model
potentially be one where the project
itself is more open to challenge within
itself therefore you know accepting
changes more broadly not voting against
you know not having easy vetoing and not
having very select approvals
and when dealing with larger projects
like distributions that model has
massive scalability problems you know
you can't deal with that many incoming
requests you and then your poor core
maintainer x' have to approve every
single thing and you have to have at
least three of them so that thing all
backs up there you can't just add more
people to the committee that's what some
projects drive is with this kind of
approach but that just ends up with more
people in the committee arguing with
each other so it doesn't really solve
the problem at all in fact it quite
often makes it worse
and like to be talking about the last
few minutes really it provides a barrier
of entry to the project a new
contributor is going to feel that it's a
bit harder to get in there in some cases
some of these projects some of these
committees that follow this model you
know the people involved are really nice
friendly opening people which somewhat
mitigated the reality of that you know
if you've got the right people in that
place they you know a lot you know
they'll accept crazy changes they'll
accept that challenge so the model
doesn't will this assembly always mean
that barrier of entry is real but it's
perceived you know as a new person
you're not going to know who that nice
guy is so are you gonna send that crazy
change that you have that you've baked
in the in a dark corner somewhere or are
you just going to declare a new project
on get up and do it in there and you
know this is why we end up with so many
Forks of so many projects for the place
because they never realized they could
actually contribute to the upstream
because the upstream was structured in
the wrong way the first place and this
is why I talk about Debian because
Debian has their technical committee you
know which is there to decide any matter
of technical policy especially where
you've got situations where developers
have overlapping jurisdictions they can
also just make a decision because
someone asked for a decision and they
have the right to overrule the developer
which I find really weird because it's
like we're all volunteers and we all do
it especially in Debian you know that
there's no company behind it but what do
they expect if they ever overbought a
developer like this guy is doing it this
way this committee said he's doing it
wrong it's like it's a volunteer really
gonna change what he's doing no that's
how you lose a contributor or you
at least don't get the person's
contribution on that topic and the
system sitting in a debian systemd you
know it's kind of a perfect case study
on on how the debian model can be
followed perfectly every part of every
person involved in the decisions with
system D did their job in debian
perfectly the Technical Committee I do
not fault for their decisions at all I
think they were perfectly right invalid
I also think the Debian community who'd
objected sir
everything going on my system D were
doing their part perfectly right and
valid but and yeah more about that in a
minute but yeah the Technical Committee
decided in Debian decided the system D
would be in Debian as a default but they
purposefully and I think quite smartly
decided that they wouldn't decide on
where the packages could depend on a
specific system but you know some people
don't like system D so there was a
phlegm the last nine months and that
that discussion pissed off a lot of
people that discussion had a lot of
upset people on both sides it led to the
focus of Debian and ultimately they
decided let's have a democratic vote on
this and decide you know what is our way
forward and after nine months
collectively the Debian project decided
that they didn't need to make a decision
which is ultimately the right decision
it's the one that a committee made in
the first place there's nothing wrong
with that but how much pain and upset
did their process and their structure of
course it's not you know no one's at
fault but the entire project
organization created this problem not
system D but the model they decided to
follow and therefore what benefit did
that model really bring Debian it didn't
make the quicker decision didn't get
more people involved people away how did
that work and in fact the technical
committees generally how often does a
technical committee bring nothing to a
project but an opportunity for someone
to say no to a developer
because developer doesn't need someone
to say yes they're gonna do it anyway
corporate overlords companies you know
working and working in this space
because you know they do so yeah
obviously I work for Caesar so I'll get
to that in a minute but I'm gonna start
with our friends who've read out I'll
get back with that later Fedora have
left Dora Council which speaking as
chairman of the openSUSE board I can
shamelessly admit when we started the
open seas of project we basically copy
and pasted a structure from their
structure but things have changed over
the last 12 years
so the Fedora Council as it stands today
has a very similar role to my purpose in
the open to the project but so it
doesn't anymore used to now it has this
role of identifying organizing and
enabling the project's goals it's
currently ten people eight of them are
employed by Red Hat
two of them are elected by of the
community so three of them are directly
appointed by Red Hat the remaining five
are appointed by the board so you know
it's a nice internal loop and even one
of those two elected by the community is
employed by Red Hat how much yeah how
much non-red had community influence can
possibly be in that board you know do
you think fedoras goals might ever be
challenged to do anything other than
what red Hatter deciding they want to do
yes possibly
but that may be yeah but ultimately I
mean when speaking of somebody who works
in an organization very similar to vet
hat you know organizational bias really
is a thing inside Sousa we have lots of
well-meaning people who have their own
ideas and thinking their own thing but
when you're surrounded with a whole
bunch of people doing something you know
for your corporate overlords you're
gonna end up thinking along the same
lines even by accident so you can't have
if you're trying to do a general let's
say for example it's like fedora and
openSUSE you know pretty much a general
purpose distribution in the open-source
space if you go this model you're not
going to have anything challenging
you're kind of perceived organizational
bias you know you're going to go in that
direction which you know your corporate
management or whatever decided either
fully wholeheartedly because you know
you're forced to do so but like I said
we don't really have slave labor in the
open source world but even by accident
you can be thinking along those terms
focusing on those goals that you know
corporate Red Hat or corporate souza
have decided and you're going to be
pushing in the direction even if it's
somewhat unconscious and I think it's
better when dealing with with with a mix
sort of corporate and open governance
model to have a system that is designed
where your challenge must be baked in
you know there must be and I'll get to
that more later at this otherwise talk
about later and yeah just to really be
hopeful to Fodor again but you know in
addition to their leadership board they
also have a technical steering committee
which basically doesn't set the long
term goals but decides want every single
bar every single package that's going
into the distribution and what the
software should be available to the end
user that is also currently nine people
that's a copy paste from the Charter for
the attacker
that's a copy-paste but it's what they
wrote down okay so that's what they say
they're responsible for you know they
may not practice it but whatever
whatever they're doing you know there's
nine of them seventy employed by Red Hat
my my other point ultimately and yeah
and like we've been talking about you
know in open source I really I do agree
with in us here you know I think you
know our contributors should have the
right to control their own destiny if
it's not real open source if one person
can't make a difference in a project and
then it cuz of the worst example of that
is somewhat you know I do give credit to
canonical here at least they're honest
and very very clear about it you know
their their organizational structure is
one where basically mark is in charge
and mark nominate who he wanted to have
in their community Council which is sort
of doing the the conflict resolution and
community management side of things and
Mark decides who's in the technical
board you know so again that's a
structure where a new individual come
into the project or any individual
within the project it's going to be
somewhat limited in how much they can
change you know in the project as a
whole and and you know how much I can
grow and maintain and move faster in the
future and putting myself again there
what about Caesar and openSUSE because
we like you think we started well we
started pretty much copying what Fodor
we're doing you know when Fedora started
12 years ago we started sort of six
months later and and you know with the
the goals from Sousa was to kind of
bootstrap something on the same lines
but inside Sousa there's some mentality
differences than inside Red Hat and it's
really interesting to me to see the
difference now 12 years later of just
how far those two original starting
points have diverged and also how
humorously bad some of the experiments
were the we tried
and one of those that we tried straight
out of the gate because we thought this
was really really good was direct
democracy you know let's have everybody
deciding everything about the direction
of everything in our distribution and
yeah Winston's right it's the worst of
everything yeah top of everything else
has been tried in our case we even you
know in typical Sousa fashion made a
tool for it so there was a tool called
open trade you can still see it today
sadly because I haven't quite taken the
harder to kill it yet but it started as
an equip and openSUSE equivalent of
Souza's initial internal feature
tracking tool so that all that they use
still today for deciding what features
go into the enterprise products you know
fate you decide deciding the fate of the
world its feature or has a comma before
the it's a pretty abbreviation for
something as well like feature and
tracking enhancements or something yeah
an open freight was decided to be
totally and utterly open where anybody
can suggest any feature they want and
the community can vote on any feature
that they want yeah and and there are
hundreds of feature requests thousands
of votes and I can honestly say as the
guy who quite often goes through this
trying to see how we're doing with that
kind of thing the impact on the projects
priorities are negligible every time I
close a feature is done on there we
fixed it by accident I'm yet to find a
developer who's actually looks at open
fate and done anything because it was in
open sight you know there's been a few
times the susi where we've like copy
pasted it put its a feature sleeve but
that's you know just convenient but it
does not work but this quote about
democracy can be thinking because in
fact when we when we think about open
source projects especially we think
about how did it all begin where did we
all start how does the Linna linux work
you know it the inmates should be
running the asylum
why why not as where we started in fact
you know looking way back to the
beginning the first of all over the
cathedral and the bazaar every good
software starts by developer scratching
their own itch so why have we forgotten
that you know you don't need to tell
your volunteers what to do they know
what needs to be done they're working on
the code base they're using it
themselves they need to have the tools
in the environment to do that so that is
something that a project really should
be thinking about to bring as a value
added to its contributors that's what
that's what that's one place they should
definitely be starting and your
volunteers should be feeling empowered
that they can do whatever they want to
be doing with that software for that's
for that project as a whole and it
doesn't matter if you had someone
telling them what to do anyway because
they're not going to listen to you
that's what we learned from open Freight
so there's sort of core principles that
I really think that more projects need
to remember they should have at their
heart whatever they're doing
distributions or otherwise respect your
volunteers they do not need to work for
you they can move elsewhere even if
you're paying them they can move
elsewhere you should be focusing on
enabling them making sure they have the
tools and the processes to do their work
and you should be trusting them you know
you they don't need to have management
or project managers or you know
technical committees deciding on what
needs to be done the best person to
decide is to volunteer doing that work
but Alec ease our crazy so and our keys
don't sustain either they have a habit
of exploding so respecting your
maintainer x' is great but don't give
them too much respect no another example
from Debian is the Debian maintainer
ship model you know a debian maintainer
is pretty much God for his package
which is yes which is nice to hear
because the the model of sort of yeah
yeah a single overload of a package will
not last in the long term so structure
your project in a way where any person
in a position of influence can be
challenged new volunteers should be able
to come off the street start working
with the existing volunteers you know
all ultimately replace them which can be
a daunting concept in some example in
some projects in some structures but you
know if you if you can't pass that test
I think you're doing something wrong
enable them but you know too much
freedom can be a bad thing everything
going off spinning in different
directions so if you look at what for
example we do with openSUSE in our tools
and and things like OBS and open QA all
of the tools and processes are designed
in a way that they're there to not just
let the developer do what they want to
do but encourage and guide it towards
good practice good guidelines and
ultimately long-term sustainable
maintainer ship because you have that
first concept where you want to have the
capability of any developer possibly
disappearing and being replaced by
another you've got to have a little bit
of sort of common standards and common
structures so you know you guy off the
street can understand what the hell the
last guy did but doing that into in as
part of a structure sort of tooling or
processes generally works a hell of a
lot better than relying it to being
people in technical committees and
decision-making groups because
ultimately as its kind of fun to admit
with developers we argue with people all
the time if you do it in a tool we're
really unlikely to argue with a bot so
you know having that there is a very
clean way of making sure that you can
laughs with this model in the long term
and you do want to trust your you know
your developers knew your volunteers but
conflicts of opinion will arise and you
need to have a tiebreaking solution
in openSUSE we basically sum this entire
philosophy up in what phrase those that
do decide which I say way too often and
citation needed can't find an excuse
besides where we use it so openSUSE so
where we're living this philosophy you
know where we're we're focusing on
making sure our volunteers are the ones
deciding where openSUSE is going down
obviously we're not expecting everybody
to do everything on their own so we
encourage to have self organized teams
we just had that last talk took before
last we're a collaborative were talking
about their how they were using OBS and
that whole kind of model of multiple OBS
projects layering over each other that
feature in OBS is born from this concept
of self organized teams because we
needed to have this model where anybody
can go to our built service anybody can
start working on it and we kind of start
grouping people together based on common
packages that they're working on but
they do that in a separate project so
they can have their own rules it can
have their own structure they can do all
things their own way so it's devolved
but not at art and anarchic and again in
those tools in those structures we
define that by consensus generally you
know a mailing list aware that the
general concepts are defined and agreed
and then they implemented generally in
tooling which are then overseen by other
volunteers so they're open source too so
if you want to change the tooling and
you know what you need to do is it
commit request so that that's of how we
keep those general standards rather than
having a bearing technical committee
making decisions in a dark room it's all
done in tooling in open in the public
and therefore all changeable at any
moment's notice because it's all easily
just committable
so in action you know this this sort of
do a critique approach yeah yeah I
wanted avoid using that word anybody you
can log into the openSUSE build service
today and check and submit any change to
any package in the openSUSE codebase no
permissions were quite existing
volunteers will automatically be
notified the OBS would automatically say
hey this needs a review and but they
give it they're not that review isn't a
blocking it's there to give an
opportunity if they don't review it in a
timely manner we're going to assume that
new person off the street is probably
you know good enough to at least reach
the next stage of the review and move on
from that so you know they have a chance
to start working with the person they
don't have a chance to block everything
and therefore the contributions do all
of the talking we generally are when
we're dealing with the new contribution
in the open to the codebase are our
first criteria our first thoughts are
much more about how easy is it for us to
carry that change we generally don't ask
at least on the human side of things
very reviewing does this actually work
or is this actually want to go in
because we have those automatic checks
in our tooling with OBS and with open QA
so the does it work question is a simple
case of what you know we leave we leave
that out of the equation entirely and of
course that does sometimes mean that
some changes take a little bit longer to
get in because the person doing the
change also has to write the test to get
it into the test suite so when they can
prove that it works but it really
doesn't mean that those contributions
can go in any direction there's no
overarching control there's no
overarching features or functions so we
don't have any steering committees we
don't have any technical boards
benevolent dictators project managers
and you don't even have community
managers I mean it's the whole thing is
meant to be self managing self-governing
and ultimately self-sustaining and
therefore systemd ends up being another
good example because we were the first
distribution to actually have system D
in our code base it was like July 2010
like I mean the first commits were in
like April and we had a package in our
distro in July because one guy
I mean we think he was the upstream
developer system they wanted to put it
in the distribution and it became a
default in 2012 the changes were made by
the people who wanted to have it in the
distribution and actually one of them
sitting this morning at me if people
didn't want it and there was of course
some objections on our mailing list and
then some discussion the answer in this
model is simple fine we're not forcing
this on anybody there's no overarching
decision that we must use system D if
you can do something better if you can
do something else if you want to still
carry sis V in it as well then do the
work in this case the Commons assisting
in it maintain us weren't really that
interested in carrying on doing that so
you know it didn't it didn't happen and
we now are only a system D distribution
but there was no conscious decision for
that there was no management decision
because the management and ultimately
there was no major strife you know there
wasn't a huge blow-up we didn't lose
contributors we didn't have a you know
whoever dienasty time we are where we
are and we got there without yeah
without the drive that other models by
accident just calls
Pease and this model has some really
significant benefits openSUSE the more
we've embraced this model than what
we've fine-tuned it the more we realize
this is the way we should be doing
things has become more and more agile
where we can now as a distribution deal
with changes with whatever upstream
projects are doing at a rate of pace
that not even arch linux can do you know
we're able to keep up with everybody at
every speed at full pace without any
problem and we can also deal with all
the wonderful centricity Zavala various
upstream so you know every upstream does
something different they have different
valishia jewels they have different
structures because we've got this
devolved model where the contributors
are deciding how it works and they're
you know they're working close with
their upstream they know what crazy
stuff they're doing so they're dealing
with that and there's no kind of
overarching policy of okay I'm picking
on debian sorry but no overarching
policy of like you know we cannot change
version numbers ever you know in our
case even in our stable distribution
even in our enterprise distribution you
know if an upstream has made some change
for some patch that's security critical
or otherwise needed for Souza's
enterprise customers Susan will look at
that and think okay we can back forward
that change we can change the version
number and they'll decide there which
one makes more sense for that case
sometimes they'll just backboard it
quite often they do sometimes end up
with a version bump even an enterprise
distribution and therefore you know you
end up with a nice yeah free approach of
yeah if it works and you support it it
gets him
it isn't perfect freedom has its
problems one of which being the
powerdocs of choice you know if develop
a new person coming into your project
has an option to do whatever they want
so they decide to do nothing good they
can't decide what they want to do it can
be overwhelming and I don't have a great
answer for that you know obviously
things like you know obviously
documenting your current pain points
documenting where you know where you
dearly might need to have a little bit
of help can can help but then of course
you want to avoid crossing that line
just telling people what to do so that
yeah that part does get a little bit
tricky so my current approach to deal
with that one is do presentations like
this to make people realize you know
this is how we work this is how we're
thinking and don't panic just pick what
you want to do and go ahead with it it
also has a common tendency to have
misconceptions you know obviously you
know you're gonna have senior developers
you've been in your project for a long
time you know they might be seen to be
in a vow that can't be questioned but in
this model everyone needs to realize
that everybody can be questioned in
addition to my work that I do with
openSUSE orbits a chairman of openSUSE
I've currently been working on
restructuring how we do all of our BT FS
sub volumes in Slee and openSUSE I spent
months on this it's been like keeping me
up at night everything is now finally in
the distribution I know tomorrow some
other guy can come in and change
everything and I can't stop them but
that's fine that's how it should because
if they think they can do it better than
me isn't that why I was doing it in the
open in the first place you know so yeah
they did but that mentality needs to be
communicated people need to realize they
can challenge everybody in a project but
that sometimes means you've got more
than one person wanting to pull in a
different direction and conflicts happen
I knew what you need to have some
solution to resolve deadlock or void
deadlock
we need to have life aside calling now
organization will check sums now did you
don't want developers slapping each
other conflicts happen you know the same
volunteers we're human mostly we have
different ideas those ideas might not be
cut yeah compatible with each other and
compromises can be hard to find but most
distributions go and call this a
technical problem you know they put this
this conflict resolution under there the
role of their technical committee and
you know and how many mailing lists
threads do we have in our other projects
or arguing about the technical benefit
of this over that and whatever
it's not a technical problem you have to
developers or multiple groups of
developers who have an interpersonal
issue with each other and you need to
think about these problems in that
context forget about the technical
solution because ultimately even if one
of the answers is 100% technically
better it doesn't matter because
possibly the only one that matters is
the one that's going to be maintained
two years from now or three years from
now in the future so ultimately the only
bit that matters is the one that has the
you know the motivation behind it the
people who want to make it move you know
if the the better solutions don't
necessarily win the motivated ones win
and so when you've got these
interpersonal issues you need to find a
way of basically satisfying the
motivations of as many of the people
involved as you can it needs to have a
human touch you need to be dealing with
the humans and seeing in human terms and
you need to make sure that all sides of
the argument are not just heard but feel
that they have been heard feel that
their concepts have been understood and
thought about and dealt with and that's
how you get to these compromises of
actually how we end up with everybody
moving the whole Linux and distribution
ecosystem forward it's also how you
sometimes end up with like five or six
different versions of a package new
distribution but that's not necessarily
a bad thing
because you can find compromises to the
weirdest problems another perfect
example is you know consider the desktop
options we have you know we have KD
years are kind of default know equally
fully supported and looking away in some
dark corner of the tumbleweed codebase
we still have KD III because we've got
maintainer x' who still today managed to
get it in the distribution and make it
work no KD for luckily but they still
have KD III I think they're crazy but I
can't stop them and that's fine because
you know they're able to they're able to
keep it working and they're able to work
that way and you know that's fine and
every now and again the KDE 5 guys in
the KT 3 guys end up doing something
stupid like sharing a library name and
everything goes horribly wrong
but you know when you get them around
the table and talk about that issue
there and deal it on a personal level
every time they found a compromise for
their problem we don't have to decide
oh we're gonna drop KD 3 because the
like we got the same name so
decision-making should always be a naps
in this kind of conflict should be an
absolute last resort you shouldn't be
trying to decide this side versus that
side or this solution of that solution
you really should be aiming for
compromise you really need to be aiming
for in really ultimately going back to
the original concept of enabling your
volunteer to do what your volunteer
wants to do in the first place so if you
can find a way from everyone involved to
do what you want to do and if you do
make a decision you've got to realize
that the the thing you're deciding at
the end of it the people conflicting and
yelling at each other for the last six
months on your mailing list still got to
be the ones implementing that solution
so you know you don't want to be just up
in a situation where you've made some
overarching decision now developer must
go do this and how could it do it do
they disagree with it so what's the
point of the decision-making process
so basically what you need you know if
you have a problem and no one else can
help you need to have an a-team of sorts
in openSUSE we have that as the openSUSE
board which is our evolution of what was
once sort of our copy of the fedora
council unlike the fedora council this
board has no responsibility whatsoever
when it comes to dealing with goals and
long term planning and I mean sometimes
we do it and give suggestions and
sometimes people listen
but the responsibilities are just that
that you see on the board there we're
there to resolve conflicts we're there
to be a central point of contact for the
project and we are the absolute
decision-makers an absolute must result
and because of course we have a
corporate sponsor in the case of Sousa
we also had the responsibility of
keeping touches Sousa and vice versa cuz
you know it's easy for the company if
they go just group of people to
immediately talk to you and ask
questions of and that kind of thing
internally we've taken a model which has
somewhat changed from from what everyone
else is doing
apart from gnome actually this is very
similar to the known project model where
we have five elected board members the
elected by our community which are
currently openSUSE members which are
basically currently established they're
both existing established volunteers
they're the selection criteria for
openSUSE members is actually something
that I think we need to fix right now in
openSUSE there is a selection committee
or a membership committee which decides
have you done enough stuff to contribute
which of course goes against everything
I've just been talking about for the
last half hour that is something which
well hopefully the rest of the community
will be to see the presentation and now
understand why I'm about to suggest that
we simplify that and make it a case of
if you've contributed and you want to be
a member and you remember you know it
isn't gonna work any different it's
going to be a lot easier to get people
involved and integrated into the
community
an elected board member has a two-year
term we don't want to keep on replacing
the entire board every two years so at
one year we were placed two of them one
every yeah every other year we placed
three of them but we have this really
hard rule no more than two board members
so no more than 40% which is the same as
the gnome foundation can have the same
employer so if you do the math you know
best case for Sousa they can only have
two people on elected into the board
that's it
therefore you know you've got a company
that's actually adopted the same
mentality here of creating a structure
in their own friendly project which
they're you know which they started and
sponsored but is designed to challenge
themselves they you know there is no way
that yeah Sousa can have overarching
control of the board six person which is
appointed by Sousa so they guaranteed to
have at least one person in there which
from several years in openSUSE I've been
the only one you know there's you know
the community elected you know all non
Sousa employees and I was there on my
own which is great yeah and nothing
nothing wrong with that whatsoever and I
have the additional responsibility of
you know being the one guys went to talk
to Sue's it all the time
ultimately I whereas one thing I forgot
to put on the board this board is
answerable to the membership we have a
25% rule I think which is the 25 percent
of the members say they don't like the
current board to get anyone the pretty
low threshold and you know pretty easy
to replace the whole lot
however the members they didn't elect me
they can't get rid of me but the board
can so again having a system with voting
checks and balances everyone's caught
yet you know I can't go rogue and take
over the entire project even if I wanted
to and that's how it should be you know
there should be a challenge in there
there should be something to keep me on
my toes and keep me honest and keep
everything yet smoother because yeah
yeah otherwise how can we be sure I'm
doing things here with my
responsibilities really in mind
and so you end up with back to this
quote roof yeah corporations of people
in a democratic model the corporation
has to start acting like one because the
only way that Sousa can get something
done in openSUSE is if they're acting
like peers the Sousa employees have to
be part of openSUSE the same way that
some random contributor is a part of
openSUSE they don't have any additional
control because they've got a sues email
address the only control they have is
literally through the commits which they
put into the project but their commits
are no more important on and watching
than any commits from any other person
who's also working in the project that
means they have to keep up with that
their upstreams either various different
parts of the openSUSE project or you
know obviously the different options are
dealing with across the world which is
an interesting proposition when two
companies to realize okay
there you know effectively other people
are creating work for you because you
know you have to keep up with these
other people and when there is a change
that they want to have for example thank
you restructuring the you know look like
maybe we recently restructuring up etfs
layout you know I had to go and persuade
the community at large that that was you
know a good thing and you know I
couldn't just go in there and throw it
in because I'm chairman of open susan
and like i say they can take it out any
moment they want anyway but corporations
already know how to do this you know the
kernel works under very similar
principles of this no single company has
a vouching control of the kernel no
single company has over arching the
toilet open snack so why the heck do the
Red Hat's in the canonical of the world
who know how to work in this kind of
environment not create one when they're
building a system yet building their own
project at home yeah they go and make
some nice little feast in which they can
control with their guys in charge and I
think that's wrong I think it's really
missing a trick and I think it's
actually really holding these companies
back because they can't be as agile and
as fast and as flexible dealing with
what's really going on in the open
source world at large because they're
just going to be focused on what they've
decided internally in their little ivory
castle
so in conclusion distributions all of
them I think you should get rid of your
technical committees entirely and your
dictators you know you should not have
them you do not need them you're just
creating ways of saying no to the very
people you need to keep your project
going but when it comes to decision
making models you know favored duoc you
see over democracy you know especially
direct democracy you just will never get
a decision made if you ask everybody
everything that means you need to trust
and empower your volunteers to drive
your project you therefore need to have
some way of dealing with deadlocks and
breaking that cycle like like and be a
mediation body but the limit Desco don't
fall into the trap of starting with them
as a mediation body and then they end up
revolving to some kind of technical
committee and any end of you know being
responsible for deciding your long term
goals it doesn't work and corporations
need to realize especially with their
local their local distribution projects
that there are the close of them give up
the control you don't need it it holds
you back when you have that control yeah
if you treat your distribution
communities like your other upstreams
your distribution community can start
moving faster like your other up streams
that's how you can make money quickly
you can go to market with that new stuff
faster you know so why hold your teams
back why hold why holds your friendly
volunteers back it doesn't make any
sense and yet we see it all over the
place and have a lot of fun this is what
open source is about and with that I am
done and have a bit of time for
questions yes
where it's more like a building code and
yep always and we often have
contribution contributors the Congo is a
big chunk of change but there is no
ground not always a guarantee that we
will continue maintaining this which
which is why I like you your review
process and then your fooling there you
know that that should be a primary
question of you know can we understand
this this contribution in a way that we
can maintain it you know if this guy
disappears so that that and does it work
are basically the only two acceptance
criteria for anything in like openSUSE
for example and I think those are the
only two acceptance criteria really
should have I don't think you should be
getting too much into the nitty-gritty
of deciding is this you know always the
Wrights best technical solution if you
can understand it and it works why not
accept it in the case of openSUSE we
throw in a new open QA test at it but
yeah i mean general generally i mean
that that should be a fair question for
that time and that initial contribution
basically you know in something like a
new platform there you know yeah they're
creating is an environment with a
problem to ask it a little bit of
question of you know okay are you going
to be able to look after this for a
little bit longer but thinking in those
terms totally changes the way you're
gonna ask that question then just saying
no we don't support that platform so you
know just that's kind of I know it seems
over like psychic mumbo-jumbo but yeah
you do need to think you do need to kind
of realize that you should be thinking
in these terms to frame that question
that way spider
with festiveness of a unmaintained
package the things building it lost it
it's still an integral but nobody really
wants to touch then you throw it away
and with everything else that's attached
to it it's amazing how quickly that
motivates someone to take care of that
nasty thing at the bottom I mean you you
you threatened to do so first and then
you do but you mean you know you want to
break everything you have there but in
fact we just had that a car which packed
we had just had that we could yeah we
just we literally just had that with
Rico diem openSUSE so yeah that's and
but that kind of that that sort of
craziness actually in this model drives
innovation we've now the food Rico to
less fortune it's a good model yes you
mentioned that canonical they have this
place quite a corporate structure yep
which is like I'm I might have been
developer and I find it quite difficult
to be in 1700 Jewish things into the
bundle even for packages I maintain in
Debian and which one to take home
yep it sort of makes sense for them
because like it isn't quite some
difference between Bret Hart and Fedora
for example and Devin and a bundle
because like and what happens to door at
like most of the drive happens comes
from Red House even though even if it
happens since the door at first maybe
I'm not quite sure
well how it works and in there but I
guess like most of the people are like
rock on employees and they do things and
their sees but in heaven and a boudreaux
relationship is different so like the
driver force becoming to behind get in
and the water builds and death that's
why probably four canonical makes sense
I wouldn't argue that it doesn't make
sense I agree that it's yeah you know
this makes sense the canonical canonical
happy fine I think it's wrong you know I
don't I don't think it doesn't make
sense I just think it's wrong and I
think I mean there's the the kind of
practical examples that I've mostly
focused on in this talk of you know the
agility and the ability to deal with
crazy changes quickly but also I just
think it's morally wrong we're meant to
be an open system innit we're meant to
be doing open source why are we limiting
our up why we are wire canonical
limiting their options in their codebase
long term isn't that just shooting
themselves in the foot with how fast
they can go to market with their own
stuff so you know I mean I don't really
want to make the bun to a nice you know
better competitor than openSUSE but you
know if they did pay attention it would
be quicker I'm not sure how familiar you
would I think it's like what the example
you have with systemd for example you
know the Technical Committee and Debian
is the very last resort which is like if
nothing else helps they step in you know
normally it it it doesn't have any role
in any decision taken at all when if the
huge fractions of developers cannot
agree on something or if this is just
what the average which gives say no to
everyone in this case this when the
techno committee steps in because like
consistently it was one of the
situations like that so yeah there was a
discussion without a ball in them should
we switch the system the whole probably
we should under as much of he'll come in
saying oh no we hate Lerner
[Laughter]
like when he kept you know going on a
long time someone said okay let's take
it up to
see see see TT because we can't stand it
anymore I mean I get that but I can't I
kind of want to pose like yeah yeah I
get that but but I still kinda want to
pose the question of if Debian didn't
have a technical committee you know how
different could things be if they
followed this model because you fought
this half a year more mostly because it
took quite I took it to quite some you
know detail when when he ended it by
just saying okay I'm I'm the chair I'm
ending this now and I'm using my chair
vote which is normally not being used
what he did use it like to gain the
majority it mostly like okay people who
continued hate let up they went out and
they created a bill whatever like I mean
it's thought without that decision
probably would continue for quite a long
time I see where you're going but I
think I think there is another way I
think I think this all with you thank
you thank you
[Applause]