okay thanks again there we go from map
down to XML
exactly so yeah I'm Stefan I'm a
technical writer Susur and I'm going to
be presenting about what we do to try to
keep our documents here eight
automatically or even just hop
automatically at this point I've been
working with Sousa for the last two and
a half years before that I was a working
student there so I already have some bit
of history with the company so first of
all this is the outline of the talk I'll
give you some pointers on our workflow
and our team what we do actually then
I'll come - yeah the normal client based
checks that each team member can do
individually on their machine afterwards
I continue with this server based checks
that we do and finally I won't be
speaking about the documentation as such
but the star sheets that we used to
output HTML and PDF from our XML sources
so first of all the team we're actually
pretty small I mean we were actually not
that small but we kind of look like this
this is a few of ever seen as soon as
the documentation presentation in the
last two years you may have seen this
photo already but that was just a few of
us
and given the people the amount of
people that we have we have quite a big
task so we have to maintain around
15,000 PDF a full pages mind you there
are some pages that are counted twice in
there I will come back to that in a
minute and the content that we do is
everything that is published on Surat
comm / documentation and also the
release notes that are absolutely at
home - release notes or shipped with our
products our main formats for
documentation are HTML and PDF and epub
what we do not do is we do not do Linux
Mint pages and we also do not usually
work on the output of the various
management help commands so and our
workflow is based on docbook we're also
currently looking into adopting asciidoc
at least for some tasks that are easier
but we're otherwise still quite happy
with docbook even though there's
sometimes this is kind of pushback that
developers want something that is
supposedly easy we always put that in
square quotes and scare quotes when
people say that markdown is easy because
it's actually not that easy but asciidoc
is a good compromise I guess you lose
some semantics yeah our basic approach
and what we do is this robustness
principle so we try to be liberal and
whatever
and input formats we accept but we are
relatively conservative and what we
output which is pretty much always stock
book at this point so yeah we have
single sourcing that means we have
multiple output formats multiple output
documents that are produced from the
same source so that means for example we
have this less and so the server and the
desktop product documentation that are
basically produced from the same XML
source the only difference being that we
exchanged the product names and also
that we switch off some chapters for
each of the guides that are not relevant
[Music]
and of course the second aspect of
single sourcing is usually taken for
granted I guess today because it's just
that you can produce multiple output
formats our workflow is intentionally
oriented at what developers at Susans
are also do so we use git and github and
increasingly use pull requests and
radius on those pull requests and we
also use the so called git flow
branching model which I think helps us a
lot and you know keeping an overview of
our branches
and since we have this thing called oh
yes the open built server that also
builds some of our documentation and
because of that we also have a fully
open source tool chain so because this
server basically operates only on open
source stuff and this tool chain is
called that's the doc book authoring in
publishing suit which we need because
the upstream doc book tool chain is sort
of not a tool chain at all because it
still needs all the glue that holds it
together
and it also has some functionality gaps
that's a bit different from detail where
you actually have a full tool chain that
is prefab and that solves this tool
chain problem for us and it's also open
source so if you like you can take a
look and maybe so it might solve it for
you and what it does it takes pieces
from various up streams that are glued
together for example to enable the
single sourcing of documents from four
different products we need something
called profiling and those profiling
style sheets need to be run before the
actual output style sheets and this is
basically stuff that Dubbs does keeping
this flow if the command line tool yeah
so we're linux company we work pretty
much all on the command line
and it's also editor agnostic and that
it's not particularly integrated into
any specific editor and we all use
different editors so that's also
something that I guess somewhat special
among documentation teams there are some
processes that are external to our team
and also are not really handled by DAPs
or on the some fringes of it are handled
by dubs which is translation which we
have outsourced to another company or
yeah free translator freelance
translators and final publication is
also something that another team at our
mother company micro focus is doing so
with that I come to the actual topic so
the first main thing we do client site
is of course validation because
validation is necessary for XML and it's
also one of the things that makes XML
worthwhile because you can very strictly
say which kind of content you accept and
which way then your document so we of
course need validation to validate we
have an own docbook 5.1 based rng schema
that's called picot doc basically what
we do with that is we restrict docbook
to a certain degree because docbook is
quite free and for example allowing
lists within paragraphs which for layout
reasons are not really what we want so
it's quite hard to lay out stuff like
that
sometimes it's run using depth validate
so that's just the command we use and
the validation is based on the Jing tool
which is just yeah an upstream Java tool
the next thing we have is something
called style checker we have a Sousa
style guide for our documentation
basically laying down language and
structure rules that authors should
adhere to why do we do this because we
want to avoid confusing our readers and
we also want to avoid translation costs
so that's why we have a Stargate that
also includes some terminology rules so
you get better translations and also
avoid confusing your readers with
synonyms etc the Stiga result checker is
a custom thing and it checks for both
language rules and some sort of soft
syntax rules that are usually helpful
but which we didn't want to yeah have
validation crash or yeah
which which we didn't want to pull out
the big hammer of validation for so one
example for a language rule is that you
that if you use the words in order to
which is a quite wordy phrase
it asks you it suggests to use just the
word - which is already a lot shorter an
example for syntax rules is to avoid
lonely sections lonely sections are
basically subsections that don't have
any peers in their own section and this
usually hints at a structuring issue one
of the nice things that having this
custom program means is that we can
actually integrate with XML and it's
also a nice assist a necessity for us
because our documentation features quite
a few commands with very idiosyncratic
names and it also enables some nice
things for example we have a rule
against using the hit the word hit to
mean press a key and because we mark up
our keys in docbook with the key cap
element we can just look for the key cap
element and look whether there's the
word hit or press in front of it and
I'll put an error message or a warning
message if there is the word hit it's
written in Python of with lots of XSLT
and lots of regular expressions and I'll
give a short
okay let's think
other I'll give a short preview this is
what the output looks like so we have
messages you see this is an XML file
actually start with CSS which works but
and attempts to produce quite a bit of
output so checks for sentence length so
this is just actually a relatively well
checked file and it's also just the
installation QuickStart guide which is
maybe 30 pages in a lot of screenshots
it tends to produce a lot of output for
longer documents so some of it is also
false positive so yeah that's that's not
ideal
okay
so what do we have in terms of future
plans one of the first things is that
when we already have a work in progress
for this is adding spell check which
might seem weird to you because you
might think this is the first thing we'd
add but we already had a pre-existing
spell checker in depth so I didn't
really invent this immediately there's
also an issue with source lines and
that's also a bit of a heart problem and
we have the issue of output formats
because this XML file is not stops
caring that well I must say and we'd
also like some editor integration though
we probably need HTML output and also
some kind of plain text output that is
readable next on we have server based
checks and that we have Travis which is
relatively new in our tool chain Travis
is a docker based CI system that
integrates with github it's a free as in
beer unfortunately only why do we want
this so I said we have this github pull
request workflow and this pull request
workflow also means that we get four
requests from others other teams that
Susa not everyone is actually running a
validator and some people are validating
only with topic 5 instead of our more
strict eco doc schema and Travis gives
us some sort of quick feedback there
it also consistency consistently checks
all output documents which is necessary
to prevent a problem we've had before
that is that sometimes people would only
check for a would only check some output
documents and other output documents
that were not needed at the time were
then languishing sometimes even for
months and we're basically not buildable
so Travis makes sure that we keep this
stuff buildable all the time and yeah to
do that we have a docket to container
with openSUSE and apps on it with which
we validate when do we also make sure
that all images successfully seconds
sometimes people forget get adding an
image they added to the documentation
and it's good to check that from the
server but we're not really at the end
there so one of the other plans we have
is that we want to use Travis to
actually build our documentation and
publish it to github pages and
integrating the style checker would also
be a nice idea but we'd have to look at
how to not inundate people with too many
messages fathers had just spoke about
publishing we already also have an
internal basically nightly build
publishing platform which is helpful for
getting early developer feedback and
sometimes unfortunately ballots XML does
not mean that our PDFs bill that's
basically fringe cases but it's relevant
enough
so in those cases you actually get a
mail from our internal publishing server
yes this server builds documentation
automatically once a day or on demand
from a web UI it also has a search and
it has a quite interesting sort of
technology stack if you want to call it
that I have a quick example here so this
is not the actual life server but this
is what the overview page if it looks so
basically you can just request to
rebuild here and our documentation looks
like that then so with the draft logo
and thanks for that
yeah now on to our style sheets so I'm
finishing with the documentation itself
these style sheets what are they
actually so the doc book upstream
project has these XSLT stylesheets that
format your document as HTML or PDF or
man pages or any per lots of different
formats but of course we want to add a
dash of green to that and our Suzy logo
and things like that and so we have our
own custom Sousa style sheets that
actually import the dark book star
sheets from upstream and what do we need
to check that that's actually pretty
simple XSLT is complicated it's not
always clear at the first glance how the
flow works because it calls template
rules and depending on which template
rules are also present
the template rule and use my change then
we also have to keep the wonderful five
compatibility we have to keep language
compatibility and since we output quite
a few uh performance those are also in
need of checking whether they still work
so and since our HTML is also responsive
that's basically like three different
formats or at once okay and yeah we need
to check what our bug fixes work and as
a bonus we we also get documents that we
can use for manual tests so what steps
compared to it creates lots of little
images from our documentation and then
it yeah you basically run it once before
you make change to the star sheets and
once after you made this change to the
star sheets and it automatically
automatically compares those reference
images to be in comparison images and
then shows you in a nice little cube
based viewer side by side view of those
images with changing sections actually
highlighted yeah we made something
custom for that because what we wanted
was actually pretty simple we just
wanted to run ups as parallel as
possible and then get those images
unfortunately I can't show you the
program right now
not even the viewer because it hung up
on me this morning so I'm sorry for that
but we have some future plans we need
more example documents there
and with that documents yeah XSLT as you
say is what it is but explain to you how
to write XSLT at the start
unfortunately you're not German there's
actually quite a good documentation site
that is German only
there's there's a company called data to
type if you're German that actually they
have actually produced quite good
documentation for XSLT sometimes you can
use muscle develop the network that
works but also Microsoft has particular
the documentation I must say that also
works for me quite a lot of times yeah
sorry the question was whether there's
good documentation for XSLT okay um more
questions yes
you see any supplementary I think small
Kira opsal about that how do you go
together you reviews with
so the question was whether we use JIRA
or Bugzilla or another back tracker and
how we pull that together with github
with our github workflow so yes we have
souza Bugzilla
we also have an internal feature
tracking system called fight it works
basically the same but it's full
features not for bugs
which is sort of arbitrary distinction
but yes we we do that but we do also
notice that a lot of our developers are
actually working on get up as well so
keeping the people on github is actually
not a bad idea
okay mr. problem you you have your kind
of custom relaxing gee that's a modified
version yep sure doc books and you have
some various other checks have looked
into using schema Tron to implement any
of those checks so the question was
whether we are looking into schema Tron
yes we currently are on the other hand
schema Tron is sort of like XSLT light
in a way so yes we're currently looking
at schema Tron - because Jane also
supports schema Tron but it is a bit
buggy because the doc book orangy
actually includes some schematron rules
but Jing can't execute them because
they're in because they're embedded in
the RNG so we're currently looking at
how we actually can solve this pickle
there yep
cool okay
[Applause]
[Music]