yes'm
hello I will join the session about the
tracers so we have moved from a stage of
trace to the trace now yeah how do you
know what the trace is have you seen it
or has anyone here some experience with
the trash from non Linux environment
cool
so briefly introduce the DTrace itself
because it was first released in 2005 it
was designed for San Suarez at the time
and it was the answer for performance
and observability our system so we can
support the customers of of some servers
and so on today is 2019 and the trace
has been ported to various operating
systems so it is now used on iPod micro
at 6:00
of course Joanne because it is a fork of
Suarez basically FreeBSD adopted DTrace
we are working the Oracle Linux it's
working progress but it's port to Linux
in general I have also seen some
attempts to develop DTrace for Windows
so yeah so why we need another linux
racer
well the idea behind DTrace is it's not
a linux only tracer so our goal is to
basically add a Linux operating system
to the family of dtrace supported
operating systems not just great another
just linux only tracer one strength of
the trace it can trace kernel it can
trace user space tracing happens
directly inside the kernel at the block
time we will talk about this later and
the traces its own scripting language is
this called the D it is a basically
superset of C programming language so
it's very simple
and it's quite powerful I will show it
on the examples I have yeah and because
it was in 2005 we have been using it
that Sun and all records for about the
decade to troubleshoot production
machines of our customers and also
another benefit is there are a lot of
books and documents about it is already
so it is not a new technology that's new
for Linux so I think one of the key
differentiators is with dtrace you have
everything but you need so there is no
need to install external tool chain
compilers there is no need it does not
produce a kernel modules unit load so it
is designed to be used in animal
for example you need to sign the kernel
modules which are trusted so you cannot
just load something in the kernel yet so
basically that's it so I'll briefly
describe some basics of how details work
so from your user perspective the
workload workflow is similar to EBP F
and BCC kind of tools
well that's because this is the
predecessor of those tools so you write
some tracing script in the D language
the script gets compiled into a bytecode
which uses DTrace instruction format so
we have internal machine that interprets
this bytecode before we start
interpreting anything we verify that the
bytecode is safe because the test was
meant to be run on production machines
so part of the protection is the
restriction on the language side so you
cannot use loops for example to not
create something which will stop CPU for
too long time and also we verified that
the produce bytecode because someone
else can send something down the kernel
is safe to use if everything is fine we
basically enable the probes and start
processing the actions recording the
data to the tracing buffers and our user
space components perfectly extracts the
data from kernel and father put system
as it's similar to other traces you have
seen already
so the key components of the defect
architecture is a probe
do not make it a decay probe or you
probe a probe in the trace environment
is just an event it's identified by
unique to pole which consists from
provide the name module name function
and name of the probe we will get to
this later so it is quite abstract then
there is something called provider a
provider is responsible for creating
probes in your system so it knows the
internal logic the implementation of how
probe should be fired what does it mean
because our probe does not necessarily
must be tied to instruction stream or
something like this a consumer is the
other part of the architecture that
extracts the data and process them in
user space and since down your script
and then there is a framework the
framework is the core component that
basically
everything together so framework is
responsible for managing the probes if
you have a multiple consumers it is
basically subscribing the consumers to
the probes and sense the data through
and yeah that's it so to give you idea
what the provider is for example you
have a dtrace provider which is just the
framework itself there are some three
simple probes I will show you later how
they are we have a profile provider
which is able to create a probe that
fire sporadically on one or multiple
CPUs we have a SDP providers code
statically defined tracing so you know
it probably as a equity stress point in
Linux kernel or if you you as a
developer statically introduced some
point of interest to the code function
bandit racing is similar to pay probes
it basically scans the kernel kernel
modules for possible instrumental
symbols so to build the probes out of it
faster provider is now being in the work
so it allows you to do the same thing in
the user space at the moment we support
static instrumentation of user space
binaries but we don't have an equivalent
of FBT on Linux yet yeah and everything
is about Cisco so we also have a Cisco
provider that allows you to observe an
instrument Cisco's in the operating
system so how does it look like from
[Music]
binary or deployment you need to have a
kernel which is a d3 support because we
need some architecture specific stuff
directly in the kernel and you need a
set of modules one module is called the
trace is the framework itself and then
usually a provider is another separate
kernel module which can be loaded and
and it had some features of the probes
to the system then we have a Lib DTrace
which is the core of the user space and
is responsible for compiling your
scripts and talking to the kernel part
running the staff extracting the buffers
parsing the records handling them
then there is a lip block which is a
basically broke FS wrapper because it's
supporting player for de tres so it's
some simplified interface on top over
proc FS so it can be ported to other
platforms and then we have a compact
type format help library I will get back
to this later so and the last thing is
the command itself you use it is the
consumer but most of the logic happens
in the Lib DTrace so thanks to this
architecture you technically can remove
the D trace command and write your own
command using direct the library API to
create your own place or integrate these
rays to your application on unsliced we
used to have a Java wrapper so you could
basically use the library from Java but
I think you should be able to get the
trace integrated to other language like
Python go basically whatever that can
bind the C language from from your
language not it's not easy I've tried to
go and it's not so easy so yeah finally
we have some project page which is open
source so if you want to see the sources
or state of the project we try to keep
it updated it's not always the like this
guy taste yeah this is well at least
right at least for now so now let's move
to more interesting part and it's
actually how how you can use the details
how it looks like so even though that's
not so much time to talk about
architecture in details I try to prepare
some set of examples so we can see how
how you can use it in real life or so
the first thing you need to know is how
the language looks like so it was
designed to be simple so if you know or
you basically provide a list of probes
identified by the tuples it can be more
than one Pro because you can share
action blocks with multiple profiling
it's up to you then we have a
per decade a predicate is optional and
allows you to write the expression and
if the expression evaluates to true the
action block is executed in the car now
expression is false we just skip it away
so it's to allow you to quickly filter
out the stuff just directly when we are
the probe firing point
yeah the trace actions you will see some
of them but basically you can work with
variables you can call something which
looks like C functions and that's it
your script is executed from top to
bottom and you can have multiple action
blocks for the same probe it will be
executed from top to bottom
so yeah now to explain the things you
can use ooh we have something we call a
subroutine you can think of it as
function returning a value so subroutine
is used if you for example need to
convert data or copy something from user
space to Connors place or other way
around and it can for example write a
new pointer Bar is the destination in
the kernel kernel space only trace and
usually can be used in pretty case
because it is a returning value the so
you can use it to do some some decision
the action is only in the action block
it is a statement so it doesn't have a
return value and allows you to record
something into the buffers or or
basically perform some effect on the
system so the actions can be executed in
two places straight in the prop context
where we basically disable scheduling
interrupts so it will happen on spot or
later in user space in that in that
moment basically the action is not
anything with the prop firing but for
some actions it does not make sense to
do them in the kernel just to save CPU
cycles and also some of the actions we
support can be destructive to the
operating system we are cooking because
we have an action like panic for example
if you intentionally kill the host so a
destructive action requires usage of
explicit argument the idea is we try to
be as much safe so you avoid killing
your system by some random accident but
we want you to explicitly say you know
what you are doing before you kill the
system and no it doesn't tell me it has
to kill the system but their actions for
example you can introduce delays at
random places in kernel so we can mess
up the scheduling interrupts whatever so
there are some hard limits which can all
the actions are blocked from you to use
so now basically we get through the
language description so you can see well
if you try any new language the goal is
to write a hello world
so this
hello world in de três so I'm using a
DTrace provider so you can see the full
description of the probes is provider is
DTrace it doesn't have a module it
doesn't have a function is just
beginning and error Pro they are kind of
special because the begin probe fires
always first and it's always last but
before we terminates racing's so you can
do some innate cleanup and error probe
fires only when an action block you
execute cause this summer for example if
you touch memory and would cause a page
fault or something like this details
will silently ignore it and replace it
like loading volume zero but it will
fire the arrow probe for you so you can
introduce your own hand link if you
don't you will see something like there
was an action at all on action number
they've instruction number and and so on
so yeah you can see the example we use
just the begin program it is not fully
qualified because you don't have to if
the test is able to identify uniquely
what you have to get there is no other
begin probe in any provider so you can
just write a beginner and it has adjust
to actions the first one print something
the second one terminates the tracing
with the return value so when I was
talking about some actions happening in
the user space the printer is a good
example because the printer takes a
formatting string and optional set of
arguments like you know from language
but if we would try to assemble the
final string in kernel we would just
wait CPU cycles so what we do we store
only the arguments in kernel and thence
pass it through to the user space and
then we are in user space we do the file
string formatting and the print so it
just balances the performance between
kernel and the user space
so one great feature about DTrace is
that the framework knows about every
available probe to you and you can list
it so you can think about that MBT is
similar to k probes it has a we support
only Ethel and 20 points at or right
tool and entry points to a function we
don't support arbitrary instrumentation
but technically we can add for example K
Pro provider and use K probes underneath
but the great thing is you can list the
probes so when you come to some random
system you know nothing about it you can
at least as a first step of debugging
take a look what's available for you to
use
what is missing
so you can do more you can you don't
have to list all the probes you can just
provide some partial specifications so
you can lose just a subset of probes
that matches what you are trying to look
for and you can loop more detail
description of a probe so as you can see
it's just some kind of identification
yeah and somebody is propionate but in
addition because it is usually a lot of
about stability and backward
compatibility you have some stability
attributes for every probe this is
interesting if you want to implement a
script and don't want that script got
broken like next day when we change the
kernel we basically give you some
description how stable the probe itself
is so whether it will exist tomorrow or
not you can see private private identify
names means this whole private we can
change it whenever we want but for
argument's you can see it is evolving
which gives you some there is some
document about this what are possible
kinds of of types but basically it shows
you act we will change it probably in
future but not today or on daily basis
so you can base those on top of it
and the last interesting thing is that
for some probes we can say you what is
the type of argument appropriate so you
know what structural type you can access
from
from the descript so the one of the most
powerful things in details are
aggregations aggregations happen
directly in the kernel so and they are
represented in the D language as a
special variable which can use a
multiple keys a key can be anything it
can be stacked it can be string it can
be number basically whatever we can make
a hash out of it and then there is
aggregating function there is just
limited set of such functions it can be
from simple counting or to something
more complex which I will show later
what it does it means whenever we record
this kind of keys we have a sort of hash
table in Carnell and we apply the
aggregating function on top of it for
every CPU and then we merge aggregations
together so it is quite effective if you
need to see some counts because it
happens straight it doesn't need
post-processing you don't have to send a
huge stream of data up for some further
post-processing later you can do some
kind of things with this directly
so in addition to aggregating variables
of course we have some some built-in
variables which are accessible for you
in the D language itself it's probably
better to see documentation but just to
give you an idea what it is there is a
current threat variable which always
holds a pointer to the running threat or
task on a CPU at the moment when the
profiles current vs inflow is equivalent
but for our process we have a time stamp
which is something like clock monotonic
kind of time so you can sort the events
based on time we have a vole timestamp
which is real-world clock right time
based on yeah on the system time and
each probe can have some some arguments
like R 0 arc 9 everything is exposed to
variables this kind of variables is not
typed if you if I go to few slides back
you will see there is slight difference
when I listed the probe this is a RI so
if we know the types we expose you a
variable which is an RI and argument
index the argument number is indexed to
this arise so you can access it directly
as a typed argument if we don't have it
you have assembled in variables which
should be like 64-bit integers that's it
yes so now we enhanced our D language
skills so we can look for more advanced
example so in DTrace you not necessarily
need to write a long script so I based
this on examples of so-called one-liner
so whatever you see here just imagine
that there is a
dtrace - and this is add it as a string
argument so it is just a one-liner yeah
and you are missing some part that I
will I will explain it so basically what
it does we use a profile provide profile
Pro which should fire all each 9 9 7
Hertz on every CPU it's it's important
to not to use your number to not fight
with the scheduler because typically 10
milliseconds is some time of scheduling
so that's why the number looks weird the
probe if you look at in the
documentation has a two arguments which
are program counters where argument 0 is
kernel program counter argument one is
user space program counter so whenever
time of fires you know both of each
variable is nonzero whether you are in
user space or kernel space context and
then I have abrogating variable the
variable is anonymous so it's just and
the name is missing we just means
details who print it at the end because
it is very simple script so I don't need
to use some variable name and I'm using
two keys one key is the process ID and
secondly the key is the executable name
and what the party missing is it equals
to count
so the aggregating function just bumps
counter each time we see the same
p-value pair so if you run D trace this
time you will see it at form one probe
and the output will be this is the pate
this is the exact name again somewhere
here are the numbers so it is sorted
from smaller to higher so I have a 51
for the top process so what basically we
did in this example we created a user
space profiler
just with one line that monitors every
CPU and accounts for every program
counter in user
space so we know the top because it was
my VM back you know face was running
just the top and nothing else so if we
just swap the arc one to r0 we change it
to Colonel profile because r0 is you
know if there is no test it's basically
test for if R is zero or not of the
argument so now we are testing but the
caramel pointer is set to something and
if it is we aggregate and remember I was
talking about the subroutine so the funk
is a subroutine which takes a pointer
and give you Gazoo back a string name of
a symbol so again if you run the dtrace
you will see that this the output is
exactly the same it gives you the symbol
names and yeah the counts so the most
often called function in linux kernel
was native Safehold because most of the
virtual CPUs were either
yeah one last thing is that a profile
provider it's kind of dynamic so there
is no such probe like nine seven Hertz
so if you ask a provider to provide you
some probe the profile one will sync
synthetically created when you request
it and if the probe exit gets reused
because the framework they duplicate is
the existing stuff so this is just one
interesting so not everything must be
present from loading to provide a module
it can come up to life dynamically yeah
so now let's talk a bit about the
variables itself over the language so we
have a three scopes of variables there
is a global scope which is kind of
obvious but you have to realize that
every block action book for any probe
can fire multiple times at the same time
because you have a more than one CPU
there is no synchronization because
synchronization means matrix for locks
and we are in kernel holding interrupts
and schedulers so global variables are
problems of race conditions then we have
a self scope which means a variable is
bound to a kernel thread so whenever you
write something you can in completely
different Pro extract the variable back
because it's bound to the kernel thread
and this variable is per probe which is
interesting for you if you have a
multiple action box for the same probe
you can fill in something local for at
the first call and then use it
subsequent later to shorten down the
processing time yeah global stuff is
like a compiler so if it is statically
allocated we have a memory for it if
it's dynamically it's basically
allocated by your first store and
whenever you are set a value of dynamic
variable to zero it will get garbage
collected and freed if you run out of or
memory leak the dynamic variables you
will see something else like I don't
have a more dynamic variable drop and so
on we have a support for our eyes but I
even index by integer is always
associated because it's based on this
dynamic variable stuff
so to get quickly to the types D is a
superset of C we are not using dwarf
because debauch info is not always
installed on production machine it can
be big and dietra is historically is
based on CTF CTS are smaller because at
carnival time we duplicate the dwarf to
create a small description of CTF and we
either put them in a kernel module or or
have an archive next to the kernel which
is shipped in rpm so we have a this way
type information what is some subset
reasonable for data is always available
on production machine so if I come back
to the profile provider and just again
change the aggregation you can see I'm
using the button variable which is
current thread which has a die because
we have a type system and I can very
friends it which means now I'm basically
picking an internal member of the task
starts from Linux kernel and aggregating
by name so it is profiler that shows you
the names of threads that have been seen
on CPU yeah given the time constraint
details are so many options like I bet
we probably run out of the alphabet the
lower case and the upper case but
there's no problem we have a minus X
should I compiler you can provide the
key equals value you can change a lot of
things in interesting one is the buffer
switching policy by default we have two
buffers one is being recorded when it's
been extracted ring policy basically
overrides the buffer again again again
and for example you can extract it from
crazy dam so you can let the machine die
load it up and look what was the few
things before the disaster but only
looks it would need to change the crash
or other tools so it's not not on linux
lazy attache is basically the problem
with astrays conditions like in a probe
doesn't exist you get an error if you do
the lazy attach option it means we will
compile the script and run it anyway and
run the probe appears in the system we
enable it and start processing your
stuff
yeah so speculative tracing sometimes
sometimes you need to record for example
function arguments and decide to keep
the results only when it returns Error
error which which is quite hard for a
tracer to solve it so in DTrace the
speculation tracing allows you to speck
water based or something si to different
set of buffers and later decide whether
you commit or discard the value
depending on for example the return
value can commit if it is an error then
we will copy your temporary buffers to
do mine one and it will appear to the
trace in userspace
yes so given them quickly work on D
trace is not only above the tracer
because they are well known statically
defined probes across many operating
systems so for example you can see this
is a probe which is a lock stock
provider for linux kernel for every
adaptive mutex acquire so what it does
this one liner it collects all stacks
counts them so this is the stack which
was the hottest who was successfully
acquired new tags during the time I was
running this one-liner the best thing is
it works on Mac OS and Soares too
because we add the SCT providers in the
same way so that's the point that's
another part of our work is to create it
is to create it to really up Linux to
the other family of operating systems
here is another equivalent but this time
we are using TCP providers so for every
receive TCP receive event internals
we aggregate now you can see there is a
pipe argument I don't have the details
here but it allows you to get a source
IP address and you can see we use a
different aggregating function now it is
quantized which basically creates an
exponentially
of power of two sized buckets
and uses its argument and increments
count in each bucket it fits so you can
see I was at the time just anti-parallel
ssh to my machine so this was some
slight traffic and you can see I have a
1/1 pocket between one kilobyte and two
kilobytes but most of them were like 32
to 64 so you don't have an exact size
but you see some histogram or
or how or distribution of the values
it's very useful for various i/o stuff
and also this is printed for each
address in the aggregation so if I would
have a multiple power connection you
would see different source IPS with the
different histogram inside it so now a
different example typically from from
the support case like someone wakes you
up and just say hey something's going on
with my machine tell me what it is good
you don't know the Machine you don't
think about the environment so what
details is very good at is to narrowing
your viewing field so you know where to
focus so again still I'm using one line
as I haven't brought any single complex
script well yeah this is a bit risky but
basically this script instruments every
kernel function entry point and I use
the built-in variable as I said the
probe is at Apple so we have a built-in
variable which can you access which
allows you access to the part of the top
of the probe definition which is quite
effective because each time the probe
wires you know what is their name and we
aggregated by the module where the probe
presides so I just run it for a while
terminate and boom surprisingly VM Linux
is yeah well biggest candidate you can't
see but it's like seven hundred thousand
times been hit something from VM UNIX so
the next step is okay so what the kernel
is doing and we just restrict the FBT
probes to the kernel itself and start
aggregating by the G function yeah you
can use wildcards so you can use
something like VM Linux
Oster days or if you leave it empty
details so much everything it's just a
wild card so it this matches every entry
symbol from the kernel itself and we
aggregate by ad function which is
exactly the missing point in the probe
description so what you get you find out
that this is the hottest function caught
in the kernel
yeah well this is this is something I
have changed recently because I moved
from interrupt handling to look for
algorithm and resolve this this will be
always the hottest because we look we
are looking in the kernel itself the
machine was idle so let's take a look
for the stinking part because someone
was calling stinkums are like 12,000
times so your next question is usually
why why are we calling sinkhole parts so
often so as you can see we again
narrowing down
FBT description and start aggregating
based on stacks so this is just the
hottest stack which was auto top with
the highest number and you can see we
are doing some security context to sit
compulsion which is probably based on
sync compare but most importantly if you
go bottom to the stack it calls from
open Cisco so it is a result of a user
space activity so at this point you need
to know who the hell in the user space
is doing so much this cost so I switch
your provider use the open probe open
Cisco probe and aggregate based on
process ID and exact name Wow
it's the trace and it is done hundred
twenty eight times interesting so what
next
keep the Cisco but we're a stick it to
the D trace itself and aggregate based
on the first argument of the open Cisco
because the argument lives in user space
we need to use copper in string to get
it to the kernels so details can work on
it so this is one way you can do all
because we have narrowed the field down
you can pick your tool because probably
maybe you know better than I have got to
how to debug the stuff and you will see
most of the time it was opening
something like this because in the DTH
a call which does be online and checks
for how many available CPUs to have on a
system and that's ever implemented by
iterating over this kind of path
checking for some reason 128 CPUs on my
H CPU sized VM if there would be a user
space implemented we could follow with
the user space stacks directly from this
example details and just switch towards
the user space tracing so weekly we are
running out of time so now this could be
small complex but average Cisco at
threated us we set a separate variable t
2 1 1 we return from the open Cisco we
set it to 0 then we trace every kernel
function for every thread that has this
value set even though it doesn't have an
action so basically we have bucketed
some execution between open and and /
Cisco and if we use - F for details it
will change the printing star to show
you how you entered and return from the
probes so you can see on CPU 3 we start
with Cisco open we entered Cisco open
this is basically everything that has
been called the collide code flow in
between this is another nice feature if
you want to see some part of God for
execution in a car now
yeah the last thing is completely
different like let's say you have some
telematics this time you want to see
fancy graphs and so on so how much reads
and writes GCC and LD does during
Colonel compilation this is kind of
limitation in the language with this
hack it is not a nice stuff but you have
to add everything four times for the
retried and different process but
important thing is each one second we
create something like dtrace dog GCC dog
bride and use the amount of rights we
have accumulated then I add a timestamp
at the end of it and just click the
aggregation so current starts from zero
so we now have one second based numbers
getting out of this and because this is
accidentally format of the graphic
database there is a carbone parser which
understands exactly this so I just run
the DTrace with my ad hoc created matrix
pass it we applied to net cut and send
it somewhere to database and from
somewhere else you will start seeing
peers when I started building the kernel
yeah and here is where the link time
happened and because kinda has like 300
megabytes and there are two in our case
three rounds of linking it's like here
but you can see I can't show you on the
computer
yeah I don't just wake on but questions
[Applause]
[Music]
because they are tied to the user space
well if there is a us DT then then the
yes but I think on Suns Java there's an
option which forces the G to generate
the s DD instrumented code I'm not so
sure about the open JDK well I I think
curve and BCC and other tools do
something about that so I but there will
be
you there's an option for the dtrace
command which will dump you this
assembly in the diff language which you
can loop the only thing you can operate
with it is DJ itself and it's always a
plane so usually we need to bridge it
from sources be quite patient well
basically we do similar things that kpop
do so if you access something invalid we
have a hoop in general production for
page fault handler there's a kernel
layer of the details and the action now
I'm working on nm eyes on x86 and
because it just ends up with random
corruption or registers and you need to
find something clever no details like
connect doesn't have a straight is there
a need for a TD tree script that can use
to do some Ewing or Mac well on Mac I
think
Regt script I think on Mac the answer is
the expo because expertise using a lot
details for the iPhone development and
most measurements of your application so
I don't think there's a library of
Spitler I just wonder if there's some
simple script that it just broke assist
[Music]
and you need this to you - Cisco
provider yeah Mabel everything
winter-like about these different sense
so you can use the printer because hand
should you see I have to write that no
one actually it's like four lines of
code probably doesn't doesn't make okay
people just write it just for either
okay I thought it would be something
simple then there used to be sonically
there was used to be something called
dtrace toolkit
it's not something
okay