have a bit of a culture I'm hoping my my
my voice keeps up but okay
well hi mark
reddit is my employer I work in the
birth tools group with Scott
I hope still with sometimes change names
and I mostly work on fragrant elf fuel
system tab well in debug stuff so when I
wrote the title going from binary to
source that's just part of what dwarf is
because if that was all there is then
you just need the debug line mapping you
take an address out that's the source
and wine but dwarf does well so much
more you want to know which functions
there are what parameters are in the
function either variables what is the
scope of the variables what are the
types of the various things so you have
that and then given those variables you
want our values the location descriptors
which I thought works pretty well but
then well you saw the Lost Ark you want
to know ranges of things so you've debug
ranges you want to know how you got in a
function so dwarf provides you unwind
information not just to know where you
came from but also
- to get back at the the coloring work
the flow use of the registers when a
function was called you can inspect the
values at the previous frame it even
provides although most most compilers
don't emitted directly macro so that if
you ever you know the source you want to
copy/paste it you can use the macro to
expand all the defines in your code okay
that's a lot of things and dwarf has a
lot of design goals probably a bit too
many because they conflict with each
other of course it's kind of interesting
that the loss talk was a lot about well
that's defined by the ABI because one of
the design goals is that its
implementation independent
so in principle for example unwinding
you can do almost without any ABI
knowledge the and the only thing you
need to know is which registered number
corresponds to its actual register on
that architecture so it's kind of
interesting to see that it's not always
done but what is really nice at least I
think so now I talked to Tom man Tom
that's the worst part that's not not
really true but various places dwarf
defines vendor extensions so to reserve
the space of constants
you'll use that then go ahead and add
some extra operators or forms and I
actually think that works out quite
nicely because a lot of new vendor
extensions that then get standardized
later on of course the problem with the
vendor intensities you have to implement
them in all the producers and all the
the consumers for them to actually work
and I think Tom's issue is that then
when they get standardized you get to
implement them all again but but I think
it works quite well this is one of the
design goals that I picked out because I
had to pick something to talk about and
when I started to list everything that
dwarf I've got from the various new
extensions it was way too many so it's
it's it's I like this this design goal
that you you tools that have to process
dwarf don't have to know about Wharf and
I think that really helped dwarf become
quickly usable because it means you can
easily compose pieces of code with dwarf
and combine them
of course this bites
some of the other design goals but I
thought there were some so clever
extensions integrated into y5 that
counter some of these limitations yeah
go look there for the whole standard and
then we we just discuss a couple of new
data representations so to compose to
are from two objects which contain dwarf
you you don't need that much so this you
have an assembler where you can
reference labels in the data section you
want a way to reference between sections
so for example you have the info tree
which describes a variable and attached
to reference where the location the
scripture is in another data section you
actually have addresses of symbols which
you don't know yet where they will be so
you you need some way for tools to do
the relocation and it would be nice if
there someone knows how to to create lab
one to eight I don't know how you
pronounce it but a a company compact
form of writing are constants because
otherwise you have to do that and it's a
pain but but that's that's it with with
just that which is basic
the generic assembler linker you you can
combine dwarf one of the nice things
about that is that you can combine
different dwarf producers if your first
c4 assembler file you get two object
files and they get combined even though
they produce they have different dwarf
producers you don't have to know
anything about the dwarf they get
combined so to do this show of course
not
you know
now it's a tool it's somewhat readable
it's I wanted to have an example where
it was a completely trivial but even
this actually produces too much to us
and sadly it also doesn't show size
reduction because on the other end it's
way too small so the overheads just
dwarfs it so all the files are almost
the same size even though I want to show
reduction inside anyway what we what we
have is a header file with a simple
struct and defines a function that takes
a pointer to search the struct and we
have two files yeah this will most
likely crash and burn so this defines
the function and you have an main that
cost function and the nice thing is that
you just create 200 files and you
combine them together and the linker
doesn't need to know about the different
dwarf what the dwarf data precisely
represents so we just looked at the
debug info for this so you have the
first compiled unit which comes from F
dot C
the flop function errors name was
resolved and the statement the statement
list is the line table to use for this
and that's at offset zero and that's in
principle all the relocation you need in
in this case the matching debug line was
placed at the start because the first
object file that you will see for the
word for the second one that the
statement list is at the next of offset
and all the link has to do is place the
debug line pieces after each other so in
the thing you see immediately
immediately here is in this in both the
first and the second compile unit we
just redefine that that that such a type
which is a bit wasteful especially given
that one of the jungles of the earth was
that doesn't shouldn't repeat itself too
much but of course this comes from we
want as simple as possible tools to
combine dwarf and object files yeah
let's go back precisely
that's the conclusion yes
so it's a simple concatenation well what
happens if you combine the option showed
up to the linkage it sits in that's a
nice question because the dwarf isn't
touched so if the dwarf in the original
object files describes the function that
you then Leeman eliminate later its
and then get it this is
yeah so and indeed one of the questions
is if this design goal is but so what if
we put all the all those types in the
their own section and what if we add
tools that had a link once section or
section group which is a good question
to ask because that's how come that
sections and link are supported so
that's a nice thing then if we would
calculate some hairs or checksum over
the type that we put in in a special
section that we could reference those
sections with the net with the has name
well that's basically what deeper types
do it was actually an extension for
dwarf tree interpreters in 12 for the
only thing you then need is a way to
reference a a type with with a signature
or here so the the problem is that it
does need a new 12 unit header so you
couldn't easily combine them and for
that reason in others they were put in a
different section
so well no first example no - yeah yes
so not so far so DC implements this with
Deva type sections we compile it again
and this time we see the same debug info
let's see if I can find flop and flop C
F F is defined as a type 2 D where okay
bears
which is no well I have to one time I
knew I made my example to be sorry now
I've run not so ok the argument F is
type 92 it's a pointer type and pointer
to oh wow that one and the nice thing is
that in the other compiled units we
should have the same when we posit yes
we when we create a variable it has the
same signature I'm sure that's the same
one
and now we have a debug type section
which at with that same signature and
there is only one of them there is yeah
there's
so that that's really nice because we
need another linker mechanism but now we
duplicate some information for free
Oh though that's my example I was trying
to show that it really saves memory and
actually they're also object files are
slightly bigger because this one
structure is too small for the header so
doesn't really help there but you most
programs includes watcher here there's
more types lots of types so it actually
really helps there the problem with it
is that it makes things more complicated
so now to tie data sections it's not
enabled by default and you see even
though I believe don't try to make it
the default sorry well one of the
problems was that everybody was kind of
lazy so most consumers have offsets into
the data section and they just keep an
offset and now they have to keep an
offset and oh it could be one of those
sections I must say I'm I'm I'm showing
the new extensions but in the par 5 what
they did was extend the die compile unit
headers so you can now combine five
units in all kinds of different units in
the same debug info section so that's
actually simpler
but they also added more complexity that
yeah so it's it's it's still very large
and it's if you look in the example you
see lots of relocations references to
other data sections and the linker
actually has to deal with all that so
what what could we
we need them really forced for Strings
it's really nice if the tools know how
to merge strings because a lot of
strings and you really want those to be
merged and of course for the other
symbols you need relocations and you use
relocations for the intersection
references and what if we could do
something about that and as always the
answer is you add a layer of indirection
of course so what we do is we put all
the addresses in their own section and
that's basically just an index and then
you can use an index into the errors and
debug address section and the same we do
with strings we add a new assets section
so you have instead of having to point
directly to a string and asking the
linker fix this up if you put the string
somewhere else you have a new oops
an indirection so you can just
I want string one
and just relocate the addresses of
things in that section and then finally
instead of for example the location the
scripture descriptions saying okay my
workshop instead of saying my location
the scripts is at that offset in the
debug log section or the range you want
to range what we do is we add a an index
at the start of the section and we at
the start of the compile unit we just
say I'm using the debug log section that
one and from there you just again use
indexes to where your real ranges or
what they start one of the nice things
is that true about if we use all those
in directions we can move most of it out
of the objects valves so we don't need a
linker to even see the most of the dwarf
data it still has to see the addresses
but even the strings can be moved away
and this is kind of interesting because
so I first show how see yeah that's
so what we do here is this is actually
the war for new extension that kind of
the same and I should have shown that it
now creates about an an alpha and a DW l
to our object for twelve objects I'll
and a drop objects all is well what you
see is in the object file you you
instead of a real compiled unit your
skeleton and well there are some
addresses there and it's there are some
section offsets it has the bay at the
base address to index into the the
address list and at F say hey another
signature and a a name and well that's
it
and for the other compile unit it's the
same well different ideas different DWR
files and this is really nice
except if you want to look at the debug
info because now the the linker doesn't
have to deal with most of the dwarfs
data so for for l few tools we Delphi I
implemented info Plus which picks the
the after the skeleton it shows it's too
technical
I thought I'd
that's in should actually show from
which how it cut now it doesn't and you
you see in the dwrl it it it it uses
indirect string references and let's see
what okay well in that can hmm
this wasn't supposed to happen this
address comes from from matching up with
the the the skeleton seeing where the
divot errors is and then using an index
into that which doesn't work why not
it does it every time too bad sorry at
least it's consistent yeah so and it is
also a small difference with one five
year it it still says it use the section
of that it doesn't really it should use
a different form in into r5 but the idea
is it uses the section offset from this
dwl file ten minutes okay
oh man that's yet so the same for for
the other skeleton and you look up
almost most of the the info in the DW of
there so this is really nice for your
that compile debug cycle because your
linker the compiler has to put the debug
info site for most of it but the linker
doesn't need to to see it that need to
copy it we do have lots of duplications
again even for the strings now but those
were already original into the other
files so 12 consumers need to be a bit
smarter they have to do some of the
deduplication that the linker would do
it's awful for this solution because
some programs are links of thousands of
our files and you really don't want to
ship thousands of DWR of us I am also
not sure people have used this in anger
yet really with thousands of the wfl's
because for few tools I try to be smart
and it's all very lazy so we just open
the dwrl file so now you read them when
we need to and after a couple thousand
you don't get more fun descriptors oh
that's not nice I assume gdb does
something smarter so because that is the
kind of concern if you're not in your
edit debug cycle being yuto's comes with
the dwarf tickets Wow picture that
twelve big picture I don't know
[Applause]
and it kind of does what you expect to
do it it reads the dwarfs data it sees
all the references to the dwl files and
adds them together it acts as a kind of
mini linker because strange actions make
up so much that you really do want to
merge although all the strings but it's
nice because you only have to update the
offset table and because you concatenate
the data sections luckily you only have
that one relocation against it
what it does is it it creates a index
section therefore every DWO it says for
the info part and ever Parton well all
the debug sections where it starts and
ends and in principle that's all you
need because you have all those indexes
that you now know start at zero or dead
offset in the concatenated twelve stuff
[Music]
so
of course the next kind of logical step
is we're getting to a point where the
tools aren't simple anymore so why not
write a tool that understands dwarf and
does a lot more and that's basically
what DW said does it the nice thing
about if you know about dwarf and you
don't mind
one extra extension which is actually
also into r5 now is that you can
deduplicate between the work files you
need new forms again to to follow string
pointers or references but now you can
say oh yeah for all those debug files
just look there
I've made one large string section or
info section pipes so five minutes I
wanted to go in more detail but the
number of references between the various
dwarf data sections is kind of daunting
especially if you then combine it with
split worth and I thought it was kind of
funny about these come from the the
dwarf spec that they didn't even try to
have split dwarf plus supplemental files
because
I thought I don't think anybody does
that yet but it is all specified as you
should be able to have split types a
split wire and supplemental files
together all right yeah so I just showed
that there are still blacks but I
implemented most of this at least the
new extensions with an eye on how they
are also done done slightly differently
in into r5 so if you are writing a 12
consumer right maybe you want to try out
lip TW and write documentation for it
it's really nice library and every time
I say could you do you want to use it
people say okay where's the
documentation ya know but it's it's a
nice library I'm kind of proud that we
keep a B ABI compatibility even while we
support newer versions of dwarf of
course the value is kind of you often
need to use new functions to really get
at some stuff for example with the split
dwarf everything works except that both
programs not using the newer functions
only see the skeletons it's it's nice
yes did I do it okay yeah yes does need
to and it's actually another extension
but that's an extension to elf the L
file format where the compiler
compresses all the the dwarf Dayton and
the linker expense concatenates and
compresses it again there are people
will say that's useful you can also do
that yes and you you can also use a few
tails a few tails compress which
actually does that for you look
it's nothing stops our elf confess sorry
I don't even know my own tools sorry
yeah stupid small screen so by default
it compresses all the data sections
that's what you want for the debug
circle I would recommend splittorf but
gdb supported and articles now support
it and certainly tools using their
photos libraries need to be updated to
support it but it's really easy super
easy API so gdb I would but I'm not
completely sure people have used it in
anger and there are some questions okay
in instead of the linker spending a lot
of time you know FTD be opening a
thousand files but
out of time okay
[Applause]