so if I ok so hello everybody I'm Quan
start with a scheme I can represent as
neatly two presentations later and today
I'm going to present you a perfect that
we call easyJet which is a library that
tries to bring just-in-time combination
for sea bass bass curves so as I said
it's a actually it's a compiler that
sister library so it's not only a
library parent and consideration so it's
not a critical machine a magical vector
machine but optimizes your code and
looks at it on monitor set and that's a
lot of tricks and it's also not the
building blocks for a just-in-time
compiler like the LLVM or like the new
GT is so to figure out more or less what
it is I'm going to show you a quick
example
so here trust me this is a convolution
kernel we are playing a convolution
kernel over the video stream and for
example if you look at the mask the mask
size on the mask area that may be
changed by the user at any time during
execution let's a cup okay they may say
limpid same and they bit same I'm going
to come the dimensions of the image and
the number of channels of the image this
may change depending on their on the
video input it's not the same for I work
on that maybe for HD video or something
else we can make some assertions appear
but we don't know the exact value at
compile time that this battles will take
so it could be profitable to generate a
specialized version for the kernel
function for the values that are taking
actually at one time for all these
variables how do we do this we use the
easy shin-bi ready and how do we do that
we choose the code like that so we have
only one color on one function call in
the entire library
I don't know clear if you are familiar
with STD Wynd
anybody have ever heard of it so it's a
standard C++ construct it's really all I
think and it allows you to get a
function object and by binding the
parameters of the function that is
passive parameter
to respect the same semantics as st vine
because it's practical to to not come to
learn a new interface so here what this
function call is doing is specializing
it's simulating advantium a new version
of the kernel function it's going to
pass masks
maxsize and mask area are the first
single and third parameters of the new
function of the code to kernel is going
to put the actual constant the actual
value of these variables in the new
version so for example on some
optimizations like confirm propagation
the controlling can do some extra work
now now that they have this new
information available we are going to
take the first and the second parameter
of the litigated function and we're
going to forward it to Colonel us the
image seen as the input sign on that
thing and then we are going to also fix
the image dimensions and the number of
channels to the values taken here and
this is going to give us a function
object that we can call us any function
object like we do here and it's going to
complete the same function as it's going
to compute the same as the code that we
seen before
let's cool all this is that wherever
doing able to in C++ so everything is a
C++ object we can do everything that we
do with our typical C++ object so we can
store it on a vector move it around
study common or stow it on an STD map
for example to create a code cache and
we actually provide so we have a second
thing that we played with the level that
it's a simple code cache that allows us
to not you have to recompile the entire
code if you are ready compile it before
so the syntax it's the same as before
and the only thing that it changes that
we will return a constant reference
because the code it's owned by the cache
and not by there by us how does this
work
okay I said it was a container I see a
sister library it's because it actually
needs some container health so we have
one led I'm plugging that it's loaded
that is going to cut the cost or live a
nice way to embed the bit code
associated to a coach to alert to a
railway