hello I'm family da da da and this is
Rafa Lamia we are both software
engineers at a decor and today we will
talk about labayda long so yeah we have
lit very little time to explain to you
so we'll let's go so first of all what
is debate along exactly well in just
three bullet points labelled along is
the library and we wanted to allow
people to get insight about beta source
code and also to modify it
for this we want to offer both high and
low level API so by llola very mean some
small details like okay what is the
location of this token what is the token
under this location things like this and
also we're highly valley PI such as ok
what's the type of this expression or
can you please rename this type and all
use occurrences of this type libanon we
also want it to be very versatile so we
want it to be usable from any language
technology so for this so the Batarang
is an Ida library it also offers a C API
and on top of the C API well can talk to
it basically every everything so we ship
with Abed along a Python wrapper so that
you can use whole the whole Nebadon on
library from Python so this offers an
interesting feature which is you can
basically you have a really short path
between having an idea and watching your
tool because you can do a quick
prototype in Python and this is great so
yeah one important point so liberty'
long is an ADA library we are going to
present you some examples that will be
written in Python because it fits in
slides but everything you will see in
Python can be done in later of course
let's go so let's have a well first of
all
let's see why why we need Lebanon in the
first place so this is a screenshot from
GPS the worldwide known editor of either
GPS needs to know where the block starts
and ends so here you can see that in it
knows it seems that in a type
declaration that starts here and ends
here you get you get to do some passing
to understand that so Lebanon will
provide that it also will provide well
in in intelligent cut editors sometimes
you want to click on an identifier and
you expect the editor to lead you to the
definition corresponding to this end of
identifier so this is often called name
resolution or cross references we want
to offer that to make it easy for idea
is to rename a function find stance or
do transformations like this and also so
here you have a subprogram and we want
to make it easy to to write for people
and for like everyone to write custom
tools that will for instance at as
interest so detect variables that are
fully cased this doesn't match but
doesn't matter
so here are variables names if you have
a rule like this variable names should
start with and should be capitalized
well you can easily write a checker to
do that we want that to make it we want
that to be easy with later
at this point you may if you know enough
the ADA ecosystem you might ask okay
what not use it using ASIS it does
precisely that well in Lebanon we have
because we want to serve as the building
block for tooling including editors
there are some several mismatches the
first one is we want to be incremental
which is you open your project okay you
you flip it down and that is the project
and you perform a very minor
modification you don't want the GPS for
instance to freeze for seconds or
minutes because it computes recomputes
everything that depends on the
modification you made so when something
changes we want to do to perform in
America computation most of the time
when you're writing code your code is
incorrect because you're writing it and
we so be monthly but along to be as
helpful as well as helpful as possible
when you're when your cut is incorrect
and also something very important we
want you leave it alone to be somehow
bonded in the resources it uses so we
don't want the bedroom to crash your
program after three days of running
process because it's exhausted all
virtual memory so ASIS and in particular
nuts implementation of aces well the way
they were implemented with some
objectives in mind here we have a
different we have needs that kind of
contradict them so goodnight and Isis
are not our police treated for for what
we need so we decided to do yet another
library yes okay I just want to make one
thing clear here there is no problem
actually with the implementation of aces
sorry with the specification of aces for
those needs the problem is more with the
implementation that is based on net so
the net is a compiler and it was done to
do all its work in one pass so basically
it's not adapted to be in
serrated edges and hence this
implementation that we provide is not
that that kid either but we found other
problems with edges at the API level and
we wanted to take a shot at doing
something that is more user friendly
anyway so this is why we created later
on thank you for those decisions okay so
what
as of today what does using Li better
long look like well first let's start
with the basic level of languages tokens
you can only buy the wrong as to pass it
a file to put to basket to pass a file
and then to ask for the list of tokens
that came from this side so here we have
a native program a really simple one and
this is a simple usage of the API so in
Python you create a context to to host
your computations you ask it to load a
source file and then so you take your
analysis unit and you take the root node
of it and you ask for the list of tokens
corresponding to this footnote and you
print them all of them so this is the
results so well asking for the token
stream is quite easy next let's go to
the syntactic level so this is a more
complex ADA program well you can ask
here too so you take the root node of
your analyzation it and here you ask
okay find all nodes that comply to this
predicate so this is a type so find all
nodes that are objective declarations
print this look well Seuss location
arranges and there are text and so this
is the results so against something
useful so yeah performing this kind of
curry is useful for instance for linters
and next level and this is getting more
and more interesting so this is yet
another other program where we defined
two double functions that are overloads
so they called the net the same they
only differ by their signature so one of
them takes an integer returns an integer
the second one takes a float and returns
a float and there is a call to one of
these double functions so in the
better-known okay we are so I didn't
repeat it there there but we have asked
to pass this analysis unit then here we
call return to get the double call so we
find all call expressions that who's
who's called function is named double
and okay so here we have so this call is
present here and then all we have to do
in the bedroom to get what double
function is called is to get the name so
the call is actually gets also the
arguments and if you get the name you
only have this and you asked for the
reference declaration and you print it
and the bed along select as we are
calling double with an integer the first
of a load is chosen and so the battering
finds which is the one that is called
this is good
okay yes sorry
previous yes the second night of office
there's only one line syntactically no
this is in the ADA grammar there is this
is a single object declaration that
declares two objects so that's an
interesting point in the grammar syntax
Ikki you have one object declaration
node but indeed semantically you have
two so since the beta Long's
prime goal is to make analyzers and to
that act on syntax we want to keep as
close as possible to the syntactic
representation which is why you only
have one node we don't modify the tree
after parsing or stuff like that which
is another thing that is difficult with
Bennett and Isis because they are
compilers I want to omit code so they
might get rid of that representation
very early on and then you don't have
access to it anymore
so for the moment reference declaration
we just give you the whole reference
declaration so what we plan to do is to
have an API that will also give you the
precise identifiers that you are looking
for but that is not done yet but it's
not too difficult to do know okay now so
this is being worked as we speak almost
so we want also to provide a feature
that enables users to actually modify
the source code so here we have on the
top of the side an ADA program and then
here this is the use of the API we
intend to to facilitate whistle battlin
so yeah so first of all you are so
imagine we want to turn this into this
so all we have to do is to take the call
put to put line and to modify the input
argument so first of all we find the
node transporting to the call then we
start rewriting session because while
we're rewriting things we want to keep
the old thing available for perform to
help you doing the refactoring and then
so what you do here is to take to take a
kind of rewriting handle to the to the
parameter here and then what you do here
is to say okay let's rewrite this
parameter and we write it using a string
literal this one then you apply so that
replaces the old and the old source code
with the new one and then you're
supposed to get this so we want to
provide that and work in progress
yes sorry edits and part of bootstrap a
built at work and we have problems with
other okay because other is implemented
in other and you have and I wanted to
ask is it possible to use this to
transpiling to see little bit of topic
but yeah let's discuss that after so
this actually this this example is
incorrect because final returns you a
list so here we would supposed to be to
extract which which found element would
be we would have to work on so in this
example if there were multiple calls to
put line we would have several several
results and we will have to pick which
one we would we would want to rewrite so
if I if I can be a bit more precise the
way you are finding the node is not by
searching for the text but you have the
option to search for precise context for
example you can say I want the first
call or I want the call to this function
even if you have another function but
the same string literal so you have a
lot of granularity because you are doing
a query on the tree and not on the text
itself so here we say we want the first
cut expression but you could say
something else and get the note that you
want to rewrite very precisely okay I'm
afraid we'll get out of time okay so
this is an example so if you remember I
in the previous slides I talked about a
linter that will check your variable
names identifier this is one possible
implementation of it so it's the whole
script
we just iterate through its given high
name we pass it and then we check for
passing arrows and if everything is okay
you just look for all object
declarations and all identifiers inside
object equations because they can be
multiple anyway and we check the
identifiers and if it's not capitalized
we want about it so it's really simple
we want it to be really simple to write
this kind of tool and now I will let
Rafael talk about more usage example of
the library
okay I guess it's good so camera showed
you a bit of how it's supposed to work
and how you use it
I'm going to show you what we did with
it so far and what we will be able to do
with it in the in the future so I didn't
get that I will I was going to start
with the demo so a little demo to start
with so yeah I'm going to find it don't
worry so so far we showed only Python
code so you might be like okay so a
decor guys that do only Python so the
example I'm going to show is done in
Aida okay so we don't do any Python we
also do it so what it is is a syntax
highlighter slash code browser so it's
basically a very small subset of the
functionalities that you want in an IDE
okay so you just
it's a common lie tools that you launch
on your project here it's a signature
project and it generates a hierarchy of
HTML pages and then if you click on one
of the links
all right so smoke then you get
highlighted code okay so basically this
is done with the debate around API we
highlight tokens in certain fashion but
we have the three so we can do a bit
more syntactic highlighting so for
example you can see that types are
highlighted correctly etc etc and then
you have links to the cross-reference
these two right here and if you click on
it it will bring you even if you twisted
the size which is the back but it will
bring you to the correct source and to
the correct line with the line
highlighted so this is very simple
but it can still be practical if you
want to browse your sources offline and
it is shipped with you later on today so
you can already try it if you want it's
in the country the directory of debate
on my demo went well I'm so happy so
another thing we did pass and again is a
very small syntactic based analyzers so
this was a fun project done by Yannick
who is not here now but did a
presentation on spark so it was like we
do it this really complicated static
analysis based on spark and cut here but
let's do something really simple and
this checker is doing something very fun
it's looking for binary operators and
looking for cases where the left side
and the right side are the same and in
most of the time it's an error okay and
this is the way you express it in with
debate around so we look for every
binary operator and if it's in the list
of interesting of the right house so we
have multiplication addition the
concatenation of the writer etc etcetera
then we check if syntactically the left
side and the right side have the same
tokens and if they do we print a warning
so what is really fun is the number of
problems we found with that in our code
bases so basically you would assume
since we ran static analyzers and we
have big test suite and everything
no this cannot happen it's ADA right
it's a very safe language and everything
but when we had a lot of bug in in our
codes linked to that so it's really
interesting it's also an example of the
power you have at your fingertips where
you have access to the syntactic part of
the code so you are not into the text
anymore you can browse the tree and find
interesting stuff what we are working on
right now based on e-bay the room too is
a static analyzer are based on semantics
so it's not a full interprocedural
analyzer like for example code fear that
we have some of you might know about it
but it's less powerful less ambitious in
scope it allows to you to do
interprocedural stuff a little bit like
sarong static analyzer so here for
example we have a simple example we
where we have a file and we open it and
I'm going to take that too and here we
get a line and we close it every time in
the loop which is abuse llanera
but when you write the code you might do
this kind of error so what we want to do
is to be able to warn you very early
when you write this kind of API code and
say Oh be careful
file might be closed at this point and
when you close it might already be
closed and so we are using a simple form
of absurd abstract interpretation to
make that and what's interesting is that
users will be able to specify their own
checks for their own API so if you have
an API that has some simple invariants
like that that you want to enforce you
can add a simple checker for it and it's
a work in progress run by one of our
interns at Attica and you can check the
progress on this repository
and we also did copy/paste detector
because we searched it was fun given the
number of bugs we found with the static
analyzer maybe we could find like maybe
a whole project duplicated at a dakar or
something like that it didn't happen but
we found some copy-paste also an example
of the API of anybody around and it's
very lightweight it's a few hundred
lines of code and it's pretty efficient
so if you want to try to run it on your
ada code base you can find it on our
blog here and in the config directory of
debate around so inside of the car we
also use debate around Forester not only
prototypes so we are gonna we are in the
process of changing the semantics engine
of GPS the main IDE to use debate around
so it's a work-in-progress it should
happen in the following year and also
the new versions of kinetic metric the
net stub and net Tiki so again alpha t
is a pretty printer it goes through your
code and pretty prints it the next step
generates step for your sub program
bodies and specs and that metric give
you some metrics about your code and all
of those tools are based on ages for the
moment and are being adapted to run on
top of the bedroom and outside of a deco
we already have some people using it
some guys are doing a instrumentation
with it for coverage
some people are doing automated
refactoring to make code smaller some
people are making sanitizers and this
allows us to JSON on top of it so this
is an example of the kind of stuff that
you can do on top of a bed around
so in conclusion if you want to check
out the data on it already or not you
can go on this URL you can try it and
open issues if you find problems so API
is still a moving target and should we
really see that as a real product but
it's very stable for some part some
other are moving so it depends on what
you do is it I guess
thank you for listening and if you have
any more questions I have one or two add
rows it's if you want to know how
Lebanon was implemented beside this we
doing a presentation that's what 1:00
1:00 p.m. tomorrow I think it's 2 p.m. 2
p.m.
anyway check out for the linkage
presentation in the source code analysis
live room yes thank you thank you very
much questions yes
so the question is does it mean that we
will give give up support for Isis so we
are not going to release new versions of
Asus so it's basically baselined
we are we will continue providing
support for the current version of Asus
for entertainment undetermined time for
the moment but don't worry we won't see
Jean Pierre hanging it's not part of our
plans yes and we don't want to do that
so obviously as as long as we have some
requests for a de se support we will
support Asus we internally there even
been some discussions like oh we could
rewrite the current Asus based on the
beta on so just to give you an
impression of the kind of discussions
that happen
we we would prefer not to do that
honestly but if we have to
ends in customer pressure
[Laughter]
oh yeah so you had to know which is
which I think there is one really big
thing that is missing in Nevada now is
the implementation of execution
semantics I mean the knowledge knowledge
is not there for for now at least
so there's still a huge work to do from
starting family but alone in order to
create basically an interpreter or
compiler on top of it it's not really
the job to translate to another language
for now so basically you have a small
part of the front-end you have the cross
references if you really need the
legality checks you can use net on top
of ebay they're on but then you still
have a lot of stuff to do if you want to
compile your code actually in it's C and
produces a full later runtime
but I think the line of because can you
parse it was that the question okay so
the question was can it pass rate that
compiler sucks good and the answer is
yes you can pass any source code that we
could find the parser doesn't fail on
anything that we could find the semantic
analyzer name resolution still fails on
some stuff but it's getting really small
and that's all we have for the moment
anyway so