all right so good morning everyone can
start right away to keep in time so this
is actually work that was done by one of
my student pagado
who did a very great job in the
implementation I really want to
advertise this because it uses a lot of
things that's been around on software
different radios for a long time but
it's heavily under use for the moment
which is the FPGA part of the radio and
so what we're actually going to do today
is make a spectrum scanner on the
software-defined radio platform so why
did we need to do this well it was
originally a demand from the belgian
regulator so every country has its
regulator which one of its mission is
make sure that no one is transmitting on
frequency bands they're not allowed to
all right and in our country that's in
Belgium that's a bi PT who is in charge
of making sure that whoever uses
spectrum has seen it paid for it
otherwise you get a fine so what did I
want to do well they want to they have a
bunch of technicians driving all around
Belgium on all kind of missions you know
going in cell antennas check antennas
whatever and they want to have something
in the back of the van of these
technicians that's gonna run
continuously and do opportunistic
spectrum scanning so whenever this guy
is driving around there is setup running
in the back of his van that's going to
detect all the signals that are around
and if any of these signals is not
supposed to be there then it's gonna
send an alert to the bi PT headquarters
so what are the constraints that these
guys imposed on us well first of all
they want to use us RPS and two-tenths
which is not the most recent model but
they have a bunch of them lying around
in their offices and they don't know
what to do with it so I want to use
these ones they want to have the host
controller to be a single board computer
something with a form factor of a
Raspberry Pi so that's actually posing
some constraints in terms of computation
power if you want to start doing a 50th
and stuff on the Raspberry Pi you're
going to get the dreaded overflow all
the time so you need to somehow offloads
saying from the host controller and they
want to have no user intervention the
guy who is driving in the van should be
solely focused on driving the van and
not on tinkering on the radio on the
site all right so when it comes to
spectrum scanning this is not exactly
new there's been a lot of code rounds
just listed a few I could see here
that's what is the main mutations with
all of these codes or at least all the
one I know of
well first one is very off on the
scanning bandwidth is limited to the
bandwidth of the USR p4n to ten that's
ten megahertz all right so we are
talking about scanning hundreds of
megahertz maybe even gigahertz the
second problem is that most of these
solutions for all of them are software
based all right and if you want to do
something that sort of real-time on
something like a raspberry pi then it's
gonna run very slowly all right you're
not gonna be able to be the fully in
software and that's why we go to the
FPGA part all right
there's been some effort on the FPGA
front especially with new radio ARF
knock well one of the problems is with
this model of us our PE RF knock is not
backwards compatible so you have to kind
of dig in the fpga code which
fortunately is available online and do
the tinkering yourself all right so talk
is gonna be structures as fellow first
general introduction about what the
system looks like from the outside a bit
of details about FPGA a bit of details
about software and then if everything
works well hopefully a demonstration
show how well it works all right so who
here is a bit familiar with FPGAs right
that's roughly half of the room so I'm
gonna go one slide version of what an
FPGA is and how it's different from my
controller right if you have a
microcontroller you remember for from
computer engineering 101 that you have
something like this you have a CPU which
can do typically about few dozens of
elementary operations all right so
whenever you write your high-level
language source code you compile it it's
going to make a long list of micro
instructions which gonna mean yeah it's
acute it one by one
by your CPU all right the crux being
that if you have codes that need to do a
lot of operation it's just going to take
a longer time to execute so nephew G is
different how well an FPGA is made of a
whole bunch of small elementary blocks
right and each of these blocks can
implement just handful of logic
functions and FPGA programming is
essentially connecting deciding how you
want to connect those blocks to be able
to do more complex operations to be able
to do more complex computations or yeah
more complex processing all right so you
basically decide which blocks are
connected to which other blocks and how
these are connected now when you write
when you want to work with the feejee
you typically write I'm gonna say high
level language which is VHDL or Verilog
these are really hardware description
languages and there are actually much
lower level and C so it's you know
really still step below C programming
and the big limitation that you have in
FPGA is the size of your FPGA if you
want to do a lot of operations you need
to have a lot of logic functions and
eventually you're going to run out of
these logic blocks it's so that's the
main limitation of your FPGA if you want
to do a lot of operation and you run out
of space you need a bigger FPGA all
right so what's what about the PGA's on
the USRP well there is an FPGA on the n2
10 it does a bunch of elementary things
that are required for receiving and
transmitting signals but if you look at
the hardware resources so this is all
the hardware resources of the FPGA you
can see that they're still quite some
space available we're using anywhere
between 20 and 80 percent of some
resources but the lis that means there
is still some space left to add your
custom blocks in between so going back
to spectrum scanning what do we want to
do on the in our system well this is
basically your us our PE you get your RF
signal you don't convert it
to the ADC and then we want to do in 15
take the square magnitude of a 50 and
then for each frequency bin see whether
it's higher or lower than a given
threshold all right if it's higher there
is a signal if it's lower there is no
signal we sent the result of the host
controller and the host controller is
then gonna check with database or just
post process it or store it for offline
processing the second task of the host
controller is also to retune the
front-end all right we want to scan our
newsmaker so you need to retune the
carrier frequency every so often alright
so going into a bit of detail so by the
way all the very low-level details
already regardless thesis which I put on
a false time webpage so if you're really
if you're interested in going to really
fine details already modifying the code
I suggest you take his thesis it's very
complete and he explained every single
wire that's that's been implemented in
the FPGA design so if you GI design is
basically composed of four blocks the
first one a 50 second one taking square
magnitude then the energy detection and
then a data sink model which I will come
back to so the key point of FPGA is is
that all these things are working in
parallel right
unlike a microcontroller which is first
going to do the FFT then do this then do
this then do this in an FPGA all these
things happen in parallel all right so
that's where you get the big speed
improvement so each input and output has
well each module has two inputs and two
outputs one for the actual data
streaming true and one that's just a
control signal that indicates the next
block whether a data is valid or not
alright so this is fairly standard in
FPGA design and we have two versions of
this energy detection block which I will
come back to a bit later so I'm not
going to go to the internals of each
block because you know it takes way too
much time and the screen resolution is
just not fine enough to show every wire
that you have in there so I'm just going
to give a few of the key elements that
we use in each block so the first one is
the FFT so that's probably most critical
one give a T block thus 2024 point 50
and that's fixed that's not something
you can chain
so if you want to change the resolution
you have in frequency you have to change
the USRP sample rate all right
the size of the GP is fixed for
practical reasons in this case the
second block is just taking square
magnitude of each frequency bin very
easy to multiplication one addition in
FPGA you can do this in hardware and it
takes three clock cycles in
microcontroller this would typically
take several dozens of clock cycles in
the best case all right so the next big
block is the energy detection modules so
basically this block implements the
following equation you're going to take
the energy of a certain amount of
frequency bins and you're going to
compare it with a threshold all right so
if you have an endpoint of 50 you're
going to look at the size M sub window
and you can change this M from the
software all right so this allows you to
consider a different type of signal
whether you're considering CDMA signals
that might have five megahertz of
bandwidth or FM signals does have much
lower bandwidth and we have two versions
of this block and you know two different
FPGA images one where you have a fixed
threshold where you just set this lambda
manually and one where you have a
semi-automated threshold which takes
into account the overall energy in the
band so I'm not going into the details
of this equation but the key point is
that it makes it much more robust to
noise spikes all right if you have big
noise spike it's not going to be
detected as a signal all right
and the last block that we have in the
FPGAs data synchronizer module so the
key idea is that in these three blocks
we mess up the signals and the timing of
its sales bit and this block is
basically going to readapt
the signals and especially in time
inverse signals to what we had at the
input and the big advantage of this is
that we don't need to rewrite all the
drivers of the USRP all right we're
mostly electronic engineers in my lab
we're not that much software wizards so
we don't want to mess too much with with
the drivers right and this block allows
us to just leave everything standards
the only constraints that we have
because of that is that the ratio
between the USRP sample rates and the
clock rate of the FPGA which is fixed to
100 megahertz should be integer value
all right you can you can set 1 2 5 10
measures we can not set three point two
megahertz for example all right so let's
take a bit at let's look a bit at
resource usage so this was the default
FPGA image you could see what we had in
terms of hardware resources and you can
see that the two versions of our image
just add a handful of percents to each
of these resources so we still have
we've been quite quite economical on the
resource usage we can still add a bunch
of things so typically in real spectrum
scanner you also have I have filters
that you put at the front so we still
have some space to add those blocks in
here alright so moving on to the
software some the software is actually
very very simple right it's very
lightweight because it needs to run on a
single board computer and it does very
little things but it needs to do those
things very well so I'm just going to
give a few a few examples of low-level
commands that we have used that are
maybe not not so well known in the
community so the first one is how to set
an FPGA registers from the software side
so there is actually commands in the UHD
drivers allow you to do that very simple
very easy to use the second command
we're going to use quite a lot is
setting the command time so you can
specify at which time in the future a
certain command should take place for
example if you want to set carrier
frequency you want to change it exactly
one millisecond from now you can use
this set command time to do that all
right so this allows you to change the
carrier frequency in a very very regular
intervals alright so this is basically
what the software does alright as you
can see it's very simple
you're infinite loop it here you're
basically going to receive sample reset
the carrier frequency if you're sweeping
over a wider bandwidth and I receive
sample again and so on the only
smart thing that we do here exactly
sending a bunch of commands in advance
of the USRP so if for some reason your
host lags a bit the USRP knows what to
do for the next immediate few
milliseconds alright so that allows your
host to catch up a bit and when we're
running it with a standard laptop so
this is you know four four gig of ram
stuff like that so nothing too fancy
we're able to scan 1 gigahertz in 250
milliseconds without running into any
overflow problems right and this is
continuously so we can leave it on for
half an hour and no problems on that
front alright so I'm running a bits
heads that's good so we also have small
GUI it's just for field testing you want
to first verify that all your settings
are done well that your antenna is
connected properly things like that so
there is a very lightweight UI it looks
like this we're gonna see it later in
the demo you have your frequency
spectrum and then here you have a
detection result a zero there is no
signal 1 if your signal and both of
these both of these results are written
to identify so currently it data file is
overwritten at every sweep this depends
a bit on what you need to do exactly all
right
you can have you can store data for a
bit longer but of course eventually your
data files are going to grow quite
rapidly so you want to manage that a
little bit all right
so just some few results from the lab
before I do the actual demo so this is
when we generate signal with a signal
generator this is roughly over a 100
megahertz band we have a Bluetooth
signal here and then a multi-carrier
signal with 20 carriers and you can see
it's all of these signals or I take it
appropriately if you if you would zoom
in here you would see that the bandwidth
of your muted signal is roughly
compatible with demand which we set at
the transmitter side so this is with a
cable between the USR penis signal
generator you're not allowed to transmit
whatever you want especially at these
frequencies this is just detecting FM
radio stations so well you can see that
you detect a bunch of stuff between this
or 20 megahertz band and I gather was
very patient and able to match
detection result with one of the actual
FEM broadcast stations that we have
around here Brussels and match them to
the different transmit towers so we are
here to university and a bunch of
transmitters all around Brussels we were
able to detect well all of them up to we
could see up to 12 kilometer kilometers
of range so before I move to the actual
demo all the code that we did is
available on github
so what do you have in the guitar folder
you have the FPGA source codes so
unfortunately to turn it to something
that you can put in the USRP you will
need silence right so this is
proprietary software it's not cheap but
if you work in a university most of the
time people have it and you can use it
so we also have the FPGA images which
can flash straight on the FPGA right on
the USRP and of course all the hosts C++
code and teammates and some junk we used
while making the software alright so
let's move on to the demo alright so
this is basically the command that you
need to execute to call for - - to start
the function so you can see some
classical stuff like USRP sample rate
the carrier frequency the gain and then
you have a bunch of more precise
parameters so threshold is the level of
your threshold window size is the size
of the Sun window that you're
accumulating energy over and this end
parameter is just a number of 10
megahertz windows that you want to
accumulate over so in this case we're
going to look at two times 10 megahertz
or 20 megahertz bandwidth alright so
so we first gonna start by looking a bit
at what we have energy gsm bands which
was pre-loaded the commands so these are
basically the different GSM signals that
you see and the different signals that
are detected so you can see a few things
here so you can see some of these are
always present these are G's and
broadcast channels alright so those are
signals that are always present that's
your cell phone used to lock themselves
onto and some of these signals pop in
and out so GSM is TDMA time-based so
signals are there for a short span of
time and then disappear alright so here
the refresh rate is very low because we
don't want to overload the processor
it's 1 Hertz but the system is actually
running you know it's get doing full
scanning 5 milliseconds behind here
alright so well GSM is bit 90s let's try
something a bit more recent so this is
looking at 3G signals so I'll set the
center frequencies to one of the one of
the 15 megahertz of bandwidth that's
allocated to one of the operators I
think it's base in this case and you can
see they have 15 megahertz to use for 3G
signals and well it's not always so
clear but what they did is they
basically split their fifteen megahertz
into three bands of five megahertz right
so you can more or less CDs represented
here where you have chunks of five
megahertz being detected
yeah so sometimes the full signal is not
visible so yeah that's basically the IE
alright so that's about it for my talk
so I will be happy to answer any
question I just would like to also
shamelessly take the opportunity to say
that we are hiring some people to work
on this kind of stuff so if you guys
know someone who would be interested
well please get in touch with me thank
you
[Applause]
yes so the the question of the remark is
whether we could do the carrier sweep by
using hardware solutions instead of
doing software so is one possibility now
the main idea of this is to have
something very quite low weight that we
can put in the back of the van so you
know extensive hardware every piece of
hardware you add in my experience is a
potential cause of problems that you add
into the loop all right and it would be
a solution to even speed up more the
scanning that we currently have so that
would work indeed I don't think it would
make the overall system much simpler and
actually most of the issues that we have
or more more in terms of SNR in terms of
scanning speeds so that's a bit of the
limiting factor here so the 15 is a
fixed point multiplication that's
something that we want to improve on in
the future so you lose quite a lot of
resolution in in the lower bits and your
feet unless you there is a purchase
we can yeah yeah
in terms of signal-to-noise are you ever
itching over each frequency channel
before you going to no we don't do so oh
yeah sorry are we doing any averaging
before we do any processing behind so
currently not know so that's something
that we also want to add in here so we
still have a lot of space left whether
it's on the FPGA we can also do it on
the software but I think the first
priority is increasing the resolution of
the 50 and then going to add additional
functions such as averaging or max hold
or anything that you can do that would
kind of make the whole system more
robust yes this is generated with a
signal generator so we set the carrier
frequency yourself yeah it's it's random
it's run yep so the question is whether
we tested this on frequency helping
transmitters so currently not now so we
always track signals or static frequency
hopping is certainly something that
would be interesting it roughly depends
on how long it takes to scan so that's
one of the reason that we want free this
reasonably fast scan times sorry well
not the one we generate with signal
generator
[Applause]