hello everyone and welcome to my
presentation faces the challenges of
updating complex systems with a subtitle
putting it all together
well should about me my name is Andrew
yawns I'm and that a software engineer
working at penguin onyx
we're basically an embedded Linux
consultant company and I am the co
maintainer of the rock up dating
framework so on from the tropical bit
close to updating this is what the talk
today will be about so a bit on the
background on the motivation so in the
past years we've seen green zoo of
embedded update tools like SW update
mender or rock rice and so you could
think that updating and that it's system
is well ass off topic but if you take a
closer look at your system well there
are many different aspects many
different components in your system
they'd not only or live together
separately but they are connected
together if you're in the system that
has to start your application you have
maybe watch watch talk you have to care
for your daughter during updating handle
in the bootloader then your the
deployment server where your update
comes from and in the end you also want
to test this entire change on there are
a lot of building blocks that and that
cannot be covered by such an update
framework and that are very custom to
your hardware to your use case and to
what your application needs and well
when we do with updates the bootloader
is a very critical point case and most
systems the Buddhist a single point of
failure and now when you want to start
with you boudoir grab for something like
this and
implementing your redundant system often
means that you have to write a script
for the bootloader that takes some
variables and do the selection of the
proper blood targets so this is exactly
what we just remove in the user space
with the update framework so why don't
we use frameworks in the bootloader too
and here's one example of an already
existing framework from the Box
bootloader it's called the boot choose
of framework well gives it a short
overview about the structural wheel so
it has a basic algorithm that does the
actual boot selection some configuration
to adapt it to your systems needs and a
persistent status which stores
information about the current status of
Sibiu Chagas and if we take a deeper
look at it the basic simplified
algorithm looks like this we have for
each boot target two variables that we
maintain a priority and a remaining 1/10
counter and if we start our system we
power it on and then first of all check
if they were remaining 1/10 counter for
the individual boot target is larger
than zero if then then we choose the
boot target with the highest priority to
preset remaining attempts counter and
then boot and if the booting fails
either because we can't load see the
kernel image are because we hit a
watchdog we said during starting then it
ends again in this bootloader and does
it again and again and doing this their
tenth counter decreases and if the
attempt counter for one of these boot
choice reaches zero then we switch to
the other one and the normal case would
be with decrease the attempts counter
then moved to our running system and if
we assure that we've put a successful
ease and we reset their remaining
attempts counter to its default value so
this is basically what the framework
provides with some country
raishin like for example if you power on
the system we want the year remaining
attempts counter for all tides to be
reset to the default values so that we
can recover our targets by switching the
power of Iran well another example where
we don't have to implement the switching
itself is on x86 so any on x86 you have
unity in normally and there you can or
have the boot entries for each target
you want to boot and with it boot and
this it is possible to load the kernel
fully without an additional bootloader
just by referencing the kernel we want
to boot and giving a root of s argument
that references is a root filesystem to
boot and then we are able by setting Z
or if you boot order variable to
atomically switch the order of the
targets to boot and also we have the
boot next counter which is some sort of
temporary setting into a boot target for
trying to boot and if it's fails boots
and it's not persisted and the next
times of target reboot we have the
original order back so there's no inner
drama fest required no bootloader just
Colonel Andrew the first boot so this is
an other option for that well when
updating is a bootloader it's often is a
single point of failure you don't have
redundant one but depending on the
hardware that your users there are some
exception one example I have fear is if
you use an emmc this one has a dedicated
or two dedicated to boot petitions so
root zero and third one and we take this
example we put it with our boot loader
from boot one starter system and if we
now want to update the bootloader we
simply write it to the boot zero
position not having switched anything in
the X CSD which is responsible for
the one code which boot petitioned to
load and then at the very end step when
we're sure we've updated the the
bootloader successfully then we do the
atomic switch and have a running updated
bootloader in an atomic way
so another become an issue when starting
your updated systems something goes
wrong and the system Hanks maybe in the
kernel or during execution of her
application so a common way to solve
site is using watchdogs of course and a
watchdog is normally triggered during
booting so we start doing booting and
then the camel and the init system they
have to trigger the watchdog in regular
intervals so that it's counter does not
remain zero it does not count down to
zero if that happens in this case shown
there when the system Hanks then the
watchdog counter expires and the
watchdog puts the reset of the bark and
reboots support so that we don't end up
in an in an undulating system well as
for the basic system also our
applications might hang and we want to
be able to detect it and want to be able
to recover from that and a nice too for
this is system day watchdog system the
init system that provides the watchdog
multiplexer interface so system D itself
triggers the hardware watchdog so that
you can be sure that system D is running
and also for rebooting do device it says
watchdog so that if you get stuck during
reboot and then it provides the software
watchdog for the individual applications
that you run and for each application
you can configure a proper interval and
then your application has to notify a
system D in that interval
do not get reset
and if it's not notified then you can
select ancestry what you want to do with
it what do you want to restart it or
skip are also reboot the entire system
depends on how critical the application
that just crash this and in general
system D are using an embedded system
that you want to update in a robust play
is a good idea because it's a very
central point and it has a very central
view of the entire system and all the
components running on the system and it
provides fine-grained control about
behavior when an application or a
service failures so if you want to
restart it when you want to restart it
with which intervals between multiple
tries and when you want to abort trying
to restart a service and we boot the
entire system and so on as you watched
up multiplex I already described and for
example the system update method that is
a way for bootstrapping the boot serving
configuration data on the initial boot
of a system by just placing a system
update file in the root filesystem then
system D boots into a special target
perform some actions and then reboots
and so you can boot strip or initial
data on your system for example well
what you also have to care about when
thinking about developing your system is
how you store and where you store your
data and how and where you migrate your
data so a simple example is that you
store your data in the root file system
if you have a rewritable file system and
then your update you has to care for it
to first write the image to the
secondary root partition and after that
copy all the data that you need on the
second petition to it from the currently
running one so it's good if you fall
back you or still have
data that is accessible by the system
but it may be outdated well of course
and another purchase that you have a
single data petition as I just mount it
in the root file system there no copying
is required because of both the current
and the updated system will use the same
data migration is also possible but if
you fall back and migrated data before
that might be tricky because the old
application might not be able to read
the data you just just migrate it with
the new application so there's a third
approach if you have redundant for
systems to also use with other data file
systems and again the copying of the
data can be done by the bootloader the
migration should be done by the
application because this has the best
view of what data it requires mounting
is a bit more tricky because you have to
find out is a system which of the data
petition belong to your actual root
filesystem and not mix it up and you
have falling back or is again more
simple but again depending on your use
case you always you also access all data
so you have to make clear if this is a
valid use case for your application to
access all data or if you want to not
allow for backs in general also a topic
is I'm frequently asked about how
updating performance with verified or
trusted boot just a short note about it
is because in many cases this is
orthogonal to the updating taking them
Verity here as an example is there in
this case you create your root
filesystem image and the hash trees in
our cohash tree for zero fascist money
build system and for the update system
itself it's just like writing data to
your block device so it's transparent
first if you're using them integrity
then you
got the handling in your community in
your running system covered and then you
can use for example a child extraction
to update your system then also the
running system will handle all the
mapping itself because it's like simple
extracting at our to next four file
system and the dam integrity layer below
handles journaling and the tax creation
and so on well as I already said it is
important for an update that you test at
your update for robust updating and it's
not like only testing software
it's like testing the entire updating
change so from the from the or start of
the system to the updating cycle to the
reboot to the newly running system and
this is quite tricky because you have to
interact with the hardware and a good
framework for this that provides this
functionality is Leopard
it's based on Titus and you can it has
an abstraction and way of interacting
with shells over serial line so shall
drive that knows how to deal with linux
shell battles drivers that knows how to
communicate with pair box how to type
something as a gel shell get variable
names and so on and power drives that
allows you to power the system and then
a simple test case for your device could
be you provide chess it provides a
target sheet is updated to to install it
power cycle it and then testing the
bootloader okay did it select the other
root filesystem petition and test in the
Linux okay or am i running the right
root filesystem the new application is
every service up and running and so on
well normally when we want to perform
updates over the network so remote
updates we have two major issues that we
come across is that your update too
large we have have devices that only
have constraint connection and so an
update takes very long and raises a lot
of data and we also require a temporary
storage for the update image we download
where we can download it to the target
and temporary start before actually
installing it and so what you want to
come across it is Delta updates and you
know in this is an example taking from
the route update framework and we wanted
to have Delta updates network
functionality and we didn't want to when
to reinvent the wheel and then suddenly
say Aysen Plata and according to
Wikipedia I think is a linear software
utility designed to distribute
frequently update faces and images over
the Internet sounds like something we
could use so let's have a look what it
actually does jason is a chunking
algorithm basically so you take your
block device either or a full directory
tree and see I think creates a similar
lie stream of this and then splits the
stream into small chunks into producible
way and in a way that you can later on
compare chunks to similar to similar
images in a good way so then it takes a
little it's hashes of the different
chunks and store some sequiny in an
index file and all the chunk data itself
it compresses and stores under the name
of the hash in chunks door and now we
can reverse it and extract it then if we
extract see async index file to either a
block device or a directory tree thus
jason scans susie or index file and look
Chang store for each of the chunks fetch
addressed it over network and directly a
DC realizes is and writes it to the
device so there's no temporary starch
required we have remote access because
Jason brings other remote functionality
required to work over HTTP HTTP FTP and
so on and yeah we can wide it
sequentially to the device so now how do
we use it in route currently well what
we do is we want to update running from
today which is not B and so we perform
the same chanting I personally performed
on the image we want to use for updating
on the slot and store the information
about where to find the data for each
chunk in a so called seed store on our
target and then when installing an
update which is a basically an index
file of see icing here and we scan
through all these different elements
then we first take a look at our seed
store if you can fetch the data from
local and if it's there we get the data
for most lot a and write it to slot B
and only for these chunks they differ
from the or currently one for this we
have to make a remote access and Kyle
call this small chunk from the chance to
server so this is basically how it works
and another topic that you care about
when having a lot of devices is fear
deployment well if you have your update
and deploy it to a large field of
devices and yeah there is a box that you
didn't discover during your testing or
something like this in the update then
you've updated all your system and I say
oh damn I braked
almost half of them so it's a good way
to have it
one strategy for this and for this also
did open search tool exists called hop
it well hop it is basically a deployment
server provides a map interface or UI
for the user where you can manually
configure updates or and configure
complete roles we see later on and a
management API that allows to do this
automatically also by some other
backgrounds or something like this and
on the other side it has a device
integration API this is where the
devices registered your heart and verify
and pull of in a fixed interval to check
if there are new updates for them
available and if we take a scenario of
them hop it supports deployment
strategies like I could switch I could
split up the entire group of of targets
here into three groups and say ok a
certain threshold at 50% which mean if
at least 50% of the devices come back
alive ok then I continue updating and
what Rockets and asses start with the
first group updates and then after
having updated successful easy or Chagas
reports starters back and ok we see more
than half of the targets came back
successfully so hop it will start to
schedule the next group of updates and
in this group of updates we see oh it's
below us right
it's a baffle threshold so two devices
failed so we say oh stop something went
wrong we stop our update and we will not
kill the other targets with a protein
update so yeah what we've seen we have a
DS update frameworks they are so much
challenges we had in the parse but they
don't solve all challenges you still
have to know what
system requires our application behaves
which part of the system you want to
monitor have running on the system and
how to properly configure watchdog and
rebooting of your devices how to
interact with your hardware and so on so
this is only yeah it's not just taking
different components like an update tool
and a deployment server CIA sync and so
on but you have to well configure all
these components so that they can work
together and give you a robust of fully
robust update system so come to the apps
are there any questions say we have a
few minutes left otherwise if you want
to discuss a bit more tomorrow at half
past 1:00 p.m. I'll be at the open
embedded stand there is a small updating
demo that shows route in interaction
with outfit so if you like to come and
see all the time and if you want to be
sure that you can discuss with us just
visit us tomorrow at 1:30 p.m. yes
well it depends on the actual on how you
built a system if your system is secure
or what do you mean about a secure
system if you want to be sure so the
question was if someone could change
something in the system and does it well
the updating itself is if you use route
and most other tools to is verified so
only those who've the right key for
signing the image will be able to create
images that will be accepted Parag this
is a part of the update system then on
the target you are can prevent some body
from accessing it by using trusted booj
and all these mechanisms said it just
briefly came across or yeah does it
answer your question basically okay
great yeah
could you speak up a bit I don't get it
so the pressure was the smallest system
it's working on so a bit and
dependencies without uses chillip so it
has to be a system that is able to run
dilip it has to be a system that is
running in Linux rock itself is quite
small and it also supports not yet fully
setup code it's need more storage you
can also have a recovery or something
like this which needs less storage so I
think julep is about 7 megabyte or
something largest and Iraq is a few
kilobytes ok
you still have time questions left so
otherwise thanks for attending my talk
[Applause]