I don't okay so I think we're out of
time thank you Quentin
[Applause]
doesn't matter
Hey
you just spit onto your back
okay folks can be been shipped from the
sides to let more people sit down okay
folks we're starting the next
presentation okay so I'm going to okay
so I'm going to introduce my good
friends Magnus son Bjorn and they're
going to be talking about AF XTP people
that we have some cry from the room
please
alright let's get goin so my name is
born to Apple and this is my partner in
crime
Magnus Coulson we're from Intel as you
can see from the nice blue and we have
to tell you a bit about what a FX dps
was that is this better better ok ok so
you missed the word from our sponsor but
we'll skip that right ok so why why why
are we doing this so if you ask most
developers or network application
developers today like you have to pick
your platform and you have to pick an
API most people say Linux and BSD
sockets so why is that well it supports
a lot of features it's there it works
people are familiar with it so that's
the pic so say that this developer wants
to develop a dpi application that's deep
packet inspection application and he
goes to was provided by the kernel which
is the wave packet sock layer after a
while he realized that ok I'm not
getting the performance
they're like so what can I do about it
well I can't throw more course at it
which is I mean we as Intel would love
that but it's not for everyone so and I
mean it might not even be possible to
throw more hardware at the problem so
the typical solution then is to go to a
hardware down there for example someone
that provides specialized niche or some
kind of specialized hardware and the
problem here is that usually with these
hardware you get a proprietary SDK so
you have to change application and if
you want to try another hardware you
have to change the application once
again the usual hard to use the usual
lack a lot of feature that Linux has but
this specific specific order doesn't add
but then there's software solutions as
well for example deep decay and there's
PF ring and rat nap they're really fast
but they're not really integrated into
Linux so again it requires you to
rewrite your application and the biggest
problem here is that it's not really
integrated into Linux so if you what I
use the feature from Linux then you're
sort of you have to re-implement them
yourself in in your software and that's
not optimal doing things twice so the
problem statement is so can we take
these of use and features of Linux and
command the software and combine it with
the performance from here and let's see
so what we're proposing is a new socket
application hosting is a new address
family called xtp and it's a socket
it's a socket layer and it's it so you
can view it as the use of space part of
XTP and we just had a great introduction
to XP from our previous speaker so I
won't dwell Internet
the solution is free from system calls
so the transmit path and receive path
has zero system holes we also provide a
new kind of allocator that if you modify
the device driver and use this allocator
you'll get two zero copy semantics all
the way out to use around so that means
that the Nick will DMA the frame out to
memory in use in the user space
application ok if you do not use this
allocator and use an unmodified driver
you will still get a copy but pretty
good performance
anyway the last thing is that we do not
expose any hardware details to the user
application so instead we're exposing
virtual hardware descriptors that are
being translated from in in the kernel
to and so the virtual hardware
descriptors are being translated to
hardware descriptors in the kernel yes
all right one thing to note so if you're
using the zero copy mode then your
hardware has to support Hardware
steering so for example we have two
sockets receiving to two separate flows
then in order to use zero copy ltu
surround we you must be able to steer
the flows but Magnus will tell bit more
about this later okay so what else our
goal is to hit 40 gig for large packets
for you gigabit per second and for 64
byte packets we're hoping for 25
gigabits per second alright so from
Linux perspective why is this good well
get a new socket layer that's fast and
we're hoping to be closer to deep decay
or just a some percent off you get out
of the box support for all network
devices that's already there there in
Linux so a Linux support a whole lot of
devices what else
it states that xtp is required which is
not entirely true to get the best
performance we require XDP but it can
fall back to a term mode that's based on
SK buffs instead of X 2 XP and it's so
you can you can use the same application
interface for all the device drivers but
some device drivers will have better
performance obviously
okay I'll skip I'll wait for the future
work for later fights okay so from deep
k perspective why why should deep decay
care about this well say that he
implements a promo driver based on a FX
TP then you can still use your DPA
applications without any changes but
instead of having the device driver in
userspace
you let the colonel handle the the
hardware which is honestly the kernel is
pretty good at that so the goal here is
to have of course there will be a
performance hit but we're aiming for 10%
and for some application that that might
be good enough as a follow-up what
another good thing is if we leave all
the used space drivers aside then we can
actually use tip decay inside containers
which is not possible today at least not
in our easy way and another thing is
that you don't have to re-implement
things like scheduling and back off in
your new use of the space application
because the kernel can do this so we
support for example a post is called so
we can first be polling and then if we
don't want to do Bispo anymore we just
back off using the polls is called so
again maybe the goal is to if the case
is using this driver then DPA can be can
be seen as a really good packet
processing library which is currently is
as well so we think AF x2p could work
really good in conjunction with deep CK
all right all right so enough talk
here's the code so you start off by
creating a socket you allocate some
buffers using your favorite alligator
and the buffer is where where the frame
daughter will be DMA to you pass this
buffer pointer to the kernel so you
registered memory to
the kernel you create to the virtual
descriptor rings the aurochs and TX for
ingress and egress and then you bind you
bind the socket to certain interface to
state okay I want to bind this I findex
and a specific Q in the neck and then in
this example I'm using basic polling so
I read messages from the ring I posted
them send them out so again I can put
the whole siskel in there if I want to
back off right so wait again so where
does XTP fit within AF x2p so my plan
was to do some introduction X to be here
but again I'll skip that so what we've
done is that we're taking the redirect
action from x2p and I said that you
cannot own you can on top of redirecting
your frames to other net devices you can
redirect to an AF x2p socket as well
this is just another target for redirect
and some somewhat crazy idea well here
is that maybe we can't do descriptive
rewriting from X to P as well so we
could from X the P support another
descriptor format for example Verdi
Annette and then we could do virtual
machine networking using the F x2 piece
are clear what else right now the
current patch that only consumes the
frames and the the received frame that
are being redirected to to stop yet it's
consumed but we need to be able to copy
the frame to a socket then pass it on to
the stack because then we will have TCP
dump could be able to use that and have
a much faster TSP dumped on the current
a packet based one and also I've been
discussing with Jasper down here
about doing little balancing from x2p
program so you can receive your frame
and down little balancing it over
multiple sockets right yep and just a
few notes on the operation on so if the
driver is unmodified and doesn't ever
have XP support we support something
called HTTP KB which is a mouthful but
that means that you can still run your
XP programs it'll be slow obviously or
as slow as the skb pass it is but it
will work so you can use that on any
device or any net device driver and in
that they have device in from the kernel
if the device driver has support for xtp
then you used the mode in the middle and
that's that's still copy but it's much
faster than the first one and finally
there's the modify driver that's using
the zero copy allocation scheme and
that's the fastest one right so I'll
take a pass on it - so how do we do this
zero copy stuff now if you look at the
picture on the left hand side there
that's the classical non zero copy case
in that case they TX and rx descriptors
of the harder' ring is just mapped to
the kernel they're not visible to users
base same thing with a packet buffer
only visible to the kernel
what Linux does then is is copy out the
packets in to user space and with the TX
and rx script it just translates out
into some hardware gnostic format that's
that's in in user space and that's a
good thing
I mean operating system is about
hardware abstractions security
robustness isolation you get that here
so we want to keep that in our zero copy
solution so the in the zero copy
solution we do not expose TX and rx
descriptor harder rings into user space
they're still translated by by the Linux
kernel into some format which looks
different than other sockets but it's
still a hot bag gnostic format and you
know it's going to be secure and
isolated and stuff but the key
difference here is that we take the
packet buffer and map it straight up
into user space so packet from the neck
are mapped by D D made straight into
user space if you have two applications
you two processes note that the RX and
TX descriptors are never ever shared
between these two processes packet
buffer zone that I can be shared by
default they're not shared but if you
like shared memory there's nothing that
hinders you to share the packet buffers
so of course you create a huge fault
domain you know the other process might
actually pollute your data and so on but
yes yeah you chose it that's what you
get but it's possible but never win the
descriptors thing okay so secure it in
isolation that's very important so what
are the inquire monsier so we make sure
that I mean uses this can never crash
the kernel or another process and also
that you cannot read or write any kernel
data which is you know of course you
have to and you cannot really write any
packets from any other process so what
do you need in order to use let's say
you have two processes at this point a
and B and all your traffic goes in
through a single interface so you have
to split up the stream of traffic to
process alien process P and if they have
like ap address X a TLS Y then you
actually have to use some hardware
steering in order to steer this factor
that's the requirement for for untrusted
applications multiple address
applications where the flows going
coming from the same port because
otherwise I mean you couldn't just take
that flow and just push it up into a
single untrusted application and have
that spread it out because then it would
be able to see any packet and modify any
packet so that's not not a good thing so
but fortunately I mean since like ten
years ago most NICs
actually support classification and if
you look at Nick's today I mean they're
coming more and more advanced you know
and can do more and more stuff you can
even download x2p programs international
stuff so they're becoming more and more
flexible so I don't think this is
problem but there's always going to be
in some cases something where you can't
perform the classification hardware and
in that case you have to use this TP skb
mode or they X deeply driver mode which
copies out the dating too
user space and then what we want to
achieve is having than the the
classification being done in xdt so you
download CP program it does the
classification of course gonna be
slightly slower but you know still a lot
better than before okay let's look at
some numbers so we have this
experimental setup here it's the latest
RC that came out Wednesday no Tuesday it
was it it's just on some Broadwell
server here we just only two cores to
this simple micro benchmarks here and
the app runs on one chord and then I
know this is completely brain-dead but
TX and rx runs on the same core of
course that's not good but we're gonna
fix that you know it was just a faster
way to get to to this point TX of course
should run with some code but it doesn't
at this point so they will compete as
you will see in some of the benchmarks
when we use both TX and rx want to use
one cue pair it's a 40 gigabit portal
Nick and we use an Excel OH generated
blasting it is 40 gigabits a second full
traffic all the time we have three micro
benchmarks we have our X dot which just
receives the packet doesn't look at the
data just drops it t Express is kind of
the opposite it has pre computed TX
packets just try to send them out as
quickly as possible only rx only TX and
lt forward is then receive a packet swap
the mac header send it out again so this
actually does touch touch the data and
we have four different columns here we
have a packet v3 that exists already in
Linux and then we have the three modes
that we have introduced and the first
thing that you can see is that well even
this X dpsk be more would work with any
you know net network device it's like
two to five times as fast as the
previous fastest one and when we
compared these to two minutes similar to
this so there's nothing special with
these three so that's pretty good that
works on anything and it gives you you
know pretty much the same it's it's a
raw data interface in both cases I think
that's that's good
and then we have X deeply driver case
which gonna work on any driver with XTP
support and with ARC stock you can see
it's like 15 times faster than v3 I
think that's also really good you can
see that there are dashes on TX pushing
at the forward so that's one of the
challenges we had with this RFC we
couldn't reuse the XT PTX and the O's in
the driver but I think that's going to
be worked out so hopefully we will get
to some change those indios where we can
actually use have a mode for this even
in index here so we'll get some numbers
here but the code is not ready but even
better performance you can get with a
0-0 copy one if you we start by just
looking at TX Bush it's about like 22
times what you have here and Oryx top
and on hand it's it's like 17 or that
actors also done 20 times but something
to note that I mean we had a previous
version of this which we called a packet
v4 it's the new version of a packet and
it actually had like 40 times the
performance the reason for that is that
we have done absolutely no performance
optimization on this code it's just that
for functionality while we're this guy
we actually did some performance
optimization so my guess is that's
there's lots of low-hanging fruit to be
had here so this will definitely
increase we have spent no time of
performance of my session this so the
goal is to get it at least above 30
million packets per second for this 64
byte packets but still clearly we have
we have working of my session area to do
basic in all these numbers to me look
promising there's lots of to to work
that we can do I'm gonna say we have
nine minutes of course we have to do the
performance optimization work and really
something very important and it's a call
to you guys if you have some real
workloads please try them out I mean you
know I throw in micro benchmarks here
it's very different from real workloads
and those for micro benchmarks
if you want to try it out the RFC is on
the mailing list just download it and
you know let us know what works what
doesn't work please we really want to
make the Cisco we have a cyst called on
the T axis to get it going
we'll try to get that to get rid of it
and also to get TX of the Earth's core
because I mean you saw that performance
of their l2 forward
I mean it's limited by or it's in TX
completing on that core of course that's
not good but what will fix it
Pakistan you see xtp talked about also I
mean xtp has metadata support now you be
nice to tie it into this you can have
metadata maybe maybe it's hard hard work
load stuff or it's things that the Nick
had already pre computed for you and you
can you know get that up there also I
mean let's say you start an application
you bind to a certain mix can you bind
to certain qid
let's say qid 100 and then you run it on
anomaly it doesn't have a q ID 100 you
still want that program to work so you
should be able to emulate that q ID by
some you know copying or whatever today
that's not supported but really want to
be able to have the same program working
on every single nick you know
independent how many cubes it has most
would like to see a next EP redirect to
other Neph devices or XPath today you
redirect it to the TX path and send it
out again but it makes a lot of sense in
certain cases tax to drill directly to
the aurochs path enough upwards again
today there's only at least in the
previous corner in this one you correct
me if I'm wrong yes but you don't have
one xtp program for the whole your whole
Nick you don't have it per cube pack but
here if you can open an X AF x DP socket
/ q ID it makes sense to have the next P
program pack you pair you can do this
today by by just first patch you can
have one X to B program and fill the
stuff out on qy d in your in your HTTP
program but it's still easier from a
management point of view to have this a
separate program since there were just
one monolithic entity
somebody talked about was another
question about XTP support on TX I mean
yeah ii b PF has TX support but X deeply
doesn't have it but it makes a lot of
sense to have it especially in
conjunction with this AF x DP sockets
actually aim to
to execute the next EP program on the TX
path - that's not in in place today and
the cues are really single consumer
single producer just to be as fast as
possible but there are use cases where
you really wanted to be multi producer
you know single consumer or even senior
producer multi consumer so we are nice
to be able to plug in such a ring into
it we have try to write the code Solar
the ring structures are completely
abstracted away from the rest of the
code you can actually plug in different
ring structures so we'll be nice if
somebody could try this out and the
clone packet configuration just to be
compatible with AF packet Mahopac it
today it clones the pack it sends it out
to you space and another one is sent
through the stack we want to be able to
do the same thing to save support like
TCP dump Wireshark in these things and
in the previous version will be the TCP
dump implementation that took I mean
only took three four hours to convert
TCP dump and we got 20x performance
improvement on TCP dump I think that's
that's this and for four hours of work
so we want to be able to do something
similarly right so we've got five
minutes all right conclude so we
introduced this FX TP formula of a
packet v4 it's integrated xdp it's
basically the user space interface of a
next EP program and the zero copy we
have it up to 20 times now we had it up
to 40 but the current access is 20 so we
hope you can bet it will be even better
than this and there's an RFC on the net
mailing list please check it out the
House of course all the details this is
just an overview but there's still lots
of performance of messaging work we need
to do it's there for you to look at and
is there for just getting the design now
to you to comment on it's not there
because it has the greatest performance
on earth yet it should have start to
optimize performance before it's ready
as we all know but it's very tempting of
course and we think also think there's
lots of exciting xep extensions to be
had in conjunction with this and I'm not
going to go through this but there's a
couple of people in the audience that we
want to thank and more people here
I see you can find here hey questions
yeah I mean okay so if you started from
scratch I mean you made a choice what
should I do
so it depends on if you for example had
very very tight performance targets or
you were making an embedded system in an
integrated box then that would probably
you know you could probably go with DP
DK especially they had different
deployment snares you wanted your code
to run on both the embedded system a box
you wanted to run in the cloud you
wanted to run on on somebody server then
go with if you dick and you could deploy
it anywhere for example there's many
other things too I mean DPD care
supports or floating we don't think that
at this point as on any other have to be
an either/or choice right
you know so the question was why not
already MA it's a good point where I
should start out looking at that and I
think the main thing is that it's so
different from what's in the the
networking stack terms are but I mean
hey it might be a good fit but lots of
things where it is inspired by our
Dominion and you know this right yeah
and it's this is my subjective opinion
but it's a bit too much I'd say for for
most applications I mean or DMA is for
all the storage back things there are
too much bets but I mean might be right
and I mean it's Orion Bay has been been
around for a long time so it's really
mature as well but there's like two
people waving yeah one more
sorry for ya yeah the question visitor
how you design it but let's let's take
that offline sorry thank you
[Applause]