this one's going to be tied to MSM
Francisco
[Applause]
anyway what am i talk to you about today
is a little what does that mean so if I
do a nun chair and I'm in a username
space I try to make note I'm not allowed
to and that's sort of a reasonable
because dental is it fairly harmless
when I stood lice which they sent us and
check basically which is this and the
important part is this capable bit so
there are two devices likes def k
members mmm which are you would not
necessarily want to have access to
because then you could do bad things but
in you know the devil devs hero these
kind of innocuous devices it might be
nice to relax a little bit so what would
be a hard code a list of acceptable
devices and in the kernel and the FS
make note layer and blue box our lives
but then it attentively eyes on your
device
the maintainer of that device about is
this okay or not dadadada
so another another problem is you can't
master the file system so that the
window kernel actually has some patches
that are out of treat matches that
there's a sissy Taylor you can enable
mounting of x4 there's a flag it's FS
there's four user nests underscore
something else that record is in the
kernel that indicates whether or not a
user think on that file system but the
reason these descriptions exist mostly
because you know the thousands of parts
it's not safe or you know whatever and
the you know some of them engineers like
the like tests of export maintain is
that they all fix weird classes and
parts of bugs that cause exploits so
some of the processes might be safe so
maybe that somebody needs to doing and
basically it sort of has the same
texture
you must be roots and have the access
empathic ability to do that so what if
we could instead do something like this
and the network's bags I had last
animation doesn't die so anyway if I
started the container and the container
runs announces call you know that would
go into the kernel to the you know
regular entry path and then do some
magic function and then poured that to
the host which could then set an S to
the containers namespace do the mount
assuming it approve things and then lie
to the container
say pay your pop call succeeded it
didn't really run the big mouth called
in the context of the container but we
did it for them we liked them and it all
worked out so you can imagine doing this
with mouse or with made note or loading
kernel modules so ordinarily you would
not want to let a container load a
kernel module because also but there is
this thing where it's actually maybe
reasonable to to look at the module
block that the containers asking me to
load and then load the host version
because in particular in the column that
the host is running may be different
than that kernel but the container was
running so even if it wasn't malicious
it still might be incorrect and you know
it would be able to look that module but
if you're you know trying to load the
iptables module or whatever as long as
you load the host module and it exposes
all the guys that the iptables thing
then it should work just fine so this is
a way that you could allow kernel their
containers to load kernel modules
you know suleiman you've had a saint
version that you've actually trusted
nibbles on the clothes so this is like
another application of this you can
imagine there's a whole bunch of these
or we just kind of be nice to have an
implementation of this magic function so
how do we implement magic so the easiest
way is with Petrie's and this you can do
this today and in fact if you look at
the checkpoint restored school that live
migration over containers they give you
a lot of this stuff but actually TV and
every other thing they do this stepping
where you attach to something pass you
step through the syscall basis Paul you
look at you know whatever they are doing
it's already processed and
of course the problem of this is get to
stop buying this is Paul and expect it's
slow and most of the Cisco's we don't
care about you'll be care about mountain
and an inaudible which are fairly
uncommon and the rest of the thing you
wanted this run you know forever so
there's a second way actually it's still
using P trace where do you can you set
off and basically this is like code for
this is like the assembly code version
of India but the important part here is
the second operand traits basically what
this says is you can see a mouse's ball
trigger of he traced event and so then
you complete race attacks to attacks and
it runs along normally not stopping at
resist ball but then when this program
says hey something happened that it
triggers an increase event and they
could be listening for that so this is a
lot faster because you don't have to
stop on it's just Paula make sure it's
when you're looking for but it still
means that you have to Pete racing track
tax and so you find like between a run
time when trying to implement this lines
and containers about if it's just called
a returning that means I have to pee
trace them so then we the user comes
along wants to debug that what do they
do if they want to debug will they use
the Fineman algorithm which is right
down the hard problem think really hard
on it right down the solution and that's
not really ideal what you like to be
able to do is use as tracin and you're
familiar with so what we really like to
do is implement something that doesn't
involve me great and so that's basically
what this set does so we have instead of
doing the set comp right trace we can
sort of introduce yet another set a
pattern code which is returning user
notification and that basically would
trigger this this magic to happen and
then
how you interact with that as a as a
programmer who's on the other side of
that is it's basically at least in a
permutation that I composed it it's just
a file descriptor and so you have two
things we have a notification the kernel
sends you this structure you have an ID
which is a little disco key the process
idea of the task that did this and then
the second data if you look at this is
the same structure you get you know for
like yes programming this struct that
company you get basically the same data
and this is important because this
second structure does not expose stuff
like actual memory of the process so for
example for the mouth system call you
actually pass it the name of the file
system and the source and target
locations that you want to now that you
pass those as pointers and so in the
kernel the way Cisco implemented they're
not atomic so if we're so for example if
the second policy was the first thing
right after entry it might read some
pointers check the memory say ok this
not seems reasonable we're just buying
here there
those are both not important paths and
then you know it says okay go ahead do
the Cisco but then when the offense
layer actually reads this if you change
that value with you know another credit
somehow with shared memory or something
then the second filter already said it
was okay but now you change there's
something there various so there's a
time to check time of use and so that's
why seccomp traditionally does not
expose the memory programs and so you
might think ok well don't get the same
yes you have to be a little bit careful
about how you do this so the magic trick
is there if the task has some shared
memory with another thread or something
and it's space you can change the memory
for that task but if you as the tracer
the person who's doing the the mounting
or whatever on behalf of this path you
copy all of the relevant memory out and
then expect it all on on your side then
so as an atomic thing because they can
only edit their memory they can edit
your memory so whatever you whatever the
initial value of assist call is that's
what they're going they're going to show
you and then you can apply your policy
and say yes this is an okay or no this
is not okay about so with a little bit
of cleverness you can actually work
around this other time I checked I don't
issue which has so even that's what the
notification looks like so you basically
you know you do is and then you respond
and you can respond with an error code
you know and you respond and that's all
well and good as you might imagine new
stuff is slightly complex so there's the
timing check time of use issue that I
just mentioned there's also this problem
about actually accessing the memories
just itself a complicated problem
you basically access these files called
map files where you can open some other
test memory
and about that and then read whatever
addresses you want or you think if you
really like paint tray speaking polka
user but and then there's actually a
third problem which I sort of have
discussed you're doing this with you
know I'm gonna fake opening neckline
suffix for you or something you can all
sorts of but in that case the system
collects that returns the file
descriptor and you need to inject them
that file descriptor back into the test
set because you know if you open the
file descriptor here it's got to go
there somehow and so there's a number of
ways to do that basically trace the
index some code that then does it
receive message on some flowers or clear
something you could check the code that
just opens the file descriptor from
somebody else's laptop if it's actually
viewable or the potential extension to
this set is we could add a way to do
this very nice to come in a spawn
structure which may or may not be
interesting we'll see how this goes in
the first place so then there's a
question of how do you get a hold of one
of these things so I can you read and
write for this file descriptor so this
is also sort of an open question if you
have an API design but you think it's
cool come talk to me right now I have
sort of two different ways to do it the
first one is you install the cencon
filters we normally with the set
consists of all the fastest additional
flag and then you get the aft back and
then you can send message that F penis
whoever and then that server will
subsequently right pull do whatever of
course the problem that is if you're
sent out mostly black sent message can't
do anything so that's not really ideal
another way we use P trace again but you
could then you can attach script asking
better listener for one of its set-top
programs and then you don't have to send
message weirdness but you have to use be
traced to do that so it's a little
lengthy great so I think if you have
another guy designing that sounds cool
I'm happy this is a fairly hard to
implement so yeah there's some
implementation issues synchronization
across tasks because they're passing
messages back and forth with me test
this is somewhat challenging took me a
while of sitting and thinking to figure
out how to do it I think it's right but
but maybe it's not so comes tell me I'm
wrong there's another nice view about
synchronization with an expired ID this
sort of detail status there's get up we
discuss the Linux plumbers which is sort
of the genesis for this idea and then
it's sort of sat on the shelf for six
months and so that's why i commended I
push the v1 delivery route various
people notice that that URL is today
so there's not a lot of discussed there
yet doing it you could tell camera I'm
gonna do exam oh but I only have five
minutes so I'll do this I'm a polite
person
yeah I think my expense is a system I
can't die or the Viet Minh self-type
routine so it's through the demo I
wasn't really gonna do anyway do
anything cool thanks
the same with the second
let's assemble the space and then come
back
so you want to use the kernel to check
the permissions of the task but here of
me Tracy see that information is mostly
exposed to like roxelle staff and other
things need to tell availability if
that's what you want yes so you know
they've been asking lots of those things
the idea here is really to relax the
constraints a little bit but there's so
like from our visitors have a lot of
insight that I think the kernel distant
and the general doesn't so value here is
to sort of exploit that we can still be
allowed there's many more things but
although somebody pointed out to me that
desist call like is this about a system
own code this run after second so if X
uses to implement missed calls so I
think the applications are this sort of
it's gonna be a little bit weird but
other questions
you