okay it's time and so I'm rake insula
and I'm here almost accidentally and and
the reasons for that will become clear
and I I have my garage is full of
half-finished projects you know stuff
that I kind of get started on and then
lose interests or something with the
kids or whatever it is and I've just got
tons of them so I try to spend as little
money on the mass possible because the
likelihood is 9 out of the 10 of them I
don't finish and well before we talk
about that I'll explain him a little bit
Who I am I'm a software engineer I've
even worked an open-source software
engineer since 1995 and I work for micro
processor manufacturer today I'm a
tinkerer in my spare time I like to take
things apart and then try to put them
back together successfully that kind of
thing and I want to give a shout out to
my friends at the fab lab in Limerick
it's that my hometown now and the Fab
Lab in Limerick is a makerspace and I
hang out there on Thursday evenings and
talk about these half-finished projects
in various stages of completion and so
this is about my weather station so in
2013 we bought a new house at the top of
a hill overlooking the Atlantic Ocean in
Ireland and it gets whacked by the
weather like you I know if you have
heard of you've heard of clearly
hurricane or failure and those kind of
things we have trees down everywhere we
really get whacked so when we bought the
house I said jeez this would be a great
place to have a weather station um so
this is loop edge most westerly point
from us and this is where my house is an
Asscher oh and this is the geographical
profile between loop head and my house
and you can see here I'm a fall 120
metres above sea level we're pretty much
nothing between me and the ocean so it
seemed like a logical place to have
station so that year I just after buying
the house I asked Santa Claus for a
weather station and Santa Claus
delivered and Santa Claus asks they have
any stipulations about the weather
station before we got it
because Cedars to Santa hush on the
weather station any stipulations and I
said yeah I like one with a USB port so
at some point I can pull the data out of
it and maybe try to do something with it
one software engineer right
so I Julie got an Oregon scientific
weather station which is a pretty well
known brand I erected it it was up for
two years I did nothing about nothing
with it until I started to think about
green energy electricity prices in
Ireland are pretty expensive so I
started to think well with all this
weather could I put up a a wind turbine
so I said what I'll do is I'll monitor
the wind over a year seems like a
logical thing to do and then I can plot
how much energy I would generate whether
the wind turbine seemed like a very
obvious thing to do so let's go pull the
data out of the weather station so first
thing I learned them pretty quickly was
unlike most Oregon scientific weather
stations even though this thing has a
USB port to pull the data out of USB
port did not work
so first fail should have but two years
later I can't return that it's full it's
full with green mold so the second well
it's not fair to say it doesn't work it
does work with proprietary windows
software so it's what does in context
this past 250 euros in in order to run
the software to pull the data out of
this it would take a board and probably
$100 board running Windows which is
another $100 yes are you're already up
to 200 bucks just to run the software to
pull the actual data out of this and
because so there's no Linux software
that actually supported actually pulling
the data out of this and this was the
this was this was the conundrum Oregon
had done something that people weren't
able to figure out their stuff people
from getting no open source software to
talk to the weather station
and the other thing that I found out
other thing I found out while I was
hacking this is this is actually quite
unreliable
well the antenna and the hardware that's
actually in the base you know the other
weather station drops samples all the
time and there's absolutely no way
knowing it there's no there is no
indicator to tell you how good the
signal is so but on the positive side
it's pretty accurate you know it gives
you when sensor gives you a temperature
sensor it gives you a rain sensor and
it's pretty robust but there's no way to
get the data out so um I came across a
couple I came across an Australian and
maker magazine article that had used an
RX b6 $2 $2 written at 423 megahertz
receiver mounted on an Arduino shield
and this is something you can actually
buy from a company in Australia it's
like a premade arduino shield with the
or xb6
already on it and then and you could
load the sketch Jones when Arduino and
you could see the bit stream from the
bit stream from the weather station but
it was like it was like something like
$25 and then shipping from Australia was
like another $50 okay so that wasn't
gonna work and so what these were
available for like $2 on Aliexpress so I
bought a bunch and bought a bunch of
them and then I needed an Arduino to run
them with so I bought a whole bunch of
Arduino Nano clothes now let me just
preface this by saying that if I had to
stop being a cheapskate and I had to
just bought an or T LSD or at the start
I would have saved myself probably about
a whole bunch of hassle a whole bunch of
money and probably about four months
work with worth of work so but yeah but
I was on the path and I was gonna keep
going so and then obviously you need
something this so this kind of this the
Arduino talks to the receiver the
receiver receives at the 433 megahertz
received signal and then the Arduino
decodes it and then relays the data back
to an orange PI PC
which is you know takes that you know
takes the decoded bitstream and actually
turns it into something to recognize
pulls the sensor data out of the bit
stream and then uploads it to an entry
in internet so we're up about work to
about twenty dollars twenty euros worth
of investment at this point so a few
other bits of information that I had was
that somebody had reversed and so most
of the Oregon Scientific weather
stations have a do have a USB important
back that does work and does talk to
open-source software not the one I had
but most of them and somebody had
documented the protocol that these
things talk because all USB port does is
dumps the bit stream that it's received
so that was documented it's pretty old
was actually turned out later I figured
that was quite accurate and somebody had
published a sketch for the Arduino and
it did Dominic Pierre he published a
sketch for an Arduino that took T was
able to decode the Manchester decoding
bitstreams from the from the from the
weather sensor sorry from the weather
centres back to the base station so
these things talked with Manchester
encoding based on the based on the
length between pulses you can tell
whether it's a 1 or a 0 and then you
just send any bit bang the bit into the
right position and you were able to
decode from there and then finally I was
you I later used a piece of software
called the we W X to take the data that
had been decoded on the Arduino and pull
the sensor data out of actually decode
take the bitstream and decoded into you
know temperature like humid and
temperature humidity wind speed rainfall
those kind of things so I had enough
clothes I had the reverse engineering of
the protocol from people who are
actually able to talk to their web-based
weather stations directly I had a sketch
that could talk to the 433 megahertz
receiver and decode Manchester encoding
and turned the turned a 433 megahertz
signal into
into a bitstream that I could decode and
then I had some Python software and to
turn that into sand temperature and
sensor data that I could be uploaded so
this is roughly the design I ended up
with so you can see the orange pie is
talks to the Arduino the serial on the
Arduino was plugged into the orange PI
serial pins the Arduino is then plugged
into the or xb6 and the or xp6 is pretty
it's pretty simple there's only four
pins that you actually use your power
with five volt you give a ground you
connected to an antenna which is 433
megahertz antenna actually started
passing this around so people can take a
look at it that's now be careful that's
a whole two dollars worth of investment
right there so you plug it into the
antenna now here's where is mine is a
clearly far superior to what the Oregon
Scientific guys designed because I
connected mines LEDs that are told they
were never solid samples were received
if you actually it was actually good in
situations where I was sitting looking
at the base station that Oregon
Scientific provided knowing that the
circumstances have changed and the
screen should update and there was no
updates on the screen which was great
fun so what else is good to say about
this is very very it's a pretty simple
circuit so um this came from the
document that the Oregon Scientific
holding the Oregon scientific protocol
document that I showed earlier and it
basically indicates the basically
indicates what the header looks like in
the payload looks like and you end up
with you get the sensor ID and you get
the channel you get a rolling code which
changes with every power cycle of the
sensor you get various flags to tell you
if the battery needs to be changed you
get the the sensor data itself and then
you get a checksum so it all should be
fairly straightforward at this point
right well not so much
and so this sensor ID that I was pulling
out of it and this one a eight nine but
it's nipple orientation so we flip it
around so it's a one nine eight
it didn't correlate with any of the
sensors in the document so and the
checksum wouldn't calculate I couldn't
get the checks on the calculator it
drove me mad
sitting down read the document read how
the checksum should be calculated and
read about all the variances that Oregon
Scientific had and their different
devices but I couldn't get the checks on
the calculator it always seemed to be
hex and always seem to be hex a out or
decimal turnout so I made a mental leap
here I came to a conclusion that seemed
to be pretty evident from the
circumstances I was looking at a new
weather station that nobody had ever
seen before nobody had ever decoded this
weather station and that's why I need to
go off now and it was completely new
Oregon had designed a different way so
the bitch that's why the bitstream was
different so I started to create you
know well-known circumstances in which I
could control the bit what's in the bit
stream so I put a fan on the the weather
the wind sensor
I put the temperature sensors into the
oven and then into the fridge very very
just to change just to change and then I
watched what I would get on the base
station and then I correlate what I got
in the base station with what I saw on
the bit stream as a way to reverse
engineer a reverse engineer the weather
station and this I did this for about a
month and I successfully deke this way I
successfully decoded the wind sensor the
rain sensor and the temperature sensor
which altered they'll be quite a lot of
work but the rain sensor under that
faucet the tap and I opened the tap and
I left I heard that I let it go and then
I had an epiphany I looked back at the
document again and I figured out that
the very very the least significant bit
in the first bite that you get from the
air you get from the receiver it was
actually not
actually part of the payload it wasn't
actually sensor data
it was the sink fish and this had
actually cause of its position it had
and it was corrupting the checksum this
was actually also corrupting the
position of all of the bits in the all
of the nibbles in the stream so this
extra deck a decimal 10 at the very very
start which appeared as one zero one
zero was actually what was causing the
problem so this is after I had done all
the decoding turns out as soon as I
dropped that everything fell into place
and I ended up where the proper sensor
ID which in this case was one 984 and
that correspond directly with what was
in the document of course this was after
like six weeks worth of work that I just
had to throw in the billet ISM
now if I go back I might remind you at
this point that if I had I just paid $20
for an or TLS tea or I could have used
the RTL 430 treatment it's a it's a fork
of the RTL soft work that would have
done all of this for me but my I was
doing all this stuff the hard way right
so I rewrote the sketch so the original
sketch from Dominic Pierre was great but
I know improved it to ignore the sink
bit so I made a more robust so that when
interrupts came in from the 433
megahertz receiver it didn't drop it
didn't drop bits I made I gave a
variable output so it could or output
ASCII or binary dependent and obviously
if you bel put in binary it's more
efficient you don't need to do
conversion on the far side and the
output output USB serial or the arduino
zu X or X or T X pins and then I also
gave the Arduino the ability to identify
which sensor was so it could trigger the
LEDs and you can actually see how
frequently you're getting your goods
you're getting a good sample that's ones
that would be immensely useful because
you know when you're soldiering the
little antenna onto the board and then
you're insulting the even bigger antenna
on the board you actually have no way of
knowing how well it's actually receiving
sensor data and then I wrote a driver to
take the
but to take the stream from the Arduino
and to turn it into the sensor data and
I am I integrated the driver with the we
W act software and then I was able to
take all my information and I was able
to upload it to a Thor underground I
don't know people are familiar Weather
Underground but that's basically it
it's like a community website where
enthusiasts weather enthusiasts can
upload their streams from their mother
station so that's essentially what I was
able to do so if you all want to Weather
Underground you'll see my weather
station quite happily uploading the data
so that's it I thought a great work
thought I was done so I posted an RFC
v12 as I said I'm an open source
engineers developer so this is come
naturally comes naturally to me
Publishing or FCV want their mailing
list after all of this work and then
about a month later some of the email
popped up to say somebody had figured
out how to make the USB port on the back
of the base station work what the
problem was that it was talking and
non-spam non-standard serial speed it
was talking like if you're familiar with
community serial communications one two
eight one two aka serial speed is kind
of fairly on you is fairly unusual a
slightly faster than what it ought to be
so it turns out that when you when you
configure the serial port this way you
can talk to the base station perfectly
from the next software works fine five
months on so now we're doing an or fcv
to output so we no longer you might say
we no longer need any of this stuff you
don't longer need the receiver and
there's stuff I'd argue that mine's
better because at least I can tell them
where mine's dropping signals and I can
at least plug in more rolla I can plug
in bigger and more reliable antennas
which is what I've done and so you'll
continue to support both ways but for
the vast majority people who are not
going to go and build circuits as I have
we're going to support in the RFC v2
talking directly to the weather station
so what did I learn from what did I
learn from this experience well always
be willing to challenge your own
assumptions so you know assuming that
assuming that this is a brand new
weather station we're probably wasint
right those kind of things and always be
willing to adapt as changing
circumstances somebody figures out a way
to decode to turn on the USB ports or
works it kind of adapt to those kind of
circumstances so that's my war story of
decode hacking my Oregon scientific
weather station and yeah it was it was a
lot of work and a lot of fun and it's
all to say about thank you
and any questions yeah well orange pie
can't do real time so you don't know to
what extent you're actually measuring
the latencies in the orange pie or the
actual you know you're you need very
very precise mo m measurements of the
pulses when you receive the pulses from
the aurochs v6 the orange pie can't do
that reliably just because it's simply a
general purpose CPU whereas the Arduino
because it's a microcontroller can do
that great yeah go ahead
I'm sorry
well oh yes so so for who's to do with
all I get how much it'll cost me well if
I hadn't just bought the rtl-sdr I would
have spent about twenty books I don't
know how many of those little things I
fried but I think I fried about three
Adam and I think I ended the point about
five of them and I fried a few deer at
nanos along the way as well so I
probably I probably put about 60 to 80
euros per - worth of money into it if I
was to deal with all efficiently I
probably get it alright first go but
that's the nature these things right
sorry go ahead
do I have to oh yeah so I will publish
this on my blog and probably next week
it'll my blog is you can get me on a
Schroder you thank you any other
questions
I just need should thank the room
organizers for inviting me to speak it
was very kind thank you very much
[Applause]