adios good it's on
you
I'm gonna talk about I'll first give a
bit of an introduction talk about some
tips when installing jido how to use it
with Python some random tips and then a
bit about how to use these cloud
optimized and how to make cloud
optimized geo tips and also where to go
for some help so there's a quick
introduction about myself I'm the team
lead for today pipeline team in Berlin
for playing labs Germany I've been there
since 2014 working for blackbirds and we
were acquired by Planet
I am Belton but I was raised in Florida
so that explains the accent of it this
is my fourth year attending Fossum and
the first time speaking so a bit about
GTO who here has used G tall or is using
G go already alright good so I'll just
quickly go over this so G dollars the
geospatial data abstraction library I
was initially created by Frank warmer
damn he's actually my colleague back in
San Francisco the project is damaged by
osg oh it's a c e c++ library can read a
whole bunch of vector so shapes and
raster or image formats there's a whole
bunch over 150 raster's and 90 vector
formats it's as you heard it's kind of
like the base of everything that like
they say every geospatial project uses
this internally so something like most
common GTL utilities are like Chitale
warp 4 if you're like jim was aching
reprojection and warping g'd all
translate to change from one raster
format to another and then the vector
equivalent of ogr to OG r and then GL
info where you know you can not just get
the information but you can also
generate a whole bunch of statistics out
of that and get it in a whole bunch of
different formats and so in on the
insulation side on mac is pretty easy
there's a if you use homebrew which you
should
there's the OS do for mac tap that you
can use
it's also managed by OS geo and they're
always looking for some help there and
then you just install the G del 2 and G
talk to python bindings on a bun to
there's a about to das PPA that has G da
there but there's also a cross-platform
way of doing this so if you're already
using anaconda
you basically just kinda install with
jido and that kind of like sets up a lot
of the dependencies that you need there
but I don't really recommend doing
either of those because you get a lot of
dependency problems so
planet we use a lot of VMs and
containers to isolate all the system
dependencies to basically make it so you
can just rebuild the whole system and
get back to a working configuration you
don't have to worry about like upgrading
something for some other package that
you might be using and breaking your
whole jido insulation and it also kind
of lets you avoid having to use the
Python virtual lens where you also get
some problems if you're trying to do
like multiple versions of GL and
different virtual environments that just
gets very messy and basically you can
just put the setup instructions in
docker file wagon file or use an
existing set up to kind of get started
and then just build up there with
whatever dependencies you might need so
working in Python G doll two gave us a
lot of powerful Python bindings so you
don't need to use the command line call
anymore you can just basically put the
command line arguments in the Python
called Vegeta wart
for instance and there's also I was
reading a bit about this at the OG o - o
gr for instance it's not called øg øg
are in the Python bindings but is jino
vector translate there's a whole RFC
about how this was set up but yeah it
makes it a lot easier to have that and
you don't have to worry about the full
sub process call also there's a very
good numpy integration so if you are
doing things like windowing you can
actually just read the array and specify
the offset that you want and then you
get full numpy array you can do all the
vector and sorry all the raster
computations that way as well also if
you are just kind of trying to do some
small things you don't actually have to
use the detail Python bindings directly
there's a few good libraries that we use
as well rest here you or Rosario from
Matt Fox
it's basically a pythonic version of G
Dahl so
it's all jido under the hood but it's
basically just a Python API that's
pythonic and it's a lot easier to use
when you're wanting to open you can do a
lot with that for vectors and shapes
shapely and Fiona and the same person
it's also pythonic shapely only has geo
spend see if I remember correctly and
then Fiona has full geology our
dependency and of course they're also a
lot easier to use you can load GJ songs
and wkts and all this stuff and do your
validation and intersection area
calculation and all these other
transformations so some other tips what
I really recommend is that if you are
wanting to learn a lot more how to use
jeetil especially like the C++ API
there's a lot of the utilities that are
some of them that I mentioned in
previous slides that you can just read
their source code try to understand how
they work and then that gives us
basically a bit better than the
documentation on how to use things
especially if you're looking at GL warp
that shows you how to actually do all
the things that it does under the hood
as well as there some of them that are
Python scripts so the g-dog calc for
instance general calc I that does all
the loading into the numpy array and
does the for instance if you want to do
like a difference then you can just look
at how it extracts the operations and
execute them so that's basically my
first tip on that also if you're working
with geometries that you get from random
places or that you're generating
sometimes especially around Dateline you
get some weird issues where the the
geometry doesn't validate anymore and
basically you can just apply
a zero buffer on it and then that ogr
kind of magically makes it a valid
geometry so really helpful whenever
you're having weird problems with
geometries just apply a buffer to it
with actually no buffer but that makes
it work
there's also VR T's so VR T's are
virtual data sets and you can basically
treat a whole bunch of imagery tiles as
like one big image you can also
basically take a big image and chunk it
up into smaller files and then join it
all back together in this VR T which
just references all the images and where
they should be in if they were one
raster oh yeah so VR T's are just
basically XML files that describe all
the operations and they do need
everything to be in one common
projection so just keep that in mind if
you are trying to do that the other
really cool thing is that a lot of
imagery providers are now making how to
optimize do tests so what's the cloud
optimized use it so these are geo tips
that work a lot better for cloud
processing
so essentially what they do is they have
like the header information in the very
beginning and it's a tiled image so
usually 256 by 256 or 512 by 512 tiles
and they also have all the overviews
built in sorry by doing this we you can
essentially just do a range request so
you can get the header or jido looking
basically get the header and then figure
out what bike range the imagery that you
need if you're doing a window or where
the overviews are if you're just getting
some
if you just need any overview of the
image and then it downloads only the
data that it actually needs so if you're
using the vsi curl driver in Gino you
can basically just put the URL in there
and of the image if you're getting it
from open area map digital globe planet
the Landsat 8 bucket on AWS is also in
this format and there's a whole bunch
more Co giotto org has like a lot more
information about this then you can
really save on the download times and
not having to download the whole raster
just to get the small piece that you
need if you are generating image and you
want this to be in the cloud optimized
USA format there's basically two things
that you need to do if you don't already
have overviews builts then you could
just use gino add oh and overviews to
build the overviews so basically just
put your image where it says in TIFF and
run this should be pretty quick
and that actually modifies the image and
puts it indirectly if you are doing an
external overview it's not going to work
the second thing is to then do GDL
translate where you basically tell that
you want it to be tiled and you want to
copy the overviews that were in there
and then this recommends to use lzw
compression you can also use deflate but
there's some issues some some things
aren't fully compatible with deflate and
and the other important thing is that if
you're when you're hosting it the server
needs to support the range request so
HTTP 1.1 if you're doing if you're just
putting it on s3 or Google Cloud or
Azure they all support this byte serving
as it's also called to use the cloud
optimized unit if basically if you're
using the VA site kernel driver that's
all under the hood handle magically
some examples are on the G dal wiki
there's also a good basically Jupiter
notebook that describes that and slinked
here I also have the presentation
uploaded on the Boston website so if you
look up the page for this presentation
you'll see the presentation link there's
a PDF so here's an example of using the
via site curl driver as you can see it's
basically just doing the slash a sidecar
slash the URL so this one is Landsat 8
image on the glanced at it alas pocket
which is a great open data source if you
want to start playing around with raster
and need some imagery so where to get
help this is also a very important topic
but the GI Stack Exchange which I think
I saw a shirt there that's a really good
place you'll find a lot of people from
the developing community Frank and I
both answer questions on there there's a
jido IRC channel as well and the Udall
dev mailing list is a great way to get
answers
you know or the main website has you
know the wiki and everything else so you
can really get like all the
documentation on there but another great
resource is there's a series of medium
posts by a colleague Rob Simon where he
goes over really introduction to G dal
you know a bit about the history of
projections and whatnot so it's a really
good read like three part series there's
also the Python geology our cookbook
I've used it quite a lot when starting
out would you dull to figure out how to
do things in Python doing that and the
reading the general utility code as well
those two things were important and I
also made one of these awesome
geospatial lists on github so a bit of
shameless self-promotion of that there
and yeah so basically these people
helped out with the presentation mostly
some my colleagues and Evan who's
basically one of the main developers of
G Dahl now and all the imagery here is
from my company so all the beautiful
pictures you saw on the slides the we
also have an open data set of a
California so it's Creative Commons
Licence imagery from like two weeks ago
or something like that or you can
basically just go on plan website and
make an account and get some data if you
want to have some more free data sets
that you want to use for your stuff and
that's it just picture my cat and thank
you and you can reach me on Twitter
github you can send me an email and
that's it
thank you
any questions yes
no this has been supported indeed all
for a while actually
so the cloud optimized geo tips are
nothing really new the it's more like
leveraging existing features of G doll
I'm kind of like a bit more standardized
way so
so the question is when you have all
these different libraries and you they
all recommend to use docker but they
have their own docker containers and you
want to basically put them together we
kind of have had the similar problem of
doing that we rely heavily on GTL but of
course there's other libraries that you
need to use and basically one of the
things you can do is to kind of try to
glue these different doctor files
together so to like look into it and
build it that way
we also rely heavily on the atoms that
planet and so basically we have like a
big script that you know as you start
trying to integrate these different
projects you kind of build up a VM and
if you start going down the really weird
path then you can kind of still recreate
the whole VM back out so it is a lot of
work unfortunately but yeah the the VM
makes it really like sure that like you
can always back out and kind of start
over and that's kind of like your source
of true if it works on the fresh PM then
you just use that but if you're like
doing something weird then you can
yeah
so I don't think Yugi is fully supports
it yet
I think in qgis 3 which should be
released sometime soon they will have
some of that support but yeah it's not
fully supporting TGS yet so the question
was our Kyle optimized gos if supported
QGIS correct yeah you could once it's
supported then basically it's streaming
the data right and especially if you're
viewing it at a higher zoom level for
instance it'll just use the over views
instead of downloading the full roster
any other questions all right
[Applause]