thank you a good morning yet my name is
Alistair Coles and I'm with their
swisstack and I've been working on Swift
for about five years and I think for 30
years have been on the core developer
team and this morning I'd like to tell
you a little about how Swift can be used
to build geographically distributed
clusters I'm going to begin by doing a
brief overview of Swift I apologize to
those of you that may have been here
earlier this morning and heard Iago's
talk and but I'll try and get through
that reasonably quickly before then
starting to talk about geographically
distributed clusters and hopefully
answering the questions
what are they why might you want to
build one and how to Swift enable that
and then I'm going to look at another
really nice feature of Swift which is a
rager coding and talk about how erasure
coding also works with distributed
clusters so disruptive clusters has been
a feature of Swift for many years and a
rager coding I think has been available
for maybe three years to three years but
it's only in the last year that we've
kind of managed to get the two of those
to work together and better so kind of
really excited to tell you about what
we've done to get get those two working
together okay so what is Swift and Swift
is an object storage service so it's
great for storing blobs of unstructured
data pictures media files virtual
machine images and whatever it might be
it was one of the founding projects of
the OpenStack cloud software suite and
it's been around in production for seven
or eight years now Swift offers a REST
API accessed over HTTP and this API
offers standard set of operations to
create objects read them back update
them and delete them now it's important
to understand Swift is not a
our system and it's definitely not a
block storage system it does have a very
simple naming hierarchy so objects
belong to containers and containers
belong to accounts okay so what are some
of the properties of Swift well first of
all data that's stored in Swift is
extremely durable
typically swift will store three
replicas of every object that is written
into the storage service so here just to
explain this is a very simplified
architectural diagram of Swift we have
an HTTP put request that's putting an
object to a URL and a see oh that's the
account container object name structure
and that request is handled by a proxy
service which will write three replicas
of the objects onto three disks in a
pool of storage service and at the heart
of Swift is this component which we
called the ring and unfortunate have
time to go into a lot of detail about
the ring but it's a form of consistent
hashing so there's a data structure
there and the ring is always trying to
disperse replicas of our objects across
both disk devices and servers in the
storage pool so that's how Swift used
durability we always have more than one
copy of an object and they're written to
different discs on different servers the
Swift is also very scalable and there's
two factors that contribute to this
again the ring has a role to play so as
well as dispersing replicas of our
objects the ring is always trying to
balance the load of objects across the
storage pool so here we have two
different objects being written to two
different names and the ring has chosen
a different set of devices to store
those objects and I said it's a
consistent hashing algorithm so the
hashing kind of naturally causes objects
to be dispersed somewhat randomly and
uniformly across the storage book so
this helps with scalability but also we
have no centralized services so for
example we can have multiple instances
of these proxy servers and multiple
instances of the Ring and there's no
need for any communication between them
as objects are written there's no need
for any coherency protocol they're
essentially stable independently
operating services the only time the
ring does need to be updated is when
changes are made to the devices in
storage pool and then finally Swift is
am highly available so Swift will
continue to accept writes and to serve
read requests even when one or more of
the storage pool devices has failed so
in the example I'm using here of a three
replicas storage policy Swift will
consider a right to be successful if two
of the three replicas if a quorum have
been written to disk and here you can
see for some reason the third replica
has failed to be written maybe there's
just like a network failure discus
failed congestion whatever reason but we
have two replicas written and Swift
considers had a quorum and so the right
has been successful and then we have
some background asynchronous processes
that are continually working to replace
missing replicates by copying data from
the existing replicas so not much long
after this right request there's
background processes will ensure that
that third replica is in place now I
haven't actually told you the whole
truth there Swift is actually doing a
little bit more but I'll get to that
later in my talk but needless to say it
just gets better a little better than
that but that's the basic principles
behind a high availability now a
consequence of this is that we can end
up with stale data in Swift so here's a
little bit more complicated example
where the object that was
written a time t1 has now been
overwritten at time t2 only the override
was only partially successful so I still
have one of the the blue replicas and on
disc that was written at time t1 and
only two of the three replicas at t2 at
time t2 were successfully written so
this means there's some stale data in
the cluster and it's possible to read
that stale data because our ring will be
choosing randomly one of those replicas
to serve reads so this is kind of like a
very different property of Swift and
other objects doors and when compared to
a file system or a block storage service
you know the file system we expect that
when we've written data when we next
read it we'll get back the data that we
last wrote and that's a contract that
we're very used to and I emphasize this
point because Swift does have a
different contract with regard to data
consistency and we've we've heard two is
eventual consistency eventual because
those background asynchronous processes
are always working to update all of the
replicas and ensure that eventually your
data becomes consistent now if that
sounds odd to you rest assured there are
plenty of applications where this
consistency contract is totally
acceptable and this does enable Swift to
be very scalable and highly available
okay that was my very brief overview of
Swift we're going to touch on some of
those concepts again as we talked about
as I talk about distributed clusters so
first what is a geographically
distributed cluster well my definition
for the purposes of this talk is this is
a cluster which is consists of data
being stored in multiple physical
locations and that those physical
locations would typically be connected
by a wide area network and importantly
at least the process is my definition
every object that is
stored in a distributed cluster will
have at least one copy of itself in each
of those physical locations so we might
be talking about multiple data centers
and here like I think approximately in
London and Geneva connected by a wide
area network and the entire cluster the
global cluster operates under a single
namespace so objects are written and
read in any region within the cluster
under the same names okay why would you
want to do this um first reason is for
increased data durability and in
particular for disaster recovery so if
in the event of some catastrophic event
you were to lose the availability of an
entire data center you'd still have
copies of your data available in another
physical location but it's also useful
for achieving data locality so if you
have users accessing the same data sets
but in multiple geographic regions a
distributed cluster can mean that you
have copies of your data at located
close to each of those users and your
open observe their read request with low
latency oh and just to mention if you if
you look through Swift documentation
literature you'll also see these
distributed clusters referred to for
obvious reasons as global clusters or as
multi region Swift okay so let's see how
that actually works out when you map it
onto a swift cluster and so what I've
done here is I've added a few more
storage servers to my storage pool and
I've grouped them into two regions now
this is really easy to achieve in Swift
every device in the storage pool is
annotated with some metadata and the
metadata associates it with a server and
also associated with a region so in the
same way that the ring was always trying
to disperse replicas of an object across
disks and across servers
the same principle is extended to
include regions and the ring just
inherently works to disperse our object
replicas across these multiple regions
and that's great because it means now
that if I lose an entire region from my
cluster
I still have replicas of the object in
the other region and are still available
to me now you may have noticed if you're
sharp that I've changed the replica
count of the storage policy that I'm
using in my example originally I said
that typically deployers might use three
replicas in a swift cluster the reason
I've increased it to four it's not a
requirement for a distributed cluster
but it's a nice number because it gives
us symmetry between the region's means
we end up with two replicas of every
object in each of the two regions in
this example and that also means that
it's well as being able to survive the
loss of an entire region each region can
also independently survive the loss of
one device and still have at the object
available to it so a four replicas
policy is just a nice choice and twist
that many deploys use when they're
operating multi-region clusters so this
is great it looks like we haven't really
had to do much with our swift cluster to
just naturally achieve
data durability and disaster recovery
and what about data locality well
obviously I now have copies of my object
in both of these regions close to any
users that might be in those regions but
we need to do a little bit more work to
actually achieve data locality in this
cluster and that's because the ring as I
said it's always trying to load balance
so by default when serving a read
request the ring is selecting a random
replica for each individual read request
that means that a read that's arriving
in region one may by default actually be
directed to a cop
of our object that's in region two now
that's not optimal but fortunately we
have an option in Swift to override that
behavior it's called read affinity so
this is just an option that is set in
each of the proxy servers and all it
does is it puts a bias into the Rings a
selection algorithm to prefer replicas
that are resident in the local region
when serving reads so real affinity is
basically is giving us a means to
trade-off load balancing for read
performance in the case of a distributed
cluster and it's typically recommended
to use it's good idea okay so we've seen
that relatively simply Swift has been
able to cope with my service being
distributed we've annotated the devices
with some region information the ring
pretty much operates as it would for a
single site cluster and we have this
read affinity option just to optimize
and and create data locality all sounds
good
just pause at this moment though because
we should just consider the fundamental
difference between this distributed
cluster and a single site cluster which
is that we now have this wide area
network component that's sitting in the
middle of our storage pool with a single
site cluster it's reasonable to assume
that all of the nodes in storage pool
are connected by low latency high
bandwidth reliable networking that
assumption may not hold when we have
wide area network connection between two
regions in our storage pool so going to
think a bit about what consequences are
first of all if that wide area
connection was to fail and in particular
what happened to our rights when the
wide area network has failed so this is
where I said to earlier I wasn't telling
you the whole truth about the way Swift
writes replicas
read during a write request so in this
case the ring is temporarily unavailable
and unable to access the locations
intended for two of the four replicas
but it can write to successfully so it
can achieve a quorum in the case of a
four replica ring two successful writes
constitutes a quorum what I didn't tell
you is that actually swift works harder
than that
to write data it down onto this so it
doesn't just stop when it reaches quorum
what it will do is it will look for two
temporary
alternate locations for the remaining
two replicas and write them there and in
a game we have these background
asynchronous processes that are always
working to move replicas that are
misplaced to their correct location in
this case once the wide area network
becomes available again so despite the
fact that we've lost the wide area
network we're still writing fully
durable data all built into one region
this gets a little more interesting
again when we consider an overwrite
operation so here just like my previous
override example some data has been
written at t1 and then at t2 the wide
area network fails so what happens to
the overwrites at t3 well as it just
said it's what's really hard and it's
gonna write down four replicas two of
them will successfully overwrite the
older replicas in region one two of them
are written to a temporary location in
region one but we still have our old
replicas down in region two so again we
see this eventual consistency effect
that there is a window of time why the
wider while the wide area network is
unavailable when reads in the second
region may be reading temporarily
inconsistent data as soon as Network
heals background process has fixed that
Swift is always working to heal and to
put the most consistent set of data into
the cluster so hopefully I'll our wide
area network doesn't fail too often and
but it may be that it has lower
bandwidth or higher latency than the
network within our our single site and
it wouldn't be unreasonable to ask the
question well it isn't actually this a
terrible idea
that now every one of the write requests
into the cluster are actually having to
write data into the remote region isn't
this going to slow down every every put
request every write request and the
answer to that is potentially yes it
will so here I've just built a kind of
development cluster and I artificially I
have this cluster I have some some
storage devices in two regions and I've
artificially slowed down the right time
to the storage nodes in one of those
regions and you can see as you'd expect
that starting from a baseline of the
fairly responsive solid the y axis here
is the overall
completion time for a put request it
starts pretty healthy but as I start to
increase the time to write those
replicas to the remote region you can
see the overall request completion time
increases it's actually bounded add
enough upper limit because there's a
final part of the whole truth that I
need to tell you so Swift will require a
quorum of successful rights it will then
try really hard to write the remaining
replicas but after some time outs which
we call the post quorum timeout it'll
give up and say I have a replica I have
a quorum of replicas and I'm going to
return to the client and say this write
was successful so that puts an upper cap
on this degradation of right performance
that you would see as your remote region
became slower and slower but this may
not be great and I mean these numbers
are quite extreme the latency that I put
into these remote writes but this isn't
great so is there anything that we could
do to improve this write performance
when we have distributed regions well if
we think back to what happened and when
the one failed then what I described was
that the ring would just write all four
replicas into the local region so how
about if we just deliberately did that
all the time and that's the mode that
Swift has this called write affinity as
opposed to read affinity just as I said
what this does is it overrides the
behavior of the Ring so rather than
directing all four copies of the objects
to their intended locations in both
regions it actually writes the remote
copies to temporary locations in the
local region and that means that the put
requests will complete much more quickly
but we still have four copy to a data we
have a fully durable write our data
albeit in one region so this write
affinity mode is another trade off and
it's temporarily trading off
the dispersion of our objects for
increased write performance clearly
there's a window of time here where if
our second region was too sorry if our
first region was to become unavailable
we would have no copy of the object in
the second region but it's a trade-off
that we can use to improve performance
and as you'd expect and I wouldn't be
telling you about this if it didn't work
so at the end of this graph you can see
I enabled and right affinity and my test
cluster and immediately the overall put
request completion time has dropped back
down towards our baseline so this is
great I should point out though of
course with write affinity enabled
although we're writing all of the
replicas to one region the data is still
available in the other region it just
means that any read request that's made
during the window of time before those
replicas have been asynchronously moved
will be served by propagating back
across the wide area network and reading
the data from region one once the eight
wants the async process completes their
nose reads that we served from the local
region so we have no loss of
availability we have a temporary loss of
dispersion but we still have full
durability in the first region and our
write performance is hugely improved and
of course I probably don't need to
repeat this but we're also trading off
consistency before write performance
again my example of an overwrite the
first write of t1 in the background
swift has relocated all of the replicas
to their correct locations so we have
two replicas of the object at t1 in the
second region with right affinity we're
now deliberately deferring the update
update of those two replicas in region 2
we're leaving that to our asynchronous
background processes which means there
is this window of time when we may be
reading stale data in the second region
but that's okay as long as we clearly
understand the contract of eventual
consistency the Swift offers so right
affinities is is a powerful tool but you
do need to use it carefully it's not
always appropriate I mean first of all
there is as I say no free lunch here at
some point data has to be moved across
the wide area network so those replicas
that we've written into temporary
locations do need to be moved at some
point so if you have a workload that has
a continuously high write rate you know
continuously high ingress into your
cluster then those misplaced replicas
are likely to back up in your local
region
if the asynchronous processes can't keep
up with the ingress rate of your rights
also if you have a use case where users
clients of the remote region are trying
to read object data immediately after is
written then well those reads are going
to end up having to go and fetch data
back from their remote region because it
hasn't yet been moved to low to their
local region and if that's happening
well you might as well have written the
data across the wider network rather
than go and read it immediately after it
was written into the local region thanks
so there are some workloads that
wouldn't be suitable for write affinity
and in fact if you have a very high
ingress rate it's probably best to just
take the hit of whatever the latency is
of doing those remote writes and that in
turn will generate some appropriate
feedback to the clients and just kind of
govern the ingress rate into a cluster
but there are some workloads where write
affinity is a really useful tool so if
you have bursty traffic for example and
where you want to accept a lot of writes
into the cluster but then you have a
quiet period when you can be
asynchronously moving replicas and
working towards the dispersion goal that
we have and in particular if your remote
clients don't have
acquirement to be immediately reading
data them write affinity is perhaps
suitable to so for example if your goal
is to replicate archives for delayed
access by clients in multiple regions
okay so swift is very well able to
support distributed geographically
distributed clusters and shown you a
couple of the tools and tuning options
that we have to make some trade-offs
when doing that and we also have this
other really nice feature we have many
nice features but another one is rater
coding and I say here with an
exclamation mark Swift now supports
these now what I want to emphasize is
Swift now supports the combination of
erasure code with distributed clusters
and until this last year that was
something where the two features didn't
work too well together and and so I'm
just going to kind of explain why that
was and the steps we've taken to fix
that because there's some again some
interesting choices that we had to make
apologies to those of you that have a
really great understanding of erasure
coding I felt I should very briefly just
describe and what it is so a rage coding
is a very popular technique for storing
data and durably for using less storage
space than a replication policy it's a
mathematical algorithm and in the
example I'm showing here we would have a
coding algorithm that accepts a blob of
data splits it into a number of
fragments so in this case us the data
has been split into four data fragments
and in the erasure code also calculates
a number of parity fragments and the
example I've chosen here we have to
parity fragments and we at least in
Swift community we'd refer to this as a
four plus two erasure coding scheme
now each of those parity fragments is
the same size as a data fragment so in
this example we've added two more
fragments so we have added 50% more to
the size of the original data the really
nice interesting feature of erasure
codes and the reason they're called
erasure codes is that we can lose we can
erase any two of that fragment set and
still reconstruct at the original data
now raising to sounds familiar to a
three replicas storage policy we had
three replicas we could lose two of
those replicas and we'd still have a
complete copy of our object and here we
can lose two of our fragments and still
reconstruct the original objects but
we're actually only using one and a half
times the size of the data that's why
Rachel coding is very popular here's how
it works out in Swift so erasure coding
is implemented in the Swift proxy as
data is inbound into the cluster I'm
sticking with the same example for data
fragments plus to parity fragments I
just mentioned we have a couple of open
source libraries that we use to
implement the algorithms and the ring
behaves exactly as it behaves for
replicas in fact the ring is completely
unaware that is dealing with erasure
code fragments rather than replicas so
as I said before the ring is always
trying to disperse fragments across the
storage pool and we end up with one of
these fragments on each of our servers
on a disk which means that we can lose
two disks and still reconstruct our
object data and we're using
approximately 50% of storage compared to
a three replicas scheme which gives us
similar durability so that's great what
was the problem with distributed
clusters isn't this just going to work
well let me add back in the regions into
my storage pool same array coding scheme
for data fragments to parity fragments
the ring has done its job the ring has
dispersed the fragments
at uniformly across the regions
unfortunately though this only leaves us
with three fragments in each of our
regions and we need four fragments to go
to reconstruct the object so now we
don't yet have our disaster recover
recovery data durability property if we
lose one of our regions we don't have
sufficient fragments in the other region
so although in the single site case this
4+2
rater code policy gave us similar
durability to a triple replica when we
move to a multi region case it's not
actually quite enough and which is
reasonable because we're storing nowhere
near as much data as we were in the case
of a replicator policy so what we need
and we need some more fragments and so
how about if I change the array to
coding scheme that we're using and now
I'm still going to have four data
fragments but I'm going to have six
parity fragments get to be a total of
ten fragments why did I choose that
scheme in particular well that it ends
up with five fragments in each region
for fragments is enough to reconstruct
my data so I can lose an entire region
and still reconstruct my data and in
fact I can lose a device within a region
and still reconstruct data so this
scheme is now equivalent to four
replicas and it's using about two and a
half times the size of the data versus
four times the size height of the data
so this is looking looking good okay
this this works this gives us our
distributed cluster with a disaster
recovery we have data locality we can
read and the data from either region
without going across the wide area
network are we done
no unfortunately we had another problem
because we realized that calculating all
of those extra parity fragments
introduces a compute burden in the proxy
server and I've just calculated an
example here it's like the the relative
compute time for a fourteen megabyte to
encode a fourteen megabyte object
using one of the backends that we have
available the x-axis is the number of
parity fragments and I'm always using
four data fragments so as we go from
four plus to where we started to four
plus six we're roughly doubling the
compute time - to encode this object and
that turns into latency in our right
path so that wasn't great so we had
another thing and somebody very clever
not me
made the observation that although we
want to have five fragments in each
region and the fragments in each region
need to be unique with respect to each
other they don't need to be different
fragments in the two regions so instead
of calculating more parity fragments how
about we just duplicate the set of
fragments we have and spread them across
the two regions so this means I can drop
back to four data fragments and just one
parity fragment much less compute burden
and and then I can to placate the set of
fragments distribute them across my
cluster and I have the result nice
looking for still using same amount of
data as storage data on disk
two-and-a-half times the size the
original data getting the durability and
the data locality that I would have got
with a four replicas policy okay great
looking good again I'm I'm smiling again
with this but there's one last problem
that we faced which is unfortunately
although the ring does a great job of
dispersing fragments throughout our
cluster it makes no guarantees as to
which fragment goes to which device or
to which region so we can end up in a
situation like this where we have five
fragments in each region but we don't
actually have unique sets of fragments
in each region
so here I've ended up my example in the
second region I have two copies of
fragment one two copies of fragment
three and one copy fragment to which
only gives me three unique fragments and
again that's not enough for me to
reconstruct data from that region alone
so there's one final piece in the jigsaw
or the the journey if you like towards
this getting a rager code and support up
together for just distributed clusters
and that was to add what we call a
composite ring and it's actually quite a
simple idea what we do here is we just
take two of our record two of our
regular rings and allocate one ring to
each of the regions so now we have a
ring just behaving exactly as it
normally would but it's just responsible
for managing the dispersion and the load
balancing in one region and another ring
for the other region and then this new
composite ring concept we have
guarantees that the duplicate sets of
fragments are always spread between the
two regions and that was the end of our
that's the end of our solution that's
that's how it works
so now we're guaranteed to always have a
set of unique array two code fragments
in each region we have disaster recovery
we have data locality and we get all the
benefits of reduced storage requirements
that come from a range of coding and
that's it and it's in my talk thanks for
attention and I think we have some time
few minutes for some questions why you
think B questions I'm just going to pop
this up and welcome anyone who'd like to
come and contribute yeah great question
so the question was how do we do
rebalancing and I probably need to add
some context of the question so
rebalancing is a process in Swift when
devices are added or removed to the
storage pool I assume that's what you're
referring to and and so when that
happens we need to move data that was
previously resident on a device has been
removed and we might need to move data
to populate a device that's been added
and so actually rebalancing for an array
decoded scheme operates much the same
way as it would for a replica scheme so
the ring at that point the ring is it
recalculates and
new data structure that captures the
mapping from and what we call partitions
which of virtual subspaces of the hash
space in the consistent ring and the
ring has an algorithm to try to move as
few replicas as possible and when it's
going through rebalancing and still
maintain the properties of dispersion
and balance throughout the entire
cluster and it's the same with an
erasure coding scheme which is partly
why the ring is sort of ignorant of the
significance of the individual rate
coding fragments it's just treating them
like replicas okay
any more questions yes yes and and I am
aware of sorry repeat the question can
we do more than two regions yes and I'm
aware of production clusters that are
operating over more than two regions I
can think one example immediately that
is a three region cluster and for their
use case they've chosen to deploy three
replicas so they end up with one
replicas in each region because that
gives them the durability they require
and with a rage of coding I would say
cautiously at this point in time - it
might be good to experiment with two
regions before jumping in with four or
five regions and depending on your
choice of a rate coding scheme you can
end up with a lot of fragments being
written a lot of connections been open
to back-end storage notes and so it's
probably good to experiment with a two
region cluster first and but yet multi
regions is definitely possible yes
let me repeat the question to make sure
I understood I think the question was if
I if you would like to use a razor
coating can you can you move to a razor
coating without losing you without
downtime and the answer is yes and no
sorry so um I have glossed over a topic
that Iago covered earlier which is that
actually within a swift cluster we can
have multiple storage policies operating
at the same time so in a single cluster
we could have a replication policy
running alongside a storage policy and
the client can actually choose which
those policies to store data is
absolutely possible to introduce an
erasure coding policy alongside a
replication policy what we don't have at
this moment time is a mechanism to
automatically migrate data that was
previously in the replication policy
into an erasure coding policy there is
some work in progress on that but we
don't have that at this point in time
but absolutely you can add erasure
coding to an existing cluster okay I've
been told time's up
sorry
[Applause]