Hey so my name is Chris I
with Twitter and so this this year I
thought I'll do something different and
I was a little worried because I'm doing
basically everything's life that was
more or less and a wife I didn't really
work so I was a little worried about it
but we got it working so I work for
Twitter twitter has a small vm team
comes just like the four people and then
we have another guy working on the
machine learning stuff if you're going
to tweet about this target would be nice
if you at that hashtag so that my other
team colleagues know what's going on
here at FOSDEM
so in general why am i doing these talks
you know you might have seen a talk of
mine before and I know always about
growth stuff and how we do things I
don't know if you've seen my previous
talk where I talk about that we use
growl at Twitter in production so it
actually works in stuff so you can watch
that on youtube if you want but the main
purpose of my talks is always to get
people to try it like Christine just
said try your Qi cease I said try your
compilers so a Twitter we save money by
using raw I cannot tell you how much
money but it's substantial it's way more
than I get paid so yeah I don't know if
that's good in that so you can also save
money but yeah right exactly so that's
one good reason or something you can you
can approach your management and you
know say hey we might be able to save
some money so you have to try it the
other thing is that I want to fix all
the bugs that are there right
that's also very selfish because if you
guys find the bug and you fix that bug
we our Twitter we don't hit it and
Twitter stays up so that that would be
good and then lastly the also to improve
crawl right there's still a lot of stuff
we can improve on and it's a little
easier to work with in situ so it's
actually easier to do improvements and
then people come to me after my talks
and say well is it safe to use or does
my data center burn down if I run
so our data centers are still fine and
since I don't know - last year or
something we are running our main
Twitter services so basically everything
you when you tweet or when you retweets
everything 100% of that stuff is running
on crawling production today since last
June or something so it's fine then
people ask me how do I use it where do I
get it sometimes I get emails later and
people have been trying it and they
mostly complain about the benchmark
numbers and they usually say well it
really sucks that's because they don't
really understand that
Rod's different than the existing
competitors and so this talk is to
explain this so what is Gras just
briefly it's a child virtual machine
just-in-time compiler takes Java
bytecode and translated translates into
native code actively developed by Oracle
labs John Rose was talking about it
earlier a little bit so I don't go too
much into detail these are the links
where you can you know read up on it it
uses JVM CI and it's written in Java and
that's very important to remember
throughout the whole talk it's written
in trouble too it has all the properties
that Java programs have right it uses
Java heap memory
it loads classes all this stuff so
remember this where do I get it the
answer as always is it depends
unfortunately but this will change
pretty soon with with JDK 10 this will
change but where do I get it so there is
chap 295 which is the head of time
compilation shop and this one when you
go to this chap you see oh yeah it's in
release 9 and it's delivered so right
because lines out when you scroll all
the way down you see the dependencies
and it says it depends on JVM CI and
then it uses crawl and so on and the
project will merge crack or into the
and and it delivers it magic and
delivered in Linux x64 built and so
that's the depends so if you're running
on Linux x64 you can take JDK 9 and you
have grout automatically if you're not
only an X x64 then you have to either
build it yourself or you can download
them Cheeta contain early access build
and then you get it there's this there's
this one bug here that adds support for
basically the reason why it's not in 9
is because we couldn't write the native
shared libraries for the alt feature
that's what kind of do it ok so what do
you need is a JDK with JVM CI chip 243
and with äôt because that gives you gras
for free basically and that's on linux
that's created equal in jdk 9 or mac
windows critical than 10 and you can
download it from here
and we're not doing doing that now so
you the way i do this talk usually is I
use an Oracle cloud container and I've I
start that container up like on the fly
and I'm doing this to show you when when
people like when I when I go to
conferences and I see talks with people
who live demos I always wonder how many
hours did they spend to prepare the
container or the machine that actually
everything worked right the demos and
stuff so and but i decided i fire up
like a clock container with no setup at
all and do all the demos and show you
that really all you need is download all
the you know the jdk and so on but since
it's only 25 minutes i can't do this so
you have to trust me on this one I'm
just showing you so I started one up I'm
part of the of the Oracle developers
champions program and so they give me
free access to two cloud
time it's like a budget and then I can
use it that's really nice so that's what
I'm using so I have I have a machine in
Frankfurt as you can see here and
everything's so small that I don't even
know how to get there
all right usually I don't know how to
get there now there's more up here where
you can see I don't know ah yes
instances that's what I want thank you
so I have a running faster instance and
it has a public IP address this one so
we just log into this guy right and the
second time and so we have I've already
downloaded all the stuff that I need and
we have the JDK 9 that's that's the open
JDK 9 build you can get from Java dot
whatever it's called the link I had
earlier so just download that one and we
are setting just Java home here to this
directory and then we are also putting
it on the path and I've done this before
so I can shortcut a little bit and then
we have this Java version and over here
we are doing the same thing we're
comparing c2 and Gras that's that's why
I have two windows here
so we're doing a Java home again this
guy and the path and then in this
instance oh yeah I'm also using this
environment variable called Java tool
options and I use parallel if you see
because it's a little easier later too
to not look at g1 output it's easier to
look at parallel output and and we do a
512 Meg heap and maximum and start and
there you go
and the same over here wait no let me go
back so usually I start up this
container and it takes a while and then
I talk about myself so the only thing
I'm saying here is because Charlie
called me out
I'm the lava one organizer so if you
guys want to come
a white next January you know so the
rest I skip so back to the demo in
what you can do in 89 is you list all
the modules it's like I don't know like
75 modules or something like this and
then as we've seen before the äôt chip
depends on on on JVM TI + + & Grau
basically and then you can say okay Java
was got describe describe module right
so we want to describe the jdk äôt
module and just no that's not right just
correct here we go
so this is the che DKA okie module and
it requires jdk dot internal Dom be m
dot CI that's JVM CI and it also
requires this guy here and that scroll
this module contains the cross source
code so if you have these two or yeah
these two you don't need a it to you
really but if you have these modules in
your chain ek9 then you're good to go
okay that's all you need so get a tvk
with JVM CI and the OT yes check Merck
we just verified that we have that and
then the only thing you really have to
do is to turn it on that's all so how do
I use it so let's go back to our chaps
here and then if we go to chap 243 here
you can see when you scroll down a
little bit oh look this is how you turn
it on so all you have to do is take this
so so since these are experimental
options you have to unlock them and then
you say oh I wanna enable JVM CI which
not automatically turns on the compiler
it just enables the Java interface and
you could then use something like
truffle to schedule compilations but
what we really want is to replace C 2
with a JVM CI compiler in in our case
that scroll okay so we take that and we
stick it into our Java tools options
like I have it somewhere here already
right we just changed that to 512 here
real quick
and as you can see unlock enable use GPM
second okay so if we do something like
this then we see oh yeah the options are
being picked up but there's no real
difference right nothing's really
happening okay then then we could go
back yes there is so we have now JVM TI
enabled and then you can do print X
final version and we grab for JVM CI
okay here we go
these all the JVM CI options that we
have so for example yeah we enable it
and that's true the one I'm looking for
is to champion CI print properties so
this guy here we go that's a long list I
mean a little wider here that's a really
long list so there are a few chavin CI
properties so since JV m CI is written
in java mostly and Gravas written in
java the command-line options are being
passed as java properties still -
capital b and then you know whatever so
there are a few chopped achievement er
properties and then there are a bunch of
Grob right so the one we are looking for
is this one here which tells us a little
bit about when kvam CI starts up okay so
we do this and we say capital d timer we
have to say true because if we turn it
on so we do a dash version and we see
nothing's really happening so what the
hell is going on so the way it works is
we are running tiered right and if we do
a print compilation here let me do it
again you see this column here is the
level of compilation the tier level and
and tier 4 would be c2 or Gras and
everything we compiled so far because
the dash version doesn't do a lot we're
not actually doing a level 4 compilation
so JVM CI will never be initialized
because it's lazy you lazily initialize
so we have to do a little bit more
we can do we can run the couple for
example into it at their shell so we can
see okay something's being in their
shell initialized and it's called
hotspot gbmt our runtime that's a class
but it seems like that's only it and
it's not really finishing it and the
reason is the initialization of JVM SIA
and growl would take too long so the
program actually exits before all the
initialization is now so we have to run
a little bit more so we do a small run
of Aurora and in Z oh yeah that looks
much better
so we initialize GBMC I there's a
there's an implementation of GBMC I run
time called hotspot cheating if they run
time right that could be technically a
chain nine GBMC I run time just throwing
it out there and then we initialize
something called a hotspot bra run time
and that's that's really the compiler
you see we initialize all these
providers and then we initialize we
create the back end for our CPU and so
on and so on and then we run the
benchmark okay so now we are really
using it good let's go back to the
slides and I have ten minutes okay
usually a demo takes five so maybe I can
do two more bootstrapping
is you you have to remember it's written
in Java right so God is just another
java application that's running in your
TVM so if you want to run it it will get
compiled as any other Java code you have
running in your VM okay so it loads Java
classes because it's written in Java it
has Java methods obviously and these at
some point when your compiler when
growth starts to compiling your
application these methods get hot as
well and they need to be compiled that's
called the bootstrap okay so let me do a
quick bootstrap demo you can turn this
on explicitly and you'd say oh let's
drip my JVM CI okay this cloud instance
by the way has I think four cores so
eight threads something like this and it
uses a bootstrap it uses all the threads
it can get in bootstrap C so what the
what a bootstrap really does it takes
all the Chava java.lang object methods
which is super simple right and
schedules them for compilation and then
because you're compiling these small
methods the whole compiler gets warm and
compiles itself that's what the
bootstrap does so it takes 10 seconds to
compile 2500 methods which is quite a
bit right so that's something where
people are razing well you know I don't
want to wait 10 seconds every time I
start something but you don't have to
explicitly bootstrap it
you can also bootstrap it basically
automatically while you go okay so when
you for example let's do a print
compilation here oops a print copulation
off yeah let's run that same benchmark
again why not and we crap for orc for
all VM there we go so here we see that
we didn't do an explicit bootstrap this
is just being implicitly done while we
go along right and you see how it's
being compiled and the benchmarks done
and some methods are still being
compiled but what's important here is
you can see the compilation this level
is always 1 and there is a flag in growl
it's called wait I may not what it's
called
JVM see I I want this guy properties
right and we grabbed for c1 only ok here
we go so there's a property called
compile growl with c1 only and that's by
default true and the reason this is set
up that way is c1 throughput is much
much faster than any that let's say c2
or grott itself right so we went growl
the growl itself to be compiled as
quickly as possible and not take as much
CPU away from our from our application
compilations or even the application
itself
so we just compiled with c1 and that's
usually fine yes
I can and if I have 50 minutes I will
show you how to do it but apparently we
don't so yes you can next year the other
half of the talk will be next year yeah
so this is this is what a boot strip is
and how bootstrap working we could we
could also turn off you know if we if we
go here and say okay - capital B and
this guy and then we say false they will
see oh they are a bunch of one
compilations in there and then three and
so at the end we'll get to level four
compilations like here so if you turn it
off
you go through the whole tiered system
and grog will compile itself takes much
longer but I have six minutes left I can
yeah well I'll show it to you why not so
we do the bootstrap and we say okay we
do false here oh wait no no no I'm not
doing this I have to show you something
else this is important and I'm still
debating if I should file a bug for this
or not because when you do a bootstrap
an explicit bootstrap it's actually
ignoring the compiled growl with c1 only
flag so it's compiling it with itself
every time you do an you do an explicit
bootstrap so that's I think that's very
important and I don't know if it should
do it actually I think it should honor
the flag and if you tell it hey only
compile this you won't just compile with
c1
I should mention sometimes an explicit
bootstrap might help even if it if it's
upfront time that you're just wasting
and waiting on but see one's not
optimizing as well as a c2 or Brawl does
right so if c1 doesn't have as capable
now sit for example so all the
allocations that will be done in Brawl
the compiler will then go to the Java
heap nothing will be escaped analyzed or
scalar iced or anything so if you're
expecting that later in your application
run you were still you still come
piling a lot and you want these
compilations to be quick a bootstrap or
turning off the c1 only flag might be
better okay so going back to the slides
when I asked the bootstrap demo what
they were learned well we compiled about
the bootstrap composite about 2500
methods I didn't do the non teared one
but it compiles even more because then
more of corral gets hot and it just
compels more of itself so you can do it
either upfront or on-demand during
runtime I would suggest to you to not
touch the bootstrap flexib just let it
run if I could do the production demo
that I have you you would see that it
really doesn't matter and then by
default we compiling
only with t1 and bootstrap they explicit
one does it a slightly different so Java
heap usage crawl is exactly it's written
in Java so if graph compiles a method it
uses Java heap memory to do that
in depending on the the C one only flag
that you're using if you if you set that
to false all the groud methods itself
will use Java heap memory that that's
very important because usually I'm we're
Twitter we do the same right you tune
your heap to exactly like how much you
need maybe a megabyte of free memory but
then suddenly a compilation can kick in
a big one and that can take up 100 or
200 megabyte of memory so let's do a
quick three-minute Java heap demo so
we're actually doing something over here
as well what I want to do is yes no it's
still alright so we locked you see and
we run I think we were on that one again
we do that ok and then we see I'm using
this benchmark because it's very
computationally intense and it's not
really doing a lot of allocation and she
sees stuff so it runs like 10 seconds
right it and there is no GC happening
during the benchmark run it's just the
this the da capo
hardness does these GCC's very
explicitly so if we do the same over
here we'll see that as a little bit more
going on right and that's exactly what
I'm talking about so if we are compiling
the Aurora benchmark itself and while we
are compiling it Grodd is using Java
heat memory for that so you have to be
aware of this the the two things oh yeah
one thing I haven't shown you yet I want
to show you that too I still have time
so there's something called CI time it's
a really badly named option because what
what did what that means is the compiler
interface time that's not actually true
what it really measures is the compiled
broker time so how much time does it
take to compile methods and how many
methods does it compile so let's do that
over here - CI time and as we can see
so we compile about a thousand methods
with c1 and about 300 with with C -
don't don't pay too much attention at
the at the time and the especially the
bytes down here when we look at the JVM
CI numbers because these contain this
number contains inline bytes while the
JVM CI one doesn't and it's just the way
because it's C++ code and it's hard to
get that value back into the VM so just
believe me it's it's it's really not
that important so we compiled about a
thousand here
and here we compiled 6,000 okay and
that's all the ground stuff right you
remember the the implicit bootstrap is
compiling just with c1 so we're
compiling roughly 5,000 additional
methods they're not all ground methods
because there are also core library
methods involved because grodd is
written in Java it uses a bunch more of
the core of the core library so core
library method methods get compiled as
well and we compile 400 with JVM CI
which I'm not exactly sure why we do
that it's a hundred more and I also
think it's we
have to look at the compilation output
but I think it's also our core library
methods because the growl ones are only
compiled with c1 but if something
because of Gras gets hot in the core
library it will still get compiled with
Tier four okay does that make sense I
hope it does and I'm out of time
[Applause]
[Music]
that's that's that's the last thing I'm
saying so Java uses chorale uses Java
heap memory that will change at some
point but at today we don't have heap
isolation and keep in mind something
that Christine also said it's important
how much memory you achieve JVM uses
because situ also uses that hundred or
200 megabytes to compile a method it's
just not as visible because it's not on
the Java key
all right thank you
[Applause]