okay so welcome everyone and thanks for
the kind introduction Michael my name is
Gabbar Suresh and I'm a final year PhD
student from Budapest Hungary and in
this short talk I will talk about how to
make better software with graphs so as
Michael said javascript has some sort of
bad name to it but it's difficult to
dispute that it's very popular so if you
go on Stack Overflow is consistently
ranked among the top languages with
respect to the number of questions asked
and it's getting standardized so there
is a standards body that releases a new
version of the standard each year called
ECMAScript and essentially things are
getting better for the JavaScript
community is getting a better language
I'm not going to say that it's the best
language or it's like the top most
popular language but it's widely used
from IOT devices to the browser so it's
important that we make good JavaScript
code and one of the techniques to
guarantee good source code is called
static analysis the full name is static
source code analysis which means that we
test software without compiling and
executing it so we take the source code
do some analytics on the source code
itself and then try to check rules and
check violations of these rules on the
source code this is a complimentary
thing to the traditional testing so
basically in most continuous integration
systems nowadays you have your
development environment you push code to
the source code repository it then gets
compiled by the CI server and it gets
tested by unit tests and integration
tests and static analysis is sort of
complimentary to all that it's a
different step because it just reads the
source code does some analytics and then
as a separate feedback loop it returns
the results to the developer this is
quite popular so I'm sure most of you
have seen some of the cloud services
like coda C code climate and so on
but the problem with this is is that
this is an offline feedback loop so you
commit to your code and then you receive
an email 15 minutes later that your code
is violating this and that rules another
approach is to use command line tools
and ID integrated tools if you have done
some C programming there is an old UNIX
tool called lint this is such a defining
tool that actually it gave its name to
the family of source code analytics
tools called linters and if you're a
Java developer you're probably aware of
fine box or PMD and obviously there are
tools for JavaScript there is es lint
Facebook's flow engine the turn trail
system and so on so essentially these
give pretty good coverage but all of
them have some drawbacks we tried to do
analytics over JavaScript in the past
and we found that there isn't a single
system that allows users to define
global rules evaluate those rules
efficiently and can be extended by
custom rules so these are pretty
difficult satisfied advanced obviously
others have thought of this problem as
well so checking global rules is
computationally very expensive operation
in a large source code repository and
this is actually so slow that it's
sometimes even difficult to integrate to
the CI workload so obviously there are a
couple of workarounds the first
workaround is just don't bother with
global rules write your code in a very
modular very separated way and then use
file level static analysis be eslint for
one does that another workaround is to
do some battering on your CI analytics
so you run your build and tests on each
commit but you only do a single analysis
a day and also you can do some custom
algorithms so if you make your algorithm
smart enough it is going to be fast but
then it's going to be very difficult to
extend with new rules so in short we
made
important design considerations for the
product we wanted to create a static
analysis - for JavaScript that allows
users to define custom analysis rules be
those global or local and it should
provide high performance
ideally close to real-time evaluation so
if the user is editing the code in the
development environment the user should
be able to receive timely feedback on
the changes that they made so one of the
cornerstones of our approach is the
architecture and the workflow it's all
built around incrementality which means
that we want to do some changes we want
to do the analytics in a way that it
incorporates the changes made in the
code so essentially first it analyzes
the source code on the whole and then
for each change it uses incremental
processing so if only a single file is
changed in a fifteen thousand five a
positive it tracks the changes to that
file and second we want to use a
declarative query language now if you're
in the graph dev room you can probably
guess which declarative graphical
language that is we will get back to
that in a moment so this is the high
level architecture of our system it
starts off with the version control
system all your code is committed to the
version control system it's then loaded
to the workspace of the analyzer where
it gets transformed to a syntax tree and
it gasps transforms to a semantic graphs
we then load this to the graph database
and we get a set of analysis rules that
we want to check and then we perform
continuous checks on the server and give
feedback to the client continuously so
what are these steps if you have ever
played around with a compiler those
should be very familiar because
basically this is how most of the
compilers work essentially they start
off with the source code which is
sequence of statements for example this
is a very simple source code which says
we declare a variable foo which is equal
to one divided by zero it uses a
component called the tokenizer to split
this into token into tokens tokens are
the shortest meaningful character
sequences in the source code so for this
where foo equals 1 / 0 we get 6 tokens
the tokens then go through the parser
which builds the so-called syntax tree
according to the grammar specification
for the source code line that we've seen
we get this syntax tree and this is
already quite close to what we want to
use but this is still missing some
semantic information it's missing on the
scopes which will be added by the scope
analyzer and this missing on information
on various accessibility features so
essentially the abstract semantic graph
enriches the abstract syntax tree by
adding some scope information so we take
this and add some more edges actually
once we have already added these edges
it's no longer a tree because it has
some cross edges all the scopes are
defined and also the accessibility kind
and other meta information are added to
the specific nodes so this is like
compiler construction in a nutshell and
you can see that even though we started
off with a very simple experiment like 6
tokens a single line of code we get more
than 20 nodes and this can be a lot more
so for a very sophisticated line of code
we can get 50 to 100 nodes easily so
these guys are pretty large graphs we
can do all sorts of pattern matching I
said that we are going to use a
declarative graph pattern language and
this is cipher so if you have a graph
like this and you know a bit of cipher
you can actually specify validation
routes for example you don't want your
code to do divisions by 0 so
you create this rule which matches the
binding identifiers that are in a binary
expression then do a filtering where the
expression is a division and the right
value is a zero and then the projection
operation to return the binding and this
is very useful for the developer because
the developer can fix that instantly
it's a Van Daan truth that the sooner
the developer gets feedback on the
errors that they made the cheaper is to
fix these errors so ideally we should
give the developers timely feedback on
the mistakes they made in the code so
workflow wise it starts with the
developers ID and the version control
system as a first step
code is loaded from the version control
system and transformed to tokens ASD and
ASG step by step then it's transformed
by a set of cipher queries and Java code
and is loaded to the graph database and
once we have this we trace the core
issues of the errors back to the source
code and display the errors in the
developers ID so once we have a workflow
that like this running
actually it allows us to do very cool
things one of my favorite ones is type
inferencing because as you know
javascript is a dynamic language and
it's very easy to write code that throws
runtime errors because of type
violations obviously there are some
workarounds for this you can use
typescript or other typed flavors of
JavaScript but you have a lot of legacy
JavaScript code that's written in plain
JavaScript and type inferencing is key
to use those in a way that will not
return errors while while running the
the code so another use case is global
analytics because we have this graph we
can do a lot of cool reachability style
queries we can do that code detection we
can do a detection of async awaits where
you run an async and it's dangling
somewhere in the code but you'd never do
any weight on that piece of asynchronous
code and you can do potential division
by zero detection by propagating these
issues to the code so you can check
whether value can be zero at the point
of the time that it's evaluated some tag
details I think will be very interested
interesting for this audience one of the
key issues in implementing gold is is
that imports and exports are just crazy
in ECMAScript you have a dozen ways to
import and even more to export so we
have drawn this nice matrix of
compatibility and just to give you an
idea of how long it takes to implement
all this single black dot which says
that that's compatible needs like 15
lines of quite complex cipher code to
work with so it's a lot of work to cover
all these and obviously once we have
this we have to implement the algorithms
now as I said we have some propagation
algorithms where we want to propagate
some property along the graph
be that typing formation or the fact
that this value can be zero or not this
is actually something that's called run
to completion scheduling so we give a
set of transformation rules to the
system and then ask the system to
execute it until there are no more
changes to execute this is actually
quite difficult to do in plain sight
first so we use a mix of Java code and
cipher code and the Java code does the
propagations while it can another thing
that we struggle with is efficient
initialization of the database state so
in the first implementations the initial
build of the graph happened with cipher
statements so we build the graph pretty
much node by node with separate cipher
statements and this obviously was quite
slow so we started to think around this
with a bit and used CSVs to generate the
graph so in the for as the first step we
generated just two CSV files one for the
nodes and one for relationships and then
used the neo4j import tool to load it to
the database this is not a very
sophisticated approach you could do
multiple CSVs or binaries or other
things but already this gave us a 10x
speed up so it's actually like one days
of work and the initial load went down
from an hour to a couple of minutes we
also stumbled upon regular path queries
quite regularly because there are a lot
of cases when we need transitive closure
on certain combinations so for example
you can have a situation when you have
function that's assigned to a variable
that's in another function that's
assigned to another variable and so on
transitively and essentially we would
want to do a transitive closure style
operation on those relationship types
the problem is that it's not supported
by cipher yet so we created a workaround
the workaround is let's start the
transaction add some proxy relationships
there
sort of go over those relationships do a
calculation for transitive closure on
those proxy relationships and then roll
the transaction back and essentially
deleting those edges from the graph this
is I think a proper workaround but it's
not the nicest way to express it and
obviously the cipher team is very well
aware of this so for the next open
cipher there is a proposal for creating
path patterns this allows users to
create an expression where there are
several relationships type next to each
other and then do a transitive closure
style operation on that ok so I said
that incrementality is very important in
this work and actually this was my
motivation to start working on this
topic so as I said we built our system
around cipher queries as you probably
know there is now an initiative called
open cipher which aims to deliver a
standard specification of the cipher
query language it was released about two
years ago and it's been actually adapted
by industrial vendors that are listed on
the logos and there are also a couple of
research prototypes most notably there
is graph flow which is developed by the
University of Waterloo and there is
ingre which is my PhD project and
interestingly enough both of these
target the same goal it's the
incremental processing of cipher queries
so you have a sort of cipher queries and
you can evaluate them incrementally
continuously in your system if you're
interested in some of the details
last year I was here in the same room
giving a talk about this system in graph
and here are a couple of my slides so
the way in graph works is to first
compile the open psyshock various
relational algebra and then transform
that relational algebra to a
representation that's incremental
maintainable and then use an incremental
relational engine to calculate the
result of those queries
in the last year we expanded in graph by
a lot of new features it now covers the
substantial fragment of the open cypher
language including sub-queries functions
aggregations some of the data
manipulation operations like create or
delete and there are some features
missing on the roadmap like merge remove
and more sophisticated expressions like
list comprehensions but it's getting
nice together and the state of in graph
almost allows us to evaluate the most
important javascript static analysis
queries so it's possible in theory we
have two papers on that one is about the
compilation of Scythia queries to
algebra and the other is on the
incremental maintenance of those
relational algebra expressions so this
is I think a very cool use case for in
graph so as Michael said his pet peeve
is software analytics and I think this
is an area that's very important we as a
developers we should strive to make
better software and others have realized
the need for this and the usefulness of
graphs for understanding code and
analyzing code so there is a tool called
JQ assistant it's basically a code
comprehension - that scans the software
turns into a graph and then you can use
arbitrary cipher queries to understand
the code and you can reduce the a set of
validation queries that you want to
check on each build there is a blog post
on this on the neo4j blog there's also
slicer which is closely tied to JQ a
system this is actually an interactive
front-end on top of JQ assistant and the
idea is the same you take a bunch of jar
files Java files and so on throw it at
the system it scans it loads it to the
database and then you can use this
interactive cipher editor to visualize
and discover your system it actually has
an eclipse based IDE
and as part of that idea it has a
grammar to provide an editor and funnily
enough as part of the ingre project we
managed to extend that grammar by some
new features we actually added some
features that were introduced in the
opus cipher language recently we added a
scope analyzer and you know you might
think that you're not using Eclipse so
this is not very relevant but actually X
text is quite independent from eclipse
so you can run it in the web UI so this
is an editor which allows you to
refactor cycle queries correctly if you
do refactoring operation you can
actually change the value of a variable
and then it will trace it back through
the query okay to wrap up if you found
all this interesting we have to this
works on days from 2016 and 2017 these
are very well-written and nice few
Illustrated works and I think they are
quite pleasant rates so all these are
clickable if you're interested and as a
conclusion I think it's fair to say that
interesting analysis rules at least some
of them require a global view of the
code so it's not enough to just scan a
file and do a standard linter style
analysis instead you should use some
graph representation for your source
code and property graph databases are
definitely a good fit for this they are
very expressive and the cypher clear
language is quite easy to use and easy
to understand and in particular these
are very good use cases for incremental
graph queries so if you make sure that
your system incorporates incrementality
multiple levels you can end up with a
system that's fast enough for real-time
answers these are the related resources
that you can find on github bear in mind
that these are all academic prototypes
so they work some of the time on some
use cases they are more like
proof-of-concept softwares and I would
like to thank the whole team that worked
on these students my colleagues
and Adam actually Adam Lipe is my old
friend and he's giving the talk in the
source code analysis dev room tomorrow
so if you came here just for the
JavaScript part and you were left
unsatisfied you can go there tomorrow at
4:30 4:20 and tantus talk thank you for
your attention
ok questions yeah we can talk we can
talk here or fine absolutely feel free
to come along after but any other
questions Hey ok ok so let me repeat the
question
the gentleman is from Firefox I
understand so yeah ok so the question is
what code repositories we have tried our
code on so you're probably concerned
about scalability obviously we went on
github and grabbed a couple of the
source code repositories most notably
there is treasure 8 which is a cloud
storage system so it's like Dropbox but
it's more focused on encryption and
security and their front-end library is
approximately 70,000 yeah 70,000 lines
of JavaScript code and that was the one
that took us like an hour to load and
then we optimized it and it went down
like to like five six minutes so that
was the largest one that we have used
and we had a lot of struggle to get a
parser that works well because we tried
the Bible parser and the problem with
that was that it doesn't really provide
scope information so
just DSD and it's very difficult to work
with but this logo here is the logo of
shape security the S on the figure and
they have very well written library
called shift - Java that's an ASD
builder but that has a lot of scoping
information that's a very nicely written
piece of software actually it's
beautiful Java code the problem with it
is it's not really maintained so it's a
well written and we have to maintain it
now because it's it seems abandoned and
we actually started to add the
ECMAScript 2017 features like async and
await - to the parser which is a work in
progress now okay any other questions
yes okay so the question was what do i
quantify as real-time well essentially
it should be quick enough for developers
to appear while they are working on the
same file so you're writing your file
make some changes you press you know
ctrl s command S and it should pop up
next to the other errors so it should be
sub-second ideally
yes yeah so the follow-up question was
different size of code repositories will
mean different different execution times
and whether there is like an average
dick should take well for this actually
we planned to use the in graph engine
more extensively the whole idea of in
graph is is to build a huge gash on your
code on on your queries and once you
have that cash you can do I won't say
constant time but very very quick clear
evaluations because you have all the
interim results of your queries cached
so essentially if you just want to
introduce a small change which you
usually do while developing it should be
very quick and it should stay within but
I I'm you know I'm not an experienced
JavaScript developer but I believe there
is also a need for queries that are
global like reachability stuff is this
Coast it is this piece of code still
reachable is this still correct from
typing perspective and so on so you can
think of of global no but just like more
motif detection so the question was
whether we try to identify patterns in
the graph and no but that's a very
interesting like a mixture of network
science and and source code on ethics so
that's a suggestion Thanks
okay one last question I think yeah yes
so Facebook flow actually uses custom
algorithms to make the evaluation very
efficient so I so from what I understand
it does a few things and does those very
well and very quickly but it's very
difficult to extend flow with your
custom rules so if you say that my
company policy is that you cannot do
this and that in the code and I want to
enforce this with my that's you know and
Jake your system does that for Java code
already so that's yeah yeah we could use
some help sir absolutely okay thank you
again
[Applause]
okay the last talk will have a general
tip of grass medical records and
like you just because you know we are
supposed to put them online like half an
hour before the tow I did that so I hope
it works
no no we I think we took
[Music]
what start Hey yes sir I asked you a few
questions okay okay yeah absolutely but
I think there's a dog here so maybe yeah
start soon
I think we can talk let me talk I'm just
gonna shut this down so no internet
connection absolutely actually my phone
is I am but it never works on my Linux
because of your right to thank you yeah
but it just never works for me
I should be besides out here yeah here
they are so so you should should be able
to see yeah yeah absolutely and I will
give the microphone to know so you'll
have
you