hi I'm an elephant from kultura an
architect in a a Kaltura
open source video platform and life just
like cats as well I'm going to talk
about a lessons that we learned during
the during the years in patois how to
overcome them they're a known limitation
that rustic guy is textual and how we
deal with tweeny a MIDI files using our
REST API so video is used today video
media generally is very significant in
content in the internet you need it for
it's affecting your course it's
affecting your traffic it's affecting
your storage it's affecting everything
that you do and the first is affecting
your API first we have to define the
enemy to know what's the problem I could
show you a graph the chart say of how
media used today in the Internet and how
it will be used in 10 years and of
course all the boring charts always show
the same it's always going up and the
conclusion is always the same you can't
ignore media anymore in your application
because media is used today not only in
mega companies media is used today on
your cell phone methods is today in
enterprise companies in universities and
so on so in a culture we are doing a we
aspire to do what we call everything
video everything video means that we are
doing that we are doing a capturing and
conferencing transcoding encryption
streaming both live and VOD ads teaching
client side and server side recording
playback distribution syndication and so
on everything is done in Kaltura using
API
everything is REST API which is text 12
so of the rest is HTTP and HTTPS
originated originally created for a
hypertext since the very beginning HTTP
supports MIDI files and we know
production to push files to the server
you know post action that can sorry post
method that able to to upload files to
the server get you can get progressive
tunnel you can get video or image using
get method and today you can even stream
video over HTTP using HLS VOD or live
rest though it's based on HTTP it's
fully text all it's a industry standard
and what we used to usually we use get
delete post put all these actions using
using text twelve path where textile
word string like if you need a complex
data structure you will need JSON or XML
whatever you choose even in the response
everything will be textual JSON or XML
of course there's a further simple
solutions in the industry and some
providers use a push to push files to
the server
the problem with approach is that it's a
process only what single file and you
don't have the ability to add to the
request complex data structure first you
could use a very complex data structure
in the path or in the query string but
it's not design for that and it could be
a very uncomfortable for the developer
to push complex data structure in the
cursing
[Music]
another solution is the form data again
the problem here are load supports
multiple files if the problem here is
that you don't have a native support for
complex data structure that like we do
in JSON or XML so I decided to
investigate
a bit further if I took two specimens of
these media providers home and after 10
years that I'm raising them I can tell
you that they took over my sofa my
kitchen
probably even my brain
ten years ago we started with a very
simple solution and the most simple to
get to media and from the Internet is
get and you can get you can get the file
using progressive download but usually
in the industry standard the action to
perform on the server are using HTTP
methods like put purge head get and
whatever I missed anyway it's very
limited realistic we have five or six
methods HTTP methods and you don't have
the ability to add a complex request to
the server what we did in patois
is that all our requests are sent using
post or gate doesn't matter how it's
arrived to the server and the action
itself what to do about the object about
the service that we are calling we just
added it to the URL which is a bit
different than the classic API classic
REST API and if the labeling class in
many different options and a of course
we support the regular crud create read
update delete and we also added another
standard power standard that called
serve the server instead of returning
the object to the XML or the adjacent
that represents the object it will
return the media that related with the
object as for upload we are using a post
of course and you can post more than one
file and unlike get that enable the only
path or incurring the post enable you to
send
another option that we have in order to
upload content to contour are you just
in front to control the location of the
file and control will pull the file for
you of course because we are talking
about REST API we have to manage the
status of the upload of the download in
this case the status if it's failed
succeeds with progress and so on so the
serve options enable us many different
content types
every object in control for example
media entering control contains few
video renditions use thumbnails close
caption files may be license file
different related files and a fella
would enable us to upload all these
first now we encountered few issues
while using it fell out of the first
problem with video is that it's huge
we have customers like Walt Disney Walt
Disney of course they have large videos
and you don't want to wait four hours
for the Apple to finish and then it
fails five minutes before it's a week
before it's done and then the entire you
have to do the entire process since the
beginning so what we did is to support
chunked upload you can upload the files
in chunk and on the server side we
combine all the chunks together to one
single file another problem that we had
is we have different data centers when
we call the API you don't know what data
center we are calling in fact a one
chunk could arrive to different data
center and then you couldn't combine
them together so we just redirect
according to the first server that the
first chunk got selected to all the
chunks from this moment on will be
redirected to the same data center in
its data center we have multiple
machines we just share this with solve
it with a shared disk chunks may arrive
in the wrong order and we manage it in
order to know what Schenck to put where
and another problem that we had is that
the falafel could take a long time you
don't want to hold the file and only
then to do something about it you don't
want to wait a few hours until the
entire video is uploaded and only then
associated it with with a thumbnail or
with a video and so on so what we did to
support to enable you to run the upload
and forget about it we're able to
associate the object the file before
it's created so we have some kind of
pointer to the file that is not created
yet using that pointer you will relate
it to the related to the object that it
relates to and later when the upload
will be finished automatically we will
use that pointer to associate it with
the object these are two examples for a
common API call in this case it's Apple
token get which returns an XML JSON
representing in the object you can see
that the JSON you can see that that's a
JSON because it's okay anyway trust me
Jason you don't see the other screen we
just send the JSON using content type
application JSON unlike when we are
sending files we will send a multi-part
form data with the JSON as one of the
fields separated with boundary from the
file itself
that's the binary data try to save trace
on this slide they don't have a lot of
binary data here now if any of you ever
tried to implement the API of WebEx or
Akamai or other companies that deals
with media it could be very difficult
not easy to implement the HTTP by
yourself and for that in Kaltura and you
generate automatically SDKs in multiple
coding languages in each coding language
we try to follow
the standard that the best part is in
this according language some coding
languages using a string path for their
it's represent files like PHP somewhere
with a fellow object streams buffer and
nodejs
c-sharp Java each one is different in
some places we even implemented
sometimes two different signatures of
this of each a method in order to
support a more than one standard in each
in one language its perform download we
assume that a customer don't want to
download the entire content intermedia -
it's a application memory but we unlike
the object that you want it in the
application memory the data the media
itself you don't want it in the memory
you don't want the binary data you
probably want to do something with it if
it's image that we want to present in
your HTML you can using our API instead
of returning the media itself we just
return URL that from using that URL you
can download or get the media itself so
every place that we defined in our API
that action server action returned MIDI
file or any file instead of returning
the file the SDK will return URL to that
file later we can use that URL is image
source or as to send it to the player
and so on this is a selected the PHP
which is symphonic language code is a
shorter here is example I'm using a file
path which is the standard in a PHP
creating upload token which is the
pointer to the file that will be
uploaded later and defenses is not
mandatory but if we're loading in chunks
it's very important because otherwise
the server want to know when is the last
if the last chunk arrives or not it's
comparing to the file size that we
defined in the beginning and I'm
creating the Apple token using client of
the token service add action
than the sin everything related to PHP -
sorry - HTTP and then using their
created the Apple token I'm just
uploading using upload action with the
upload token ID in the file path very
simple very easy to use the other hand
serve action you can send complex data
structure to the server our cultural
some params support scaling and trimming
and background in many different
parameters just chose to which the
height which are quite standard in this
case and I just called the serve action
with the complex data structure and what
I get in return
is remote URL the URL is the your that I
can use to get the contents later and in
this case I just downloaded the file to
the disk but I could do anything else
with that URL now a we have large
customers with large amount of media and
very soon we understood that just upload
and serve options are not enough so at
the beginning we edit a CSV which enable
you to to upload a CSV file which is I
will talk a bit more about it later
XML file which is more complex not so
easy for a human for human to it write
it the contrast structure because maybe
entry could be related with a lot of
metadata many different files families
media and closed captions and so on it's
not very easy for a human to write it we
support your folder drop folders could
be on the customer and servers in this
case we will see what using FTP SFTP SAS
three doesn't matter
and how we can watch the folders and see
what's going on on his server or it
could be on our servers and then the
cast
you
our customers our enterprise companies
many of them use WebEx that we just
added another ability to scan using
api's the WebEx server and we're
downloading the the files from WebEx
this is when I implemented the web-based
API it wasn't easy
okay since we as I said is the design
for human writing it's a supporting very
simple properties main midi file and
main some 1 samuel file and a few more
properties like name didn't write all
the properties but basically its name
description tags very basic properties
however that's ml and could be could
contain many different related objects
all of them could be in a single XML
item we enable the drawer father to drop
the files manually by humans which is
very simple for users just the drop of
the file and MIDI entry will be created
on our system but it wasn't enough
customers we wanted to add a tags or
category or user ID
many different information so we started
to enable them ragged to extract data
from the file name but it's again not
enough so we decided to support the XML
which is complex data structure with all
the related objects it was a lot of
metadata data a time-related the
information on the video and with one
different from the regular small that I
mentioned before this XML could relate
to files that worked in the drop folder
now in control we found that we have
many ways to upload content to the
server so we decided to associate this
content with the files in many different
ways
we have asset resource which is in fact
linked to another media that already
exists on the server dropped from the
final mentioned server file which is
integration between our systems
sometimes one system create a file on
the server uploaded file or total file
the token is two different ways that we
do that webcam remote storage which is
stored Ramos was that predefined for
that specific customer string it could
be relevant for authority for example if
you want to upload a certain you don't
have to upload the file you can just use
string resource and URL resource which
is of course just specifying what the
you are what you are at the list and in
order to associate the content with the
object you just define the resource in
this case it's URL so I had to set the
URL property and we call some assets set
content and associate this tenacity with
the resource and all these resources
supported in all our API is on all the
object associated with content you can
use each one of these resources and also
in the XML so the XML can use each one
of these resources also in order to use
each media doesn't matter how you are
ported it to Kaltura we also support
publishing the content to external
system using push we are pushing the
content to the media itself to remote a
system so few example soon and
syndication which is publishing
MRSS of our content and the external
systems downloading the content to their
to their systems these are the standards
we said that we support as you can see
there is no industry standard but the
most important one here is Kaltura are
not because we are cultural but because
Kaltura explain
was all the information that we have on
the media and you can apply XSLT on that
media and using that excessively you can
apply any different standard that exists
in the industry
and sometimes for small companies that's
what we do questions any question most
of that code is client-side examples
what do you have to have on the server
side to support that all our systems
internally using api's between them okay
but we know there are specifics after
burn the Kaltura server
presumably one for to our server use API
to talk to me another API said to
another server so okay so you saying
it's kind of symmetric yep another
question what do you support us back-end
storage we use our own data center and
we use our own shove this case Isilon
but we just IT thing it doesn't really
matter you could use any disk we used
NFS ER for many years it was a very good
as well for any specific amount of
content today we use ice alone there are
many providers in there in the market
thank you thank you
[Applause]