okay so I'm going to
you know who's going to be talking about
building high-performance Network
function
DPP okay hello my name is Ola Turin I'm
an alcoholic
oh sorry I was wrong meeting I'm a coder
I want to be a coder I guess I might
cheat code ran a network engineer so my
I got so inspired by the keynote this
morning with you know all the logo and
the empathy my wife has just been to
this presentation course and she told me
that I had 30 seconds to grasp the
attention of the audience and it really
didn't matter what you said after that
but if you didn't you know you missed
the first 30 seconds you could you might
as well just leave the stage
and you had to start with a story so my
story is that I come from proprietary
software in Cisco I've been there for 20
years at least 15 of those working on
proprietary software made me bitter and
cynical and despondent I guess
because life there was working on you
know with clearcase as your favorite
source code management system you know
the the development environment in
itself was was good you know you got
packets everything was you know run to
completion in with pointers everywhere
and you had full access to the packaging
you do whatever you you wanted to do the
packets your date United State to
stretch structures and stuff but then
you had to deal with all these platforms
which was one thing and the interfaces
to the platform so you know talk about
pain with Nick drivers you know we could
always you know walk over to the guy who
wrote the hardware but or design it but
I didn't really make life work very much
easier and then you had the other case
of you know we had to double commit all
your code fixes to 150 different
branches and you had to run lots of
sanity checking or each of those so that
would take you you know a month of of
the pleasurable work day and but then I
started working on VPP so VPP is is
open-source something come out of Cisco
but lots of contributors now
it's on github use Kita's as the sem use
more than tools modern way of doing
development don't have you talked to any
product managers were you know in my
previous despondent life you would spend
you know seven days arguing with someone
if you should write code and now you can
spend you know seven days writing code
and very little argument so that's I'm
very much in love with open-source I'm
in love with VPP but I think this way of
working is incredibly much more
efficient and much more fun and if
things aren't fun at least I built that
way that then I just shy away from it
whatever must you paid I might be a
first world problem but you get very
reluctant to do to fix bugs if it takes
you you know two year from you wrote the
code until it reaches the customer here
you can fix the bug push the button runs
through you know all the CI stuff in in
Jenkins and Garrett and and the code is
there and available for everyone to use
so that is a lot more fun I mean does
anyone in the room disagree with me on
that
no anyone want to go back to the old
world
I mean you have to look so jobs there
you know and so purpose of this talk is
to make you all interview PP developers
at least think about becoming
contributors to be PP or you know if you
want to do anything with packets of
course you can do it on snap as well I
mean snap and and bpp are you know quite
similar in the approach to life so go a
little bit more detail on on the VP
architecture and talk a little bit about
a DNF written in in VPP so let me just
diverse a little bit with I don't you
know I might take someone here now but
you know this nfe thing it's clearly
designed by
by someone on you know having retirement
homes in in South of France which is
where these guys are based it seems
insanely complicated I mean what are
they trying to achieve so I'm what I'm
working on this summer sort of down here
somewhere
and I'm sure there is some justification
for this possibly but yeah III never
figured it out that might be you know I
might if someone buys me lots of beer
this evening and and you try to inject
some clue into me why why this is is
really really necessary especially when
we're talking about this decompose
Network where you you make these network
functions into small small services I
mean there's all in a data center
there's all you know your Apache web
servers have doing a few sort of rest
calls do they have all this malarkey
around them I hope not
although you know like I could see to
Charles who really wants your own net
come from yang in models everything has
to be modeling in the you know of tools
tools up on tools Ubuntu to do a
regional approach for the fork for you
know building Network function doesn't
really that it was just take take
whatever hardware appliance you have
ported to and x86 platform stuff it into
a VM and and you're done and then you
can sort of do the same thing and with
you know decomposition that you take
take all the features and to those in
separate VMs and and declare victory but
what I'm trying to look at here is
really just take that micro service that
micro function just a few sort of bits
of packet mangling and move that on its
own so that's kind of this idea of
decomposition and disaggregation and you
can do that with VPP you can put it on
bare metal or in DM or in containers or
in eunuch URLs if you like
sort of the use cases I'm largely
looking at is with service providers who
need to ship quite a lot of traffic so
in the last case I'm working on now is
sort of building a six tear up bit cgn
like large gay laugh so it doesn't
really make so much sense to take that
VM tax or you know have a virtual switch
that then is going to route packets
through the VMS because you just turn
course enough providing value so some of
the models were you know looking at
would typically be you know you could
just run you to the bare metal server
then it looks exactly like all the other
prophets this is to make right more or
less but there are some great benefits
in in in sort of the deployment model of
containers and you can just three speed
a container within universe and have to
in store constraint that and deploy so
so perhaps this person for that
particular use case makes most sense
where we have a container bound directly
to fiscal physical interfaces and we're
currently about with VPP we currently
have we can build sa4 for you server
doing what about the terabyte a little
bit less than a terabyte per second and
that's what fantastic right we're about
a decade after hardware so you can buy
now a you know one ru server with 6,400
gig ports right 6.4 terabit per second
you know white box programmable with p4
so you know where where this is going
you know do you want to do everything on
general-purpose CPUs or not I don't know
I mean one benefit of competing with
this is that we we make the hardware
guys make their hardware a lot more
programmable as well which is cool so
what's VPP as said in a few earlier
presentations as well it's it's largely
framework for building forwarding
functions it can be a route or if you
want it to be a reader
it can be a switch if you only to be a
switch or it could be anything in
between written fully in C I think
Andrew your chenko did a a plugin in Lua
you know taking somebody ideas from the
Lua guys in the budget so you could look
at alternatives it scales linearly with
numbers core number of course you put on
it runs on arm x86 it's purely a data
plane so somewhere else should put the
head on it although that you know that
boundary is a little bit hard to to
distinguish at at some points you know
do you put R inside or outside you put
neighbor discovery inside or outside
where do you put your reaching protocols
so you can certainly run you know at
home I run VPP on its own without the
control plane just to see line
configuration that's my CP there works
fine very integration with the Linux
kernel so you can pump packets to the
Linux kernel to run your routing
protocols for example we can pump over
tap interfaces safe socket where our own
shared memory interfaces you can use if
you need high-performance or we can just
send a package over a UNIX domain socket
as well lots of tracing logging
encounter so it makes it quite easy to
after the fact see what happened
we have full tracing of all the you know
control plane today to play an API as
well so you can replay all the commands
that the some controller gave you so you
can easy to debug you know so VPP enough
senses an OS just without the bootloader
and I had unicorns in parantesis there I
really would like to put it on a unicorn
and had that bootloader and that would
make it its own OS but it has a
scheduler it has likely processes he's a
fairly self-contained useful an
application we also have hosts stacked
with our own TCP implementation SCTP is
also also coming and the main drivers
beautiful physical Hardware they come
from DP DK
we also have you know AF packet tap
mammoths and I think you know it would
make sense to put VPP on top of your AF
XD p as well that would be that would be
a cool thing to have a thing because
then you could you know you could split
off control plane traffic before it hit
VPP for example so you just left VPP
were doing the data plane and then you
could you know splitted displayed TCP
port 179 for BGP for example off in a
XTP and send a direct little disco so
you know the highlights this is more for
the people downloading the slide
afterwards so some of the main
differences in in the PP vs. Cisco IOS
which I used to work on was in iOS we
did scalar packet processing which i
think is what a Linux kernel does as
well which is take a single packet and
run it through every feature you could
imagine you know form rx 2 TX and you
would have lots of get an instruction
cache would you get lots of me sister
you don't flow that because the number
instructions you passed on a packet
would be very high so the difference
here is that you take a fairly limited
set of instructions run those on on up
to 256 packets and so the first packet
heats up the cache and then you run the
rest more or less for free and that also
has benefits for the for the data cache
because the tables you look up and you
look at one particular type of table for
that graph note we have lots of data
structures that are are you know
designed and optimized for packet
forwarding we don't use pointers we use
indexes or a dynamic arrays which are
very nice to program against each of
these graph nodes are relatively
independent and you could sort of
assemble the graph any which way you
like to achieve whatever forwarding
function you want of course they are you
know you can't combine your random graph
functions because I wouldn't necessarily
make sense but you can you can add on
graphs as you know as plugins and you
can inject
or program the graph in quite a few
places to you know to add new functions
that's not me I think and we have you
know pretty much all the features you
they expect from a from sort of a a
framework we have all the tunneling
mechanisms we have v4 v6 MPLS bridging
[Music]
sweat segments routing we have in banner
a.m. IPSec VPN Lisp support lots of
monitoring stuff a very easy and quick
to to write new functions for for v3 and
these are all written from scratch I
mean earlier today we had an argument
about you know how much do you want to
care about your legacy legacy code and
in some cases it is nice to just write
things again from scratch because you
tend to become better you know you
really get things right for the first
time you implement something and you
know perhaps on the fourth time you
implement are you've got it reasonably
right so I'll at least I'm not too
worried about you know you provide a
nice new and different and better
programming environment and then
implement things from scratch you know
carrying things with you legacy things
with you aren't necessarily a great
thing so I think you had some of this
with with Jerome which is I hate people
doing oh my god
a few people who do these things with
slides should have a you know they could
be in the sort of entertainment industry
or something have to be an engineering
but he's kind of sexy at all I mean we
we have a rx point here you put a gain
input for example spins round poles gets
256 packets in the frame since that too
depending you know if it's Hardware off
no Hardware on the eight and a type
people just send it directly drive to
six input otherwise it goes to Ethernet
input and it splits off here depending
on what ot2 type you have and it so
trickles through this this graph
checksum is already done by the by the
neck and then it goes to v4 look up and
you can do you know rewrite or you can
do load balancing in case you have you
know multiple adjacencies going to the
to the same destination in the field so
you end up you know with most orbit or
the frame are going more or less the
same path because what we've seen in in
real traffic is that you know the the
next packet pretty much looks are quite
likely to look like the one you're
dealing with now blah blah blah
so I was thinking I should show you one
natural function that that we built on
top of the EPP this is a very very
simple one I don't know if anyone knows
about India it so I'm also in the ITF
and we done lots of work on on v4 to
these six transition mechanisms and this
is one of these how can you make v4 live
forever mechanisms which tunnels v4 or
v6 but it splits the v4 address so if
this is an service provider and it has
you know a thousand you can take one
single v4 address and split it among a
thousand customers and each customer
then gets 64 ports of UDP and TCP space
no other transport protocol works well
she's so stupid that you can't use v6
well that's what you get and well so
that's a fun thing now with with you
know you know all these people who
refuse to move to v6 and and they think
that v4 will just continue to work the
way it's always worked but no absolutely
not I mean we're we're day by day making
v4 work worse and you just have to learn
to live with that so we're you know
seriously thinking about you know one of
the issues with these tunneling things
which I'm sure you guys have experienced
as well as fragmentation and we have a
draft coming up at the London IGF now in
March which basically said well don't do
fragmentation because it's yeah it sucks
I mean throw your fried moves away
anyway so which makes you learn people
learn application developers learn very
quickly when you throw all the packets
away then it sort of try something else
but this is essentially you know a v6
only access network v4 packet comes in
here you look at the destination address
and the port you do either an
algorithmic mapping order or a table
lookup figure I'll go to these six
destination addresses send it here and
then this runs a traditional lat for
four and the graphs nodes for that are
are represented here so you get Ethernet
input you do a bit more
before checking the packet we used to be
for lookup table define the particular
mapping table to use do the mapping
which generates a v6 packet do v6
rewrite and shape the packet back out
again and really you know looking at
this as a micro function it's you can
skip a lots of things right because this
packet just loops around it goes into
your it you're you know graphing comes
back out again this you know same
interface or there's no complicated
routing function you need to do here
this is just a bump bump in a wire so
this is a few hundred lines of code 150
lines of code or something
and for a particular project we we did
I'm sure the control plane was a million
lines of codes it doesn't necessarily
make too much sense but as you see you
know the only complexity here is what to
do with fragmentation because a
fragmented packet you don't see the TCP
header and you can't do routing here
unless you see wave for information so
you do virtual reassembly and you have
to deal with fragments let me see
so I thought that for fun should just
show you the code so this is oh this one
no that one no that one no that one yes
so this is the main graph function and I
can do that I have a Mac I can do
anything
oh my god it's that big enough yeah
so here I get a frame and then left from
tells me how packets there are in the
frame then I spin through an outer loop
through all those packets and I have one
in the loop here
whereas been through two packets at a
time so I you know it's quite simple I
have you know few buffer pointers she
indexes the buffers solely for head
during these six header information and
support these are tcp or UDP ports and
then next tells me where do I expect
these packets to go next in the graph so
they go to the v6 lookup then to keep
the the memory hierarchy busy so now I'm
processing in this loop I'm processing
packet 0 & 1 but while I'm doing that
I'm already
prefetching information and the headers
for packets 2 & 3 so they're ready the
next time they come around the track
then I would set up a few pointers here
- to the next next frames so these are
the two next are the frames of in this
case ip6 lookup so I just assume that
things are going to go well that I can
send this to the IP 6 lookup graph note
that might fail and then I will unwind
this later here I just get the pointers
from the the buffer index I get the
heaviest v4 headers for both of these -
and you look up in the ins model table I
have to figure out to get a pointer to
some domain informations that which is
specific for which basically finds which
v6 user this is and then I find the TCP
ports
you know decrement the TTL to lots of
let's see and then
here I'll just do the algorithmic
mapping which is basically take you
thirty two thousand four address you
sixteen is a these people are there a
little bit of big magical all that stuff
and I return you the the first half of
of the resulting these six address and
then again I have a similar function to
get the v6 suffix then I just knew my my
buffer point or I'll stop all that
information into a v6 header or to these
exciters actually like so I'll do
everything here for for two packets at a
time and then I do a little bit of
checking to see if if what I expected to
happen was was correct and then I
evaluate the buffering and Q both of
those two buffers and then I go back up
again and then I have a similar loop
just for the single packet you know if I
got 255 packets right there will be one
left over and I do the same thing for
that one as one and that does the sense
essentially all the code required for
that for that you know micro function if
you like right so that's just an
introduction know how you know vehicle P
code can look like code is on github and
it's all open source or we do go into
that repository and yes any question
yes yep
so so actually the tiny delay it could
be could you repeat the question
oh sorry yeah so the question is that
you loop is it you know really worth it
you know what gains do you see for that
I mean we do see significant gains doing
juleps actually to the extent that we're
doing quad loops in the v4 lookup node
now I also do remember the first you
know when I go to CVP Pecola hope gee
there must be a prettier way of writing
this could I be you know domain-specific
language Oh could you somehow make this
less than some some guy who invented
this de boracay yes you know lots of
Emacs skeletons doesn't give you all the
outline of this and I know I would
always write the single packet loop
first and then when you optimize you and
go back in and do the do loop one issue
is studied it you know so much CPU
specific right so you might not get a
total it might be great for you know the
latest it was eons it might not be the
same on a different platform so I yeah I
I get your point right it would be I
looked an improvement if this could be a
lot more flexible and you could you know
even dynamically adjust this right if
you or at least generate code in it in a
better way yeah if nothing else thank
you
[Applause]