we're going to talk about carton most of
them I'm talking about is me using
carton however I'm also abusing docker
and in really interesting way and a way
that I'm a little ashamed of and I'm
also abusing circle CI and so both of
those are in in the talking topic so
good morning pearl today I want to talk
about how you manage dependencies I have
been managing dependencies for various
years in various situations mostly what
I talk about these days is bugzilla but
I want to mention that I've actually
worked on other things before I've
worked on a thing called lon POS which
if for the French speakers in the room I
think is an amusing name this was
created by an American and the since we
were in Belgium their translation would
be this and but it for the English
speakers we're since we're in English of
course it's called the ass POS and which
is really funny because you might not
know but if POS is frequently an acronym
for that so it's also well that a piece
of poo so packaging I've done I did
packaging when I worked on this on this
point-of-sale machine I did
Debian packaging and oh and there's one
more thing there's some of the worst
Perl code that I had ever seen this is
how it rounded numbers so I did
packaging on this thing I used used D H
make pearl and I I made I think that was
something a couple hundred different
packages things that weren't in Debian
at the time and I needed them and I did
a lot of work on this but this was all
for the developer machines because
everyone else was using well the
production machines they looked like
that and they ran sent ran Red Hat for
not Red Hat Enterprise Linux for like
older than that like Red Hat for this
was in the early 2000s and but the cool
thing is if someone else worried about
rpms so I didn't I didn't have to worry
about that
I knew about C pen to rpm but I never
had to deal with it and at the time at
the time I was doing this I was very
much in the camp of using the system
Perl and using are using packaging that
the system provides for all the apparel
modules even if you have hundreds of
them so then I joined infinity and I
worked with some really cool superheroes
and the
infinity today we didn't use a packaging
meant for most of the projects that I
worked on anyway we just used C pen or
CPM and it was really great I did notice
that when I was installing stuff for
this work code that most of the modules
came from this man who cannot be here
but I like my first day when I'm here I
was I've been sawing like 70 things that
are all from one person it was it was a
bit interesting when I made that
correlation but then I started working
for Mozilla and that was really exciting
like I really love working for Mozilla
Mozilla is wonderful I got to work on
bugzilla which is the bug tracker and
it's incredibly important and it's it's
difficult to characterize my experience
is working at Mozilla on bugzilla it's
it's incredibly difficult it's like it's
a whole complicated situation but it's
been fun so bugzilla I kind of provide a
little bit of background about why the
cart while using carton for this was a
uphill battle and so I want to tell
about my first impressions for using for
using it my first actual impression for
using for doing bugs all four years ago
was that I had to learn bzr what the
hell is VCR it's some was some kind of
source control thing I had to use it for
about a year but we migrated off of that
we're on get now the second thing as a
Perl programmer that's like had been
working for people that do like modern
Perl stuff for like Steven that I was
this check setup thing that's in the
Bugzilla directory and I was like what
is that is it like make file dot PL no
it's not like make file the appeal how
do we specify dependencies bugs ill had
his own way of the specified
dependencies which was a constant
defined in some module and it was kind
of interesting because specify the
package name the module name and also
the distribution name as far as I know
usually those there's not those on a
one-to-one mapping like in the pause
indexer but most people don't care about
the distribution name they care about
them they depend on a particular package
and if the package moves between
distributions that's fine this actually
is a problem Bugzilla when lwp split out
some of their modules but I do rest so
the next headache was install module dot
PL which was this thing that the
documentation recommended to not use but
they still shipped with it what it was
was a custom Sipan client that's
actually being generous hi and I've had
copy and pasted parts of Sipan P
and it installed stuff into the
directory on the route called lib so I
wanted to point out that the code for
bugs though actually still now until Tom
submits a patch to me that to fix this
is in the route and everything that we
every third party dependency was in Lib
now that is actually kind of backwards
and that is the code that accomplished
that we had a really fun experience with
Moo because back in an older version of
Moo Moo thought that all of our code
that was like a library and all of the
code in Lib was first-party and so
warnings and things were turned on the
wrong way those that got fixed though so
since then I've been working on creating
new problems and one of my I think the
new problems are good they're kind of
like an investment you get rid of the
old problems and you have new ones and
so the first thing I want to talk about
that was a problem that I've solved and
created it was can inconsistent
environments and then we had
inconsistent environments for my bugs
all the bugs I'm talking about is the
insult it's Bugzilla mozilla.org to be
clear but they it's most of the most of
what I talk about is not important to
that but production runs on sent OS 6
actually I think it runs on Red Hat
Enterprise Linux 6 but close enough it
uses our PM's
and somebody else built the RPMs as in
my career that's been the case so I want
to actually thank fubar who has been had
been working on Bugzilla rpms before I
came there and basically knew a lot
about what the dependencies were more a
little I think in some cases a bit more
than the developers did themselves so
then the developers use fedora so if you
have like you have a VM on your desktop
using VirtualBox or VMware something
like that it would be running Fedora and
this is the other two people that were
working on Bugzilla I think actually
sometimes your reason sent to a seven
but Fedora sent to a seven not the same
as production but it gets better because
the way they install modules we
sometimes we install our PM's and
sometimes we use CPM of course the Hugh
CPM I think originally they would have
to use the cPanel eCPM but I specified
every module which you could get by
repeatedly running check set up and
collecting the modules that it requires
at some point there was a shim to module
build
and at that point they could use CPM but
it was still kind of really bad so by
the way continuous integration we've
been running continuous integration test
for a long time and those ran and sent
to s7 which is good to be one version
ahead of your production environment but
then a thing happened there's this
repository called version control tools
which is a bunch of tools related to
Firefox development and so on and a
co-worker of mine created a pest thing
oh there's a typo there
no it's not that bad created a testing
suite to test an application that we
were using called review board against
our bugs oh because we had this
integration stuff in it and so he went
and he created we had a docker container
at this time but he didn't use that he
went and created his own based on Ubuntu
1404 and then at some point we also had
Amazon Linux although this has gone away
so we had about five different systems
and each of them were installing Debian
and so I see pen packages in a different
way including Debian ones and that was
kind of fun so just to relax for a
moment I didn't actually set out to
solve the problem of having a bunch of
different environments
I want to didn't want to solve it I had
a different problem my problem is that
laptops don't like me and I have
hardware failure all the time not that
literally all the time but like enough
that it's been annoying so oh snap my
laptop's broke that's annoying how long
is it gonna take me to reinstall
Bugzilla well a day or two about two
years ago this would be a true statement
so at some point I started disusing
because we had the module build shim on
our own dependency specification I
started using that and then to get it to
work so I didn't have to modify every
file because at one point I was
modifying every file to use local Lib
every entry point into the code which is
like every script and every not every
CGI because we're actually just a mod
Perl application that's pretending to be
CGI but yeah so I tried patching all the
files with local it didn't work
I asked at some point I do remember
asking can we use local Lib and this is
at the time when they were there were I
was just kind of junior on the team and
I asked and the answer was was pretty
much no
so we don't use local Lib so what I did
ask is how about I add the local Lib
Perl 5 directory 2 to the top of every
to every non module file and that patch
got applied so I did that so we weren't
using local Lib but we were loading all
of the modules from the local directory
the same which is the same directory
that Carton uses by the way I had wanted
to use Carton but I didn't bring it up
until much later so we're not using
local Lib but we have local Lib local
Lib Perl 5 in our path
next thing I want to bundle I want to
use I want every module that I'm using
nicely packaged and I want to use carton
I've been looking forward to doing this
I had used carton before previous to
Bugzilla and I was excited to get back
to having like a complete specification
of all my dependencies which Cartman if
you do not what I am if you do not want
carton provides we will have a bit of
time for Q Q&A on that but anyway so the
carton documentation disagrees the
carton documentation says that a you
can't use the system Perl if it's on
certain system so this basically means
Red Hat because they split off core
modules it also says that you can't run
it without using cart and exec and this
is also not true and I think this is
known and agreed to not be true however
a is basically true like you really
shouldn't use the system Perl - you can
if you try to use the system perl with
carton and install stuff it's going to
get confused and it's going to think
modules that are core modules are not
core modules and it's it's just not
going to work but you can fix this so
what you can do is you can build your
own Perl that's the same version as the
system one so this is a script called
Bill a Perl bit using Perl build the
script is called build vanilla Perl
which I wrote in duh it's a little bit
hard to see but this is taking the Perl
version number and running Perl build on
whatever that version is with some flags
that I think are vaguely compatible with
what the distraught was testing this on
worked with multiple distros actually so
then you you have this you have your own
Perl you install carton to that into
that Perl and then you have cartons all
of its dependencies and you have carton
fat pack itself that means that the cart
and executable gets put into
directory inside the local directory
that it manages and then you just get
rid of all of that we throw away all of
our hopes and dreams and we start using
the system pearl again so we use the
system pearl to reinstall Carton this
time hold on missus I and this time we
in the bottom part of the slide which
capsule it's the previous steps we rerun
the cart and insult using the fat pack
version cache deployment basically
prevents it from looking at the internet
and looking and only looking at what his
head has already downloaded so it has
that complete specification that it got
from the real pearl in the system I have
not the real pearl but the the pearl
that's not messed up so this is pretty
good this this is a few of bit of
annoying steps though and I think that
it would be frustrating to do this for
five different systems so I wondered
about abstracting it I kind of think
that that we could use something like a
function that kind of is a function over
the operating system over the Linux
distribution and the Perl version and
the list of dependencies and it could
spit out what the what it is so it would
be nice to write such a function however
it's not really possible but we have
docker so we can do something similar to
writing a function that operates on a
system I don't know how to do slides
apparently
there we go so how do we do this well
bad form there we go i parent lead made
sub slides and subsides are a thing I
don't understand how it works so there's
I wanted to modify the dockerfile
language I thought this would be fun to
create like a dockerfile function that
is parameterised over the git repo and
then when you have that dockerfile
function you could have your set up the
base system to match whatever production
looks like and then run it but I I
didn't actually end up doing that like I
thought about it but I did something
kind of worse I kind of wrapped docker
in Perl well I made a DSL that generates
a docker file and that lets me use Perl
subroutines to to have consistent to
have repeatable repeatable environments
this is hard to read but basically the
first few lines are all the setting up a
sent to a6 environment that matches our
production and then it calls this
subroutine down at the bottom to build
all of the dependencies and the end up
dock the docker file you end up with you
can't definitely not read but I want to
show for length is it's that the same
thing is possible for a bun too and then
the same thing is possible for sent to
s7 and then so we have these pearls
files that generate docker files and
then of course do want to use make to do
the build process so this builds docker
files and then it builds a docker
container and then it runs the docker
container and in running the docker
container it produces all of tarball of
all the dependencies as previously
specified so then I would just have a
target make upload that uploads it to an
s3 bucket each of the the tar balls for
each of the different systems and I just
need an s3 bucket and I asked our ops
guy I said hey fubar would you never
would you like to never have to make an
RPM for a Perl module again and wouldn't
you know it within about 10 minutes he
had me an s3 bucket and so we do that
and we updated the production pushed
scripts to pull down
the tarball for every deployment and
that was school now meanwhile version
control tools which was using their own
thing in Ubuntu
we got them patched to do that there's
the thing there there were they made it
significantly shorter in lines but it
also made it faster so the builds for
testing the review board stuff would the
slowest part was Bugzilla and the the
slowest part of that was building all of
the dependencies using Sipan am it took
I think 20 minutes 30 minute basis leo I
save 30 37 minutes off of the bit of
their build times and also their build
stopped breaking when I added new
dependencies which I had never done but
if in theory if I added new dependencies
their stuff would break it also made our
test run faster because I upgraded our
testing suite from this sounds weird but
from sent OS seven to send to us six so
that it was actually the same as
production because I couldn't update
production but I could make continuous
integration match production and I think
it did Amazon Linux docker images later
after someone else created there there
used to be docker images that matched
Amazon Linux but now there are and so we
shoved 270 modules into one carton and
it fit a bit like a horse in a cup
that's not a metaphor and that's that's
the first that was the first battle the
second result was once I could use
actually use Sipan modules we could have
fight smaller battles and have bigger
wins so for instance the time in Moscow
was wrong
the our bug tracker is global we have
users from all over the world including
in Russia and the time zones hit change
at some point and the fixture that was
updating date time timezone so that was
good I also got to use Moo I used move
for generating content security policies
and as it is now my co-workers are
starting to write new code that's using
Moo in Bugzilla and they're actually
enjoying it which is really good we were
able to pin DB D my sequel to prevent
things from breaking which happened
recently we upgraded Jason and Jason XS
I realized that we should probably have
maybe be using cPanel Jason XS which is
on my road map all of that's pretty
boring but basically I could update
stuff and updating stuff was something
that I had wanted to do for about - this
was two years ago so I had been wanting
to update stuff for about two years but
more exciting and doing the moving up
then updating stuff is shipping features
so I had a feature request which was
make all the users of bugzilla hate me
then by making their passwords harder
and so this was this is a very important
high level request from like important
people that wanted to make sure we were
secure so I asked a is switches
enterprise information security what do
you recommend how do you want me to make
passwords secure and they recommended a
sea library not recommended but they
said that they were using a sea library
and I'm like oh cool is there a pearl by
need for that and as it turns out there
is there's a pearl Bonnie for that it
needed an additional feature which I
which I patched and I want to thank
Sherwin the author of that module
because I was able to ship a feature
that was important to a lot of people in
about a month
and that's that's pretty good so but
they know what's even faster than like
shipping features faster and having
being able to use new modules what's
faster than that is having a development
environment that you can throw away and
Cree create as many times as you want so
I at some point created a vagrant
install it was pretty easy to to get it
going because all the dependencies were
already packaged for sent to us six for
production so I just made a vagrant VM
that matched production exactly and that
was pretty good the stats were like the
previous year there were about three
three ish people contributing on average
to on a given month to two bugs about
mozilla.org in the last month we've had
eleven and I think that that's actually
really good now I'm like a majority of
those commits but the second majority of
that is like half half again as much as
well it's a nice it's actually nice
curve what you would expect pretty much
so we're actually pretty darn agile now
we accept pull requests people can set
up dev environments we've contributed
we've participated in both outreach in
google Summer of Code which meant
hundreds of new people not hundreds but
dozens of new people have tried
installing and getting a dev environment
working so we're really happy now the
the next problem was we have a cloud
migration pending so our current
production is Santo by six on
like machines in the data center and
that's got to change pretty soon and so
there are people working on that and
they had some requirements 12 factor
yada yada Batman but they needed our app
to be a docker container and they
strongly strongly hinted that it should
be circle CI for running our tests and
for building a docker image so I stared
at this task and I thought well this is
a good chance to clean up some stuff
so the ocker they were recommending
circle CI
the first version and they had
experience with that but right as I was
doing this circle CIA two had come out
and it had a lot of shiny features
including the ability of running docker
containers it's not literally running
inside docker containers but you can
create and build docker containers from
what amounts to a arbitrary docker
container and so the gamal that you have
to write because this is all modern and
basically engi in G's gamal language is
one of them more popular cloud languages
at this point I think so here is a bit
how we do a build its notice it sets up
form a docker environment and it builds
docker everything is fine you probably
wanna see what that docker file looks
like so there's the entirety of the
docker file nothing to see there very
boring I'm kind of hiding the fact that
there is a cut off by the projector
there is a thing that says from Mozilla
b-team BMO slim so BMO slim is our base
image and I kind of I'm obviously
alighting a lot of stuff in there so I
should tell you what that looks like
that is this hard to read em I wish I
could have changed the font colors ahead
of time but this is the steps that are
required to build the dependencies so
this is what was previously in the make
file the make file by the way is gone we
don't use the make file to do any crazy
things I'm not generating doctor files
from Perl anymore either but these steps
run so let's take a closer look so that
you can actually see the docker
environment gets to be based on an image
which is our base image of sent OS 6 and
it runs a set of steps which you can see
in closer detail here that does a check
out of the code it installs
all of the RPMs that the system of our
PM's like lib see stuff and then it does
build prepare build stage one build
stage two and then it makes it hard ball
so build prepare build prepare is a
simple script that's basically doing the
downloading Sipan sorry not only in perl
build and carton and then it's also in
compiling those things so then build
stage one uses the real pearl the nice
one that we just installed to do the
previously mentioned step i think the
code is a bit cleaner than the old make
file stuff build stage two is when we
remove everything and do that all again
and then this kind of long spiel here is
how we package all of that up I'm
actually packaging up a bit of metadata
about what system libraries are linked
to any shared objects that are in the
Perl directory and I check for that
later to prevent the case of missing of
a mismatch in the current in case we
could have a mismatch between production
and this build environment in the future
that will be impossible but at the
moment it's still possible so I make
that check so this is how we build VMO
slim which is once again you can't see
very well but it's our on they will be
on the slides you it's know based on the
docker image so I'm running a docker
image for running docker commands and
then inside there it's copying it
starring up I'm sorry it's untiring the
tarball that it had previously built in
the in the other step and it's putting
that in a directory so docker workflows
have these directories that you can put
stuff in and share between build
processes as so technically I'm still
uploading a tarball to s3 but that is
for the existing production environment
and if if all goes well I won't have to
do that anymore and the entire build
pipeline will be building all the
dependencies and just putting them in
the container and uploading the
container to docker hub and everything
will be fine
so build times there's a bit of a split
here that I should explain so there is
the stuff that where I'm building and
doing the interesting things with carton
is in the director in a repo called BMO
systems and this is mostly because it
takes a lot of time
technically I only need one branch of
this for production for the deuce down
here I only need the central s6 to the
BMO slim pipeline but that one alone
takes 20 minutes so the dependencies
don't change that often so the
dependencies live in outside of the
master copy of the dependencies is the
repo but there's a cached copy that's in
another repo that is generated for each
system because the actual requirements
can vary between a bun to and sent OS
and so on like you don't have this exact
same set of dependencies also because
you don't have the exact same version of
Perl I think there are three versions of
Perl at play in this arrangement so
they're separate but when you what we as
a result of this the build times for
everything else are quite small I think
the longest test is our selenium test
which is running a full Firefox browser
and that's me and that takes a bit more
time because it's it's actually hitting
a few I know hundreds of pages on thing
to make sure it's not broken our build
time though because everything's
technically already built it's just a
minute so I kind of like that I would
like to show you one of the bits about
this circle see our thing that is nice
so to spin up our testing environment I
can specify an any number or some
arbitrarily large number of docker
containers that we'll be running so when
this is running we have our code running
in one box one container we have my
sequel we have memcache we have the
selenium thing having a container run
selenium is really nice because I don't
have to worry about the details of
updating that we used to have all this
run in one container and back before we
were using circle and that was not good
so that that said it's obvious that
there's a bit of them and it must be a
manual step between these two
repositories because if I just add
something to the make file dot PL of
bugzilla then how does it get into BMO
systems and into the multiple files so
I'm going to show you what that looks
like it's still a painful process but
it's not that bad so for instance we
edit them make file that PL adding in
the new dependency and we have to use
make so I run make and with which Brandt
and the sets who make variables the
branch and the repository that I want it
to look at because obviously it can only
have the dependencies for a particular
repo at a given time which does makes
deploying this a little bit difficult
you have to have some planning but still
you run the make it runs and compiles
things creates two tarballs
and then I do a commit and I have new
new Sipan file for each distribution and
a new Sipan file dot snapshot for each
distribution which those don't change so
the process here is actually feeding
back in on itself because the c-pen file
there's an artifact of the CP of cartoon
called CP n follow that snapshot that
gets fed back in which prevents me from
upgrading packages when unless I
explicitly do that which is not shown
here there's a separate process for
actually upgrading something that's not
that bad and it is documented but it's
still this is not ideal but having five
at this point actually only two
different systems is also not ideal so
that is the monster but I wanted to also
mention that in that last patch I have
I'm adding mojolicious as a dependency
for my Bugzilla for a couple of reasons
and if this interests anyone and they
would like to to do things I'm all ears
and I should have a sufficient amount of
time for questions and I suspect that
there should be questions and I have all
of the code opened in my IDE for those
so questions
yes I'm gonna use mojolicious to
implement off too but I'm also going to
have like as an endpoint that I can move
my great features to for instance the
next thing I could do is we need to use
JWT I would like to use mode mojo JWT
for email confirmations instead of the
current token system that we're using so
I can either I'll ask myself questions
if no one has any questions but yes
the orchestration is outside of my so I
just make a application that's roughly
twelve factory and the orchestrator that
that the the other part of the team uses
is up to them I don't think they're
using an Orchestrator right now actually
but it theoretically it could I've
actually got this running myself on
kubernetes so it's not hard it's just
not it's not not in my responsibilities
at the moment and if you just speak just
yell if you're if I don't appear to be
noticing that you're asking a question
yes yep yeah and there's the one that
lee johnson wrote i haven't played with
it i've looked into a proof-of-concept
disusing mojolicious itself and then
i've done another separate
proof-of-concept of tying it to bugs off
the system so I know that these two
things will work and I haven't played
through them together yet but Lee
Johnson's Oh the fact that he has
packaged that up for mojolicious
and it seems like less work than using
the underlying thing is the reason that
I want to depend on mojolicious because
I want to I don't want to have to do a
lot of work yep are there any questions
about I think that it would be
instructive and I'll just show you I'm
going to show you the entire config file
for built for the entire workflow that
generates the the carton files and how
are we on time what ten perfect this is
exactly amount of time I was hoping for
a little bit more questions after all of
this madness but this is fine so the
entire we have just under about about
two hundred lines of Y Amal the world's
best scripting language and
and I think that should be visible on
the screen how's that and a much larger
font look at that that's amazing
there we go Oh
I wish I had a Linux machine in front me
I would know how to do that then but
then I won't be able to see it bingo
and now I need to decrease the font size
okay
so oops what was not clear when I lied
it over this which I did because I was
worried about time is that each of the
so forth in the current case you have
sent to us and a bun to sent to us and a
bun to task each run and they deposit
something in a workspace the workspace
is shared with the upload task and then
the upload tasklist uploads the tarballs
to an s3 bucket specified in the bottom
of this is the basically the
relationship between each of the tasks
and as you can see here the tasks are
also filtered on only certain branches
so we only look at the master branch and
the the jobs that get executed are as
follows or wait that's for that's for
builder so we have also builders which
is something you don't need to worry
about no one should use that that's
actually so builders is a hack to make
it so that I don't have to always
reinstall everything when generating a
new Sipan file and a new Sipan file dot
snapshot but in the New York in a ideal
situation you will only have one
environment and you won't have different
environments to do ok by the way if you
are doing this as of last week sent to
s7 when you are installing it on when
you are using it on Circle C I will
break because of some bug and the way
they're running docker so if you if you
need to do a yum update in a sent to a 7
environment you should do that and build
your own docker
build that name it and upload it to
docker hub and use that because running
the yum update inside circle CI will
just crash but there is everything these
I actually kept the existing when I did
this I kept the existing CI docker
container around which was called BMOC
I basically had no interruption of
service while doing this we just turned
off eventually turned off the LTI and
turned on the new CI but all of that can
go away now as well so there's really
just three containers in play three
build processes and play in here now if
there are no other questions and I think
I am going to be done literally no other
questions no other questions about the
dockerfile language either