okay so I'm Todd gamblin I am going to
talk about compiler dependency
resolution in spec or rather how
compilers affect dependency resolution
inspect this for some context I'm from
Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory
it's this square mile facility in
Livermore California it's about an hour
from San Francisco it's maybe 6,000
people who work there we do national
security stuff for the Department of
Energy and we are pretty invested in
high-performance computing and so that's
where that comes from
this is Sequoia it's a 1.5 million core
system the cases are off so you can see
the network on there these are the kinds
of machines that we have to try to build
for and it's not pleasant and so that's
where we're spec has come from specs a
general-purpose from source package
manager it's inspired somewhat by
homebrew and Nix and we're like I said
we're targeting HPC and scientific
computing it has a growing community
these are lines of code by different
organizations in the packages by
overtime and so you can see that like
I've been told about 2015 it was all
Livermore and then we started getting
contributions from all sorts of people
after that and it's been it's been going
well the goals of spec are focused
around flexibility we're not trying to
be a stable of distro yet we're mostly
focused on helping people get things
built for high performance on big
machines and also running on laptops and
other places that scientists need to run
and come out of the blue x clusters we
want to make it easy to build packages
with lots of different compilers
different compiler options different
flags to swap compilers in and out of a
build and to swap implementations of
libraries so like MPI and other ABI
incompatible libraries we want to be
able to swap those in and out easily
from a built and and so the end goal is
to help scientists in the Department of
Energy and elsewhere actually get their
software up and running on fairly exotic
architectures how do we do that we have
a CLI syntax that's supposed to make it
easy to install a package lots of
different ways in the base case it looks
an awful lot like another package
manager you might say stack install MPI
leaks that's a tool that we developed
for analyzing MPI programs a little more
and it's fact should do something
sensible if you say that if you want to
get more specific you could say install
MPI League's at version 3.3
so you can specify the custom version
you can say what compiler you want to
build it with so you can say % GCC @ 4 7
3 4 that you can add build options that
are exposed by the packages you can
inject C flags into the build and then
this syntax is recursive so you can
basically apply the same constraints on
your dependencies so that's saying I
know that thing depends on n pitch
somehow so build it with M pitch version
3.2 and build that with GCC so how does
this look from the package perspective
we're trying to keep that simple to the
fact packages this should look familiar
to anyone who's ever seen a homebrew
package they're just Python classes it
has a simple Python DSL and what's going
on here is all the stuff at the class
level is metadata this is so this is
your homepage URL these are the
different versions that you could build
with the package and also the hashes
that you could download them from we can
sort of try to extrapolate these URLs
from this one these are the dependencies
and so this is C make it's a built
dependency these are all the link
dependencies and you can see that you
can provide those same constraints that
you can provide on the command line to
the actual dependency so you can say
that this thing depends on boost 1.42 or
higher with the multi-threaded option
the the methods the actual instance of
the package is basically an installer we
call these methods on it to get things
installed and so all this does really is
it it deals with CMake and it calls make
and make install so we passed the
dependency tag in here through the spec
and so you can refer to all of your
dependencies in some fixed configuration
from inside the package file the idea is
that by the time you get to the install
method we've already worked out what the
dag should look like so you shouldn't
have to do any searching around on the
system we just tell you what to build
and you translate it into build
instructions
the other thing inspect that we do to
enable that swapping is we have virtual
dependencies and so the idea is that you
depend on an interface something like
MPI or maybe people are more familiar
with like jpg where there's JPEG and
JPEG turbo those are interfaces and
they're not implementations and so in a
lot of package managers you can only
depend on specific packages here you can
have one package that provides MPI and
they can provide it at different
versions when they're at different
versions so I can say I'm
and that bitch I provide NPI version too
when I'm at 1.9 or higher and then the
actual packages like this one here you
depend on MPI at a particular version
and so it's fact that's the job of
looking at this dag saying oh it depends
on MPI what version of MPI does it
depend on and I'm gonna pair it up with
one of these providers and you can also
specify a specific provider on the
command line and so it's really easy
with this to type a bunch of commands
and essentially get lots of different
builds of the same package to compare
and in to sort of settle on a nicely
tuned one to do the compiler swapping we
build with compiler wrappers this is
kind of like homebrew shims these are
basically little wrappers that add
include library and our path parameters
to the things that stack built and so
what this guarantees you is that all the
libraries that you build masback all the
executables and things they know where
to find their dependencies which can be
useful if you're building lots of
versions of things and you don't know
you know which which things you what you
were doing at Build time when you get
around to running things to manage all
that versioning the way that versions
work in spec is I mean we have the
actual version of the package but we
have those other options as well you can
think of a stack version as this entire
dependency tag for a project so this
would be the version of MPI leaks plus
all of its dependencies plus their
metadata that stuff turned into a
document and then hashed and so then you
take that hatch and we give every
package that we install a unique
installation directory like this and
essentially the libraries in each of
these directories they know which other
directories within the same install
route to find their dependencies we like
our path a lot because the rationale is
you knew what you were doing when you
built the package or at least the
package manager did and by the time you
get around to running it it's you know
we don't want to put it on you to
remember all the dependencies and things
that you and where they live for these
packages which is what people have done
manually for a long time so we're trying
to fix that the dependency model centers
around something that we call
concretization in what mode most package
managers I guess called dependency
resolution the concretization it's kind
of like dependency resolution except for
like I said we're solving for more than
just package inversion you can depend on
something plus an option you can depend
on something
with a particular compiler and so the
constraints can be a little more
extensive throughout the packages so
what happens when you type that on the
command line if you say install MPI
leaks with with this dependency at that
version and it's other dependencies
another version is we build an abstract
dag with some of the constraints on it
and then we take that we run it through
the concrete Iser and it's job is to
fill out all the details on this thing
so that by the time you get into install
you have all the information about the
thing that you're going to build you
don't have to ask any questions you
don't have to go searching for things
you just say okay what you know what
it's back tell me to build the other
thing here is that and this will be
important later is that the nodes here
they can have different compilers so
currently we're modeling the compiler is
an attribute on the node and I'll get a
little more into that later the other
constraint that we impose on this is we
want there to be only one instance of a
particular package in a dag so if I do
one build of an application I enforce
this constraint that basically there can
only be one call path library in here
that's imposed by the native language
runtime languages like JavaScript have
support for multi version tags and
they're their module system will
actually allow you to have one package
over here calling one version of a
dependency and another package over here
calling this a different version of the
same dependency we're dealing with
native stuff and so we have to deal with
LD data so or dial D or whatever the
linker is on the platform and so you can
link and executable where there are
different libraries in your DAGs that
depend on different versions of
something like lip standard C++ we
really don't want to because it's a race
it runtime basically the first version
of that library will get loaded the
second one gets invoked and then it ends
up calling a function in the first
version and if the ABI isn't compatible
you get a nasty error and the things
explode and so one of the things we have
a lot of problems with is managing all
the different versions of C++ compilers
in the standard Lib with with you know
the recent proliferation of versions of
C++ I think that's a good thing
personally because I think a lot of good
things have happened to C++ lately but
it is something that makes the build
harder for users especially if we're
using older versions of the OS like rl6
where the the default standard C++ is
pretty old and you
we often want to build with a new one
that's not the system version so in
general you don't want to have two
versions of one library in the same
process basic alright so why aren't
compilers proper dependencies inspect
right now well it's mostly for
expedience we wanted to mix compilers in
one dag because we wanted to play around
with lots of different types of
compilers and we can't do that with our
one compiler per there are one in one
thing per one instance of each package
per dag restriction and so what spec
does is when you run in spec for the
first time or if you run spec compilers
it searches your environment and finds
all the compilers in your environment
and sets up a file like this essentially
this says here's here's your C compiler
C++ different Fortran compilers what
operating system was it for things like
that modules if you can load it from a
module and it uses this as the
description of the compiler and you have
this spec identifier down here this is
what gets put on the dag right now so
we'll just say use that particular
compiler and we trust that if we
detected it then it's the same version
across the different systems so that's
what we did
what do we care about that so much so we
want to use lots of different fancy
compilers for high performance we like
running the Intel compiler it tends to
get better performance than GCC on the
Intel machines we run on if we run on a
Cray we tend to like the PGI compiler or
the Cray compiler and you know there's
there other nice tuned compilers for
different systems on the IBM's Excel
tends to get the best performance
slightly even though it takes forever to
compile and then the other thing is that
on many of our machines we actually have
to use a special compiler because we're
cross compiling for the compute nodes so
like on our Blue Gene systems the front
end is not the same architecture as the
back end and that's the case on a lot of
the crates today that uses the unthe
eyes they have a Xeon front-end and they
have a Phi back-end and you can't
compile
you can't run back-end executables on
the front end the front end is where
people log in to build and so the other
reason that we care about the compilers
is people want advanced compiler
features so a lot of our programmers are
using things like OpenMP to do threading
on the big fat cores that we have on the
front end nodes we care about those C++
language levels and features like that
we care about building with CUDA Oh
those things are features that are
exposed by the compiler you might say
that their interface is exposed by the
compiler and we want to be able to
experiment with them and you know it
would be nice if we had a proper
dependency model for that stuff so all
of these things pose some challenges for
the dependency models all right I
already talked about this a little bit
but the the the fancy vendor compilers
do tend to get better performance the
other issues that you can have with
those are that if you're using those
most of the OSS projects don't test with
them so if you're trying to build
something like C make with the Excel
compiler it is unlikely to work because
they probably haven't tested with it and
so and there's also no reason to do that
so for a lot of these build dependencies
we tend to not build them with the the
nicer compilers we'll just build the
numerical stuff that does all the number
crunching and we'll try to build these
to build dependencies with something a
little safer because we don't care about
the performance so what does this look
like we want to we have a dag like this
where I've got a bunch of different
packages the bees are build dependencies
two L's or linked dependencies the ars
are run dependencies I want to go and
build this so that the build
dependencies get built with the easiest
compiler possible where I don't care
about performance but anything that
links into this thing which I intend to
run on the back end where then which I
intend to run fast it's going to get
built with the fast compiler what we
tried so far is we've made it so that we
just if anything is a pure build
dependency anything under there that
needs to run in the build environment we
make we just build that with the easy
compiler and so what ends up happening
is so this is a pure build dependency
here you get this whole tree building
with the easy compiler so it's like GCC
or something this is a link dependency
so it forces this guy to be built with
the fast compiler along with the route
and so on down this this link and run
chain and we know that this needs to run
in the run environment so we figure it's
something computational so we'll build
that with the fast compiler too and then
this is a pure build dependency so we
just make that easy again you'll notice
that this is a build dependency but it's
it's something that's fast that depends
on this other library as both a link and
to build dependency so here we're just
prioritizing the link dependency because
we could still use the code that we
built if we're if we
two different compilers for the same
architecture so we get away with that
here this seems to work pretty well for
a lot of our numerical codes and we're
planning on where'd you get in things
get a little more complicated when you
try to cross compile so why do you care
about cross compilation well your big
machine has a different architecture
from the front end so the user login
knows we tend to provision with these
nice big fat cores for building like
power 9s or power 7s on the actual
blue-jean machine they run a standard
Linux distro it's a nice easy
environment to work in but to run on the
compute nodes
you know we run a special core it has a
lightweight OS it's not the same runtime
that exists on the front end and that's
for performance and for reducing OS
noise in these parallel applications
have to synchronize frequently if you
have a lot of noise
the synchronization can be a lot more
costly so we care about that when we're
running on a million cores
you basically build the things here you
submit jobs or workload manager and it
runs them back there and then that's how
you get your speed that's how we get
machines this big is by compacting the
processors more densely and using
special cores why not build natively on
the compute nodes in many cases if you
build on the compute nodes it's pretty
slow we have lots of those cores but
that doesn't mean they're fast
they're fast when you use lots of them
but if you look at say a Xeon Phi it's
like it's one chip it has 72 atom cores
on it each one is 1.4 gigahertz and if
you tried to build any kind of
significant thing on that it could take
hours and hours typically those things
only talk to the network file system too
because the nodes are diskless and so
this is the giant pain to build out
there and then also many of the
compilers aren't even ported to the
compute nodes you want they only run on
a straight Linux distro and so we don't
really have the option of building on
the compute nodes in some cases we've
also had people try to do a make - J out
on these Leon 5 chips and they've blown
out their Intel license because there
were so many threads on the thing and
instead they started you know 256 copies
of the Intel compiler and only had 64
licenses so that can be sort of a
problem
so there's all kinds of reasons not to
build on the on the exotic in the exotic
place so how do the build dependencies
actually work with cross compiles so
recall we've got these three builds up
and it was getting a three build or
three dependency types builder things
that you want to run at Build time link
are things that the package is gonna
link with and run are things that you
might invoke at runtime so the build and
run ones are basically commands you have
an issue now because you need your build
up in disease built for the architecture
where you're building because they have
to run at build time and we got away
before with cheating and basically
building some of the things that we're
both linked and build dependencies for
the backend and so we can't do that
anymore because we're actually cross
compiling if we build the build
dependencies for the backend they really
won't run on the front-end even if even
if it's they won't run on the front-end
because it's a different architecture
and so we could use our build dependency
trick here sort of but we have to modify
it a little bit here's that same dag
from last time you can do the thing
where you basically run the front-end
compilers for these libraries that are
basically dependent on through pure
build dependencies but if you have a
problem this build dependency here it
needs to be run in the build environment
and this won't run anymore because now
it's for a different architecture same
down here this build dependency has a
run dependency on this thing and so this
won't run because it's a different
architecture what we do here and or at
least what we're planning on doing this
is the new model is that we would
actually duplicate these guys and so if
you have built if you have these kinds
of dependency relationships you actually
have to make a different version of
these two guys to run on the front-end
and so we have to actually split the dag
now you have sort of a violation of our
original constraint which is that this
now you have two versions of five in the
same dag and two versions of eight in
the same dag that's not so good but we
can handle it we have to modify our
model a little bit but at least now we
can run we can actually run on the cross
compiled machines it's just a little
more complicated and there's a few more
relaxed constraints that we have to deal
with there's some other interesting
constraints that come up in this
environment that like this when I wasn't
even expecting there are certain tools
like set up tools and Python that
actually add code to the installed
package and so you may think that you
could just do resolution kind of
separately for the front end in the back
end
but you actually can't because this
setup tools is running in this Python on
the on the front end and it's gonna
inject code that needs to run in this
Python on the back end the pythons
interpreted why does it care about
architectures well you don't care about
architectures but you do have a
constraint that the art these two
pythons now have to be the same version
otherwise the code that setup tools is
going to inject to run back here is
going to fail and so we now have you
know we have a dag where we have to have
two different versions of the same
package in it and we have constraints
across architectures that run through
the dependency problem that we're
solving and so that one actually
surprised me I was I was it was it was
pretty cool that we actually have to
deal with that all right and then the
last issue compiler dependencies I said
that compilers are a special case
inspector right now and we did that to
get it working quickly that's true but
what we'd really like to do is have a
more natural dependency model for our
packages where you don't have to
remember all the different versions of
the compiler that support the level of
C++ that you care about we don't want
the packages to have to say I need GCC
for 93 I need Intel 17
I need this other compiler at this
version we just want them to say I need
c++ 17 or I need these features from C++
17 the other issue is that compilers in
our current model can't easily have
their own dependencies and actually this
comes up you would be surprised some
compilers actually depend on other
compilers so if you run the Intel
compiler it depends on GCC because it
relies on it for its lips tender C++ and
so there's the nastiest version
synchronization problem that you've ever
seen when you try to build with new
versions of the Intel compiler on
systems where the standard C++ library
is very old and so you have to actually
you have to tell it to use a newer GCC
then the system GCC and you have to
remember to our path that in so that
when you actually run the binary it
finds the right live standard C++ either
that or you have to have the user
remember to source all the right files
to get the applications availing to run
so what we're planning on doing is
factoring the compilers out as actual
dependencies and actually this would
allow us to have virtual dependencies
for the different language levels so we
could have C++ eleven seventeen fourteen
things like that openmp is another one
that I think it's really good I could
say we depend on openmp for and we could
have compilers provide both say C++ at
different versions and OpenMP at
different versions so suppose we do that
you've got a package here you've got it
depending on the Intel compiler at
version 17 which then depends on GCC
this is actually kind of fine we don't
have to do very much special here and
you could actually do this with
conditional dependencies you could just
say Intel at 17 depends on a specific
version range of GCC and you wouldn't
have to introduce anything too special
to this dag but suppose that you now
want to build against something that's
already installed that used an older
version of Intel and this actually comes
up because we have so many compilers
running around frequently where now you
want to link this against the second
library and that one's built with Intel
15 this is already installed and that
built with GCC at four point nine point
three well if you if you have these
virgin ranges here you have this Intel
compiler depending on a specific version
range of GCC you have this Intel
compiler depending on a version range of
GCC it's still not constrained enough
that you can sync the standard C++
versions between the compilers and
ensure that they're consistent and so
what we have to do here is actually
introduce another type of dependency so
what is a compiler
it's a build dependency that imposes
some link dependencies on the things
that it builds and so in this case it's
the runtime libraries it's things like
lips and your C++ it's deliver that here
it's all the different libraries that
are bundled with the compiler that you
don't see on the link line and so what
we have to do is add hidden dependencies
to the dag and normalize them like we
did originally where we only have one
instance of them for the whole dag
so the new dependency model looks kind
of like this if I have that dag from
before now I say okay these compilers
here I need to figure out some way to
get their standard C++ synced up so I
have them impose a link dependency on
the thing that they're building and
now you get these two implicit hidden
dependencies from the compiler on Lib
standard C++ and we forced this to have
one node for lips tender C++ per dag and
when those constraints get merged then
you'll get a conflict at the lip
standard C++ is are not synced between
these different compilers alright and so
this is the model we're planning on
going to I think it's pretty cool
because it allows us to actually have
virtual dependencies for compiler
features and ensure consistency of the
runtime libraries and get the árpád's
right which will make a lot of people
happy on our clusters so that's the
summary we're working out constraints
for compiler integration it's not easy
weird things can happen surprising
things cross compiling can affect how
your pythons have to be synced between
the front end and the back end and and
also thing is you have to add additional
dependencies to the dag and we're trying
to make this part of spax build
configuration and we're hoping that this
will make it really easy to write a
single source package that you can
compile in lots of different ways on
some pretty exotic machines so I have a
bunch of stack stickers over there if
people want stickers so come and get
them and that's all for my talk right
now I think so it was taking forever
because there's some really oh sorry
let's repeat the question so the
question was for the sizes of DAGs that
we're dealing with how long does
concretization take it takes no more
than like five seconds right now for
what we've got it may take longer once
we go to a full Sat solver I'm not sure
we're a little greedy right now in the
way that we do the solve but you know
most most of that is Python being slow
and not how fast saat can run when
things go wrong how exposed to the user
I guess the ones I'm most interested in
is if it's a kind of quite
concretization fails yeah yes you can
result something or similarly if say you
asked to interview
CCC 4.7 yes it will be built 4.8 and
that's not being defined in the package
sure because then one's tried that
particular combination right what do
each of those cases okay so I guess the
the shorter so the question was how is
that exposed to the user when
concretization fails and if the packages
don't expose all the right constraints
and if the build fails so the short
answer is not well and so you know if
computerization fails I wouldn't say
that we have the best error messages in
the world yet if it's a simple
constraint you may get the two
constraints conflicting that you expect
so it may say this thing depends on GCC
and you're trying to build with Intel
often it takes some thought to figure
out exactly what it's trying to say to
you which is not great so that's
something we can improve for the build
failure part we've tried pretty hard to
make it so that a big build will give
you intelligent error messages we stole
the magic regular expressions from C
test and so we'll actually go and parse
the build log and spit out highlighted
error messages for with context for what
happened but yeah it's still an error
message so this is still an improvement
over building by hand which is which is
the bar that were we're trying to get
above it would introduce a new version
of spec it wouldn't be incompatible with
the old one I'm sorry but so what's the
time frame for all this stuff and we'll
it makes back incompatible with old
versions of stack we try to stay
backward compatible with like the stuff
that we installed so that a new version
of spec cannons can understand the old
database so you would still be able to
see your old packages it may just
rebuild a lot of stuff yeah and so the
time frame would be by September is sort
of the the latest we're hoping for
earlier
I think so I think my time is up Thanks
[Applause]