so hello good morning everyone welcome
watch out
some of you they don't leave couple of
goods be related books so I made step
one shoot today I'm just going to talk
about QSP at home so if you came here to
listen about blue is me now we've got
time to leave even though let's go to
stay stuffy dirty last year I took a
part in a project that was main goal was
to keep bison awesome Beth Williams
distribution up and running even when we
accept sound for a code 3 code means
does the middle or he's able to provide
very low air begins to dignity and we
like to make the user experience better
if it means that we don't practice it
means that we don't more resources our
main target are alone crying devices it
means I will be so glum prank devices
are kind of similar to the server by mg
similar server they're all running
pretty low so to stop our problems to
keep our platform up and running we try
to
reduce experience of surfer bats came up
our solution because it turned out that
those multiple December wards are to pay
me for owls small endemic devices the
whole thousand image they ordered for
diabetes up to 40 megabytes so we would
like to keep our solution smaller the
menu for today is the problem statement
and that solution is known from the
server warned our solution some short
summary and wish so what's the role that
we understand the problem I would like
to talk about good ever be in USA rise
your hand yeah why I love the view did
you enjoy your visit I have to be couple
of years ago in California it's a really
nice place it's astounding it's
beautiful when I went there I sell
another Pope houses like this one
the house is big but what love is my
attention is this beautiful green low I
hope in college Mariana seems to be a
rather dry place down wet and you have a
green grass in the water so I expected
rather loss like this one so I woke me
to keep this long grief they have to
water each other others so it is
possible then you're doing this by the
volume it requires a lot of time if you
how to make this it might be vanity show
but it is
you have to do some initial investment
so I took with some gun from California
I asked him then I'm here doing this
hierarchy Pyarelal so great he answered
me we are just thanking them they're
just thanking their loans because they
know the user experience is important
they're good houses are like showcases
so when it comes to someone house and
you see a beautiful green loan you know
that this house is beautiful when you
see a lot like from the greatest picture
when it's really dry
you say oh my gosh it could do this
better and the same is with software our
products are being wide using eyes
mostly eyes so what's the most important
is user experience DUI but not only
because performance can influence your
product and real I agree annuity user
don't want you to devise your product to
hang and you would like to move it
smoothly you like when you product to be
ready to use every time so how to do
this make sure to ensure that the
project is running smoothly that your
product is well recognized by user that
we put some efforts into develop in our
case we are not providing it from our
product is free our product is called
Windows distribution it's time operating
system so as I said Taizo image is
customized ooh customizable it means
the webserver and choose which we
presumed likely to move in your image
and then you may also add some pasta
rpms we don't know what's your attic
clear image we don't know what's your
use case we don't know if your code good
so we know you end up with a platform
where pieces of code are comes from us
and we may say that they are pretty good
or they come from professors project and
we can say that they are really nice and
then we may say that you are uploading
some foreign code and we have no idea
about the quality of the scope but in
the end you may always place a sticker
on your product and say hey i'm rony
pricing it doesn't matter that too tense
of our good services you have sang crap
you may always say unrecognized
so the first piece of to have a good
piece of code you need to have a well
defined a good software development
process like in open-source you've got
code review you got tests but there is a
question how long are you testing your
problem I want every testing new
software are you testing your software
running or a year not really usually you
just run some unit tests and see okay
it's working so it should be working
also for a year long it is not always a
true you need some continuous
integration and you need some stuff
analyzes to improve your code quality
but even if you put all the stuff in
place you to know is going to be perfect
take a look at unwillingness colonel
there is a lot of divorce a lot of
reviewers cuts they're still box it
doesn't mean that you can throw the
stuff trust me and stop using is no
what I'm trying to tell you please keep
this in place but remember that even if
your process is really well defined that
a lot of equals dear software may be
imperfect this means that it requires
monitoring and this is what server guys
really know so the second piece of code
is the for encode the one you upload to
the platform and we have no idea it has
been reviewed at all have you test it or
not you are just uploading this today
image so it even more requires
monitoring during the runtime so what
kind of problems we may encourage there
are memory leaks file descriptor leaks
but in terms of box I mean everything
which make cold you know we make many
years service behave unexpectedly which
made major server crash there are some
good loops
people try to reboot your platform then
you may enter some good loop is common
especially during the updates for many
other so it means that our solution has
to be extendable to allow you to
customize monitoring infrastructure so
how to fix those problems in a runtime
so we try to restart service from time
to time it may it's also a common
practice from a server world the my web
server seems to be running fine for
around the day but then it starts using
all them gram memory so how to fix this
well you should go to the code and paste
it but then you open the codebase and
say oh my gosh it means line of code I'm
not going to find the back here okay so
let's just rested it every day let me
have some
pastries because services may also
corrupt its data so you have some simple
fixer no change inside the service code
itself but change something script
that's going to be to the database or
something you may have their recovery
boat it means that you may have a
separate eat ramen festive when can wear
it in Boots and in somewhat repair
well-defined environment try to fix your
problem in the end or maybe firstly you
should report the back to the developer
it's important to not only restart the
service but also let developer they want
to grow this piece of code know now hey
you've got the bug in your service you
should try to fix it so we can upload
the better version for the next release
and of course any other method that you
can think about so as I told you keeping
platform up and running it's the
well-known issue in server world those
guys are really hard contracts for
availability of their service like
ninety nine point and some number of
nine percent so it's really hard to keep
your service up and running for such a
long period of time so how they are
doing this
the answer is monitoring and service
restart the first method which helps us
keep our service up and running
consistently who is the assistant yeah
that's like also so it's come on and
it's almost free to use system D
provides couple two nice options to fix
yourself
or at least the restarted first one is
the restart it means that system B is
going to automatically restart your
Saturday's based on the conditions you
choose the most common version is to
work long - Ambra in service to restart
the service every time when you entered
past the host a it means that has been
killed by the signal it has exited with
unclean coal or something like this the
other backup fixing the service is to
use home failure option on player is a
unique which will be automatically
started by system D when a service fail
so instead of simply restarting the
service we are running some kind of
fixing screen or some kind of developer
notification mekinese something like
this but it's not enough for circle guys
that's why there are some more extensive
monitoring tools like nauseous I think
it's the one of the most popular
solution so the core part of this
software is scheduler and web interface
why we heat the scheduler well the very
basic principle of managers is to run
some script every 10 minutes every one
hour or every minute to check the status
of the service we just check the status
and collect the result in our database
in the services file or for example some
server is not responding from the
message we are changing our state there
are five different states and during
this change we are generating an event
this event may be handled by some event
handlers usually even handler is a
simple shell street that is going to do
the job so for example if you do the
paint as of some server you may try to
handle the fact that it went from the
okay steak to soft pretty dog
it means that server is down so you
write a stop a show street that is going
to do the power cycle on the server to
reboot it and try to keep it up and
running and we obviously notify the
administrator that something is wrong
with that machine the other way of
checking the status is passing tests in
terms of classic plugins
I mean classic screens with are checking
the state they are being run by the not
just itself every 10 minutes passes
thanks I are kind of different because
independently granny's street or a
service that submits the stages what it
like to do or when the state uses change
so for example if you would like to
change the amount of RAM memory use it
but only with 100 megabytes resolution
you may report the status to Denarius
only when passing 100 megabytes of RAM
usage not every 1 megabyte change or not
every 10 minute
what's the disadvantage of marking
checking is that you have no idea what
happened
detects so we've got a ten-minute gap
for intervention meant you guys kind of
poured of nachos and it has been created
to be more distributed their main there
are monkey mode set up separate
databases etc people say that it's
they're both equivalent but I think that
this one is much more prepared for being
distributed but it's still very heavy
we provide similar functionality it has
additional mobile clients
it doesn't matter for us because we're
doing something balancer the next one is
Douglas was different in from our
perspective is that it has much more
events and it has been no end in ashes
and eating up you just say that each
step of this shape changes from okay to
soap or to create a new soft critical or
too soft warning then execute the street
over here you may write a rule that will
combine stages of multiple services of
multiple checks and execute the street
for example only five or ten services is
done not only one so images you have
only piece of stay and here you may
consider that type of whole system of
all tracks but it's still really hate so
in general several entering tools are
really good in addition there are 12
scale like the MongoDB so it's really
good piece of software but not tailored
for embedded needs
that's why we just couldn't take it and
fit this in your pocket but we needed to
develop something which which is small
first of all
we did all those stuff as the center of
decision-making point it may be
distributed among multiple notes but all
the devices all the checks are being
uploaded to to some cloud to some kind
of central central server we don't want
to make a decision about your devices we
don't want to collect your data so we
would like your your product will block
your service to be independent that's
why we don't want to keep this thing on
some remote machine but on your product
itself so it's a single point of the
single machine you know what enterprise
the device should be low and we should
not set any pooling interval so we
focused on passive changes for example
service public pay week change of number
of file descriptor or something instead
of executing they check every 10 minutes
why because it's more power efficient to
make the check only when the spectacies
check we try to make
measurements and it turned out that most
of our IOT devices are usually idle so
it means that they are in deep sleep
state and there is no point in waking
them up every 10 minutes or every five
minute or every one hour just to check
the status which didn't change so what
we have developed we created a poll deal
from our perspective it's a generic even
processing framework it consists of
single diamond which has as usual input
and output input is a change of state in
the system for example system D may
notify us that some service value so
this is our e it's captured by some new
listener and recorded as an event to the
cover every event that goes to the core
is being saved into the database for
further and eyes then we put it to the
decision maker
what is decision maker decision maker is
the business logic that decides what you
should do in this case it may contact
the database check the history it may
contact some external server it may show
user pop-up or anything or send push
notification to some mobile phone or
something it doesn't matter
Colby is a planning architecture
assuming human right decision maker on
your own when the decision is made so we
now know what we should do
there are implementation of actions
currently we have only four actions
restart the service recover the service
reboot and reboot to recovery because
implementation of this action may vary
between different platforms
different devices they're kind of
abstract so the business logic only
decide what kind of action should be
taken and this part decide which
implementation should be used so what
kind of listener do we have now
first of all a system the listener
it's subscribed on private system give
us or why quite private because because
treatment is a service to be more
precise it's a critical service for our
platform because most of our services is
using the buzzword communication so we
don't want to get notification from
system D via give us the moon we want to
get this notification directly so we use
the private system device which doesn't
involve any other demon support
communication so system D may send us a
signal whenever some service fail when
we got the signal we're reporting events
even to the core and then run our
business logic to decide what we should
do with the service another type of
listener is LD listener why do you shout
it listener because we like to keep
resurface usage let's say we would like
to touch resource list like my
descriptor bleeds like memory leaks so
for every service on on our platform we
said the memory leaks the marks file
descriptor release all the standard
error leads then we use outage system to
catch the moment when service gets some
error message from a suitable Cisco and
then we report this to the core and
decide what to do with that service
what's important here that
perfect because service gets integra as
you know hardly ever be services
especially errors which are uncommon
like Empire who have ever met an e/m
pilot ever in his service please rise
your hands okay so not so many people so
you see that it's enough common
that's why error handling paths are not
well tested and usually they contain
sparks the perfect solution would be to
get an application that service fits
some resource usage level without
featuring an actual error to the service
itself apart from this it turned out
that for our platform how the system is
not free it's rather expensive because
if you use Alice Cisco this slows down
your open system for a 33% run hope for
a cloak file and up to 45% 400-500 file
means that the file is in I know
deprecation so that's why we develop
everything it events which are
lightweight mechanism of notification to
the user space when service reaches
given amount of resource usage so we
mentioned this and is quite point six
percent for whole file and one point six
percent phone for coal unfortunately
after I developed and post and ever seen
we moved to the other project so if
there is someone who'd like to pick up
those patches feel free to do this and
try to make like them the next part of
Cody is decision maker currently we've
got three of them just before our
showcase first one is VIP process
handler and VIP processes for example
the busty moon when the bus demon dies
there is nothing to do on this system so
it's time to reboot the standard
recovery means that if some service
fails ten times is being recovered
recovered means that it will define some
recover Street we're running it if not
we are simply restarting the service
after and after end times of recovery in
the service we are doing angry boots
when we detect a reboot group we are
entering the recovery and maybe sending
some crucial message to the phone hey
something is wrong with your IOT device
try to change the last one is
decision-maker for reasons why why
should we service population means
messages from how big or from our women
even if we detect of some services
resource mobilization we may generate a
report report for the developer sand
thank you your service is using much
more resources than your declared you
should take a look at this and then we
are we starting a service actions like I
cope with that we cover the surface it
means run the recovery
servus servus simple restart reboots and
we've got three different types of
readings
the first one is forced which is use the
system the second one is reboot reboot
using system D once again be his private
bus to talk with it and the last one is
Tizen specific because of eyes and
password is being reviewed rebooted
using device and because the last one is
unreal not reliable
we are trying to use it and then it with
tales we just go to the previews of the
last one is the recovery is simply
pretty the same as we do but with some
special parameter with Mike Tyson we
built in a recovery node and the
separate in chemicals the last part is
database like a culture every event is
stored in the database
why because toady is a demon that is
running as a root both T is a demon that
is reviewed rebooting your platform so
as a user and as a developer I would
really want to know who is rebooting my
clacker
and why so that's why we decided that
every even every action should be
traceable from beginning to the end so
every event that is reported by our
listener is as a trigger stored in the
database then when the decision is made
it is also stored in the
a vase and the log from executing every
action so for example we say to contact
device the end we are using system B
reboot or something like this it's also
stored inside the data context this
allows you to implement a decision maker
which not only change the current state
of the system but check also the
previous action so we can for example
detect these really blues initially for
our implementation of database back-end
which is easy to be is kind of objective
database without external Timo it's
really fast but it turned out that it's
not efficient in terms of storage not
only in terms of storage for the
database itself because initially the
database may be tailored to one megabyte
but the problem is does easily be binary
together with dr. cabinet algorithm
which is use Thanks around 700 kilobytes
and it turned out to be too big for our
platform so that's why we are switching
now to SQLite which is let's say the
default implementation which we used was
around 10 times 10 times slower but
after changing and reaching the database
schematic we reach only - thanks - thank
you know what sorry I need to look like
an English speaker
ok so summary
how does hold deeds of google you've got
the system notification our input to
system the listener and our big listener
the Linux kernel was important here is
that before all three we didn't use a
leak on our platform so we eliminated
the LGG demon why because it was slow
because it took some space and because
no one on our uses so there was no
reason to keep it we are like like
directly listening messages from from
the outlet then we've got the core part
which is simply our routing for the
events database actions and
decision-makers so summary what we
learned during this year
first of all several monitoring tools
are really used if you've got your own
server
try to install and play with them there
is a lot of benefits you may see what
your server is really good it's
important not only in terms of kind of
full tolerance or banking your grass
dream is important in terms of security
because like my friend told me in
Internet there is no machines that does
not be old machines which are connected
to the Internet may be subjected to
attacks and be used for example tonight
a Bitcoin so if you're using IOT devices
remember to monitor also them because
you know the botnet Mirai who cares
about this yeah so you know what you can
use those IOT devices for unfortunately
those tools are too big for small
embedded platforms that one never
all the-- we try to keep it generic so
if it in serious case is great try to
use it it's available free and open
source available unzip the Tison of art
if it doesn't be curious case try to
develop some plugins it should be easy
and maybe it would be better than
writing everything from scratch the next
one is that out with Cisco is not free
why it's kind of surprising because a
lot of server is using Albee to trace
activity on the server but it turned out
that on our platform public Cisco is
much slower than put on x86 on x86 is
around five to ten percent so arm is
time at least three times slower than
x86 in gdb is pretty classic so if we
need a fast objective database or in
clockwork try to use it unfortunately
you have to have some spare storage for
both library and the data backs and
that's all questions
well hopefully is not using any
distributed system the goal is that they
should operate independently it means
that we don't want to have some simple
point of decision we don't move to have
some central cloud to collect the
information we want only reports about
research violations or about some some
attacks but it's up to the manufacturer
because we are releasing this image what
sort of things probably some kind of IOT
gateways obviously it depends how you
configure your image that is why I
mentioned that there is a web
configurator and you can put anything of
this
we didn't need to angle C groups because
C curves v1 already provided a kind of
that functionality at least in terms of
members we didn't develop such plug-in
we didn't develop such a listener but
we've been testing this for C groups and
why I told for the very see group there
was a functionality similar to heirloom
it evens it means that you can subscribe
and get notification when the C group is
using some specific amount of memory so
it's really cool but it's has been
dropped in C groups we do some more
questions
and I come earlier with PS mine
nope I'm not talking okay
okay so just to repeat kilos monkey
seems to be a system that is randomly
shutting down some servers just to check
if they are able to recover I'm not
available maybe I'm not aware of this
solution and we didn't try to use it
thank you
okay so the question is if we have all
the weight money for this we try to
follow it but it also will increase but
I didn't mention about this because it's
kind of similar to the other stuff so
all the server tools are let's say they
have some different features but I'm
over like di itself a is Python we don't
have a scheduler here we go the money
checks we are using any other questions
[Music]
okay so the question is if science for
schools there is a kind of rule engine
well yes because we've got the data
basement and we decision-maker and
contact the database and check the
current state of the system and only the
parent state which this any other
questions
[Music]