thank you so much for coming this is
going to be a bit of more technical
presentation so I'm just want to know
how many of you are web developers here
okay so it's a bit at the at the bridge
between designers and web development
and that's what I'm going to present how
we implement this kind of concept inside
the inside this wiki but if you have
something similar in your product I
would be very curious to see how you did
it
so for the people that don't know what I
can teams are the most similar concept
are our color team so user always wanted
to have different colors or their
favorite colors and in the past we did
that with alternative style sheets so we
if we wanted to provide for three colors
you have two different style sheets one
with red blue etc but when the bootstrap
framework became more popular and
actually when preprocessor had variables
in CSS then the customizations of the
themes become much more complex so not
just colors but now you could change the
typography you could change the borders
the margin so so a lot of other things
besides colors but one thing that was
always missing was the ability to switch
the the icons and for some that might be
something very not important so why
would you do that well but for for
designers or for users or if you want to
have your interface consistent and maybe
go through the new technologies changing
that it's it's important so I'm going to
tell you a bit about the history of how
and what themes we we needed to apply to
to our platform so and I'm sure many of
you that contribute to open source
project hit this wall too and the things
I'm going to compare our silicon fantasy
in material and I don't know how many of
you used the the silk icon it was an
image icon so in 2009 was used so nobody
from here you still do I used to used to
okay so in that period of time silk was
very popular it
it had the freelances and it had over
1,000 icons so for something that was me
in that period it was very very nice to
have the problem with silk was that it
was only a 16 pixel by 16 pixel and also
in that period of time Internet Explorer
6 was was popular and Internet Explorer
6 had problems with transparency so
people needed to use the gif gif format
and when we finally dropped Internet
Explorer 6 we needed to go all over the
core code base and and replace that gif
with PI ng is PNG in order to have a
proper transparency and this might sound
like an easy change so just the filename
is the same just change the format but
if you need to go in multiple places at
windows so if you are extensible and you
have extensions that you cannot control
and you rely on also outside the
contributors to change them that might
be a problem for the record this is how
an interface would look like we with
with silk icons and this is how it will
look with phantasm there was this switch
from image set to font icons and all the
way up started to be monochrome iam so
if before we we had lots of colors on
the icons now everything was looking
like this but one of the big advantages
why people made made made this switch to
2 icon set were because in that period
of time we needed to provide responsive
interfaces so 16 pixel bicycle pieces
was not yet enough and we have the
mobiles and lots of resolutions so also
in that period time frame bootstrap
became starts to became popular and when
they launched their 2 and 3 version they
provided by default the glyphicon set
the difficult at was not a free set but
they had some sort of agreement and it
was a nice alternative one of the
downsides of glyphicon was that it only
had 200 in icons so if you were a
platform and you wanted to switch to
this news
technology and to bootstrap you had like
a downgrade of the icons you could use
and if you have applications and those
applications have dedicated icons that
was a big problem so we also wanted to
find an alternative in that font Aston
was one 702 was kind of okay for us one
note more about glyphicon if you you're
using the bootstrap 3 version and now
you wanted to switch to bootstrap for
substrate for launch like 2 months ago
you had another problem glyphicon was
erased they were done bundling anymore
they tell you that you should look for
alternatives so you were you had three
choices you either you don't upgrade
either you stick with glyphicon but you
paid the license or you find an
alternative so this might be you might
fund house you might have found yourself
in the situation of again needing to
change the the icons that you were using
again a comparison of how glyphicon a
photo Sam looks like for users they
might say look kind of the same not many
differences so a good alternative so now
we want from I can image set to switch
to icon set so we have a problem of how
we are using this icons inside or our
code so on image you are using the image
IMG tag well if you want to use font set
you they say that you need to use a
spanner and italic tag and you give the
name of the icon in the CSS class name
so it was not that simple anymore like
switching from gift PNG you needed to
switch the the whole the whole tag HTML
tab and this was not the only problem
the problem is that if you want in your
interface to have icons there two types
there are inline icons and decoration
decorative icons so for example and
oldest font sets they were promoting to
use the
version so in the universe on you said
this is the image and then you have the
label compared to the creative images
where you have the label and the image
is on top put with CSS in the background
image and there are multiple ways why
you would want to have the decorative
version one of them is print so if you
want to have your page printed and you
don't want those images to appear on
your print they should be external or so
separation of concerns so the code is in
one place the the styling is is in
another and another reason are also
screen readers so when a screen reader
goes to over the the syntax and it finds
that image you would try to read it and
it might be an image it might not mix
for the search it will crowd the the
user with things that it doesn't need or
if they were to use the the font that
font well maybe it's not supported by
the screen reader and which would read
something like British and so the the
flow of the user when he reads something
might be disturbed so we have different
ways of entering sets and also different
ways of using them so this word some we
need find a solution for these problems
another thing was that how the years
pass by the web standard community
started to say that okay everybody is
using icon set but maybe they were more
hawkish and they were not meant to this
we use like this and the proper way to
use them are SVG's so everybody should
switch to s which is why are we using
icon sets and font sets
another thing that in 2014 material
design specifications become popular and
everybody wanted to use them they were
very well documented
they were also consistent with with
Android so if you had a mobile
application or a web application there
was something that you might need to
switch to this is all material look
design looks compared to phantasm one
thing that you might notice is that
material design has slimmer icons let's
say that this was fixed by
1005 when they released they provided
three different sets so they have
regular solid and light but the solid
and light versions you need to pay for
them
so still one one said yeah that's and
that's how material looks also the
version four of phantasm had only the
icon font while in material if you
wanted to use the the set you could have
used individual images or image sprites
or individual SVG's or SVG sprites or if
we were to take the common denominator
between sets and try to find a solution
that it goes at least for fonts the same
way in material design they are using
actually the typographic ligature so
instead of providing the name of the
class in the the name of the icon in the
CSS class they're using inside the
content so again another discrepancy in
usage mom so a lot of people are kind of
confused though okay if it's a new
project which version should we pick
should we pick the font technology
conversion or the SVG's or the images
and mostly it depends on what you want
to do but as a general consensus
switches are considered more powerful
and that's because the browser styling
is more extended and also if you want to
have animations but in our case and what
I'm describing in Indy icon themes
usually use more icons for actions like
save or edit and those icons are pretty
basic doing animations on them is it's
pretty overkill so in this particular
example if either refused fonts or SVG's
they are kind of the same thing depends
if you want to do advanced stuff on top
of them okay so what we want to do is no
matter what I can set we we have we want
to be able to write it in a in a
particular in a single way and that's
why in XP key for example maybe it's a
complicated solution but the
that's what we had we developed a
service and you call the service that is
dico service and you tell them the name
of the icon and no matter what is the
active icon theme it will translate that
in whatever syntax is needed so this
solution applies if you know that you
have a big project and it's going to
stay for a long period of time and you
might want to switch technologies it's
useful when you have a customization so
one user will want to have I don't know
colorful icons or other we want to have
a special technology so this is where
having this abstraction layer came in
handy because it will rapidly allow you
to change the icon and another thing if
you mark all your icons with using this
system all the icons will be consistent
everywhere so I'm sure you've seen open
source project like they have some icons
from one set and another's because they
didn't had the time to switch everywhere
here you're just using an abstract
version and it's changing from from the
from the set ok so this is how it looks
like on the code base or definition of
icon themes so we have two sections one
is general setting where we where we
define the icon theme and then is the
mapping so for example on silk you would
tell them that okay this is an image set
while compared to phantasm that is a
font set and if you want to render it in
HTML you're going to use the the image
tag Y on on the font a pointer is the
span and this was important for us to
provide multiple renders because wikis
usually have their own syntax or support
multiple syntax one is that they're
they're wicked syntax or markdown or
whatever and remember the example I gave
you with the creative icons and inline
icons if you're having multiple renders
you can you can say in CSS
I want this icon to be render using
background image
so that was another use case that we
needed to think about and solve okay and
the second part of when I continue is
doing the mapping
so for the mappings we have like 250
names that should be defined by all the
sets so for example if you want a home
icon in silk it should be house or in
photos on its home and at home but in
your code you just write home and
depending on the mapping he will know
what icon or or glyph to bring and if
you're thinking of implementing or using
a similar solution I would ask you to
reuse the work we did for Ford estates
and I also provided the reference model
there are other websites that do this
mapping because the mapping can be kind
of hard so for example in front also you
have just one icon that is useful for
home but in Eco mode you have like 3 or
like in I only cons you have left 4 so
which one you pick so here the designer
or the person should be careful that all
the ekend be consistent and and this
decision you need to take and those were
first not examples but if you want for
example to map the add icon in material
design this will be all the solutions
because they have generic icons like
pluses and pluses with with squares and
extra but they have also very specific
so at the user or add an icon so
depending on your application and the
what type of icon you need you might
need to extend the the the names of the
icon team you support okay and what is
nice about this solution is that you
don't necessarily need to to have
support for a set that is that is well
established you can create your own set
so there are some icons that generator
and you can go there and select like I
want this social icon from this set and
the social icon from set and they
generate you an SVG sprite that you can
use in a project so if your designer and
you want to get crazy with your with
your icons you could make your own set
but it's not just that you can consider
this also from a performance point of
view so instead of embedding like 1000
icon it since you're using just
20 icons maker your said smaller and
just just load those icons without
thinking about the others that you don't
need one thing to know is that since
there are so many technologies when
we're thinking about icon icon seems try
to find as I said the common denominator
so one features this to be supported by
by all the sets and one a one name for
the icon needs to be present and all the
set so some sets maybe they don't have
an icon you need to find the replacement
or maybe something generic but if you
still want to do advanced I can stuff
this you need to do them outside of icon
themes so examples of it advanced stuff
you might want to to do with icons so
for example animations and rotations for
sure the image set will not support that
so you still need to do them in the in
the classic way but at least you will
know that all the rest they will be
easily changed or stacking phantasm had
that ability to put multiple icons on
top so for example like here and they
say that the camera is band this will
need to be separate or there are some
version of icons that them being on the
SVG's and these widgets you can
individually control different aspect of
an icon you can create your icons to be
colorful so when you map your set you
map everywhere to be colorful and this
is an alternative to the to the old
image sets that were very colorful some
sets for example they have three
different icons for for the same so that
is zoom and depending on the resolution
of the of your screen it might be bigger
or a different different style like here
so the details you know they won't be
seen on the the mobile so don't put the
dots put them only or on big resolution
and another thing some sets have support
for right to left or left to right
reading okay so example of list or even
all the arrows
laughs might be the the other way in
that in that other perspective okay so
instead of just choosing one or SVG's or
phones or images if you have this
abstraction layer or this mechanism of
easily switching you can support
multiple and let the user decide what he
wants and for example if you need to
create an accessible customization of
your project for for some people provide
them with the with the fonts or or the
icons that they need and these are the
other examples that I give maybe you
needed to change the license or you
wanted to be more performant or or and
low just a finite number of icons or
maybe you were using a very small set
and then you wanted to expand multiple
because you grew all these are reasons
why you should think about having this
kind of system and I know this applies
for very large project and in the open
source we kind there are some
organizations that that span over the
years and need to extend and and they
are the particular users of this use
case okay
do you have any questions yes yes I
don't know how to say how to answer that
floppy days no sleep
yeah no because we don't have I'm not
using fluff at this and this kind of I
because I don't know how to answer this
particular question so no there were
some like here like the noun project
were you you could try to search for the
floppy disk and see what's it's and they
provide that icon and see if that said
applies to to your particular needs
something else from here it's using
SVG's icons in their project ok and font
sets okay
so the others are using images quizzing
using images no ok yeah so do you plan
to switch from one technology to another
or do you see reasons why you would want
to do switch
so if you still plan to use images you
want to switch to another set my
recommendation would be to to have a set
that provides SVG's and maybe export the
image format from that SVG if you want
to paint so no no process alternative
for doing Victoria's and doing images
it's in scape so yes that that would be
a good tool to create them okay so thank
you for all right
[Applause]