in general Felix and then I'm waiting
open source especially with the open
source project called open platform for
network functions virtualization which
deals with integration of open source
components and your under eye workout
hat I'm an engineer so got the most
diverse health partners of customers
telcos in the Lavi idea with OpenStack
intonation like taking all the Navi
features and integrated into their
probes especially on OpenStack different
technologies such as all these companies
have developed integrated and tested by
different open source communities and
they are all doing great job and they
all try hard to make sure these
campaigns work fine in communities that
are dealing with integrating all of this
company integration of these compounds
and there was a gap which need to be
solved
especially when it comes to functions
authorization and if you look at
traditional networks how they are built
it was obvious that the tradition
networks are not possible to scale not
possible to build using technologies and
it wasn't so easy to innovate in that
space in traditional networks and based
on these concerns let's see if we came
up with this nfe architecture and 2012
about five years ago to see how the net
can be developed and built up using
these new technologies such as cloud
virtualization and lately containers and
cloud native as well most and that's the
great job but sometimes Senate work
takes a bit longer than some nights went
to be and based on this concerns or
thinking this network functions
authorization in short or PFE was
established around the end of 2014 so
it's about three and a half years ago to
do integration work using these
different technologies empower to
standards work to see if the idea the
architecture works and at the same time
if the compounds work by different
organs of committees work well together
to be at this platform up so basically
open platform for network function
virtualization project aims to create a
reference platform for nfe using open
source components open source
technologies and this is challenging
because when you look at a few stock I
mean a few architecture you see many
different things that like NF UI itself
all can put if you go down you're
betting awesome you enter all that you
have virtual networks virtual storage
and virtual computer sources there and
then you're in FBI you have mono when
you put us on to it so it's really
challenging work to bring up this
platform using open source compounds and
since the developing fee has been trying
to do this by bringing different
technologies together such as OpenStack
or obvious the BTK and kubernetes and
why leave this open if we try to be able
to and the safe sites meaning that we
started with using stable release
[Music]
and as part of this bike in September
and we release over at least six months
late time upstream and since the point
of a fee is integrating these companies
and finding what works and what doesn't
form tight a point of view when you find
problems with these components and how
they work together and go back to those
counties is pretty late already
it's six plus months and all the
communities we work with they are pretty
helpful and friendly and so on but if
you have put yourself in their situation
if someone comes to
after half a year and asks you okay we
have this we have this problem how can
we fix this
you might erode moving to another item
in your backlog and you might not have
time and interest in fixing that thing
or maybe that might even out from your
stack so you might not have any
possibility to fix that either so this
speed we have been doing t snow PV this
kind of became it became challenging for
us because we are not not seems like we
are taught not non-conformities maybe
and if you put all these delays mounts
of glaze together it's like years of
delays when it comes to feedback time we
are getting out of our integration
efforts based on these findings we
started thinking about how we can make
things faster and become known to
communities we are working with and we
said guys I think officially is from you
but can you get more recent versions of
law technical campaigned with faster
than have we are doing and they start
working on this today with us to enable
contused Laurie in the community so we
can do point integration in our PV as
one of our friends died nefarious like
you can go as fast as slows it of its
upstream so if someone is very slow we
can't be faster than that community
because we depend on them and by using
this thinking and using open daylight as
our first community to go after this
confused little idea and we brought up
this country's dual pipelines from which
basically means that many they build
something in there CI using the auto
release process from their master branch
it should be possible to get that latest
built and tested artifact into open fair
environment so we can basically
integrate latest and greatest
of opendaylight into our and a few
platform and that looked very positive
and we starting about how we can do the
same thing for all the communities you
are working with time as I mentioned
many times the 11th OpenStack as well
and OpenStack is pretty important in nfe
reference platform and we start with
talking secondly saying okay guys we
want to do what we have been doing it
all day like we can want to consume the
latest and greatest version of OpenStack
for master branch and based on those
conversations maybe we can hear this
yeah based on those conversations we
okay we can open stack which basically
means that OpenStack community has been
working this news cycle in this case it
screens we get at least in worst case in
a week later which basic cross the
feedback time form six months for a week
which is a great improvement and again
if you look at all these different
campaigns in a few stack you can see how
big difference this could break instead
of waiting for months for different
communities to sign fixes to us we can
get those fixes in a week's time and
hopefully later on on a daily basis and
you see all these different things on
this slide and it's really complicated
thing to do this work integrate these
components and obviously we are not
doing this manually we see on nationally
for open afyon which basically there's
two different compositions of the
platform because some of the compounds
can't be co-located together and some of
the components
no no people are working after the
morning people are interested and then
based on those things we create
different combinations which we call
scenarios and first thing we do is
basically reposition our machines with
three different groups one of the three
different distributions who want to send
us or weapons who say and then we put
either OpenStack or command to send them
and then we put different net stem
controls instead of Neutron for example
we put autumn daylight or Ono's and then
we construct different feature
self-service function chaining or bgp
evpn and finally once we construct or
compose this termination we run testing
against this integrated stacking which
is a big difference campaign OpenStack
or opened a lot of other communities
because they may not deal with their own
companies in very small scale and in our
case we put all these compounds and try
to find what works and what doesn't and
as I said this is impossible to do
manually and we have a CI mesh near for
a penny fee which is distributed bare
metal labs all around the world and
currently it's like I think 15 laps they
are providing resources and we have more
than 200 valentino supporting two
architectures x86 and arm and as part of
our latest waves we had more than 50
scenarios more than 50 different
combinations of components and we
deployed a boost at more than 8,000
times in six months time because we
trying to use try deploy in things and
try to see if they work and we started
open the daylight when it comes to HCI
consuming things from master branches
and then we are we even working with
OpenStack which we can deploy both upon
stacking up in daylight front trunk and
me
Fido has been handled in a similar way
but in different scale in Europe in Fe
because that only dealt with Fido and
OpenStack in our case we are dealing
with all the components we have or
aiming to deal with and hopefully will
include anything to this as well and
these are share pipelines these are
upstream projects here pipelines there
that's that verification daily master
jobs and so on and we continue to track
the master branches to find working
versions and once we find working
version showing them we pin those
versions in open a therapist and then
run create the scenarios using both
paint versions and run testing against
them on bare metal notes okay so now I'm
going I'm going to talk a bit about the
tooling that we are using for that so we
are having different components here we
have June my flows OpenStack uncivil and
cool spray so June is what we are using
for project 18 we are using that for
project gating it means that all the
changes that are created in a project
they go through through these two
component and it will pass a set of
pipelines to verify that the jobs are
are working and that in that arena would
stay to win state to be measured so one
jewel is doing all the jobs they pass
through the gate pipeline that is the
one that is used for merging passes a
lot of checks there and after that it
goes from adjacent to the coat and you
can trigger another set of jobs to to
packet building or to polishing or
whatever and then we were using buffers
that is used for hardware provisioning
so you have a set of parameters several
or bm's we are going to use by first
okay so Bifrost is just a set of uncivil
play moves to deploy on standalone
hydronic so ironic is a component of
open style that is in charge of
provisioning built on machines for
parameters are especially easy that it
is routine and uncivil and it supports
like three major districts like if this
one to send to us and openSUSE
to yield by for us it is very easy to
use it's just that it's starting a set
of ansible playbooks and you basic
basically have four steps so first of
all you need to create an inventory that
is collecting the data from new servers
like the IP address user and password
you are going to
to connect you put it on a file after
that you run the second estate that is
insulin by floors so it is a set of
playbooks that will you start by first
on your server and once you have it
running you will do the enroll step that
it means it will collect all the
information from your inventory it will
run on your machines and it will collect
info all of their machines like hardware
that of disk all the information you
need to introspect the data and it will
pass to a database once it is you have
it the spirit on the database is the
final step to deploy so what the deploy
means it will means that it will take
all the parameter servers it will start
operating system that you wonder like
you can install CentOS Ubuntu
also you can cause to customize the
image that you are going to start so you
can add like custom packages or extra
configs extra projects so you will have
all the servers in the same state
the decided a state after that it would
also add you a basic Network config so
the for the very meta service will be
accessible in the network the way you do
choose and it will also copies edge keys
so you will have SSH keys that you
decide and you could could access the
service with that after it it is very
solid I mean it has been use it in all
of us tied in stress of all OpenStack
that they are using parameter are mostly
using ionic and we are running for
partition I test on it it means that all
the changes that go on by for us that it
is an openstack project are gated also
against our open a fee testing so we
validate that any changes by process is
breaking the open e 3 CI setup so it's
really good for that you can do
contrasting embarrassed ok next step is
robusta concealer it is a tuning for
historic OpenStack basically there are
several tureens a triple but we choose
this one because it's easy to customize
it's based on uncivil as well and it's
very very flexible you can choose the
way you want to deploy a post and there
you can use it in containers using the
oxy or you can deploy directly on
Parramatta
it is very very easy to integrate are
very flexible you can decide the type of
roles you want including your deployment
if you wanted to know about Keystone HJ
or not or even if especially for urban
MV you can go ride around horse so you
can decide I need to put any extra layer
on top of OpenStack it also has several
ways off of the brain so you can do
program developer mode and production
with H a with an affairs
you can complicate it as much as you
want and then we support also measure
distros like through window centers from
open source as well okay you scuba spray
so we started also to work a bit on
cover letters so we are starting to use
cover spray so it is a set of ansible to
play books again to start open a
kubernetes cluster that is created
inside cover not this community it can
be created on multiple platforms you can
deploy on for example you can deploy
marry me terrible trauma teams like with
fancier or there is also possibility to
determine OpenStack on Amazon so it's
quite flexible for that
so it's also very compostable so you can
decide the kind for example the kind of
network plan you you want to bring you
can't have different options there it's
reporting color OS Ubuntu they're young
so you have flexibility there and it's
solid because it has like end-to-end
integration testing like perform it on
different platforms as well so it's
reliable and what we are starting to do
it as a proof of concept so we have
mostly OpenStack down there but we're
starting to get governmentís integrated
into open every as well get something if
you have five minutes for questions
before you move to questions I want
highlight now we talk about an atheist
yen and Tory Nancy and stuff here the
moon
we are trying to achieve is basically to
increase the awareness in open source
communities when it comes to integrating
all these compounds together and
creating a platform because sometimes
dissipated good when it comes to
continually render stuff but sometime it
is our starting just starting now and
based on what we've been trying to do
the different communities started
understanding what we are trying to and
I think first time in like the in CI CD
space mean different community is coming
together to see how it is and then they
disappeared and we want them to come
back so intercept one last question
I just say it another big question
so all the pipelines fully automated or
is there some human interaction needed
for failures or depend on testimony but
since when compared testing sometimes it
requires human intervention to see what
went wrong and reproduce issue and find
the problem okay no more time thank you
very much Fatih and Yolanda our next
presentation is from Emma Foley
who's going to present the barometer
project which is an OPI Navi project for
a collection of platform metrics and
telemetry
[Music]
we've been having some AV issues