well hi everyone thanks for coming to
this presentation we're going to be
talking about the graphic CI system that
we have at Intel so it's it's something
that we've been working on for the past
two years something like this and it
really started to - yeah - get a
traction about a year going so we've
we've got pretty far already so we're
going to be talking today about what
services we provide oh yeah okay maybe
you can move out oh yeah yeah otherwise
I'm not in the video so yeah we're going
to be providing what it's fine to my
right here okay okay so yeah so we're
gonna talk about the Intel graphics CI
but also the the test suite that we run
i GT and what changes went through it
recently we're not gonna really talk
about lessons learned
unless we'll really have time and so
it's more like backups love and dealing
with Linux in products is is also
something interesting but I don't think
we're gonna have times but at least you
know that it's there if you want
so the Linux kernel it is a massive
beast so you get yeah basically release
63 to 70 days so that's pretty pretty
fast and it's difficult to do QA and
this properly because you know the
leanness just cuts the final version
whenever he is happy with the patches
doesn't mean that we had you would have
had time to to do proper proper QA on
this there's about 14,000 changes per
release pretty okay you know in average
that comes out at nine commits per hour
so good luck keeping up with that that's
1,500 developers
okay well ten percent of obvious and a
lot of companies what I mean by this is
that good luck having a centralized
system that would cover everyone's use
case so we are gonna just cover our own
and it actually covers quite a lot it's
pretty big and what is really
interesting is that there's a lot of
integration trees hundreds and and then
after the release there you get six
stable trees which also means that you
need to verify that this is still
working because this is what you know
users are using no one is using
integration trees so one interesting
aspect also about Linux is that it has
no architects which means that you don't
have these people deciding what the
project is going to look like it is I
don't know if you've read the cathedral
and the bazaar so essay by Erik Simmons
about about how Linux is different from
anything else
so the Linux development model is
everyone just goes there proposes
changes and then either it gets accepted
or it doesn't so but there are some
rules and the first one and the
strongest one is that there should not
be any user visible regressions so
whatever new kernel you would have it's
not allowed for it not to work as well
as it used to so that is a strong
requirement from from Linux that is very
hard to actually enforce when you've got
a lot of hardware then of course the
kernel changes need to be open source
fair enough and the kernel features
cannot land unless you've got a user
space that goes with it that is the
general rules of Linux not all of them
are problematic for us the the problem
is is the first one so why do we need
continuous integration so when you've
got that many people working in parallel
on a massive we can't really do anything
about it sorry I'll be saying what is
there anyway so when you've got that
many developers like 1500 working on
different parts of the kernel and you
know I develop at some point is gonna be
changing the memory subsystem and it's
gonna affect in in very weird ways other
parts of the of the kernel for instance
graphics
and so how do you teach people what are
the dependencies between the different
components of Linux well you can't
really but if you make a test system
that shows that there is a regression
and let the developer know as early as
possible that there is this interaction
then they can rework the patch before it
gets inside the Linux kernel so that's
why pre merge is so important because
once it has been merged it's very
difficult to get it reverted so some
people are fine with it and they're
gonna revert very quickly but our
experience with the rest of the kernel
is that reversion reverting anything is
almost impossible even sometimes before
it even lands into the I see one we say
like hey this is not okay
please revert and they just say like oh
I'm gonna fix it I'm gonna fix it I'm
gonna fix it and then sometimes it even
gets released like this so yeah the
sooner you know the better so yeah one
very important aspect for our
development team is that we have our own
integration tree that pulls in a lot of
other integration trees and we don't
want developers to be to be using like
one version a blessed version of the
integration tree and then let the rest
change we really want to be rebasing all
the time and checking that the current
integration tree of our or the merge of
every other integration tree is still
working for us so is this is still in
the idea of of testing as quickly as
possible so as you have more time to
react and one problem with that is that
it would be very often broken and so how
do we make sure that it's not broken and
how do we make it as stable as possible
so developers have can concentrate them
on making their patch works Apaches work
without fearing regression well it's by
doing pre-emerge testing so that's
that's the goal of it and yeah very
important is that it scales better with
the number of developers because we put
the cost of integration on the actual
developer who is making the change when
you've got 1,000 yeah 500 develop
this really no other way okay so now of
course it's it's all nice and good
theory but then like what are the actual
challenges that you get out of this well
this keeping the integration tree is
indeed very difficult because whenever
you get a back merge from Linux or from
an integration tree you can get
thousands of lines of code even more
coming into into the integration tree
they have not been tested because other
CI systems are not necessarily as
thorough as as what we do or at least
they don't concentrate on the workloads
that we care about so that's a lot of of
code Lending Act once that is untested
so that's usually LC one is a big
problem for us so usually I mean it used
to take about only two weeks to
stabilize everything now we are down to
usually two three days so huge
improvement thanks to CI but still is
problematic and and another problem also
is that when when when you make a bug
fix for a person particular branch it it
may work great on the integration tree
and then you ask it to be merged to
stable kernels and what the patch was
supposed to fix it actually makes it
worse and that's that's something we've
seen and so every if you are about to
apply a patch to a tree you need to test
the integration of this patch on the
tree you want to apply it to so that
means even for stable branches okay and
I'm gonna hand over the mic to Eric
yeah so I'm Eric and I'm one of the
maintenance of the IGT GPU tools as it
happens so I think it's good that I will
be talking about that
I'm also maintaining the some of the
parts of the infrastructure that we run
tests on so I'm helping with that quite
a lot so I do tgu tools what it is it's
a collection of tools and tests that are
aiding the development of drm drivers
actually there are mostly test we have
40-something thousand tests sixty
something thousand tests right now sixty
one thousand tests and we are running
them quite often not all of them
sensible subset of 4000 I'd say because
we are scheming the gem congruent so we
just made a couple of changes for the
project to eight new development so we
change the name previously it was named
Intel GPU tools but we drop to the Intel
from the name because we support other
drivers as well so it's not only intro
now we support AMD GPU have couple of
tests for that we have couple of tests
for integration of Nvidia drivers and a
couple of tests for vc4 so it's more
than Intel we also move the mailing list
so people won't be of put it by sending
mails to company named mailing list we
have separate IDT vendor agnostic list
for the IGT now and also we are starting
from invasion from outer tools to messin
build system because it's much faster
and Snyder is this new shiny thing all
people like to work on so yeah let's
take a look at what tests we have an igt
so sixty one thousand tests in total
there are eighteen tests dedicated for
the AMD twenty seven tests for vc4
mostly by Erik on halt
also we have fifteen thousand thousand
five hundred tests for kms and those
should be mostly vendor agnostic as well
because kms is cross vendor API kernel
mode setting so it's for certainly
resolutions and displaying images from
the frame buffers so the
she mostly vendor agnostic and we have
in a specific Jam tests which are the
most and as you can see we have 2300 of
the tests without the gem concurrent
which has a combinatorial explosion of
edge cases and it takes quite a lot of
time to execute them all so we are not
executing them on regular basis but the
aid the development so is this kind of
tool so let's talk about why I duties
are more than Intel because we are not
only in the end driver we can share huge
parts of the code base for the testing
and the testing infrastructure as well
because kms is not the driver specific
as I mentioned before so all the GM
drivers follow the kms and we can test
that together because API have to be
consistent so if something passes on one
driver and not passes on one on the
other and what behaviors should be
should be consistent across all them so
busy for info MD so that's good to test
for using one suit and because why
should we duplicate effort because Eric
started something called VC 4G beutel's
and it's a small project but then he
ported most of this stuff I think to the
today IG teeny so if for that and what
has to be done so it started a single
project so there's a lot of Intel isn't
there and as will show you another slide
not all the tests pass are passing on
other GPUs because of the intelligence
that sneaked here and there and cleaning
them up should be rather trivial but we
need your help with that and also we are
not handling multiple GPUs per host yet
so it usually defaults to into one first
you can guess why because of the history
yeah so and one one GPU at the time so
handling multiple GPU configuration to
test the one you have if you accidently
have discrete GPU and Intel GPU that
that should be done and one of the
requested features so let's see how it
looks with ok so it was cut off but we
read that to you so we tested new
BC for NVIDIA blob drivers and as you
can see for nouveau we have 125 buses
for VC for its 118 and for blob drivers
is 20 Soho but don't blame the drivers
it's not come fair comparison because
most of the fails are because of the
requirements on in the hardware that
shouldn't be during the kms tests so
that those are the long low-hanging
fruits that you can just jump in test
run the tests on other GPUs and fix them
quite easily it's about 90% of the fails
and skips I think for the kms yeah for
the open-source drivers for the
proprietary driver it is not all the API
is yep so we know that bit the the 20
test passes so that's not bad
something-something does worse
that is standard so let's also talk
about Intel G of X so now we know that
we has a testitude yeah and now about
the infrastructure we run it on so we
want to provide an accurate view of the
state of the all hardware and software
configurations we support so which one
to run as often as possible on them and
we believe that wizard should be
transparent so they should lease the
hardware configuration we have a page
that says all that Melissa all hybrid
configuration and the assigned labels
and in the results you receive from the
system you have the name of the
configuration and the results are every
Delta's every changes in the test site
we also believe that it should be fast
so basic residues should come in around
30 minutes that's heavily dependent on
how much patches sent are sent the
mailing list so usually the test one
takes on one to ten to fifteen minutes
for the fast feedback so if this is
small set that just is sanity check
whether you haven't broken anything
seriously so it takes 15 minutes but if
there are multiple order series in the
queue it will take longer but around 30
is safe bad so it
should be visible so we don't want to
have system that makes it struggle for
the developer to find the results to
explore them we are sending them to the
mailing list so if you send a batch
series the mailing list in 30 minutes
you can expect first feedback from the
CI system saying that okay
those tests you're fine to go or those
tests fail or those changes state from
pass to skip or something like that and
with all the devices listed and all the
bugs associated if we know them and also
if the series fails to build that's even
faster because when we fail tile to
build or fail to boot it's much faster
to send that feedback and the result
should be stable so we are blacklisting
all the tests that we not don't trust
yet and we try to work on them on making
them more stable and exploring whether
there's actually issues in the kernel
driver or in the test and for the no
known failures we issue a bugs and we
blacklist them during the run time so
that s our still run they don't make the
hard work going into some strange States
but they're consistently failing for
some reason and we have issues for them
we know that they are failing and the
issues for the free desktop Pro
kernel.org Bugsy's laws are listed along
the results and they do not affect you
pass or fail final result okay go so
yeah so let's talk about current state
so we are providing pretty much testing
for DRAM chip integration Brandon Martin
mentioned so all the patches that we
developed for the i9 15 should be on top
of the DRM tip we also have pretty much
testing for the test suit itself so
whenever you submit new patch for the
testitude it's also getting tested on
our infrastructure and referenced with
the previous version of the merged one
ok post-merge we are doing much more
twist so we are doing different tip as
well just to be sure that nothing was
broken
lineage trees leanness next all the DRM
fixes branches and we also have one
branch for a day fairly the
he can just push to and test whatever he
likes using current infrastructure
yeah he's the maintainer of the whole
subsystem we have totally 74 systems in
our CI running constantly and that's
about 21 different configurations that
includes like discrete points in the
result because the different
configuration of the displays connected
or SKU no we don't have low power and
high power systems
so it's from gen 3 to upcoming systems
that were not released yet so we have
from gen 3 up to kind of like which
should be reached somewhere in the
future 14 years is quite a lot of time
no we don't have yeah
developers can access them but they are
not part of CI ok so we have also
started machines as you can see in the
previous slides we have quite a lot of
tests and they take quite a lot of time
and if you would run them on a single
host it would take multi powers so we
came up with solution or sharded
machines these are identical machines in
7th or 8th copies 6 for human-like and
we just split the workload among them so
you can get full a GT run excluding the
Jim concurrent in about 40 50 minutes if
there's no queue so that helps us we
will bring timely results and we have
haswell's keep you like sandy bridges
apollo legs and Jimmy like Jimmy legs so
it's smaller pool of machines but those
are pretty current and it gets you with
pretty read those verses are pretty
important because we test the whole suit
on yet yep we also have Zenon machines
that scale once we have g bt d Broadwell
skylake for the virtualization testing
we have plenty of different monitors and
EMS and dummies connected to those
machines we have HDMI DVI DisplayPort
I've added DisplayPort MST displays DSi
ones and connected to thunderbolt and
LVDS so yeah and we are running there GT
on that so we have the fast feedback
list of around 288 tests and those are
the ones that run in 15 minutes
providing the first feedback and then we
run the full KMS suit and quite a lot of
jam tests that's around 2071 tests and
they take 50 minutes on the Charlotte
machines and as of thought put so we
started in August 2016 with 22,000 tests
executed today and we grew quite a lot
so we total are at around 850,000 tests
executed today for the whole CI system
okay and we filed the box for all the
issues we find in the CIA usually under
half a day so if there's something new
it gets filed during the workday in less
than four hours that's pretty good
weasel
and this game is called spot the holiday
week so yeah Christmas yep you can see
that we execute quite a lot of tests so
on the side that only if you can read
the left side it's millions of tests
executed and so it went up to 5.5
million yeah but before Christmas and on
the other side it's our number of bills
made per week so yeah up to 300 400
sorry yep okay and here we have
different numbers of bills per week so
the top one is DRAM Intel fixes the
orange one then we have the yadu um tip
is the biggest one it's the day long
blue one in the middle
oh no that is bad for that much work
yeah so much work is pretty much okay so
what what this slide is showing is that
post-merge testing is basically using
about half hour time and then the rest
is the boss bridge testing of all the
other branches yeah pretty much testing
of Tiran tip and jgt that's that's the
main thing okay
here we go well we've been going pretty
fast that's surprising actually
okay so what we're going to show you now
is is a demo of what we provide so this
is the landing page of our graphic CI
and because you know we are yeah you are
engineers we don't really care about the
design sure we do graphics but
ultimately you know it's an engineering
UI you just want to get to the point and
I don't want to be writing as much HTML
as I'm currently doing actually okay
anyway so first things first is knowing
what our system is running so you've got
two things you've got the short
hardware's list and the full ones so
we're gonna have a look at what we have
here
so whenever report a bug we would use
the hostname as an indicator of what it
is because you don't want to be
explaining the entire configuration
about every machine your report of
failure on so it's easier to just have a
nickname and then if people are
interested they know where to go and if
they don't know what we can teach them
because the people anyway we're gonna
read that odd our developers and I think
we can teach you know I don't know like
tens of developers to you to understand
what it is so you've got the host name
what is what users would be usually
reporting so you can see the name of the
like the brand name of it
what generation it is for the CPU and
GPU so that's the the nice nicknames
like the the public ones not the ones we
use most of the time then you can see
what are the connectors available on the
machine and then you can see what is not
connected so for instance on the first
one DVI is not connected but if a
developer would be interested in testing
DVI because he or she has a reason to
believe that it may be more problematic
than anything else then yeah we can get
a request to connect it so we don't have
to
to have as much communication as one
would expect so for instance there is
this ALK machine here has been very
problematic with DisplayPort on display
pod the machine just dies one executing
of certain tests but in HDMI it's fine
who would have thought so that's the
sort of things that is very important
you know oh and it's not updated oh well
done okay cool
then if you want to have full
information about the hardware then you
can go off on since yeah this Braswell
here and you can have all the stuff so
cpu info is well you know proxy PU so
you can check that then you can also
check what is available in the BIOS the
hardware configuration if you want to
look at the the RAM okay you can see
what ya what Ram is available so this
one only has one
Ram and it's in you know like in memory
channel a you can see the clock you can
see the voltage you can see really like
a lot of things from this ok the
hostname ironman so to see where the
bios is putting every every peripheral
in the physical address space and things
like this so that was the first two
links ok a lot more to go
next thing post much so that's all the
trees that we test i GT drm table
industry blah blah blah blah blah blah
what matters is that on the side you've
you have fast and full so we're gonna
take grm tip and go for the issues the
first issues so here you don't see the
list of 288 tests that we are running
you only see the issues for the past 5
runs or more or 6 runs for the past six
runs 505 okay I knew how to count and
not and and you can see what is going on
and here at the top you've got the list
of machines that are being tested
there's a decent amount especially for
when you don't have a 4
okay monitor but you can see that well I
mean everything is fine right most most
things are green yeah sure but not
across the board on this semi bridge
this test is the problem and then
actually not every time because
apparently once in in these five times
and so if you want to know what is going
on you can click on the test and you can
see across all the machines on the
vertical axis and way more runs so you
can see that on this Sandy Bridge this
test has been pragmatic but quite
sporadically so that's that's a nice
view and then you can click on it and
see what is going on so you can see the
list of commits that was I did between
the previous version and this new
version so if there is a regression you
could find more easily already who to
blame don't assign blame no I'm sorry
would you contact okay very good
then you can see the the log of the
execution of ITT so well in this
particular case it's just the timeout
the watchdog just killed the machine
like nothing moved for 10 minutes so
it's just yeah freaked out
so this one is probably since this test
is about reading all entries in debug FS
there is one that allows you to read the
CRC that of the of the output and if
there's no output the CRC is you're just
gonna wait for it so it likely is the
problem that in the kernel it thinks
that it has a display are active but
actually it doesn't and so it just waits
for it oopsie but you can see also the
the boot log so whatever
yeah happened at boot time so apparently
this one was taken from the CRL console
up so nothing interesting so that's what
happened before we started running the
tests and then the mask here is what
started after running the tests so you
can see that Oh watch our watchdog is
opening the watchdog and what time out
it said like 100 seconds then you can
start seeing that
a certain test is executed here court
started executing then starting this
particular sub test and then this sub
test is done blah blah blah okay so that
was the first one obviously if you look
for the full one you're gonna get a lot
more issues yes okay so that's the list
of issues only the issue so think about
otherwise loading the entire page it
takes freaking forever so you don't have
as many platforms as we said we only
have the Sandy Bridge as well Apple Lake
KB Lake and Jimena Lake so all of these
are the recent platforms and you can see
that there is like sporadic noise and
and this is this is what is the enemy
number four number one in CI you really
want to have stable results because
otherwise developers are not gonna trust
when they say when you tell them hey
actually your your patch is problematic
so this is what we need to address this
I don't know if I can move more left but
all this area here that's bad that's
really really bad if it's constantly
consistently failing super simple right
it went from fail to fail who cares
but when randomly a test goes from yeah
past two DMS one or I don't know what it
is oh it's a bug okay so do you miss one
probably yeah that is Pro Matic because
the patch has nothing to do with it
but how can a stupid CI system know that
so you'll have to have another layer of
bug filtering and we're going to talk
about it later so that is the first
layer just presentation of raw results
okay so we're not gonna click on they're
all things because you know what it
means it's gonna take forever so we're
not also gonna care about the other
trees it's exactly the same logic so now
for pretty much testing so we would you
promote on the graphic see I mean list
on wall basically for DRM tip for i GT
and well that's it let's not care about
the tribal so I don't know if you're
familiar with patch work so
patchwork is is something that got
developed by someone actually overlaps
first so it's a part of IBM and it was
developed quite long time ago and then
it was not developed for a long time and
our pure dummy unless PL yes exactly so
and then the original part for starting
to catching up modernizing the user
interface and having all the nice
feature so kind of we are now in the
fork situation when we have the free
desktop flavor of patchwork with all the
modern features and there's also the
original one we are using the free
desktop one obviously and Eric is also
the maintainer of this this Fork
so what one nice thing about it is that
it has support for patch series so
rather than having a lot of patches and
just selecting individual patches yeah
why means terrible support anyway no UI
UI wise it's really really not how I
would do it at least so what you can see
here are just a serie in a series so one
line is one patch series if a patch
series contains 100 patches then you
don't you don't see them in this view
and since we test only patch series we
don't test any video patches that would
take too long then you get test results
on a patch series and here you can have
a look at for instance this test this
patch that was sent by Chris Wilson you
can see when and you can see that there
were two revisions of it and then oh
yeah this one is bad because it of
course yeah apparently is working on a
Saturday yes Chris Wilson so and yeah
this one is more interesting so you get
a lot of different results the first one
is fic I bat so that's the basic
acceptance test that was the fast
feedback to the you are fast feedback so
you can see here that there are two
problems there were one path to a fail
and a path to an incomplete but these
were not you potentially not due to this
but series because we have a bug
associating with this particular entry
on this particular machine we're gonna
go again into that a bit later
so basically no changes so no worries
you get here link so as you know what to
do
like what you go for if you're
interested in this failure so you can
check if it is actually you know false
positive of the system that suppresses
noise or if it's actually exactly what
you will expect then you can see their
list of machines how many tests got
executed how many passes bla bla bla how
long it took and the list of commits
that dad that was before and after them
know the list of commits between the
previous tested version and new new
tested version and if you're interested
you can have a look at the full results
that does the complete like the a be a
comparison so that's the on the first
column it's the previous one and on the
right column it is the new one
so here the CI CI grm 3270 was the
baseline and then we applied the patches
and this build was named patchwork 78-75
and so yeah it's a be testing okay so
much work the idea is can you go to
patch mark yes so the idea is that it's
it's us unobtrusive as possible so it
picks up the patches from the mailing
list it has email address associated
with it and it subscribe to the mailing
list and parses them for you and
arranges them for free and when the CI
system sends the results here so what
you see by expanding this section is
also sent out as a reply to the mailing
list so you don't expect
we don't expect developers to know about
the tool to go there to discover that or
have the knowledge from somewhere they
actually are replied with the results on
the mailing list and the link to the
patch work as well and expanded results
too so it's awesome as unobtrusive as
possible
Thanks okay so yeah we're not gonna talk
too much about the rest but there's
Czech patch run so you can see if it was
fine or not and spouse also checked
that's something that we started working
on so as every pattern in these cases is
being tested but okay so that was patch
work we can also verify that that the CI
system is indeed sending results on the
on the meaning list and so let's pick up
one well here for instance you've got
this particular patch and then you get a
first result here so this patch got sent
at 8:29 and let's see how fast it it was
well exactly 30 minutes later no not so
bad
Oh a bit a bit more actually oopsie but
generally that was it so you get the
results immediately in in the manga
lists that makes it much nicer not
everything is there but the most
important things are there okay then
what else no it was here
you may also be wondering where your
patches in the queue so if it's you know
still waiting on yeah you want to know
when your patch is gonna be tested and
if you get twenty patch series sent at
the same time after the system is not
going to be able to test it in 30
minutes so we've got a cue system that
allows you to to check it out
unfortunately we made an update to to
our CI system and now this is broken but
we'll fix it on Monday but it's good
because now you can see that yeah
exactly
it would be empty so what you don't see
on the right is time posted so you can
see how long ago the patch series got
posted and indeed the last one that we
saw was posted 18 minutes ago well the
one that didn't get all the results yet
so okay and we have it for all the yeah
pretty much I stopped it accidentally
press the SDK
okay so that was pretty much so so
actually we're going down then so we've
seen how to get the results very good
now where do the issue get reported
because if you have a CI system it's
wonderful but if no one is tending to it
and reporting bugs and making sure that
the bugs get addressed it's not gonna go
anywhere so we use two of them there's
free desktop Bugzilla which is all the
bugs that we make for IG t and i 915 and
the second one is count overall for
everything else that is not support and
that is not yeah
what DRM or X or whatever so then we can
have a look at the system that we use to
suppress the test what we call black
listing before but it's more like
suppression so that's the old tool and
later work I'm gonna show you the new
tool that I've been working on that is a
bit shinier so here you what you can see
is the list of of active issues that we
have so funston's this FDO blah blah
blah you can see what is the status of
the bug when it was last updated the
summary of the bug then what tested
effects so it's actually only this test
on this particular machine and you can
see the failure rate which is quite
useful if you want to make a bug report
and you can see the history of when it
was seen last and all this so okay it
was seen only once that makes it not
that interesting but this one would be a
bit more interesting so it has this test
is problematic on three machines and we
can see the history of them all so yeah
so you can see that it was prom Matic
five runs ago six runs ago seven runs
ago well basically all of them and it's
potentially fixed already because it was
very stable and now it is not anymore so
it probably could could yeah close it so
that's the old tool and it has some
statistics and metrics you can see for
instance the number of issues over time
so it just grew because we added a lot
of machines
and we kept on adding machines but it's
slowly going down again so that is nice
and well there's there's plenty of
metrics actually but one that is it that
can be interesting for you is to see the
distribution of of testing requests
throughout time and you can see what is
the origin so the this one here the blue
well ish is AI grm tip then you get the
try bots that we will not going to talk
about it and then the Intel GPU tools is
the green one so you there's only a
couple of them so it's not very common
for them and then you what you can see
also here is how long it usually takes
so you've got weeks here at the bottom
and then though basically each line or
each column is showing a distribution of
how long it took to two tests so for
instance here it means that most of them
got tested in about two hours but then
we had a long tail and the last the the
highest one was 18 hours so sometimes it
just happens that there's a lot of
things happening in this priorities and
all this and then you can see the median
here so and that's the debt and that's
what we would like to keep down the
results and them so okay so we'll
continue with the demo if we still have
a little bit of time actually we should
you have yeah okay so I can show you the
new tool so this is the the old one that
I was saying it's not exactly the cutest
looking one but I've been working on
this new tool here that is a bit nicer
so right now there's no issues filed but
you've got a ton of untracked issues
because i imported some runs that were
that our CI system made and then we're
gonna have a look into into one of them
so let's open the first one so the first
one is on this test on this particular
well configuration our configuration and
software configuration that was a failed
by ITT standards you can see when it got
started duration how it got run you can
see the standard output of the tests
when the error output of the test and
even if there were met Colonel messages
generated during the execution so okay
and you can see the history of this one
so I imported three bugs um
you have three runs you can see here
like 36 69 36 70 and 30 and 671 and it
got them ordered properly so what we're
gonna do now is file a bug for this
because why not right we want our CI
system to be able to categorize to know
what bug it is in order to filter in CI
the the results so we know if a patch
series introducing a new problem or if
it's something that is already known
this is the tool that is gonna be like
telling the system this is known or this
is not known so we're gonna teach the
system how to know this now so um I'm
gonna just copy this up well okay it's
copied whatever and I'm gonna file a new
issue so you get this lovely thing so we
get we're gonna create a new filter and
of course it doesn't fit the screen
because yeah so there is this string
that was very well typical from this bug
it is yeah this this string at EC wake
failed with one and this is what I'm one
and match I want to match this and
actually I would like to know on which
machines it's a it's problematic and
it's all it's telling me that out of the
858 failures that I have currently do to
get the systems you know 131 or matching
this one so it's pretty good so it is
available on okay tag it doesn't really
matter but it's the DRM tape then on 31
machines okay that's a lot 10 tests okay
and one state is all of them are all
fake
so since I'm very lazy I just you know
added a button so as it would select
everything for me of course this is
unreadable because the the screen is you
know super small but I can ex I can show
what it is so here are the tags so if
you've got bugs
onlyonly industry or drm next-gen or
whatever tree you have then you can
select it there then you've got which
machines the bug is visible on well here
it's really impossible to see and then
the list of tests that are that we want
to cover awesome and the list of
statuses so the output like a failed
pass whatever so you just put all of
these then you just create this come on
what are you doing they're more effect
come on seriously well I mean it doesn't
matter let's let's pretend that it added
it here of course it's not supposed to
work I mean I use this in production and
it works except now in you know
development environment yeah exactly
but then what you need to do then is
match this filter with a bug because we
want to report bugs it's not just to
know or not know we want developers to
know also so the tool is forcing you to
associate filters to bugs one or more so
I already know that this bug is actually
this one it used to be your a TC wake
failed with 256 but then the output
changed recently but whatever so then
you just say like here is the bug and
here's the bug tracker then you put your
email address so as it's well it's known
and people can know who to contact and
then you press save so I need to to put
one and then I just press save and it's
complaining because there's no filter so
well oh well but I can show you how it
looks like on the production one I can
show you the address so that's why it's
in a different tab so on this one you
can see it's
a bit like the other one except it's a
bit more stylish so you can see the
failure rate for instance of this one so
this bug is okay a performance counter
bug and we have three filters matching
this issue because we consider that it's
somewhat like three ways of the the the
problem to appear and you can see what
is the failure rate of the issue as a
whole so it out of the twenty last runs
21 last run six times it was pragmatic
and then you can see that it was more
pragmatic this failure mode than this
one and then then this one yeah
okay so let's so what we want to do now
is keep on doing this for by adding more
hardware configurations new platforms
and new display types and especially
ones that allow you to plug in and plug
stuff automatically so it's Google's
chameleon we want to add more test
suites and more tools to auto do auto by
section so we're gonna see that now so
CI backlog energy is what I was showing
you and we are trying to I mean we're
looking into open sourcing the tool so
everyone could be using it and then
there's easy Bancha i've talked about
this project before it's an auto by
sector for changes in performance
rendering and unit tests this way you
could improve automatically debug
reports by having auto bisect on it it
would tell you how this actually was
introduced by this comment and if you
want to help us you can help us on
infrastructure of course because we're
trying to open source it on a GT because
you can write your own KMS test or test
for your actual driver and if you've got
self test also that are somewhat
impacting graphics like suspend and
things like this then then we can even
run it in our farm and file bugs because
it affects us so we all have to do it
we're not gonna do your QA because yeah
but if it it can be you know a synergy
so that would be good and here are the
contacts if you're interested I don't
know like how much do we have
okay so yeah any question yes so the
question the question is how do we
select the hardware we run on and
especially you were talking about VC for
I guess oh that we don't really deal
with so well that's a good question why
not I don't know
and we did not investigate any other
question okay how do you how do we
implement some boxing for the bills we
didn't know we do yeah there's separate
Network they're separate machines and if
something fails we just roll them over
so yeah the machine's not running you
know inside the Intel network it's
really something that is separate and
completely separated from the internet
or the corporate Internet
then we just roll over it and have a new
nothing
yeah okay
[Applause]