kind of stuck okay
oh no well wait it just long enough for
the left up to alright so hi everybody
for those who weren't here for the last
five minutes of random rambling I'm
Tobias from the Grimm project I'm a
designer there and I'm not really gonna
talk about that in detail I'm gonna talk
about the more specific topic which is
animation and specifically sort of the
ramifications of adding animation to
interfaces but before we get to that
let's briefly make the case for
animation in interfaces so I think
especially among the more like technical
maybe people in our community I think
there's this notion that animation is
like this really frivolous saying that
you can do it but it's like well it's so
much work and it doesn't really deliver
any actual value and you know it's it's
kind of eye candy and it can be that
right you can just like make your
interface and then be like oh let's have
it bloop bloop somewhere and and and
that is one way to trade it but it's I
don't think it's a very useful way to
think about it I think the more sort of
productive way to think about it is to
just think about it as adding the
dimension of time to your interface so
regular like a regular interface is just
a 2d surface and then you like do some
fake 3d sort of depth with shadows but
if you had time you have like a whole 60
frames per second between every sort of
state that people see where you can add
more animation more information it
through animation that you used to tell
people things right and that that is not
really like something that is inherently
functional or like just visual but um
you just sort of see it as an additional
way to to to communicate things to users
and here's a very simple example from
gnome
where this is when you switch between
two workspaces with no animation what
you see here is just this hard cut and
then you kind of try to look around like
figure out what happened and didn't you
look at the little sign then you're like
oh yeah now I moved up to the other
thing because so if you do all that
matching yourself the same thing with an
animation looks like this so immediately
this this animation tells you that there
is a spatial model here things are above
and below each other and later when
you're like not even in the overview you
can just use the the shortcut keys to go
back up and down because you learned
this from the animation and this is one
of many ways that you can use animation
functionally and but that's not really
what this talk is about what I want to
talk to you about is sort of if we do
animation first of all what are things
that we want to avoid and second of all
what follows from that so a couple of
pitfalls that we're all familiar with
you know like animation is great but
most of the time like somebody gets
really enamored with an animation
they're like oh how about we make it
three seconds and make the user wait and
this is a great example Mac OS where
like if you add a workspace there's this
button that you click and the thing
moves all the way to the areas of the
screen and while it's doing that you
can't actually click the button again so
for these kinds of like things that
happen a lot in your interface that
people do a lot it really doesn't make
sense for very slow animations because
people get it after a while
whereas maybe if it's animation it's you
only see once in onboarding it's fine if
it's a little slower but so yeah
generally make your animations fast and
then maybe a second common thing is like
interfaces that go way overboard and
like the problem with animation is that
or like one of the things about
animation that you have to really
consider it's the fact that it's really
good at grabbing your attention but if
you overdo it like you're gonna get
crazy fast so you need to like make sure
that you communicate the things that are
important and you don't overdo it with
with your animations because that does
just like to distract from the content
so these are kind of the obvious cases
let's get to the more interesting ones
this is the iOS home screen up until i
OS 11 and this is animation when you
open an application so what happens is
you click the icon it zooms in like the
whole home screen zooms in and all the
icons get bigger right the whole home
screen is now huge and the icon has
transformed into the app and so this is
great so far right we know now that we
are inside this huge space and like this
is our app right the problem is if you
go to multitasking you get kind of an
opposite animation but now you're
somewhere else and all that stuff that
it just told you like those icons being
around you that's now not true anymore
and if you go all the way to decide
there's another homescreen inside the
home screen so you know I'm like there
are some inconsistencies there from from
a spatial perspective and things like
don't really line up and I think this
this example is is it's indicative of a
way of thinking that we've had an
interface designed for ever really
because up until very recently like
doing lots of animations was not really
feasible from a hardware perspective and
so it's fine if you're not doing any
animations to just like design all your
screens right and then think well maybe
we'll add an animation here or there or
something because at the end of the day
like if you just loop between screens
director you don't have to think about
these kinds of things and so like this
the screen based kind of way of
designing sort of works like this you
you design all your separate screens
right there's like a home screen that's
this grid of icons and then we have the
full screen application and then the
switcher is its own separate thing and
then at some point later we think like
oh how are we going to connect these two
screens and then how we're going to
connect those two screens but if you do
that you don't think about like how all
those things exist inside one larger
system and that's I think how you get
this this inconsistency I mean I don't
know how that example happened in
practice like I can only speculate but I
think
if you if you do animate all your
transitions at the end of there you
always have to contend with space
because in the users mind they don't
think about screens they think about the
stuff they see on the screens and so as
a user I see a thing and then I see
another version of that thing I expect
them to like just be the same thing just
transform
I don't expect there to be multiple
versions of stuff and sort of there's a
whole bunch of implications that come
from this and so I think we need a new
way way of approaching like a new
process for designing interfaces that
takes the store into account if we are
going to do animation and this new
approach is semantic animation the the
difference with semantic animation
compared to the process we've just seen
is this instead of thinking about the
screens as units first you think about
what's on the screens first you think
about semantic components that have a
meaning and that have States and so in
this case we have this app component
that's like an icon or an open app or a
card and those are the three states that
we have and then we have a bunch of
transitions right those five transitions
are all this sort of transitions that we
will have to handle and we think through
that entire system and then when we
actually get to the physical sort of
rectangles that are visible on on the
user's device it's kind of obvious what
their animations are gonna be right the
icon is the same thing as the full
screen apps it just expands the whole
Holmstrom doesn't have to zoom that's
not really necessary for this to work
and then when we go to the multitasking
thing it just gets a little bit smaller
right but it doesn't affect everything
else because that's just not necessary
for for this component to change the
state and interestingly this is exactly
what is eleven dead so now it's a little
fast but if you look on the part here
you can see that the homescreen doesn't
actually zoom the home screen just like
fades a little bit into the background
but it doesn't do anything crazy and so
on the multitask animation what happens
is it's still there so
we have not broken the promise of like
like in the other example we we are sort
of keeping that off that stuff behind
the application around and all that
happens is our sort of application
component changes its state and like I
really love this example because it's
been like under all of our noses for the
past five years and they just recently
fixed it and I'm so happy so yeah some
examples one very common pattern is this
kind of interface with it's like a list
of things and then each of those things
you can click it and then you see a
little more of it right so like this is
an email client the default is email
client and you see that the email and
the sort of detailed view of the email
are totally separate right but for the
user that doesn't make a ton of sense
because for them the email is like a
semantic idea right like this is my
email so why would there be two of them
and why would there be like I don't know
a totally separate thing over there on
the side and this is especially
interesting in the context of this email
application that does the exact same
thing like functionally but it doesn't
duplicate the object right see that it
actually comes from within the preview
and and this is the kind of this is the
kind of thing I mean now there's a lot
of examples of this and sort of I think
you're getting the idea you basically
think of what all the states are that
your components have and you think of
all the transitions and then you will
not have these contradicting situations
because you've already thought of them
so but I also know what what what are
your thinking sort of on a larger level
right because those of us here who are
designers and developers look at this
and they're like dawg I cannot
implement this because like all of our
all of our toolkits all of our layout
technologies are just fighting us on
this left and right and so I would like
for the second part of this talk I'd
like to talk a little bit about how
we're gonna do this and so I think it's
important to keep in mind
in that regard that there are some
things that maybe we will not be able to
do for a couple of years or maybe like
even many years because the technologies
we need to catch up but there are also a
few things that we can do right now and
so like if we sort of look at the
timeline of that I'd like to talk about
a few points on that timeline like first
of all what can we do today right with
the technology that we have this is an
example from from Gloam this is the
genome to do app in its version like
that came out last year 326 and you can
like drag and drop these tasks and when
you click on what happens is you get
this like panel coming from the side
with the details everybody we want to
edit the thing like you have to click it
and then it's like a totally separate
thing that shows you the details of the
same which is exactly the pattern we
just talked about with the email right
and what we did in 328 is with it this
instead you can click it and from within
that preview comes the actual detail
stuff which functionally the exact same
thing but like semantically makes so
much more sense and this is something
that we were able to do relatively
easily because GDK already has this
thing called I think GDK revealer that
that just does this thing it's like
expands the thing sort of like an
accordion and there are things like this
that you can do in a lot of in a lot of
technologies where you have an idea of
sort of how the components should behave
and maybe you can't get the perfect
animations but thinking through all of
the component stuff I think it's useful
even if you maybe don't do any animation
because you have like a clearer picture
of what's what's going on so that's the
that's the present let's talk a little
bit about the future so over the past
few years I've built a bunch of pretty
hacky prototypes trying to explore some
of these ideas this one is it's one of
the most interesting ones I think it's
like I built it for a large touch table
it was like a university kind of
research project where you would
essentially like order food by dragging
these
towards you so you could like you know
drag drag this towards you but then you
the the plates are sort of semantic
components so you see like the the label
when it goes away it like goes into the
component and the the like detailed view
for it comes from behind the plate and
so I was exploring some of these ideas
there and it looks and also like there's
the spatial navigation where you have
like these these categories on the
horizontal axis and the sort of checkout
flow on the vertical and it looks really
simple right but the implementation is
just a garbage fire because like this is
this is actually just super simple
component actually has five different
states which is like when it's not
spawned yet it's it's invisible there in
the middle and then you sort of respond
it to the grid and has the label and
then you start dragging it and you need
to get rid of the label and then you
order it you need to change the
constraints it needs like be fixed to
your viewport and like there's the
dialogue and doing all that stuff I mean
I built this in web technologies but I'm
not sure it would be any different in
like most other stacks because most
technology's just expected you like give
them a bunch of XML files those are the
states and now click OK and go to that
other XML file and doing this kind of
stuff just requires hacks on every level
at the moment and which is why it's it's
not really feasible in real world
product products I think unless you have
insane engineering resources this is a
second prototype that exposed a little
bit of a different idea well it's kind
of like this this chat email sort of
thing that actually sort of goes
directly from the preview to the full
view without ever sort of having
duplicate items or breaking breaking
spatial consistency and you can actually
like interactively kind of drag and drop
the thing to expand and an open it I
mean like this is also very small and
tacky prototype but this is I think the
kind of thing that we should enable in
layout technologies and sort of toolkits
to make easier
so yeah that's a little bit about the
future now how do we get there
and I think I've already alluded to this
we need tools that sort of just have
this baked into them and that makes this
really easy and this will have to happen
both on the design side and on sort of
the toolkit development side a little
bit about like from my experience from
my experience what what would be what
would be good to have an on the
development side in in the web ecosystem
there's a lot of like talk about reacts
these days and sort of stare hole but
you know you need a directional data
flow and you have like this one
hierarchy of components where like this
component renders these sub components
and I think that really goes in the
right direction what they don't have and
were like what is much harder there is
to like have multiple states and
actually do animations between it stuff
but I think like that that ecosystem is
going I think in an interesting
direction so probably like if we were
thinking of like the future API for
awesome interfaces that I think would be
an would be an interesting part of it
then yeah like the whole component idea
where each component is essentially a
state machine but not only that like
each of those sort of state machines
it's made up of smaller components there
are also state machines we saw like
essentially like you have your list that
has like three states and then the list
is made up of list items that also have
like two states each or something like
that
I think like that that is also an idea
that that goes in the right direction
but yeah I mean take all of this with a
grain of salt I'm like a designer and
sometimes web developer and then the
other thing that's also really hard to
do right now is like actually sort of
transitioning the properties without
just manually putting lots of values
like hard-coded values all across your
code like just declaratively defining
all your components and then like these
are the properties in state a these are
the properties in state B just
automatically like between them and then
yeah for interactive animations super
super hard to do right now I think in
almost everything because what do you
and that even goes kind of against like
the component idea in a way because then
you
if you want to do that declaratively
like you have to sort of map the input
to the two like the property changes so
like that that introduces a whole bunch
of in-between states and I think like
that that is maybe a whole separate
discussion on its own so a couple of
things that I'm excited about as I said
the react ecosystem there's a bunch of
libraries for react there's something
called react flight that kind of allows
you to like have a bunch of states and
then it will automatically tween them
but it's a little hacky and like HUD and
I haven't actually personally tried
using it and then in react native they
have this thing called like animated
values where you will essentially like
assign a value to a like you sign this
like value variable to a property and
then you change it somewhere else and
that kind of like allows you to nest
these structures like it's really
complicated I barely understand it but
it's it seems it seems promising
um and then I think another ecosystem is
very interesting is like the the kind of
prototyping tools they're mostly Mac
apps for the most part but like this is
also a JavaScript library that's kind of
ecosystem has a lot of interesting stuff
this is a tool called framer that's a
JavaScript library that you can use to
sort of prototype interface it's not
actually for production use but they
have like this idea of components with
States and they actually do most of that
like animation stuff that I talked about
where like you can animate between those
states so that's definitely I think a
very interesting thing to look at and
then finally I'm very excited about GDK
for coming out
soonish may be end of the year or
something which will make animations
much easier from what I understand which
also take it with a grain of salt and
there's a lot of like really cool work
happening there about sort of redoing
the way we do layout with constraints
and stuff like that and we've actually
been talking about potentially sort of
like having graphical tools that allow
you to to kind of like have have these
these nested components structures and
edit them in a graphical way which
ultimately is probably what you want
right probably we want some kind of
interface builder that just allows you
to visually build these graphs of states
so yeah I mean as you can see this is
all like very hand wavy and like maybe
at some point in the future but I think
yeah this is the direction that's that I
feel like it's most promising to work in
but that's sad if any of you have any
ideas in this direction or like are
involved in somewhere like oh yeah this
is the thing that we've already solved
wait just a second then we've already
solved I would love to hear about it and
like come talk to me or you know come to
IRC and um design you know find me so
yeah that was like a brief look at
semantic animation and sort of where I
think we are right now in the timeline
towards the future and with that I'd
like to thank you and if there's any
questions let me know all right that was
Wonder I think
I think I need to repeat the question
right okay sorry go on yeah sorry I
don't I guess I need to remember right
so okay so the question or remark was
that qml or right already kind of does a
lot of this stuff with nested components
and like mapped values if I understood
correctly right ends declarative and
yeah that sounds very interesting what I
would be interesting is like doesn't
have states like so okay interesting we
should talk more any more questions
remarks discoveries as we've just yes I
do I haven't used it personally I mean I
know it how it works
yeah absolutely
okay so the remark was the principle for
the Mac does sound the stuff with what
it's called drivers right yeah I think
like a lot of these these sort of
experimental Mac Mac prototyping apps
have some really cool ideas what I would
really like to see is like those ideas
going more to do like into the base
technologies where you just like can use
it and don't have to don't because then
at the end like what I've heard a lot of
times is like the designers makes these
cool sort of prototypes and then the
developers like kill me now but yeah
thanks okay okay that's great to hear
there was another question here
so the question is do I think that
animation improves productivity in
graphical user interfaces so um I think
that's maybe the wrong question to ask
that's like asking does color improve
productivity in user interface you can
you it's another variable that you use
to design Wesley you can use it in ways
that might impact productivity but like
that's a very sort of difficult thing to
measure in the first place right
like does you know if we use more like I
don't know color or contrast in our I
can just that kinda improve the
productivity maybe but it's something
that we can use and that we sort of have
the academic sort of proof for lack of a
better word that like humans can sort of
be we thought about things with and and
that can be useful for anything I think
also yeah in general like any kind of
productivity applications yes whether
the user learns so the quest or like the
remark was the they're sort of the idea
of like animations being something that
used to teach people and then maybe
later they're more in your way right if
I'm Anderson correctly rather than
helping and I think that's definitely a
fair point
I think for the most part like that's
what I sort of alluded to before if it's
something in the onboarding process that
you only see once it can be slow it
doesn't really matter if it's something
that you see every day it should be like
200 milliseconds and that's it I think
like at that point like if they're not
fostered and sort of like they're really
sort of the limit of perception I think
there's not really a huge game that you
can get by like shaving off maybe 20
more because humans can't really react
in the time I anyway right so at that
point I'm not sure like maybe you could
speed them up a little bit but I think
that's a larger sort of discussion about
should we change interfaces as your
users learn them I think there's also
like sort of that's another point of
contention that I think it's maybe
separate from
discussion entirely last question right
yeah so the question was like yeah we
just talked about Mac OS prototyping
tools what do we have on Google Inc I'm
sorry to say nothing I mean there's
JavaScript libraries and that's what I
do I just like basically figure out the
thing on paper and in Inkscape and then
write a little bit of very bad and tacky
code it's not very efficient and I'm
sure it could be better like if I have
any graphical tools but if anyone's
interested in working some tools for
that I would be interested to talk yes
suggestion yes the suggestion was using
figma which personally as someone who
cares about software freedom cannot
endorse I'm sorry
you