so for economical is the flexibility as
I'm going to do a demon that is being
worked on
it's not yet a master it will be
released again forever for let me ask
who has no idea what let's leave
okay before birthday it's putting a
magnet for system containers that means
your container will look like pollution
so I'm not going to speak about that no
I will assume that you know something so
I have three beautiful machines here
each one is run in a plain black sea
demon just spread from from that branch
field as you know the legs Digimon
usually knows only about thinners on the
machine from home but I will click
create a cluster of these three demos
from these three Ian's and they will
appear you as one you can use the
regular Alex the API transparently
against the class render there are also
these the first thing I need to create
the class that can be done is in it
commander asked you to create the faster
yes some leaders but it's just the name
of the node address if I'm driving
note no trespass for them I will create
a storage pool just the default values
which will use the best pool backed by
fire
a network bridge
all right this is the boost up now so
this is the first note of your posture
and you may see it's been successfully
configured that I can go recently so I
can go to the second node and run again
[Music]
and change the name of the Machine and
the address
I'm joining an existing cluster now I
have to give the address of this one
this will last me for the trust password
and accept a fingerprint yes it will
warm a little data will be lost
yes care right now and asked for storage
of the gryphon that has mentioned the
original node and network operation as
well so now see we still have no notes
but by Iran
let's see cluster list as well
so you can see there are now two notes
in the glass there and that I'm going to
add another one with the same sequence
of comments essentially yes
I'll go dance
okay so this was a stove on
yes I want to news class get dressed
[Music]
yes and no now has the classroom now has
three three notes so I can use the Lexy
common line transparently across the
cluster who know some containers for
example for example I can launch an
[Music]
image called Swan anything
Thanks and with this new flag / / target
I choose one of the three notes for
example I'm on notes trillion 3 gamma 5
actory I can target m3 with the whole
image and start the container or there
and once the container is started it
could be visible from all clusters all
nodes in the classes I can mount another
one on the m2 / axis
Oh for ya thank you this is still
looking for less so that's in the
meantime I can go to the fourth mode
which is the game 3 and that is by list
the containers like I can see it's there
anything was created from the from the
fourth one last one exists and also from
the second node this is visible so this
is created and still stopped but they
should be started right now yes both are
running and if for example I shut down
the first node I shut down so it's not
there anymore and they list the
containers I will see that the first
container is down there there's an arrow
on c1 and post the list of clusters we
show me that this particular node is
offline I think I can still create
plaster for the notes that that are like
for example I can change the
configuration of global past events such
as the trust password well surely that
is there yes there is a trust password
I can unset it for example
and it's not there anymore so the first
note doesn't know of course about this
change and I can't even shut down this
third note that I just made this
modification on and restart the fourth
on the n3 and the change will be
automatically replicated so if I run the
show
you can see that the trust password is
not there so you're given in the note is
down when it comes up the state gets
replicated and I can listen again
they're still there the note 2 was was
up so it's still lying so the way this
is done by replicating the signal like
Wagner had lovely using raft so the
point is that it's very convenient to
greatly don't need separate photo and
distributed data store it's all in
process of all you need to run is the
next process it will take or care of
failover and
[Music]
of your data you might ask why
probably classroom management is
considered by some solved the problem
since I was wondering that myself
probably at the beginning I asked why
don't we just create a CRI plugin for
other medicine and let people drive a
single legs in all the yeah that is
possible but the drawback is and also
kubernetes is a big drive so one of the
use cases also Stefan mentioned these
systems applications that were not
designed with cloud application that are
not cloud painted and need in cases
expect full systems and that can work in
on system contain but not so well an
application contain and soon we hope
that this feature clustering makes it
easier to run those warm thoughts
without the operational overhead
associated with the state permeate is
lower solutions so that was it
I can't short if there are questions or
anything I know I went through rather
quickly so let me know questions yes
the network falafel contains so if the
note that you saw the question is how
feel over for containers for if the note
you are running on dies of course your
container process dies in that case that
there's nothing you can do but for
example what you could do is use a SAP
as storage back-end for four different
systems of your containers in that case
if your container dies unknown you can
pick another node and start speaking and
it could be really the same state as it
was because what was written on this is
replicated by set that is an example but
clustering by like XP clustering by
itself does not manage container
failover that's out-of-band it gives you
some primitives to build on you have
options one is a certification with
staff there are others but yeah this is
more or less it
so yeah I'll show you
so as I mentioned very briefly what
we've done is to create a little patch
to the sequel light which replicates the
sequel light blog is a rough draft
algorithm so it gives it a split brain
and in order to make a database change
for example an update sequel query with
this machinery you need to have a form
of nodes that are knowledge that you
wrote that right allow the entry if you
don't have a forum and the Gryphon face
because of split brain this just failed
the trade-off here is that raft in the
like cat spectrum consistently
availability partitioning gives you
consistency and partitioning but not
availability in that case the class is
not a little more and more but you won't
get inconsistency so it won't work but
it won't do harm so you need to have bad
form of nodes and then the actual
current base we call it as
love is itself so if there's a bit
drained they do they all know exactly
what their prom should be read others
mommy knows you can see me so the
windows
[Music]
okay the design is that each node is so
the question is can you have just one
single node which is your point of
reference and all the Grecians changes
from that node and the other knows you
don't touch them you don't use them the
answer is probably no because the design
that each node is is equal in some sense
with some details perhaps in the future
what will you be able to do is to set
users and permissions to limit for
example who can the water from for now
all nodes are are equal
yes just like that two things that I
mentioned
one of them is if you feel that a 14
especially on your straight at the base
notes there's no reason Bobby modems
free he always makes it goes three
percent increments that's what makes our
computer makes me knows that base notes
on them just goes to dat i you know the
other thing that might come in your
question tomorrow his leg speed by
itself supports company containers
company company images in augusta bitch
win
next we know it's even at the hospital
so you can Tory of a Tom Kha still tasty
and it's just the end that computer
containers coming forth that's perfectly
fine just like you got to like sneakers
girls want Wallach staging a college and
you can also cut your campaign has a new
images in between the two student no
more next eat
what will happen when I will create a
contender we found a target for now it
creates the container on the note you
are persecuting the command on by the
release it will pick the node with the
least number of containers yes so it's a
try to very simply load balancer
at work rules by default if you don't
specify target between people this is
basic basic scheduling star we see that
we can