everything we're about to say is a lie
so don't be basing the decisions on it
we're here to tell you a few well-chosen
words about Java and this particular
Java in a world of containers of
containers and clouds micro-services and
all those buzzwords managed to fill up
the whole room just based on those
buzzwords I guess so
let's we'll go through a bunch of things
25 minutes we'll try to sprint through
it and not for the best again let's
start out with on a high level Java in a
world of containers so in general in the
world of containers we expect a few
different things so the first one is
that we expect safety and security to
become increasingly more important over
time both on like you know we've seen
both obviously on the software side but
more recently also the hardware side
that security well it can be a bit of a
thing let's say so over time we expect
that to just increase and become even
more important we also expect there to
be a lot of sprawl and what I mean by
that or sprawl it comes in a few
different flavors the first one is that
we expect there to be a large very large
number of instances you basically are
encouraged to create instances and
create processes on the fly and create a
lot of them run more small instances
rather than a few large ones so that's
one of the major shift to a seeing you
we also expect there to be a lot of
different applications where in the past
maybe you ran the same thing over and
over again with containers
you're almost encouraged to create
custom containers and custom images on
the fly when you need them instead so a
mix of applications we expect these
containers to run on a mix of different
machines heterogeneous systems not all
machines look the same way and also with
different configurations so even if you
you know you can and maybe in some cases
it will help to create containers that
look at the same way in many cases you
will probably tailor make them with
different settings and so on and so
forth
so bringing that over to what it means
for Java so we like to think that Java
is ideally suited for running
applications in this type of environment
so and there are many different reasons
this slide lists a few of them it's
everything from the fact that well after
all we have a managed language at
runtime that gives you all the the
benefits of not having to care about you
know malloc and free and pointers and we
do bounce checking for you and all those
both those nice things that we've come
to learn and and love about Java we have
with the JVM we are abstracting the
exact environment you running in we're
both when it comes to operating systems
to CPUs and all that we are John Rose
mentioned earlier today that the whole
platform is a reliable one both in terms
of obviously stability but also the fact
that we value compatibility very highly
so it's a key design goal of ours to
make sure that new functionality will be
backwards compatible and even forward
compatible and and really try to make
sure that when you take your app and
deploy it on another version of the JVM
or the JDK it will just continue to work
and you get all the nice benefits of
moving up the JVM also obviously adapts
to any changes in in the environment and
make sure you take advantage of whatever
is in there and compile code is needed
and all those nice things and of course
we have a very rich ecosystem built
around all of this many different
frameworks and libraries that all make
this a good environment to run Java in
yeah so with all that said we are
committed to like obviously continuing
with the stuff we've done but also
committed to making sure that Java is
the first choice when it comes to
deployments in container environments or
cloud environments in general how many
people in here have played around with
docker
excellent how many people have created a
docker image with Java in it okay most
of you okay good okay good good so I'll
go through these next few slides really
quickly it was just a background if you
have never touched talking before so the
point is it's super simple to create a
docker image with Java inside of it you
basically create a directory structure
not unlike this you create your doctor
file you put your JDK target Z in there
and your application in this case
HelloWorld you create well and I should
say inside of that docker file you
select your base image so what what
operating system effectively do you want
to base this image on you say well put
the data key inside of that set up some
environment stuff tell the the docker
image to what what to run when it starts
up yeah and then basically you go
through two different steps one of which
you do ahead of time to be months ahead
of time you'd be so will it is building
the actual image so in this case I'm
building that image and I'm calling it
I'm giving it a tag my /jt nine it could
be anything and then from that image you
stamp out individual containers when you
start up the application so to speak and
and obviously you can reuse the image
across machines and again across time as
well yep
like composing my people a shared round
independently of each other but there is
also a cost to having lots of layers
which is the overlay file system support
layer so generally like that three four
five pipeline doctor file is minimal as
well to squash your images into a single
there
so now when we know how to create darker
images one of the things I'd like to
talk about a bit is crazy creating
custom je Ari's so it turns out that if
you take the JDK the world good old JDK
we've been used to dealing with for a
long time and you just bake that into
all your darker images or in general
into into your deployment it can be a
bit on like the large and unnecessarily
large side let's say the whole JDK
weighs in at around let's say half a gig
it's 568 Meg's is I think the JDK 90 JDK
on Linux x64 and as much as like it
contains a lot of great things you have
the stuff that you absolutely want
java.lang Java Ione io things like that
it also contains a lot of different
things that probably you don't want
we're trying to help you not want them
over times the core but for example
we're trying to deprecated and remove
but that said there are there's a lot of
stuff that in there that you either
don't need or at least for some some
application probably they're not needed
so with JT 9 and which exhaust in the
lk9 we now have the support both in
terms of modules and tooling to create
theories on the fly as you need them and
for tailor-made for your application and
yeah yeah right in the past we only
provided you with basically one JRE it
was like DJ ori and we decided what went
into that JD JRE specifically but now
you have the option of saying well i
want these and these pieces one thing
you cannot exclude this java rock base
that module is needed to well start up
the JVM at all but in basically for your
application you can select really what
you want to include and we also have
tooling to help you select whatever
should go into the JRE so specifically
there's a jade depths tool that now
lives in the jdk itself and you can
point it at the class file or a jar file
and it will help you spit out the
modules that it depends on so I for
example here this and these are just the
first few lines of running that on the
Tomcat jar I found somewhere and it's
saying that
you need Java to face Java instruments
German aiming there were a few other
things but basically that's that's it in
a nutshell so creating a custom theory
is very straightforward you use two
jailing tool that then mentioned earlier
and you you give it a few options so the
example there shows how I'm creating a
JRE with only the Javadoc base module in
it I'm basically saying create spit out
a JRE in this directory the directory in
question is my - JRE I'm saying pick up
the modules from here the modules live
inside of the JDK so you start out with
your JDK and you say pick modules from
this JDK and I only want to include Java
top base and a few microseconds later
you'll have a Jade JRE that is
tailor-made to only include Java top
base and you can run hello world with it
it should be noted that the application
hello world or Tomcat or whatever you're
running does not need to be module
modularized to armaid modular where to
use this you can create it for your own
let's say job applications even before
what do I do the build stage at the
start saving stuff in there and this is
where
and then you can copy things in the
second kind of stanza from the Java
field and you only end up with the data
and players from the so what kind of
benefits can you get by doing all of
this why would you create your own gary
well yeah it turns out that one of the
key things is obviously science but dan
mentioned there's more to it than that
it's what as well I'm going to talk a
bit about size specifically over the
next few slides and the first one here
is showing a chart with three bars on it
the large dish one there is the JDK as I
mentioned it's five hundred and sixty or
so Meg's
and again it contains a lot of great
stuff a lot of which you may not need so
the other two bars are showing what a
corresponding Java top base only JRE
would look like so here this is where
I've run jailing can I've said only
include Java top base and I end up with
something ballpark 50 Meg's which is
obviously you know pretty pretty sweet
savings almost like 10 times or more
than 10 times even yeah it's it may well
be the case that a lot of applications
need more than Java dot base so as some
kind of you know more realistic number
we've created something called natty
it's like quote neti it's it's a set of
modules that are like key for your job
applications it's almost like likely
that that it will work if you include
those modules so it's but obviously it
depends on exactly which application you
have but as you can see we're still down
like almost like ten times smaller sixty
Meg's or so so that's pretty sweet you
know it's starting to get bearable let's
say still a bit large compared to I
guess your average C++ application or
something but then again you get all the
benefits of Java and the safety and all
that I should point out that the nanny
bars and all of these bars they don't
contain any application it's just the
Jade or EE itself the core libraries of
JVM so obviously depending on what is
what you add on top of this it will
become bigger the size can be optimized
further one of the key ways of doing
that is by specifying a command-line
option - J link called - - compressed or
there's a short version of it as well
and basically what that does is take
some of the resources we have in the JRE
and compress them so it's not entirely
unlikely that you'll see something
ballpark 25% savings on top of all of
this so you can squeeze it down even
further
good point
okay so now we've optimized the JDK or
the J or if it's a will and it turns out
that if you if we now go back to and
look at what a full docker image would
look like you look something along the
lines of this so on the left hand side
there I have Oracle Linux because I work
at Oracle but you know think any Linux
distribution and obviously you can tell
that like we can continue optimizing
that top 46 Meg's but it's not gonna
make a big difference if like the bottom
thing is still the big one right so time
to start looking at what we can do on
that side and one of the things we can
look at is obviously sort of in the same
vein as like using J link on the jdk
side we can look at stripping down the
Linux distribution itself and it turns
out that there is a version of the
Oracle Linux docker image called the
slim version and it's basically the like
the same thing but stripping out
everything that an application is
unlikely to use and that's obviously a
good thing you know if the application
in the end doesn't P did why include it
at all
and in general it's true obviously that
in the world like the one we have with
docker in containers you're unlikely to
sort of log into your containers part
managing it and running things on the
command line so as long as it runs the
process and as long as it runs the
application you have inside of your
image it doesn't really matter what the
base image is as long as in our case it
runs Java
why would we care about the exact
distribution that is running so with
that in mind surely there must be
something we can do about those let's
say 100 or so Meg's or base image and
that's where we queue up Alpine Linux
and the muscle sea library so alpha and
Linux is a distribution that has this
it's tag line that it's small simple and
secure and it's basically targeting
environments much like you know the ones
we're describing here with dr. in
containers on the key interest for us on
the Java side is that it's using the
muscle C library so normally on Linux
you'd see the do C library that's what
you know we don't even think about it
all that much we almost associate the
university library with Linux but
obviously there's nothing preventing you
from running another C library and the
muscle C library has that it's tag line
that is lightweight fast simple in lots
of different things yeah in the end it
should just be another C library right
the old C libraries should be the same
and you know it's a standard API and
whatever it is and that turns out to be
almost true hence we created the open
prov open JDK project Portola Thank You
John Rose for the name comes from by the
way the fact that Alpine Road in Bay
Area leads to Portola Valley yeah nerds
do you know exactly where all nerds here
so the the product is the goal of the
product is to provide the port of the
JDK to the Alpine Linux distribution or
more accurately because it turns out
that what's relevant for us is the
muscle C library and I the stages the
status of the product right now is that
it's sort of working we have the code
all the changes that we know are needed
in the
forests we're in the repo and it's sort
of working only we haven't integrated
into mainline yet and I will get back to
to that in a second but basically in a
nutshell the changes needed were
relatively straightforward there's a lot
of you know if you have code and you've
only worked with a single library for a
long time then you tend tend to rely on
things that are in the end libraries
specific in this in our case you know
you see library specific and a lot of it
was just shaping up codes that are
actually compiled I happen to be the
lead of this project and I happened to
be the person who made those changes
again they're sort of straightforward we
found one latent bug in hotspot while
doing this and that has been integrated
into mainline so that's all ready to go
okay the good part about Alpine Linux is
that it weighs in at four megabytes so
that's pretty impressive basically it is
to see library and nothing else
it does have busybox inside of it as
well you do get some tools for obvious
reasons but it's very very small and
what that means is that we can take our
you know whatever it is a hundred and
fifty or so megabytes and turn it more
into 50 megabytes and now we're starting
to say get to the point where yeah we
can optimize it further but it's
starting to look pretty good
I have a section in here that I tore out
which is talking about the minimal VM so
there's this version of at the hospital
um that only contains a subset of the
components that brings down the size of
the VM from the Lib jb MSO from
approximately 20 banks down to 5 so that
will save some additional space but then
you don't get all the functionalities
there's a trade-off to what I have two
questions coming up on this so the first
one is is there interest in Alpine app
or to alpine in here hands up
ok a bunch of hands second question
anybody interested in helping maintain
it hands up I tried ok yeah so again
there are only axis minor E's we publish
there there next to the normal be a
binary sub ten and all that so please go
ahead download them if you have feedback
if you have questions if you want this
do speak up because we need the feedback
to understand if it's worth moving
forward with
size matters but I didn't mean okay
let's touch on a few of the features
we're working on that are specifically
well suited to docker let's say the
first one is something that a few people
have already touched on so I'm gonna go
through it extremely quickly which is
sharing across instances now we've
optimized the size of a single instance
by bringing down the size of the image
and all that what can we do to to
leverage the fact that we're running
multiple instances next to each other on
the same machine yeah and on the
operating system side you already get
that two shared libraries that's the
sort of standard mechanism for doing
exactly that
so on the for the JDK we already get
that type of sharing with the the shared
library that makes up the JVM itself and
all that but what about Java class data
and then in general stuff that is
specific to Java s class data sharing
was already touched on but in essence
it's doing exactly that it's taking data
that that we have inside of the JVM so
data that was read from the byte the
class files and massaged into something
that the JVM liked better
and what this functionality does is to
dump that data down on into a file that
can then be used later as you start up
additional
right we if it's good to point out that
when we created this many years ago it
was more meant for multiple processes on
the same machine but since dr. is in the
indian sharing the same file systems
like deep down inside if you put if you
cleverly put the archive in a shared
image then it can be shared across
different doc containers as well yeah we
are yes so quick quick you just we have
seen good startup time improvements I'm
no I know fault Curtis has not seen the
exact same numbers let's say but we've
seen good startup time reduction and
also footprint savings I'll mention
quickly that we're also working on alt
which does the same thing but for JTED
code experimental so far but being
worked on last part we're going to talk
about is how we are adding support in
the dadk for honoring the limits that
you can set when you create and
configure docker containers so the JVM
obviously as you all know has a bunch of
different ergonomics inside of it that
makes like it looks at the environment
where it's running and it's trying to
size things correctly both the heap size
the number of threads
you know how who will serve set up and
so on and so forth and we talk to
returns out that this is not transparent
as in we need to do something explicitly
it doesn't just work to look at the same
old numbers so a lot of work has gone in
lately into making sure that the JVM is
aware of these things
[Music]
and Jacob will try its best to represent
both in terms of the choices that are
made by but also to your code and you
ladies code in runtime available
processes which is looked at by life by
succession 18 points like lots of IDs we
use that to size that thread pools
there's a lot of detail what they wrote
up on this what we found is that on a
very large machine starting lots of jail
units in containers with slower than the
starting lots of Genesis virtual
machines even with the hypervisor over
there because thread pools are being
sized the host and
we specify everything wanted to pay a
hundred forty four place but everything
and it was in JK ten we've done some
experiments in the movements of JDK ten
minutes yes sure you can ice to mention
why doesn't the heap size isn't the only
memory Canadian uses so there's a couple
of flights for allocating the percentage
of the container
so yeah that last slide that's on the
real neural resource limitations or
limits we've done a lot of other type of
work as well making sure that our tools
or serviceability tools J command J
stack and all those work across
container boundaries as well more work
is coming this is as I said we're
committed to making sure that the other
runs really well in containers so keep
your eyes and ears open for more coming
up
[Applause]