all right next step is going to be an
security all right how's everyone doing
oh god somebody here react to me so
today I'm going to be talking about
Korea security best practices this is
gonna be pretty high-level overview I'm
not gonna get too deep on this stuff but
by way of introductions I'm in I work at
at Google I'm based in Tokyo Japan and I
do a lot of you know kubernetes related
stuff go and I have a background mostly
in Python development so I heard earlier
that some folks were kind of waiting for
Python for before they migrated so just
just to let you know that I'm waiting
for Python for - I'm kind of a Python -
person I kind of skipped the
odd-numbered versions and if you're a
Python 3 person that really likes that
you know so how many of you have
actually touched communities have run
coop control ok yeah like pretty much
everybody so I'm I want me to tell you
that you know Kirby's describing
companies as a coup as a container
Orchestrator is kind of a misnomer it's
it's a lot of things I like to think of
it as an Operations framework so it like
provides a lot of features that you can
use to do operations make things like
you know more fluid that sort of thing
but you guys know all this already so
today what I'm going to talk about
mostly is I'm going to talk about
several different best practices that
you can do when you're deploying
applications and so me use this little
guestbook app that I wrote it's kind of
a micro service II architecture it's got
a little message application that's it's
basically just a G RPC service that you
can use to save messages in a list and
that saves it you know backing writers
store and then we've got an energy word
method or service and that's basically
just to check if like you're saying bad
words in your messages you know we want
to keep these things g-rated so there's
that service and then we have like a
little web front-end application so to
look at it it looks just like this you
know everybody's seen one of these
things you'd say like - stand and you
like run that and it writes it into the
into the list yadda yadda yadda okay but
this one also has like you know it's has
like a little NG word check system so
like if you do whole gay which is this
is a word that I have registered in
there I didn't actually registered bad
words and because I wasn't going to do
that during this talk but you know it
pops up and says like hey you know you
can't write that all right so so we have
this little application it works like
this you know like this is the kind of
like flow so the first thing that like
you might do when you're thinking about
like attacking a system like this this
running in kubernetes is you might seek
hey why don't I just like try to take
over the API server for the cluster like
typically or a lot of times folks will
have an API server that is exposed to
the Internet and you know normally you
would have to off authenticate with it
using certs and you know it's not too
big of a deal but that it's exposed to
the Internet but you know one way that
you could attack it is attack an
application is to attack the the cluster
itself so if you're familiar with
careers you'll know that that
applications each pod can get a service
account and that service account can be
used to authenticate with the API and so
one way that you might do that is to you
know if you got control of say the front
end is then
touken and then like access the API and
then use that you know to get secrets
then further attack the system so you
might do something like don't judge I
have a cheat sheet here but so here what
I'm gonna do is I'm going to assume that
you have like access to the to run just
basically arbitrary commands inside of
the the front end
you've broken in there is some sort of
bug in the front end that you used to
broke in break-in and so what you're
gonna do here is we're just gonna run
coupe control exec into the the front
end and we're gonna cat out this token
that's saved from the service account
and so what you can do from that is then
I have this like long command here to
actually this will run and call the
kubernetes api to get secrets and then
parse out the using that token and then
parse out this the Redis password for
our database and so we get out this
database here and so we can do like
telnet let's actually break let's
actually go into that pod first so if we
do this oh yes I need to say - so I've
got like a little okay that's better
so we'll do telnet Redis and six three
seven nine and then we'll just like off
with this password that we got up here
right so then I can just be like hey you
know give me out all the messages
you know and then we'll say like zero
negative one and that like you know
gives us out our messages you can
imagine maybe like we have hey somebody
else has been posting into my this book
yeah that's a public IP address so if
you you know you can you can post stuff
there but let's see so that's the idea I
mean if you had like some maybe some
user data or some other like kind of
stuff that would be exposed then that
would probably be a bad thing for you so
one way that you can kind of mitigate
that is to let's go back to the slides
here to you is to use our back so our
back is a is you know role based access
control for kubernetes and this is
allows you to basically create rules
that you can assign to to users and then
that role gets assign some permissions
that it can do so like in usually that's
like some sort of verb to a type of
object so like get secrets is one that
you probably don't you want to give away
sparingly this particular cluster is
already set up to use our back so I'm
kind of emulating the fact that that I
have accessed everything but if you have
if you actually we're not using our back
then by default your service accounts
just kind of get access to the full
kubernetes api so here i'm just gonna
like delete the the web binding that or
the blind cluster rule binding go ahead
to for that service account and now if
you if i go back and try to do this
again you know I probably don't need to
do that but if I try to do this guy
again I should get back that I don't
actually get the password back and if we
look at just this port
No
let's just get this part that one right
there
we can actually see the result that
comes back that it's like hey you know
you can't access the secrets alright so
our backs of thing you should use it
that's pretty much you know if you're
using a moderate a recent version of
queries it's pretty much always or it's
pretty much enabled by default let's see
like the next thing is to actually put a
firewall in front of the API server so
if you want to you can like kind of
limit the the folks that can actually
access the API server by IP addresses or
by networks so if you're somebody that's
using it on you know gke or on at Google
then you can create your cluster and set
the the authorized networks that can
access the API server or if you like
running this on Fram or whatever then
you can kind of use whatever messages
you want to firewall that but that's
another idea because that will make it
so that folks can actually access the
API server externally of course they can
still like you know tunnel through the
the front end if they have access to it
another idea is to use network policy so
network policy allows you to at the
network level say like this pod can
access this pot or this pod can't access
this pod and that sort of thing and you
can set that up by pod labels so here we
have a pod selector that said that
matches the Redis server and then we'll
say that like that only guestbook
applications or the guestbook
application can have access to ingress
into the Redis cluster so like if I go
back here and I say like apply that word
policy like that and then I say bash
and I try to do that telling that thing
again six three seven nine yeah like I
just can't connect to it anymore it's
that one I think no telling it you just
don't like me okay all right so that's
actually this type of thing getting
access to the API server so once you
have like kind of blocked off access the
API server you've walked that down I
another thing that you might try to do
if you were an attacker would be to kind
of break out of the container and then
try to get access to the host and take
over the host
maybe attack other containers that are
running on that host maybe attacks a
couplet that's running on that
particular server and so those types of
things
you can kind of try to mitigate a little
bit better using a few features so if
you're familiar with things like set
comp and a Parmar and selinux those are
things that you can use to kind of help
mitigate this so you'll have running
just by itself is fine but like when you
put it into like a container it's it
helps it to so that it's it's harder to
break out of it but it's it's not always
it's a little bit porous in the sense
that like if the if there's a if there's
a kernel exploit or some sort of problem
that you could have within the kernel
that would that could potentially allow
you to get out and so what you do after
you've put your application into a
container or you've changed it up you
put it in a lock box and then you put it
in another lock box so these are so
using these really help it so that once
that even if you're able to like kind of
break out of the container
you still can't really
very much that's useful and so SEF does
that by allowing you to you know create
a filter a whitelist filter on the
syscalls that you can do a plumber and
SELinux are both the what is it the
security frameworks for for Linux so
they can stop you from like doing things
like mounting things extra stuff inside
the container or like writing a prop or
doing things like that so kind of by
default kubernetes doesn't really a lot
like have you set this or doesn't set a
set come from profile for you
so it's pretty recommended at least by
me to go ahead and I put in that because
otherwise you'll have things like where
we are going here let's go back into our
little guy here and we can say like okay
well we're gonna just unshare the user
continue the user name space oh well I
can just do that you know so like if
there's a that doesn't really
necessarily by default like or as it is
let me do very much that's useful but
you can imagine if like there was some
sort of exploit that through I'm sharing
a new space that allowed me to break out
of the container that this would be
actually a bad thing for me to be doing
like most applications don't need to do
this and so if you just say like well
you can't do that at all then that will
help you know mitigate those type of
problems so we can go in here let's see
and we'll say in the web app deploy
let's go ahead and add that in this is
really
all right
so now I updated that so that it's so
that the web this web server now has a
set comm profile like the default set
profile running on it so I could say
like control exec that guy like so we
here I can try like on share again yeah
so like by default like so if I use the
default set comm profile for docker that
is not whitelisted so I can't actually
do that if I'm actually applying the
default set comm profiles so when you
want to so if your most applications
will like will run just fine with these
and so you'll want to just go ahead and
do that if you're if you're running an
app application like also the app armor
depending on that which you know
provider you're using or whatever like
however your your cluster is set up you
might have happened armor installers you
might have se Linux installed and so you
can kind of go ahead and use the default
the doctor default or the runtime
default profiles for a polymer NSE Linux
as well
so here the a polymer one is just the
default and then you could set your own
selinux options within the security
context in a pod so those are things
that are like pretty pretty nice to just
go ahead and do another thing is that
you might want to restrict the
permissions that if the couplet has so
if you were say trying to once the
person who's got out of the container
and then like gets access to the couplet
and the couplets tokens and and
certificates then they can basically do
whatever the Kubla can do and so if you
restrict what they can actually do then
help you kind of mitigate problems so
there we go so one thing is to enable
like the our back mode for for the
couplet and then set no restriction so
that means that each couplet only has
access to things like secrets that are
running four pods that are running on
that node and so it won't have access to
those secrets that are available on
other nodes or four pods that are not
running on that node also setting the
certificates to rotate is also a helpful
so that like if somebody extracts the
certificate for that couplet and then
tries to use it against the API server
that you know it'll eventually get
rotated or it'll get rotated relatively
quickly so that they won't be once
you've kicked out the attacker from your
from your cluster they won't be able to
just still use that that sort of kid in
for food in perpetuity so another issue
that you might kind of run into is
[Music]
listening for listening to traffic
within the clusters so like once they
have access to the web front-end the
they might be able to like say listen to
the traffic between the our message
service and Redis and like you know pick
up the password or pick up like some
data that's being transferred and use
that to attack or just extract the data
so that sort of thing is also not
particularly good and you can also think
of the the hosts perhaps making requests
to other services within the cluster so
like you know creating essentially
fraudulent requests to other to other
services so this is something that like
you I mean even if you use T RPC you're
not really
that's not really going to stop somebody
from sending just B RPC requests to to
the server they're a little bit harder
to do than just sending a core request
but
there's nothing stopping an attacker
really from doing that so that's where
like things like service meshes come in
so so sto is a is a service mesh that's
you can run on top of kubernetes and
what it does is it includes like a
non-void proxy as a sidecar for each of
your containers and then the Envoy
proxies for each of the container each
of those sidecars essentially are the
ones that talk to each other and all of
the applications just talked to this
sidecar so you go from the application
to the sidecar proxy then that sidecar
proxy credit goes to the other pod
sidecar proxy and then up into the
application and everything in between
the sidecar proxy is authenticated and
and encrypted so the way that it looks
is it looks kind of something like this
where you have this little sidecar proxy
running on each of your applications and
then the communication in between them
is authenticated and encrypted so you
can't really from the web front-end like
listen in between the what the message
service and the Redis service are doing
and then you also can't as easily just
send requests to a particular service
because you're not authenticated with
that service so as part of this you can
create like policies for which services
can talk to which services and so maybe
our front-end can send a messages to the
message service but if you had another
service out here that message used and
the web front-end didn't access directly
you wouldn't be able to send from the
web front-end messages to the other one
because you know you would run into Paul
the the policy would forbid that and so
that makes it a lot easier so that like
people can't can't really do very much
once they're inside the cluster so
the only another issue is like that once
you've taken taken control of the web
frontend
the the attacker could then potentially
gain access to the sidecar the actual
Envoy proxy running the sidecar okay
yeah and the so this also does like the
COO blade and does rolling surf activity
updates so like even if you've extracted
that sort of kid you can't really
continue to use that sort of certificate
forever and that's it really
[Applause]
five minutes left but maybe not four
minutes for questions you sort of skim
this over this fast for the rbac stuff
at the start once you have access to a
specific thing like the web frontend
great can you not from there just then
talk directly to kubernetes api server
anthems and coop control exec on another
machine how well so know so like the the
reason why I like an executor it is like
because I'm a cluster administrator yep
myself and so I'm I'm just assuming that
like I can get into the front-end like
in this case I'm exactly into it but
like that wouldn't be like how an
attacker is actually getting into it
they would be doing it through like
however like through like some sort of
like tunnel that they know concrete one
of our pluses at the moment has a
Jenkins thing inside it right then have
permissions to start up and destroy all
the containers right which then means
that any of those pubs have permissions
to do basically everything so your
server for sure like we'd have
permissions to do a lot but you're the
the pods that Jenkins creates doesn't
necessarily have to be able to do
everything you can set up the roles in
such a way that they only are able to do
what they need to do
so one of the things docker really got
was having a good default second profile
do I need to explicitly enable this in
kubernetes can you say that again and so
when things don't go right with I mean
good cycle right profile do I need to
explicitly enable in Goodman 80s to get
a default circled per file so if you
kind of install it by default right now
like yes and I believe that's mostly
because it's like it's still like kind
of an alpha thing the I imagined that
that will become like kind of a default
in the future and it also depends like
it could depend on the vendor or like
whoever's like setting up setting it up
for you like so I believe right now like
gke doesn't do that but in the future it
will be ill you'll probably have default
set defaults security policies that
enable those defaults that comp profiles
and defaults like Appanna profiles and
stuff like that well the like with the
CRI and all these new tender runtimes
well they also have to support the same
format a second personal right they
would they would have to support setting
the set comp profiles as part of like
their execution and framework or however
they they start up the containers but
yes like the way that that it was sent
there to say like runtime default is so
that you basically have a way of setting
the default that that runtime whatever
runtime gives you there's also like you
can also put it in if you know it's
docker you can just say docker slash
default
yes this is just about Sanh what he was
asking a little bit um how many of the
recommendations that you suggested are
actually are implemented by manage
communities like gke like especially
like the cubelet we don't we're not
really you buuuut gk users can't really
start adding flags start up flags or not
to my knowledge and right
we kind of have like everything like api
server and the scheduler are kind of
hidden away so there's no really way we
could actually install like some yes no
security yeah that's these are kind of
like getting better as like things are
going on but like the so things like
alright if you create a server that's
like on gke for instance like if you
create a 1.8 cluster like quite a full
power pack is there and like everything
works fine so if you if you create a pod
like with a that that pods service
account like really can't do anything
but so as things go on like more and
more things will become defaults but
yeah you don't really have at the moment
like a lot of flexibility in terms of
like turning those flags on and off
unless that particular vendor supports
it
um Network policies are thinking on
alpha feature and alpha clusters kind of
get destroyed after a month right right
Network policy I believe it's actually
not in alpha anymore it's in beta if I
do percent traffic loss that I'm seeing
constantly when I enable that yeah it it
depends on the network implementation
really like I mean you're probably using
Teleco or something like that right okay
yeah Network policy is it's actually
implemented by calico on gke
so like yeah like and I believe that
it's it's probably I believe it's using
IP tables underneath the like and
setting those rules so that you can
access but yeah hopefully that will
improve in the future I don't I don't
know if hands like
yeah yeah so I believe that'll get
better but yeah there is a little bit of
network cost for things like Network
policy all right I think that's all the
time we have it is yeah
[Applause]
[Music]