okay so let's get started thank you
everybody for coming my name is Vicenta
I am a software engineer for the MRED B
foundation and today I'm going to give
you a brief overview of the new
developments in optimizers we've already
heard oysters talk about histograms so
that's something that Murray DB has in a
different format in a 10-1 and onwards
and now we're going to compare a few
other things that optimizers can do so
first of all what is the goal of the
query optimizer so we want to get given
a certain sequel query the fastest time
possible when executing it and we have
different tools to do that we can choose
to either cache something some data
before we actually compute the full
result we can do some index lookups and
get your that data faster this way or we
can try to rewrite your query in a more
efficient manner that we can query it
faster that so now problem is the number
of possible plans grows exponentially
with the number of tables it's actually
a factorial number of tables but let's
say that it's exponential and in a
perfect world the query optimizer should
be able to give you the best result all
the time unfortunately that's not the
case for many queries it does happen but
there are certain instances where it
works quite badly we're not going to be
too concerned about those for now but
any optimization that we do we try to
reduce the number of possible queries
which behave poorly so in order to
explain what kind of optimizations we're
doing in recent developments I need a
bit of background so first of all a
derived table in my skill is any sort of
table which you can find as part of a
sub-query in the from clause whenever I
say they're derived table it's either
this or a view as part of the from
clause so a view is basically the same
thing here's our query example we want
to get
all our customers which had orders with
which had large orders so greater than 1
million entries in their order there's
only a few customers so that's why there
are VIP customers and the orders have to
be from October start to end 2017
how would you execute this in a naive
fashion well we first compute the result
in this table here so this is October
orders we just do a filter on the orders
on the date and then we try to join this
table with VIP customers using the join
condition the amount must be greater
than 1 million so here's the set of
October orders a head-mounted a 1
million that part will enter the join
with the VIP customers and you get your
result however we can do better than
that and this is something at my skill
and Marie DB and obviously percona says
there based on my skill also do we
rewrite the spiri because we can and
this data this condition here it's only
based on orders and if we move this
condition outside of the sub-query and
just replace the custom table with the
orders table we're going to get this
query so now the optimizer has a more
general view of how we actually want to
query the data we have all the
conditions in one place and this leads
to a better query plan if you do explain
you will see that we only have two
tables visible VIP customers in orders
we don't see October orders anywhere in
the explain plan and the execution goes
as follows we get the orders then we get
the October orders and the amount
there's an intersection happening so
there's not there are orders that are
not in October which have greater than 1
million amount only the intersection of
all these conditions will enter the join
operation and then this gets joined with
VIP customers
so instead of first computing everything
here we just do one table scan over
orders and one over VIP customers
there's there are some tricks to buffer
results but I'm not going to go into too
many details details here so conclusion
is that merging is good it simplifies
the query and as I said it works in all
stable versions of mysql or mariadb
however there's a problem when we when
aggregation comes into play we can't use
it when aggregation happens because if
you rewrite the query which has an
aggregate function in the sub query
results are not what you expected so
here's an example we want the october
totals so all the the number of orders
the number of items ordered per customer
in october if we were to join this query
inside the main one you would actually
start aggregating stuff in this one and
you don't want to do that you actually
want the totals for one customer in this
case which is customer ID equal one but
we have a group by customer ID so we can
make use of this here all right so we
have lots of customers we don't want to
get all of all the totals just for one
customer so you make use of this group
by column here and we identify this
condition customer ID and we push this
condition all the way to the where
clause here because we have this group
by column here
so now when aggregated we only aggregate
one customer so we get our orders we get
only customer one orders and then we sum
those up so instead of doing aggregation
over the full data set we just aggregate
one customer this optimization is
available in MariaDB 1010 - and this
tactic also works for window functions
if you are here from the start
if you've seen that we have window
functions in more ddb 10th 10 - and
there is also window functions coming in
MySQL 8 0 so we can push the same
condition if you have a window function
with a partition by clause here so
partition by means that you compute this
rank sequence for each customer you can
see here customer ID equals 1 has orders
1 2 3 or the ranks same for customer 2
and so on and we don't want to have to
compute this rank column for all of the
table if we're only interested in
customers and customer ones top 3 orders
so we only want this here and because we
have this equality condition here and
there is this partition by clause here
you know what we know that we can
simplify the query and push this part of
the condition all the way up here in the
where Clause of this query so here so if
you if you push this you only get to
compute this part and this information
is not not even accessed okay so if you
compare how execution would happen
currently in Mirae db10 2 which is the
stable release minus QL it's 0 which has
window functions my escalate David
computes all free top top free orders
for all customers and then you would get
the customer the rows for customer ID
equals 1 Emory DB 10 free and also in
pause Bears we've also tested how
possible asset you will only compute the
top 3 orders for customer ID equals 1
and in some cases this can be much
faster because we can make use of
indexes to identify the rows for that
particular customer make sense so far
okay either I'm very clear or nobody's
understanding anything at all so final
optimization I think the name for this
is not quite fortunate so we're probably
going to change it so for now we call it
split grouping for derived so what
happens here where we have a similar
query to the one before we have a group
by statement but because the there is no
equality we don't filter by one customer
ID we have a range of customers we have
customer name in John and Bob but we
don't have customer name inside orders
we have customer ID ok so so we have the
join condition here customer ID equals
October totals customer ID and we filter
by customer name so we can't do
condition push down immediately because
there is no column customer name here
however we can be smart about this and
actually let's first look at how we are
not smart so when we're not smart we do
a sum of everything so for all customers
we get the sum and then we this means we
get the October totals and then for each
customer we filter only Bob and John for
both and join them so we have to do
aggregation over the full orders table
again not good this gets big very fast
as you see we don't need customer X when
we're smart we actually look at
customers first we see which customer
IDs we are allowed to use and we only
aggregate those customers so we can
compute a sum for Bob and we can compute
a sum for John and this way we
completely ignore this part of the table
as well as this part of the table there
is some requirements for this though in
order to actually do this we have to
have a joint condition here so we have
to have something that links orders to
customers in this case customer ID
is linked this is the column that links
the two tables and we also must have a
index on the group by column to be able
to quickly check if the customer that we
are looking for is actually in the table
so here we want to have an index to
check if it's Bob in orders but Bob is
Bob Bob's ID in orders if you don't have
this this optimization won't actually
work right now it's still in the
beginning phases so we haven't really
optimized this for all cases we only
apply it when we're definitely sure that
it will bring a speed up otherwise we
are very we don't use it because we're
not sure if it's going to produce a
better query plan and to look up to see
how features stack up well we have the
right table view merge this the first
thing we talked about in all stable
versions condition pushdown is a Marida
be only specific feature window
functions are coming into MySQL h0 and I
haven't personally check but I believe
merge actually works with cities too in
my skill and also condition pushed down
for partition by and split table
grouping is only available in Murray to
be 10 feet so we're hoping that MySQL
can also implement this because if more
more users get optimizations it's better
for everybody
obviously this is not a comprehensive
comparison I'm not trying to show that
MySQL doesn't have any features or we
that we have so a lot more this is just
on the features which I talked about
during this talk okay this is actually a
overview of how things work this is
based what I talked about if you want to
read we read this somewhere it's it's
available I will make I'll post this
talk on on the FOSDEM link so you can
download it there okay that's all I had
thank you very much
yes if there's an I actually have more
slides possibly but it's a bit difficult
so if people are interested I can talk
more about it offline yep go ahead
so is it this this one
so I'm not really sure I get your
question so let me try and rephrase it
so the question is why don't we have a
where clause inside the view view here
right well for example if you try to
make an application for users which
which works for multiple you say say
you're in a company and you want this
view to work for multiple departments
maybe don't want filter by a specific
user for that department so that's why
well maybe the example is not the
example is to showcase the optimization
possible it's not to show that this is
the way you should actually write all
your queries okay yes you can optimize
it manually but yeah
the idea from the start of the talk is
this so in a perfect world any query
should run fast okay so that's what
we're trying for even if you shoot
yourself in the foot
okay thank you