yeah welcome to the talk about Linux
boot maybe you're out of it it's let's
say fear map replacement for a crew in
VMware Heights
let's say it's not a complete
replacement it replaces most of your
parts and it's a bit aggressive with
your current VMware for example UEFI
coreboot or you boot thanks to trauma
Hudson providing these slides because
yesterday I got the information that I
can do a talk or I have to do a talk
here after someone canceled his talks or
a little bit unprepared you know I
didn't do so much preparation but it
should work anyway
so that's that so this guy is one minute
maybe can seem on the left side he
worked a long time on dataset house for
the government and also now for Google
and he was also the founder of Kabu
together with Stephan right now and on
some points they started a long time ago
the so called Linux buyers maybe you
have maybe a lot of it it's it's started
in 1999 and yeah after sometimes they
had to rename it and since 2008 its
cobbled yeah basically that's what
happened in the past and Linux buyers
itself the idea was that you use a Linux
kernel instead of rebuilding your film
via was let's say your own
implementation and the problem was that
in the past there was not so much code
in the Linux kernel you know we had bad
graphics drivers we don't didn't have
printer support whatever you know what I
mean so the drivers stack was really bad
and so they couldn't do that and yes
they did their own thing and today it's
called coreboot yeah you also have this
today in the most laptops you use
currently it's called UEFI unified
extensible firmware interface and it was
introduced by into a long time ago
before it was called EFI and used by Max
and later it was called unified
extensible firmware interface and was
introduced by Intel and together with
Microsoft
currently the fee investing or let's say
the UEFI stack looks like this you have
the security phase which does some kind
of secure
beauty stuff then you have the pre Fe
phase which is platform initialization
that means that you have there as a film
a support package for example and it
does memory in it and whatever and after
that you have memory initialized and
then you have the DXE phase which is
basically drive us and so on environment
whatever and then you have also a boot
device manager afterwards and then it
loads your boot loader you can see that
first final OS boot loader and after
that you have your operating system or
whatever so this is a standard graphic
and what we plan to do is that we have
something like this so we try to rip out
everything yeah let's say after the pay
phase so we need to pay phase you know
normally if you don't have memory you
can't use the Linux kernel that's not
working so we could also do the memory
initialization inside the Linux kernel
but that's not a good idea and you would
have something like additional init
stuff and if that doesn't make sense so
we we stay like this and just have the
sex face and the pay phase and
afterwards we load Linux and yeah then
you can load your operating system for
example Linux you could also load
windows it's not a problem at all you
know that can work as well in terms of
security so if we look at the UEFI boot
flow it looks really complex to be
honest yeah maybe maybe this path the
second page fast is not that bad because
it's really small but if you look at the
DXE face extreme huge and it depends on
the vendor or how much modules are added
there so if you have a renderer which at
thousands of mode modules areas they
have dependencies to each other and
that's also why your boot up is so slow
you know they have if you put make a
dependency graph out of the DX e face
it's horrible so they they have a really
long so the boot face takes a really
long time Excel or also on servers for
example they you wait 20 minutes to boot
up your server that's not really good em
it costs a lot of time and money and
also the diggsy phase can introduce a
lot of bugs because you have a huge
amount of code in the
and that's normally not a good idea you
can you can look how many modules you
have that the only few modules you have
different stuff in the and sometimes
when laws forget to remove stuff and
then there's more in it and you don't
need it and that's normally not a good
idea because you want to have a minimal
TTB which is a trusted computing base so
keep your trust account mutant commit a
computing base always small not big yeah
also in this in this schematic we have
as a graph which is our bootloader for
example but also web has a lot of code
and it's mostly C and in general this
are the biggest problem yeah you don't
have defense in depth you have weakest
links and there's a lot of code in it
and if you look we have compared some
things so you have UEFI for example you
have grew up you have the Linux kernel
they all implement for example what is
it this time it's the GT p6 they all
have a TCP stacks or your UEFI some TCP
stacks grab has a TCP stack and your
Linux kernel recipe statistics so it's
code D public and so it's code
application everywhere really everywhere
and that's not a good idea
same goes for a drive our file system
driver and whatever so you can see that
yeah USB and fat so whatever it's it's
it's completely it's it's a lot of code
the duplicated over some time and yeah
that's not really good so on the link on
the side we have nearly unlimited
contributors on get up if you look at
the edk to project it's around 100 144
contributors and then we have co-op is
one hundred and see so not so much it's
crap so and that's a problem in general
so the most developers doing Linux rock
and it's better maintained you know if
only if we're grabbed for example you
only have maybe one core developer some
other developers working around but they
don't care so much about the quality of
the USB stick or the fat filesystem
rather you know and then you have bugs
in it and security holes and that's a
problem
yeah currently this is this interesting
picture so this cop would we had Linux
boot since 17 years yeah because you
always can load with kabuto Linux kernel
and normally that makes sense you can
use it on some devices and it works fine
but today it's change of the way of
human development change we got more and
more code everywhere and it's a general
issue that we have so much code
currently which initializes a platform
itself so in church started to have a
project called into FSP which is the
VMware Support Package and this female
Support Package itself is a does a ram
initialization and afterwards you only
do small platform in it and then you can
directly jump to the bootloader the FSP
can currently be used with cobble
together after what so you see this with
examples you have to pay and the sec
phase that's around so we don't have
that in court but it's the same level we
have Co boots the f SP and afterwards
you have the bots in it and then you
load Linux boot same goes for you fi you
have to pay in the SEC phase afterwards
you look load Linux boot so Linux boot
itself it's it's independent from the
VMware
it's the idea of having the Linux kernel
doing all driver stuff you need to have
for for example if you have data center
you want to have a tcp/ip stack for
loading for example images through
Ethernet or you have different other use
case so for example you can do in Linux
boot you can easily use v jet mount
tempest as the whole memory then you
just download for example each server
inclusive a Mesa through network and
also load at immediate or started and
you have an 18 meter
editor in your BIOS yeah on the flash
ship so in the memory you can unpack it
it's so I only want to say all you
things you can do with link on is really
great the you have a small system you
can reduce it and you have two megabytes
of Linux kernel loaded by the film
itself
and that's how it looks maybe you saw
that on the news booth homepage so the
the basic stuff is done in father ram
minute which is you fi pay cord warm
stage in Ubud SPL and afterwards he
loads the nukes corner including an
inner drum of s and then you can jump
into your operating system or do other
things inside your female yeah that's
how it works
so yeah I'm done that was short but yeah
so if you have questions you can also
there's currently there's a comment on
how boot which you can use as already
links but integrated in a better way and
you can also go to the newest boot
github and the new dog home page yeah
and no questions currently not because
you don't need to do that anymore
because you have said UNIX driver so the
funny thing is for example VGA option
roms or graphics in it option 1 you can
do that with a loom phone you don't need
the optimum anymore for the inter driver
for example if you have something like
an ad driver or whatever you can
additionally include exe files or option
roms and load them rocks as well so if
we talk for example I can maybe extend
it a little bit more in detail we have
for example the system management mode
you could ask yourself what's happening
with the system management mode we can
do that inside the neonscar and later
have some application doing interfacing
whatever so that works as well regarding
device to a murmuration which is mostly
used under x86 PCI device generation
it's done inside the Linux kernel
already you can just check an option and
it does it so there's no need for for
let's say fork or boot ROM stage or UEFI
DX e phase whatever after you would SPL
comes you know you can just use the
links come don't need don't applicate
code it's a bad idea
currently you can do this with Callwood
as well sure and if we talk about UEFA
currently we are on the way integrating
that we have already I guess three
different types of service running they
started with server rock so maybe it can
take some time and also we need support
from from Intel and as our let's say
when us because it needs to be in this
inside the specification otherwise you
can load something different you know if
you have into boot guard or any
protection mechanism which protects the
film headset we can change the future
because it's signed but if you have an
option to load it into the female itself
to some concept then it works so Kubiak
currently on the right doing that in
discussion with them and see what we can
do so the trusted computing base for the
unique repeat the question okay so the
question is if the linux kernel itself
it has a huge TCP you say and how to
make it smaller for example yeah so
that's how it can be done so I got
stripped down the new expander to 1.6
megabytes and if you look into the fi
code it's it's more so for Co boot it
may be less sure the new tunnel
currently is really big but it's not
that and big issue because it doesn't
open interfaces you know it may
initially is only drivers you need and
the cost structure which is really huge
it's mostly let's say setup for the
kernel itself it's not loading drivers
you can make do make tiny config and if
you have 10 you make if you have done it
then you can easily strip out everything
you need oil only at things you need
there and then it's really small
that works sure
our new platform so hum okay how much
work is needed to port it to a new
unified platform so we did that really
fast so maybe you need a few days to do
that sometimes it's really easy because
you're just rip out the DXE modules and
you then you just throw in the the
kernel itself and it works out of the
box sometimes you have problems but it
depends on the vendor what they did and
sometimes they did some wired stuff you
know but in the so if you have an
predefined interface and we allowed to
do that then it's not a problem at all
otherwise it takes maybe a few days or
one week yeah yeah so how do we enable
one bought components what do you mean
by that so
this cut yeah it's okay but setup okay
so this can be done normally by parts of
said so you can you you don't have to
strip everything out of the UFO you know
you can also keep some D X YZ or white
you're only exceed which does the job so
that's what we currently do and we maybe
have one DC which has a job for you if I
for coreboot it's not a problem
you have the code you can just modify it
let's say or does your do your own
implementation and then it works it's
not a problem at all you can do it it's
you fi layer works we can also you can
also white a driver for for limits
itself yeah what yeah what is if it's
from a third-party vendor so yeah then
you have to reverse engineer that at the
moment but maybe we get some support and
we already did that so it's not like you
can't do it it's it's the first time at
some work but I can tell you more so I'm
not the ufi guy you know and we have
terminal Hudson working on this if you
want to get some more information you
can ask one or two on the Hudson they do
the whole work I'm currently more on the
coreboot side but I'm also looking into
the EFI stuff here
so what do we have currently and for the
funds are in a drama fest the inner
Graham office itself can be ever in a
drama fest you can load your own inner
drum FS we currently use you you would
Andrew you would just go in go language
in advance maybe you want to talk about
that that's your part so he's one of the
you go developers yeah yeah so one of
the possibilities yep so one of the
possibilities in your route is to have
whatever Rama fest you want and one of
the rama classes we are working on is
called new route universal route this
rama fest is basically an open-source
drama fest written and go where you can
actually have your tool chain which is
attributes like to chain or source code
in your theorem but that you can modify
or compile on the fly on the film or
chip itself and from there you can
literally double you get your
provisioning image and boot your
installation software or you can boot
from disk or you can expect into your
camera or do whatever literally whatever
you want you basically have a full linux
environment with a shell and from there
you can compile your own code bring any
existing read existing linux to anything
like that so basically you are literally
limited to whatever you can download in
your system and run from a linux kernel
which we know is pretty pretty broad
limit and Linux boot is also linked from
the sorry you route is linked from the
Linux boot website so that's very
interesting project go have a look at
that and we are looking for go
developers that want to make it better
so we can get a UI better tooling etc
but you can also use for examples ahead
in the drama yes it's already there so
there are different inner drama fest
also and do whatever you want you can
also just implement something in rust or
sea have fun
so this is so main that you have for
example recovery mode so so they're
different options so if you have control
over your own inner drum if as you can
implement it there in C we can also use
film by mechanisms like for coreboot we
have V boot with some failure safety so
it will just jump to another image
inside the flash itself and execute that
if that works and if not we the only
part that depends on the female so you
can implement it in in go currently it's
not there any other language and all you
do it in the femur which is currently
yeah it's a normal way how you do it if
you if you want to get code on it you
have to first do a hat so the basic so
you need to check if the platform in it
is already available for your
architecture and if it's available you
have to adapt that and if you talk about
you if I for example it's it's already
there so you just pulls it your Fi image
just strip down every DX e modules put
the Linux kernel in it and just start it
that's what you do with your fi on the
most laptops there's no car boot
installed you know what I mean
so you can do more work on the cob web
site or you just pull out the ufi image
modify it and put a Linux kernel it
works as well it's easier for you
because you don't need to understand how
that hardware networks that's the thing
so that's why we working with with
different VMs we don't care if you use
code are you if I were you would or
whatever
yeah so let's say so the question is if
you can buy it and we are to get it and
when when it's done the thing is this
always takes a long time to be honest
modifications in the VMA level it's more
like decades yeah maybe you can buy it
soon for example currently this server
hardware out there from the compute
project which works with Linux boot you
can already download images just flash
it on the chip and it works so but until
we do laptops or desktops that's a
different level you know maybe you can
do that but then we need to have vendors
as well which allow us to to flash
VMware for example because normally they
assigned ends it's not a lot so it can
take a while maybe it's adapted there
but we will see that always depends on
your windows and to be honest just buy
from vendors which are really let's say
which which try to be more open for
example if it's not perfect even then by
force and hardware by Chromebooks by
whatever which is which includes open
source VMware you know you would laptops
or whatever just use that instead that's
my opinion about it so because otherwise
it's never changes because you're only
small the amount of people and you have
7 billion people out there they don't
care about it