should be working that starts hi
everybody
so hi everybody
time is the seventh day from tox lab and
there's a third guys here so I'm the
only one talking about all real jobs
they all speak about the fun stuff and I
have the less fun stuff so as part of
our job we develop an anagram of skater
called Ethan arc and we have one problem
and this problem is that we have users
and users want documentation but we are
developers and we did not to write
documentation and furthermore we don't
want to maintain our documentation and
that's the topic of this talk how to do
minimal stuff so that users have the
documentation and we don't write it or
maintain it too much because there is
very low support for documentation of
passes in RM if you ask for
documentation of jum setting because
don't watch this you can get the help
and jumper do is jump reading so it
doesn't help much but well we don't know
that the code and then reads the
commands and then you know what is just
reading and maybe you can use it the
proper way so our program is that you
know obscura
we have superstition from 11 byte code
to OMB code and we have this user
directory so you the user can control
how the compiler behaves so it needs to
know what every passage does so our
passes obfuscation passes but it's
globally the same as and you can tell
optimization and so how do you document
that because the usual is not an expert
on compilation that needs to have an int
because there are three way for him to
ensure the compiler
I already used we'd hold compiler flags
but generally speaking it's not a good
way to control enough station because if
you say to sum all constants in my code
into something that is not difficult to
understand when you hand
it is very large code and it's not
performance-wise a bit thing so you can
use directives progress so you say okay
we're going to escape this very friction
this resist very obscene and this is
some parameter and then this constant
will be appreciated using the heavy mud
which makes regenerates ball code but it
can also write scheduled fire because it
doesn't want to touch it filed so
everything is put into a separate file
and then its global is the same there's
a very same options and you apply this
pass than this pass on this function and
this person's instruction so you have
three way to ensure the compiler the
program is that how is everything
consistent and how is everything
documented results to match report we
have one file this file is located in
the same directory as the pass and it
describes a lot of thing about the pass
so it's not like the oxygen which try to
document things we forms that we will
generate various piece of information
that will be used either by is a C++
code or by the documentation so that
everything is consistent so as a level
is like module pass function pass
basically pass reckon it'll build means
can you use it as a Padma on just an
instruction or block of instruction even
if it's a function pass the compile time
of your head from our measurements when
you use that your computation time is
going to be to be multiplied by this
factor which is a big factor but still
this is a textual description and then
you have all the options this will be
forward provided to CL and at the mcl
whatever mcl it's global variables which
is very surprising to me but still
that's the way it is and it's this will
plays well with our directives because
we want passage to be parametric to be
able to instantiate different passes
with different options so we have some
wrapper to do that and describe them and
whatever and we also have these
classifiers because for
users didn't know about about Winston's
but he knows that it's that application
so when digging through his problem you
know okay this is the best I can use to
escape my data and it turns out that
this path supports any targets which is
not the case for all passes things about
anti debug tools or thing like that so
from that file you have the description
you generate some header files so your
actual editor implementation will derive
from that and it will get access to
options to good path level and several
stuff we also generates documentation
that will be forwarded to thanks for
user documentation generation we also
generate part of these classifiers which
is a bit tables that summarize
everything and we also generate
parameters for our test suits so that we
can test that documentation is that
should be correct and from this we can
access to regionalize repairs to CL to
the plasma manager code and the actual
class so everything is generated from
one file so that brings us back to
literate programming where you have the
code and the documentation and both are
used to generate the tool which consists
in the documentation and the program and
we have something very similar to that
so there are several benefits of using
this approach first
everything is always synchronized the
documentation the code the directives
the pass code all the documentation you
can get from the command line the
documentation we get from the
documentation everything is recognized
so though once it's written you don't
need to maintain it anymore and nothing
happens like you change the code that
you forget to change the documentation
because the code is generated through
the documentation so this kind of step
backward which is really a pain does not
happen another thing is you need to
support something else has everything is
generated from one script from all the
description you can retarget it's easily
instead of changing they could if
every pass so that's very cool because
we write less dock which gives time to
my teammates to write their family tools
instead of maintenance of documentation
and just to this is the kind of
documentation engineer right so also
it's generated documentation there's
actual interesting staff here code
examples that explain how we how it
behaves and all the staff here are
automatically generated from the
description and it turns out that even
as we sometimes go to the documentation
copy that and paste it because that's
what we want to do and that's how the
documentation is have been used that's
all if you have an equation please feel
free otherwise its audience John
[Applause]