government over here this late hour
I'm a writer and you know that I am a
writer because I got the single thing
you need to be a writer great her
sometimes over the head so we are in the
era of bolon book writer now you have
platform where you can publish
everything Kindle or Smashwords or many
other it's it's a lonely world you have
to do everything by yourself including
the color a mesh bumper kittens in a
space I mean pretty much he checked all
boxes right so they're Amish
there are killing some day pretty much
having a space so this is actually a
fake color they're not killing mrs. ping
a space but there are books that say a
mish bump icing in space emission
missing in space and everything and this
is this is something you have to do you
have to write the cupboard you have to
do to edit you have to do everything
okay okay you have to run by yourself
you're the built on machine that's
running the book algorithm I'm sorry
theater but it could be any kind of book
it could be a technical book it could be
a novel to be a to be a poetry it could
be a short test sorry whatever so what
do you do this well the book is not
finished
you have to write you have to write
that's what I should tell check
sometimes you don't then you go back and
write again a rate again I'm sometimes
you take check if you think everything
is finished you check around because you
have to check that everything is in
there so that you you have made up one
character of what a finger in the third
chapter and then you just introduce him
and or her and then give it like there
or there is some funny things you need
to do is when you do a dialogue you have
to check that the every time someone
talks it's a different person so that
they don't have to two times the same
person in a row so that that's the kind
of thing you do that it's usually done
by copy editors but you have to do it by
yourself then you have to format then
you have to package you say you have to
put it in a package in service um so
format that can be processed by a
publishing platform I'm actually got to
upload
usually there's no kind of API and
that's a problem so a means that we do
upload things sometimes you run into
problems because I mean there are many
many many different things that can go
wrong may takes quite a while so it
takes like prolly
20 minutes to check your your manuscript
and think eventually subject' manually
and then you might run into more trouble
this is this is kind of difficult so if
you really want to do it and and you
want to do it well and you want to do it
several times you want to produce new
editions from time to time I mean the
text quite a lot so I think that book
realm is actually very similar to the
developer world so it's not that
different there are many things that are
the same in creating books or in writing
books writing and creating and producing
everything and also in the index
software development world for instance
the manscape is the source code you
don't deploy directly source code you
don't publish directly the manuscript it
has to run a series of thing to do that
kind of thing right second thing is a
spell check is like testing that's like
the minimum minimum thing you have to
you have to do you can't publish
something if it's got some some typos
which of course doesn't prevent lots of
people from doing it but it's something
you have to do right and then you have
to copyright which is a came to
debugging that kind of thing you know
like someone who is who's a character
from the Midwest it's got to have a
Midwest accent someone who is I don't
know someone who saw a cat just looked
like a cat
please like that and you say you see the
guy appear it's a really funny thing so
it's you have lots of fun copy editing
it's something that everyone hates do it
because eventually you have to be
something that you know has some quality
then publishing is like releasing or
deploying you eventually have to produce
something that can be sold in the
platform so it's like deploying right
that you have to do something that that
can be used you have to create a product
can use they would be nice if you will
be able to mated because right now every
step I have said it's a it's a manual
step everything is manual you have to
run everything you have to run a
spellcheck you have to do this and you
have to do them it would be nice and the
total issue is what I call a tops it's
what I have been doing in my books
mainly way I have won my books here
I don't have it but you can go and buy
it in the in a pair it's done it's it's
a book about / 6 I've done this with
almost every single book of I have done
pair on Python on novels and also some
travel travel book whatever then it's
kind of literate to us code right so
it's kind of having same as DevOps is
infrastructure as as called you can
reach a dress code and you have the
seaming goes goes a long way because in
fact Halawa lace at the beginning what
she said was that an alacrity might act
upon other things beside numbers what
she's saying here basically is and one
of her insight was that the medical
engine could be a universal computer I
never saw machine a machine that could
do anything as long as you could
represent it in some suitable wave so
much' break firmly or whatever what I'm
saying is that you can use computers to
neroli the whole process of you know
producing they the artifact that's going
to be uploaded but also to help you with
the actual writing famouse as you saw I
mean you go you're writing your wedding
software and you use some some editor or
some ID or whatever and you write a
keyword and then it completes a keyboard
for you just imagine you could do that
with with the charity I mean think about
writer's block it just disappears you
know it you click on a button and it
finishes the death sentence for you it
would be just amazing and then the
manuscript is written in markdown
plus utf-8 so that means that you have
to turn the manuscript into something
that similar to a Dom a document object
model since its mark I'm gonna call it
mark dumb
this isn't mark in German Cathedral you
say dumb so this is Mark Tom and the
worst joke you're gonna
here today then debug in Japan doing it
github on my books are on github so you
got to make it have a town which is JJ
by the way so I got it very early so
that's why I wrote two letters in github
so you go there and people can tend to
pull requests they come for in fact they
do so I got one novel it's got like a
seam around 100 Forks different for my
technical books have got also a good
amount of Forks so you can you can
create your own book it's got a free
license of course and and debugging
remember you have to do everything
yourself but you put everything in
github and just exactly the same way
that if you were doing a JavaScript
framework and you put it there and
people do pull requests and you if you
have some some error or type or whatever
which is right within our eyes all type
of our shallow second wall joke right
and then you can do continuous
integration remember you have to do a
spell check every time you ask something
new you have to the spell check that's
something you can do it's continuous
integration in fact this is what what
everything is started all the radius say
I wanted to do continues integration I
want to do learn Travis I say okay well
I'll do it with what this thing I'm
doing now which is reading a novel so I
started to do continuous integration on
the novel I was doing a spell check
everything I did it this way so this is
this is a Travis configuration basically
anything impaired because I I got a pair
model for for continuous integration
because Paris and prayed language long
like Perl and what it does is you know
basic biggest thing it tests how many
things you have it's got very
interesting side effect which is
counting the number of words you have so
you can follow your progress I mean it's
got all beautiful sees but basically
what it does is it creates on-the-fly
a test right which is yes these few
lines and then it transit check at the
end of the day I said you got you past
twenty five thousand and two hundred
test you failed to test and those two
tests are the words that are not yet on
the dictionary or Alice typist
so this I do this routinely so I got I
mean all my novels have the Travis batch
at the beginning saying Bill face or a
bill but also you can check many other
things you can check vocabulary entropy
so a rich novel must have a lot of
entropy and to be shredded to surprise
is related to information you can bei
literacy so for instance you can if you
want you want to do something at a
certain level you can have it check it
because there are algorithms oppresses
or you don't want to use word first as
you write a group of children you want
to say fact more than three or four
times maybe five so you come the number
of times to this a particular world on
kind of things I mean you can imagine
all kinds of things on your on your text
or kind of of kind of literally
monsieurs and eventually you have to
deploy it this is the Tristana because
it's nice to have Richard Stallman and
keeping on at all and it's actually
deploying this book you deploy your book
me said you produce it and you get to
autograph it to two people
it's book transpiling because what you
are doing is you're transpiling a
language which is malcolm to another
different language okay paper you have
to do it eventually on paper paper is
hard paper is the Internet Explorer of a
little swarm you have to go out of
accommodation for paper if you publish
sitting in my power in some eBook format
it's nice you got flexible format you
can use some kind of utf-8 or not only
you defied you can use phones that
actually support Unicode characters when
you go to the paperwork everything is
hard you have to check for the length of
the lines you don't you need to take
care of the phone that actually has
everything that you're saying in the
book and so so far I mean that's not a
problems you are writing a novel you're
not you have a character written in a
true scan or whatever but if you're
writing some technical group you might
want to have Unicode and that's not API
or SDK so you have to do everything by
yourself so the only alternative is to
go to Thomas we go to Amazon KDP and say
okay here's my manuscript tell me what's
wrong but enjoy wasting time with that
the tops is about not wasting time is
about automating this this is per six
felsic is a very nice language and this
is actually the actual flow where I
check whether the lines of code in my
book are longer than a particular length
because if they are longer they are
going to produce an error so I do that
in advance this is something like check
it so it's a single sentence so what it
does is you know it gets all the
markdown it extracts the the code or
Othmar now is that's the lines of the
code then it checks for lens everything
is I mean all this you see pad six
amazing and then you have to do some
other things like for instance ebook is
hypertext this is not hypertext so what
do you need to do you need to convert
those links into something else this is
another because I was reading a book on
Python I say okay I'm going to do this
in Python I was writing the hokum pulls
per six or I did it in Perl 6 actually I
use per stick for everything but you
know Python is there what it does is to
extract all the URLs and to turn it so
actually what I'm doing is is an English
daegu --gel API to extract a short link
and then I transpile the original to the
paper version with the short link but I
could do some something else the thing
is the tops in the pre-alpha so we're in
the in the path it's a still a long way
the two changes read yet all right right
now there are a few scripts that I am
doing I mean the concept is there the
insight is there I think that lots of
thing can be done but we need still to
have complete SDK for for policies that
allows you to do things automatically
fast to produce to release early to
release nothing and all that but anyway
meanwhile keep writing or colleague
that's it thank you very much
you have time for questions or two
minutes okay JJ double J so J another
day another person is a question up
there please yeah please do it
repeat the question okay I repeat the
question
[Music]
I mean I got everything in the same
repository so all the other checks and
everything are in the same repository
everything I do is with cherries
I created a Perl module so I don't have
to have the per module in the same
depository so it's downloaded from Sipan
which is the repository sip and every
time it's checked so I pretty much try
to package all the tools I have put them
up on the on the cloud or in github or
in some repository so it's pretty
straightforward when you do it you all
right that's very annoying so that's how
I would front from the front from the
get-go so if you start from the very
beginning it's not so annoying because
most words that are not there you know
you can you can get them I also reuse
dictionaries you know I mean
particularly dictionaries from one
project to the left to the next so if I
read is something about plow I use it
for you know something as if I'm reading
something about docker or whatever
that's all the kind of dictionary see I
mean writing something about my city
core nada so I write something else I
will use the same the same thing so your
rights annoying I think it can't get
better if you way you get used to it and
do it from the from the beginning from
the very beginning it's not a big deal
thank you very much for the question
nice time's up
thank you very much
[Applause]
and