[Applause]
my description but also we mostly hear
CIA working and so on and so first
what's LP dmg well it's a suite of tools
mostly a kernel tracer which I hope some
of you are I'm doing and also a user
space racer also other parts of the
project are the racing which is called
CPS the common interest and also other
tools like for example with trace and
well you can also pressing it and
possibly a project project as a single
command line tool which is used to drive
both the user space and compressor and
it's also
than use two bindings - and other
languages and there's also oh come on
lion trainer which is that if he reads
the binary phase formats and comforta to
human readable text and on the multiple
graphical interface that user interface
keywords like compatibility scope which
he gets through the ability to vote from
traces export them run some analysis on
them some grasses and other stuff and
then why would you use LT PNG well I
won't try to explain why you should do
this race well I'll try to this tell me
why you should choose opportunity if
you're looking for
it's very companies and unlike some more
traditional legging frameworks which are
comparable some tracing in some of these
cases can be enabled and disabled at
some point so they don't be to activate
racing since and studied whenever you
want work and also there's a lot of
flexibility in how you would explore
your traces of the traces can be the
default mode will be discarded on this
but also if you have like this mess
system
systems with a little service is
constrained over the network they can
also be written to memory buffers and
only snap so that when you need to get
natural data so this descent that you
running along without using any started
them just when you need to the actual
trace and then extracted some memory and
then for a container park well what is
it in its container I'm sure probably
most if you want to surprise though that
there's no actual concept of a company
inside of this channel it's multiple
subsystems like sea routes and the
spaces that are combined to make
different third-party implementations
like dr. rocky at least the end many
others so supporting all this in the
kernel tracer can be a bit complex since
they use different ways well technology
has with home way of using those
features so the least common denominator
here is the main station so that's what
we chose to use as a first
implementation of our weekend to
integrate with donors and of the team G
so what's the current status within you
today without zeros so that camo tracer
can use on those techniques models but
there's no way to filter pinions per
container so you get my excess thousand
pencil didn't but you cannot really
easily match them to a specific
container and then for the user space
Treasury and
inside the Oh spray can also run inside
a container just need to run two
instances like one instance or container
but again there is no there's one
foundation that will make that would be
where you would be able to correlate
like a trace from the whole site with
the entire container right now so how
can you fix that today well we have
currently some passes where we have the
support for namespaces context so what
is it context you know that you can
attach to teach event in the kernel so
for example existing term that's our
theoretical so when you get assist all
you will add metadata to say which yeah
this is always issue from and so we we
added support to for namespaces of a
tree you can now when you get the kernel
event you can app to hold it in space
then you know which in which gave me
special process than thought this is
called words
and also we have another feature that is
all stayed up when you start tracing
state of the events will be issued that
will basically give you a current state
of the system so another thing that we
need to add a like a dump of the current
namespaces that are on the system for or
the tree of next basis for each process
so yes all those matches are going to be
not must meet their future branches and
yeah so
so for example here I have the text view
of a colonel event for the sysvol that
defined what this is called
so with these facets added with the the
men spaces I just pop it off so we can
see for example in in in green we have
the fitness which is basically the I
know number of the next base in the
process then because that's the only
unit I differentiate one leg space to
another and then we can see other useful
things we charted yanky yanky yanky is
the unique ID of a process inside the
kernel so tread lightly in the space of
the cow and then the CT which in this
case this one is the process ID as the
inside inside the next phase of the
container so infer this in this example
we can see that the Travis is called
rate observer and it's ID is 1 so we can
extrapolate from that that we're running
inside an application container and that
reduces running as the process efficient
so in this case it will be a registered
Republican thing and then the spectrum
so this
each processor running inside contains
four friends are called here we have
this is lengthy process and we can see
that it's sorry we can see that it's the
ID is 1527 so that's the background and
then we
- Canadians they don't get em so we can
see that the namespaces are nested so we
see a better statement that as a level
of one so this is the namespace that the
Nexus of a container and then the other
one has a base level of zero so that's
the house remains backwards and we can
see that the div never changes between
those cases you need 90 but you can see
that the VP ideas will change so in the
NS level one is the detective one and we
kind of slide 15:27 so with this
information
Enderman and we do the same thing for
the and with all this information now we
are both separate so we can start a
training session and say oh I want to
trace the Cisco that comes from this
container but right now it's not very
the greater because we need to know what
is the PID tuning space I know number of
our container to filter it we can the
doctor inspect we can get the CID from
the process and them with LS and s we
can get is the idea of the link space
and then using this information we can
create and of the session that will will
filter this and the resulting trace will
only contain syscalls that comes from
processed in this container so we're
starting to get somewhere but then we
will
company for example instead of I mean
angle number so to do this we need a way
to map Tara like human readable thanks
so right now the solution we found this
to use a small well they SL script based
on whether it's only before that will
iterate over all containers so you need
to write a helper for each kind of
company or any manner system that will
basically dump this information inside a
user space race that can then become
combined with an old friend and run
through some analysis for example and
here we I wrote a basic implementation
that occurs events and you can see that
just contain your name and I and with
all this you can use that we already
have an houses which are basically based
their houses space on faces so for
example in this fight it's probably not
very readable but this is a speed-up
analysis so we will take a penetration
input and we'll do a graph of city usage
for process but I've modified those
anything's at the down on the slide
where there's a bit of covered up you
can also now see city uses by container
and you can see the container name its
ID and its type so there's a lot of
those
that were provided by the LTTE analysis
project and we could all be adapted to
the company or wherever and it does
another analysis here it's a memory
allocator and how is this based on beta
like a patriot race wins in McDonald
so you could usually filter it on some
condition that you can have container
filter and see which companies leaders
under system are giving each elevation
and base allocation and so with those
tools a complete scenario would be to
run a an annular space racer on the
earth so you can get panel traces and
yet this beta or the neighbor solution
from chiron tanks and then for the
containers were you're running
applications that you could internet
with the hell and sorry the space racer
you could also run one in each of those
containers
[Music]
you don't have to have the same version
and and then we could string those all
out of those traces to and really over
the
and run some analysis applying get the
information therapy for so and web next
all the things I've shown you are not
yet a suite so we're working on emerging
this meaty forbidden expertise book
we're in Australia
another thing that someone else is
working on is adding the same kind of
things for context and speed up for
sequel patties so that's me at work home
and maybe land in in the following
months and longer times improvements
would be to instrument company rough
lines so that we could advance planning
company is created when configuration is
changed and all interesting information
that would also be integrated into
existing analysis a better view of
what's happening and also a better
integration with the existing come in
like people so for example instead of
having to type a big filter because just
like that's that
and that even would resolve the company
name things like some solid issues and
then as the ones also have a very
integration between the command line
tools and the different company around
that but what we're most interested in
is what do you need so I would really
like to ear off you guys with which you
are interested in what your what your
needs are before you do spaces and
finally first questions what do you do
with nested in your space yes well in
the state dumps we get nested advance
for all there so we can resolve know
what's the chain of just yes yes
so this simple example yes but we have
information about the hierarchy of the
second person is advanced the you see
the
[Applause]
[Music]
is it
for example another treasure
I take advantage of 2012 is another well
but if you can convert your references
to the CDF or not then you might be able
to run the analysis but that would imply
that the event names and so on are all
the same as for
apologies if I missed this but what
would be the point of container doesn't
want to maintain isolation between the
US and the containers well you could be
wrong the US based on the old trace
process inside a container but well
first couple of simple passes would we
have life of those expectations that
meant that by mounting at I agree with
the proper sockets inside of your
container I mean it works but the goal
right now is do not great isolation so
it's totally doable
from a user space trickster inside the
container also for it be plain
employment purposes issued up like this
on this rose in different containers
with different libraries it could get
very messed up so it's a lot easier to
just have one new space mixer for
foundation but like there's no technical
there's nothing that will prevent it in
the end to the one pressure inside of
that reference
all your spaces
No