welcome to the distribution stem room
our first speaker this morning is no
don't undo taken our first speaker this
morning is going to be under undress
chador Andre Oh Andrew butcher did what
under Sidora because any managing build
infrastructure of a debian derivative
yes the talk is being recorded the video
has been set up there's no queue minute
all right
you show up others pointing out the wall
well wall he's also quite nice thing to
see okay so I probably I didn't need to
prove myself once again but I will do
this anyway so I'm Andre and I'm a
Debian developer and well I started
using Debian around 2006 and very soon I
understood that well Debian is great
because of the contributors so I started
continue contributing myself at first by
sending bug reports then patches and
then finally I became well I started
maintaining some packages on my own and
at thousand thirteen I became a Debian
developer and started maintaining even
more things in Debian and then two years
later I started working for kelabra an
open source consultancy
and which is great in a way that we were
doing lots of fun things with open
source in our work time and at Cobra I
started working on a project which is
called a purchase of what which I will
talk today and just some background I
never run I need there been
infrastructure in my life even though I
have been part of a different project
for for quite some time and so I've got
no idea how to run like proper things
like build Z or D install other things
and because when I started working on a
purchase I had to manage quite similar
things but not based on normal Debian
software at all right away this is a
deep and derivative distribution which
is based in fact not just on Debian but
on a bun - and one bunch of other
packages of weave developments ourselves
it's been originally developed for for
automotive purposes in particular
entertainment systems in the cars but
since then the focus has been shifted to
all sorts of other onboard computers in
cars and as a part of the project we
provide lots of infrastructure for
development based on a purchase which
means code hosting at the moment is
sigit but we're planning to migrate to
get lab soon
backtracking system code review at the
moment its fabricator
and of course package build services
image generation services and automated
testing based on lava which I was going
to talk as well at for the but
unfortunate talk wasn't accepted so a
purchase is mostly based on the bunt at
the moment so we're a derivative of a
derivative we take a bunch of packages
directly from them and most notably
system D D bars and some other things
and we've developed a few of
sort of frameworks of our own ap ice and
other software packages so as I
mentioned we use system D for processes
tracking and the application lifestyle
lifecycle tracking we started using up
our many years ago when it was just a
new thing and it won t only so this was
one of the reasons we used to blunder
because they were off stream for
up-armored about a year ago I think
we've migrated from X log to Wayland for
graphics and we've been using GStreamer
for multimedia playback since the
beginning in a purchase we used flat
pack an OS tree so the application
bundle format is based on flat pack
which itself is based on always tree
it's not quite the same thing as flat
box bundles but we plan to migrate to
actual flat pack and not a solution
based on flat back soon
we have an update system based on our
history originally we had our own system
based on bitter butter affair snapshots
to make sure that updates are atomic and
we've got recovery modes and so on but
because of certain drawbacks of butter
fests we have developed our own system
based or we've developed a system based
knowledge tree so a couple of more
details so first of all or the butterfat
system had significant maintenance
effort because we had quite lots of
custom codes based around were working
with butterface snapshots then our
whitlow didn't support butter of s so we
couldn't use it on /boot for example and
other file systems which had to be
something else with butter fats we
needed to use any term affairs at all
times which isn't the best thing
sometimes in a better systems because
the updated direct and manipulated more
butter fest volumes which wasn't
suitable for for example unprivileged
containers and then with what reverse
testing was a bit difficult and
butterface itself has quite a lot of
issues which are being tackled but still
like it's not I myself don't consider a
really production-ready system so in
comparison os3 works with any file
system at all any file system which
supports UNIX semantics you can store
multiple trees in the same repository
which is definitely benefits and you
don't need extra partitions for upgrades
so it saves quite some space because
it's a more complete solution on its own
we have less custom code so the
maintenance is much easier and because
it's a user space solution it works
better with containers and we can use it
with unprivileged containers as well
so some people may ask question why are
we using this crazy mix of a bunch on
Debian and not just there because you
know Debian is great Universal and
obviously it's free software and it's a
community not company so but despite all
of those great things about Debian at
the moment when a purchase was created
there were certain issues with Debian
most importantly if there are people
here who are here who ran sod for
example they may remember that it took I
think four years or about that to get it
released because in Debian the policies
the release is when the race is ready
there's no until recently there wasn't
any particular time in employees so if
the world to many release can reach
critical bugs the the release might be
the way it's even the years since then
it's changed but when a purchase was
created it was still an issue and then
stable it's the truth table for many
people and you know with the frequency
of releases it means that you get
updates only once in two years and it's
not always what we want and then with
unstable things may break too often and
well I myself broken stable two weeks
ago when I updated one of the key bits
of it with POSIX shell unfortunately I
didn't do much testing didn't do enough
testing and I was something which was
broken for a couple of hours until I
poured it fixed and a couple of people
well quite a few people ran into this
issue and well it's been resolved since
then but this is an example of what may
happen in stable we kind of use it
directly it could blow all of updates
from there so bun - on the other hand
also quite large install base because
what lots of people who are too lazy to
run their band they just run a bun - for
example and so there's quite a lot of
testing despite me no more frequent
releases so Ubuntu is in upstream for
up-armored which was quite important
when the pipette is was created because
we heavily rely on up-armored for a
privilege separation and security and
well they've got regular times releases
and they also had an LCS when a Pettis
was created so these days we've got LTS
in Debian as well but but back then it
wasn't yet like that so there are a
couple of downsides obviously a practice
is a derivative of a derivative or
what's going on yeah
so this complicates upgrades into basis
because you know in every release of
Ubuntu there's quite a lot of updates
from coming from Debian originally and
when we are relating to a new version of
Ubuntu it just this impact amplifies and
then we don't really need all of the
things we haven't been to like Mayor for
example and other things so it doesn't
add any value for us because we use way
lawns we don't even use xorg anymore I
think there's the destroyed Mason anyway
so we are currently reconsidering this
decision and we might change back to
Debian because lots of issues Devon had
when decision was taken no longer issues
and it might make sense to rebate to
Devon LTS for example right so
and now bit more about the
infrastructure we have so the core of
orbital is open build service which
built packages in controlled
environments and maintains repositories
from which we create images and the
updates and so on so this code 49 review
tool at the moment it's the combination
of sigit and a fabricator but we will be
using github quite soon for for
co-hosting and probably for reviews as
well so the we will pull a few packages
directly into our gates like system D&D
bus so that we can apply our patches to
them if needed or we can reuse the newer
versions from Debian and the rest goes
like the normal packages from Bunter
Debian they go directly into OBS but
I'll tell you more about what OBS is and
how we use it in a moment so obvious it
every time it needs to build a package
it creates fresh fruit of operators in
this case build the package there and
publish is the binary packages the devs
in internal repository so all the source
packages are version controlled the
system resembles a subversion in a way
because it doesn't handle like proper
branches like and gets you can create
branches but they it's basically just a
copy with some version information which
you can build packages in their own
space they are not published in the
normal repositories so you can test how
things work in the branch well it has
some quite some fine-grained access
control tools so you can
let you users some users can just read
packages some can commit some can do
reviews and so on but well with more
information OBS was in the torque of and
early yesterday you can watch it online
so the purchase is split in multiple
components which a target development
help believes and so on and important
these snapshots each of them is a
obvious project on its own so it's more
less independent from others in OBS
project hang can use each other for
builds so for example here development
can depend on packages from Target and
is the cake can develop can depend on
packages from development and this means
that if the packages in development
require dependencies to build from
Target di installed in the truth by OBS
and used but normally not other way
around so an exception of this is
basically targets because target needs
some packages in development to build
but basically this plate is mostly for
for images but we we have several target
images and we don't want development
stuff like GCC in them so while GCC can
be used for builds it it's not installed
in the images so it naturally goes
development not target but Linux kernel
is obviously in the target so when
packages get built they are published in
an internal repositories in OBS which
are not enough formats but they use for
OBS itself to build other things
basically so when your package is
depending on something else
Orbis internally fetches the their
package in plain stores it in the truth
but for apps we use really Pro which
takes packages from OBS internal
repositories and publishes them a format
app can understand
so in obvious it's quite easy to do full
distribution rebuilds we're just adding
one more repository to the project it
obvious starts rebuilding all packages
in this repository and they don't know
where they stay in the repository but
they're not published in the actual apt
repulsive you explicitly ask obey to do
this and well it's a quite a tiny
screenshot on the screen but basically
you can add as many repositories in
obvious you like and you can select like
all like you can tell obvious which
other projects it depends and what
architectures to build for as you can
see we don't support I five eight six
for example or three six so right so as
I mentioned the packages which we apply
no changes relatively to bunt or Deb and
they go directly to obs
we just import them with no changes some
packages where the patches are trivial
like you know fixing my knee minor tiny
things we maintain them directly in the
OBS using the the obvious version
control system and we just apply patches
drop them in the in the Debian source
package and increment the version so
that we can see where we have local
changes and we a fork of bundles merge
ematic tool which pulls the updates from
one two and does automatic merges when
it's possible and then packages were
this approach does or doesn't work we
keep them and gets any use get for
merges and other things so that we it's
just we don't relate on Mathematica at
all those packages like I mentioned
system DD bus and the Meza and so on so
for non operative packages packages from
Devon on the bone so we use the fourteen
format from Debian so we have upstream
appeared in a purchased namespaces for
tags and branches obviously what we we
we try to reuse the git repositories
from Debian so we just we also have Deb
and slash something tags and branches in
repositories normally we use git real
package and GB ppq to manage the patches
in the repository you can read about
them in in one pages for godot package
basically I won't go into details and
for native a purchase package with a
similar similar scheme so the master is
like the the current diversion in the
current release there are branches for
previous releases like 7.12 and we
normally are it's an approach which is
not accepted in Debian usually so we
keep the Devon metadata the package and
stuff in the master not in a separate
branch as normally is done in Debian
because they just adds some maintenance
burden for for no reason and we we
normally just put tags on on those
budgets for the releases the the version
numbers are normally like zero and then
the release number and they just
increment so Jenkins build never commits
on those branches in any in controlled
environments if the built exceeds it
commits the result to OBS and OBS
creates merge requests and builds it in
a property road which we done review an
income and apply and merge we use it
tool called build snapshot written by
Simon which just creates releases out of
grid branches and if it's work in
progress not target as pop release it
just builds a package which has the this
this funny get number get for the
revision number in the version
so that we can see its development
version and well every time new pages
are submitted at fabricator they also
get applied and build by Jenkins
so until recently we used the narrow
image tools to build images it was split
in multiple stages I will talk about
this later but didn't our image tools
proved to be quite difficult to use and
maintain so we've changed to our custom
tool called dev Oz which does the
process much better and reliable so this
was the original scheme we used so we
had since we had this separation between
system Hardware dependent and
independent parts so OS park was
basically a table wall with the root
filesystem not including any hardware
dependent things and how do Park was the
kernel firmware and other things and we
would combine them in the images like
this so with DuBose Devils is a tool
written and go which is basically Debian
or as image builder mmm
we with Devils we split the build
process into stages in Yama file and
every stage does like its own thing and
you can use templates similar to ginger
to basically and select parts will be
depending on the type of the image it's
a really cool tool written by short
Simmons and Denise thinking basically
and here you can read more about it so
in this tool we got rid of the harder
boxes such we still use the term but
it's actually just packages and files
installed into the images when they are
built well so generates sis routes for
software development kit and then the
Jenkins jobs they trigger tests in lava
and when the packet the images are built
the it also goes through the fabrication
closes the box which were fixed and
images so this is how it looks in
Jenkins when it's all
greenin and happy so drugged quite some
challenges working with all these
because well obviously a mathematic
cannot handle anything more complicated
than just a couple of patches applied
locally gates does help but we cannot
put all things ingots so we need to
decide what can we do what can we put in
gate from what have we mentioned
manually removing old packages is quite
tricky sometimes because you need to
check what's going in a bunch on debian
and so on and draw a couple of more
issues with obvious basically because
obvious is not debian in the debian
stuff and they it doesn't do the same
things we are we're building well as I
mentioned we going to migrate to get lab
soon and become a common platform for
automotive system automotive systems and
not just entertainment to learn more go
to operate it at all and there's a wiki
where you can read those things and
learn more about the system
[Applause]