figure is under Chris yes it's me so
hello everybody
I'm Andre Kish and today I'm gonna talk
to you about some moldable analyses with
moose so first so currently I'm working
in a very very small consensus
consultancy company called Fink's so
you've probably never heard of it
and our job is to help other software
companies better understand their
software systems and better make
decisions about how to further evolve
their software systems and for that we
are using moose and moose in a very few
words is the platform for software and
data analysis it's completely open
source under MIT and its goal is to help
developers of you guys to write custom
analyses easily and today I just want to
give you a gentle introduction to what
does mean that doesn't mean just so
you'll have an idea of what we are doing
and how we are using this platform so in
short the focus of moose in order to be
able to make it easier to create those
analyses the focusing moose is not on
providing you with a huge list of
predefined analyses that you can apply
out-of-the-box on your software systems
rather than that the focus is shifted
towards what we call engines so these
are tools for building other tools
so that's plug that's moose in a world
that's a collection of engines that
allow you to build different types of
tools that we're going to use during an
analysis and for example there are
engines for building various types of
parsers in order to import data into
moose
so John before was talking about smack
see that's one engine that you can use
to build parsers in moose and here we're
not just talking about parsers for
source code because source code is just
one aspect of a software system you have
log files you have configurations over
configurations you have deployment
scripts compiled a compilation scripts
any other scripts you may have usage
data and I have real data all of this
should be able to you should be able to
import all of those into moose and
reason about them then once the data is
imported we need to store it somehow so
for
to have various engines to build
different models to represent data and
then link it intertwine it and reason
about it
so here the simplest is for building STS
so that's a simple one and then once the
data is imported
we have engines to write various types
of analysis for example you think you
can think here of static analysis tools
or checking dependencies or looking for
an application but there are also others
and now in the rest of this talk instead
of working through a list of just
features of MOS I want to show you two
use cases where we can use moose to
guide certain tasks that we have to do
and first one is going to be related to
investigating deprecations
so for this we're going to use Java and
the system that we're going to look at
is the leucine solar so that's quite a
big Java system and luckily I've found a
lot of deprecated classes in there so if
you're not familiar with deprecated
classes but I think you are it's this
little thing that you add to a Java
class in order to remind yourself I
should remove this at a certain point in
the future but then a lot of times you
don't remove when you keep using it and
then it's this usage the usages of this
are everywhere and but at a certain
point too let's select remove them and
what I would what we are going to do in
the next minute is assess how hard or
how hard are these how hard will be to
remove the deprecated classes from
Apache from the steam solar does that
and then see if we can do that in five
minutes so first this will be the main
interface that you get if you'd go and
load the sim solar into moose you don't
have to read this you just for example
it to say very generic things like all
methods there are 75,000 methods there
are 12,000 classes and so on so just get
a brief overview of the system and then
now we'll say okay I'm really interested
in the classes this 11 5 12 thousand so
then you can click and then you will get
a new pane to the right that information
so here we have a list of 12,000 classes
and now to find the deprecated ones I
definitely don't want to scroll because
that will take some time I could but
I will not do that instead we have here
another pain which is a pain where we
can write the query against the data
that we have loaded here so here we have
a list of 12,000 classes and now I want
to write the query against those to only
get the classes that are deprecated so
let's do that so this is the query can
you understand it good who can't
understand it okay so this is your first
so this language is the syntax is in
Pharaoh so Pharaoh is the programming
language on which planet moose is built
so it's an open source object-oriented
programming language so we'll just say
self so this is the current objects for
the current list of classes we want to
select only those classes that are
annotated with deprecated that's it well
if you run this we can execute it and
then in a new pane to the right we will
get the list of deprecated classes and
there are 36 deprecated classes here
lovely now can we remove them no because
they might be used so one option would
be to go to every one of these click on
this and say give me all the classes
that call this is it 0 the list remove
it so we have to do 46 times give me the
list of references to this class but we
don't want to do that what we want is to
write a query and we can update our
previous query to add another condition
so we want also and that are deprecated
and I forgot here some parentheses no
matter
each client type is empty so for each
entity in this case each is a class I
can ask it what are your client types
what are the classes that are using you
and it has also provider types what are
the classes that you are using so in
this case I want all the client types in
the list the result should be empty easy
so if I run this I would actually get
one result so there is one single class
here that happens to have no clients so
that we can remove done so now if we
change the query so here says is empty
so now let's make it not empty is not
empty we get the rest of 35 classes and
now that we have this
what would you do okay yes but we still
need to find where it is used how is
that using it or okay so what we want to
do is look at this list and see how many
usages does every deprecated class have
and maybe we have a deprecated class
that calls another deprecated class and
then we can just remove them together
maybe we have a deprecated class that's
used in 100 places or just in one place
so need to be able to understand this
structure of these deprecated classes
and how they are used and we want to do
that in the next to three minutes
because I don't I'm running out of time
so the idea would be done to build a
visualization to build something that
visualizes this so let's do that so we
can start from the previous script and
now I'm just naming these classes so now
this result the previous list is in the
variable classes and we want to build
the view we want to show shapes that are
circles and if the class is annotated
with deprecated I will color it in red
and then we want to display the current
list of classes the current list of
deprecated classes together with all
their client types so we're getting give
me all the deprecated classes give me
all their types put them in one list add
edges to old it between all client types
and then color them in red and then use
a force layout in order to make some
sense of this data so I guess we can
write this in five minutes if we go
slowly slowly
and then we can do this and we get this
so now we have took us a few minutes and
then we have a different way to look
approach this problem so now we can all
of a sudden see some interesting things
this one easy this one easy this one who
knows who knows who knows so we got an
idea now of the problem that we are
facing we still not sure how which one
would you start first I don't know is
this one easier than this one I don't
know so we need to go a bit more and
investigate so we'll adapt the script
with a few tweaks I will show you the
script at the end but first thing that I
would like to do is in this loosing
solar project as it named the Zener
solar they are actually two projects
they are loose in a solar so first let's
highlight these classes with blue if
they are from the scene and with green
if they are from solar exactly so then
we can see more interesting things so
this so most applications seem to happen
actually in the scene this cluster here
is mostly loose in this one here also
this one here and these two are more
company the more complicated ones
because these are all mixing things this
one even worse so maybe we can start
with this one at the beginning as it's
just one system if we don't want to
start doing the application depends
you'll see in a second we could start
also with the smaller ones but then we
could make a plan we have a bit more
information but still here how bigger
these classes may be this here is a
monster and maybe these are all small so
let's add one more step and let's add
let's make the size of a circle be equal
to the number of methods in that class
and then we get to a different story
so now turns out that one of those
deprecated classes is actually huge this
one I don't want to look here this seems
scary this seems more manageable but
still not maybe even this one is huge
and this one is huge maybe now I just
put a number of all matters there so the
size of a circle is given by the number
of methods that's it
but maybe half of those methods are not
used from deprecated classes so we're
just interested in those methods from
deprecated classes that are used from
somewhere and all the
methods that are using them the rest we
can ignore so we will take our script
with a few more lines and then we get
this so now here we have all the methods
and from other classes we only show the
matters that are using a deprecated
class from another class so now we have
get a different story so now we can
start actually to get more info and see
what's more going on here so if you look
here seems that all of these classes are
just I have one method that's using
another deprecated method so those are
should be easier to do okay this was the
big one but it's just three methods
using another three methods we have no
problem there this is problematic indeed
this is seems problematic this also
seems odd just two or three methods are
using the deprecated ones quite easy but
we can do one more thing let's change
the size of an actual circle of a
deprecated method to be equal to the
number of other methods that are calling
it so the bigger a method is the bigger
the circle is the more code is from in
other places so now we have again a
different story and now we can actually
start making decisions on how we have
all the information that we need here so
it turns out that there is one two
methods that are really problematic so
these two methods if we deprecate if we
remove carry move they are used
everywhere this and this and then here
it's still a few but is more manageable
here turns out just one so now in just
out five minutes for six minutes we are
able to move through a big it was a huge
project and reason a bit about what can
we do about this problem of removing
duplications and then if we go a step
back then this is the code that we need
to write in order to do this it still
takes some time to write but all took me
around one hour to do this whole
scenario of thinking what do I need to
do does this help me doesn't this help
me and notice here there is no scrollbar
so it's not that much of a code and
that's what I mean that's what I mean by
custom analysis with most and by
allowing developers to write custom
analysis this is just code you just code
that uses and provided libraries in
order to make sense
of some data that we have but then this
is not just a static picture so I run
the script and I got a picture for
example we can also select highlight so
if I go over a node so if I go over this
method here I can see the list I will
get highlighted all the links with all
the other methods that it calls but now
it might be the time when I want to read
the code of this method so until now we
reason about this problem and we never
looked at source code but we could make
a lot of progress without having to read
any code but now will be the time when
you should read the code of this method
maybe so then we can select it and
whenever we select an method here we
have the model entity that represents
that method so we can open a new pane to
the right where we can show the source
code so now we can look and see does
this make sense what does this method do
now we can start to do the actual task
of removing it and if we take here a
step back so using this scroll bar at
the bottom we can change or expand how
we look at our session how look at our
exploration so we started initially with
some overview of the system then we
selected the classes and we wrote a
query on those classes then we build a
visualization for the result of that
query and then we use the visualization
finally to explore source code so it in
the same workflow we have three
different very three different very
conceptually different things so writing
a query building visualization and
exploring source code and from here we
can continue we could say now let's look
at the senders of this or let's continue
so we can always continue the navigation
you don't have to stop at a certain
point and then we always can go back and
see what how did I get at this point
what was my query what was my
exploration session until this point
questions for this one yes
so I'm not sure I got the question but
you can come back afterwards to it
because otherwise we are losing some
time yes so so this model that I'm
showing you so he asked if there is a
universal model to model all languages
currently in Faro so we have a model
it's called families but mostly for
object oriented languages but that's be
losing an engine so does that engine you
can build a model for whatever language
you prefer but right now out of the box
we have for object-oriented languages
not any other language okay so now let's
move to a second use case so here this
was Java this is maybe boring so let's
look at another case study that we had
to do so the previous one was more or
less an example that I took and just to
show you something that we can do it
move so this one is actually from from a
real client that we had to work with to
help them with the angular application
and their problem was that they had a
big angular 1 application it was around
three hundred thousand lines of angular
one so it was quite a big monster and
they were trying to decouple it it was a
big monolith and they were trying to
decouple it in a few components so that
they could develop those independently
because until then everything was in one
place and everything was connected with
everything so it was not as easy to
develop and to maintain as they would
have wanted so we said ok but however we
had nothing in Faro for modeling angular
or anything like that so ok
so first I will give you a quick very
quick introduction to angular and how
dependencies are specified in angular
look at sort of the problem there we
needed to understand all the
dependencies from the angular things and
then it make them explicit so in angular
there is JavaScript and then there is
HTML and then in JavaScript more rest
you have modules that define components
and those components can be injected in
other components and then you have
templates that define the actual HTML
and then templates can refer to
component
Mora's like react but different slightly
different terminology and then if we
look at a very simple code example I
hope you can read it I try to make the
font as big as possible so we have a
module and in this module we are using a
template so we will define template URL
and give the name of the template this
case module X and then in module X we
have a component so using some -
component - B so this means there will
be another module that will define the
component so it's some component B and
this module is using another template
this is module Y component B and then
this defines so this is using another
template and this template defines uses
another component so this uses some
component a which happens to be defined
in the module above so now we have
actually a cyclic dependencies between
these so now if you are trying to remove
this will get errors because it's cyclic
so ideally we don't want to have this
kind of things but to detect this
automatically so we have to find all
these dependencies and then so now this
here some component a is specified in
camel case and then it's used here in a
different way so it understood - so you
can just grab that would be idea so I
don't know who design angular or why did
they do it like that but you cannot just
use search to find dependencies between
components that's never a good idea ever
but here I found the same problem in
pl/sql so that's a very old language but
since that things are repeating
themselves it's ok so we had this and
what we said is ok so let's build in
moose infrastructure that we can import
this analyze it so we import the
JavaScript we import the template and
then get all the components and all the
dependencies between these components so
we did that took a few days to get
everything working correctly and then we
could write this query so it could write
for example view giving all the angular
templates and give me all the angular
components because we had them in our
model imported and then we could build a
few more things in this view so you
could just have a show me some lines and
then I want to see edges from
all the angular templates - for all the
templates for all the angular templates
from the templates to the template that
it includes and then from all the
angular templates to the template to the
component so just draw lines from the
template to other templates and other
components and then apply a force layout
something and then we got this so this
was the thing with all the modules and
all the components and their connections
together now this view before with the
previous view we use that view to make a
decision with the one with the actual
without deprecation so in that we could
Circuit this is the class it has many
deprecation so this one is that really
useful for making a decision immediately
but it gives us an overview of the mess
and the complexity that we had to deal
with and the task that we had to work
with them to do they had two modules
module a and module B and they wanted
those to be split so then we said okay
how widespread are those modules so it
took the script with a few lines so now
red is module one and blue is module B
so this is the scope of the issue still
this view is not useful to make a
decision just shows that's okay this is
the problem deal with the problem what
we did then is say okay ideally we can't
we could take all the red things move
them in one place when we can take all
the blue things move them in one place
and it will be fine except that some
components and I'm not sure if I can
find one so maybe some components are
using both a and B so if I have a
component that's using mode both module
and module bit and have to do something
about it so what we did okay let's say
let's look at one component individually
so for example we could say give me all
angular components and I want one that
all the ones that have so this is a
made-up name so just give me all the
angular components that are for example
in a certain folder and I want to have
those and then if we have that component
we can build show a different view that
shows us the component so now we can see
again the components at all their
dependencies and for every component we
can highlight in red if it's used by the
module a and we will highlight it in
blue if it's used by module
and we did highlight it with both if
it's used in both so means that this
component that are used in both are the
problematic ones so now we have actually
a tool that allows us to look at a set
of components and see are these
components okay or shoot these
components be touched then we can write
a query to detect what are all those
components and then we this is how we
can make decisions and make sense of
this nice mess and then also from here
for example I would click on one of
these and get the source code that is
behind so it's blurry because it's
sourced further from the company but
then this tool we actually used for a
few days and then we were almost had
clear what the plan was clear what
should be done and before they are
spending a few months trying to do this
refactoring without success because
dependence is for the more implicit they
were not exposed they didn't see them
before ever
so you're just fixing one running and
hoping to it will work okay so these are
the main two things I wanted to show you
if you want to find out more about how
to use mousse so just showed you now
mousse and how it works but how do you
integrate mousse into your for example
scrum if you're using scrum at your
development process so for that there is
also we did the methodologies called
human assessment it's also freely
available and open-source and this just
in this we start with a hypothesis and
there are always several hypotheses can
we refactor this component into two or
can we split this into two then we apply
an analysis then you interpret are we
confident we do something not we do
again but the problem here is what
happens if there is no analysis so if I
have a question I need to answer it try
to build and there is no analysis what
do I do
nowadays you build the analysis and this
is how we are using mousse so for us
mousse is in a way in this process to
support us when we have hypotheses for
which one to time analysis but which
don't have the analysis so using mousse
as a tool to build those analysis to
help us make decisions and steer systems
in one direction or another
so if you want to find out more please
go to mousse technologies at org you can
join the community it's quite like I
said it's open source and we'll be happy
to have you on board so thank you very
much because it's so much exactly so
first question was what libraries are
using to draw graphs so we have our own
implementation of a framework for
drawing different types of graphs so
that's custom-made and second of course
if you have the graph is the second
question one was when is it worth it to
draw your data as a graph so that's the
exploration part of mousse it's never by
default if you draw just your data as a
graph because if you draw all your data
then for sure to not make sense so the
probe that we're doing it moves in this
iterative way where we start with some
data we try to visualize it and say can
we make a decision based on this data is
this data in a way that we can show
somebody then possibly non-technical and
help you make a decision and if not we
need to reiterate what do we need to
change do you need more data we need to
change our way you visualize it so it's
always a iterative process of finding
the right way the right visualization to
show based on the data that we have
yes dependency relationship is that a
common theme for you in most of your
projects as analyzing dependence
yeah that's appears quite a lot it's not
the only thing that we do it moves but I
want to just show one thing here so this
is y button D this is the main thing
that we're using in moose analyzing
dependencies are analyzing the
structures seeing how we can split
systems or how to control dependencies
as systems evolve that's that's a big
part yes yes okay so the question is if
it's possible to use our tools to make
like quick fixes or other automated
analysis in IDs so we don't have
anything that works with that by default
but it's possible so what we have that
works is for example you can write some
queries and have them as unit tests for
example I could say I don't want module
a to depend on module B or I want just
to be one one this is the only
dependency allowed between module and
module B you can write that and you can
have it as a unit test that you can run
in Travis or in your continuous
integration for example so that's some
part of it not really for other ideas
currently
I will use your toe today good okay
times up so thank you very much
[Applause]