thank you
hi this is my first FOSDEM and I'm
having such a good time can you hear me
okay awesome
um I'm Larissa you wanna just did a
great job of introducing me she's right
I am a former developer and product
manager I worked on many things but the
open source projects you would know are
buying the name server software is C
DHCP open Solaris and then Mozilla
project used to be a Perl hacker hacked
a lot of Perl long ago so other things
about me which are may be interesting
I'm a mom I'm 45 don't have a technical
degree I'm from California English is my
first language I attempt Spanish and I
attempt German in French but if you come
at me too fast I won't understand you
I'm pointing those things out not so
much because they're relevant to the
content of the top of the relevant to
Who I am and they're elements of
diversity right I'm also a queer woman
what else not there's a lot of things
about me that are me that are part of
who I am and they're part of what I
bring to work into my community
contributions right and all of you have
lots of things about you that are
relevant to your work into your
community contributions and the best
environments for us are the ones where
we can bring all those things and not
have fear about that so that is what
we're gonna get around to talking about
it some things we might cover I'm gonna
talk to these loads but I'm also going
faster than I would have because it's a
half an hour or not an hour took a
little bit about our CPG is a quick way
of writing community participation
guidelines a little bit about why we
changed them because we went through a
big process of changing them what we
have learned through changing them in
case you might want to change ORS or you
might want to learn from our mistakes or
you're part of our community and you're
curious any of those things
just a side note I love questions there
are no wrong or stupid questions with me
ever and you can ask them any time just
put your hand way up because there's a
lot of you
okay so feel free to interrupt me it's
okay so this is something that Mitchell
said about why we have our community
participation guidelines I like people
to read it I'll let you read it
basically
if our mission as Mozilla is to make the
internet a global public resource open
and accessible to all we need to be a
community made up of the diversity of
the world and we need to be a community
and a product welcoming of the diversity
of the world and to do that we need to
have ways that we work together that we
know how to work together okay so I'm
gonna have you answer questions if you
want
I have t-shirts they look like this they
are this t-shirt I will give you one
after this out there so that we don't
interrupt the next talk if you want to
answer any of these questions and you
don't have to be right just like there's
no stupid questions there are no wrong
answers there are just different answers
anybody or I can answer them all the
t-shirts will be mine
it's okay if you don't want to I'm gonna
start and people can jump in so what are
the community participation guidelines
we talked about that but basically they
are Mozilla's code of conduct for how we
treat each other are the behaviors that
we expect and their behaviors that we do
not think are acceptable and they are
applied everywhere that mozillian czar
together when did we make them I believe
it's eight years ago the first version
and what's changed about the guidelines
and why I'm gonna get into in my
presentations that we learned to worry
about that why do we need them at all
well we talked about that and I would
say because in order for us to feel safe
bringing our whole selves into a project
we need to know that that's not going to
cause us a problem or a barrier and also
that if you're a person who is in some
way substantially different than the
other people already in the project you
need to know that you're specifically
welcome not just that people are welcome
but that you are welcome that's really
important anyway I'm going to keep going
because
so I like to highlight this slide
because it's sort of why we have the
guidelines right we need to have a
baseline shared understanding for how we
treat each other and a process for what
to do when that doesn't work out if we
don't have that then we don't know
what's expected of us and we don't know
what to do when things go wrong which
happens more often than we would like to
think all right a few statistics about
more about the why and there's three
here first one is based on an EU study
about inappropriate behavior and it's a
workplace statistic but I think in many
ways open-source is like a workplace and
this in this regard so 14% of people in
the EU report problematic behavior and
20% of Mazzilli UNS have reported
something happening online that they
found inappropriate and that was a
Mozilla staff statistic but it's also
seems to be being borne out in community
research and also relevant is that these
kinds of situations often shift who feel
safe to participate and that may be one
reason why only 11% of open-source
community participants are women there
are lots of other diversity demographic
statistics we could go into that's not
really the theme motifs talk but I love
to talk about it someone wants to find
me at lunch tomorrow
feel free okay so one of the things I
want to talk about is like how and why
we changed our process so we created our
community participation guidelines and
they were much like an event could have
conduct but a little more general and
they were not necessarily extremely
specific about the different groups of
people and communities and attributes of
people that they protect or what would
happen if something
went wrong right it was more general
than that and over time we got a lot of
feedback from people as well as I would
say the entire culture around these
types of documents shifted and has moved
forward and so we decided we needed to
do a revision and I tried there to map
out what we did but basically we got a
lot of feedback then we also did two
different substantive diversity and
inclusion research projects one broad
broad project with a more more involving
Mozilla stuff and the second one being
very specifically community focused and
in both cases we got a lot of
information that people didn't know what
the guidelines were or what they were
expecting them to do or how to make a
report of a problem or what would happen
if they did or whether the guidelines
applied see were protected them so we
were like well this is a problem right
so we started a revision and we did some
community forums where we met with lots
of folks and asked people what they
needed we gave a revised version a
period of comment or we put it on a lot
of different Mozilla discourse and other
forums public blog posts etc to get
feedback we got a lot of feedback we
incorporated a lot of feedback we then
revise the guidelines with a team and
with Mozilla leadership so what we ended
up with involves directly editorial work
by our most senior leadership which i
think is important for any project that
your that your leadership team your your
whatever that group of people is really
support and buy-in to whatever you come
up with as guidelines because otherwise
when things go sideways they may not
feel strong about backing you and you
really want that and then we re-release
the guidelines and I'll go over the
content of them in a second but we also
very much consider them a living
document and that people can recommend
change
or effectively make a pull request and
submit a patch right anytime and in fact
there's one place in here where I tell
us has something because it's something
that we're really into grating in right
now based on someone's contribution so
what's in the guide lens anyway does
anyone have any questions yet all right
I'm gonna talk about what's in there and
then a little bit about what you might
want to do if you have your own
guidelines or you're trying to make them
I'm gonna go quickly there's a lot of
stuff here but also I put the slides on
the FOSDEM page and I'll send them to
anyone who needs them this is the first
two paragraphs of the guidelines I like
to share them separate from talking
about the more sort of bulleted list
sections because I think they get into
the spirit of why we have it and what it
really means we really want to recognize
appreciate and respect the diversity of
our global contributors everyone who
engages with mozilla in any way and all
of the different things that we are
right and we expect agreement and
adherence to the guidelines from
everyone who's involved right so that we
can have a safe and positive experience
and that is important enough to
emphasize many times and I would
encourage those of you who organize
Mozilla's stuff to make this that clear
to your communities I find it has
nothing but a positive benefit when we
do lots of words here but the high level
the TLDR of this is that any place that
you are representing mozilla or in a
mozilla space or engaging with mozilla
ins or doing the thing that you have
mozilla attached to you you are covered
by the guidelines and so are the other
people there so like one of the things
people don't always think about is if
you're at a conference that's not a
mozilla conference but you're
representing mozilla and something
happens to you that's really not awesome
then you feel violates the guidelines
the other person is not necess
mozillian we will still try to help you
and we will talk to the conference and
do our best to advocate with you because
you are there as a resilient right
for example basically if you're not sure
whether a situation is covered by the
guidelines it probably is um you know
the long list of diversity dimensions
and then you'll notice the nice Firefox
Orange any other dimensions not listed
comment that means if it turns out that
in your community there's a huge war
between the people that wear the blue
socks and the people that wear the
orange socks and someone insults someone
else based on their stock choices still
in the guidelines right we just don't
take our commentary to personal
attributes we don't and also there's a
lot of things here that are specifically
described in English that may not be
described in the same way in your native
language and maybe aren't clear and
that's what I mean when I say there's no
stupid questions if you want to ask me
later like what does that mean I don't
understand it's really okay I'm happy to
talk about it whatever it is and I mean
that sometimes people don't think I mean
it there you go and sometimes there are
also dimensions of diversity that are
really important in a specific cultural
context that aren't listed because
either we were unaware of them or
they're really important to a small
group of people as opposed to the
broader global community they're still
they're still covered okay there we go
so
these are like the the titles of for
long paragraphs in the actual text of
the guidelines which is on mozilla.org
and there's a link to it in the slides
but also if you just use your favorite
search engine
DuckDuckGo community participation
guidelines you will find them the four
things that we really expect from
mozillian Zand which I believe are
really important in general for all of
us are to be respectful hopefully I
don't need to explain what that means
being direct but professional and
professional is a little bit of a funky
word in the context of volunteerism but
I would say what we mean there is it's
really ok to have conflicts it's really
okay to disagree but we need to do it in
a way where we really let the other
person know but in a respectful manner
right and then listen to them and have
even a heated argument just without
devolving into personal attacks
appreciating and accommodating
similarities and differences I think the
really important thing here is
accommodating and like within Mozilla
one of the things that comes up a lot
here is thinking about other people's
language or timezone or food it was too
dark
Thanks yeah it's getting back outside
and I were really jet-lagged so if I
don't notice like you know meteors
coming at us that's because I'm I'm from
California
oh it was just like nothing all right
thanks for that so um and there's more
detailed examples on the and again in
the full version but also I think
leading by example is really important
we're all anybody who's here is probably
involved enough in your communities that
you are in fact a leader so the ways
that we act in the ways that we treat
people other people notice and do the
same it's really important to me and I
think too many of us right this is the
fun slide about the things that we don't
do so I think what's important to me to
point out here is a lot of this is
relatively obvious but one thing is that
the impact of violent language that is
just and I'm using what Americans call
air quotes there in words on a screen is
big and it sometimes might seem like
that's not a big impact but one of the
things that studies show is that violent
words lead to violent behavior right so
we don't tolerate violent words we don't
tolerate people talking about killing
each other people talking about guns
know another thing that's maybe not
always obvious is influencing or
instigating unacceptable behavior so
like heckling a speech is not okay
neither is elbowing your neighbor and
being like oh this person yeah let that
guy right that's not okay
the thing that's in italics that's
because that's a recent submission that
I'm adding in to the guidelines which is
that it's not okay to be at an event and
see someone say something totally racist
or sexist or homophobic to someone else
and not deal with it that doesn't mean
to like interrupt and make a giant scene
you need to find a way to deal with it
right and that's hard that's a big
expectation right but I think it's
important that as as community we stand
together and take care of each other so
that's why we're making that evolution
of our guidelines well this is a big
long slide and I'm not gonna go into
detail here but what I want to say is if
you are a person who's creating your own
guidelines our code of conduct it's
really important to spell out really
clearly for people what will happen if
they make a report or if someone makes a
report what potential sorts of
consequences there are who will hear
about it because that makes people both
to a more safe reporting and feel
hopefully less worried that there's
going to be some random thing that's
going to come after them right if people
don't know who's at the other end of the
thing right they have something really
painful that they need to tell someone
and they're sending it to an anonymous
email alias and they don't know who's on
the other end they may not do it right
so we try to be really explicit you will
reach these people these are the things
that could happen when people respond to
us we have a whole process that we go
through and you'll hear like I will get
back to you in this many days I will not
tell anybody else about this until you
tell me it's okay those kinds of things
really I have found this to be important
and in general I would say if you're the
person who's created a code of conduct
or guidelines for your organization
what are the number one things and I'll
get to this more is just be prepared for
people to actually use them it's really
a big deal things we've learned we
learned a lot we're a little tired so
the first thing I noticed when we
revised the guidelines we just started
talking about them more talking about
them a lot more going to lots of
meetings and talking about them and we
started getting a lot more reports and
I'll admit it at first I was like oh my
gosh something's going on suddenly
there's all this problematic behavior so
I went and talked to people who know a
lot about this kind of thing you know
about this kind of thing human resources
departments because they deal with it at
work right I said oh no that doesn't
mean there's more problematic behavior
it means people are telling you about
the behavior that was already there so
then I started hearing other things I
started hearing I feel so much safer
thank you for making it really clear
that it's not okay for people to bug me
about why I'm not drinking right thank
you for making it really clear that it's
not okay for people to walk up to me and
touch my hair right thank you for being
really clear that it's not okay to
comment on my religion it's not okay to
make snarky comments about my not doing
work on the Sabbath whatever it is
because it's not okay and it was going
on all along and once you start talking
about it things start changing but they
start changing in a lot of ways there's
a lot of value in the positive
reinforcement there's a lot of surprises
here was a really unexpected story that
I heard I got this email and it was from
some people who had gone to JavaScript
Brazil and at JavaScript Brazil
something had gone down that they felt
like was really not awesome and they
were like we really want to write this
letter of support to this woman who got
up on stage at Java Script Brazil and
talked about gender and tech and had
this really negative experience and we
want to know if we can say in it that
this but that we got this idea from your
guidelines and I was like yes please go
for it javascript people of Brazil I
don't know these people I've never met
them it's just the power of the internet
doing something really awesome it's
gonna happen it happened to me in a few
so I would say the biggest thing that
we've learned is that enforcement is
hard but not impossible
if you build these policies you have to
expect that people will use them you
need to practice responding we literally
came up with scenarios and talked about
them and we're still doing this I think
not everyone has gotten to do it yet but
it's like all right here at a conference
and somebody comes to you yeah question
time it's been half an hour
thank you for that um I'll wrap I'm
almost done so I want to take questions
oh this is a plug we only have the cpg
in five languages those are the five
languages if you speak another language
and you'd like to help us localize it we
want you this is advice for people who
have guidelines I'm just gonna zip along
and you can read this or ask me it's a
quote from a miserable person about how
when they don't have resources to solve
conflicts they just don't solve them and
they go underground that's not what you
want we're done that's how you reach me
I'm happy to talk about any of your own
code of conduct issues or DNI questions
and I'll be here all weekend and
tomorrow I have like no formal plans so
just send me a message all right that's
it thank you
[Applause]
you