presentation was originally planned for
one hour I had to compress stuff and do
some tricks and these tricks work at
best when you actually prepare also for
yourself by properly opening that the
link that I put there on the screen to
actually be able to follow that because
at the beginning the light was not bad
idea on so looking at that screen was
not that perfect experience so however
let's start so like there's a lot of
talk about deep speech recently and I
just want to present here more like a
users and developers perspective not
that much machine learners and
scientists perspective more like what
the outcome of that is and what
contributors can do to help us so to
start here first this simple question
like what are we actually doing so what
we do is that we develop a
speech-to-text system that means like
this is this little component while
little is probably a bad part for that
it's actually quite a powerful component
that enables voice assistance like for
example Cortana 0 and allocate Alexa
echo and so forth and this is that piece
that translates audio bra do data into
text so these assistants need more
components than that for example like a
voice activity detection and the reverse
operation like creating a voice from
text but at the moment we concentrate on
this actual hard part of translating
speech into text and this is based
actually on tensorflow and those of you
who know this is actually Pais based
framework developed by Google and we
built deep speech actually following a
paper from Baidu that that's actually
quite famous and we just realize what's
in that paper intensive flow to make it
accessible for everybody so
why are we doing this that's actually so
like I want to answer this as refold so
because it's it's a nice thing to do
like that so first thing is we actually
want to have a state of the art solution
that's not proprietary so state of the
admins like there's this classical
approaches that are based on hidden
Markov models and so forth and there are
very manually driven like programmed
literally from end to end like every
piece of that solutions is programmed by
people and what we wanted to do is like
to have this state-of-the-art solutions
like Google and and others do and have
this actually available for the broader
public and not just for proprietary
players and we know that this is
typically proprietary solutions we tend
to get evil at some point so and
therefore we try to get a better
solution here so the second reason is
that we actually want to have offline
support so as you probably know like
most assistants nowadays actually are
based on this schema of having some
audio data recorded locally send over
the network translated on some server
sent back and this comes with many
drawbacks and most importantly this
would our approach of offline support
would solve this privacy issue that this
has actually inherently and secondly
this will also lead to lower latency
like and if you have if you feel if you
really like experience the the solutions
nowadays even small improvements in
latency actually are really recognizable
you actually get different and better
feeling of the solution like and the
third reason is that an end-to-end
machine learning approach namely not
coding everything from A to Z but
actually having machine learning filling
the gap from input/output more or less
automatically is that our scaling you
mean actually that means actually
if you have data from let me say like an
unknown language X and you have enough
data of it you would not have to start
coding actually based on a linguistic
pattern a new solution but you would
instead just train the system to learn
this language by itself more or less and
the second thing is also that you have a
better degree of quality and that means
like these end-to-end machine learning
solutions are better at actually
accessing that details in the
abstraction levels that you typically
have in that systems in a way that is
actually more powerful for the outcome
that is actually leading to greater
quality so it's it's actually also in
quality scaling better so I actually as
I said already like want to give a bit
like a users perspective and first thing
I want to say like we released means
like it was a bit like a silent release
but in the end we released and this was
actually a couple weeks ago like was
last year and this week actually had
already a secondary release like um and
I actually wanted to show you what's in
the package so first thing is how you
prepare the environment like we have
software packages that you can just
install but for them to work you need
the data namely the models the brain you
could say like that we train you have to
download it and you have to get it
somewhere and this is what I actually
now want to show you it's a bit like
accelerator I'm not able to type that
fast I have to admit and so first you
actually get the models downloaded it's
actually a huge package that we provide
on github then you actually download
also some audio data and you can see
here like the audio data is actually
provided for you for demo purposes for
testing simple tests and I would now
like to try to play one of these samples
that are you throughout this demo now
this is that eight four five five XYZ
simple and I will go with the microphone
near to my notebook Wow
so it's actually somebody telling us so
saying like your power is sufficient I
said so like I do not want to lose too
many words on that but the thing is now
I want to show you like how this
actually works in pison to understand
this sentence so like you first create a
virtual environment as this we like from
scratch like you create in virtual
environment you source it then you
actually do pip install off deep speech
and comes batteries included namely it
has a command-line tool as you can see
here this use it parameters and now
actually we just pass in the model that
we downloaded the wav file that I just
played and the alphabet and you can see
here how it was translated actually into
that sentence that I just showed you and
the same happens here in the second pass
with a GPU power solution as you can see
like the GPU one is actually faster and
this is what we currently also
concentrate on to get the solution fast
and regards to real time like you have a
certain computing overhead that this
model actually implies and at the moment
if you go with the CPU there we are
almost around real time on normal PC
with the GPU you will get more so like
you can see that from the interpretation
times that you that you can see here in
the lock so it's a simplified
representation of this code it's
actually we like simple you have an
import you do then model you create a
model then you enable the decoder was a
language model and you pass in pretty
much that what I passed into this
command-line utility and then in the end
you print the transcript
so there's also a no chance version of
this it's very very similar um you
actually also can just use NPM install
deep speed well the typical kind of like
NPM workflow here it warns you here now
on uh not an initialized an
uninitialized project and then you can
actually here use the client that comes
also ship whether it was a model again
with the audio again and busy alphabet
again and you actually get the
translation the same with the version on
GPU basis you just replace in the former
statement you will see in a second
you'll replace keep speech with deep
deep deep speech - GPU and you get
actually the faster result this is a bit
like same similar code is completely
asynchronous like Noda stupidly doing
things by the way our community also
provided already rust and go bindings so
you can just also work with rust and go
on that somewhere to the performance in
regards to quality and this is kind of
like a measurement that's called vert
error rate whatever it means like how
many hours you have on how many correct
words and there is typically a done
measurement is a some table in the net
that compares the different solutions
against each other however part of this
tables also some from some deeps from
the leap speech paper from by do they
measure to the human performance so like
they actually let I think like they let
humans do the test and to have some cuts
some baseline to compare with and the
system that we currently have in the
model that we actually provide for
download is already actually performing
better than humans
just to get some some comparable will be
here
so now two more kind of like development
centric view on on to all of that not
embedding stuff but really like using
that stuff and extending it mainly
training models and development so like
when you want to train a model you have
to have also done some preparation work
I show that here this is primarily
actually about you have to by the way
this is one of them most often questions
and our forums it's both like why isn't
the download working it's because git
LFS is not instance so you have to
install git LFS first and so like when
you actually am clone our project
there's three steps that you have to do
afterwards the first step is actually to
install the requirements the Python
requirements there's a requirements txt
file and so like you can see that here
so we activate the environment that we
just created we install the requirements
and then after the requires come
installed I install manually this is
actually an additional step you have to
do when you have a GPU on your machine
you can additionally to the deep speech
package actually on salt also the these
requirements for a GPU solar that tends
a flow GPU support we have a tool for
that that is actually integrating for
all sorts of platforms the binaries that
are required for that like this tool
that you can see here is actually
automatically downloading that in
regards to your local machine so yeah
and you have a tremendous amount of
parameters you can see you're just the
tail of the whole parameter bulk that
deep speech docked I has as a command
and we actually because this is so
complicated we want to later do an
example that we like goes end-to-end
through the whole process of using it so
first we need to get some data and the
data we actually gather together onto a
page that we use voiced or mozilla.org
slash data and we not only provide our
common voice data which is a corpus that
we actually provide but we link also to
other data sources so it's really like a
one-stop shop here for actually getting
actual data I have to say this is only
for the English language at the moment
like this is English language corpora
that are used for training that kind of
deep speech models so if you want to
contribute your own voice you can do
that there is a mask for that you can
actually just tip tap this button and
then it will actually start a recording
process and then you can contribute
actually you was by reading at a
sentence that's presented to you and
this is the way how we built up our own
common voice corpus it's free to be used
by everybody in innocence premiere
important to say like it's not just like
let me get this data then it's really
like completely open data and and here
you can see also like it's not just
recording stuff but also like verifying
things like if something got recorded it
needs also to be verified by independent
people and there's some statistics
process running in background that says
like if you have more positive votes and
negative votes or no negative votes at
all then it's actually already validated
as as a valid file and and somebody had
not been just like accidentally hitting
a record and recorded his cat in the
background and whatsoever so this is how
that works so you can install easily
this common voice corpus we have
batteries included in deep speech
because we provide actually an own
importer tool for that this is again
like sourcing our environment and then
we actually go into the bin import CV
and this is really like just downloading
everything this actually what you saw
here is super super accelerated like it
takes really a long time to do like and
therefore I had to fake all of this
so you can see here actually I'm in the
last command that we have all sorts of
CSV files people look into those CSV
files later but take a take a look at
the different names that we have here we
have typically three different in this
case suffixes and one suffix is def and
train and and def train and test and I
will come later to that
so now we'll give you a micro tutorial
actually end to end how to use all of
this first a bit of terminology so loss
is actually a name from from the from
the machine learning and this is like
indicating leg as a number how different
the actual outcome is from the from the
expected outcome so like if you have a
translation of some audio into text and
you compare the text or outcome that you
expect with the textual outcome that it
computed you will get a number and that
number is actually important for the
system to actually do back propagation
in the process of learning sets in the
data corpus as we already saw the data
that in the train set is used for
training the deaf set is in every
application of the training data used
for validating that we are still
learning and not overfitting we will
come to that later and the test set is
in the end an unbiased set that is
executed after the learning is
completely done you actually do a final
test and this is typically used for
comparing across the industry the
different systems because all of those
tests are actually fixed by the ones who
create the corpus not by the by the
machine learners that actually use it
but by that that people that actually
provide the corpus so that across the
industry you can then compare solutions
an apart is actually when you trained of
the whole training set one time but
actually typically in training what you
do is you could you apply it several
times over and over and over again
so and this is actually what we will do
now in a second this is we will try to
overfit that means like this is just the
hello Baltimore and machine learning
it's not actual training overfitting
means like you learn your training set
it means like it will only understand
your training set it will not learn a
general understanding of the language
and this is because I have just one
sample I will I will show you that
sample in a second
and so in the end when the validation
said the orange one starts to to the
loss starts to increase again not a
decrease in the beginning of the train
it starts to increase again you actually
failed already but we do that on purpose
to just show that training works so what
I will show you now is actually not
realistic in regards to creating a real
model it's just a fake um so like and by
the way we have two different models so
like we have an acoustic and the
language model the acoustic one is that
one that we train now this is actually
mapping sounds to letters it's very
simplified but that's bonus what it does
and the latter one the the language
model is more less is it pro you
remember typing support on mobile phones
like it understands on a stochastic
point of view it understands language
and and can correct kind of like
literally translated audio into
characters into actual written words I
just understands language on an auto
graphic point of view and this is the
terminology that we need so first we
actually start to to try to actually I
can trend I can really like now it just
read it it's I recorded myself saying to
bukhov Yakov soon twice we create from
hidden text this is a stupid German
sentence that is a pan ramp Engram is
every letter of the German language is
one at least one time in this sentence
it's like the twig fox jumps over and so
forth just for German
now we create a corpus from that simple
oops this and this is really simple it's
in the end just like we have the simple
we make a corpus directory in that
directory of a file directory remove the
WAV file there then we actually create
one of these in this case a train one
CSV file the CSV file consists of three
columns a file name
this is actually an absolute file name
namely it needs needs to be rooted then
the wav file size of the transcript and
enter we like the absolute class now of
this jack-up WAV file the file size of
that that are just remembered and write
down this stupid sentence lower case
because it's not required to be
different encasing because you don't
hear Kaazing it's just like the system
will translate case-insensitive from
there on we now create a language model
this is a bit more tricky for that I
actually used wooden barrack
book they'll just download it and that I
actually used with a tool called kennel
I'm this is that tool that is used for
language models typically and you can
see here like how this is used to just
passed in their text in a sense and you
get this kind of language model
automatically there so there's no
training in the sense like it's more
like a conversion and you can see here I
am now doing a German alphabet I removed
this apostrophe that is not used in
German I add instead the umlaut an asset
and that's pretty much it then
downloading the arm the book wouldn't
back book you can see here like it's
simplified it's lower case all sentences
are actually on separate lines and then
actually we create using Ken LM this
model you there's a need to convert the
also to a binary representation that is
cheaper that is cheaper in n space and
then last not least we create a
so-called tree file that is used by our
piece of software that's not the
language model but the the acoustic
model from
for connecting to the language model now
let's do the almost last step all
together it's always a good thing to
write the so-called God run script or
run is actually get ignored in the root
of our deep speech project so you can
just put in your own run and that is
actually parameter rising deep speech to
your needs so you put in in this case
this simplified one sample corpus that
are just created three times for
development test and validation just
allow that like four four four four not
development for training test and
validation and they're they're linked to
the alphabet file that we created to
this language model the tree and the
binary paths that we just traded I
actually measured or figured out the
hyperparameters learning rate and
dropout right this is in machine and
called hyper Camrys I had to try out
like what the best values are for my
purpose for the demo here and the rest
is more like clutter except for the last
one this is actually then here
specifying this directory German models
actually acts as an export directive
once it actually got trained it will
store the model there and we will have
actually a similar directory to the
English one that we provide so this is
whoops this is like a real time view now
of the training process this is not
accelerated this is also me typing slow
by the way so you will see like he first
complains about our no validation step
needs to be bigger than zero for early
stopping to work this is just like me
doing overfitting stuff without caring
on invalidation at all but you can see
here he is starting optimization and the
first thing that he learns is something
yah-yah-yah and I learn something and
then he's shortening it into just one
letter and goes on like that and you can
see here if you look at the loss if you
spot the loss it's going down over the
steps
but I just this is boring to look at
that because this will take a while so I
actually prepared 20 time accelerated
version of this and this looks like this
and now look how the sentence on the
bottom converts over time as the network
understands what that means
except for this Rudin which is by the
way I can I consume this Rudin is a
German word and DN is a German word and
problem is DN is matching better here
and therefore he actually wants all the
time once to match T and but he will get
it at some point he will get it and then
he will not list this entries anymore
because he is only listing stuff that's
failing here already he matched it so it
means like you can see we trained an an
over fitting fashion perfectly this one
sentence this model is understanding
only in just this one sentence and not a
general general German representation
and you can see here now in the German
models folder it's actually also if you
see that output graph PB we already have
the kind of like similar directory that
we ship for English by our release of
deep speech next steps for you actually
if you want to go for doing something
something more serious on that is to get
more transcribed voice data get more and
contemporary language model texts the
texts from Gutenberg are not
contemporary German so like it's not
matching certain things it's really not
not working for modern Germany you can
say nein similar for of any other
language but you do not have really like
contemporary texts you have to tune the
hyper permease and for a wheeeeel
scenario not for this overfitting stupid
stuff that I demoed here and you have to
get hardware because machine learning is
computing intensive as hell we use two
machines with eight Titan X Pascal cards
in it for two weeks to train the model
for English that we should
and spread the word so last not least
our roadmap for 2018 is to train for
another language not named yet to have
streaming support this is like that the
computing starts already when the first
samples come in not just when the when
the recording is done and then you pass
it into the machinery so you lose some
time I'm optimizing for noisy
backgrounds this is really like having
samples augmented with Street noise
Restaurant noise stuff like that
actually barking dogs in the background
kitchen backgrounds and so forth so to
actually make a capable of understanding
language also under that conditions and
in the end we are currently working also
on text-to-speech so we want to actually
also have a text-to-speech component so
like you can talk to us be on IRC we
have the machine learning loop and that
is actually our discourse so please feel
free to contact us that's it
[Applause]
[Music]