hello everybody so
second only 20 minutes to tell you all
the fun stuff of this about me so very
short just working full time about on my
scale performance 3 milli fun stuff and
I can you tell much more so little yes I
have only 20 minutes about of try to do
it in 15 and so well what are my main
problems so in fact if you if your
problems are something how to tune your
query or use right in right way MySQL
and so on
everything you can read from HT FM it's
not my problem
so my problem is it's about what you
cannot fix which is broken by design
will not work by design and so on so
many problems are can only many problems
will just discover and well work in
progress so it's a progress here
historically so from 5/5 myself I fibers
who already tested medical a two guys
who already move it to five seven at
least so five five you know we deliver
adjust both some fixes which were
already known in five six we started to
do some deep changes which bring huge
pain because there was many regression
many difference and so on the most
painful point in five six was and rights
were faster than reads so in fact if you
want to read faster you need to you need
to send some rights and they will unlock
your reads and you will read faster so
it was completely odd dumbed what you
want and in five seven finally we fix it
reads so reads become faster but we
started to lose in efficiency so there
is always cost on something we always
always bouncing the code to get the most
optimal stuff so in a toe we are
fighting and I think it will be main
find for many years now for efficiency
to get the
best possible performance on the same
card or so no we are not running for the
bigger table you should be more
efficient in the same way so you will
see some flame graphs so it was a huge
progress on 5/7 you can see here once we
delivered on the read only a monstrous
result it we were so happy since this
big machine was upgraded from 72 or 96
so we are happy to get more than 2
million square now so Kate's real
numbers it's possible but the difference
between 800 and 5/7 not really big and
in fact well we don't care about this
anymore it goes with all this sauce and
we can do two million five
so for it only it's fine we don't charge
this so there'll be probably some
regression because we added new stuff
okay but our main problems it's
everything which was reminding from 5-7
so I will just add potential fixes which
we'll have here and speak about the
problems so on read-only there is still
Romanian block logs for example so if
you read constantly the same rows you
will have contention so it will go just
slower the other the work around here
it's just use query cache or proxy SQL
query cache there is no more query cache
in NATO
so proxy proxy Square is the best
solution look up on sector secondary
indexes on energy be can be many times
slower than primary key so the main work
around just to use primary key or while
we are working in another solution to
speed up all the stuffs there is also
adaptive hash index if you enable but
for the problem as soon as you have
rights it can slow slow down your staff
so these are hot topics for us here and
for utf-8 it's extremely faster now in a
tall so before for example in five seven
you are probable you can be ten times
slower if you use eg f8
so at least in a tow it's only 10 20
percent slower than legend one huge
progress here for double right so this
all read/write problems double right is
expected to be fix it engage also a
window will not speak here and will tell
you about the redo log changes we are
doing transaction logging and log
management so I will stick you about
cuts some come in with a doe transaction
installation will still work in progress
there is a huge potential fix here on
update there formats directly related to
redo logs and insert performance we are
working here but as soon as we keep v3
gadgets like if you if you can use
partitions of different tables you can
go very fast on yourself otherwise well
b3 is impacting you and for pooch if
George is lagging in your production so
at least with a toe you can truncate
undo so you can truncate as a space
which is your garbage correction effect
so to be short so we touch it so we try
to select the most kill'em problems we
only have so one the most killing one is
redo log so as soon as you optimize it
everything's and then you cannot write
on the redo log as fast as you want your
block yet so this is the final
bottlenecks on the heat
well except if you hit some other
problems if you don't hit them so this
is one so we for this was using this one
we attack it to fixing it all another
one is every IO board workload so in
energy we have global lock currently as
soon as you start to read something from
the disk you every i/o operation taking
the global lock so of course it cannot
scale and as you have faster and faster
storage you cannot do a faster uighurs
faster storage and so this is related to
file system Lakhan and also so for
Rolle working so we takin contribution
from Michigan University so I will speak
about this later so now about the
Riddler so what happens inside so well I
suppose that you know and we have the
transaction commit you know how to use
them so you flash on every commit or not
or once per second so in what was three
years ago we discovered and we can go
faster even if with flash on every
commit so in fact the storage is not a
problem
all the problem was about the looking
inside so all threats of users files I
fight him to write to redo work and in
fact this was the old model so you see
the global lock which is blocking
everybody and the new models and we have
dedicated log writer thread lock flashes
fed and notifications heads around so
just simplified structure so users are
not block it anymore
they are writing directly to the log
buffer and in parallel we are flashing
all this data to the disk
so in fact we are blocking it only by
your storage performance so faster you
can write faster will your redo log work
there is no more group iam so we don't
wait in its nature all grouping by your
flash speed on the disk
that's all so you will go as fast as
your storage can go so this code is
extremely well instrumented so you can
know exactly how many weights you have
what your thread are doing so what
happens inside and all the configuration
is dynamic so you can change whatever
you want inside and see it even resize
your buffers log buffer for example life
or even stop all the redo log if you
want so this is multi thread model now
but we have a trade-off so with multi
thread you never can be faster than
singles head which is that just doing
alone so it will do write a fin try to
think without any weights without any
centralization so of course it will be
go faster than in the right place with
threads so there is a trade-off and the
only option so we
disappointed them even driven system
cannot be as fast as spinning so opinion
is the most efficient way anyway so this
is painful probably later will will we
will invent something more efficient but
currently only spinning help them to go
as fast as single user doing the same
actions so you can imagine here so what
happens or just to give you an example
so if we do nothing if we don't use redo
lock so you can see this is we're going
this is a red line it's about the
current at all so if we don't do this
changes on the red lock you see we don't
reach the levels so this is say let's
see me this is the highest level than we
get with spinning but spinning as soon
as you eat a lot of CPU so then you go
down so in fact you need the balance
between spinning and even driven and so
currently what we decided to it will be
adaptive spinning so in fact you K you
can tune at least to say okay as soon as
they reach this level of CPU usage I
don't want to spin anymore only as soon
as my disk become slower than a given
response time I don't spin anymore so at
the end it will be just out at unit we
will out a disk our what happens on your
system and you will don't touch anything
but as a first release Bob would prefer
to give you some Union points here so
what we have is this for the first time
we present in the result with
transaction commit one because before it
was never possible as soon as you use
one
everything was level now it becomes
faster so a to become faster than five
seven five six in purity period right
test and much more faster yet in pure
update so when you go on Bombur then
when you have heavy updates workload so
the difference you will see
what is amazing heels and you see in
five seven we got huge regression here
and five seven is lower than 56
so in fact we had two times faster than
five seven fine but we are getting back
these regressions only got since five
six so this was related to all this work
about read-only improvement and so on so
we are still not scaling why so because
redo log is just the first step and we
have next layer log
so all this transaction locking lock
management and so on so just to give you
an example how it should be so this is
our prototype so in current development
version and it's so if a toe is not
scaling on one so this one CPU circuit
on on the left side so this is one CPU
socket and here in fact it's two CPU
socket so we we can reach 400,000 days
per second which is enormous number so
never seen until now but what this work
is in progress I hope it will be fixed
soon once we deliver into now what about
I work thoughts so well any i/o boned
workloads were bloated by storage until
now but now you you have a huge game
changer is flash storage which is coming
become faster and faster and faster and
in reality you have max throughput on
your flash storage but you have real
performance today is both driven by i/o
operations per second so in fact the
throughput is limited but you can like
divide it like a memory access so it's
not like before you know and we try to
do bigger IO to read more on whatever
now you can read small I only use too
much the same throughput but you you
will have more operations per second
especially if you need to read few
records from big block you know so it's
smaller blocks book will give you better
performance but in fact what happens on
energy be by default we have 16 K page
okay so compression that it is very
popular so we say okay let's compress
imagine we can compress it four times so
we will be able to read four times more
because so page of 16 K compress it to 4
K and with the same throughput we can
read form all pages great the problem is
we have exactly the same buffer pools of
your memory is not 4 times bigger so
once you uncompress your data it's still
the same useful data set so in fact you
can read faster but you cannot use your
data faster because before to read you
need to process what you already have
otherwise why you read write this data
and what happens if you will just
instead of 16 K page use 4 K page in
reality fold in the same memory you will
have four times more useful data and he
really will go fast
so of course this works if you need only
few data from the same page not if you
need the whole page otherwise okay this
will be a case bow but all the store is
not possible just because we have this
global lock mutex so global lock for
every eye operation so as soon as you
start him to read faster this global
lock is blocking you so you cannot read
it any more and so the good news is that
in a toe we fix this
so to validate these changes so we we
got the chance to use the latest Intel
obtain drive which is alone able to
deliver to the imagine so just one
single thread do in Furio can just read
with one gigs per second so one thousand
megabytes per second one single thread
so in fact using two drives like this in
theory with 40 page we are able to do
the 1 million reads per second but is it
true this secret
and in fact yes so we doing more than 1
million real IO board selects per second
so he is huge so bids to your IO bond
point select here and the same huge jump
in updates because in update it's much
more expensive so you can have to read
the page update the page write the page
and so on so a constantly doing I
operations and well this is the progress
and we expected from a long time and
finally a version cannon good on the
same time so we have storage solutions
which are coming with flash from any
vendors and we have code which will work
with this and for the last point I
wanted to tell you about the cats
so in MySQL it's colored cards initially
it was believed that and that's just
contention where transactions scheduling
so was invented by University of
Michigan and adopted in my school now
available since my CEO Ito so the idea
is Louisville looks pretty simple so in
fact not all transactions are equal and
you you have some transactions which
will look more data some less so some
objects are more important less
important so in fact this is a simple
schema I put you links also here to read
more about so it's very long paper
scientific paper explaining all the
logic with many examples and so on so in
fact how to decide tradition is we just
using FIFO and first came in for some
locket but in fact if you do it in more
smart way so you don't unlock the
transaction which came first but
transaction which is blocking more
others you have better performance but
in fact all the story it was much more
fun disease because it's turned to a
real a detective story in fact so there
was a claim about huge performance
improvement but as soon I started to
so any frog test did not show any
difference any difference no gain zero
all you just going slower so well we
started long investigation and
discussion with guys from Michigan but
because the first impression was there
just kidding you know there is nothing
real just it's fun something random they
know Murrieta biology applied the patch
so everything is working we did not
see any results okay so we started on
the sidewalk they want to solve final
layer so I found the way to to build
this scenario which shows a difference
so then it was big looping finally we
can see what will be improve it and as
soon we started to see the workload
sunny stuff had discovered bugs and bugs
in the patch and then it started to loop
in fact on the remaster in fiction
retesting again do we have again we lost
again with what can be again another bag
is open it so and so on so ball in fact
or it's probably with some nine months
on this in many loops before fixing
everything and at the end it was still
unclear in which way you should use
which algorithm and again GBA cannot sit
down and look on the workload and say
okay let's five minutes around this one
or now I switch to another model again
so finally we've come with solution
which after detection the problem and
the you will switch from fee for cats
accordion what is better for you in your
current workloads so we'll just discover
how many locks you have and decide what
is better so it helps everywhere when
you have rule load contention how you
can recognize it just follow your
showing Jean mutex output and you will
see if you have locks on your current
workload or not so in fact you need to
go somebody never when it all the
production both
bit questions everybody monitor
production right so well you mean eater
the sauce at times so if does you will
see your spikes and you will see okay
you it's your case so you will be happy
with Sato and so here is example with a
soul level it Pareto distribution so
means them you will have artificial
contention on data and many threads when
users will fight for the same data so
with a growing load you can see them
so without this algorithm you lose
performance who is growing load with
this one at least you solve something
okay
but you should be also realists and well
if you write your application and you
look every time everything so we'll just
bad programmer right so we try to avoid
blocking in fact so it's because if by
design in your application so you don't
want to create problems and main
problems are Canon
mostly because in energy B we have
repeat able to read the transaction is
relation okay we want to move to emitted
read the problems and this currently
it's creating even more problems because
of transaction looking but this is away
what we will do but in fact even this
case when you can use read commit you
don't see is any difference you know you
use what or you don't use or whatever
everything is fine so well I think once
will believe all the fixes and we want
everything will be transparent to me or
you'll be much more happy even worse
than before and with this solution is
wrong so go to action download the staff
and the most important point have fun
because otherwise we are doing action
and all our job is stupid
so if you don't have funds disappoint
thank you
I'm on time
[Applause]
[Music]
so any questions yep yep well so in fact
the main problem with double life you
see is guarantees so you have you just
have a small double right button which
is very small and especially than we
have working inside so in fact what is
the problem with double right so if this
is the only protection we have today
because of corrupted pages and what's
amazing then no storage vendor can linux
on linux can support using it you will
not have corrupted pages there is no
support so in fact we need to write it
twice every page and the only problem is
and you need to write them sequentially
so in fact you're right time will be two
times bigger so as soon as you can write
two times more in parallel everything is
fine so the new solution is just
allowing you to write faster in parallel
and because you will have many rights a
conference runs going going together and
you will side this latency time which is
increase it by two it's not bigger it
will be unlocked in fact so young mostly
blocked at only by storage currently are
blocked by design so this is a problem
but as soon as in veeram will come in
also you just you don't need storage
anymore
because the problem will you write twice
you will kill your flash device for
example two times faster so as soon as
you will have in V ROM which you can
rewrite any time as you want and it's
battery protected so you don't care
anymore it will just go in memory and
it's fine
yeah but this is double I first tried to
memory and protected as any right to
disk so at least one will be safe it's
fine other question here
well so we are working a full redesign
of transaction management so in fact all
the slogan which happens today which you
may kill you I have a detailed blog post
for example explaining the stats around
why it will be dangerous
so as soon the slogan will go you will
they just kept it with committed rate
don't you know so just be patient
it's canon no question