okay so we were starting in a minute so
the next stock is is Nakata even broker
by evil no even ailment here
yes exactly so thank you okay so I guess
I can start right so my name is veneer
that was fantastically well for enhanced
and I'm an engineer at dorando I'm sure
you before and I'm very lucky that I get
to do open source software and get paid
for it so that's really great and I work
on something that's called NACA DeHaven
broker a kadhi is a Georgian word that
means trim so now that makes a bit more
sense for you and what is it it's a
RESTful API on top of Kafka rock you
will come to that Sona kadhi is entirely
open source you can get in on github and
run the exact same version we're running
internally but we have our own
deployment of course for Zalando
we've got about I don't know 150 200
teams of engineers and we have an
architectural services micro services
and REST API and Jason format so they
use naka D in order to exchange messages
between between services it works quite
well they seem to be quite happy with
what we do so that's quite nice and but
that's not all we also use it to archive
all the data that should be archived
into our own data like and then it can
be used by researchers and data
scientists and bi people and everything
this is on you logo and it's actually
showing you that it's not even on the
website yet so you get to see it for the
first time and let's go back to the
let's see what is it - that's not ID
it's a RESTful API on top of Kafka like
you so restful api I think that's okay
for everyone
but can I ask you to stand up if you use
or have used Kafka like
it may be one-tenth of you if that
okay that's great and who's heard of
NACA D yeah that yeah go through me so
we're going to change that because now
you all have heard of my caddy right so
Kefka IQ is a little bit different than
the cues in like something like rabbitmq
or something so since not that many of
you used it let's spend a few minutes to
do a quick recap right
so in Kafka and in Accardi you can write
to an append-only log right and you have
producers who write and you have
consumers who consume today read what's
on the log and here you've got one
producer but it could be several ones
and he's writing like messages 0 1 2 3 4
5 and consumers they can say well I want
to stop consuming here and I'll just
sequentially consume everything and I'll
wait when I get catch up to with the
producer for and to write something and
then I read it etc so the difference is
that you can have several groups of
consumers and they can all consume the
same amount the all the data it's not
distributed to all of them so what do
you do in Kafka when you want to have
more throughput because you want to
write a lot of messages we get a lot of
messages well you can create partitions
and Kafka guarantees order only within a
partition so the producer gets to write
to either partitioning it's the truth
probably okay poor choice for him and
the consumers they can read from both
partitions and they can write twice as
much that's really nice so Kafka is
actually a distributed streaming
platform so every partition in Kafka is
replicated on a number of books on in
your classroom for us at three but I
think you can configure it to something
different and that that's how you get
distributed very highly available system
because anybody can go down it comes
back up there's no problem and even
while it's down things keep working so
that's really great
what does it have to do with mcaddy
this is the very high-level architecture
of Makati we've got Nakata sitting
between the producers and consumers in
our case everyone is under but maybe you
and Kafka on the other side and when a
Cathy does is quite a bit more than just
being some sort of HTTP proxy for Taft
although it is an HTTP proxy for Kafka
it's got a bunch of other features so in
Kafka you create a topic as we saw
earlier and that's your append only log
that has a number of partition the
equivalent in Makati is called an event
type but essentially it's pretty much
the same and with your event type you
create it in a caddy and it appears in
Kafka okay that's all fine and the caddy
has this nice feature you can say well
this is the schema in json schema that
every single event that is published to
this event type is guaranteed to -
confronting yeah and you can also do
scheme evolution so there are rules to
evolve your schema and only a forward or
only a backward compatible way so that
all your consumers will you don't
necessarily know have a number of
guarantees with regard to the ability to
read your messages even when your schema
has evil so these are three features of
Makati you've got HTTP proxy you've got
schema registry you've got schema
evolution that forward compatible
backward compatible not compatible at
all if you want and it's a bit more
risky it's got other things too you can
say well I don't want everyone to read
or write to this event type and I don't
want someone to go and train to my
schema and then break everything so you
can set per event type optimization
rules that define who gets to administer
the schema the event type sorry so
change the scheme admission to some time
bunch of things
who gets to write to the event type and
you get to read from the event type
which is very useful when you have
sensitive data to to put in there
you can also set a knock over that gets
to read everything by the way
this isn't you so that's that's for the
high level view of Macaulay and it's got
a bunch of other features but there is
one I really want to talk about because
I think that's what makes McCarty
different from the competition which
would be something like maybe a
confident platform or geniuses on AWS
what we've got is called timelines new
logo and timelines is really cool
because we'll have that problem with
operating a big kafka cluster we handle
several terabytes of data they is that
sometimes you want to move data from one
broker to another or from one cluster to
another and that requires copying a lot
of data between brokers and when we do
that we have a big problem we use more
bandwidth we use more we have more io
usage which means that everything slows
down for everyone else and if I can take
an example last year and the last year
we had to rebalance a cluster because we
wanted to add three new brokers to the
cluster the rebalance operation took an
entire week of copying data around for
an entire week we had people complain
why is Naqada slow because we're
rebalancing when is it going to finish
we don't know but it's probably going to
be a week it was a week so they weren't
happy and we thought well what can we do
because sometimes we really do we need
to move data around there's no way
around that but can we do it without
actually copying the data and can we do
it in a way that will not interrupt
service either for consumers or
producers so we want to be able to move
essentially an event type from one place
to another without no one noticing and
without slowdown and that's what we do
the timelines so let's imagine
we have an event type that is
represented by a topic in our cluster a
and we want to move it to our cluster B
right so we've got one producer right
here he's connected to naka D and the
kadhi on his behalf writes the messages
to depend on the log in Kafka and we've
got two consumers so this can't be
disconnected they have to be able to
keep writing and reading and the data
that is in topic 1 mustn't be moved to
the cluster B because otherwise
everything will slow down well we decide
to create a timeline we consider the
topic one is the first timeline and we
say well for this event I am creating a
new timeline back there you we create a
topic a different topic in the other
cluster and of course Naqada keeps track
of the end of the first term line which
was offset v and immediately the
producer is connected to the other topic
and he's publishing to the new topic and
the consumers there are still catching
up so they're behind with the the out of
it eventually some consumers will be
reading from the new topic others will
be reading still from the old one that's
fine
at some point everyone will have caught
up okay and because these these topics
they have a retention time that is set
we send it to four days but you can set
it to of course however long you want
eventually the data in the first topic
in the first timeline will disappear
it's gone so at that point you can just
delete the old topic and everyone is
writing to you and reading from your new
topic a new timeline using this you can
move the data but you don't move the
data but you move your event type from
one cluster to another so we've done
that that's fine the producers haven't
noticed because they kept writing all
the time no problem so that's fine
no consumers are happy to because they
kept consuming just a lil bit of slow
down at some point for some blocking in
synchronization but that's it and data
hasn't moved
so NACADA hasn't been slow
the first time we use this feature we
need it for a specific event a much
bigger Kafka cluster than the one we had
we needed it to be three four times
bigger we could have added more brokers
to our cluster don't know one week
rebalance have everyone complained for a
week and then at the end of the event
done the same thing
rebalance everything back to you only a
few of the brokers another week of
complaining and and remove the the
brokers a second planing but their right
to complain well if it's slow its slow
it's a problem so what we did is we
created a new cluster that was bigger we
create timelines for every single event
type that we had we have over two
thousand and everyone immediately
started using the second cluster and
then what did we do wait it we left the
old one still there because we knew
we'll have to go back to it after the
event again timelines for everyone back
to the old cluster and when the the big
one was empty
the event was past we could just get rid
of it very easy so that's our first use
of timelines or second use of timelines
we're working on this right now so
feature that's coming up it well you can
use terminals to repartition
a topic if you want more throughput as I
said in the beginning you want more
partitions now it's got a bunch of
problems but essentially you could use
timelines create a new topic that has
more partitions and because we have a
very nice consumption API you will
actually the consumers will also get the
data from all the new partitions that
didn't even know existed immediately and
we benefit from all the locking and
synchronization we have already
implemented in timelines so that's
really nice another thing we can do with
timelines is well actually who says we
need to have only Kafka any pub/sub
model that works in the same way could
work potentially and by the way who said
we need to have a single cluster we can
have several ones and configure them
differently depending our users
requirements and we
move the event types from one cluster to
another depending on changing
requirements from user which happens
actually quite a lot so that's it for
timelines Naqada you can find it online
the first link is mccurdy itself it's
written in Java it's a spring wheat
application there's all you need to get
started with docker images and only one
second link is an ecosystem we try to
create around riccati there's a bunch of
client libraries there's some for Scala
several ones for Java there's a Python
one and I think there's a go one that's
coming up at some point we have a web UI
which isn't open-source yet but we're
working on it
so you can like see things it's really
really nice and waiting for your
contributions thank you so we have time
for one or two questions so if anyone
has a question
any features that we lose by using naka
D and not Kafka directly yes so one
thing we're working on at the moment is
log compaction in Kafka unfortunately
doesn't play well with timelines because
you have to somehow we feed the data
from the old topic to the new one so
what we're working on a solution for
that but at the moment you wouldn't be
able to use it this is one example yes
sorry we don't have immediate plans to
do it but it's a possibility yeah that
could work sir oh yeah obviously are you
going to support Kinesis as a as a
back-end so you mean like yeah yeah yeah
we thought about it
actually someone implemented some proof
of concept so it's possible but it's not
production ready yet do you want to
contribute all right okay okay thank you
it's stateless
yeah it's stateless we use it in we're
running on AWS and we use auto scaling
groups and it just changes all the time
okay okay I guess time is up all right
thank you