native gtk stuff all right running on
VGA but it works so what's a native
right now in the existing releases we've
been eight of gtk file dialogue and
that's been dative forever
the most recent releases and the gk3
back end our two tips are now native
tooltips
we just tell gtk where the tooltip this
far and what the text is and GDK itself
renders a tooltip so that means that if
you have the case where you have to
screen side by side and the tooltip is
cut off that the gtk issue is not a
libre office issue and then i also
additionally we're now using popovers
for some of the things that used to be
tooltips
they're a little bit different gtk is
free and they have little indicator that
points down what the thing being pointed
to is they're pretty nice we have them
for formula type-ahead in calc and the
page indicator in the impress type in
the region motivation for making them
native was that the under Weiland is
very difficult to do your own tooltip
style things you just use each K ones
and we use them
what else is native in the react menu
which is available in Rome is fully
nation of course our context menus are
nowadays if you right-click and
something we actually have real gzk and
menus there and the menu bar is now a
native GT k3 menu bar and obviously the
menus within it are near Sochi TK 3 as
well and that derives out of the unity
work that was done there a couple years
ago so all of the menu positioning stuff
is all native to the case so if your
menu won't fit in the highest available
of the screen the fallback there is a
cheesy kateinasia fallback so there it's
the GDK positioning and gtk behavior for
what happens if something doesn't fit in
so all those books can go the toolkit
for item towards what's not native and
all of these special effects are all
just OpenGL Wayland OpenGL on Wayland to
show that it's flicker free I showed
them last year and they were flickery
this year they don't flicker so what do
we actually do for everything else to
mix look like it's native everything
else is actually not native
it's our own tool case but we use the G
key api's to render their widgets on to
our actual locations where we pretend
our widgets are so it's never quite
right you have all these EAP eyes that
are fine but you had to set up the
context the style context quite right to
map our space to G K States so obviously
for a radio button you'd say that it's
selected or not selected and then it'll
render it into the space that you set
out that you wanted rendered into but
you have to get the size right as well
you have to query g TK what would a
radio button what size should radio
button be in GD k figure that size out
then tells you to cater to render into
it
so if you get the size wrong you get
little artifacts that you see on some of
our areas where it's not quite right you
also have to use the rice call so you
might get them wrong it's it's quite a
complicated set of affairs and the
actual stuff that's available for use
outside the tool case is no longer quite
the stuff that's being used inside the
tool kit so you're using maybe context I
contexts that are quite right to try and
get the effect that you're hoping for so
it never really quite works but you were
pretty close but it's not quite right so
even get this stuff wrong little bit
wrong anyway yeah so backstory then the
UI descriptions where we've come from
all of our dialogues you just be
described in a SRC file farmers where
every widget was a fixed size everything
was measured in arbitrary character cell
widths and then again there was when you
load the UI under Germany would multiply
everything by 105 percent to get a
little bit bigger because German tends
to be a bit longer if you open up the
same dialogues in the Japanese it would
divide it by some amount cuz Chinese
does takes tend to be quite small so you
had this kind of guesstimate arbitrary
stuff going on here and there's no GUI
editor for all this old stuff so we come
from there to a situation where we're
now using the gtk builder file format
and all our UI is described in terms of
jjigae widgets we're not using gtk
widgets reducing our own vcl widgets but
we have described everything in the GDK
file format and then we're mapping that
at lower time of our own
you I educate build a fire farmer with
our own loader we added in some
resizable widgets equivalents
equivalents to the ggkp adjudicate box
so now we have widgets that contain
other widgets and then that dynamically
sized and positioned them according to
inter constraints that you can describe
in the glade GUI editor so the results
of all that is that you've got about a
thousand July files and parents we have
like about each accessibility bugs in
each one but they can be fixed in Glade
so that's the UI file so if everything
is now described in the GDK style fire
farmers but mapped at lower time for own
widgets and translations then are yet
again more in our own custom file format
the same SRC file format and the output
here was a braised binary file each
translation is indexed by a unique ID
and it's all converts to two relatively
standard po-2 go up to the website to be
translated there if you brought back
down and then converted back out into
our own custom file formats as well and
then when we converted everything over
to this UI file for the dynamic layout
and new description we had to keep a lot
of this stuff and have a little barge
there so that we run those translations
true the oil translation system and back
again so that's the old translation for
us but we've done at this stage for 6.0
i think is that we have finally gotten
rid of that file format and we're now
using the more standard get text file
format so it means that we'd get text we
can extract our translations directly
from our UI files and from our c++ with
the standard tooling for that so we use
get takes to pull out the tooling then
we have our dark pure files which are
now directly created from the
translations they can go up to the
website back down from the website and
then we can use get text to create the
standard
dart mo output file format and then
we're using the boost get takes
implementation to read them that the old
translation format is gone and the new
translation format is the standard get
takes file format so that's 20 2000
aren't translations so a thousand UI
files and 22,000 translations taken up
from the old binary file formats
converted into the dot UI XML file
format and to a binary but standardized
get text a mol file former the
consequence of moving all of the UI
descriptions and the translations out of
those file formats into standardized
performance is that the dialogues are
mostly GDK compatible in the sense that
you can use Glade previewer on any of
our UI files put the data in more files
from our translations into the path
where they can find them and you can use
Glade previewer to look at a localized
version of our any of our di files which
should mean that if we were to deploy
that deckard web utility for displaying
translations in a door ui file as
translators modify them that should work
in the majority of cases out of the box
now so obviously where am I Who am I
kinda hoping to go with all this it is
possible to load those that UI files
natively with UK with its own ggk
builder api bypassing our real
implementation of that and because GDK
handles the get text file formats let
ggk load those data more files and then
rather than and then come up with a kind
of a compatibility layer where we would
bind to those layers of cheese carriage
it's rather than using around vcl
widgets which are basically then
emulating those ghk widgets at runtime
and then we use our take our entire
existing stack that currently works and
just keep that as a fallback case for
guys under windows and the other ones
and further for the non gtk case for the
GDK case we'd use its alternative just
we'll walk through of my development
version which first shows a native gtk
menu fitting on screen as best it can
and I will just show in case anybody
hasn't seen us the popover still when
I'm talking about now that's a pop over
there that's animation do to get popover
that's just a native gtk thingy and as
the toolbars are native of course and we
will go for a simple one first more
breaks in search manual break so what
this is then is a native gtk this one
has been loaded by the GDK native gtk
loader they can boot exist at the same
time so this one dialog is using the
native gtk stuff and the other dialogue
step one or two other ones are using our
far back VCR one so what difference does
it make if you keep an eye on the grady
button and the top-left fades in rather
than concentrated fades in fades in okay
if i change to a different style and i
change the file number here when i have
gone down to the minimum allowed value
it has great house the left button and
left it or none great we in our
imputation we would have left them both
clickable and you would be an example of
where we get things wrong again if we
move back here and I hit this page break
one this should fade in gently
rather than coming in hard and then all
these things are native and fully on and
it works of course it works now the
style insert table has a bit more detail
again gently fades in fades out when you
get to that level and it might be there
we go and so on suppose so it all just
works out and it's needed now what's
maybe a little more interesting as well
is that there are cost there are
standard widgets what we do for the
custom case now this is another native
gtk dialog loading up the UI file that
we currently are
Dibley using first look at that non -
the fall style all these guys are going
to fade in at the same time they are
fading on the right hand side there is a
custom widget so for handling the case
of custom widgets that's adjudicate
drawing area we've got callbacks then
where we draw onto our own existing
output devices and then when the GDK
drawing area needs to refresh it can
take from our existing output device and
convert to its own so there are native
and they all work and let's go back to
the thingy for the conclusion yeah
walkthrough yeah so does a halfway house
API some of the problems though is that
the dialogues will not be usable
directly without some modification of
the dot UI files because we have our
implementation in GTA has this
implementation there are some divergent
areas where we have to modify our UI
files for some of the quirks between our
two different loading implementations
one minor one is like radio buttons in
our case we have already buttons and we
linked them to each other in a circle to
make it work on the GDK you have to link
the inactive ones to the active one so
their changes like that and there's a
whole bunch of smaller details as well
where we have to modify the UI files
hopefully in a pretty much shriek offers
automatically kind of a way one small
one is where we have our buttons on the
right-hand side we're just going to have
to put them on the bottom but we want to
put them on the bottom anyway so there's
nowhere final things there some gutters
and the gutters I described there and
there's some difficulties where some
parts of ECL have have leaked out to the
you know a P I so you can even up down
handlers for the plus/minus buttons and
spin buttons for the up and down there
there isn't an existing and equivalent
one in in GD k so they'll have to be at
work on to under interfacing the
existing you know stuff that has leaked
out that should never relieve leaked out
and to have to be some amount of you
know support as well to tunnel the
dialogues true and one of the things
that we probably need to do is
to move those extend the tips out of
help and into that UI files and if we
wanted to do this for ages and it's
still a good idea but the translators
have been through a lot of pains so the
other one wasn't true anymore misery but
that might happen anyway we're with the
help changes if the help goes the
tooltips aren't there so something will
have to happen and if we stick with the
model of we need a fallback then we're
limited only to gtk widgets that exists
as equivalents Toro and vcl widgets we
would have to remain within the subset
of of the existing implementation unless
we went down the line to just try and
use gtk under all platforms the rid of
our toolkit and then we could use
whatever be available but for the moment
and there's limits to what we already
support okay thank you any questions as
any of any questions or concerns