thanks a lot for having me and no
pressure like 500 people in there
another 500 out there cool and that
works right so we're gonna talking a
little bit about networking just to get
an idea who has been using go six months
or less oh a year or less okay and
the rest of you since the beginning okay
cool
the only interesting bit of information
on that slide is probably that I'm a
developer turned ops I've been doing
software for a few years now and since
2014 essentially I'm a gopher Island I'm
doing everything and go if you want to
follow along follow up and given the new
set up I'm not actually gonna type this
stuff in there wouldn't have been
possible with that like anyways so you
would just trust me that the code that I
show you actually executes you can also
grab the code and the commands I'm using
from that URL here so everything is
there everything's online that's the
reason why I can present now all right
quick look at the agenda looks more than
it really is unfortunately because it's
only half an hour I don't really have
the time to go into really deep detail
but if you are interested in you know
hitting up I'm here until Monday all
right the net package the TLDR of that
talk is essentially how forking awesome
go is because it brings so many things
already you know typically in the
standard library and has awesome
packages for everything else so this is
a kind of very high-level overview of
the net package not very useful just a
screenshot there are things that you
would expect like you know HTTP URL RPC
mail SMTP and so on and so forth and I
thought about how can you actually I try
to come up with a visualization that
makes more sense if you're coming from
networking sites so who of you is
comfortable with looking at that network
the layer stack
pretty much everybody right cool awesome
so then we can just you know I I just
you know I'm not gonna explain what
these things are just one electrical
thing I think it was Vint Cerf who said
we won because we focused on the
implementation not only documentation
otherwise we would be looking at the OSI
seven layers but yeah that's where we
are so on the physical layer there
obviously dotnet interface and hardware
address the thing here I don't know if
the pointer works yeah that is pretty
kick-ass I had a look at that
essentially allows you to dig into the
Ethernet packages and so on so if you if
you're down there IOT or whatever and
you really want to look at packages on
that level
go and have a look at that networking
layer you have multiple things to
represent ipv4 or six addresses and then
you know some asking and some so forth
and then go packet which is kind of like
Google's go packet which is kind of like
on that layer as well
moving up the stack transport layer you
have connection IP connection and then
the application layer pretty rich and as
you can see so the black stuff is part
of the standard lip and the blue stuff
is you know not yet part of the standard
lip yeah so as I said already
things like HTTP URL and so on all of
that is built in and then there are a
few things which I wish that would be
built in and I believe correct me from
Iran who who is here from the go team
might be able to clarify that someone I
heard someone earlier no so is there any
good reason why WebSocket is not in the
standard library okay who if you wants
to have WebSocket in the standard
library that will probably be 1.15 all
right so I keep using gorilla WebSocket
there probably others as well
yeah we're gonna have a look at that
later so I think I personally think this
does not totally suck but probably there
are better ways to visualize it but at
least you get an idea on which layer
certain packages
[Music]
if you have any question you know feel
free so the first example we're gonna
have a look at is a curl mini curl
really in a few lines of code
essentially essentially focusing on this
part here right see we do HTTP GET here
with the URL provided by the argument
and then using HTTP util dumped response
to just have a look at the result and
this I mean obviously has a few more
features but this already kind of like
shows you the power of the actual
building the standard lip stuff yeah
okay so second part here that actually
you know pulls out this stuff from the
body and then in this case the example
used here essentially allows you to
specify the amount of like payload and
in bytes that you actually want to
display then just to show you how you
can you know reads or read only partial
responses there next example would be an
app server so some something that has an
HTTP API and responds with hopefully
something useful so in this case
actually that would already be the first
term go there from with 3000 if they
would fit in so in this case you're
essentially just using the the standard
vanilla HTTP handle funk and provide the
path so whenever I do a curl or hit
hippie on you know it's running on nine
eight seven six the port slash about
then I would expect to get back this
this struct in in Jason Corrigan Jason
and believe me you know if I would have
my own laptop I would now do curl that
on you would see that Jason there again
pretty pretty straightforward the only
thing and I'm gonna talk about that a
little bit later on the best practices
is that this here is a little bit too
convenient a little bit too like the
defaults could be a little bit better
again if you disagree with anything here
you know please tell me later this is
essentially what I'm kind of criticized
like if you if you're doing that right
you're probably doing something wrong
what you really should be doing and
someone thankfully put together just so
I didn't have to do that and that's the
kind of like the the gist of the whole
gist of which is the the real thing here
so you really want to set timeouts here
you really you can have a handler here
for tracing the requests in here an
arrow logger and so on it's the first so
really like it's there so please use it
it is in the standard library please use
it to use timeouts to use free tries the
next example that I had is around a very
very like silly stupid simple RPC client
server that essentially in this case
it's really just you know a fixed call
so I have a look at the the server here
essentially is listening again on a
certain port in our case 1 2 3 4 and
then just waits for for incoming
connection and then executes on the
server side a certain method here and
the method is essentially just
multiplication so it takes two input
parameters and then multiplies them and
gives that back in the sorry that was
the client oops that was the client and
the server side effectively just sits
there and waits until client connects
and RPC client connects and caused a
certain function that is great I'm kind
of like on the fence here with the RPC
built in standard library it's it's you
know good enough but they are I'm gonna
come back to that in a moment
better options or more flexible more
powerful options any questions so far
second level programming I love that I
didn't put the link to the video there I
think it was Linux con Australia or
something like that a guy giving a talk
about yeah essentially ipv6 and that
that really like took a snap of that
that really fascinated me so if you
compare ipv4 with ipv6 just a summary
here just to get everyone on the same
page this one here is the real the real
thing right so if you assign every IP
address essentially some weight it would
be 75 milligrams for all the ipv4
addresses that we have and roughly the
the mass of the earth that ipv6 has
which means that's quite a lot of
addresses rights a lot of things are
possible and will change but
unfortunately which I'm still pointing
out there you know it's a bit like the
year of Linux desktop right it's any
every every year it will happen and yet
still 2018 we're still using ipv4 like
how anyways quick reminder or recap
regarding ports everyone familiar with
ports and those different ranges here
privileged well-known ports I am a
registered ones and ephemeral ones yeah
and you know for next slide essentially
just we more or less distinguished
between connection oriented TCP for
example that is used by thank you by
HTTP and many many others and
connectionless or broadcast types like
UDP which is still used by Athena's but
I would argue that many many layer four
protocols nowadays actually use TCP so
in this case what you would see if I
would type it in here would essentially
be a HTTP GET using the low-level
functionality that the standard library
provides so we are actually the main
things here we first resolve the address
then we use net to beoh
TCP to get there actually send the head
request so not to get but ahead sorry
help
with 4ht p10 and then the rest is more
or less the same as we have seen earlier
on getting the the response back and
parsing that and printing it out so
obviously for HTTP you probably don't
want that but you can use that pattern
for for other layer 4 protocols to just
you know build your own client or
whatever using these low level
primitives can be very useful so I'm
halfway through the time and my talk
that's awesome so let's see timeout and
retries so who has who has not used
either timeouts or retries in their
production code everyone you liars come
on I I'm raising my hand I am guilty so
it is still very much the case and given
you know cloud public cloud and this and
dad that you know either the network
between you and you know your favorite
cloud provider within the cloud provider
or any third party services that might
you might be calling out to which is
increasingly so the case this is not
reliable so you will run into things
that you know it just times out and if
your code is not aware of that well
you're probably gonna debug and then you
probably should use those and it's
really it's like there is it's minimal
overhead it's not like that you need to
to invest a lot of time and pretty much
natively support it within the standard
library so please please do use timeouts
do use retries for that and to me like I
nowadays would say this is really a hard
requirement for production level of
production quality software if you don't
do that the code review should be should
point that out
there are three resources I found real
good many but these three I cut it down
to these three that I personally think
really are very very helpful if anyone
of you is in the audience or is looking
live hello thank you for putting that
together that's very
hello security
who doesn't like security I must say I'm
pretty again very very impressed when I
had to look first when I came to go to
what extent go really provides security
related features we know crypto and
there are many many things that you can
use out of the box or or you know
packages that are available and
essentially again pretty much like with
the timeouts and retries if you don't
leverage that if you you know don't use
TLS many many other things around there
then you know don't come and complain
it's not ghost fault dns that is
probably my most favourite topic and
maybe either now or over a beer someone
can explain to me like my hunch would be
it's probably due to portability reasons
but why the fork does go have two
options here why does it you don't have
to pure go resolver in The Seagull
bastes resolver there I have no idea if
you know the answer please hit me up or
or yell at me now I am more than happy
to learn essentially what it means it's
a very very simple example just to you
know grab something fqdn and and look it
up and luckily I put the result here as
well so if I do that on my local laptop
with the go D botnet DNS set to see go I
actually can resolve I don't know if you
see it here that's the name of my you
know dot local domain on my machine but
my machine but you know the one that
doesn't work and I would actually get an
IP address here so the DNS lookup here
would work if I do the same with net
Dinah's go he panics right so I'm not
like I'm not judging that fact I'm just
really really really if if we forget
everything else but please remember that
and it will probably save you a few gray
hairs or a couple of for your life a
couple of hours of your life getting
back if you're running into that issue
in in whatever set up it certainly did
for me
yes so my favorite topic is gun coming
back to our PC getting more and more
interesting and and thank you you know
the the rest hype if you wish seeing a
little bit of yeah competition here from
our PC so as I said it's perfectly OK I
think to use what the standard library
offers you in terms of our PC if that
doesn't help you or if you're limited by
that here you have two great choices
chair PC originally created by Google
and I believe it's pretty much the same
that they're using internally it's now a
CNC F project a cloud native computing
Foundation project it's very past and
powerful I guess the only reason that
twitch came up with syrup here is that
it requires HTTP to so twitch apparently
was initially a cheap PC user and then
said well we really like to use hate the
HTTP 1.1 and would like to have a non
binary JSON representation which makes
it easier to debug and that's why they
came up with 12 pretty new a couple of
weeks or so old so I didn't really have
a chance to go deep into into that so I
can't really answer questions around it
if anyone from twitch or who has used
that already is here I'd love to talk
with you and then there are a bunch of
other non-standard libraries or packages
that I encourage you to check out we
already had the WebSocket there and and
the epics gateway DNS FS is a pretty
cool heck implementing a file system on
DNS that's pretty nice we have Google
packet packet inspection and for low
level stuff Ethernet packet that gets
this one here so depending on your use
case and the situation you're in you
find yourself in you probably want to
have a look at you know before you write
it yourself maybe have a look at those
things they they're pretty kick-ass web
this is probably my second favorite
slide on that back and I could you know
if I'd been my laptop I could actually
actually go present still doesn't
support videos that's a feature request
right we should really have videos in go
percent it does but not which one I love
you Francesca
so this is an animation where this guy
goes like into that you know time sink
so if you must if you typically if you
come from another environment if you're
you know Ruby on Rails or whatever and
go like oh doesn't have you know or what
are the frameworks well you know someone
put together the top six and actually
that's a very nice you know very nicely
done so there are of course there are
you know people especially coming from
different languages put together these
and you know as you can tell from the
stars and forks and whatnot
pretty popular but I also encourage you
to read that one here because it is
quite often true you don't necessarily
need stuff like that a little bit on the
fence probably I'm doing the wrong kind
of things to actually depend on that but
it's there if you want quick recap or
summary of best practices writing
networked applications in general there
is this old you know the fallacies of
distributed computing gave a contract
last year about that it's again it's
still very valid and probably even more
so to be aware of the fallacies there
there is a very nice context package I
didn't really go into great detail early
on so do use the context package wisely
and again reminder do use timeouts to
use retries and obviously the three keys
test test test in terms of and I I'm
coming from the community's land so this
kind of like health checking probing is
is kind of like you know built in there
are two kind of philosophies there are
two ways to approach that
you can either subscribe to the idea
that you push the instrumentation to the
developer so it's you actually writing
instrument to code people of theirs go
metrics whatever or you kind of like
outsource that to a service mesh like
mr. hundred they have site cars and they
essentially do that stuff for you
whatever you do please do it any any
kind of metrics either the developer
themselves or some other thing that sits
in the sides and does it for you it's
really useful you're really helpful and
with that I'm already on the last slide
and happy to have a discussion a number
of things that are very very useful if
you are not that deep into networking
with go I based many of the examples on
this wonderful online available book
network program with go by young and
then there are a couple of other you
know blog posts and so on that that I
really you know depending on what you're
into BCE or whatever level would
encourage you to read and with that I'm
open for questions thank you
[Applause]
before we do the QA quick reminder if
you're in between my face and the camera
you are on the video we're gonna do a
Q&A and afterwards I'm going to have to
kick every single person that is
standing up out of the room it's not my
rules so please make sure that there's
no free seats anywhere I remove all my
stuff from my seat so if someone wants
to use my seat I will be just chilling
here so please try to do that and now
can i any questions yes please
right
ready
okay
quick common Q&A so we're gonna accept
only questions especially because we
cannot hear you so if you have a
question please go for it thank you just
to quickly recap what you said it's
essentially the the DNS stuff that I
mentioned they're essentially more or
less to be more flexible to accommodate
a range of different naming resolution
systems okay
thanks I'm gonna build it in any other
questions that seems not the case you're
just scratching yourself okay cool
okay yeah the question was if I wreck if
I have any recommendations for libraries
like pick happened yes the answer is it
is in that slide it was the topic yeah
thank you so have a look at that and I
tried it out it's pretty pretty kick-ass
[Applause]