sorry yeah that's okay thank you so we
talked a bit about VPP this morning's
but but I realize many people here may
not know about about DPP so let me
calibrate my presentation who in the
room knows about VPP okay so some of you
know but not everybody so I can what I
can do is I can I can share a few slides
about what VPP is and then while while
gel gaps was talking I did set up a
quick container demo using using VPP so
perhaps I will be here and it's very
risky because I just did it now so we'll
see and maybe we'll have one of those a
demo effect and then I will share with
you slides explaining our VPP is
integrated into OpenStack with ease
networking VPP ml to driver okay so let
me share few slides first quickly and
then we'll go into the demo
okay so VP P stands for vector packet
processing
it's a project it's an open-source
project and the Linux Foundation and it
actually it is a curie under another
umbrella project which is FD dot io
which stands for fast dot a dot io VPP
is a software that does packet
processing what that means is that reads
packet and forward them and modify them
and follow-up them again so this kind of
of thing which is usually done in Linux
kernel or in order of packet forwarding
or in our way right so it's a software
implementation usually it works on DP DK
but then you have also I net packet I
use that on top of which it concedes and
this project sits here in the in the
intern stack so this morning charge was
talking about opendaylight which is here
I guess later in the afternoon the days
there will be a presentation about Oh
infe so VPP is really low layer right
the single reading packet forwarding
packet and the thing which needs to be
really really fast
so this Fido project is actually a
multi-party project with many people
coming from many companies complete
contributing so we see people from Intel
Ericsson so many many companies are
actually contributors and it's a very
active project right so here it's I I
won't go into the details but basically
I took a free project in the same domain
so VSD PDK and VPP and try to to show
the number of commits so it's it's it's
a very active project you have many
components but on that I will go quickly
so that's the thing I like well that I
will go quickly
why is VPP fast and what is what is that
really okay so what DPP does is it it
hit packets and forward them so that
does layer 2 layer 3 and now we also
have layer 4 what is extremely important
to understand is the secret sauce of EPP
and don't tell it because it's a secret
sauce it's it works with vectors of
packets in order to make the best use of
instead instruction cache as well as
data cache right so what we do is when
we have to process a packet we go
through save all nodes so for instance
we can read packet from GP DK and then
we'll get a bunch of packet from the PDK
there will be processed at a tannic
level and then we perhaps will do ipv6
all right before we do a lookup and then
we'll forward it right so we have
several steps right if you look at the
usual cut data path as usual code for
data path it's actually 13 all right so
you have a lot of instructions to do
because forwarding packet is not that
simple you may have to do a calls you
may have to do it not not or not you may
have to do many many things right so
it's a lot of lines of code and what
what we are trying to do is to make sure
that
we execute an instruction to process a
packet this instruction is actually in
the cache of the CPU so how can we do
that either we increase the instruction
cache size and I guess our friends from
from Intel's are all doing that but what
we can do as well is try to be smarter
in writing our software and instead of
executing the full data processing the
full code for every packet and coming
back again what we can do is have small
portions of code that are and that are
applied to a bunch of packets so this
bunch of packet is actually called a
vector and what we will do is we will
execute a limited number of lines of
code on this bunch of packet so with
that we make sure that the code is
always or 99% of the case the code is in
the cache and then all the packets will
take benefit of that because the penalty
to fetch the cache the code from central
memory is actually huge
when you are processing millions of
packet per second so that's very what
VPP is about so that secret sauce number
one secret sauce number two is okay
let's assume we are good with our cache
for the instruction we need we now need
to also to make sure that when we have
we are fetching data to process the core
the packets as a data here as well so in
order to do that we we will process
packets with quad loops order loops and
I will show you out so this is a very
slow animated slide so I ate that so you
have your vector of packet which arrived
from your NIC card right or any other
thing could be is who DPD care if you
have a VM that can come from a via user
interface that can come from regular
Linux kernel and this vector of packet
will arrive here and basically will
process this vector of packet and
because we always have the we always
process a vector so let's assume we are
in this node called ipv6 they write when
packets are
Paquette zero is is being processed
probably zakat won't be in the cash
because before that CPU was the
executive a pv six lookup and before
that he was executing ipv6 input so
probably when when packet 0 will be
processed there is a very little
probability to to have this pass this
the code of ipv6 rewrite in the
instruction cache but but now the beauty
of this model is that for packet 1 2 & 3
they will all have the benefit of the
town of the cache warm up which was done
for for packet 0 so that is really one
thing which is fundamental in VPP so if
the assessing this graph is slow what
that means is when we will then come
back to the AF packet input or to the
DPD key input will probably have a lot
of packet waiting to be processed so
what we do in VPP is we tend to measure
what is the vector size so if we have
small vectors that means that VPP is
doing nothing because it because it's
processing very small vectors and when
VPP is very very active or when there is
a lot of packet to be processed then
we'll have will have wrong vectors so so
the size of vectors is typically between
1 to 256 and if you have 256 vector size
that means that your CPU is under high
pressure
if it's if you have small packets it
means that your CPU is no is doing
nothing so that is that is what we do
for for to process packets of course you
may have vectors that do not go through
the same score the same path in this
graph like here you have a packet which
is a NOC packet of course this packet
will won't go here so we are not saying
that all packet have to go in the same
path in this in this graph okay one of
the beauty of this model as well is this
nodes are actually data so file right so
it's really easy to extend if one wants
to add nodes to do some special
processing Idol
that maybe for for a curls that can be
for whatever you want it's really easy
to extend you just have to write a note
here you do not modify the rest of the
code so you can localize of your
specific plug-in that can be open source
or even close to us you do whatever you
want to is that you are you have you
have your plugins and you can extend
this graph at one time without having to
recompile VPP so that is something
extremely powerful and you can think
about our acceleration like we see
people I think Nick cards which are able
or accelerators which are able to do
crypto for instance in that ko or that
can do the first you know levels of
processing in this graph so that so of
course vias chooser and they have packet
input these are software nodes but
nothing for by forbids you having cards
which will do some level of processing
and inject packet later in this poly in
this processing graph in VPP okay that
they will skip numbers when I when I say
fast what what do I mean so just few
grafton and I'm sorry this is a bit
older version and we can't read anything
resolution is not good enough can you
read something no it's it's it's
actually very odd so trust me
that doesn't work and I will show a live
demo because slides are good but demo
are better so after that I prepare kind
of a demo of risky demo but we'll see
what is important here is I did a test
with ipv4 and test with ipv6 by the way
we have with VPP we have also testing
infrastructure which is all public you
can it's called sis it it's in the cloud
you can connect to it it's under the
Linux Foundation and you can rerun the
test hit the measurement all that is
public so with what is interesting here
is so we have ipv4 and we have ipv6 and
what we did is we increased number of
calls right to do routing what routing
means it it means three operations
basically one is receiving packet two is
taking your routing decision and three
is forwarding the packet right so with
two calls we do like twelve forty forty
twenty twenty four million packet per
second whatever is packet size right so
that is really good and and and one of
the beauty of this model is that when
you are adding calls yeah you have a
linear increase of the performance with
a number of course that's extremely
powerful because we did this test from
two to twenty to thirty six calls and we
see this line your increase thanks to
this cache effect that we are taking so
so that is really good this is with one
minion ipv4 on trees and we have exactly
same effect with ipv6 where we have we
are increasing number of calls and we
have the same linear increase right here
it's 24 million packet passing on and
two cores which means twelve million
packets per second pair cause you seem a
bit sleep I mean wake up 12 millions
packet per second right
Thank You say wow that's what twelve
million except recipient of coal while
receiving
routing and and then forwarding if you
do the math that's not a lot of cycles
per packet right so that's what we do in
this test and then we did the same for
it sounds like some people are still
doing switching in this world so you
have layer two processing here and with
with the layer to process things this is
a twenty minions packet per second taco
with the same linear increase right so
that is pretty cool and now it's enough
talking and forgive me if that doesn't
work because I just did this demo before
here it is so what I did here is I have
I have two containers with an ipv4
address each ipv4 sorry about that and
and what I did is I put VPP to connect
those two guys and I will run an IPF
client and an IPF server between these
guys right so and then please help me
praying the user the gods of demo we'll
see whether that will work so well where
I'm lost
okay so I puff two regular Linux
containers running iperf it's it this
this is not a bare-metal service exactly
actually this is a vm right so i have
two containers in a vm okay running in a
vm well if i remember correctly and and
these two containers can do with with a
regular TCP connection with VPP in
between like 1337 gigabit well 36 37
gigabit per second so that's cool but I
told you before what is actually
important is what is the vector size for
that right so what is let's have a look
let's have a look at the vector size
sure so we have a magic command for that
so vector size so these are the nodes in
the graph so you remember the graph in
the graph we have the we have all these
just nodes and vector size is thank you
is 6.90 third right for this tab zero
output and and and for the TX as well
what that means is what that means is
the way you have to understand that is
if we come back to this presentation
which was he when effect when the vector
of packet arrives we typically process
six packets here right that the average
we do in order to process 30 gigabit per
second in regular Linux kernel which is
fan is at the bottleneck so then when
when we are only processing six packet
that means VPP is not the bottleneck
here what that mean is let's have a look
with the bottleneck then so let me run
again this iPod
and so I don't know if you are familiar
with H top but the Hardys kernel
processing the grain is VPP VPP is in
polling mode so it takes 100 cell
percent CPU when it has to work right so
in red this is a TCP stack so the TCP
stack is actually the bottleneck here
and if I stop my traffic of
now everything is at zero VPP he does
have this ko so called adaptive mode
when there is traffic pressure it starts
pouring the packets right so it's an
active loop but when it when it when
there is no longer a lot of traffic
clashes and it stopped doing that to
avoid burning one core so that is what
is VPP but this presentation was
supposed to be about networking VPP and
I only have 10 minutes so I will what I
will do now is I will switch to the
other presentation explaining you how's
that that can be integrated into
OpenStack because all that is useless if
that is not integrated somewhere ok ok
so networking VPP is animal to driver
OpenStack it was primarily designed to
support energy right at the beginning
what are the OpenStack features we
support with VPP VLAN vehicle on the VM
connectivity is only with via chooser
interface otherwise that that's too slow
we support many security features
including say regular OpenStack stuff
such as security groups but very
advanced stuff such as JSON web token we
certificates I will show you what that
means and we do layer 2 and layer 3 with
a chair and all those stuffs so
networking VPP as this architecture it's
at CD centric
what that means is when you when when
Neutron have to create a port instead of
communicating directly ways with the
compute nodes what it does is it will
put that in at CD and then the the
compute node will be whether we will
wake up and will take into account that
stuff that is very cool because a
problem with OpenStack in such a
distributed system is you don't know
when a failure will arrive but a failure
will will arrive at some point and what
we are doing here is
we are making sure that when let's
assume neutron wants to create a port on
this VM okay on this on this compute
node if this compute node is dead for
some reason so he booting or whatever
you want when it will restart it will
actually fetch the states from @cd
instead of hitting that them from from
Neutron so it's kind of intent based
networking if you will because Neutron
is writing its intent the desired States
in in at CD and then the compute node
actually reading these those desired
States and if the agent so let me show
you what that means
so typically creating a port will go
through these several steps so first
there is neutron asking to cater port
then this is stored in a TV later that
will be understood by the agent and then
the agent would send the feedback and
we'll notify Neutron so that the VM can
be created if for some reasons the agent
cash what it will do when it when it
will restart it it will do what we call
state reconciliation what that means is
every object within VPP comes with a
unique ID and when we restart this agent
will actually fetch the state from from
a CD state in federal states from from
DBP and will reconciliate the d we will
do a diff between those guys and and
remove states which are useless now and
include new states which are required so
that is something interesting also
interesting thing is it's very much a 3d
centric which means that if for some
reasons at CD files there is another one
which can end over there are many many
cool features with with networking VPP
one of them is now we have this
redundancy between layers where halters
based on kip arrived d so that so if one
dies then the other one can end over so
that's also extremely useful in
production
security security we have a hole based
access control so when only few compute
nor the compute nodes comes with rights
and there you cannot write and hit
anything in that CD so basically if
there is a malicious compute node for
some reasons then you are sure that the
database cannot be overwritten by
someone we would doesn't have the rights
so that is another cool feature we have
these JSON web tokens that can make sure
that the states which are written in the
database have been written by the right
compute node so we have all that right
so I will just go to the roadmap slide
we are now have a lot of features the
next thing we need to work on is this
Vilano where VM that we don't have and
have a better appending for her for v6
so these are very the remaining features
we have now and you are more than
welcome to contribute or to test it if
you want I realize I may no longer have
time so do you do we have time for
questions so ok
five minutes to until the start of the
next presentation before questions I
just like to for those who aren't on the
mailing list we're having a gathering
there's some space in the man campus
cafe later this evening from 7:30 so are
you all well and some of you are welcome
to join us come along if there's room
there's room and if there isn't then
then it's it's also the center of Center
the central part of town so and so it's
a big enough place we should be able to
fit a good number of us in VPP used to
connect containers or for OpenStack I
know it was a lot of things being showed
in this presentation is there is another
VPP presentation later which will go
into more detail I think in the in the
higher level technical details of VPP
anybody have any questions okay you
shout it out I'm Jay John can you
there is it so the question just just
for the record was does the agent of VPP
repaid replace the agent of neutron on
the compute nodes I will not say so
there is an I mean there is not an agent
for Neutron in general people are you
people may you use will the agent which
which is on the compute node will depend
on the virtual switch you will use right
so if you are obvious you will get a
neutral agent if you are using you know
regularly Linux but you will not use
another agent so we have written an
agent which is running on the compute
nodes and that will drive VPP so yes the
agent on the compute node replaces this
agent because this agent knows how to
talk to VPP and knows how to talk to at
CD I actually have a question as well is
this different from the honeycomb agent
it is absolutely honeycomb bees is a net
confidant agent and here it's a net CD
thing right so it this one is written in
Python you say VPP we must be on top of
DP DJ I know there is also an option to
run on top of a DP please can you
explain the benefit sure so in the past
in the past VPP was a tightly coupled
with the PDK and during the last version
what we did is trying to have DP DK
being a plug-in an important plug-in but
but just a plug-in beside others so
there are many reasons why not having
not using the PDK so forth and since the
demo I was showing before I was
connecting regular containers which
doesn't work with the PDK so so uh no DP
right now I don't know to be honest with
you because I have not done a lot of
tests a lot of tests with it but I know
people who are using with it working
with it or I guess there may be some
better performance with some mini cards
but I'm not too sure about that so I
don't want to answer so last question
anybody else have a question
I'll go beyond the usual suspects yeah
so the question was can use the BBB
agent along with the I think Candela
OpenStack OpenStack enables this option
to have hierarchical driver so I I don't
see good reasons why that wouldn't work
but I don't really see the benefit of
doing such a thing right so in theory
yes but why would you do that I mean if
you use one for water it's probably for
good reasons so I don't see why you
would you would have those two guys cuz
it was that alongside just to again for
the recording the VPP agent alongside
the OTS ml to it okay or another custom
agent to me a bit like a Funkenstein
solution but but but why not why not
okay that's an that's a world of time so
thank you very much Sean thank you so my
next speakers are we'll be meeting them
for the first time on the stage so much