oh we're gonna get the next talk by
Roman on networking Swiss Army for go
run the philosopher him okay hi my name
is Roma Moore
I'm working for a residence of tension
here and great to see so many people
around it's always the small rooms are
pretty full and I want to tell you today
a little bit about go and how to solve
networking problems with it and also in
general why go is such a nice language
to bridge the gap between providing rest
services and still go having the
possibility to work pretty low level to
note at the same time and basically I
want to go with you through three main
points in my talk first I want to talk a
little bit why I go is so nice for
infrastructure service writing second
thing is I wanna introduce you a
networking example or a task I had to do
to solve and finally I want to show you
how we can solve that with purely with
go first let's start with why go it's a
nice for writing web services and one
thing is pretty obvious
compared to languages like C here you
can just for instance annotate your
structs and just Marshall today der and
if you run it you're already done with
creating a chasing that's not something
which is so trivial with some other
low-level languages see also providing
rest services is pretty simple here you
see an example where we are creating a
rest service with a slash user path it
can take xml or tracing and there isn't
even a sub path for it where you can
specify the user ID to fetch it and it
takes some parameters and then you just
register to find user callback for
looking up to user based on the ID and
what you see here is the go restful
framework which is for instance used
inside kubernetes
so far is good but there of course other
languages like Java Python Ruby
they all have nice web service
frameworks and there is definitely
nothing wrong with using them instead of
go
might even be better because of
especially with travel because of the
library supporters on but what go also
provides you is working on the low-level
details on your notes here for instance
that's something you would see if you
for instance try to use pcap extensions
for Python and when you don't have to
pick up that Oliver is installed you
will get a message like this if you want
to pull in your dependencies but Jesus
he will try to compile an extension for
Python and it will just fail because you
don't have to bet the devil ever is
installed and how do you solve that
normally you pull in GCC pick up
developer ease and then you can finally
add your application that's a whole
process name you don't have to kind of
package the results to bring it to a
node and that's not really necessary
with code because there you can
extremely easy access all the low-level
details of notes and to show you how
easy it is to work with go I came up
with networking example I had to work on
some time ago it's basically based
around VM - no host networking so we
have wanted to attach virtual machines
to host networks which were already
existing without they need to modify
their host network too much and
integrate the virtual machines in the
host network for instance you had an
external HTTP server it should get the
THC piece the piece from there and so on
we didn't want to make assumptions like
that the network already consists of a
bridge or an ordinary interface and
McVie taps would have been nice to use
there since they gives you some nice
reduction to the delays of the network
traffic compared to bridges and finally
since I'm working in the communities
area with virtualization add-ons there
we wanted to have the possibility to
ship our our code as a single binary
without dependencies so that we can use
the pretty common pattern of init
containers from certain communities so
you'll you just put your Piner in a
container and then you have to place it
somewhere in the host so that management
application there
or a diamond there can find your binary
to use the plug-in and therefore you
don't want dynamic dependencies for your
code if we now look a little bit more
detail on the tasks what you normally
see when you do virtual machine
management is you have a bridge on the
node you attach you have your interface
attached to the bridge and then you have
to be two machines here in this case two
this way I mean this VM they both have
their own tap devices they're all
attached to the bridge and if now let's
say the VM on tap one wants to ping the
vein with the dot three suffix it can
just bridge it and if it wants to ping
the node which has to tether to address
and with two that's also no problem
now with make V taps it's a little bit
different there are advantages that you
can directly attach McVie taps to the
Ethernet bridge so to the ethernet
device you don't have to prepare the
node in any way for that and in
principle that works reddit can talk to
every other node but it can talk to the
node it's currently running on that's
limitation of my three tips so the
virtual machine on negative one
interface can without any issues reach
the other metro machine and it can also
reach every other node in the cluster
but it can't reach the node it's
currently running on so this ping would
fail with theta2 prefix who wants the
motion for that is adding extra routes
so you can say that traffic coming from
that bread from the dot for suffix IP
should be routed or wemmick villain on
the node which is also part of the same
network and since this is on the node
finally we can ping the node and that is
actually pretty complex to solve if you
want to make the generic because you
need a route for every virtual machine
you create and if you don't want to make
any assumptions about the host and if
you don't want to make any assumptions
about how the virtual machines gets
therapy I mean except that it's done by
DHCP it's pretty complex to find a
solution to get all the pieces together
what you can do is if
the Makri tap one device senses HTTP
request you can steal it with traffic
control from the ethernet zero device
move it to a bridge where you then can
which is in promise creative mode there
you can analyze the traffic and see
what's going on and once you're done
with analyzing you have to re-inject
biomech VLAN to the packet so that it
finally gets to the to the cluster or
editorial order the answer get spectrum
to make B type one VM and that's what
I'm trying to show you now with go and
what we'll start with vishwananda
metalic that's a net linked
implementation for go it's based on the
talker networking library originally but
was since then greatly enhanced and in
general already nice I'm presenting here
I'm using them every day but I never
contributed there so all the thanks go
to all the cool developers out there
which we are adding into libraries and
we will start with something pretty
simple here I'm just importing the
nightly primary and let's just list all
links on the node and it's very simple
and I'm just printing out to dump
objects again in this year here I have a
local network that's my my even that my
Wi-Fi summer to purchase and here I
first effects device which will usually
it done so pretty simple to get it
already that's also pretty simple with
the collaborative core but also notice
with Netflix I think we can also have a
look on the address is attached in this
case with linked by name I'm just
fetching there low interface and and
fetching the address is assigned to the
to the interface and then just be let's
print the interfaces in this case you
will see ok the long interface has the
typical local host interface local host
address all the creating interfaces is
pretty nice let's suppose we want to
create a Mac villain device you just
create a Mac will instruct also with net
link give it a name you tell it to which
parent interface you want to connect it
in this case my even that device has too
little too and I've just hard coded it
here and you can even say in which
moved to make a million children and
then you just calling out with that and
in this case I'm and finally fetching it
and printing out and here we go and he
received a Mac villian device it was
created and printed out and it was down
at the stage when I fetched it again now
we already have the first part of our
solution a small part but now we've
already seen how we can create McMillion
devices and so this part is not solved
for puzzle next thing is we the next
topic we want to do is with one now want
to create a sniffle bridge or a bridge
we're born is introspective traffic and
we want to use traffic control filters
to move to move the packets from the
ethernet device to the sniff asura
bridge one could also try to use IP
tables but that would not help much
because Mac VLAN and make me tape
interfaces or traffic is so slow in the
kernel stack it never reaches that
reaches IP tables so you really have to
use traffic control also if you do a TC
yeah otherwise it will just not work it
will just ignore any traffic and you
have no influence on it that's why you
need to use traffic control so the first
part is we are just creating a bridge
again you just create a you just create
a bridge struct give the bridge your
name at the bridge set the bridge to up
links it up set it to promise curative
mode otherwise we won't see much when
we're sniffing the traffic there and
then let's just print from IPA the
output so that we see the bridge and if
we go if I'm going down here now you see
it a sniffer Cyril bridge was created
and it's in promise creative mode and so
we are one step farther now we already
have two bridge to Iran in respect to
traffic so let's deal the packets is
next first to steal the packet we have
to create a ingress queue disk that's
something you need in
traffic control so that you can where
you can then finally attach your filters
to their different interests both cue
disks but here I'm just using a solid
one adding it to the interface with the
link index to and then when we've
created the cue disk we create a u-32
filter for traffic control we tell it
that we're interested in the Ethernet
packet frame in the value at offset 20
and the the 0 X 44 value 644 is just 6
is the port 68 and that's the port from
the that's the answer from the DHCP
server were interested in and we then
create a filter where we tell the filter
on which parent interface it should be
located that's again my Ethernet 0
interface and that we are interested in
Ethernet frames and then we're where is
the selector now oh yeah and and that
the filter should contain the selector
we prepared and finally we also want to
tell it that the action should take if
the filter change with the matrices
mirroring the traffic so we just create
a net link numeration and tell it to
which device we want to mirror the
traffic in this case I had a device
called foo and I'm just taking the index
from the interface here and then finally
filter add the filters there and will
output the resulting filter to see if it
really was created and there we go we
now see on on index tool that's the
device index a redirect to device food
was created and we're sealing the
package we're even seeing that and it is
its mere addiction
so we're fara we got one step Farah
we've not stoned the packet next part is
introspecting it and there go packet
from google helps you a lot that's a
really nice library for introspecting
network traffic and you normally start
by creating it by opening a pcap
connection to the interface so that you
can save an electric and
then you tell your packet what kind of
traffic you are try to in suspect on by
vibrating a new packet source so we can
try to run it and then we see exactly
what we didn't want to see an import
from C code so how we can we go around
that and the answer is pretty simple
there is for instance from nd layer raw
packet which implements the packet
reader from gold standard library I
think that's not the correct name I
forgot the actual name of our it's
called but this raw packet allows you to
listen on packets you just give it an
interface and you tell it that you are
now trying to listen even it into
Internet Ethernet frames and that's
important here here you can do something
from pretty easily for instance if you
are really listening on a normal
internet device you obviously see
Ethernet frames but if you're using for
instance millions and you're creating
the photos which we had before then you
probably have to recalculate the offset
because you're not really on Ethernet
frame at the offsets for for instance
finding out the port would be definitely
wrong and after we've created that we've
created the raw connection to the
interface we don't just have to
implement the riteca that data method
where we are where we are waiting for
packets to read first we're creating an
data buffer which has the size of the
maximum transfer unit of the interface
we read the data into that buffer and
then we are filling in some capture info
like when we captured it how much we
captured how big the plate the packet is
at all in this case the reader of us
reach the whole packet so it's the same
value and we tell the caption for which
interface it was and then we return the
data and actually there you don't see
much except that it's now compiling and
no C library was linked in I didn't
really get to the point to creating a
more useful example here
and once we have that we can use the
this new packet source from before and
listen for packets there like this and
then have a for loop over these packets
which are coming in there and then we
can just take the packet and and try to
convert it to different layers when
we're working on it in this case if I
want to see if it's on the UDP Leah I
just try to convert it to the UDP layer
by the layer method and if something
goes back comes back
it's a UDP layer it's a UDP packet
otherwise we can't just continue we're
not interested in it then we convert it
to you the people get to some checksum
calculations on it because we want to
resend it later on that's necessary
otherwise I will get mail from package
and we can also go further and say we're
now only interested in packets with port
68 since the DHCP server is in India and
yeah so there is a lot more to go packet
but that's in general on how you can
introspect to traffic there and we can
use it in our example to extract the IP
address a MAC address of the TCP ACK
which is very very valuable information
we're interested in and so now the next
part is that we also need routes now we
have to happy and now we need to create
a route and to create your out we need
to create a destination IP that's the
PFD VM we need to create the gateway to
get the address for the via part of
their route and in this case since I
wanted to create the demo in this that
the route in this code snippet I'm also
adding a device to the interface where I
want an address to the interface where I
want to create you out otherwise I can't
create your out so I am giving the
interface where I want to add throughout
the address of the Gateway and it can
simply be assigned to the interface but
at address then I'm making sure that the
McQuillan is in upstate and finally
create the route I give it the index of
the mech VLAN interface I give it a
destination appear give it to this
gateway ID and I at the route and if we
now run it we will see that the right
route was added we are now routing from
the VM IP over to make villain with
therapy to the host and if we go back to
our example we're now on safari again we
have that part also edit now we have now
we're almost done but we're now missing
is we need to write back to pack it
after we've read it and therefore we can
again use the raw packet package and
just implement the right packet data and
then we can directly write the package
we've read from go packet with that
handler to a different interface again
and so we have the party and that's
pretty much to talk here's a here is an
overview of useful libraries I've been
talking about now and also about
libraries which I didn't have the time
to talk about mostly the NetBeans
library the go pack and in brought
packet for packet inspection therefore
iptables you have from Korres iptables
there's an interesting difference to the
other packages this one requires that
Peter was to wound the host so here I
didn't completely fulfill the go of my
talk but it's very you it's still a very
useful ticket also if you want to send
and receive DHCP X or whatever you can
use the HTTP library mentioned here yeah
that's pretty much it so questions
what the testing strategy in that case
but I tell the question was what my vote
would be my testing strategy for such
scenarios I'm basically just creating
isolated pictures attaching Maryland's
Magritte apps and all that and just
sending the packets and seeing if it
comes I mean it's unique privileges so
it's a little bit harder to test then if
you're running unprivileged code but
works pretty tough does that answer the
question
yeah sure just writing test scripts
where they're creating the interfaces
and yeah so and for instance the net
link library here has some pretty nice
example of how you can write the test
because they have a lot of tests so it's
very nice place to start looking when
you want to automate it it and I mean
we're using parts of that what I've
presented here for instance in Qbert and
in Qbert we have also end-to-end tests
from from the user we saw your provision
of um kubernetes cluster installing our
add-on and then we're creating all the
objects and then we're checking the
hosts if that really happens so I mean
you have to test it on all layers
starting from type layer single nodes
with unit tests basically up to the
August
okay looks like that's it thank you
you