all right
our next speaker is
sorry he joins us all the way from Saudi
Arabia
and he is going to be talking about head
ups and I'm looking very much forward to
hear the session
last time if you just came in please
move into the middle because people are
coming in all the time
hello folks my name is Wally I work in
Saudi Arabia I am a system engineer
basically managing HPC Linux clusters
I started their interest in
configuration management automation
since 2007 with cfengine led the proof
of concept for
ansible bubble chef cfengine on 2012
2014 led the project to implement public
enterprise on the company and recently I
have been approached by the network
management team to help them on
automation I have three kids three
lovely kids net dev and three humbly
kids I wanted to name them net dev and
ops but the user name space didn't allow
me anyway so when the network management
team of Rashmi I was excited because I
love communities and in communities if
you are and from the variation
background yes there is lots of network
stuff going on simple thing is basically
the kill proxy and the IP tables there
is invoices the service master is Sto
there's lots of things that basically I
thought okay the moment I'm in the
network management team I will learn all
this stuff and I know it exactly going
under the hood it didn't happen
so this was what my motivation is my
incentive to join the network team but
it's my key takeaway if another team
approaches you saying yes the mindset
the opportunities that you will see in a
different team the assumptions that we
have are completely amazing it's
completely different we talk about
DevOps but you're not experienced DevOps
until you join another thing for example
so I presented companies which supposed
to be a checkmark this presentation has
have companies there's a cat ran a check
mark for example the project calico
anybody know the project carry coal by
the way so I don't need to talk about it
if you look at the world of calico this
is design and build decisions it's
amazing when you hear about this Dean
controllers I'm not a network engineer
but when you hear about this being
controllers and about the high
availability and it you need to make it
highly available and it's not it cannot
me for the enterprise you see a project
project Caracol it scales with every
compute node you add every commute node
you add to your community cluster or to
your virtualization it's basically
scales out and if you don't believe me
listen to the words of the CTO of bubble
Nigel Christian he says that this here
2013 will be the year of the network
automation and not just network
automations will be continuous
integration contains delivery for
network which is crazy because network
is really behind if you look at I mean
how many network engineers here by the
way
how many operations engineer systems
engineers oh you're a systems
integration Network at the same time how
many depth
okay I haven't drawn boon definitely so
my disclaimer I'm not a network engineer
I learned a lot about networking but I'm
still getting it wrong and I hope if I
do anything wrong do I say anything
wrong correct me so my little question
basically he put it really beautiful but
it's really nice if you read it it's
really nice I cannot put it any other
way
like him last week there was a tech day
for Red Hat and one of the presentation
by the company called the glue and he
presented span he presented the micro
services in a very nice way it's on
youtube if you want to see it but look
at the architecture we have three
datacenters one is what we just recover
it for this bit play so it's not really
like the datacenter hosting cost is just
hosting the arbitrator and each data
center has three hosts imagine if the
number of hosts are ten hundreds imagine
if each host has hundreds of containers
what kind of network you would see here
and imagine when the host goes down and
the containers need to load balanced
what kind of flows will happen can you
imagine the complexity of the network
setup who's going to manage it is it the
developer is it the administrator is it
the network engineer who is going to
manage it you know what do you guys
because I asked who is the engineer you
raise your hand who's the operation you
raise their hands yeah so imagine the
complexity of the network that we are
going to see because of containers
because microservices because of the new
initiatives that we have yeah so Network
automation and the message that I'm
going to give you needs to
here up the base especially in the
enterprise I'm not talking about the
flower by the way and my context is from
the enterprise physical network switches
physical traditional network switches so
we need to start the journey and the
journey we need to tactical three areas
we need to tackle the basically the
culture the people the technology and
the process the most important thing
this is my third activity related to
configuration management and I know the
main the main failure or the main
basically thing that will pull it down
or pull you back is basically the people
you are working with if you cannot
convince the people you are working with
if you cannot convince your management
your leadership about the new transition
of culture about the new benefits and
stuff like this your project would not
go forward technology it's very easy to
choose a tool if you choose the wrong
tool you have a technical depth so on
process will come along you might choose
the wrong process but then you find out
and you fix it but people you cannot fix
it it takes time to educate people it
takes time to basically transition the
culture so my other take away take care
of your people
so what's the context where I come from
what kind of soy figure basically what
I'm trying to do what I was trying to do
I was trying to give you a blueprint of
how you do a network automation activity
if you are a system engineer but I
didn't manage to do it but if you aren't
going to do it first you need this
worker scope in his scope of work you
need to go to context you need to
understand whom you are talking to when
are you going to start when you are
going to end who are you who are your
stakeholders and who are the key
stakeholders okay and what technologies
you're going to use all of these things
so let's imagine that I because I cannot
tell you much about the company let's
imagine that there is a virtual Acme
company that has the campus which are
nine buildings and has a datacenter
which are four datacenters it has a team
of five four network engineers and the
team of five for cable and access
control the number of switches the date
are under control of this management
team are around less than a 200 but the
number of switches that are delegated
are not under them but they have to
solve as the first lines of support the
issues are more than that much more than
that
so the number of endpoints is around 57
thousand points
they have a DNF Infoblox
so this is one automation point they are
not using it for automation
they have both of them for blocks you
have an IP address management system
they have a network measurement system
using SNMP they have also using they
have been using for a long time the
traditional three-tier system so
basically you have your core switches
you have your distribution or aggregated
layer and then you have the access
layers and sometimes they are mirrored
so basically from a data center the data
center the core will be back to back
they do lots of changes upgrades new new
HPC clusters and new servers whatever
so probably every week there must be a
change they do also lots of
troubleshooting before my server
shooting and always there is a new
application concentrates and in the
datacenter we don't have access to the
Internet it's very linear process there
is lots of controls especially security
wise so that's the context it's very
traditional company with very
traditional team okay and they want to
start automation so what kind of
automation is out there let's say there
are we will satisfy them differently so
basically you have the feline the CLI
this is what cisco teaches us cisco
teaches us as CCR is and stuff like this
if you want to be the CCI a you have to
do things from the command line serially
one device at a time so the vendor
called us the the problem on automation
the problem system have changed their
curriculum by the way the CCNA
curriculum now and they have something
called broken up programmability on the
curriculum Tony but we have a special
first by themselves
so the first one just basically cut and
paste and using not bad okay there's
nothing special
very traditional the second is that we
will started using Python scripting the
using well stick he'll expect some sort
of them using Excel to change the
template to change the configuration and
some of them started using puppet and
simple cfengine chef salt and stack
storm the people that started using that
storm they moved a little bit more they
are using event so basically you know
they look at the logs they look at the
SMB traps they look at telemetry and
they can take action based on telemetry
so this is a step more there is the new
intent based networking one thing I
learned about networking they cannot
agree on a term when we say who knows
what Sdn means no I don't mean I know
what you mean no for example if you ask
to be able to define at the end do not
define it the same some will say well
it's basically an technology based on
overflow somebody else will say but
you'll have different definitions okay
and I intent based intent based the
network's how many here the bottom 10
based networks okay if you so intent
based networks is like what we say in
Bobbitt and chef and we'll say the
desired State
okay so the desired state is the intent
but the network some people take it a
little bit further they introduce
machine learning they introduced
statistical modeling so they want
basically to to say okay this is my
business logic this is my business rules
and now go ahead and do it okay so you
give guidance but the actual
configuration will come from other
methods and some basically will just use
the answer and say that's desired or
intent based networking so these are the
types we'll come back to them okay so
where are we
or there's something wrong with this one
there should be so what we are we we are
in the first step we are using the
command line because we have CCIE is DC
is whatever by the way we are
heterogeneous we have lots of different
grant types we do think serially so if
there is an upgrade for 50 switches when
the one switch at the time but what we
do we open 50 terminals and we can do
this quicker yeah
there's a trick in amok where you can
actually push one come on faster so this
basically human brought one research say
from 20 to 70 percent of blackout errors
and data sent these from these methods I
just made it up by the way so one white
box vendor is making fun that the only
thing changed in like in last 20 years
is moving from telnet or SSH so why we
are not automating what reasons the
first thing actually is the vendors
themselves they are teaching us not to
automate the way they teach us to be
really good engineers not to automate do
it from the command line the other thing
is the way we work
operations like it's another technical
fad like DevOps like whatever
something else will come up okay some
people will say our environment is
really complex
we are heterogeneous environment we are
traditional there's no way that there is
a solution that will fit us another one
will say it's cost prohibitive and we
are small it's this automation is for
Google or Facebook it's not for us yeah
another one is we actually work visit
come on let's do a double date forget
this now yes so there are lots of
excuses and each excuse you can actually
turn it back okay some the ones that are
good I don't know what to start and
that's why this is presentation
so we have one civil engineer he tried
actually to automate things he was the
senior engineer and he's the eldest
actually among the group a little bit my
age so he created a template engine
using Visual Basic it's good user
interface yes it's a good user interface
it's good as a start point for myself to
get what kind of data they want to
capture okay but what problems he made
this is a lesson on how to fail Network
automation this one first what the first
thing ask if you want to develop
something we have developers he never
used any development tool he never used
like user interface design or anything
he did everything from scratch lines
statements all this design was like took
him one month to do he didn't use get
hidden his length he didn't use any
development tool okay
he never approached any developer he
never approached his team so basically
if you want to fail an automation
project do this
so we filled one activity so instead
let's fill out I mean let's start a new
one so we start the new one the first
thing we do we want to know the
information we want to gather
information that's the first thing I
really would like to know so we click
start brainstorming session in this
brainstorming session it's actually two
ways it's one way to educate them to
basically make them aware what is out
there another way to educate myself to
know what they are doing and what kind
of tools what kind of problems what kind
of time they can allocate and things
like this so it's two-way and you have
to do this as often as you can
interviews shadow Inc this is the way
you can get more information okay
I learned this the hard way so for
example the world networks the world net
DevOps it doesn't come across them they
are really busy yeah so you want it to
know and you want to make them aware
when they have troubleshooting for
performance or anything like this is the
visibility tool that we have right now
is it enough what can they do to improve
it what kind of tomato they would like
what kind of challenges they are facing
all of these are the going to be your
task list okay so maybe they are using
automation already like for example I
said Infoblox ok maybe some people don't
think the HCB is an affirmation too or
it is an intimation tornado dynamic
positioning with it and stuff like this
and they are using it heavily for the
network access control they are doing
profiling the port activation stuff like
this is done automatically this is the
Commission the Commission doesn't have
to be using an automation framework it
doesn't if you are using the vendor
tools already to automate your activity
using Hardware using vendor software
that comes with your solution that's
fine
the second thing you need to get your
management approval yeah so you need to
find what cause or what goal that
basically management will buy in and
we'll give you the resources you need
and it's very easy so it could be the
best thing mean something that a project
that we need now or it could be an
opportunity and we have all of these so
just choose the one that is close to the
heart of your management so you let
leadership task so I need a list of
tasks so we can start there was there is
a good community network to code it's
one of the best open-source there were
community I have seen I ask the stupid
questions on this selection and the
answer me I ask it again they were after
me again
it's really one of the very cooperative
you can ask what is an IB and they will
answer you yeah it's a really good
Channel good slack so they run a survey
are you going to turn another one
actually this year so and this survey we
asked lots of questions one of the
questions is basically what tasks you
want to automate so if you look the main
ones is basically configuration
management sometimes we confuse the word
automation and configuration management
there was a talk this morning about
automation orchestration I haven't
attended it sorry but basically we
sometimes mix up all definitions so if
you look at the first one archive backup
that is not risky that's good enough
generation templating let's good enough
also deploy stay away from this yet you
don't want to do deploys until you
master your system until you know
basically what solution you are going to
give them and how to test it how to
validate it before you do right try to
do the reads first
reporting yeah that's excellent
the other ones forget that for now try
just to find one task one simple task to
do okay it doesn't work every time you
go to network engineer you say okay I
want to automate he said okay let's
start with VLANs now let's start with a
simpler one let's read no no this
configure VLAN
yeah no it doesn't work the other one is
basically spanning tree staring three by
default comes with the wrong tuning
parameters so you have to adjust them
and this is one of the common issues
that we have the third one is usually
firewall policies okay they want to sync
them they want basically to control them
in a certain way granular way which if
they had calico it would be done
granular for them but we don't have this
the end unfortunately so you have to
bury it arise you have to know what kind
of task you have a list of tasks you
have to know what tasks that are highest
priority in terms of received value
received value to home to the team to
the business to yourself to the business
if it's not to the business to the team
to the operations to the user
remember application is king by the way
yeah when we talk about kubernetes we
don't care about the underlying network
we don't care about the Sdn we care
about deploying the application okay so
your priority is does it affect the user
if it affects the user that's the one
that you want to be target okay is it
complex if it is complex stay away from
it for a moment is it once a year
or is it like once in a blue moon forget
it
so take the tasks that are easy that are
simple and have the highest business
value
oops yes I want to emphasize this don't
take the hard task this is when you
automate you don't have to automate
everything there is something you need
to automate there's something that you
stay away from stay away from since okay
so in the beginning when I classify the
management methods or worse when certain
is we said the second one is basically
they took whatever we have in system and
the application and use it in network
like ansible bob hf and whatever and
it's true we have a very rich history
some would say it's fragmented fault
history but i think we have a very
progressive history and it's it served
its purpose when there is a workflow
when there is a new use case somebody
will come up with a new tool that fixes
this so in system and administration
your own system and applications we have
been doing it right we have been doing
it the black Matic way okay I want to
emphasize that but one thing we are
missing that network have we don't have
standards yes
we don't have specs except now I mean
since Bobbitt moved from poverty to Bob
Holt became an official language maybe
Ruby I don't know what will be chef and
robe is it a standard
oh yeah
no I think it's 100 maybe yeah one hour
we have time
so what I'm trying to emphasize here
that we started at 1993 with cfengine
and we are still continuing with new
population management automation tools
in different forms and different ways
okay but even when we look at the
history of networks they are the same
the people that accused them of being
behind 20 years 30 years it's not true
really academically and in certain
workload and certain environments they
have been researching the topic since a
long time for Sdn there is a very nice
paper the road to Sdn it shows basically
the research that caused as the end to
start and this the end picked up in
April 2012 Google announced that they
have been using it in their data centers
and in the open network summit ok I'm
Google now instead as the end is the
default which is not in the enterprise
but so basically they have a rich
history also the network but their
history is mostly academic protocols
standards which we don't have when we
look at the network perspective they
started at the same year 1993 with SNMP
as an immediate they claimed that that
they didn't serve the purpose when they
claimed they didn't said the virus from
management point of view from monitoring
it didn't serve the purpose to a certain
extent but from management you never
seen anybody managing the host or switch
using SNMP the SMS enemy stands for
simple it's not meant to manage complex
things yes
this flow net flow I want to spend some
time on this one
it's not like us there is software there
is a topology there is hardware
automation for the network is not just
software we have really to think
holistic view the ones the red is
actually hardware so basically the cloth
fabric yes this is hardware the open wrt
the wireless there's the white box and
the beacon 8 this is hardware and this
hard work actually made a disruptive
revolution in the network requisition we
know how long is the reference cycle for
network devices we have a clue we have
clue how long is which stays in the data
center five years who says five years on
averages 10 years 15 20
we have we have 15 years which and we
have ten years which no no switches live
okay the the average life cycle is from
seven to ten years but you can just
renew the support contract and you renew
it how long another seven ten years okay
so you have the chasis is basically they
stay a really long time and this is the
problem and this is one of the main
problems that I want to get rid of so
when you go back please tell your
finance or your planning or whatever
change the retention cycle or the
refresh cycle if you don't have
programmable switches this is one of the
challenges that you would have okay
the one in verbal snap route they are
creating switches and containers yes so
now the basically your switch will come
like a container you want a new switch
you will leave your container and you
run it
so now you have your tasks you have your
team you have your management on board
you want to start make sure you have a
testing environment make sure you have a
sandbox the Agena three especially the
latest edition seems to be great
vr matlab is a container based lab you
still need the images from your account
manager if EE next generation is also
good if you are running Cisco you have
to have the viral images unfortunately
this is one thing we need to tell our
vendors basically we need to run testing
which we need continuous integration
contains delivery we need basically to
push our vendors to give us virtual
images okay how can we learn how can we
test again from the survey of the
network to code you see two views now I
wanted to see which tools are popular
and which tools are not for which tool
which how is the awareness regarding
tools so the first to get an estimate
you need basically version control and
you need an automation tool the abstract
the last one is an a commercial intent
based operating system it does the whole
lifecycle from A to Z you design you
plan your provision you maintain your
network setup from single centralized
place it's awesome there are open source
there are open source try since the last
years and actually we're on the last
slide
so we know what's still to go in because
it's popular with children Sybil ansible
is really doing is like the main tool
for networking for network the only tool
that is competing with it is short stack
or solved I always call it saltstack the
company name why ansible because people
think that it's agentless but we can
chef also our hated case when it comes
to network they will create a proxy the
proxy will talk to the network by API
like it's talking to Amazon or anything
like that
yeah but ansible is very easy to learn
answer is very easy to deploy and this
is a problem this is not it this is not
this is not a feature it's a problem and
that's why it's a problem here because
basically it encourages individual
individualism it doesn't think Eric's
teamwork when use ansible
as it alone as a network engineer you
start creating playbook
I've been grows and stuff like this and
you forget about everybody else yes you
don't use version control you don't use
anything so this book about making unis
administration the over once again needs
so if you want to start automating using
ansible make sure to ensure that there
is the collaboration between your team
from day one make sure that you have
version control setup development
workflow make sure that you can manage
the skin so you have the best practices
of in terms of directory structure in
terms of using growth and stuff like
this
and don't use it all straight away okay
let your team learn basically how to
create the playbook first and stuff like
this before you move into rows and
and the best practices that hassle
recommenced
testing testing is a must so I said we
have to choose a small task so we chose
the tool now but we need to cook a small
task so how you do it you look around
you when I start my operation day what
things I do and if I can't improve it
one one thing at a time
I don't want to the network engineer
doesn't want to learn get by the way
this is the the hardest thing do you
think that it is there
so basically trying small things small
wins yeah start with simple use case so
the development workflow our network
engineers actually are Windows users
mostly they can use VI but hardly so I
wanted a workflow that is familiar to
them and that they can learn so we have
code the Linux Windows Mac it's
available everywhere and the user
interface is fantastic and integrates
would get so basically it will be like
one user interface for them yes and you
don't really need to know get that much
and quickly and get lab will allow them
to have history version control a weekly
for the documentation and kidnap ten
specially it's like a full lifecycle and
you don't care about the operating
system even the avatar you can use from
gate lab itself so you can even forget
vs code an automation platform nwx aw x
has surveys has workflows has lots of
things so it will state will scale up
with the tests that we will do so this
is the solution this is the technology
that we are proposing okay so what's the
first thing we do editor's
they use ignore that the moment you give
them an editor with syntax highlighting
and just a little bit checking yes this
is changes things so this is the first
thing this is the first way okay so we
talked about the software remember what
I said automation for network is not
software it's other things also so what
what is my recommendation to my team my
recommendation is to take care of
themselves
the management basically now we are
running cisco juniper whatever why don't
we run white boxes if I run white boxes
I save like 50% of DNA price it will
cost me 50 50 v of the proprietary price
yes and this saving I can spend it on
training I can spend it on the team for
the next five years and actually I'm not
saying that gardener is saying this and
they made the statistics they made the
research so whatever we gain on the next
five years will put it back on the team
on the people and I found this protocol
which says premium people requires
premium compensation may be RBC
yes you got it
I have a problem with the P and B yeah
extra toys for me it's the same think
ahead so basically we solve this or you
solve the the technical solution problem
look what because we noticed that the
refresh cycle is an issue okay how did
the the refresh cycle because if you
don't handle it now you will suffer 710
years in front so better handle it now
so recommend standard hardware white
boxes open source open standards so you
can have whatever protocol you need if
you need Netcom you will have Netcom if
you need open config you will have open
config affinity and you have whatever
protocol that comes up next year three
years from now it's just a matter of
installed not like the traditional
devices where you cannot install yes
insist on modern hardware insist on
programmability insist that at least you
have net call from the device
and if you are running 3-tier after them
why don't they run spine and leave
smiling leaf have proven to be a very
scalable way to increase bandwidth for
workload and most of the workloads are
actually east and west yes and the
latency is much less there are lots of
benefits for Spinelli in terms of
bandwidth in terms of automation and
stuff like this so bring it up maybe the
next project would be exponent leaf it
doesn't have to be the whole data center
our problem we are greenfield data
center we cannot basically burn it and
start a new one but if there are new
projects we can evaluate we can actually
test so so that's the test the hardware
side and that's the software side and my
timer is sleeping so I don't know what
time okay so let's do configuration
management 101 usually its desired state
and current state and if the current
state is not like the desired state the
controller force it in copy natives and
any basically configuration management
tool yes so the network how do I get the
desired state I get the desired state
from the controller if I have an SDN
controller I will define my policy there
if it's affable I define my playbook
there how do I get the telemetry how do
I get the current state there are like
SNMP or there is the limit reporter
calls for this net cons and rest homes
or if maybe syslog or maybe other
protocol yes okay so this is an example
of what
IETF is recommending and dependents also
by the way the vendor is pushing the
source so basically what they are
pushing they say the SI unit doesn't
work this you know you have to worry
about the timing you have to worry about
the interactivity you don't know if your
Python library needs to be updated for a
new switch for new version whatever it's
not guaranteed it will work 100% all the
time testing I mean they say it failed
us management wise but we took the best
practices of SNMP and CLI and we add the
network operator requirements and we
come up with certain standards yes
matcom fresco and the end what are these
service client is the language the
language that describes data structures
describe constraints for this data and
describe what kind of data types and you
can basically describe anything one
example by David Barrasso is basically
describing the Star Wars movie and which
actors on the movie and stuff like that
so basically you can scribe anything you
can scale the topology you can describe
the component of a network switch you
can describe the elements of a network
switch so on and so on and so on
yes it's meant to be the unified
solution to multi-vendor device
discrepancy that's our hope it's not
there yet I think I'm not sure but
that's our hope but it is the way
net comes from the name net
configuration protocol okay
Amelia net conf is the net configuration
protocol it was designed in 2006 so in
12 design nobody thought about restful
at that time so it is a little bit heavy
it uses SSH overboard 83 and it's meant
to create delete replace a configuration
okay the new come there is another one
that is restful it's a lightweight it's
restful uses restful phone over HTTP so
it can work along with Netcom and
basically both will use yank to pune
gate the data yes this was last week
I've been dipping yak if I had
pronounced his name correctly it's so
frustrated that basically the vendors
don't get it here you cannot have a
device given more than one that
basically is really programmable you
still have to put a layer on top of it
an abstraction layer on top of it so
that you can actually manage it it's not
just the traditional devices that are a
problem even the modern one
so we know this yeah the problem with
standard there is a hole was in your
standard that creates another friction
so this is an example of how Netcom with
rest call and yank would work this is
the architecture so let's say you have a
client which in this case is ansible I
took this by the way from charge yeah
charge did there yesterday he did open
daylight presentation so I changed his
sketch and I put answerable instead of
client because that's what I said in
death so basically you have ansible as
the client for the rest comp or Netcom
and he will communicate using either
Netcom for risk or if it's net conflict
will be bought 83 over x8 HTTP and it
can use multi heterogenous this is hot
between is environment and you have in
in the switch this is another thing we
don't have a system you have the
candidate to start and the running
configuration so you can actually make
differences and stuff better than us yes
so net cough can understand that and can
manipulate it and this is how it looks
like do you like it so this is the same
playbook it will work you like it I
don't like our network engineers like it
by the way
this is how it looks like if you don't
use the net cough module so basically
you look there line on red if it's an
eye or if it's an a-lister device you
just pass it there command as it is as
an initial step this is what the network
engineers like they want something that
is human readable and it's not in their
way you don't want to change their
working weighing it so start with what
they like now to declare or not to
declare so basically do you want to use
the net cough or do you want to use
basically specific Network commands
using ansible module specific to the
vendor I think they're specific to the
vendor is actually okay as the best
known as the first step one way one
thing that is great about ansible
when I started using ansible Network
modules I try to stick to the supported
RedHat modules but I had found corner
cases like for example the Zilla is
interactive how do you best interactive
comment to ansible you say /ny or what
there are people doing it this way but
there is another uncertain audience from
the community from the network to court
community they can do this when you
install the new update or upgrade you
need to say yes yes yes so this one will
do it for you without worrying about
there is no bottom which is an
abstraction layer and it's very good
with the yank it can actually retrieve
some facts and it can write some
configurations using
and so basically this is the abstraction
layer for the future Nippon
and always hit refresh so basically what
you do is select the task okay we start
nagging your planners your financial
people about the topologies and the
hardware you fix a task you go refresh
another task or make this task better
and that's what we call continuous
improvement I am finished if you have
any questions please ask
[Applause]
the slides are up by the way they
already opened on the
you