so we'll have like
station after me Jojo cilenti's will
speak from the European Commission then
Nikhil a nurse from an L net on the ng
our next generation internet study and
then Medici shock from the European
Parliament I would just have a few
stories and I think this is one of them
I think we basically know this slide
this is a little bit of a extremely
old-school situation here I never
actually took a selfie but I'm tempted
to start taking one but I'm also tended
to starting the thing which probably is
not a very good idea so this actually is
the old school situation that we all
know that we want to get away from now
we know that Burroughs is right we need
some kind of manager for the planet but
it will not be a manager like it will be
a network it will be a team it will be a
community just like we heard so just a
few stories these are the fuketsu and
they were ronin samurai without a master
and they could not carry a sword and
they were living in route 16 1700 in
Japan and when you see and they're still
around they plays shekhu bocce music and
so what they did was they moved into a
temple they stayed there for about ten
years and didn't do anything then after
ten years they got out and I went to see
the Shogun Edo and I asked him can we go
out and play shakuhachi music in the
streets and collect arms and the
children said okay you can do that but
then you have to spy for me because you
wear these masks is nobody's looking at
you you hear everything and so they said
yes so they wore the mask now when you
see this you see there's a mask but when
they take off the mask
there's another mask it's good old
Nietzsche einem Oscar Mayer give me
another mask another mask basically in
the end it's a group of people coming
together starting something and this I
think at this moment in time with
Internet of Things
they are the big over-the-top players
that uber is the Facebook to go
we all know them sometimes it feels like
it's sort of set the game is done but it
isn't done there's an alternative and
it's always an alternative in all the
situations are historical and to me this
story was always very important because
it shows that at any moment in time if
we have enough building blocks we can
start a new situation and you give him
this also was very important for me this
is these are volcano readings and for
decades actually for over a century the
volcanologists thought that the data was
in a middle layer and they had Theory
after Theory and they through ID after
ID into that little layer but nothing
came out of it because at some point
there was a physicist Bernard where he
looked at this and he realized that the
data is in the other layer the data is
in a small layer over there and he
actually managed to get out data and
information from that and now the
volcano logged the volcanologists are
actually working with his theory but was
very interesting to me that is actually
possible for a whole group of people to
get such tunnel vision for two decades
from maybe even over a century that they
they will not believe that they could
actually they should look at something
else unless of course it takes another
position to start doing that and I think
that's where we are because the
questions that we have is very simple
and actually it really really is very
simple so what this next-generation
internet is ngr wants to wants to get up
once the sub start a debate on first of
all the debate needs to be public we
need to get a lot more people involved
in thinking with these questions because
we can only get one shot and making this
a smart society if we want to make it
smart and sort of smart is what it is so
the question is what kind of smart
society do we want and you're here and
you're very much a part of this
so how can we build a kind of team
Europe a kind of Network community
like a 500 million platform making
people processing machines wiser every
day in a meaningful way
thank you so now we move over to Georgia
with Georgia cilenti's you want this one
you want to mic yes hello
good morning thank you for having me
here I'm coming from the European
Commission is the executive arm of the
European institutions and I it's a
privilege to be in a venue like this my
background however is in engineering so
a long time ago I used to also coding
but I'm ashamed to say how long time ago
now I'm going to give you what the
European I'm going to give you very
briefly the timelines and some of the
elements regarding budgets and efforts
that the Commission is putting behind
this initiative what are we talking
about here we are talking about a new
and ambitious initiative of the European
Commission in the branch were a work of
the European Commission we are funding
research just for having very quick set
of who in the room if you can wave
received funds from European projects if
you can very quickly to see ok not so
many that's a good sign
but we hope we hope that with this type
of initiatives we will try to attract as
many as possible to you so I'm not going
to say and repeats some of the things
that you already know how important is
the Internet today and how important is
it for the society we can we can have if
we have a snapshot now we can see that
still we are at the infancy we can we
can see
new radical functionalities popping in
however we see also problems popping and
we see fragmentation we see
concentration of power and for the
citizens in particular we see some
security and privacy concerns what we
will try to do and we will try to put to
put wisely the money we put for research
for Europe is try to build an internet
that serves the citizens and for that we
ask the question what what can we do and
the obvious answer for us is that we
defend with our policies European values
and we will try to do the same thing
with this initiative so we will push for
the European values with the vehicle of
the internet that we are going to
develop so the trends that we see
nowadays are trends about having
artificial intelligence on the hype
which is supported by a plethora a
plethora of data that is available I
mean if I make a comparison to when I
started my career in the university and
I see because I was looking also at
artificial intelligence the the
algorithms have not much much evolved
but what has evolved and it is dramatic
change is the availability of huge
amounts of data for training for example
and the connectivity combined with cheap
processing power at the edges of the
need internet so as I said principles of
what we want to have we won't have it
and in an Internet which is human
centric at the service of the people and
of the society and for this we need the
help and I will make the point later on
we need the help of many disciplines but
we will not forget that one of the
disciplines that is at the core of the
Internet is the tech the society that is
building the small bits and pieces of
the
so another thing is that already we have
the the people the the the if I can say
they the dinosaurs that were since the
inception and they are still giving
their nice guidelines and talks but the
other thing that we need if you want to
do this change is that we need to
mobilize the youngest talents that are
shaping now the internet and I could not
imagine a better venue for doing so that
to address to this venue here so if I
can give you a roadmap how this has
evolved so far from our side what did we
do so far did we do so far we started
with a consultation we try to to reach
as many as possible and we try to to get
the feeling what what what an initiative
like this should have as ingredients
then the second step is that we launched
a study and Mitchell after me will
present some of the wisdom that we got
from this from this study and we started
already in our cycle of programs that we
have which is the framework programs we
start injecting money asking for costs
so already we have the first bits and
pieces of of what we think will have in
the next generation Internet and how we
can support it from the European point
of view but the big the big challenge is
laying ahead of us and us now I'm
talking the the European Commission is
planning for the multi annual forum or
program so where are we going to put the
money in Europe in general and in
particular where are we going to put the
money to support research and more in
detail how are we going to do this
initiative so one thing that I believe
it's a sensor for you as a community I
will not bother you with the older
the mechanics of the course and all this
is that we adopt a little bit of
different strategy here a typical
problem in our in our in our program is
that from the moment we launch a call
for supporting researchers doing
whatever kind of research to the moment
of the implementation the time was too
long and particularly research you
cannot do that particularly in research
that deals with technological advances
like the internet that is evolving
really fast the second thing is that we
are notorious for our if I can say so
bureaucracy and rules which are coming
also by a control I mean in the
beginning when I was outside the
Commission would say what is all this
bureaucracy now that I enter inside I
can see that there is a need also for a
budgetary control but this has a problem
of delaying things so we adopt a model
of Cascade funding we call it so what we
are going to do is we are going to
launch
I tell it briefly and simple words we
launch a call and this call gives money
to intermediaries that can then cascade
this type of funds during the
implementation of this program to
smaller groups even individuals and then
these can do the necessary research for
this initiative so one in this one
important issue is the Cascade funding
which I think makes and opens the door
for communities that usually are outside
that's why I asked the question who who
participated so far so it opens the door
for communities or for individuals to
come in get support and collaborate
because it's not only the funding that
make is important in the sense it's also
the collaboration across Europe we hope
that's what we support so just to give
you very quickly the numbers for the
last of this framework program which is
ending in 2020 we have put a bet of 50
million euros around
and this is in the form of what are
called intermediaries where we have two
calls and in each call we are going to
call three different areas and where
intermediaries would get something like
seven millions and will then cascade
them to people the the upcoming call is
going to close for the intermediate is
going to call closed now in April and
from April and onwards those
intermediaries are going to inject this
seven millions euro that I say gradually
we also put some money for support
actions that are going to support also
the the reach out to the communities and
also the exploitation of results and
also we put some money for international
collaboration in particular with the US
because we believe that what happens in
the internet cannot be stay in the
European when we initially started we
may have also other collaboration in
other programs we do so but we started a
very close collaboration with the United
States and we put also some money there
so the big bed now is what will happen
in the next frame or program and this
framework program we are talking about
an escalation in in terms of budget but
I think the most important is the
multiplicative effect we expect to have
in terms of engagement of people and
communities now as I said I showed you
the timeline I showed you the money and
now I want to talk about the most
important thing which is the people and
as I said there are communities that we
could reach so far with our programs the
researchers the research institutes but
there are communities like this one or
like the
people who are dealing with civil
society the people who are not purely
technical that I think we are
indispensable and necessary for this
initiative
so the multidisciplinary context of
developing this initiative is of prime
importance and the most I could say the
most interesting thing is that we want
how we work we will strive to have the
people that are talented that could not
find so far through our usual type of
funding a support we wish to have them
aligned towards the same initiative the
initiative as I presented so in the
beginning so I would pass the floor now
to me Hill there is a simple site where
our support action there aggregates all
the information and I thank you for your
attention
this is so I quickly have to to switch
so
now I come from a completely different
world in a sense we we did this study
for the Commission even though I swore
to myself I would never ever work with
the Commission again because I totally
hated the way that funding works and I
found it to be ineffective and I found
it to be a charade
however we ran into the right people so
I work for a charity called an illness
foundation we've been around since 82
Hajis in the internet Hall of Fame he's
really cool and I'm second generation
within a Nelnet so I'm but already
graybeard so we're so we we we ran into
the Commission very early on this
process this first consultation in 2016
and we thought oh my god this is gonna
be a disaster but we need this money so
we we assemble the crack team we and we
set out to work now before we we talk
about an initiative like the next
generation Internet the problem is of
course what is that
I mean people have a pretty crappy idea
of what the internet is
I mean to them it's it's it's like a box
and you just buy a new box and then you
you start defending it and it's a little
I don't know if people recall this image
but the internet it you're connected to
the Internet it works and then you're
done just like an old TV this is more
like the Internet it is it's it's really
fast ly complex and it's not a thing
it's a network of independent networks
so you can't upgrade them all because
they're all different they're not
coherent they're owned and operated by
different people and there's some glue
in there which is shared but this this
is this this is on the top but those are
also operated by independent people so
there's not a single thing to do and
there's people interested in every
aspect of it and
whatever they feel like so another
important thing is to know is that the
Internet's had its brain split and this
is a I don't know if people know who
this is
this is Vint Cerf one of the to the IP
protocol and he came to the Netherlands
and he had a give a presentation there
and he said at a certain point in time
we just invented the the Internet
protocols and then the NSA came to us
and said well that's not gonna do that's
that's so not gonna do we yeah we're
gonna you're gonna need to Vince events
something else for us but oh by the way
don't tell the others so that is a
pretty painful thing that's the 70s that
is going really back to the roots of the
whole thing so if you think about it
it's not something you can create a next
generation off quite easily but you
really want to do and where do you start
where you start when you have like the
community we have 500 million people in
Europe with a big vessel of money we're
putting money aside to do this kind of
thing but then how do you organize that
this this can actually work well
obviously so we try to drill down a
little and say well it's not gonna be
the connections they're not they're not
the problem
the whole physical layer is just it's
okay that's why we initially believed in
the internet because we owned our own
infrastructure but now again it's a more
painful territory we talk about
conventions we talk about standards we
talk about protocols we talk about how
people operate well that's that's a lot
steeper to work on and then there's code
and there's commodity there's the stuff
that people are running and people that
people can download and start using and
there's a lot of legacy Hardware on and
we have to attach that as well and that
includes all of the things that you own
including the thing in your your
basement now changing the core
conventions and the core protocols of
the Internet that is a huge beast of an
effort I mean it's it's it's it's
bordering on the insane things have
for change before people don't realize
this but it has never been done before
all the other things that are just
individual companies with a few big
companies doing the same thing it's not
still the internet the internet has not
done it before the people that have to
do it have not done it before and to
make it even worse they sort of
simultaneously through all three and a
half billion of them will have to do it
more or less in the same pace because
otherwise it's still not going to work
all previous internet mixing and
internet next generation internet
Sheffield there's even a Wikipedia
disambiguation page for it so the
reality is this is this is a moonshot
Plus+ effort this is massacre it's the
largest and it's the most obscene thing
that man has ever created and we and we
want to change it in flight with three
and a half billion people on board and I
mean even the US alone has 11 billion of
attack budget a year just to attack the
security of the Internet so the
political stakes are high economic
stakes are high and of course social
stakes are tremendously high now we also
have a bunch of highly critical users
and when you talk about critical users
there's there's different types of
critical they're not really critical
because they will use anything that's
free but they're well they're heavily
addicted to heavily dependent and they
will whine so it's gonna be it's gonna
be a tough thing and then on top of that
I don't have people people probably know
Parker's law of triviality it's when you
it's from the 50s when you design a
nuclear power plant you assign a
committee you assign a committee to work
on that they will end up fighting over
the color of the bike shed because
that's what everybody understands
everybody gets the internet because
everybody's modern that has a Twitter
account so if you're still with me if
you're still not discouraged this is the
path that we took we set out to engage
with with these folks broken this is the
web
so we we said well you can do a next
generation if you don't I mean how do
you create next generation people you
have the current generation people then
you put them together and they make next
generation people I have a lot of fun
these people have never been involved
with this public funding because of the
obnoxiousness of the whole process you
guys don't want the paperwork but I work
for charity a Nelnet we give away money
to people we do this kind of thing our
budgets cannot reach here this is a
factor thousand higher than an illness
can reach and we know because all these
people come to us over the years we know
we need this money we know there's a
huge demand out there for people that
can actually do great things but we need
these these technical experts now we did
a workshop during this this is call and
and to be even more inclusive this these
are all the tax that we added to the
people in that workshop and so this
includes also the people that wrote the
feminist internet manifesto this also is
about whistleblowers this is about all
dimensions of the infrastructure because
they all need to be they all have their
different needs and perspectives
interesting the problem is if you have a
an internet next generation Internet's
plan and you have it all neatly tied up
in graphs when you don't have the glue
for it if you have separate calls and
people will be yelling okay I can do
something on mmm Tran transmission
protocols or I can do something on
secure web standards but if it's not
glued together it's gonna be a hail shot
of efforts gonna fail oh man this is
getting irritating I will have to
refresh my browser
because
that is so irritating okay I'm gonna
have to wing it here so we have we have
images coming up we did this massive
scan we worked for months and once we
talked went to all these events from all
these organizations oh there's there's
an end to what people can do so we're
just a small team there's a lot of
people working on the internet in Europe
and we made a huge huge effort to talk
to some as many people as we could and
if you look at the Internet as a safe
place where you can just use things do
things and party you should think of
little of the story about the three pigs
there's always a pig with the straw
house and he's having a lot of fun
that's where we built the internet next
to that house and the threat model that
we have now is completely model at the
time was completely inadequate this is
the kind of threat model that we want
you you will have AI attacks from
whatever nation you don't like and they
will find every gaping go hole every
port every source code that that is out
there that is vulnerable so you're gonna
need some pretty fast response time we
don't have response time now we have a
pretty awful response if people have
break something on the internet it takes
years to fix it when DNS was broken
you're still in 2008 people are still
seeing out their DNS servers that don't
have DNS SEC ipv6 has been waiting for
since since the previous century we it
takes ages to put things on the internet
and so we very bad at this we're really
bad at organizing things because all of
your projects they end up I don't know
if people know this wonderful sites
called rip ology org and if you've
checked your projects there well how
well they spread across even across just
Linux distros it takes ages and ages we
don't have good mech
and when you're building a new internet
you can't afford not to be in it
connected to everything so we need good
engineering practices we need continuous
integration we need well just make sense
from a software engineering point if you
make sense when you're doing a
next-generation internet we don't have
that like I mentioned before we need to
stress from the ground up the the
Internet is the fundaments of the
internet are deeply problematic and I
mean after Snowden everybody realizes
this so how do we really just trust
worthiness because we can make people
trust the Internet but that would be a
well it would be disastrous if they
trust the thing that's not to be tried
that it isn't trustworthy so we have to
earn back this trust now in the long
term we know that for instance DDoS
attacks they're simply they cannot be
stopped the Internet is designed in a
pretty bad way it's a pretty naive idea
of how the network should be in the
seventies so we need alternative plans
there needs to be a plan B and this goes
on many different levels this goes from
from making sure that objects don't have
to come from a single server like I just
had but they can just be there that the
frigging image was on my frigging
computer but it just wouldn't show
because my browser was too stupid to
recognize that it was there so why can
we not have smarter as a distribution to
make it less fragile we want anti
fragility now what I mentioned before is
the legacy middleware the internet is
hostile against itself is basically
whenever you infant new stuff other
parts of the Internet are saying well
but I was created in the 80s and I don't
understand
so I'll eject this and you have to work
on the internet so stop stop using
whatever you're doing and so for
instance even protocols like DNS sick
which are a rescue
into an important aspect 10% of the of
the networks have issues with with dina
sec packets so we we know that we need
to think clever more clever not just
about a solution but about the solution
that is able to to take care of this
this legacy situation and that means
that we have to understand far better
and that takes a lot of money a lot of
brainpower because thinking of stuff
that works is more difficult than
thinking of stuff that works in a non
greenfield situation now the user also
needs a lot more protection if you go to
a store now and you buy a laptop and you
go online here you're you're dead meat
how can this be how can this be after we
invent protocols for so long that you
buy new stuff you go on a public
internet and you're you're taken so of
course this takes a lot of stuff and i
mean we've lost control of the browser i
think everybody can see that this is
advertising companies running the show
this is no longer serving the interest
of the user so why don't we make public
money to be used for that purpose
another important thing is i don't know
how many people are here are mining
Bitcoin and together with all the other
people producing I think the 19th
country when it comes to electrical
power already and that's with 300,000
payments or 400,000 payments a day
that's nothing that's there's
supermarkets in my in my city that have
that traffic volume and that is the 19th
pollutant electricity use on the planet
if people are going to go that way and
people are proposing blockchain like
solutions we're gonna have to do a lot
better and so this is something that
again you want people to look into you
want people to have time to spend on
this now if people are supposed to be
going away from from from the the big
monopolies where are they gonna go I
mean if there's no road and if there's
no no destination there's no way that
they even can get away so
you need to safeguard the openness of
the Internet by making sure that that
there's no monopolies and if people need
stuff then it needs to be available just
like the email is available or the web
is available anybody can use it now this
is the process that we that I explained
so we had this we talked to all these
communities we analyzed what they said
we met up with a lot of experts from the
community and then we made even further
breakdown and what we then did is to
recommend to the Commission three
different topics of first we extracted a
vision for this because the vision is
where it starts the vision is there can
be many visions for instance there
wasn't for for the the previous decades
it was a vision Europe should have its
own googles you good europe should have
its own amazon's europe should have all
these big companies look alikes
that is that is not a good idea that is
never gonna cut it so we start with a
vision and this vision basically
revolves around a very few simple
principles it is legible but I actually
extracted there in a bigger size now if
you agree that the the the idea of the
next generation in the next generation
in that isn't profit but that it that it
should be an area that brings out the
best in all of us then this
inclusiveness and and and and diversity
are a real problem because that's not
what the world is heading for we're not
heading towards an inclusive system if
you work at a few big companies you can
invent the future and if not you're
basically you're your fringe activity
the second thing the the so that's the
basic I said we want everybody to be to
be on board but the second thing is we
want the Internet to actually be very
resilient because if you think about it
you're gonna put things inside your
heart and it's actually gonna grow
you're gonna put it in space and you
can't touch it you're gonna put it in
the roads and imagine that the spectre
of meltdown would happen with stuff
inside your heart or inside a road
there's a there are good reasons to
minimum minimize the attack surface and
that happens at the protocol layer the
next thing is of course we need these
components we need everything to be
trustworthy because if if you couldn't
trust your own spine I mean I think
people may have seen this Bruce Willis
film where he is where there's a spy
inside one of his teeth and he has to
get it out of it so if you can't trust
your own internet you have to be able to
trust it it's your internet right it's
we said it's a decentralized
infrastructure so it's yours
so you should be able to trust it you
should know and understand what is in
there and the third thing everybody
should be able to innovate on top of it
you can't innovate on top of Twitter you
can create an app that uses its API but
you cannot build a new business model on
top of a company like that so this is
this our call to action now
where to start the first thing that we
recommend to the Commission to say okay
first we need to clean up our act we
need to secure the perimeter we need to
make sure that that we at least have a
minimum amount of ground that we know we
can trust that's that's really the first
thing if we don't have that I'd just
spend a lot of you only have 5.4 million
to spend on these each of these three
topics this is well spent on people just
taking a clearer look at the Internet
the second thing is okay if people are
if you want people to be free to
innovate they have to be able to get
their social graph out they have to be
able to get their data out
and they need to be able to take it
somewhere just like if I don't like
Gmail I can set up my own email server
if I don't like many other services on
the Internet the popular ones the the
instagrams the the the signals the
Facebook where am I gonna go if I if I
don't agree with that company that runs
it where am I gonna go so we need to
create open source alternatives for
these services and make sure that the
data can be imported and the third one
that we recommend this renovation of
architecture so this is a long-term
thing it's it's we know that the first
proposals to re-engineer the Internet
were from already from the 80s none of
them have succeeded so it takes a long
long time to even get something done so
we need that kind of word that long-term
work to start right now now where does
this community come in okay we we know
and we understand that you guys you you
will have bread to eat I mean that's not
a problem and you don't need the paper
from the Commission however the
interesting thing is the paperwork from
the Commission will go and you actually
we will need that work and you will we
actually need to collaborate and do
stuff in a more structured way it's if
we're gonna fly to the moon if that is
actually the kind of level of ambition
that we have it's not going to cut it
from from a technical point of view to
do everything in separation to scratch
your own itch is all the time the
Internet is actually eating the world
it's eating Society it's it's
determining how people interact with
each other I mean Trump versus when when
President Trump the Trump's account was
taking down on Twitter a couple of
months ago by some engineer that felt
like it and there was no way that no way
that would happen to a state
organization because that you could put
stuff in place because that is the same
account that that guy threatens to two
foreign heads of state with so it's
that's a pretty pretty strange thing to
happen we need society needs an internet
that it trusts and if we want to launch
this thing
we're gonna have to collaborate and we
have to nurture the the right and
ethical technologies and well the
Commission is continuously being
pestered by people from industry and
citizens saying why don't we have all
these big companies in Europe where a
failure we've created packets which and
we've created the web we created Linux
and then we don't have any of these
these these unicorn companies well this
is a cuckoo I don't know if people know
how that works but if you get outside of
the net all the time because it's an
unfair competition and you keep on
nurturing the whole system without
giving it a second thought if there are
too many cuckoos that are very
successful you start they start
consulting business they start houses
they starts bed-and-breakfast places
where you can go and put your eggs in
and then it's it's kind of easy to spot
it out I mean the real internet is open
and the real internet is owned by
everybody and if it's not that internet
then certainly we can recognize this and
we hope that the European Commission
when they get that billion euros to do
stuff they will actually see it because
that is our funding that is your funding
and and my eyes opened two years ago
when I went through this workshop and
with ten experts and there were no
people from the internet world so this
was this is your lunch being eaten by
people that claim to be you this is
actors that try to do the innovation
theater and that has to stop so the
simple thing is and the as Georgio's
explained it's it's gonna take a little
while because we're gonna find people
that do the awful paperwork for you and
then it should be able to get money for
the cool stuff and the good stuff that
you want to do with very little effort
because that's the pledge that they're
they're trying to make
society is has paid up the money it's
your money it's 500 million Europeans
counting on this to happen let's say
that everybody puts aside 2 euros to fix
the internet well it's more or less an
order of magnitude it sounds like a tiny
amount but we can actually do amazing
things with you I know because I know
that people work that work for NL net it
sometime to get paid a thousand euros a
month to work tirelessly on a
mind-numbing beautiful technology I know
there's a lot of needs and we can scale
this up and we need to reinvent this
Internet because if we don't reinvent it
it's gonna it's may be lasting for
another thousand years and this is not a
hyperbole it's it's fossilized really
really fast the ossification of the
Internet is a real problem because if
everybody's on it and everybody has a
legacy on earth and its decades-old
who's gonna change it so with that I
leave the floor to Medici shaaka
she's from the European Parliament and
she's the one that guess is thrown into
her lap
[Applause]
good morning everybody
some ladies many gentlemen how are you
so in my work as a member of European
Parliament's I focus a lot on the
question of how to preserve and make
more robust the rule of law in an online
world some of the areas I work on our
trade foreign policy technology subjects
Digital Rights worked on that neutrality
we just passed a resolution in the
European Parliament that will make it
harder to export surveillance systems to
dictatorships where they might be used
to violate people's human rights thank
you and and I think that's important for
this community we put in a caution to
avoid that security researchers and pen
testers would be negatively impacted and
we call for delisting of export controls
encryption software so hopefully well I
see it's getting you awake so let's hope
it stays that way
anyway last week I was in in Davos at
the World Economic Forum and I can
hardly think of a bigger difference
between this room and and that's
community of people but what was
striking and what I took with me from
Davos is actually very interesting that
there was a very clear tone of concern
about where digitization is heading tech
topia was definitely over and the notion
that we should put people first human
beings first was a core notion that that
came across in many of the sessions and
it's one that resonates with me deeply
and I also thought it was remarkable
that Marc Benioff the CEO of Salesforce
was actually calling out other CEOs for
having failed to take their
responsibility in leading big technology
companies and essentially called for
regulation to safeguard the public
interest now why do I say all this one
because I thought it was interesting but
two because I believe that there is a mo
mentum a momentum building up where
there is more attention for the
potential negative fallout of
privatization of the web everywhere I
think one of the deep challenges that we
face is a digitization often means
privatization and I don't think it
serves the public interest sufficiently
in fact I heard someone from Facebook
saying you know what we do at Facebook
we are a privately managed public space
that certainly raised my eyebrows I
don't agree with this obviously I think
Facebook is a privately managed private
online space and it's especially a
profit profit seeking company which you
know it's fine but let's not confuse
things and let's look at how deep the
public impact of the behavior of private
companies can be and so in thinking
about the next generation internet I
believe we should really focus on
strengthening the public core of the
open Internet keeping the internet open
of course in the first place it's a
challenge enough as it is emphasizing
how universal rights apply to all of the
people all of the time and to see how
democracy can be strengthened online I
don't think we can overestimate the
threats by top-down models whether they
are author Arian governance models or
profit models that increasingly impact
all of us online so when you're building
the next generation Internet I encourage
you to think about governance it is very
very important what values you stick in
in the front and to see what impact it
has in the end so again I would really
invite you and I hope you will consider
strengthening the rule of law online
think about values are not just
efficiency and speed or I think in this
community is not so important but in
many other places not just think about
profit
I would also want to place a bit of a
critical note and invite you to be
inclusive within
your own communities I mean we live in
bubbles too much
I believe it's it's very popular to say
look politicians don't understand
anything about technology and I'm the
first one to admit that that's probably
true I mean the pace of change of
Technology is very very rapid there's
usually only a subset of politicians
deciding on any given topic anyway so
you cannot possibly expect every
politician to know everything about
every topic what is helpful though is to
reach those people that have the most
responsibility for changes in the field
that you care about and if I change
around this assumption I think it is
safe to say that a lot of techies geeks
programmers know little to nothing about
lawmaking and politics and maybe we
should both change maybe we should both
be more interested in the other it's
very easy to say it's maybe even funny
to say that politicians don't understand
anything but there are still decision
makers and I would suggest that tone
really matters saying we think your your
bureaucratic machine we really don't
like you but we like your money I don't
know how many people would like to spend
their Saturday morning talking about
that sort of proposition perhaps it is
better to think in terms of solutions
and understand that maybe governments in
Europe are not perfect European
Commission's not perfect governments of
our member states are not perfect
certainly members of European
Parliament's are not perfect but maybe
actually these people are the best we
have they're elected by all of you they
also represent your opinion at least
hopefully some of them do and so I think
it is good to work with them because who
else who else besides civil society is
protecting the public interest online
so in closing
even though individuals have been hugely
empowered by the use of technology and
there's still a lot of promise that has
not been manifested and I really hope we
can do it together governments and what
they do still matters States and what
they do still matters they can do a lot
of harm but they can also do some good
and I think that the EU is in a unique
position increasingly think about some
of the steps that have been taken on the
European level recently we've seen the
general data protection regulation we
have enshrined net neutrality into law
competition authorities are finding big
tech companies when they are violating
competition law as they do with other
companies and so the notion that the EU
is increasingly a norm setter in the
digital space I believe is something
that is very very essential and that we
should all use the EU is increasingly
more credible especially compared to the
United States unfortunately and compared
to regimes where it's not the voice of
the people that determines who governs I
also think what's quite fundamental
that's really in our DNA in Europe and
we should not forget is that there is
still quite a profound understanding
that people deserve to be protected from
government - and that is something that
we need to underline in everything we do
so when we when we go on in in tackling
new challenges like algorithmic
accountability or ethics in artificial
intelligence the security of the
Internet of Things etc etc I think you
all can help shape that process I hope
you will be invited and participate in
shaping the next-generation Internet not
so much by by staying in your own worlds
but really reaching out to others and
making sure that this is an inclusive as
possible discussion that embraces the
interests of the public internet and
manages it in a way that benefits all of
the people anywhere in the world thank
you so much
okay we have a few minutes for questions
please raise your hand if you have a
question
hey you know can I go ahead with a
question first of all I want to
congratulate you congratulate you for
reaching out and bridging the gaps
between our communities I think that's
very important as you mentioned and I
definitely share some of your concerns
about where our digital society is
heading but you mentioned some some
things on how regulation is evolving and
my concern is that the more regulation
we put the more we lock out the small
this the small guys that are trying to
build out solutions companies and
there's already a lot of regulatory
hurdles in European Union because we
have so many different countries where
people have to basically be careful with
all the legislation in these different
countries how are we going to be be able
to regulate the bid got big guys but at
the same time make sure that the small
that the small people don't have these
hurdles to pass through you know like
GDP are it's while it's good at the same
time it's so difficult for small
companies to for a small company to be
compliant with it thank you I hope
everyone can still hear because it's the
kind of challenging set up with people
changing rooms and asking questions at
the same time but I understood your
question clearly so I think indeed
creating a level playing field where
there can be fair competition and where
there can be access and ability to
comply for everyone is a key task for us
but I wouldn't look at regulation in
black and white terms I mean if you
think about net neutrality for example
it is deliberately designed to protect
smaller startups individual Internet
users from the overreach by the huge
tech giants and it's you know it depends
on what kind of regulation you're
talking about that that you know may
have unintended negative consequences
for SME small medium-sized enterprises
and I
I hear you very clearly we must be very
careful for that but unfortunately the
excuse of a negative impact for SMEs is
also often used to stop you know
better better principal protection from
from taking place so for example when I
was working on preventing the exports of
surveillance systems to dictatorships
the arguments against any regulation I
heard most was well it's going to be
impossible for the SMEs so it's very
good to target exactly what is the
problem for smaller players and I agree
that it's a legitimate concern instead
of making it a sort of blanket argument
that can also be abused that would be my
my reply but I principally agree with
what you're saying it's something to be
very careful about can I continue on
because I was I'm a bit puzzled between
the the second and the so presentation I
heard something talking about Internet
of the people and then I hear someone
saying that he wants to change the
fundamental protocols of the Internet
which I have really no clue what it
practically means but what I know is
that there is already a lot of people
and a lot of communities that are
engaged in a lot of amazing projects and
that it's not a directive approach of
changing the fundamentals of things that
you will invade the people into
transforming practices transforming
structures and transforming users so the
people needs to be starting from the
communities that are already at work and
they need to be as diverse as not only
technical so this is exactly what we're
planning to go with the grain of the
vélib they go with the grain of a
bottom-up innovation rather than to do
top-down hyper scaling projects that
fail to fund the communities that
actually do it