[Music]
the contractor service put you to - the
red team so we're in the center and
should be working to provide for years
people have been talking about the devil
teaching
automate their work that's cool
protection ops death or teaching others
to production comfortable sticking
around asking questions treat infectious
and IQ codes back observability is that
bridge the sustain that helps developers
go from understanding other codes on
their machines to understand how
bidentated
production observability is all about
answer sessions record system decide
holistically and that abilities a
sizeable numbers of people running
testing the code either this with the
operators deploying so that all the
people here are monitoring observability
they think monitoring it off and that's
certainly the part of that it's true or
else I call you kind of cycle harder to
gain the screw and some of the tools and
resources of things I focus on officer
consent so what if it was cool what if
these these techniques bill the language
that developers are already using and
thinking about my customer IDs
what looks part of so major you're
telling me that latency that word is
funny and I you know
it what kind of service what time is guy
what will tie my coat is they affected
or related another a recurrent
characteristic right when went off
what does throat over two years up what
does winning builders use why probably
nice way to probably reduce the problems
that I think the more we bridge this gap
is with more obscene by talking about
what productions it's not about some
officer standard stuff but what is
having a correction but more than that
also insurance possibility these days
there's all these great practices right
because I thought architecture reviews
TV more tests could have beauty I a TV
and then you shipping celebrates really
awesome I could have done that week we
for customer service a few Tigers to
tell us what happened like diligence
curiosity up front we're gonna go make
sure these things are covered well we
know what it's a lot easier to isolate
but during development process we've got
all these questions better system
I don't smell like correction whatever
but Cipollini hexerin production and
they're not all problems are knowledge
but how oft they exactly to pop up on
our own instead they're not
hypotheticals they're about to the
customer segments right what what
happens if I make this change the code
by optimize this over here will actually
be often this question is even dressed
what is many right oh this is what's
happening I think this will bit better
thank you sure we sure that this is what
we're seeing
well this is just what
by nature and powered leverage
production data to explore references
that are doing we can't have that not
only inform what we're building
or fixing but how about those
Scopus how to make sure it's working so
here's some you know very traditional
standard production systems oscillations
very much to turn them into things that
I think about think about things that
affect the business things that are
relevant for users yeah should be only
many production you're not going to be
able to simulate these on your laptop
without going looking what is happening
what motivates our tests are only a good
benchmarks contain a run and are
isolated or stay in college acceptance
under that sometimes must retry
exceptional Decatur doesn't always
result for exceptions so what can we do
is extend new great practices that would
have development into production
you can't wait for customers opportunity
to some taking initiative to stay mental
disability introduction exciting stories
y'all this is week
she was software engineer on small team
and that's where main house she's been
tasked to improve how thirteen of what
Reagan's so till now are able essence we
can process cash Walter Joseph strength
we research for trying to no postulate
the breakaway
well those works well enough spent that
attitude to the screw the kind of
uncomfortable correlation between well
more the customers who kind of have to
go here at the live downstairs have an
off day and I never made a little more
connection so this point it's time to
spit up a chair cash create a
perspective but just making the change
even like okay I would be careful about
changing your customers seems like the
best so she wants to know what they're
together to build comment that is great
when all their own work correctly and
not screw over too many customers but
bringing it into decision making process
should stimulate change let's do the
same
so did she
a long time in wavelength or request
shows under debate the track whether it
would be whether it would be rid of the
book I just like her makes me visualize
okay this is what's currently happening
granny world could as many get this
and she sees cool Maybelline on with
them afterwards tripped in a couple
places
desolation that's what that's what we
expect and Sheamus Kiev were able to
actually examine each case individually
to assess hey this customer this use
case
yeah like taking these test cases out of
torment
what's this double my machine right
disabilities well I mean obviously
butterflies do want to stop without the
record customers but that's what we do
that's what she was how she got all the
data through slide these are line above
statements they're lightweight
Helmuth value it is hot seats incurred
motivators for the business and describe
the execution of our alright so this is
being slowed up Scotty like statements
in the pocket that trying to do a little
more now all she witnessed or later what
you know is notice that it's something
that impacts multi customers a lot but
else but it's a very common sense of
common systems just
they change they sure about it all
existing Tesla cronies past and present
as well but it earlier we talked about
penguin connection is a cluster now
that's all the speaker that you over
this stuff with the local Texas right
it's controlled state environment where
it can construct execute tasks but the
key to the same impression using things
like find a test like that that's here
is ability to switch the trace but you
do whatever code like her nothing you go
a couple machines she was able to
compare in couple performance metrics
anything normally turn about but able to
compare the comments when you start that
are increased 10% and 20% rest assured
all while keeping a close eye on
to the server over and said future
clients like a sweater and remembering
and being able to incorporate them into
our excitability gives us the ability to
find these ephemeral segments are code
to enter these ephemeral questions they
aware that dollars can work there
sometimes though even with the best
intentions we managed to Lee's code or
the question that always comes up you
don't reaction from customer report when
did this start happening not necessarily
because they're simple concerned about
you know the black tiger alive and that
was performed to mostly that that's just
the that was wait that back to page what
makes will pull requests when you come
under an attack any other schools okay
thank you system usually came in pushing
code so he got tired of this uh
backwards
timeline down about where they're just
about time for dinner we're doing
something that to me that helped her to
convert this code whether this bill when
she comes new takes on the ground and
once she got that going this highest
single a high signal peace ability of
their whole food system she could
immediately go from this this something
that that goes from hey everybody
highlight around this time not really
sure that we should find out happening
to to go ahead
by making her observability tools talk
about my system and that she dealt with
today
should we go from this question mark
celebrate and be part of the process to
start filling in a collection to start
thinking about the technique reduction
to thinking about investigating
outliners result adult reserved options
and to move second the initiative and
exploring connection book with my poems
and I think that's how we bridge this
oxygen developer gap that's what we
start engineers like he start thinking
my weapons activation instrumentation
monitoring not just things throwing
again ok everyone we're all afraid to go
she swindled it and continually checked
even interfere health impact by
capturing the new one lightweight
transgenerational card for the switch
and shut the code everyone can make
better informed decisions deliver very
experienced users
nobody can have this departure rather
than just right to write your plan
isolation like hey I have a great idea
for my composition which might say it is
great
what are we just cut out like come a
time where we spend much time writing
code for that it was the dolly I have to
see then make sure we're doing the right
thing inspect our time where matters
all right great well cool how do we get
there what is what is what can we have
to walk away with a whole new big stuff
well you should talk a little bit later
we'll cover the ground but we're just
capturing something every HTTP request
for every HTTP server pattern is woven
and I'll make bail which end point which
method which along with the rest of you
this is great for things like
they were playing with carefully make
this changed right API over here they
were actually doing it or is it just all
marriage how this Standish request that
the south with starts trembling in some
the development identified occurs right
these things that actually are
descriptive of what the custom workflow
about what the workload looks like as
well many infrastructures into the
characteristics competitions I you
really got the right to do with that all
that further you know at some point
we're gonna be looking at that something
strange and it won't break it down we
want to find out it's not one
millisecond and its first to really set
you up for some ad hoc the federal
curves that you saw this new series
myself asking you questions
hey let's change
like that are defined then by yourself
ready set up to necessary for magnetic
4/3 after change both of those examples
we saw earlier the reason an example of
a searched an example but it's so simple
you make it simple enough to get easier
after the developers have you think why
normally be powered able to value series
especially things that really keep keep
getting easier there with
a wage read any this things are you're
very conservative thinking up its
whatever actually to have all the way
that's characterized
think about this data a concert down to
disappearing
I can't tell you how many and they folks
we've worked with who have ended up with
a set of logs where it's so much and
some systems might need some help
future news not capacity and again like
India look at what you need but no we're
developers look at what makes sensory
system right say you have a service
where about redeploy oh man I really
need to learn this about my sister like
shake these requests but everything we
request but you go in later and slice
dice of a look at okay request I have
this real these characteristics
I think about these about Southern women
I'm gonna have optimized for crap out of
the right path
I preferred path even in cases where
your expectation libraries super
optimized to the lower hood you still
probably want to be sensitive to report
be careful that hugger one thing I don't
additional for every break again this
requires those building expectations
rich and because books what if I
practice this is what guys like it's
very simple high level three children
and then we started anything Tigers
starting started to 13 that were right
who you think that work useful but we
wanted to continue building on because
more
first recycle of the more reviews or
Washington want more bills work country
so in conclusion yeah those are tools
you use so long after thinking about how
do you incorporate into some production
data into their develop process
big or small I think Lionel every group
the books for involved shipping software
building software should understand
behavior of what the software does some
the developers should be voting
observability because we have the most
to gain observability should be a core
part that's how they decide what to do
or were like cool we're pregnant
we have the carmaker users happier
building better software by making our
suitability tools reflect upon reality
but Albert's women the ladies feature
five customer rating is like things
things that are not just positive to you
the rings we know about our change
by the way on the stories that I told
they are real find enough of one girl