a fox is a management you can find here
on Las Vegas line conveyed for the last
year I've been the Technium for develop
experience of pop up and we worked on a
couple of projects to make the
life-changer for multi-purpose just
encrypt revolution has been working or
is working on a platter model that
contains native code all right
Mac show Gitex parents yeah I envy or
your pain resistance so there are some
things we came up with providers are in
the capital system they are basically we
have plateaued knows how to manage snow
pits of your systems that we went to
change the type defines the shape of the
resource which attributes are there that
can be manipulated what's the name and
what are the possible values for app it
the provider itself allows you to rate
the state of those resources and finally
enforce a desire state down to that
system and that's how puppet interacts
with resources out there
Claire has some valium providers like
fall packages are many others have
frozen resources like the obvious level
has built-in resources for ec2 instances
RDS etc etc then they're like workin
stressful Katie beachy McHenry Native
Title very difficult interfaces between
the puppet manifest language and the
actual real both systems so because I
don't have much time here this is how
resources look like in proper three and
much for advancement of nonprofit work
up here would define a new type as
that gets passed in work code then like
down here which defines a property
called size with a description in it and
this year says it's too early a lot of
us 10:24 and his problem is read-only so
there are problems with this approach
that we found over the years well it's
really cold so if another controller
understanding of how the users type
looks like the filler code and two
analytical negative puppet which is a
quite sizable code base and which makes
it very inconvenient to use those
resources or even interrogate with
resources available and what it look
like from outside of puppet the other
thing is since the properties down here
are over defined this code if you have
specific presentation needs like oh this
action should over and over all of that
expressions or custom code which again
is not available outside of tablet
itself and finally you'll notice that
the description here says this proposed
rule which if you have resources that
can show your state of the system then
it's a creative it's managed the only
thing that keeps us from trying to
prevent that is this sentence there may
be a check in the provider self but
again - yes or no safe tool to use if
you have special requirements like to a
slide so I'll spare you the pain of that
because as a side business API is
gearing up to change that significantly
well if that's much easier so here we
have to show style resource since it's
the things you need to require the
publication's API on top here and then
pass in a data structure into a single
function so again to make it co-workers
ultimately because we are still working
on teachers there currently
that's just a little coat but the coil
information of that mistrust the only
hash a little bit from Jason or
something else or maybe not so and
that's what we're planning for the next
step but it's just a really hash it has
the name it has the duck spring here it
has some features that your
implementation has and then down here it
just has a list of attributes for
example their short approach here just
the definition of present absent
supports pepper for data types there is
no guarantee of what possible values
going to your provider here on the right
side the size attribute 44 this is not
an integer and you can specify the width
only behavior here and all of that works
out of the box as expected and we're
going to any custom called only provider
to make that happen
[Music]
since talk about code is boring I'll
I've travel small demo here all of this
works with
coexist with the nightly release of the
PDK so this is the only piece of stuff
to ensure the next version of the PD
cable and after it's built in at least
is an experimental feature unless I
don't want to get your feedback on how
this works out for you I would like to
see next there and work for you so that
we can make it better over the next few
weeks and months so we'll start out with
a new novel
as of yet then as if it also requires a
couple of more full requisites so that
the unit test integration works if you
pick a new provider and the provider
name it will point you to the
documentation which is here until it is
in general here to install the
additional dependency one of our next
things that we want to do is to
integrate the business API into the core
puppet agent once we are satisfied with
that it actually works as we intend
so now the additional things have been
installed here and I can say PK
neutralizer then and it creates this new
files you need for the provider and
that's started up in an editor here
so this is the demo tarantulas created
and as you are used to yeah exactly what
I showed before to ensure my people that
trust created ensure and and the name
property but you can add additional
properties here you can add parameters
which are information that's not
persistent in the system they're just
information for your provider to work
you can have stock strings in here all
of the details of that are explained in
detail in in the readme of the business
API it's probably more interesting to
you ways then the provider itself if you
ever have touched one of those plugins
you know that there is quite a bit of
data binding
to get the data from the manifest into a
structure that you connect server kills
the instances resident prefetch that
exists method to function I thought the
property hash and if you touch me more
than a few of those will actually have
fun little implementations of the same
patterns over the work and you know it's
all very confusing
[Music]
supply only requires you to two methods
one is to get message here in the
current example come on and processes it
this done a lot but what you need to do
here is just return an array of hashes
that have the shape of your resource
[Music]
just return ashes of that and get
returned are they invisible child to
puppet as resource or returns in the
system in the simplest cases like here
in this example you can inherit from the
same provider which gives you a couple
of lines of code of base functionality
and then you get you get caught on here
either which create update or delete
pop adults from you and person assets
get passed in a context for lovin
purposes the name of the resource that
should be acted on and again a hash of
the attributes that should present in
the system and this very easily just
have that little snippet of code that
you need to either pair with an
extremely high or when they look around
to enforce the state that should be in
there we render out a your test for this
provider that provides a higher level of
coverage for the generated code
well since existing types of providers
are so deeply tied into their puppet
code base it's very hard to write proper
tests for them because you don't have to
guess my papa is reacting in all those
different methods that are necessary for
for only have to test that if the
katniss of this coil into context of
course to say an external command and if
that EXO command will trans a specific
stand a lot you can provide that in your
you can provide it in your test like you
I have the command
creates an echo command that was used in
in the example and then the test is the
issue command should receive rung and
return standard out with some resources
and for example if the return of that
command is empty cat is expected to
return empty and if they're if they come
on returns some output the provider is
expected to return those resources still
quite a bit of time left so if you have
specific questions I'm more than happy
to
[Music]
so the question is whether the pin case
may trust two E's fighting fires or
whether this year is a comparable type
of provider and now there are two things
going on here one is two versus a polite
channel itself and I have
and in the slides up to the Felson
later basically without the PK PK just
makes it easier because it creates those
straight files for you - the revival
services API Virgil's commercial support
that's going to this puppet for seven
own works because they're some
infrastructure things that the API
requires for their I sure to indicate
provider thing because it makes it easy
to get started and if they should those
those things together story without
having to type of code
sorry
yes I can I might don't see a future
with API who's in the next three to five
years right like there's something out
there it's still very useful okay pal
[Music]
there are a couple things that make our
campus API like if you're made for some
of those an access to the catalog
they're delivered to avoid some advanced
types different very same can post
processed entire catalog but that's
still your question where there is no
planter which will deprecates the
existing types of wires you guys
existing work yes cool to the API and
get rid of
fair enough two lines of code this is a
ply is as an example called off for well
for fetched the wireless like I recorded
one of the things I think that personal
adaptive management provider in an
afternoon and said that has no
approximately a third less lines codes
and sparrow test coverage went from
twenty percent which is basically a
little comments and it's the official
the differential statements are only two
hundred percent so really every single
line of the providers is tested in that
friend there's a high confidence in
there that actually if you change
something in there they know that's what
actually then tell you develop a support
for this specific edge case needs fixing
the channel currently facing the
toughest server and the population
chatter environment since they're still
in development so there's a let's you're
really something wise vegetation of
[Music]
speculative space for varying later this
year
[Music]
aim for getting interests at that point
and not have to have any
No obviously if your channel if you
specific even specific features of the
API available agents that are running
the code but once we get into of this I
I would not expect too many more uses
there was another question
[Applause]