and I timed the talk and it was 42
minutes so I think I'm in perfect shape
my name is Brian Duggan and I'm going to
talk about Perl 6 on Jupiter I want to
do a little poll first how many people
have heard of Jupiter Jupiter notebooks
or ipython notebooks or similar things
okay about 50/50 good and how many
people use Perl 6 or know something
about it or okay also okay good okay so
my name is Brian Duggan I'm here from
the u.s. from Philadelphia I work for a
company called prompt works we are a
consulting company we do projects in a
variety of languages Perl Python Ruby
JavaScript elixir go
you're a polyglot organization this is
an outline of my talk so I'm going to
start off with a little introduction
about Jupiter the Jupiter system
notebooks and the console client some of
the architecture for Jupiter what's it
all about and then I'm going to talk
about some of the specifics of the Perl
6 kernel that I've been working on
including Auto completion and then I'll
get into after talking about the console
I'll talk about notebooks I'll talk
about magics which are sort of they're
sort of like macros in a way they kind
of transform the input or the output of
different notebook cells and then I'll
go into some more clever things like
comms which are ways of doing
asynchronous communication between the
notebook and the server and then finally
I'll go through a sort of a fancier
notebook example and show you how to put
some of these different features
together but first if you have a laptop
you can play with Jupiter notebooks
while I'm giving this talk if you are
looking at your laptop anyway and want
something to do you can go to this URL
which is also linked in the schedule
this is the git repository for the
kernel github /b dug-in / p6 - Jupiter -
kernel and you'll see a button there
that
says launch binder that links to a site
called my binder org and when you click
that it'll automatically spawn your very
own docker container that's running Perl
6 and interacting with a web Jupiter
notebook okay so a little bit about
Jupiter so Jupiter started off as the
Iowas called ipython at first and the
goal of the project was sort of to take
people who were familiar with using a
repla read eval print loop interface and
just make it a little bit better so some
of the improvements that were made were
for instance making it they called them
rich interactive shells so instead of
only sending text and getting back text
in your in your repple you could also
get back graphics so you could generate
graphs visualizations of data you could
separate the server from the client so
that you could do more complex
calculations ipython when it became
Jupiter part of the reason it became it
was called Jupiter was because they were
focusing on three main languages Julia R
and Python and in fact just a couple of
hours ago I went down to the data
science track and there was a talk about
Julia and they were using a Jupiter
notebook so it's pretty popular there
are about 500,000 of them on github as a
statistic I read somewhere they support
about 40 languages and now Perl 6 too
and they're very popular in the
scientific community so a popular use
case for a Jupiter notebook is to go
through a sequence of steps in a
computation and to sort of show the
results of each one and after you do
this sort of session of interacting
showing the input and the output you can
hand it to somebody else
who can then repeat the process easily
so it's a way of sort of sharing results
and sharing algorithms between people
some some academic journals have even
had some integration with notebooks
nature did something with them on their
website
at one point so yeah okay so let's talk
a little bit about the architecture okay
so your typical read eval print loop
looks like this you read something and
then like 1+1 you evaluate it you get
two and then you print it so you print
the string two usually this happens all
in one single server you have a single
program single process come on in and
it's sort of a simple interface to most
to any program so the Jupiter
architecture basically takes the
the R and the P and the E and splits
them up so the read and the print go
over here on the client side and the
eval goes over here on the server side
actually even further over here not just
so there's a server in the middle and
then over here on the left is something
that what they call the kernel so the
client can be either a web page which is
using WebSockets and HTTP or it can be a
console client where it's using curses
or terminal stuff there's I think a
cutie client also it has another sort of
interface and then the kernel is sort of
independent it can be written in
whatever language and it communicates
with the server you can also have
multiple clients on the front end and
multiple kernels on the back end and the
server in the middle does the brokering
between the two so every time you open a
new notebook it gets its own dedicated
kernel so you can have several sessions
running at the same time with the server
in the middle making sure that everybody
gets the right messages so here's a
here's another diagram this is from the
documentation the Jupiter documentation
so in the web use case you have this
notebook server in the middle that's
sending stuff to the browser with HTTP
and WebSockets it uses 0 mq to
communicate with the colonel I'm not
gonna talk about that protocol but it's
kind of messy and then this server also
keeps track of the the Brett the session
so it writes to this notebook file and
the notebook file is basically just a
bunch of JSON that says like here's the
input here's the output here's maybe
something about the type of the output a
few other things but it's a simple JSON
file it ends with the IP ynb for a
Python notebook suffix
and if you take one of these JSON files
that ends in that suffix and you put it
on github it'll magically be rendered as
a nice visual sort of you know
representation of the session so just
the same way that github renders
markdown and these other things it also
renders I py and B notebook files so
it's a handy way to sort of share you
know this is what I typed and this is
what I got so what happened when you
typed that kind of a thing no another
note some other assumptions or some
other aspects of the architecture
there's not really security it's not
really about security you know you're
running your own code so even though
there's a client-server thing you know
if you want to crash everything you can
you know if you want to use up all your
resources there's not there's no sense
of your your typical client-server thing
it's like you know you're you assume the
client is dangerous but in this sense
you're controlling the server so the
security has to happen outside of the
system yeah that's it and Bo in addition
to github there are other places that
render the notebook files like NB viewer
jupiter org ok so i'll take a look at
the console client first so once you
install everything if you type Jupiter -
console and say - - kernel equals perl 6
this will launch a console client I like
to alias that - I fix and you get this
nice interactive shell and you'll be
greeted with this prompt it says
brackets one and if you type something
in there then you'll get out brackets
one so if I type in the string hello
world then the result of that expression
becomes out brackets one which is the
string hello world and you can do the
same thing within two and you get out
two and so on there's some special
tricks you can do so for instance the
underscore which came from Believe It or
Not Python uses underscore just like we
do in this situation
underscore refers to the result of the
last of the last output so and in - it's
a little dark here but it says
underscore dot flip and what that means
is take the last output and call the
flip method on that string which
reverses the string and then you can
also refer to the variable so then those
become immutable variables inside Perl 6
so there's a out brackets 1 and if you
just type that says out brackets 1 dot
you see that's calling the uppercase
method on the string hello world which
gives you hello world in all caps it's a
little bit it's a little bit dark there
but I don't know if you can see there's
a there's an in one out out one in two
out two in three but there's no out
three can anybody does anybody see why
there's no out three it's a little dark
but the reason is because in three it
actually says say hello hello world or
it says say say out sub 1 so it's
sending stuff to standard out so
basically in addition to having cells
that are the last expression you can
send things to standard out and those
little things will appear in between the
cells but they won't be put into the in
and the out variables so auto-completion
just sort of works the way you would
expect it to for the basics so if you
declare a Lex a couple of lexical
variables here and then
you start typing dollar-something - and
you hit tab you get a list of for the
different lexical variables in Perl 6
the way to do that programmatically is
to call the dock keys method on lexical
colon colon and that's the sort of the
local symbol table so that's how it
works behind the scenes you can also
autocomplete methods so if you have a
variable or an object or you know pretty
much anything and you type dot then
you're about to make a method call and
so then if you press tab it'll look for
the methods now this gives a little bit
it gets a little interesting in Perl 6
because there's a very rich type
hierarchy so this is a this is a picture
of the type hierarchy maybe I can zoom
in
control there we go so this is the type
hierarchy so inte is in the middle here
and you can sort of see that inte
inherits from Rio and inherits from
numeric and int also inherits from
something called cool which is something
that could be an integer or could be a
string which inherits from any which
inherits from the generic class and so
there are actually a lot of methods on
integers and so if you just press tab
you'll see a huge number of methods most
of which are probably not interested in
so by default if you just do a dot and
you press tab you only get the local
methods from the int class but then if
you start typing something then it
searches the whole type hierarchy to try
to find out what you're looking for and
that distinction is made so if we have
we'll do a little example here we have
12 we do tab we get a lot of stuff and
the way it finds out what the methods
are is it calls dot caret methods on
number 12 so these are all the methods
just for the int class but then when it
wants to find all of them it sends the
all flag like that and then this goes on
and on and on and there's a lot of stuff
in there that's probably not what you're
looking for you probably don't want to
uppercase your integer but it's there in
case you're in case you are doing
something else that's not in the
immediate class there are some other
cute shortcuts for auto-completion
you may or may not have heard that
there's some cool Unicode stuff you can
do with Perl six one of my favorite
things as the set operators so if you
have two sets and you want to find the
intersection or the Union you can use
the Unicode union or intersection
operator if you don't like typing
Unicode there are there are always ASCII
variants of the operators so for
instance usually it's open parentheses
vertical bar close parentheses is kind
of like an or four sets that's how you
do Union so if you start typing open
parenthesis and you press tab you can
see all the Unicode set operator so it's
very handy for typing typing those in
similarly subscripts in unicode behave
like exponents so if you don't want to
do star star you can type star star and
hit tab and then it'll be easier to
enter unicode exponents the atomic
operations so these are useful one of
the cool features about Perl 6 is the
threading capability so it's very easy
to start multiple threads that are then
using the same variables so if you're
not careful you can have race conditions
in order to help you with that Perl 6
provides a number of atomic operations
atomic - something and if you don't want
to type all that out you can use the
Unicode atom symbol which is a shortcut
for some of the atomic operations I'll
show you an example of that later okay
so let's look at the basics of a
notebook
so if you haven't if you're not using so
one of the online versions that provides
you with your own docker container if
you've installed it locally you type
Jupiter notebook and it'll pop open a
web a web page and it'll start a server
and then you can go to file new notebook
Perl 6 to start a notebook you'll have
cells like this as you can see already
this presentation is actually a notebook
so you get the you get your ins and outs
on the left after you type something you
see the result of the execution
underneath it
control-enter will execute a cell so
here we can do two to the 27 minus one
and then you can edit the cell and rerun
it if you want to so we can go back and
we can say - and then use auto
completion to say one
27 minus 1 so it looks a little nicer
and then for instance does anybody
recognize this member or know what the
answer is if I ask whether or not this
is a prime number any guesses yes but he
knows ok so correct it is a prime number
this is a Mersenne prime one of the ones
that he got correct there were a few
that he got incorrect but this one is
prime
I tried there was just in January the
largest known prime number was
calculated it's 2 to the 7 million
something I tried it in the notebook and
it did not calculate ok so these are the
important things control-enter alt-enter
will give you a new one underneath if
you see a little star that means it's
busy and then like for reproducibility
that's an option in the menu to just
clear all the inputs and sort of take it
from the top and rerun everything ok so
output cells and standard route can have
mime types so let's say we we have a
little expression here that's just an
SVG SVG so this is just the Q is just a
pearl six quoting construct this says
here's a here doc and this is sort of a
very tiny SVG if we run this we're gonna
get a red circle so it says oh it's an
SVG I'll render it as an SVG what else
so magics are ways of telling the kernel
what to do like I said they're sort of
like macros but they can do a little
more they're a little more powerful so
just like you can have SVG's if you want
to explicitly say the output here is
HTML you can do that too so if you start
a cell with % percent or if you want it
to be a comment you can have it start
with number % the first line is
interpreted as a magic and there's sort
of a list of them you can see in the
documentation so % % agh
EML says i'm generating HTML so this
string here instead of being escaped
we'll just get rendered in the browser
okay so this is so you get your bold and
your italics you can also generate lay
tech so this is as you can imagine a
feature that is very useful for
scientists sharing results with a lot of
equations the notebooks themselves
support sell the notebooks support latex
sells but you can also produce latex
output so in this example I'm producing
a latex that's a fraction with 1 in the
denominator the numerator a 1 in the
numerator and 2 in the denominator and
I'm wrapping it in a late tech equation
block and that gives me a half this one
any latex people can tell what this is
going to be before I run it quadratic
equation yes ok so you can you can get
as complicated as you need to with your
latex ok so some other cute magics we
have bash and run so if you start this
all with bash that means actually I'm
not writing Perl 6 I'm writing bash so
here's a little bash script that echoes
a bunch of strings into another file so
remember there's no security you control
the file system you can do whatever you
want even though it's a client-server
situation so we're gonna make a file
here that has three lines and then we're
gonna cat the file so we'll run this and
here's the file we just created and then
run we'll take a file that's somewhere
on the disk and run it and what's kind
of interesting about this is that it
doesn't just run it in a subprocess in
its own lexical scope or in another
process it runs it within the context of
the current cell so that means any
variables that are declared inside that
file are now accessible to you inside
the notebook so I'm going to say run
calc p6
which is the file we just created and
then I'll be able to print out dollar
distance which was declared inside an
external file so that's something that's
it's a little hard to do just in Perl 6
alone but you could do it in the jupiter
notebook javascript is also possible so
there is a JavaScript magic if you say %
% javascript it means okay this is not
perl 6 then it's not bash this is just
JavaScript and you can just do whatever
you want on the client so in this
example I'm saying element dot append
and jQuery is available so it's saying
additive to this element and put some
text in it it says hello world okay so
let's run this with JavaScript you can
also use external libraries it gets a
little bit tricky depending on the way
the import is done with JavaScript but
one way to do it is with requirejs so in
this example I'm loading a library
called chart Jas I put in comments the
the CDN location but I'm serving it
locally since I didn't trust the
wireless situation so I'm gonna run this
and this loads chart Jas into the
browser and so what can you do with a
JavaScript graphing library well let's
make a data structure in Perl 6 and send
it to the JavaScript graphing library ok
so here's a little data structure that
I'm making in Perl 6 this is just a
nested hash we've got a type called
Bar ascending an argument type bar
saying we're making a bar graph I've got
some labels going from happy-face to
smirky face so this is just a range of
all the Unicode characters in between
those two and then I've got a few pieces
of data underneath that are going to be
on the graph that I'm generating and if
we
on this we we get this data structure
okay so remember it's just evaluating
the parole in this case and then I can
generate some HTML and take the data
structure that I just created and insert
it into the HTML so I use the HTML magic
and I use JSON fast and then I just
write a little bit of I write a canvas
and then I have this little there's a
little interpolation here where I kind
of like turn it into JSON one place and
then turn it back in the HTML and then
we run it and we get a nice graph so you
know and you can so it's sort of an
interactive graph so already you have
some nice sort of interactive sort of
minimal interactive data visualization
just by generating for all six data
structures and using javascript graphing
libraries and you can do this kind of
thing with with whatever you know three
js4 3d visualizations any any
client-side utilities will work fine
okay so let's talk about something a
little bit trickier and that is
something that they call comms in the
Jupiter world and I'll just use the
definition from their documentation so
the comm API is a symmetric asynchronous
fire-and-forget style messaging API it
allows the programmer to send JSON OBO
blobs between the front end and the back
end okay so the jupiter kernel supports
the com API and I'm going to show a few
examples of how this works and why it
might be useful
okay so the way it works is you you use
a variable called dollar star Jupiter
and you register a comm and what that
means is you say take this name and
associate it with this function and the
function then is going to get two
channels so in Perl 6 a channel is a
built-in data type a channel is a thread
safe Q for stuff that's going in one
direction or another
so I'm registering a comm here called
counter and the arrow there is saying
here's the here's the here are the
parameters for the function it's getting
a channel which is called dollar out and
then within the function I'm creating an
event loop that is essentially saying
every one second
send a new number to the dollar out
channel okay with me so far
so we the react whenever supply dot
interval 1 means supply dot interval 1
is make a new supply where every one
second you send me the next number and
then the whenever says associate this
callback with it and then react says
make a new event loop and then we call
done when I reaches 5 so we run if we
run this code we are creating a calm and
then on the front end we use the jupiter
comm api and say give me a new comm that
is registered as counter on the back end
and then make a new div element and
associate with this comm a callback on
the front end
that says every time you receive a
message put it into the div element okay
it's that straightforward enough sort of
okay that's what we're gonna get one two
three four five very exciting yes okay
and I have another example with comms to
show you the two-way communication and
this example so bear with me for a
second we have an integer and we're
going to start it at zero now every
second we are going to send out the sum
of that integer and the next number that
comes back we're also going to start a
separate event loop that is going to
receive messages whenever we get a
message we're going to add that we're
going to assign that to our integer so
we're gonna send numbers we're gonna
start counting what 0 1 2 but that if
somebody says here's 100 then when you
say ok 100 and 300 and 400 and 5 like
that so we have to event loops they're
both using the same variable dollar num
therefore to avoid race conditions we
declare it as an atomic int and when we
assign to it we use atomic assign so
this code would work fine if we didn't
do that but there would be the
possibility of race conditions okay so
let's run this which registers this comm
and then on the client side we're going
to get one of these comms
and we're going to send it the number 10
then the number 20 then the number 30
then the number 40 so we're going to
keep on increasing the number that's
being added to so what we're expecting
to get back is zero and then we're going
to send
and it's gonna say oh I'm not gonna send
you one I'm gonna send you 10 plus 1 or
11 and then we're gonna send 20 and it's
gonna send okay I'll send you 20 plus 2
which is 22 so so this is an example of
the kind of thing you can do with
two-way communication and you can sort
of start with this as an example for
yourself if you want to build on it and
make something that does something more
important okay so now I'm going to
finish with a slightly fancier notebook
to sort of illustrate the kind of thing
you can do with a visualization and with
messages coming from the server to the
client okay so we're going to use the d3
visualization library to visualize the
Fibonacci sequence we're going to make a
sequence of we're gonna have every
second we're going to send a new number
in the sequence and we're gonna send
some other stuff too okay so we all know
the Fibonacci sequence 1 1 2 3 5 the
ratio of successive terms 1 2 1 2 2 1
does everybody know this that it
approaches the golden mean 1 plus the
square root of 5 over 2 ok
this was credited to Kepler I learned
and so what we want to do is we're gonna
visualize this by constructing a golden
rectangle which is going to have this
ratio so this is how we're gonna do we
start we start with a square in the
middle that's 1 by 1 then we put a
square on top of that one it's also 1 by
1 then we put a square next to it that's
2 by 2 then we go down we make one
that's 3 by 3 then we go over we make
one that's 5 by 5 and so the Fibonacci
numbers are the lengths of the sides of
the rectangles 1 2 3 5 and we're
rotating we're going this way this way
this way this way
so we basically have a sequence of these
directions which are vectors so we're
going the direction 1 comma 1 and then
you know one one let's say negative 1 in
the x-direction one in the y direction
so we have these different directions
and then by multiplying the fibonacci
numbers by the directions we're gonna
get a vector that is the diagonal and
the goal here is that we want to compute
these coordinates for the different
corners of the rectangles okay so the
diagonals then so are the first list
times the second list where x means
multiply a scalar by a vector okay so
for instance 5 times 1 comma 1 is 5
comma 5 ok so these are different
diagonals and then the corners are going
to be the sums of the diagonals so far
okay so start with 0 then we add 1 then
we add the first two to get here then we
add the first 3 to get here right and
then we add the 4 to get to the fourth
is that does that make sense yeah ok
so this is our so this is going to be
our algorithm now so now we are going to
do four lines of Perl 6 one for each of
these lines to generate these four
infinite sequences and then we're going
to send them out to the client one at a
time and see if we can make a
visualization okay so the first one is
easy this is one of the well-known ways
of sort of showing off some of the
functionality of Perl 6 where you can
use the sequence operator dot dot dot to
generate an infinite sequence so you say
1 comma 1 and then star plus star means
so whenever you see a star star is
called whatever star and when star is
used in an expression it turns the
expression into a subroutine and then it
becomes an argument to the subroutine
and if you use it twice
then the second one becomes the second
argument to the subroutine so Star Plus
Star says make me a routine that takes
two arguments and returns the sum of the
two arguments so by saying 1 comma 1
comma star plus star this tells fro 6
how to generate the next element of the
sequence so we say 1 1 star plus star
dot dot infinity and the Infinity
Unicode symbol works so now we're gonna
evaluate at Fibonacci up to 20 to show
the first 20 numbers let's run this one
okay all right so far so good ok so for
the next one the direction so the
directions are pretty easy this is just
this these four directions repeated an
infinite number of times so we just
write the list 1 1 - 1 1 we have to put
the vertical bar at the beginning which
sort of flattens it and then X X is the
list repetition operator so this makes
an infinite list of these four numbers
and so let's print out the first 5 of
those to see how that looks okay so the
diagonals now this is gonna get a little
tricky here so you remember how I said
we're multiplying a number by a vector
so the way to multiply a number by a
vector is to use the multiplication
operator surrounded with a pair of angle
brackets a pair of angle brackets makes
an ordinary operator into a hyper
operator and it says instead of just
multiplying these numbers together
multiply corresponding numbers together
so 1 hyper x or 5 hyper x 1 comma 1 is 5
comma 5 so we want to combine these two
arrays and the way we're combining them
so we combine them using the zip
operator zip says come
corresponding elements of the array but
zip takes an argument which is the
operator so the argument to the zip
operator is the multiplication hyper
operator I think I said that right
and so we're going to say directions
zipped with the multiplication hyper
operator over the Fibonacci numbers and
this will give us one one you know sort
of scaled so ok so far so good and then
for the corners does anybody know what
operator would be useful for the corners
okay so for the corners what we want to
do is we want to find the sum so far
okay the sum of everything so far can be
done using the triangular reduce
operator okay so you all know the reduce
operator right reduce means take an
operator and just put it in between all
the elements of the list right reduce
says like it's like take one it's like
take the first thing off use the reduce
operator and then you get something else
then take the whatever that is use the
reduce operator and do it with the next
thing so triangular reduce says okay
it's just like reduce except all those
little steps you did along the way like
hold on to those say save those and
that's why it's a triangle because you
sort of generate like one and then say
you're generating more and more each
time the way I like to think of a reduce
operator is if you do a sort of a
triangular reduce operator is that if
you do a reduce if you do a triangular
reduce over addition then from a math
perspective you're turning a sequence
into a series so the the two words
sequence and series are sometimes used
to refer to just a sequence of values or
a sequence of partial sums okay so we
are using triangular reduced but it's
not just addition because they're
vectors right so
it's hyper edition so to make the
corners we have reduced which is the
square brackets over
sorry triangular reduce which is the
square brackets over hyper edition and
then we put zero zero on at the end okay
and if we look at the first five corners
that looks like that and by the way
we're also going to need the rotations 0
90 180 you'll see why in the end so
we're just going to make this list here
so we have 5 infinite sequences and now
let's compute the ratios because we want
to approximate the ratios so you can you
can take every pair of things using
rotor if you want to and then go back
one that's also rotor so this is like
take two steps forward and one step
backwards and give me a bunch of pairs
so that kind of looks like this and then
we're just gonna use regular old map to
divide the two things one after the
other turning into a fat rat to make it
arbitrary-precision running a little low
on time but this notebook will be
available and we also want to look at
our accuracy so doing a little algebra
we can see that two are minus ones to
our minus one squared minus five should
be approximately zero so we're going to
use this number however close we are to
zero that's how close that's how good
our accuracy is so far in the Fibonacci
sequence in the ratio okay so we'll take
the ratios and convert them into this
form to get an idea of the accuracy and
then we need to make a bunch of messages
to send to the client okay so here we
have another little operator thing
happen I I didn't think of this but then
I was on a Perl 6 users mailing list and
Larry mentioned this just by chance the
other day and I thought
I have a way to use that and that is a
reduction using zip and comma so we have
a bunch of arrays and essentially we
want to take the first element of all of
them the second all second element of
all of them
the third element of all of them and so
essentially we're zipping them together
with comma one at a time to sort of make
a bunch of tuples but since we have zip
comma in between all of our arrays we
can use reduce to simplify that and so
then we're mapping that to a little hash
notice some of these things stir we're
stringify because it's arbitrary
precision and a nude stands for
numerator denominator so we're gonna get
those things and we also stringify the
accuracy okay and so now we set up our
comm on the back end and on the client
side we bring in d3 and then we have
some JavaScript which I will not go
through which I've defined for adding a
square and zooming out a little bit
finally we create a comm on the front
end and every time we get a new message
we we add the square to our drawing we
zoom out a little bit and we show the
ratio that we got from the server so
let's see what happens here okay so here
we get our ratios we're drawing using
the rotations we're drawing a new
rectangle and the ratio of the width of
the height is getting closer and closer
to the golden ratio every time for every
square that we add and you can see the
accuracy so there's no rounding here
right this is arbitrary precision so you
can sort of see the accuracy on the
bottom you can see the exact ratio as it
approaches the golden mean
so in conclusion Pro six has a lot of
cool features that work well with
Jupiter previous example so I sort of
slowed it down a little but in general
you could use it for something that
takes a while computationally that
sends back data as its able to make the
computations the Unicode supports in the
kernel is helpful other things like
infinite sequences and rational
arithmetic can be cool for doing
analyses there's still a lot of open
questions the one on the bottom
especially is interesting you know what
do we want in the native Perl 6 repple
how rich of a rich of a ripple should it
be or how minimal should it be that's it
thank thank you all thanks to the people
that's helped me with this presentation
and if you want to run this talk there's
a git repository I'll put this link into
the FOSDEM program but you can actually
just spin it up and just go through it
yourself and change it and break it and
do whatever you want so thank you
[Applause]
maybe I think I'm out of time for
question okay okay
question any question or anything yes
how did you say how difficult is it how
closes it to a native Python compiler so
there's there still - running in the
middle doing the server so it's
basically the Perl 6 is doing the 0 mq
communication to the server and so it's
implementing the same protocol