so please welcome Magnum but high enough
he is present
Oscar's Europe and he will give a talk
about posters replication
[Applause]
thank you I guess
you're the crowd who learned that you
have to get to another rooms very early
at false time right
so usually miss the next talks because
you're in here so it's a little bit too
loud I'll speak a little bit softer so
first couple words about myself I said
my name is Magnus Hollander I work for a
company called red pill info which is an
open source services business in the
Scandinavian area I'm based out of
Stockholm in Sweden myself I do a lot of
Postgres work there sort of consulting
training support you know typical open
source business within the post Coast
team I am a member of the core team one
of the committees on the project and as
mentioned I am currently the president
of postcodes Europe any one of you is a
member of postcodes Europe don't forget
that we're about to run elections for
next year so you can vote everybody else
off the board you can't actually vote me
off the body either wait one year and
then you can vote me off the board
anyway we are here to talk about
replication so does anyone remember this
does anyone remember the fact that my
clicker stopped working so remember this
right who is wrong back in these times
and then when you have this right and
these clusters that I have
locating with those quests and it just
works the first place for a long time
didn't have built-in replication right
we had external replication tools some
of them were easy to use some of them
were as I'd like to put it actively user
unfriendly that they worked and that
wasn't really the case back then that
post course didn't have replication it
just wasn't very obvious it obviously
isn't the case now and the case now is
also still at the post goes has
replication just like them there many
choices there are many more choices now
than there used to be back then
everything used to be an external
replication system that you put into
your post course now there are external
and internal options and we still have
to choose for them right I need to pick
which one to use or in fact you can pick
more than one depending on exactly what
your requirements are we still have some
there are or to use who have some that
are very very easy to use now when we do
replication we can do it that sort of
many many different layers usually to
solve different problems sometimes to
you know shift the blame to somebody
else
there are many different reasons to do
it everything starting at the hardware
well what hardware is also software
right but the things that are sold to us
as if they are hardware which is
software that somebody else wrote and
firmware anyway up to actually doing the
replication completely in your
application and just run across sort of
separate databases so I like to put this
through you know we have application
level replication with what I call up in
database level replication which is
basically trigger based right you it's
basically an application that runs as
triggers inside of your database you can
write it yourself or you can use
something else back in the days when
this whole post goes
application was the truth then this is
basically what Postgres had in the form
of four or five external different
projects that would do it and then we
can do database logical replication we
can do database managed physical
replication we can do operating system
replication which is this point is
basically things like dr BD or similar
solutions that run transparently in the
operator clock that tried to run
transparently in the operating system
then of course at the very end we can do
the hardware based replication which
today basically means ahsan right let's
go through the stack from the bottom and
see what options we have in a post quest
world today like the last thing that we
can do there is a sand based replication
this is basically your hardware takes
care of the replication it is typically
a block level replication handled by you
know whatever firmware is running in
your son it is transparent to the
operating system and that's the whole
point of it right in the OS you get a
block device and you have the same type
device somewhere else and it's all just
magic and the space race runs on top of
file systems when you mount your
filesystem and this doctor eyes and you
automatically have their replicated
solutions where you can know usually you
can't mount both at the same time but
you can mount it that for example a
different physical location written and
fell over your database there this is
very common today I think in in the
scenarios that I work with our customers
in like larger enterprise
everybody has this one way or another
especially knowing the world of virtual
machines and I'm sure most of you have
at least at one point use the virtual
machine right you probably know what
this is now and those kind of places use
nothing else right there are all these
massive like VMware cluster things so
it's a pretty common thing it's a pretty
simple thing you can do this sort of
anything from just a single rack
replication to neatly site synchronous
and the good thing about these that
these solutions are sold to be
guaranteed to never fail right because
there are multi sites and they're
following all the best practices and
things and and of course things that
never fail a perfect time yeah most
people I know who have had big problems
with it simply because there is no such
thing as something that never fails it's
only a matter of when it fails and if
everything fails at once or only some
pieces at any given time it in a
spectacular way because it takes
everything down the fact that this
storage can never pay it I've seen
scenarios where you know people lost
some six seven thousand virtual machines
at once and suddenly the fact that
they're five Postgres databases was
maybe not the biggest problem in the
world but so this works to a level but
it's again it's the whole thing if you
if you design everything you'd be able
to get one thing that cannot possibly
fail if it's really painful when it
fails and it really is a when there is
no such thing as things that don't fail
it's infinitely Postgres specific so
we're not gonna spend a lot of time on
that one we're gonna move up the stack
instead a look at the operating system
level and at this level
basically I mean dr BD is probably the
most common one at least if you're in
the linux world there are some other
options around it and they'll basically
do the same thing as this replicated
sack right except they're doing it in
the form of a driver in your operating
system instead of being a driver in
somebody else's operating system which
is really what your sign is right it
still just software it works and fails
in sort of the same way as your typical
thumbs it has usually a little less
performance but it's even if you're only
worried about hardware failure of your
hard drives it's not a bad choice for a
system where you don't need high
performance right but I mean it
replicates your disks over TCP and it
replicates them in a black level so it
doesn't know what data it's replicating
that obviously can get pretty
inefficient when it comes to performance
on the replication side and again it's
not very specific so we're gonna skip
past that one as well and see what do we
have failure of the stack in Postgres so
now we're getting to the actual Postgres
science right database physical
replication this is a transaction log or
now based replication solution in papers
we had this in Postgres 8.3 which is
people who are still saying that we
didn't have replication and 8.3 and
Infernus he did an excellent it was
highly based so basically the
replication deck was books from 16
megabytes worth of transactions which is
kind of not very real time it worked
pretty well and this is the foundation
that the sort of cool replication
options that we have in Postgres today
there were building on the same
foundation in first was 9.0 this was
turned into streaming replication
meaning that instead of replicating
decks of 16 megabytes we would now
replicate basically
ah one bite replicate transaction log as
soon as it's created as of postcodes 9.1
support was added for synchronous
meaning that you can be guaranteed that
when you commit the transaction it is in
at least two places and the system will
blip and wait until the commit has
reached the standby node or standby node
before the transaction is released and
whether this works particularly in
Postgres which I find very useful is you
can mix synchronous and asynchronous and
you've been able to do that since
version 9.1 so you can say that some of
your transactions are very important
they need to be synchronously replicated
you need the guarantees that they exist
in multiple places before your
application proceeds to the next step
well some other things are not that
important and they can run
asynchronously and you can run this in
the same system you just in your
transaction you just said you know set
synchronous mode equals F and you get an
asynchronous or synchronous mode equals
M and you get a synchronous one
depending on your need you should you
know one of them would be the default
and the other one would be the one that
you changed into the added support the
porn commit in version 10 which is your
ability to basically say well I have 10
servers and a Walkman has access to
beyond five of them before I release the
transaction or no I have five service I
want them to be on three numbers other
than two is basically quad commit nine
six actually added the ability to add
more than one that they had to be in
order and the quorum commit one in post
press ten is sort of the the one you
really want if what you're looking for
is more than two notes worth of
synchronous replication and at which
point you'll just look at all your
servers and basically count how many
have received your synchronous
transaction and as soon as enough of
them compare your configuration has
received it it's released
and the transaction will continue and
there are still things being added to
this the thing that's Claire Monica so
Elise is their own transactional based
basically as soon every transaction in
Postgres when doing anything it's first
written to the transactional order the
while and then it's written to the rest
of the disk and this is primarily used
for proper cover instead of just using
it for that we ship all these changes to
the standby nodes and they basically run
in crash recovery mode all the time and
they just keep recovering so as the data
shows up and the transaction log looking
at it's in the simplest form it's like
sending binary discs of your database
saying hey changed this piece of this
disk block over here in this way and we
just rerun that on the other side so
that one's pretty fast
the common thing again while level
equals replica is what you need is this
only you need to set in your post post
call basically you need to add a little
bit of information into the transaction
log to make it able to perform this
style replication as opposed to in
version 10 this is also the default so
you can run all of this out of the box
on Costco's version 10 on previous
versions you have to enable it you have
to configure the minimum number of users
that can log in and do it as well there
are other things that you want to set
about this is the synchronous mode
options that you can again you can set
it on a per transaction basis where we
have the ability to set it to a local or
remote apply if you said that actually
means that your transaction will also
become locally asynchronous so if your
primary crashes and general just reboots
or something you may actually lose your
very last transaction that is running in
completely asynchronous mode it will
still guarantee consistency on your
database it'll guarantee you know
everything else except that you may know
by default about quarter of a second
worth of transaction worst case
obviously that's tunable but something
in that area if you set it in local that
makes you get your sort of traditional
asynchronous replication today is
written synchronously to the local disk
but it's sent asynchronously over to
your standby switch can be one or twenty
or a hundred decided to earn then Perez
will replicate the data and when you
commit coordination happens at the
commit level when you commit on your
master then the data or the transaction
would lick until the data has been sent
and written to disk and the standby and
asynchronous mode we wait for one
stander if you have ten standbys will
wait for the fastest one of them and
finally you can also say analytical
remote apply where we answer wait for
the database understand by node to have
completed the crash recovery of this
transaction so that it's actually
visible inside of that database because
of these standby nodes you can still
open transactions this time denotes a
read-only but you can open transactions
you can get MVCC snapshots across all
your table so you may have queries
running on old data and things on this
town but so we use them for many
different things and obviously the
further down the line at least you go
the lower things will be but the more
guarantees you have in the event /
failover
of your replication system and we had
the three different methods that we can
do synchronous and the simplest way
you've set a parameter called
synchronous time by name and you list
the names of your standards in this case
I have just s1 s2 and s3 as soon as
anyone
these acknowledge that they committed
has reached it your transaction will be
released and the application will keep
moving on the masternode right this
we've had since Postgres nine walk the
first which is the one if you just say
like this it's this I'm gonna stop let
me say in this case two parenthesis one
two three then we wait for s1 and s2 to
finish assuming that they're online them
go somewhere safe as to is online then
it'll wait for s1 and s3 but it'll
always wait for the first ones in the
list and then the Koren commit that we
added in Postgres ten then you set your
synchronous time my name's - only - in
this case and it will just pick
whichever two of those are the fastest
one at the moment so this way you can
say you know you've guaranteed in this
case any two when we're guaranteed your
transaction is on the master and on two
of the stand bytes so if your master
dice you still have your data in two
places fully guaranteed at all points of
that and the common themes of these
streaming replication I would say for
most people who want to do replication
in Postgres today this is what you do
it's very easy to set up it's pretty
hard to get ready personally I'd like
that in solutions and in particular once
it's working it doesn't just silently
stop working it's very easy to monitor
this when you thing you have to monitor
it we monitor how far behind it is
there's no way that you can like lose
individual tables or anything it's
either All or Nothing it's very
efficient it's very very low overhead
and of course its built-in built-in is
nice we don't have to go download a
separate package you know install it
from whatever repository were using the
things like that
get me streaming replication working in
a modern post quest version is really
easy particularly yen as we do this in
post post version 10
you have your masternode up and running
already you want to set up your stand
right now it's basically two commands
first you run the command PG based
backup which will take a backup of your
master node so basically we take the
backup from the master to the standby
and then we provisioned
from there we'll give the directory just
where we want it
no volume PG SQL or wherever we like to
have it either the hostname point it to
the primary it could be like the address
or hostname we'll give you the user it
has to live in for streaming replication
it needs to either be a super user or it
need to be any user that has the special
replication privilege which is normally
the recommended one so use a separate
user and that has the privilege to do
replication then we have the middle
switch - R which says this is not
actually going to be a backup this is
going to be a replica and then the
system will automatically provision the
configuration file that sets it up as a
replica replication slipped to make sure
that the that's the basically
registering their standby now with the
master so that the master doesn't delete
data that the standby no it still needs
if it fails behind you know if you're
loose the network or reboot the standby
or something like that and then you can
either loot that P thing in the end
there which is just get a progress
report if you database is big if this
thing runs for a couple of hours it's
nice to see how far along it is and then
you don't have to just start this box on
the stand I know when you're done if you
are using Postgres prior to version 10
you can also add to this - extreme so
that your replica doesn't feel so far
behind before it gets started that it
never actually starts this can otherwise
be an option
if you're running it on a very active
database this is not necessary in
posters version 10 because it's been
changed to be the default but on
previous versions add a dash extreme and
that's pretty much it it basically sets
it up to start replicating before it
finishes the backup it's not replicated
immediately so that it doesn't feel so
far behind that it might not be able to
catch up its architecture and compile
flight dependent so you can't freely mix
different compilation suppose squares
different platforms like you know
between SPARC and Intel or Windows and
Linux which kind of works but it's not
really supported its whole cluster only
which is the thing that bites most
people right if you have ten databases
you have to replicate all of them it's
the entire cluster all of them are being
replicated and your standby node is
completely read-only you can't write
anything on it you can even create
temporary tables on it
basically the standby node does not have
its own transaction log so any operation
within the system that generates
transaction log will just fail and is
primary to standby only like you can
only replicate in one direction but this
is usually not a problem if the problem
you're trying to solve this availability
right if you're replicating to gain high
availability in your system then you're
probably gonna replicate between
machines that are roughly equal they're
going to be running the same thing if
you're running Red Hat from your primary
you probably gonna be running Red Hat on
your standby you know for consistency
and things like that you're going to be
running on the same platforms and things
like that but there are other cases
where it can be a problem of course
there are student educational posters
does not come with built-in cluster
management so no manual
over no
over just provides the infrastructure
you can build a federal solution on top
of it all the plumbing is there or the
API so there or the monitoring is there
but it's not shipped and in there and in
doesn't support they are back well it
isn't easy fail back particularly if
you're trying to build these things
yourself there are some very complicated
cases because this is the replication
for example happens that commit level
even as a master might be ahead of a
standby even if they're in synchronous
because there might be uncommitted data
and we can't control where we fail
that's kind of the hole then it's not a
failure
really so it's really easy to get
started but if you want to build really
high availability on top of it it can be
a bit harder to be maintained of course
that's where we can turn to these
outside support projects there are
cluster management solutions for pulse
bars they're just not built that there
are a couple of good ones that I would
say are the ones that you should
evaluate today there is a management
tool called Petrelli
it's designed to be automatic from round
up there are some others that were
designed initially to be manual and I'm
sort of upgraded patron is designed for
automatic failover management pectin I
did pretty much everything it uses it
can plug into multiple different
consensus stores it can use at CD it can
use zookeeper it give console I believe
the latest version which I think it's
out now can actually run without an
external one as well and it has nice
plugins to for example ships with
patterns for integrating with a CH a
proxy so you just you point your
application at an H a proxy and Patroni
will control your postcards nodes it
will control your H
see and you know everything just works
well until it doesn't of course that's
true of every solution but Patroni works
pretty well
and it's by now I'd say it's a very well
tested solution the other reaction that
we have in the postcode for today's in
who called web manager or web MGR this
is one of those that was originally
designed to handle replication clusters
but with manual and has later learned to
do automatic failover and things as well
I found it traditionally it's easier to
use than Petronio when it comes to
dealing with manual Louis because
Patroni wasn't really defined to do that
so if you want to do that and I mean we
can spend a whole other talk just
discussing about whether automatic
failover is actually a good or a bad
thing that will depend on your situation
so let me do that now now manager is
capable of doing both of them it doesn't
handle connection management in itself
it has my plugins where you can have it
run external commands to you know
reconfigure things you can still use it
with things like H a proxy and just a H
a proxy pulled your database make sure
it works but it can take a little bit
more integration for those things but
the advantage is that of course is you
gain a little bit more flexibility when
it comes to those things I think it's
the Postgres automatic failover it's
resource agents and configurations and
plugins if you're using a pacemaker in
course Inc one of the strong points of
that one is throughout if you're using
pacemaker coursing to manage other
things in your organization other types
of H a clusters then it's the
configuration is obviously very similar
it's something that your operations
people will be comfortable with and used
in things like that and the traditional
way to set up here is well you set up a
virtual IP and the pacemaker core sync
combination will
the virtual IP as necessary to whichever
node happens to to be the master node
again and the end though it's called
Postgres automatic failover its focus is
doing manual failover of course or maybe
automatic so if you need to build a high
availability cluster these are all very
good options there also many options out
there as well but today these are sort
of the main options that you will find
throughout the Postgres world so if we
keep moving up the stack database
logical replication is the next level
right this is the many of you probably
know it's new in postcode version 10 we
actually added a lot of the
infrastructure already in nine point
four with something called logical
decoding and then it's been built and
that up until prospers version 10 which
is the first version that released with
built in actual replication sitting on
top of this now this to piggyback on the
right a headlock right it still sits in
the transaction log which means it's
still very low overhead it's a little
bit more overhead than your physical
application that much from a performance
perspective it can be a lot more
overhead from a management perspective
but since it's in the transaction length
when we just change instead of saying my
level replicas we move to a level logic
of application it's very much that
simple then you need to set up a few
things many logical application works is
it reconstructs the changes on a per
roll basis so it's not one of those
solutions that actually replicates your
SQL statements and runs them again on a
master but instead of just sending the
binary differences they send the logical
differences saying well I replace the
row that's identified by this with this
new content and does it on an individual
basis it's still fully transactional so
it's still integrating without and
that's one of the main reasons why it
can use or one of the good reasons it
uses the while to make sure that that's
where you have your commits and it can
trigger
things directly on the commits now being
on a very basis instead of being binary
across the whole cluster means that you
can do table level partial replication
you don't have to replicate everything
anymore you can say I just want to get
this one table over here and you can
also pretty easily do parameter table
bi-directional replication it's still
easy if you say this table is gonna
replicate from node 1 to node 2 and this
other table is going to replicate from
node 2 to node 1 but we might have a
master node for each customer depending
on location and we just replicate them
in two different ways and then we have a
view on top of it or it can be
partitions or something like that which
the application works so many scenarios
were actually just being able to do
table level bi-directional replication
can be really really useful and educate
replication is slightly more complex
than to set up than it is to set up
physical streaming application but it is
still very simple which will then be
master node for this particular table
you create the table every table has to
be identified in this case if your table
has a primary key it will replicate
based on the primary key then you create
this thing called a publication there's
a crepe publication test pump for this
table it can be multiple tables you can
also filter in tables and then it will
dynamically add new tables and things
like that a publication is the unit of
replication so if you put 10 tables into
a publication they will replicate as one
unit and they will move over together
and these are things you need to
consider for example if your tables with
foreign keys between them you can't
replicate the changes to just one of
them then it's one of those funny things
that might work most of the time but not
all at the time and you want there so
those are things you need to consider
these are the cases where logical
replication can become a little bit more
complicated then on the standby node you
create the same table
maybe using something like PG dump and
and then you create a subscription which
is the other side of this is a
subscription test some connection and
this is connecting to the database where
we created the publication and they
would just say publication test problem
this test pub here is of course the same
one that we created over here and as
soon as we create this publication go so
as soon as we create this subscription
reputation of this table will start and
it will start doing it on a railway rail
basis as soon as I insert a row it will
get replicated over to the other one
logical implication comes of course with
its own sets of rivets in this it
doesn't currently do anything other than
data replication it doesn't do schema
replication so if you do with your table
you have to remember do enter table in
old notes and you have to do it in like
the right order and things like that bad
things can happen otherwise it doesn't
particularly doesn't replicate sequences
so if you have your table within our
primary key based off a sequence or
generated by corn or something like that
then the values will of course replicate
but the sequence will still be stuck at
one so if you use this for something
I've high availability and you fell over
then all your sequences are going to be
wrong which is kind of like ooze so it's
not very good for high availability
replication is no reason that we
couldn't be able to add things like
schema replication and sequence
replication on a fundamental level we
just don't have them today but it means
that today this is really good for data
distribution and it's not very good for
high availability so it really depends
on the solution you have and we also
like something that is called failover
slots
well you guys working on them called
them failover slots the general idea
being if you're replicating former a
master with logical and physical and
then you failover to your physical stand
by your logical replication will not
follow so there are still things that
need to be done when it comes to the
database level logical replication but
the built in one is still very good and
it covers a lot of people's use cases
but is not complete now if you want to
build further on logical replication in
the database there is an extension for
Postgres competing logical this is
basically an external version of the
same thing it's where it started it's
been merged sort of piece by piece into
what is now the logical replication in
postgis version 10 and you know pieces
of it will be merged into future
versions of hospice but they have more
capabilities today but it also means
that it's less integrated and it's a
little bit more tricky to work with you
don't have these nice commands that you
call functions for everything and there
are a few things that are where the docs
are you have to do this in the right
order otherwise you know Dragons show up
with this support sequence replication
for example it is a boudreaux based
filtering so you can say I don't wanna
replicate the table I only want to
replicate rows that match this you can
do column based filtering saying I only
want to replicate these columns and not
the other ones for it it supports
merging and conflict resolution so you
can have multiple nodes replicating into
the same table in a destination for
example or you can have local changes to
a table and replicating into the same
one and you can define ways for what's
going to happen when there is a conflict
because if you write for more than one
place there will eventually be a
conflict you may think that you're
vacation prevented that but it didn't it
didn't testing it always doesn't testing
and they remember other things that PG
illogical adds on top of this the PD
educational supports post was nine point
four net just post was ten and using PC
logical you can accomplish what's
basically well there was no such thing
as zero but very close to zero downtime
upgrades by using logical replication
because physical replication was tied to
specific post code versions right
versions and platforms and compiled
flags and things logical replication is
it you can use in PG logical you can
replicate from post as my for to
Buster's ten for example now you will be
able to do things mostly these zero
downtown operated things probably using
the Postgres built-in replication as
well but only a film version 10 and we
haven't released version 11 yet so
you'll have to wait a while for that if
we continue further up the stack we have
the app in database right this is the
old trigger based replication systems
and the people to those are still out
there right anyone never deployed Sloane
II did you like it
okay there's always one so it is a
really capable system but it's not very
easy to work with it is actually really
easy to break and when you do you're in
for a lot of pain they did this things
and even today even with P geological
even with all the dota and stuff there
are things that slowly can do that they
can you can set up really really strange
things in your application with
scrolling and it works pretty well with
the karo and Wendy stay which are also
trigger based system that are basically
simpler to use now Sony I think that's
their main selling arguments it's really
that they're much easier to use them
slowly and they still are they're still
good choices for cases where the other
solutions don't apply but they're not
really your primary target for a long
time they were the only one we have they
have a lot more overhead every time you
do an insert it's copied somewhere and
this is all happening in trigger it's
running in user space in the database
and then you pull it out and you delete
it and these tools will do sort of all
sorts of weird things to make sure the
overhead is as little as possible but
it's still going to be much much worse
than for the logical or physical
built-in resolution we need to do it
such as you know who in here likes
multi-master everyone sit right
everybody really needs multi-master
that's my experience everyone needs it
until they start looking into what they
really need you know in particular until
they start realizing what it means
because we most people want when they
say they want multi master is the one
transparent multi master right the month
or application to remain completely
unchanged and things to just
we work unfortunately we don't have a
lot of magic
there are things in clay here like the
speed of light and annoying things like
that that we haven't figured out how to
deal with yet if you're doing a database
in in the form of your traditional
relational database you cannot do
transparent multi-master but there
people who saw it who's ever met for
example in you know a salesman from
somebody wants to sell you a solution
based on board iraq saying it's
transparent multi master that will scale
everywhere and will work perfectly and
whenever that again we purchase all them
what I do I have yeah did you try to
deploy work using a rack adapt that
application can do some very good things
but if you just take your regular
application and point to it very bad
things can happen and the same goes for
all solutions so the completely
transparent multi master just doesn't
exist if you want the the consistent
database of your traditional relational
database system there are some options
with in Postgres still there's a toolkit
for capturing posters called b dr that
has been developed a lot together with
the PG logical stuff that does support
geographically distributed multi master
if you manage to actually run your
application completely unmodified
against it then you probably didn't need
no master right goes to most solutions
but if you engineer your application to
work together with a solution like PDR
yes it can solve those problems in a lot
of cases probably not to remove them but
in one of those cases now b dr today is
a purpose press it's not an extension
it's an actual for compose press which i
think is based on line four or nine five
at this point they're working their way
towards newer versions there i think
last I heard to still make it into an
extension in the next major version of
video should hopefully just be an
extension on top of all squares but it's
not there now but will hopefully get
there
all these trigger based solutions that
we saw recorder supports do you know to
master the big problem with doing
because the treaty-based parts are
asynchronous and the big problem with a
synchronous multi-master is of course
you will eventually get conflicts and
you need to decide what's gonna happen
when you get a conflict all right who's
gonna win and if you can define those
you can define like very complex
policies for dealing with that and the
two like Ricardo but you have to
actually do it otherwise once you run
into the conflict everything just stops
then that's probably not what you
intended but my general recommendation
when you are looking at something like
meteor master is you know first look
about five more times to see if you
really need multi master because when
we're talking about these things that
were easy to break yeah that'll be easy
to break in most scenarios it is a much
harder problem to solve than most people
realize if you want to maintain the
consistent the consistency part that
really is our relational database of
course we can build our replication all
the way up in the application itself and
just run connect to five different
databases and run things in five
different databases and commit them in
all of them and everything will be fine
right but actually doing transaction
control at this level can become very
complicated now you're moving a lot of
complexity into your application if what
you're looking for is consistent
replication which is probably why you
were using a relational database in the
first place then trying to build that in
your application is probably not a very
good idea it's setting yourself up for
for having to maintain something that
will become really really complicated
over time so where we take from this
there are these little options than this
around
things that we want like main problems
that we want to solve with replication
today in what you're looking for
assembling the problem of high
availability then you should really just
be using Postgres built-in streaming
replication easy to set up hard to break
these are very good properties when
we're talking about building for high
availability because if it breaks it
will always break in the wrong moment we
know that that's how it works and use
the fact that you can mix synchronous
and asynchronous replication in the same
faster or even between the same notes
because when doing that in an
intelligent way and in a controlled way
you can get most of the important
benefits from doing synchronous
replication with almost none of the
overhead by simply indicating the
important things versus the slightly
less important things because even on
the slightly less important things we're
not talking about losing a lot of data
right in the in asynchronous mode we're
still talking about losing a necklace
than one second
worth of transactions which in a lot of
applications really isn't that much but
it's very much more than zero like we
can be an observer and saying it is
actually okay to lose a few transactions
but if we mix those we can get a very
good performance tree and if you want to
build like if what you're setting up is
just going to be manually maintained
your application and the built-in tools
do pretty good job if you want to go a
step beyond that you need to look at
things like automatic failover don't
build your own solution for automatic
failover look at primarily Patroni and
web manager compare how they work
- what matches your organization you're
both fine tools they work in slightly
different scenarios I would recommend
that you evaluate them both look at path
if you are
using things or for other things going
to be using things like pacemaker and
chorus Inc if you're not doing that
learn it's an extra piece of
infrastructure that you're bringing in
you're probably better off looking at
these tools to deal with that but if
you're building high availability don't
use logical replication don't use P
geological certainly don't use the
trigger-based ones if you use actual
who's still using one of slowly Ricardo
oil and they stay actively in the
organization using them and not planning
to replace them by using anything that
they're planning to replace well yes
because at some point your project has
to officially be finished the other use
case that we need to cover is if you
really need to do is upload pure read
queries then we can still use physical
streaming application because our
standby notes are available or standby
notes or read-only you can still get
multi table and multi statements
transactional snapshots on their standby
nodes they just have to be completely
redone which goes back to the previous
one yes you might want to look at
management tools and things like that
but having this set up really easy every
leaf stated that is a good choice in
many cases another data distribution
which is different in that now they
don't just need to run simple read
queries on our data we might need to
replicate different data to different
places we might need to generate temp
tables generate reporting tables and
things like that though if you're using
Postgres 10 use logical replication if
you're not using Postgres 10 and while
you're not using
you should upgrade you should use mr.
Stan with his net look at PG logical if
your cooze using post goes nine point
four or newer this Wikipedia logical if
the built-in one isn't good enough for
you if you need the partition
replication for example replicating some
columns or somewhere else
only then look at P geological and this
if you're using slowly you should
probably look at upgrading your way out
of Salone unless you are one of the
people who are in one of these use cases
that really only slowly solves then
you're gonna keep using slumming just be
careful because it's easy to break these
are all good ways of dealing with your
going out in different ways but what if
you need both
if you need both high availability and
do both just put up another note it's a
very common scenario that you say you
use synchronous streaming replication
between a high availability clock try
again high availability cluster of say
three nodes and then you also use
asynchronous replication to another node
or to other nodes where you run your
read queries for example you can freely
mix and match these different types of
replication will be streaming ones
support that you have cascading
replication so you replicate from node 1
to node B and then from node B to C D
and E so you can replicate in to read
clusters that then go into a
distribution no that replicates in too
many Reed clusters to conserve of
network bandwidth and many sorts of
things like that so in many cases if you
move beyond the simplest needs you don't
want to mix different ones of these but
these should all be sort of their base
points of where you want to go for those
things and that's all I have do we have
a couple of minutes for questions yes
we're three minutes for questions who
wants to be the first one
[Applause]
so anybody yes you have to run to right
in the middle and then and then throw
them I think
but I think she might have not turn it
on for you like so the question I think
is how much latency is added by 29
synchronous replication and if the
application ends up being broken over
time it really depends on the distance
between your notes if you're replicating
like clothes these are two notes in the
same data center or so then it's this a
little bit of latency but it's very very
low obviously if you replicate you know
across the Atlantic we have to go there
and back I've seen a lot of scenarios
where you're replicating between two
data centers that are in the same city
and usually like the overhead is or the
latency overhead is low enough that you
barely notice it now if you have an
application that's just rapid firing
very very small transactions yes you
will notice the latency there of course
but mostly time you have multiple
concurrent things and things like an
optimization to minimize it so the
question is read replicas can you create
separate indexes on the read replicas
and if you are using the streaming any
streaming application then the answer is
no you can't you are unfortunately
correct in that you cannot do that now
if you use a logical replication then
you can put separate indexes on the
receiving side but in the physical
replication you cannot it's completely
read-only anywhere else
yes give us a challenge for example
different story that's a usable thing
but it is has the ability to do that
statement level replication in PG Pugh
and here my recommendation map really is
don't use it
but the rest of PG pool is much better
[Applause]
yeah