so I'm Jacobs here I'm a application
software programmer and yes I will speak
you about UFE programming that might be
surprising but you will look why such
things I will I will not learn you how
to write an operating system nor even a
bootloader so II but I will show you the
step to make and executable files that
can run in UEFI directly at the
beginning of the boot of your computer
so as I intended this presentation to be
for beginners we just describe you what
is UEFI maybe you you have a good
knowledge of it already but will just
present you the minimum things you need
to do for the rest you need to know for
the rest of the presentation and UEFI is
a specification that present a common
interface above a wide range of hardware
and it's a specification and it's
present for operating system or
bootloader the same interface
whatever the hardware so but I will not
speak in this presentation about alwa
initialization just the communication
path between UEFI and maybe your
computer or your and your operating
system or your software so you if I mean
unified extensible firmware interface
and there is a huge specification more
than 2000 pages and for shops and it
will be good enough for the rest of the
presentation
it's abuse replacement with expound
Extron externally the capabilities so
what I will discuss in this presentation
I will show you existing two chains and
what are the shortcomings with them then
I will show you how you fi executable
file is structure then how you can ow is
organized the API of UEFI because it is
what we will use to communicate with the
hardware and I will give you a short
overview of features that could be
useful and that might give you some
ideas to make something different than
just a bootloader or things like that
and after I will show you describe you
an important an important point in ufi
specification is the protocol concept
and I will explain you why it's
important and then I will show you some
more things at the end and what I plan
to do I will follow this presentation so
first just this notice in this
presentation I will don't take care of
security yeah I know it's important but
for learning programming UEFI I think
it's not that important I consider that
you disable secure boot or things like
that and you are the owner of your
machine and you do what you want with
your own out work so don't and that will
where you focus on what Oh beast
programmers like me what he needs when
programming UEFI so first I will show
you the there is mainly your if you are
already done some UEFI development I
hope you don't at this point now because
you will probably don't learn something
in this presentation but there is two
main stack there with channel PD key to
and GNU EFI and when I start locking
programming you fi I just look at
documentation and it looks like it's not
the way for me to go so from what I will
because I don't even try to install them
it was quite tedious setup process
because you don't have a package that
you can download and start writing your
program
jihui's package but you have to download
the different ones you have to configure
things and thing like that it's what I
weighed and it seems from what that GNU
EFI is supposed simpler because for a
long time it would not sure you can use
your standard Linux compiler for example
but it's not the case anymore I checked
two weeks ago and before if you are on
the Linux you can do almost the same you
don't have to answer for example wind
the minimum mingw to compile a GNU
Compiler for Windows to get the job done
it's not more we clear but yeah
before that you you have to cost compile
this on your machine to get be nervous
and with GNU if I it was maybe why it's
maybe a chocolate but act that you can
use your standard elf
Jack tries and put them in UEFI UEFI
your files executable files so why it's
so complicated for next to generate UEFI
is maybe it's because of the structure
of the application
well important things to know is that
it's a pot app executable file it's not
an elf files and so it's exactly the
same file format like on Windows so that
might explain why it's more difficult if
you are on Windows it's easy to get
portable executable files but from other
platform is more difficult and the only
difference is there is in the header of
the file
there is a special subsystem code to
organize that it is and UEFI application
2000 year
a very small difference and Joey's main
three kinds of UEFI applications those
are with applications with this code so
it's mainly it's the most used code it's
for bootloader but you can imagine to
make your own vomit an application with
this code and there is another kind of
applications there are drivers there is
two kind but I will don't explain more
on this feature because there is a good
drivers whiterose guide at the china co
website so you can look at it you shot
in your the internet and you will find
them but surely it's exactly the same
file format and it works just the same
it's just the intent and the intention
of what you're making inside that make
it to a driver
when other difference with the standard
fight is that there is a typo and five
point called efe main and there is two
parameters under on the image that is
automatic load automatically load were
by the firmware and then the firmware
give you a system table and from this
system table we will show I will show
you in the future with the system table
you can call all you will feel UEFI
api's so it's very important and to call
the those UEFI api's you have to use the
same calling convention as the column
corresponding Windows target so that
also the other problem that you might
have with standard linux object files
because you probably don't use the same
calling convention and EFI is just about
that you call something that make the
translation for you so I my take is that
Intel when they want to publish UEFI
won't to have Microsoft on board and
make life for them easier but more
difficult for us it's may take I don't
know if we always on but I think it's
makes sense
so loss of it and one key important
things to know is that the CPU is
already in protected mode so and with a
flat memory model so it's a real change
for beginners like me compared to the
Buell's things that you come in real
mode and if you want more than more than
30-years things you have to go to the -
to the protected mode and see like that
so really now you can start maybe
something like very close to an
application under an OS on an even on 64
bytes you even go in wrong mode so
you're already in 64 bytes and you don't
have to transition - but only one core
is initialized so if you want to go
multi-threading you have to do your own
work and do some hardware initialization
so it's not completely but it should be
enough for start for starting
now we will look at an important
structure in the UEFI api's it's the EFI
system tables from there you can access
some services like input output console
so you services also fields to access
comfort of configuration tables so if
you wait on operating systems it might
be interesting so for example there is a
CPI tables available there and there is
also fields but there is two other sub
structure with one is one time services
that provide additional services
available even after a good time so your
passing system can call them always and
other kind of services are good services
and they are only available when you
boot the computer and when you give give
an to the operating system this service
are not available anymore so some
example of which provide provided here
there is memory allocation functions
there is a IP eyes to find the memory
map of your hardware so it might be
suggesting it might be useful if you
write an operating system as I said
before there is a console and input
output console online you can get
filesystem are accessed it might be
useful to find a kernel for example in
partition and there is also some maybe
interesting features for biometal
applications like graphic
interface with Marvin Mouse support or
even some net came some network access
so it might give you some ideas of the
possibilities it might depends on your
hardware it might be more complicated
than just calling socket things but it
there is things here and now I will pick
like I said earlier one important
concept in the UEFI API is it's the
protocol concept well if you want to
give overview it's more or less
interfaces with a set of related methods
and field so just a structure with
different fields and some our methods
and they are all identified with a
global unique ID and example of
protocols you can find them in the
specification there is a simple text
output protocols this one under control
unlink so it's the same for input and
for example for graphic operation you
can use graphics output protocol so it's
just a few of them and there is some
more that our specified system position
but generally what you have to do is to
find the protocols before calling it so
there is api's to do that for example
you can find protocols by unique IDs or
under and from the under for example you
can check if you're under support more
protocols so which method under protocol
and you can check if
there is a support for this specific one
that you are looking for and there is
also another important ApS is located
protocol and you've with this API you
can find and locate the first under so
the first reference to the protocols
that implements your specify the unique
ID so a few programming tips about UEFI
your programming there is a function
that it called exit boot services and if
you are making a boot loader it's
probably one of the last function you
will call and because after that it will
release all resources used by your boot
loader yeah that may be you have
allocated with the memory allocation
function and things like that and then
you give an to your operating system so
after that you couldn't call good
services API anymore
you shouldn't probably need will crash
and one other important things if
specially if you do metal applications
is that boot services by default is only
available for their ways of timeouts for
about five minutes so if you want to
make longer things you have to disable
the watchdog and maybe replace it with
none with no function so you have enough
time to do your what you want to do with
UEFI
so we'll all this you're I think ready
to write your first UEFI application
it's all you need to know and so what
you need is something that is almost an
Windows compiler that can generate
Windows veena is something that lets you
define the entry point with specified
requirements so if efi your main
function and something that can respect
the windows calling convention with all
that you can do your UEFI with maybe any
language that provides these services
but it's when I discover that I think
about I think about well my preferred
compiler are all this feature so maybe I
could try a kit and white UEFI be now is
me my preferred compiler and then scum
what I plan to do is to introducing
maybe what I think it's the easiest way
to write UEFI application and
surprisingly it's with free Pascal why
this because instead of spending times
writing in selling G and the Tanaka
toolkit or things like that I think it
was more simpler for me at least to just
tweak
free Pascal to generate you fiv now is
why I think it was possible for just
software programmer and applications of
the programmer it's because free Pascal
already have an internal link for
Windows and an internal compiler so with
the linker I shouldn't have to
with LD version or thing like that
everything should be directly in my
preferred compiler so if there is no if
the tool already have a linker there is
no external dependencies so it should be
really easy to setup and one last thing
says maybe for me it was well equated
this under iku because under iku with
Tanaka would have mean to cross compile
or to pause the world stack and probably
unknown OS from channel Co and a huge
step on the contrary with free Pascal
you already have it on iku so it's
easier to start acting for me and I try
to do all my OB programming with iku so
I think it would be simpler but yeah
it's the that is the plan but is still
work in progress so I can show you what
kind of things I can do
so maybe you can't you come with
everything but it's maybe on purpose to
show you the difference
so actually cheat a little because for
free Pascal this is a HelloWorld
application that you can do with GNU
UEFI on the top and on the show you the
white so it is for channel Co but shadow
Co there is lots of comments that's why
it's longer but but if you look at the
free Pascal one and if you know a little
about free Pascal well it's just the
standout hello world application you
will do in Pascal and this kind of
application that compiled out-of-the-box
and one guy back here under UEFI so if
we have time after the penetration maybe
I will give you start in show you in the
virtual machine so it's as I said it's
an early process but it's already
compiled the UEFI binaries and what I
plan to do now is port the world and to
implement all one-time language that is
with free Pascal so you can use you can
develop for example console application
in free Pascal and just run them efi in
UEFI environment and maybe one thing
that will be weird would be to write
bindings for all you fe fi protocols
what it means is just to declare our
parameters on each functions and
resistor and declare record with all the
fields necessary but it's a huge process
so any help is welcome if you think that
kind of project you should exist and
maybe one of fun things I like to do who
with one time a full runtime library I
should be
to compile the free Pascal compiler it
just won't be now is in and you as you
an UEFI application I may be when it for
directly from the system so this is one
of the funny thing I'd like to do but it
maybe depends on your L because I only
spend maybe a few days per hour on this
project so it might take time so if me
help is welcome if you think it's why to
do so here is a couple of links about
UEFI programming just link so if you
want to setup genu you fi your event
channel Co there with links and just a
mention for the first one is when I saw
this article that I think it's about
doing you if programming and host and
when I read this article I think well I
can do that with free Pascal and it will
be even simpler than what was explained
so just everything starts for me so
happy you UEFI aking I hope it was
interesting for you and if you have a
question so yeah for now I only used
comes white white output output console
and memory allocation so maybe I can
start just a sample
so here's the command line to compile
you don't yes yeah yeah yeah yeah forget
to repeat the question
it was which protocols were already
implemented so there is the output
protocol so there is a lot of debugger
loops but it's the output protocol and
there is some memory allocation
functions that are called so this was
necessary for example well if you want
to allocate the objects or thing like
that thank you
[Applause]