okay thanks man for those of you that
don't know me my name is Nick visas I've
been working with Rene as a proxy SQL
commit over the last few months and I'm
also a my SQL DBA before I kick off this
presentation just a question a show of
hands for me to gauge who's familiar
with asynchronous replication semi sync
proxy SQL okay GT ID okay great
so let's kick off with proxies held
since everyone's familiar with this I
won't focus on it too much it's a layer
seven database proxy okay
primary integration is with MySQL
protocol there is some support also for
clique house and by the way in there's a
birds of a feather fashion at quarter to
five in room h3 two to eight for those
of you that are interested for those
that are not familiar with clickers it's
blazing-fast you should check it out
so moving back to proxy SQL it's built
for high performance high availability
and it's feature-rich so there's a wide
variety of stuff that you can configure
to get various functionality as well as
to tune the proxy as you'd like it to
behave so quick overview of the
architecture clients connect the
requests are evaluated and depending on
the configuration you've put into proxy
SQL certain actions will be performed so
like key areas are read/write split
sharding query right and for this
session we'll be focusing on readwrite
split and specifically did the
challenges that we have with
master-slave replication so roll
familiar with replication the biggest
problem is replication lag and being
able to retrieve data that is fresh
enough from our slaves so I mean we have
this problem in asynchronous replication
in semi synchronous replication we can
be more sure that our data has reached
our slaves so the integrity is there
that we can still read stale data
so in order to avoid reading stale data
especially when an application connects
both to a master and a slave it has to
maintain two sets of connections and it
also has to be aware of how fresh the
data is on a slave so looking at this in
more detail okay
typically an application will write data
to a master that data may or may not
have been replicated to the slave the
application will then have to connect to
the slave and read that data if we're
doing a readwrite split so stale data
can be received this makes our
developers unhappy with proxy SQL the
readwrite split we overcome the problem
of maintaining separate connections to
masters and slaves because we have the
concept of reader and writer host groups
so the application can just blindly send
all requests reads writes to proxy SQL
proxy SQL will route the writes to the
master and then route the reads to the
slaves depending on the configuration
that we set up in the query rules so the
big benefit is that we don't have to
make application changes in order to
route our read queries to slave or to
route our rights to a master all traffic
is sent to a single IP to a single port
so you don't have to reconfigure it on
on failover and we can dynamically
modify the configuration we have in
proxy SQL to down slaves when we need to
do maintenance to add more slaves when
we need to scale so that one area is
covered but even with this configuration
stale data can be an issue because I
mean proxy SQL in itself does provide
replication monitoring so we can set the
threshold for instance of 30 seconds and
say if our data is more than 30 seconds
although even one second old don't read
from this slave so we'll become that
issue but there's still a possibility
that our data will be one second
stale and in addition to that this
monitoring happens from proxy SQL and
it's basically polling the slaves at a
configurable interval which has a
minimum of one second so up to two
seconds of delayed data so we kind of
have to think about how replication
works and go into a bit of detail to see
how we can overcome this problem with
asynchronous replication as we all know
it's all it operates basically with a
bin lock position file in position so
all the events are written to the file
it's sent to the slaves and all of these
events are processed one by one so both
in terms of processing it's kind of a
little bit of a bottleneck things have
to happen in sequence and masters and
slaves have to be completely
synchronized in addition when we're
doing things like failover we have to
ensure that our slaves are at a certain
position in order to connect to our
masters so GPI d was introduced to help
solve this problem of course the main
difference here is that we have a unique
identifier for every transaction which
is not unique just to that host but
unique to every single host within the
cluster so the specific area that I want
is to keep in mind for today's session
is the structure of the GT ID it's
basically a colon separated identifier
with the source ID and the transaction
ID so why is GT ID important for us
essentially this gives us the ability to
detect which transactions have not been
have been executed and have not been
executed it allows auto positioning so
we can just
restructure our master slave topology as
we wish and starting from 5 6 5 and
later and 5 6 9 variables were
introduced so that we could actually
delay our selects on a slave and wait
for a certain GT ID position to be
reached before executing the statement
so this is quite good it's a better
approach it allows us to
get the data we want and avoid stale
data but there is still a delay because
we have to wait until that that data is
replicated and if it doesn't replicate
up until the certain point we'll get an
error on the connection so in my SQL 5:7
a variable was introduced that's pretty
important now this is available in
Percona server and articles MySQL but
not in Moorea DB as of yet so the
variable is session track GT IDs and
basically when you enable this you can
get either the own GT ID so the GP ID
generated for a specific set of
transactions actually the last
transaction that you executed or the
full set of GT IDs returned in the ok
packet so whenever I'm executing a write
I will know what GT ID position a server
will have to have processed in order for
my transaction to be consistent so
having this information I can query a
slave and say what's your GT ID position
okay you've already reached that point
I'm good to execute my select statement
so I mean we thought about how this can
be leveraged in in proxy SQL and Rene
was like designing this and thinking
about how can we do it there's basically
two approaches to the to solve this
problem the one is making a request to
the slave and asking it what's your GT
ID position so I mean this implies
polling this implies some delay
essentially it's the same problem that
we have when we're monitoring for slave
delay with a regular host group so we're
polling we have that delay of the
interval it can work but it's not the
best approach so what's the other option
instead of pulling pushing
something it wasn't
it's everything clear and any questions
I mean it's very important that this
everything discussed up until this point
is completely cleared for the next slide
so if anybody has questions gray area
okay so the push method instead of
polling slaves to get their GT ID why
not have the MySQL server itself have a
process running there and push the GT
IDs that have been processed to all the
mice to all the proxy SQL servers
connected in this way we avoid having to
request the data we avoid having to wait
the slaves just process binary log event
and then send their GT ID positions so I
mean it's more optimized and it's
especially important in a large-scale
deployment where you have a lot of hosts
both MySQL servers and proxy SQL servers
so to solve this problem Renee came up
with the proxy SQL bin la garita
reader which is essentially a
lightweight process that will run on a
MySQL server it's designed with proxy
skills principles of high availability
and high performance it's very
lightweight there was a lot of work done
to minimize the CPU usage and the
network overhead in fact how does the
process work it processes bin logs as if
it were a slave but running locally on
the same MySQL server it strips all of
the information except the GT ID and it
even strips the source ID and just sends
the transaction ID until the sauce ID is
changed so this very little network
traffic this very little CPU overhead
and it also has an auto auto restart
mechanism in case it fails and also
reconnect in case proxy or SQL is not
able to contact it so let's just have a
look at this on a diagram yes
yes so it will send it and then it will
it will not resend it until it changes
so basically what's happened is that it
takes the status of the or diginity
executed on the mast on the server and
as soon as a client in this case will be
Roxy sequel connect to this process it
will send the Fuji dataset and from that
moment on will send the first GT ad
executed with all the server und and the
transaction ID and then from that moment
on it will only send the transaction ID
until the moment they a new UID is
generated so it just a way to minimize
to minimize network bandit as soon as
possible because this is designed to
have hundreds of proxy connecting to
every database server so of course you
should try to minimize the probe usage
as much as possible so MySQL will send
the replication data and all of the GT
ID and whatever needs to be written to
the slaves and the bin log reader will
run locally read all of these as reneges
described and send them to all the proxy
SQL instances so every single proxy SQL
instance that connects to a MySQL server
will have if it's been configured to
collect that will have the exact
position for every instance so at this
point we know what position our slaves
are at but how do we achieve the
consistency so proxy scale can be
configured to enforce this consistency
on specific host groups and if you've
enabled this what proxy SQL will do is
when a session is initiated and some
transactions are occurring my proxy SQL
will
check the status of a host before
routing a selected and it will check to
see if the GTI be the last GT ID that
was executed for that session on a group
of service has been executed on the
slave before sending the query okay so
let's take a simple example of two two
slaves and one master it will check the
first in its own internal in memory list
it will not find it it will check the
second if it still does not find it it
will then route the query to the master
so you'll always have fresh data your
latency will be low and you can even
configure this just on a host group you
don't necessarily need the replication
host group so let's just have a look at
this in in terms of a replication host
group so the application will send the
reads and writes to to proxy SQL DML
will be routed to the writer host group
this will be written on the master the
next request look the next dql request
will come in some select or something
like that then proxy SQL will evaluate
which slaves are up-to-date and if none
of them are are up-to-date
it will route it to the master provided
that the master is included in the
reader host group so to sum up let's
have a look at what is supported for GT
ID consistent reads in proxy SQL with
basic master-slave replication we
support both asynchronous replication
and semi synchronous replication for
multi master in ODB cluster and group
replication is also supported finally a
quick note about the requirements and GT
ID is required for all of the servers
that are part of the host group and of
course MySQL 5.7 so that we can have
that information returned in the ok
packet and finally at the current moment
the bin like format must be configured
to row so
what time is it time for any to do a
live demo and for all of you to see how
this works in action so questions yes
okay so basically though it work is that
the GED of the transaction executed from
the client is written from the okay
pocket so for every client session
Rox is equally striking the GED for that
specific client so when it need to
execute the a select statement its check
which slaves has that specific gdb it
does not check the last JB written for
whenever for whatever connection just
for that specific client just
technically yes actually you might also
send the queries to our slaves it is few
seconds lagging behind
but you initially that the bride has
been written by one specific client hast
reached the slave and one important
thing is that you don't have to enable
these features for any term sort of
traffic but you can specify would select
statement you want these features to
want enabled it's not you don't enable
to globally you enabled for rare type of
select statement
technically not correct it doesn't query
them to check if they have the GDD
but it mean generally internally check
if those slaves have already the data
now the principle of a check if there
are if the slaves have the data first
and then the master because normally if
you're using replication husba the
master is in the same post group as the
slaves because it's part of the reader
but with a lower weight so the
probability of the query set being sent
to the slave is higher than to obviously
being sent to the master what if the GED
is not executed or none of the slaves
and later on the master because actually
technically it is possible that between
lock reader reply slightly later have an
unlikely but the possibility is there
the same principle apply of how proxy
seek will behave when there is no
serving our host group it just wait for
the server to come for a server to be
avaible so technically you might have a
slightly delay the worst case
the debtor will come after 10 second it
is the default for a server not being
available in the housetop let me go back
see which is the best light to probably
permit this one let me just go the side
so the wet work is that the application
is writing here so then the master reply
with the okay proxy sequel knows what is
the okay the GED and the talk a packet
reply to the client with okay then by
the time that the client is sending
another query you can pretty much ensure
that at least the master has turned the
GDD to the proxy so the probability of
having this guy sending a query before
this one returned agility to the master
is unlikely to happen technically
possible but the probability extremely
low and and then depend how fast are the
slave to process the GTD and reply back
to the proxy
but the idea is that we are eliminating
all the external Network round-trip
because when this will execute a query a
select statement this already knows what
are the GDD executed both here and there
it doesn't have to check them
it already knows yes
every client has his own state so the
GTA did
so if you have only one proxy what you
are saying is very easy to do to
implement because this proxy will know
what the create has been sent to the
other base server master
slaves whatever but if you have multiple
proxy then this process does not know
what has been executed by that one
technically can be implemented in some
other way like relying only on the bin
log leader
so whatever bin log has been executed up
to that moment but a consequence of this
might be that let's see let me think it
probably has to wait some interval to
make sure that nothing guys was executed
in between I'm not really sure how how
to implement this or even if what are
the challenges yeah okay so demo
so we were trying oh you cannot read
here
I'm trying to zoom out now so take that
yes
okay so there were two things that I
wanted to show one is one proxy sequel
instance that is collecting metrics from
30 database server at the same time so
it's collecting method for all of them
and they want to show the city
utilization and the demands of
realization but unfortunately the VPN
doesn't seem to work so I'm going to
also only to show another one so in this
session
what we have is okay so I don't know how
many of you are familiar with the web
proxy sequel is being configured so it
has an admin interface and which
basically execute DML to configure the
proxy or the configurational is on his
own tables so for example table my
secret servers in this tables there are
all the servers that are configured as a
back-end for proxy sequel and in our
case what we have introduced for these
new features is this new variable Cities
this new columns with this GID port so
we have hostname port 10 HTTP port
report is basically where the blog
reader is listening so for example you
can run select host group ID hostname
port gjd port from my secret service I'm
just removing everything else so we have
to ha stop was group 1 and host group 2
where GD ad port is enabler is not 0 so
a participant will connect on that port
and retrieve the gkd
and all this is happening in real time
so there is a new tables your tables
from start so in start the star schema
is where all the metrics are being
collected and specifically we are
interested in this table so select star
from start
that secret GTD executed so here we have
the proxy sequel is conducting GTD from
those two server it is this one is the
master and those two were the slave and
in real time is telling you the executed
set and how many gdb event has been read
so far from that server if you executed
few times you will see that of course
toast counter are changing and you can
also guess which one is the master and
which one is the slave okay
oh yeah okay so so create table starts
my sequel so this table also collect
this table collect all the statistic of
all the queries that are being executed
and it also now there is our new columns
that is queries appear DTD sync so
select star select queries where is GG
ID same
so here the host book there are some
service to have to know these features
enabled because this actually is a proxy
seek were disconnected not to one
cluster but there are multiple cluster
behind it so it's only tells you where
the queries has been executed so a lot
of queries has been executed without GED
enforced while other query have been
executed with the GED enforced so it
will read it will when it's reading is
making sure that the server is in sync
with the master teammates over okay
steady saying either question actually
the demo was going to supposed to be a
bit longer have question why
[Applause]