okay let's keep on going so next we are
having here on the podium
Michael pattern with regular expression
derivatives in Python hi everyone it's
great to see everyone got up early to
hear a talk on derivatives that's weird
okay thank you very much anyway my name
is Michael Patten I work and live in
Tokyo even though I have an Australian
accent my day job is at Google I work on
Chrome browser we're always looking for
new people to join the chromium open
source project so if you're interested
you're very welcome and please reach out
to me but that's not what I'm talking
about today today I'm talking about a
private project this is not a Google
project it's a personal project and the
motivation for my project is very simple
I just wanted to generate scanners you
know things that tokenize text that have
guaranteed Lydia performance and
understand you decode and as it turns
out there's a lot of tools out there but
none quite fit what I wanted so I wanted
to build my own and I came across a
really great paper by Owens rep Ian
Curran and they described how you can
use regular expressions to build a
deterministic finite automaton a state
machine and that sounded like exactly
what I wanted and they said in their
paper that these are regular expression
derivatives have been lost in the sands
of time I mean few computer scientists
are aware of them so hopefully after
this talk a few more computer scientists
will be aware of this technique it's
pretty cool you know it sounded exactly
what I wanted I'm so quick refresher
regular expressions are really really
simple as it turns out so you've all
used them in in real life probably but
when you start looking at them
theoretically there's a very small set
of things they boil down to is there's a
one there's a null string there's an
empty string there's a symbol you know
ABCD or whatever in an alphabet but we
normally you know use the big Sigma sign
to represent you got concatenation you
know two letters together you've got the
star operator you know zero or more
things you've got logical law which is
often used we use the pipe in positive
circular expressions but here we'll use
a plus and in this particular setup we
also have end and not as it turns out
they're kind of handy to have I'm so
examples down the bottom there you know
we can have you know a bunch of letters
in a row that's a regular expression
hello that matches the word hello
the second example there matches either
you know the letters a B and C all the
numbers 1 2 & 3 in sequence and the
third regular expression matches a any
number of B's including 0 and a c and
again if you've used POSIX regular
expressions you probably are very
familiar with this ok another refresher
deterministic finite state automata and
these are state machines so basically we
want to turn a regular expression into
one of these the idea is you have a
bunch of states there's a start state a
bunch of accepting states which are the
ones with the double circles where
things match then there's an arrow state
and of course there's the transitions
where the arrows take you from state to
state based on what letters you get it's
a really simple idea you've all seen
state machines before now did you know
you can take the derivative of a regular
expression what does this mean this
sounds very complicated but it's really
a simple idea the idea is it's you take
a regular expression and you feed a
letter into it and what you have left is
the derivative so if I have a regular
expression a and I feed the later a into
it one left weave is the null string
nothing's left I've matched if I've got
a B in a feed an a into it I get no
alert nothing matched
ok if I have a e followed by B and I
feed an A in to what's left over is
bleah it's a really simple idea if I the
fourth example there if I've got a a
star and a feed an a into it I still got
an 8 star and that's regular expression
derivatives these things were invented
by a mathematician called Janos brasov
ski in 1964 this is not new stuff but
it's very cool so
there's a bunch of rules I'm not going
to go through those but the real issue
here is that you could put you can write
you can easily reduce all these rules to
a simple program and on the right hand
side over there there's actually a
helper function and that is also used in
one of these rules but also it's used to
see if regular expression is nullable
and this turns out to be really useful
later on so there's this idea that a
regular expression is nullable which
means that it matches okay so why is all
this stuff useful well here's some
Python code this is almost exactly the
code in my project and it's very simple
walk you through it you start off with a
regular expression and that's your start
state and then you sort of add your
start state to your set of states and
then you stick the state that the first
state on a stack and then you go into a
loop so you take a state off the stack
and you say okay for every symbol in my
alphabet let's take the derivative of
that state and that's a new state now if
I'm a C in that state before or I have
it if I haven't seen the state before I
add it to my set of states and in any
case I add a transition because I found
a new way to get to that state and I run
that loop and at the end I've got a
state machine
I work out which states can be accepted
because they're those states that are
novel and the error state the one where
nothing is getting or is of a state that
is the null station and that is it
that's really cool you can produce a you
know deterministic finite automata from
a regular expression with that code
there's only one problem remember that
bit in my code that said for every
symbol in the alphabet well únicos got a
lot of symbols so you'd be running
through some pretty big loops so that's
no good so the second thing that kind of
makes his soul approach cool is rather
than do that you create derivative
classes and what these really are is
rather than go through every
in the in the alphabet you can work out
pretty much which letters are important
which letters are not important we call
these classes so looking on the right
there if we've got the regular
expression a there's only two letters
that are really there's only two sets of
letters that are really important there
one is a letter A which is obviously
important about expression and the other
thing that's important is everything
that's not an A and so we only need to
really do two derivatives if we're
trying to you know go for that algorithm
for for very regular expression a and
similarly if you've got the example
there where you've got well I've got a
bunch of examples here we don't have
time but there's a set of rules again
you can easily program them that's
probably the important thing so now we
can handle Unicode which is nice the red
is the change in the algorithm rather
than go through every symbol in the
alphabet we just go through every state
every class in our derivative classes
and we take the derivative of it we can
take any symbol out of the derivative
class and use that to generate the next
state so it's really that simple so now
we can you know handle large alphabets
which is nice and this is the last and
perhaps coolest thing rather than do
this for one regular expression we can
run this algorithm over a victor of
regular expressions over a list of them
and that means and that's very simple we
just if you want to take the derivative
of a vector of regular expressions it's
just at the riveted of each vector so
you know that that's another state for
us and then the same thing with the
derivative classes we just intersect
them all it's a very simple idea but now
we could take a whole bunch of regular
expressions and we can turn them into a
single DFA and this is exactly what we
need if we want to do tokenization so
let's go and see what it looks like in
Python and so when you want to implement
this stuff in Python is a few key
decisions you've got to make um how do
you represent these large sets of
symbols so you know you've got if you're
doing in Unicode you've got lots of
symbols how do we represent regular
expressions how do we compare
expressions for equality because
remember we need to see if we've seen
the same state before and how do we be
able to scan it from all this so larger
symbols it's pretty interesting this
this is important to get right because
it's right in the guts of the code and
fix the efficiency the easiest ways just
represent you know as a disjoint ordered
intervals so in the case here a to 0 a 2
0 0 9 you can just represented their
code points as like a couple a couple of
tuples and this is kind of cool because
now you can test the membership using
bisect which is in the standard Python
library and that's law and login and
Union intersection and differences can
be implemented as order in algorithms
which is cool it's really tempting to
subclass the collections ABC set which
is you know standard Python 3 to pretend
you've got a set of integers but as it
turns out that's a really bad idea and
it all comes down to hash we need to put
our sets in two sets of sets which means
we need hash if you remember that in
that previous algorithm we had sets of
States and the standard hash requires
you the standard hash argument requires
you to iterate over every element so
that's really slow if you've got lots
and lots of images in a set so so be
subclassed couple instead and make it
look a bit set like we could actually
ignore the requirement that hatches has
all sets with the same members is
supposed to hash to the same hash but I
didn't want to do that so that was a bit
tricky and to represent the sets so
sorry to represent the expressions we
just create a class hierarchy so we
created a expression class and then we
subclass it to have a lot of different
types of operations and that means that
we can then easily build our expressions
as trees
so here's a visit expression and you
know here's the tree that comes out of
it so we just you know pars the
expression and produce a tree it's
pretty standard and the last thing I
think that was tricky as I said before
was how do we compare these sets this is
actually interesting and so what we do
is we try to always produce the
expression trees in a canonical form
okay this is called a weak equivalence
so we always try and produce them in the
same canonical form and by doing that we
can just compare them by comparing the
trees structurally and if the trees are
the same structurally it's the same
regular expression and answer there's a
bunch of rules again that we can
implement pretty easily but a real-life
example of this we use a smart
constructor we used in you instead of in
it and we'll the reason we use near
which most people don't use in Python is
because we don't always want to create a
new object sometimes when we're being a
smart constructor we want to return an
already existing object or a different
type of object what we thought we were
constructing and so that's what we're
doing here in the concatenation operator
where we're checking to see if the left
side is a concatenation if so we just
reorder things there's always the same
structure and then we have a bunch of
checks to see how is the left side now
well then the answer's no is the left is
the right side no the answer's no we
don't need to actually create a tree at
that point so we go for a bunch of tests
like that and then we actually construct
the object at the bottom so you was
really kind of cool for things like this
and if you didn't know it existed it's
worth going and looking and seeing how
it works
and finally we can build a scanner I've
got two minutes now we can build a
scanner and it's really very very simple
once you've got the DFA you basically
run through your symbols in your text
and you run through until you get to a
point where you can't match anymore
where you get to the arrow state and
then as you've run through you've
remembered if you've seen any accepting
states and if you did seeing this if the
acceptance state what you do say well I
found
I'll return it and then I'll rewind back
to where that token was and I'll start
again and so you don't go through the
DFA just once to tokenize you have to go
through you know one time for each token
and this is the basic approach and but
again it's not much code is very very
simple so a simple example of the code I
built here's the input you can define
letters and digits here which start with
an underscore because we don't actually
want tokens from those they're fragments
but then we can put them together into
you know four different types of tokens
and all the things on the right of
course our regular expressions so we
type that in and then we put it through
the tool that I built and you get a DFA
which of course you can't see but it
looks very pretty from a distance
there's a lot of detail there and then
obviously you can run that in linear
time and it supports Unicode a slightly
larger example I took a Pascal lecture
from the internet and ran it through
flex and it came up with a hundred and
seventy four states and my tool which is
called epsilon produced 169 States so
roughly the same so it seems to work so
as I said the tool is called epsilon BAM
it's up on github and beta testers and
contributors are welcome there's a bunch
of stuff not done yet I need to do start
conditions which is something that flex
supports that I don't support yet I'm
gonna this generates different code you
can generate different code targets so
I've got Python and dot for
visualizations at the moment but I don't
have C so I need to generate a C target
the actual regular expressions are
pretty close to perl with a few extra
features so that's kind of where it's at
and again I very much welcome any
contributions I'm so ignore events
epsilon was directly inspired and based
on the work of Owens Rypien Chiron who
are referenced and of course without the
work of Brazil ski none of this would be
possible
thank you very much and I think we've
exactly run out of time so any questions
I'll take later thank you very much
[Applause]