okay my name is Hartmut I'm from
Bielefeld Germany I studied computer
science uh electric engineering and a
little bit of biology there and I've
been using OpenStreetMap for a little
bit over a decade now and in my day job
I worked as a database support engineer
for Maria DB and formerly from I school
but it is not related to today's talk at
all so what I'm going to talk about is
the map Nick rendering library and how
to use it from pison so what map Nick
does it is the rendering library that
for example renders the map parts you
see an Open Street Map but you can do a
lot of both other things so it can
process a lot of different input formats
can produce a lot of different graphics
formats this output and it uses specific
style information to do so and as it is
a library and not a standalone program
it also needs a little bit of extra
wrapper code to really make you do what
you want it to do so first on the input
side we can read several different map
data formats like shape files which is a
specific geospatial file format or we
can read geospatial data from different
databases mostly posters but also the
case data that Maskull mariadb can
provide and also what spatialite so
spatial enabled version of SQLite can
provide ant we can natively use geo JSON
files
also via plugins we can read further
file formats like the native
OpenStreetMap XML format GPX tracks and
why are the detail library different a
raster image formats like satellite
images and stuff like that and on the
output side we can produce PNG bitmap
images in high or low calorie solution
that's the usual use case for map tiles
as you see them on besides like Open
Street Map and other websites that use
Open Street Map data but we can also
produce jpg which is not the optimal
format but can give you better
compression rates in file size isn't if
you we can produce scalable vector
graphics that can for example use in
Inkscape or other vector drawing
programs to first process the generated
maps or we can for printing produce PDF
or the classic PostScript is also still
available and styles so though we need
style information to specify which
inputs objects from the input data
stream should look how in the output
image there are two ways to do that one
is to really use the map Nik library
functions to define a style information
on the go step-by-step
that's very flexible but also takes a
lot of effort so as an alternative we
have a style file format that is a
special XML format that is more compact
and more easy to use but not as flexible
as if you could decide in your code
depending on certain traditions which
styles to use
but the typical use case is to use XML
start and there is a rich collection of
different styles for a bitmap publicly
available and we can also convert some
other map stylesheet vomits especially
the cart of CSS form it into the XML
format that is needed by an APNIC so
street map for some years now actually
uses car to CSS styles converts these to
map make XML on the fly and then renders
the map darts with that and it's already
set map Nick is a library so we need
some extra code to tell it what to do
and for that as it is a C++ library we
have the option to do that directly in
C++ well that's complicated can easily
crash so as an alternative we have good
pies and bindings and that's what I'm
mostly going to talk about in the rest
of the talk and there's also now some
experimental bindings for PHP 7 but
these do not support the full range of
mapping capabilities yet if you want to
use map and a comparison together you
obviously need
Python it doesn't matter if you want to
use PI's in version 2 over 3 the
bindings for both just the author go to
different APNIC versions around still I
only used method 3 the current one but
some Linux distributions may still come
with the version 2 libraries and if you
want to add additional stuff to other
generated images beyond that welcome
APNIC renders itself you also need the
cairo bindings for Pisan and maybe a
libraries for SP 3 and 4 for handling
that's what the Pangu
years so on counter boon to this would
be the packages if you need you need the
parson 3 in APNIC bindings if they
haven't installed my Python 3 or map
Nakia these will be installed
automatically and you may need the pango
font handling you may if you want to put
additional SVG images on top need Rs 50
bindings the general ttk introspection
package to make the other tube work so
Paula metric data sources like shape
files or database bindings produce a
data stream that comes as 4 kinds of
different objects simple points
one-dimensional lines two-dimensional
polygons that cover areas or predefined
raster images they may look different in
the actual data source but that what is
what the input API then provides to the
further stages of the library inside map
Nick we have three main different kinds
of objects that is layers styles and
symbolizes the layer is what the what
the data to base our datasource provides
this data so if you use a shapefile it's
everything that is in the shapefile if
you use the database it is what is good
used by the actual database query you
bind to a layer
then we have styles styles commute zoom
and everything that is in a layer and
decide how to actually display these
data items and we have symbolizes
symbolizes are the things that actually
do the work of painting so the simple
stripe behalf is the point simple Iser
that either just draws a point the
certain position or it draws a given
image that you can specify by our point
of interest I can for tops or for gas
stations or whatever you have then we
have the line it symbolizes the draw
lines in different styles so for example
if you want to draw a road you may want
to draw it in yellow and have small
small earth small black lines at the
side to distinguish them from the
background that's what the lines
symbolize I can do then we have the
polygon symbolized that draws and fits
areas in a given color and style we have
the raster symbolize it that just puts a
raster image data from the input side
into the output side and we have some
more sophisticated symbolizes like the
marker symbolizes our can be repeated if
it is used on line or polygon data
whereas the point is just as the fix for
it
we have aligned pattern symbolizing but
is similar to the Marcus of Mars of them
use it on the line but there's the
marker symbolize of the marker image is
always up right and there's the line pet
and symbolize er
it follows the direction of the line so
lines symbolize er is used for example
when you want to draw one by rote which
has these little one-way arrows on it
that would draw the line in certain
style and then put little arrows or
symbols on top if text symbolizes to put
text on the map usually helpful if
things have names on my map
we have special markers in Milazzo
called shared symbolize er that is used
for high VIN numbers and stuff where
depending on the text in the marker the
Marcus size has to be extended and it's
called shield symbolizes because the
highway signs on the US highways look
like ancient light shields
we have polygon patterns symbolized that
is if you want to fill a polygon not
just with a certain color but with a
certain repeated pattern like a maps you
often have our forests in green and
little tree symbols in there so you
would have one symbol that has the
background color and one tree in it and
it's just repeated to fill the polygon
and we have building similar that sort
of loss SOI to 3d buildings by taking
the building height into account so now
let's go to the bison part and start
with the simplest example you can have
you just import the map neck bindings we
create a map of 600 pixels wide 300
pixels high and we render the map to a
file
file name.for PNG format PNG and
obviously there is nothing in it yet you
just get a 300 per 600 pixel image with
transparent background so let's add a
little bit to it first we give the map a
background color steel blue here then we
define a polygon symbolize er the only
style information we give it is fill all
the polygons you see in green and we
have to set up style rule that binds to
the symbolise er you have to register
the style rule here under the name of
countries in the map and then we define
a layer named world and that has a data
source that is a shape file that
contains all borders of all countries in
the world then we add that Malaya to the
map we do a zoom all that zooms in on
all the data we have on the map so that
is the map is exactly as large as it has
to be to draw all data we specified and
again we run it into a file arms now
obviously something so we see all the
countries in the world and we also see
the borders even though I didn't specify
any border style that's actually an
artifact as the polygons symbolize it as
an tile izing on the borders so that is
what's producing the the borders here we
will turn that off in the next example
so the style rules can also filter on
the input data now if you want to have a
map of alt map that has Germany standing
out we can add oh yeah first of all we
take the symbolized from the last
example and put analyzing factor to 0 to
get rid of all these border artifacts
look just the rule so now we create a
second symbolize object I'll say okay
this one is going to be filled in rat
and we set up a second rule and this
rule gets a filter so it filters by
expression by the name by the field is
named name in the input and the name
should be Germany I'm done we draw it
again and we have the map now without
the border artifacts but we have Germany
standing out in red so that was the
working in doing it in Python only and
let's now look at the XML version that
is much shorter as all it does is to
load the world XML file here zoom in on
the data again and to render into the
PNG file the map XML looks like this
starts with a map tag we can give the
background color we have the polygon
style that only fields every country in
green you have the second one with the
filter for Germany but fields in red and
we have a layer that uses the star we
defined above it uses the country
shapefile again and obviously or
hopefully yeah produces the same result
now forward using symbolizes in detail I
have created two simple geo JSON files
that are values now so instead of the
shapefile I used for all the borders and
I'll use example one GU Jason now only
have a very simple point symbolized
there just puts a single simple point
PNG image on the point position this is
here's a trace and file for this just
containing two points so we get a map
that doesn't really look like a map but
only has two points on it we can do the
same for jason containing a line this
line also has extra property name which
is test read here giving you slightly
more confused
complicated symbolize ur so first we
need a slightly more complicated rule so
first we use a line symbolize ur it just
says paint the line in blue and with the
stroke width of three pixels or three
points actually and then we use the text
symbolize ur that has placement line is
text should be along the line just given
a font name and it's given a fill color
and a halo fill that will we would see
in the example that looks like so this
is all simple tests treat just the blue
line we use the black text on it and the
halo is the slide
white shadow along the letters so that
they stick a bit more out from the
background so even if the text would be
painted on black background it would
still be visible then there are the
other symbolizes our already mentioned
described here once again then finally
you may want to decorate your map so you
know don't only want to have rendered we
solved but you also want to have a title
on it a copyright notice on it or stuff
whatever you can think of and for this
we can combine the map Nick my earnings
and the Cairo bindings in Pisan as map
Nick can use two different render
Beckett's one is the library called a GG
that is only used for high quality
bitmaps and it can use the Cairo library
both for bitmaps and for all the vector
formats so for SVG PNG epic SVG PDF and
PostScript and so here we do not give it
a file name right away but we first
define Kairos our first that has the
file name then we create a Cairo drawing
context then we set up our map as we did
before but now instead to writing to a
file we render to the Cairo context and
then we can use that context and put
extra things in there like here simple
rectangle so the two dots are from our
geo basin map rendered pan-ethnic and
the rectangle is from - Cairo we can
also use that for putting extra images
in our map like here our compass rose
that will just tell us where to north on
the map or we can use the same for text
and so in summary we now have a solution
that can render us a base map like here
you could put the last title on top you
couldn't pull it a copyright notice on
the bottom this special case is a
neighborhood error map of my area where
live
it's not very well visible but the extra
markers here on the map and these
markers have numbers and corresponds to
the list on the right so if you look for
the nearest nose or nearest
hospital you know it is in square F 9 or
if you see the marker here and want to
know what it is if he could see the
number in here it would be a 3 and he
could look it up on the index on the
right to find what is market 3 there is
also a JavaScript front-end for that so
you can produce this kind of map as PDF
yourself on the URL of Bob actually this
all stems from a solution called map
asthmatic that is also a web front-end
for creating maps from which I got all
the knowledge for this and that is used
to either print single page large format
PDFs where is the speed and mix it on
the side or you can also use it using
the PDF our context Akari Oh to produce
multi-page PDF maps like here are the
first pages of a little atlas put
Liggett so you have a title page you see
which area is on which detail page and
then there are 60 detail pages behind
this that form and actually little town
Atlas so what I learned working on this
is code-wise it turned out to be easier
than I thought at least as long as you
use XML styles and not the programmatic
starts there's always the devil in the
details and in the style it never looks
like you want to in the first try it is
a very flexible solution if you want you
to mix mapped render map data and custom
and the data custom image decorations
and unfortunately what almost also found
is the documentation of mattnic and
APNIC parts and bindings is not optimal
okay thank you
I also have to sample prints in here but
I think we ran out of time so if you
want to see them you could do that
outside
any quick questions yeah yes I left that
out because of the time slot was too
short
I have conversion code for converting
pixel coordinates into map coordinates
and the other way around using the map
NIC map object one more maybe look okay
outside
[Applause]