in my today's talk I'm going to describe
the scalability options to you hurt in
Mongoose I am so that you can build the
systems which can be more performant and
serve more traffic few few words about
me first and most of all I am happy
husband to an wonderful woman and happy
father to a three years full of life
daughter I also happened to be a senior
software engineer at the airline
solutions I'm there for six years and
the majority of the time I spend on
building different messaging systems
they were based on mangoes and the XMPP
and also I was and I am still heavily
involved in developing mangu Zion I also
like running and currently I'm preparing
to marathon in April hopefully I will
make it today's agenda first I will in
short describe Mongoose I am how many of
you does know Mongoose I am alright not
that many
so this slide will be I think helpful
for you then I will go through some
scalability considerations what we need
to think about when we are planning how
to scale systems and then I will
describe three steps three major
scalability options you can have in
magazine all right so what's what's
Mongoose I am if you know XMPP then you
you may know that example that Mongoose
is most of all XMPP server it's written
in air lank but these days
Mongoose I am it's not only XMPP server
we rather call it a platform because we
also have other components we are right
writing them in elixir they are
standalone components for push
notifications
this is Mongoose push open source
standalone component you can take and
use without Mongoose I am if you want to
with a penis or fcm also we have
Mongoose ice this is Stan turn server to
set up your audio video course this is
also written in Alex here and you can
use it just alone if you if you need we
also contribute to XMPP client libraries
for Android that's Mac and for iOS
that's XMPP framework and because of all
these parts and contributions we we call
Mongoose now a platform because we are
not focused only on the XMPP server but
we are adding components around it to to
provide better but the weather service
for our users and customers and getting
back to the point of my presentation
today what I'm going to say next may be
a bit of disappointing for someone of
you but for me I think that's actually
quite good
every man who just installation I I was
involved was unique this means that the
the users were behaving a bit different
there was there were different machines
so the hardware world different every
every installation was unique and having
that said I mean that there is no silver
bullet which you can use to scale every
messaging system there are of course
some patterns which I will describe
there are some things you have to have
in mind when scaling the system but
every every installation will be unique
and maybe a bit different so you better
monitor your service and see how it
behaves so that you are prepared and
know when to scale up when thinking
about scalability we need to consider
first of all the machine power which is
CPU memory i/o bandwidth and not only we
these days have mostly mobile clients in
our services and they are
frequently disconnecting and
reconnecting to the server which has its
impact on the server it and they are
completely different than web clients
where we have a persistent connection
for a long time so the scalability
options is a bit different for web
clients or desktop clients than for
mobile clients also the features which
are enabled and used on the server have
very big impact on the performance and
scalability in the simplest case we have
only one to one chat which is I I can
say the easiest to scale but then we can
have group chat we can have many
presences because the roster is big
there can be many pops-up nodes which
also makes the scalability harder and
needs to be properly load tested and
monitored and also the database usage if
the database is slow our performance is
also getting down so we may need to
charge users or schedule a depart scale
the database appropriately and talking
about scalability we can also describe
these free limitations about database I
already told the first and most in all
cases the first limitation is memory the
memory is our limit how many connected
devices users we can have on a single
node then this is CPU if we have enough
memory but our users are very talkative
then we are using almost all CPU power
for example and this can be our limit
here are the three free steps I talked
about you can have in when scaling
mangos first you can start with single
note then we go with the castor of notes
but sometimes in when the user base and
the popularity of the service is weak
enough the cluster may not under the
traffic as we want and we have to go
beyond the cluster alright starting
small with single note we since Mongoose
am is written in Erlang we model all our
users devices around processes this
means that every connected device has
two or three processes depending on the
encryption if it is terminated on one
goes or somewhere before one goes and
thanks to a long vm scheduler all the
course on your machine are utilized
equally so all the users are spread on
all course of of the Machine and when
putting more resources to the single
machine we can have better capacity we
can fit more and more users on the
single know a single note installation
has its advantages first of all it is
very easy to get started we provide the
docker images mode for every pull
request so even if you want to have a
new feature which is still under
construction but you want to test it you
can take the docker image for this put
request start the container and try the
new feature or build your application
quickly with starting just this one note
single note is good for small
installations when we have little users
it is easy to manage easy to monitor
because we have only one no too
after and it is also easier to debug
when some things go wrong with your
client code or with the server code you
have only one note to trace but this has
two major disadvantages first of all
this is single point of failure and we
never recommend to go on production with
single note even if you have little
users and you will feed all your users
in single note this is still single
point point point of failure and in case
when the the note is restarted you will
not have any backup and also which I
think is maybe not that obvious
single note installation especially on
staging on pre prod environments makes
things harder to prepare for production
of course in I know if there is any
staging or pre prod environment which
can simulate the production traffic
probably not but when you have your
staging with more than one note you
learn how to monitor how to debug the
system which is which consists of more
than one note in this case you have
users connected to many different notes
and you you you need to learn how to how
to debug things and it's better to do it
on staging then on production when you
realize that something might go wrong
and going beyond single note there is a
cluster of notes in this case users or
devices can be connected to any of these
nodes and messages will be routed
between these nodes so they reach the
destination even if the user is
connected to some other node than the
device from which the message is sent
and to build the Mongoose iron cluster
we leverage the Erlang distribution
layer which by
gives us fully connected network of
nodes so every node in the cluster knows
about every other node in the cluster so
the routing is very efficient we when we
have a message to user connected to
other node we know exactly where the
user is so we can send the message
directly to this node where the TCP
connection is and the information about
users is shared between users between
nodes in fact it's replicated thanks to
initial database and the tables kept in
RAM when new session appears in one of
the nodes it is secretly replicated to
all other nodes so that we we are always
up to date with the session information
considering Mongoose and cluster
installation and preparing for failures
we need to make some room on the on
every node for example if we know that
we have I know
16 gigabytes of RAM then we should have
enough left memory to handle a crashed
node or when we for example want to
restart now to upgrade the system we
need to have the capacity on the
remaining nodes to handle the traffic
which was on the just stopped node in
one more thing on production
installations all the persistent data
it's better to be kept in external
database like my sequel or Postgres ryuk
even if you want because keeping
persistent data in my sequel doesn't
make clustering easier in some cases the
node may be may take too much time to
restart because it has to sync all the
data from disks on different machines
that's why we do not recommend to to
have persistent data in Indonesia all
the RAM tables are fine they are
replicated just without issues
so this can be easily used as you may
expect cluster installations have their
limitations first the first limitation
is size of the cluster since we have
fully connected network of nodes this is
on one hand a benefit when we have I
know up to 10 nodes but when we go
beyond around 15 notes the fully
connected Network may start with a
bottleneck when it comes to replicating
data to all other nodes in the cluster
and when we have three clusters big like
that we might start thinking about going
beyond a single cluster also another
limitation may again be database we may
be serving the users fine routing
messages without too much latency but
the database may be just too too pushed
to its limits and maybe we could we
should start thinking about charting
charting the users between many
databases also another another
limitation may be a latency in in single
cluster we have we have the cluster in
one data center for example in Europe
but the latency for European users is
fine they connect in milliseconds but
when we have users in USA for example or
in Asia then it may take a bit longer
for them to connect to the cluster and
then we have to go beyond the cluster in
this case we form different clusters
possibly on different continents if you
want to reduce latency but what should
be used to communicate between these
clusters and as in many cases in
computer science it depends it depends
on two major
things first of all if we can chart
divided users between these two or three
data centers and if we need to allow
users to connect to any data center for
example to have lower latency if if we
want to charge users between different
data centers we can simply use XMPP
Federation this is this works similarly
to email you have you may have email
accounts at Gmail at hotmail and you can
send emails between these two email
providers and this is very similar with
XMPP Federation when you have different
domains you can address messages to
users connected to to these different
domains but in this case users has to be
bind to a data center if you if we
register a user on a given data center
it will always have to connect to this
one and it will never be moved to close
on location there is another option if
we need to allow users to connect to any
know any custom in the database we can
use a new feature of mongoose a.m. which
is the geo distribution this is an axiom
this is a federation but a bit smarter
in this case all the data centers or the
clusters serve the same domain but the
information the session and routing
information is replicated between data
centers using Redis with a dynamo
dynamite from Netflix replication layer
this this is already in Mongoose am
master branch which you can take and
test we still consider this experimental
as it works with only for the basic
features like message routing session
management some move services and
external components persistent data is
not yet replicated so your roster or
weaker
will not be easily replicated between
clusters but we are working on this and
we we want to we want to release mangoes
I am free all around with April and this
this geo distribution will be the main
feature of the next release that would
be all I wanted to say thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
we will never stop supporting the XMPP
Federation yeah oh okay so you're
suggesting to use only this geo
distribution instead of the regular
clustering yeah no i yeah
the difference is you can have efficient
airline clusters in one data center when
nodes are close to each other but when
you have to form cluster between
continents along distribution layer is
not to fit for that so we will still
have these two