oh wait we're gone either yeah what an
hour please yeah I'm a Leo I'm from
Albania I'm designer at uni unnis
Network measurements censorship tool at
the Tor project so you can use it to see
if there's any website blocked in your
region or country I'm also a member at
the open labs hackerspace in Tirana and
yes I met yan and a few other
open-source designers like two three
years ago and Wow there exists something
like open source design I thought like
this wouldn't be possible so this is
when I joined and like just one year
later I started which which is our own
agency with open source design values so
the story was that two years ago we we
were organizing a conference in Albania
and our designers and media sponsors
were asking us hey can you send us the
logo can you send us a via email and it
was very tiresome for me personally
because I was doing that myself and I
was like exporting SVG's EPS into JPEGs
pngs into all different formats and it
became very tiresome for me and I I met
a guy who was like having this service
it was called Randy's died and it was
proprietary but we liked it because like
you could like host your own logos and
in EPS or PDF and convert it into any
size you like and you basically just
give the link to any any of your
sponsors or whatever designers and they
they can download it
do whatever they want with them it was
pretty expensive it was like $240 a year
or something $300 like that and yeah
they sponsored us and I was like
thinking yeah this is very useful but it
was proprietary software and like one
day I got a newsletter half a year ago
and they said like hey Brandis I was
being acquired by Brent AI so we are
changing our roadmap and blah blah blah
okay yeah kind of expected its
proprietary software right and because
of this change I was like thinking we
need to have something like that which
is actually open source and well it
doesn't depend on any acquisition or
company changing its faith of the
software and funnily enough just a few
months after we decided to build a new
open-source software to do that and even
more than that envision is buying
Brandis tea and is killing it off and
next month in March
Brenda C will be dead and it will not
exist anymore so anyone who uploaded
stuff on there they will not be able to
use it so it was like the best decision
we did to actually do an alternative to
that so um yeah
enter identity up which is it's
basically solving a similar problem so
what you can do with identity up is that
you have a project for example in our
case it's Firefox where we also do to
have an open design community as in
Mozilla and you can basically host all
your icons here as SVG files so you
don't have to deal with any different
formats you just upload your SVG files
and identity app is taking care if you
want to do conversions if you want to
embed them it's working as a CDN so what
you can do here is for example I go to
the Firefox logo and yeah I want the SVG
source file
or I would just want to link to the SVG
source file so what you can do here is
actually get the embed link and put that
every anywhere you want and later on you
can update the exact SVG file here and
it gets updated everywhere so we can
basically do a rebranding of your
project in the future without uploading
new logos new visual assets everywhere
of course it's automated so we probably
need to check manually a bit but it's it
saves you a bit of time as well and
right now you can also specify if you
want the SVG in any paint PNG resolution
for example right now we have a 500
pixel PNG resolution so let's say for
example 300 you can add that as a size
and download it right away so just
download at the same logo for me in a
300 pixel PNG so this has the advantage
that if you go to all this media kits on
different websites of project they give
you a huge dip folder with SVG PNG
folders and different formats different
color sets so this would save it because
this would save time for a lot of people
because there was a single source of
truth and it's SVG and yeah if you want
different flavors you basically go here
instead of just packing it into a source
file into as a package the advantage of
SVG is is because it's basically HTML
and web compat compatible code so it's
also code which is friendly for
developers but it's also vector which is
well what designers use going further on
identity up because we had a nice talk
about fonts we decided also that we
should be able to also support fonts so
right now we only have support with
google fonts this is gonna be expanded
with custom fonts later on what
you can view right now is that you can
add a font by simply searching it on
from google fonts so your font is source
stands for example you can select it
here and select all the weights you want
to use you wanna well your brand
represents and they're being added here
automatically so this is just a preview
so if you want to download the font it
fetches it from google fonts and you can
just download it right away here as a
source file
TTFN or OTF same goes also for the
colors right now we have a color palette
of the new Firefox UX and whatever color
you need you get the you get the hex
code here soon we're gonna have also the
CMYK specification if you want to use it
for print and yeah I bet it it's pretty
self explainable you can also customize
it in a way of a style guide so right
now we have different sections here a
section for every Firefox brand what you
can do is that you can just rearrange
them in if you want to have different
different and and fast emphasizing or
different subsections at all you can
also use a description to explain what
how you should you be using this logo
theoretically you can also add it and
what not to do section if you if you
care about that as well in the in the
last section we also have general images
which is photos so you can just put any
PNG or jpg as a source file so to speak
so if you have a team photo and you want
to represent your team with that photo
you can put it up here and in the same
way as with SVG it gets converted
automatically to whatever you need of
course it's not vector so you cannot
upscale it
yeah @nd app is free software so if you
so I'm typing here in real time so if
you want to contribute to it it's a it's
licensed under a GPL so it's a even more
hardcore than GPL thank you thank you so
it's written in react.js in the front
end and laravel PHP in the back end but
most of the code as well in front end
and the idea behind it is not like a
fancy hey you can host your brand over
here but it's mostly like dues to serve
as a base for collaboration between
designers and developers how you might
say this would be possible is because
like SVG is the key word here as it's a
something used by both designers and
both developers we where we are planning
to do integration with github so we can
basically have your github repo and your
identity app project page sync together
so whatever your update on identity app
will serve as a front-end to be updated
into your github repo and ideally also
the other way around
so designers who are like allergic to
get can use ident yeah well well people
and developers who like mostly CLI kind
of stuff they can use it right from the
get to ePub and with the update function
of SVG's you're gonna actually version
control as VG's so you can basically
visualize how asset is changing visually
for designers and because SVG's code
actually developers can also see all the
differences and change sets in the
github repo so this this is well the
vision it's not reality please don't get
too too excited about that but the
vision is for developers and designers
to collaborate furthermore together
because we have experienced it as big
problem of a gap on how we collaborate
and we hope that this will serve as a
basis for further collaboration and
empathy and getting on the same platform
because right now teaching designers how
to use git and github is it's a nice
ways of way of working together but gate
is not not really the best visual way of
working so we hope to to create a bridge
it's funny because remains bridge and
obeying the bridge between gate and
visual aspect of design work so people
can work on that of course there will be
also user management so you're gonna
have a project you can get different
access to different people so you don't
need to manage it yourself and also
we'll have web dev integration I hope
towards the end of the year if you are
not helping if you are helping with
might be sooner but that depends and so
a young is working at next cloud so we
hope that with next log we can have a
web dev integration and so news your
next annex cloud folder to have your
assets and get synced in real time yeah
that's basically it
we have different issues on the github
repo we have also a roadmap post it we
hope to release the stable version in
May and right now we have demo online
which you can already use just go to the
web side you can try it out if you are
losing your assets disclaimer it's not
your our fault it's very alpha yet so
please don't put anything critical on
there and yeah get involved into it in
the repo and we hope to see more action
going on here and to get this going on
until the end of the year thank you
[Applause]
questions yeah okay yeah we do actually
yes yes
so it was a question if we have a
business plan we are doing open source
design so we are we are pretty
transparent about it so this software
can be self hosted so you can hosted on
your own server we will be offering well
you can do it already now it's a bit
difficult we want to do it we want to
make it easier for people to self o sit
but if you don't want to if you don't
care about that and you just wanted to
make it work we will be offering a
service where you can just subscribe and
we will well you hosted on our servers
will there will be a free plan for basic
things and premium plans for more
advanced features custom domains and
stuff like that
but if you don't want to pay or you are
too careful you want to care about your
own stop on your own server you can just
self hosted yep
that's yes that's not specified yet for
the servers we will be using but for the
demo servers it's in Frankfurt right now
we are yeah we didn't want to do it in
the US
face formats what if your organization
still wants CMYK that's a good question
actually we didn't address that yet
sorry if there's how will we be adding
CMYK support into identity up in the
future if it's SVG was a question that's
a good question actually and we didn't
address it yet but I guess in the future
once the priority is there we you can
just edit manually so you basically have
in the uploader you'll upload the SVG
and you upload also the CMYK it's kind
of problematic if you will do s--
version control and so you probably need
to update it every time I'm not that
developer so it's kind of hard for me to
wrap my head around that but it's
definitely not a priority for this year
for now yep yeah I was actually actually
asking our developer about that and he
said like it's too much of an overkill I
don't know about that I'm a UX designer
but we feel ready want to offer all all
ways of installing installing identity
up on your own server in the beginning
as people were saying us hey you should
make it very difficult for people to
install it so they can come to you and
pay you but we didn't want to do that so
it should be your choice if you want to
install it on your own server darker
image will be coming soon just gonna or
later if you want to help probably
sooner any other question it's a it's
utilizing mice QL right now and I don't
I'm not sure for I don't think so but
yeah we we should do that I mean if we
have the manpower yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah I know there's three of my school
and my really be so probably are you DB
might be a better choice we will be
think about that thanks sorry yeah the
question was if some pages where if all
pages were public right in in the next
versions I think by May will have also a
feature where you can make pages private
with password protection or not or just
give access to different users so if you
are using it internally in your
organization just to share stuff within
your team member so you can do that as
well
in the future not right now but we are
planning on that it's one of the medium
priorities right now it's not as far as
I know of course you can contribute it's
got the Chris sorry the question was if
the user interface is available in
different language or like people can
contribute to do that it's kind of hard
for us because we are designers who are
trying to develop this and we are trying
to translate this vision to developers
who are helping us doing that and
sometimes it's hard to know what's
possible and whatnot but every help is
welcome seriously
we are very responsive on the issues if
you want to do something even if it's
not in our roadmap priority list blah
blah blah you should definitely do that
yeah what support was that our 3d models
the question was if we plan to support
3d models it was it was in the beginning
it was a great vision we had like to
have a marketplace for VR 3d models
which you can like put into your web VR
a frame thing kind of but I think it's a
bit too far fetched right now and yeah
we we probably want to do it if it's get
it's it's getting up to speed but
probably not in this year unless someone
is doing really much of work and yeah
but we don't have the manpower right now
yeah sure okay I guess the time's up
I'll be at the open source design booth
also with the other designers asked me
for stickers and I can show you the demo
life if you really want to use it
yourself so yeah thank you very much
[Applause]