my name is Tom today I'll be talking to
you about service why they can't be
trusted and how we mitigate that in
ettus Inc which is the project I work on
and this is you know you can find the
slides over there or on the force and
website you can scan the QR for to get
the slides and this is it let's jump in
so first of all let's look at like
simple server communication so like the
most basic thing how it looks like so
you have Alice the user publish uses TLS
or whatever variation and connects to
the server so everything is encrypted
and let's you know for the purpose of
this talk let's assume that everything
between Alice and the server is safe
there's no man in the middle although
this is actually a risk especially if
you use a company where laptop and they
stole a root certificate or anything it
is a risk but let's assume not let's
just only talk about the service today
and so let's start by that communication
what are we leaking when we do that so
first of all we have data we actually if
we use Gmail for example we lick the
emails we lick the calendars we lick we
leak any personal notes that we may have
our deepest secrets secret business
information and you know we're gonna
we're gonna do a minute like buy this
company or whatever
and also this is like what's usually
looked I mean as less important like the
metadata so the IP address which you
know if your government you can link it
back to AB certain person but at the
very least you can probably get location
information out of it a social graph so
who do I know who knows me group of
friends I'll cover that more in a second
time of access so when in the day I log
in so if I always log in or let's say
from 9:00 to 5:00 in London time I can
probably assume you know this is my
business hours I work in London I can
London so that also a lot of information
is leaked there and which data is used
and how often so for example we always
call a certain person you know that
person is a person of interest and
always open a certain file you know that
file like you just hacked my computer
and you want to know you saw like the
last and father used those are probably
more important than my book report from
6r8 and and again and when specific data
is accessed so for example if I have my
computer during work hours I opened this
doing after hour
I opened this so you know this is
personal information this is work
information there's a lot actually being
leaked there so let's look at some parts
in specific so let's look at exploiting
social graphs so we have a group of
people we know that we have four I don't
know rebels or whatever we're trying to
catch we already caught three of them a
CNE and now just looking at the graphs
like by who they know so let's assume
they all use signal choosers by getting
access to the signal server which signal
is usually I mean it's and to an
encrypted everything like best practices
but still because they leaked this the
social graph like who knows who we can
already know we can know that to be just
like you see by all the connections that
be is actually part of the group and we
all Chris you can see that D that we
actually never knew existed is also part
of that group so all of this by using
best practices into an encryption all of
that this is a leak and another example
actually I really live like giving is
exploiting access patterns I don't
remember which government agency was
that wrote a report about this but these
are two mobile phones and the graphs are
access times to the servers so like when
they essentially when they on so one of
them is a burner phone used by a spy and
the other one is a normal phone it's
very easy to see I mean it's a good idea
to turn your phone off because then you
can't be triangulated but you see you
still leak a lot of information now all
of a sudden you are target and if you're
a you're not a target your information
is no but you know you're not you don't
stick out and but you know this is all
like a bit theoretical so let's take it
to something more practical which I care
about let's talk about CalDAV air caught
up sorry so card of essentially is how
most information like most address books
nowadays are synced it's used by iCloud
next cloud on cloud everything with
cloud in the name essentially and and
it's a good you know it's a standard so
it's great it's interpretable supported
in every client but let's look at
roughly how it works so you have you
know Alice Bob share all of those are my
contacts you just have files on the
server in clear-text
with all of the contact information in
each one of them and so let's look at
how you know what stick there so first
of all all the address books in from
information so yeah i have if i hack the
server have
all the you know all the phone
numbers emails position in the company
relationship if you put it like I'm very
pedantic I have addresses I have
everything in my address book and IP
address obviously you're connecting to a
server and social graph because you can
see who which contacts I have and which
which contacts have me and what groups I
grouped them so if I had oh people that
work on enlightenment which is another
project I work on this is already gives
you a very good image of groups and time
of access obviously when access the
server and again which data like we
covered which data when do I use it and
everything so let's you know let's solve
some of them like it's not it's not a
big deal you can use tor to hide the
origin you know toy is not always
perfect because first of all it's a bit
slower nowadays a bit slower but also it
doesn't work with all services so
CloudFlare and another like other
services flag it because a lot of
spammers use it so it's you'll have
issues you have to fill in a lot of
CAPTCHAs while using the anything and
another thing which I don't know
actually if this is verified but I would
assume that every government agency
Flags you as a person of interest the
moment you store like it's it's easy to
detect and I'm sure they do it and but
it's not verified so don't take me go
and we can try to control the access
patterns so I think I don't remember if
it's true but I think satoshi nakamoto
the guy who did the or guy or guys or
girls or I don't know what combination
of things and did Bitcoin used to write
posts and emails like in different times
of the day so you can't know which
continent which country which everything
is from and another example of access
patterns is when another Bitcoin example
actually there really I don't know it
was a lot in the news is when the guy
behind Silk Road a Silk Road also it was
caught they were monitoring the server
and waiting for him to login and then by
just seeing this access pattern they
were waiting for him to unlock
everything that's encrypted so they
waited until logged in and then this was
enough of a queue for them to raise him
and and you know and go go after it and
this again another very easily that it's
obvious but we leaked and another
solution obviously is trusting the
server so using a trusted provider
I don't know Google or whatever we did
you trust Oh Austin your own obviously
the top the title of the of this talk
kind of means that I don't believe in
many of that and so should we even trust
the server it could get hacked and we
get a lot of hacks everything is hacked
nowadays and you know it's every server
is running a lot of complex software
with so many you know so many places for
you have issues and even at this thing I
don't even know how many dependencies I
depend on because I want you know I
wanted the Java like for the android
client when the Java Runtime librarian I
want probably some not Google stuff and
I don't know
I have JSON like passing Jason this so
such a big attack surface nowadays that
just assume you're going to get hacked
so it's better to protect them in it and
be proactive and it could get stolen
like literally someone to break into
your house if you have cell phones at
home still the hard drive and just steal
all your data again maybe it's not it's
not interesting for you but if you're a
high profile lawyer that does a lot of
high profile cases you are a target that
will get attacked and this is a real
threat and with hosted you can have
rogue and please so employees are
actually selling your data because
they're evil or I don't know why else
they would do that I mean maybe
compelled by a you know compelled by the
government or compelled by the Mafia or
whatever it's all of those risks that
exist and also when it comes to self
hosting and don't get me wrong I think
everyone should sell first it's a lot of
work you have to be a techie at least to
an extent to do it you have to make sure
that your fingers on the pulse with
making sure that you're always update
all of the you know the latest security
issues and all of that so it's a lot of
work and it's not that available so
hosted solutions I think are essential
to make a private internet or private
world and this is why again I try to
make sure to create to create a like an
environment where the server can be
trusted and we can use hosted solution
safely and so let's talk about reducing
service trust so first of all enter an
encryption like don't I mean I'm biased
but don't use a project that does not or
project or service that does not do
enter an encryption its
it comes with flaws but for example if
you lose your key all your date data is
gone this is why it's not mainstream and
everywhere but still you know there are
solutions to that as well
like escrow of keys like just end to end
is the bare minimum and you can do
mostly offline operation if possible so
let's go back to the card of example
let's assume I want to ride the web
client so normally how I would write it
you have a website you click on a link
open a certain page and what and when
that page will open it's requested from
the web service like want to see Alice's
contacts like click on Alex a la Alice
sorry the page is requested from the
server so the server knows I viewed
Alice another alternative would be to
write it's all in JavaScript and then on
the first the first time you visit the
website all of your contact list which
is probably if you're crazy one megabyte
which is less than my logo most likely I
mean in most or the JavaScript framework
it's really low compared to everything
else that you serve and then all always
access the data from local stuff from
the local storage from the local cache
and then you don't leak that information
so lot of solutions to make that
possible
and another thing and I put in a
question mark because you can fake
access patterns so you can for example
when you edit a contact you can fake
edit five others every time randomly so
you don't know which one you edited but
I'm sure I'm not a cetacean I'm not a
mathematician but I'm sure that with
enough statistic this I mean it will be
uncovered yes I don't know if this is
actually a sustainable solution and so
let's talk about Jardin card of so we
know we know the problems we know how to
solve them let's start solving them and
so first of all as you can see we now
use IDs instead of the names so
everything is secret we enter anyone
crypt all the data so nothing is visible
to the server and you can see which one
you know which one is changed or
anything like that but there are still
issues so I mean for example let's
assume I just you know finish this talk
I met actually just before I met Keller
Caleb we exchange contact information I
put it on now all of you including
whoever's seen it online knows that the
moment I see this file was created it's
Caleb like you don't need to know the
data but you know by the date of
creation and the fact that
on camera that it was added this was
this is enough this is enough and now
every time for example I edit it or I
call him and it updates the last time he
called you can see oh Tom called Caleb
it's like all of this information like
it's no obviously always encrypted it's
fine
no it's not fine because it's still
identify identifiable so it is a risk
and it's a risk that's not solved by
entering encryption just like that and
ok let's go
I mean this is it I mean you know like
we safe this is this all we can do but
it's not actually because we can do much
better and let's go at it so as I said
in the beginning our data like our
service service cannot be trusted so I
data can also be manipulated by the
server and let's look how so I don't
know if a lot of you do encryption but
like a basic example like a bad crypto
is encrypting but not signing or
encrypting but not doing any sort of
message authentication so let's look at
a crazy example which I mean it doesn't
exist in real life but like similar
existing examples do exist so I want to
have some access level storage in my app
let's I don't know why like I wanna this
is the people that my app automatically
support automatically will expose accept
requests to join a group I don't even
know why he does and so it's encrypted
so I know the server can touch it and
the the default level is zero zero so no
level but just by changing one bit or
whatever you want you can just scramble
alright give another encrypted chunk all
of a sudden like it changes to 19 like
the level since I can't control it I
don't know how to change it to be one
but 19 is already good enough especially
if you do boolean comparison so you do
true or false so I mean this is just by
being able to touch the data without
it's end-to-end encrypted I can't I can
see it this is enough to manipulate me
as a user like again this is not a real
problem because you just H Mac or like
use message authentication codes or
signatures to make sure no one does it
but this is a real problem
and let's look at another thing so we
have we have the are hardened card of
and I just added again a con
act or I just ended the to do item or I
just added a calendar event because
let's say I have a court hearing next
week I just added it and my adversary
like the people on the other side want
me to miss it obviously so they saw I
added it they hacked my server and just
omit this file I have no way of knowing
I mean everything again and to end
encrypted everything is safe but the
file is emitted there's no way for me to
know the file was emitted because this
is normal operation of course files get
deleted get added I add a contact I
remove a contact like so this is another
problem and again I can serve it can't
be trusted so this is easy to solve
you just verify the state so you do any
sort of signature or checksum with
message authentication code or whatever
and then every time this is changed and
I will get notified but again there's
another problem with that which is data
rollback so let's assume I had like I
just had a state that is valid just now
I added the contact now people want to
remove this contact all they need to do
is serve me again the old state before I
added the contact this is it so again
server no access to my data I'm signing
the whole state I'm making sure that the
state cannot be manipulated it's still I
can get attacked and which is again
don't trust your server
never and so the solution I came up with
and I mean it's not obviously it's not
me it's like built on top of like a lot
of work by a million of our people is
tamper proof journals so what it is
essentially is that instead of adding
files instead of adding contacts what I
do every time I add an entry and so for
example here I add Alice and then I
added Bob and then I realized that I had
a typo so I changed Bob and then I
deleted and this because we're not
friends anymore and all of this is just
like every time append only append only
so you can't really know which data is
which because everything looks like
actually let's jump to this like an
encrypted blob so this is how it
actually looks to the server you're just
like oh something happened something
happened something happened and
something happened that everything is
end-to-end encrypted so there's no way
for the server to know what happened and
also the server can't manipulate
everything anything
the UID is is every every idea of every
chunk on the block is a verification of
the contact in the previous block it's
essentially like get just encrypted
inside and so every time I try to remove
this I'll get an integrity or error if I
try to just switch them like change the
order again an error and all of this
protects protects from that and because
I can't remove anything I only append I
can on I can verify that nothing is
missing because if I added I added the
contact here and then I added a contact
on another phone so the server can
potentially just would not show me the
new edition they can show me trimmed the
log for me but then when I try to add
again on the other one it will get a
clash they cannot there's no way for the
for the data to be correct unless again
they they could diverge it completely
but then the server has to identify each
time to know exactly which is which
client which is a difficult task and ok
so let's go on so let's see how we
protect cells I said it's immutable so
data can only be appended no
modifications are allowed everything is
verified by the client every time like
it so every time you had an error with
get you would get the same error here if
a server was trying to manipulate your
data it's signed so it can't be
manipulated or faked
you know it's you and again preview of
these also signed so there's no omission
or reordering and every again like it as
you can see are very much like it and
everything is distributed among all
clients so let's assume the server and
this is something I didn't talk about
actually in the hard end card of let's
assume a server was hacked and
everything was deleted this is it I'm
like actually you know what I don't care
about him finding out I'm gonna delete
everything this is something you can't
protect about but if against sorry but
if everything is distributed to the
clients and every client does not say oh
it's missing on the server it means it's
deleted I should delete it here instead
they verify it so they so in the case of
mask Edition they would just not do
anything this clients and will heart
will be able to recover all of the data
from the clients themself and let's talk
about previously unsolved attacks that
were not solved in the card of case so
which data is accessed and modified
everything is done locally so there's no
no access
like no one cares about access and
modified you can't you know there's a
modification and but you don't know
which one because that part is also
encrypted so this is actually it's not
entirely true because for example you
can say you can analyze you some
analysis to know by the by this size of
the message so for example a contact is
probably one kilobyte but a calendar
event is maybe actually it's probably
the same size but like an image would be
much larger so you could do some
analysis to figure out what's what but
again like I said in the previous
example you can you can fake it you can
fake it and you can hide it and you can
you can create fake messages but it's a
way it's wasteful that the omission in
rollback we solved as I said and so
that's just like a few words about what
editing is and how it's used that like a
real real world example so essentially
it's that secure acting to an encrypted
and journaled obviously here's the
journal and personal information cloud
sync so essentially syncs you call that
contacts contacts and calendar among
your Android devices or web or and
there's also our CalDAV and card elf
proxy for the desktop so you can just
use Thunderbird or whatever use and yeah
I use it everywhere it's seamless on
Android so like you just used the same
apps you always use and it works like a
Google account essentially just encrypts
in the background and the journal format
is very simple you have the UID I
mentioned there like in every time every
like I change I snapshot again like it I
snap shut the whole format itself so all
of the calendar of it is snapshot every
time so even if I delete I have a latest
snapshot of what happened and another
nice benefit of this am is the change
journal so now I know this is like my
shirt reminders calendar so I know I
need to feed the cats go to supermarket
and then I all of us I can see like
someone edited this event and someone
deleted it data so I know that for
example my lazy flatmate decided to do
you know remove that task was associate
was that that we gave him to do and you
can really see who change what when when
he was changed and also obviously
recover lost data because if the event
was deleted now we can find all the
contact content that was there and also
which is super useful is finding entries
based on dates so
for example I met someone today added in
the contact list it's been two weeks I
want to send them I have no idea I
forgot the name I have no idea how to
find it I just go back is that Oh
when was that weekend yeah though it's
one of those three my party will
recognize by that by then this saved me
a handful of times yeah okay one more
sorry one more thing actually and then I
finish and his sign pages so as Caleb
said in the talk before one of the
biggest problems with serving JavaScript
is that you cannot trust the JavaScript
is actually really way it is because the
server serves the JavaScript which is
the app every time so a malicious server
for example could just serve you a
malicious piece of JavaScript that
sniffs all your passwords and steals
everything and you'd be none the wiser
and like Caleb I was looking for
solutions and I decided to write a
browser extension that essentially
verifies the PCP signatures of pages so
it's called signed pages devs signs the
web pages users add the public key the
expected public key for a page and the
page like the URL and and then the
extension verifies the signatures as you
can see this is a page with a good
signature a page with a bad signature
and obviously you have external
javascript in CSS so you probably want
to use sub resource integrity and for
all of those and that's already a
mechanism in the browser that's safe and
verifies all of that so essentially by
verifying the HTML that the main entry
point for your app you'll verify
everything and that's add the same level
almost the same level of security that
you get with native apps and in the
browser and in the future and we try
them like I'm working with Daniel
airborne IO which is like a Google Docs
and to an encrypted yeah is there and
we're trying to do it also for service
workers so you can have it in in
progressive web apps so absolute like
web apps that you just have an icon on
your phone because they're not verified
because there's no browser that to run
it yeah so this is it just to finishing
notes
I mean privacy is a sacred right don't
give it up and once you give it up you
give it up for everyone because then we
outliers that care about it are signaled
out and don't forget Oh supporting no
you're the weakest link so I mean this
is a famous xkcd comic like in the end
doesn't matter how much encryption you
use if
the end like someone hits you with a
wrench and tries to steal your password
so make sure if you have really
important information like double
redundancy so encrypted by multi Keys
like essentially there's a lot of thanks
to cryptocurrencies the relative
information nowadays about the advanced
crypto
so this is that and useful links if you
want website download at the sink yeah
and my blog sign pages a lot of
information there and no time
professions I assume I have time for
questions ok so yes question over there
by the way just some good awhile
attribution like course I took a few
icons from other places in the slides
that if you download them you can see
like and obviously the xkcd comic so
just for good measure back to this yeah
thank you so your journal appears like
you seen your file okay so the way it's
actually implemented its implemented or
in a database so just like add an entry
to the database and all the service can
see is the UID and an encrypted contact
content okay so what about scalability
have you tackled the issue and you
thought about AIDS
yeah so I don't I haven't something I've
never we know I never worked on a
company like Facebook Google that deals
with a million of users like I have no
idea how it will behave in this level
but at the moment like it's not even not
even bothering my server like it's not
there's nothing there and it just uses
normal SQL like you know it just like
you add entries there's nothing there
it's like and because I I rely on
existing technologies like so it's it's
not too dissimilar from get it's not too
dissimilar from that it's not it's very
similar to other things I don't see any
scalability issues arising essentially
any more questions yeah over that
since the data set is always appending
do you do you take care of trying to
make it smaller after using it for a
long time like if you add contact delete
contacts etc like after 30 years I mean
in 30 years I still want to have my
contacts encrypted so would the data set
ever increase and downing it on my
mobile phone may be become harder or
okay so I mean it's a good it's a good
concern and you know again I can Bitcoin
all of that there are solutions to that
it's an extent I think like I mean you
could die download only chunks of it and
verify those but to be fair its contact
information and calendar like I shall
enjoy to like get get to a gig even and
like by the time you get to a gig like
will have enough storage like it's
really not a concern like I don't see
how we'll ever reach a point that it's a
concern and I have a lot of users that
rewrite and change an ad and and still I
never reached anything that's even
scratching the surface like I think the
whole database is maybe maybe like two
hundred Meg's and not even actually not
even so yeah it's not a concern at this
point there's a fair question to the the
the increasing walk and not garbage
collecting anything the same time for
new clients so if for instance if you
have an email phone and you want to sync
all the contacts it has to go through
the entire walk right yes okay so need
to repeat the question so essentially
again like I challenge you like right I
don't know how many friends you have but
like I don't think you'll get to mount
in two thousand four thousand five
thousand modifications thousand thousand
whatever I know it's still not a problem
for a computer and anyhow all of this
the data the oldest size just gets to
less than a Meg which is again less than
an image on a normal website so it's
really not it's not a concern but with
that being said I have it's not really
implemented by a plan on doing like
helping with fun and journal trimming so
essentially let's assume I add the
contact and then I realized actually I
don't want anyone to know I added this
contact
so what I can do I can help you recreate
you know recreate a new journal you
can't change the river but create a new
one that does not include this data so
you can potentially trim it if you want
I actually have one question of it what
if you lose your phone and you buy a new
one and then you don't have you cannot
verify what's on the server you cannot
even access your data what's the plan
okay so first of all luckily for me it's
because like most of the problems that
usually associated with end-to-end
encryption actually solved because end
to end here means me to me so I don't
need to use any secret sharing or
verification of who you are identity so
I use am symmetric encryption so as long
as you remember your password it's not a
problem like you can install it on how
many phones if you remember the password
which you should I mean right down as
well like it's not you can always
recover it and that was the first part
discussion what was the second part oh
that was it that was it okay yeah so
yeah so that's solved and yeah okay
question does it still make sense to say
first I mean is if it's secure enough to
to use a service like a central service
for this kind of software yeah and so
you know you should trust me but like
you shouldn't said I got I wouldn't do
anything bad with your data but like you
never know so I mean if you think yeah
would you didn't know but I for example
I have IP like if you don't use tor I
can have your IP that's I don't have
access times but I can know for example
if you don't do delay edition I can see
when you added the contact and so like I
don't know it's a contact maybe you
change the calendar of it but I can see
when you touch your phone when you're
awake if that makes sense
I mean there's still some stuff but yeah
I mean my I don't think so I think you
should use like I don't think you should
sell phones I think it's too much
trouble and you're probably better off
just using the hosted version yeah so I
think we are thank you very much for big
round of applause for your presence
and thank you for making these deliver
success I've been many people very great
presentations you will find everything
online now it's the end but it means
also that we can stand discuss