thanks if you can't hear me shout
something so I tend to be pretty wordy
in general and also this is a rebated
version of a much longer like 40 minute
talk so I'm hoping that I correctly took
out the right things but I'll talk
really really fast just in case so the
topic is we have free web fonts what do
we do next and by that I mean we have
google fonts and we have open font
library there's a couple other services
like this that sort of have the same
idea behind them which is serving HTTP
web fonts usually open font licensed
there commercial services that do web
fonts - we're not talking about those
but yeah Who am I so you can tell by the
Alden gray and I bid that I'm been
around for a long time I for a long time
was a journalist working exclusively and
open source and I sort of did fun things
on the side and then I disappeared for
you and I came back just working on
typeface design and things now on to the
topic at hands we talk about those web
fonts services they're huge right
trillions of hits and that's little I
think I checked this morning and the
Google stats were just under 20 trillion
thoughts served those are all open fonts
to one degree another may be open source
maybe just an open license that's way
more than something like YouTube will
give you and those projects have
sponsored development of a ton of fonts
but the thing I want to point out is
that that's just true on the web which
means if you look at other areas where
people use fonts open fonts haven't made
nearly as big of an impact I think I can
prove that if you don't believe it in
just a couple of examples look at like
you
books epub is virtually the same thing
as HTML so you think it'd be easy to
make a dent there but if you look at
what actually ships and readers Amazon
Commission type basis custom for their
devices that's perfectly fine Barnes &
Noble if the Nook apparently didn't they
offer a lot more this is compiled from a
couple of different devices there's a
mostly mono type fonts and microsoft
fonts what's really surprising though is
the Kobo the Kobo is a really open
device it's not the lot you can side
load things on it but they still don't
have any interest in serving open fonts
on that the same is true if you go to
like print-on-demand you'd think people
uploading things you want to give them a
choice of typefaces you don't really
have much if you have a license for
something yourself you can upload your
PDF to Lulu or one of those other
companies and use it but if you don't
you fall back to a pretty small set of
things none of which are open poets
right and if you look at marketing
things I mean like wristbands and
t-shirts it's like that
you get virtually nothing but cheapo
freeware fonts that probably don't even
have accented characters in them so who
cares I mean one of the success of
google fonts is due to marketing and
maybe if the same people spent a lot of
effort reaching out to publishers for
e-books they could make a dent there
that's that's fine that's true but the
point I'm just making is that these
things are services they're not
catch-all
and when it's a service it's a specific
service in other words so it has
predefined fixed boundaries and it
doesn't solve problems outside of that
therefore if we care about you know open
source and typography we have to find
those challenges and solve them
ourselves and I'm gonna talk about a
couple of those that I think would be of
interest to people here a couple I'm not
going to talk about I'm not going to
talk about adding more fonts that are
open there's a lot of those already
these numbers they kind of count
packages in different ways so they're
rough but that's a lot and I'm also not
going to talk about technical things
like variable fonts question okay
so there's really important technical
work like variable font support
currently the man on the front row here
Mattias is working on this I think if
you look at the top three things there
freetype are posed in flat config it's
already pretty much deployed my
understanding is it penguin GDK you've
got a release cycle or two before Lance
I'm gonna point to a blog entry by him
later on but we're not gonna talk about
that because that's being work done
actively I am going to talk about things
like this be honest how many of you have
seen a slide this weekend that looks
something like that it's not great right
I mean this is the default that you get
in Libre Office and if you open the
templates mainly you get a choice of
what color the rectangle is added to
that the version I'm using is I think
5.3 there's about a dozen templates
available and a half of them at least
used liberation sans what others use
like deja vu
these are fonts that look like generic
sans serifs like Helvetica basically and
I'm not saying they're poorly executed
fonts but they're they're a safe choice
that you make because you want to make
sure you cover a lot of languages or
something like that the design though is
intentionally unobtrusive like that's
the nicest thing you could say about it
you may hate the font that I'm using
here but I mean at least a presentation
is something where you might want to
make an impact and it'd be nice to have
some some options there and when we talk
about templates needing improvement
we're really talking about providing the
user with nice typographic defaults
Libre Office actually does a better job
at this than a lot of other projects and
that they have a set of fonts that ships
with the bundle if you just download the
bundle does anyone at the Libre Office
talks yesterday unfortunately the one
about fonts the speaker was advocating
that they stop shipping fonts with it so
I asked him a question about that don't
need to get into that and it's more
interesting to look at just what the
choices are for for open source projects
in general Scribus is debating this
right now there's a bug on that you can
look it up if you want there the
haven't actually released this but it's
in the development version Inkscape and
GIMP though they don't ship any fonts at
all so you're left the user has whatever
is already installed in their system
with Linux distributions it's a little
hard to tell because these days package
selection varies based on some options
that you choose particularly your locale
generally speaking distributions again
try to take safe choices to make sure
that language support works the desktop
environment has a default font you kind
of get a random selection of other
things there and that that makes sense
as a choice but it leads directly into
the next sort of unsolved problem that I
want to talk about in a little more
depth and that's what goes into a
package a flat package I'm talking about
free operating systems basically Linux
distributions I assume the same thing
would apply to vsts and other things
unnamed source photo credit to Richard
Hughes for this was I really hate the
fact that we package them like
command-line apps because they're not
command-line apps right they're visual
things and people use them to make
visual choices what's unsatisfactory
about the way they're packaged currently
you don't get any documentation most of
the time and sometimes you need that
especially if it's a complicated script
where you have some choices about how
things are displayed you don't really
get much visually that shows you what's
in the font and it doesn't integrate
with the system at all and and that's
that last point it's true in other OSS
too but I think you know we at least
have the ability with package management
to integrate the documentation that
comes with how to use the font into the
system help or how to get in touch with
the designer and we don't really do that
there's some sort of lower level issues
that I think we could get in order
before we start tackling the design
stuff for instance inconsistent paths
and names and what metadata is included
in the packages by the path I mean your
fonts generally end up in a subdirectory
of user share fonts the file formats
pretty well defined type 1 and 2 type
wofe after that is the Wild West this is
an example Noto is the giant mega family
from Google
each language has a separate font polish
question is that Leto or lat Oh lasso
okay lat so is a family of related
designs low heats is a family of Indic
fonts that are related and each one of
them gets a separate director even
though they're all they come together in
fact if you know these languages awesome
using Bengali use the same script so
there can't be much difference between
those two below that bank extra that's a
that's a language related package
so whatever the fonts that exist in
there are disconnected by the language
and then samyak is a project that
produces several fonts but somehow the
fonts have ended up in two different
directories there which is just a
packaging bug this is also true of what
the packages are called themselves cross
core is a is a functional set of fonts
designed to be metric compatible with
your generic microsoft fonts Dasia who's
a family with multiple styles George
Williams is a designer fujur is a
language tag Indyk is a really broad
category sial there is a foundry so they
have si L and then the name of the font
GES fonts is all about one application
go script and then you have some that
don't even fit into the same pattern as
the rest of them like any files
fortunately this this stuff is fixable I
would say it might cause a little pain
but we should do that a little more
complicated is some of the content of
those packages and this goes back to
what unnamed source Richard Hughes was
saying they're not command-line apps the
app stream metadata system used for
packages in software centers these days
has some options for fonts you can do
provide sort of lists the font family
names you can tell the license you can
put a screenshot and you can add a URL a
lot of that's not really the font
specific though the good news though
progress on this is that app stream is
being adopted for more font packages and
it's extensible I actually opened this
issue asking for some more specific
things like designer and foundry because
sometimes does matter and we'll talk
about that in a second
no action on that but I think I am gonna
get to talk to the app streaming people
next week so
I'm hopeful so um what else could go
into the packages I think if we look at
commercial fonts we'll see some things
it's not perfect but you definitely get
the license that you agreed to you also
get trademark information which is
really important to font designers and
you'll also get a specimen and some
documentation usually and you get some
way to contact the person that you
bought it from for us we do generally
include the license in an open font
package we don't do so well with
trademarks though specimens and Docs we
drop the ball if you're not familiar
with it what's a specimen this is
usually a booklet or something that the
type designers created it's a marketing
thing when you like are searching for
fun haven't bought one this is for
gentium which is an essay all fonts is
rather academic looking but it shows the
font and used in academic looking is
appropriate for gentium they can get a
little more lively this is urrh-sa' from
Rosetta type it's a Google font that's
actually on the web they can also show
you some really technical things this is
bungee which is a colorful it's
multi-layer so you need to know how the
layers work to select the colors and you
need to know how to fake that if your
application doesn't support
multi-layered fonts and in some cases
you need to see the font and used to
know if it works at all this is Bengali
and it's without any Magali speakers
here it's a little hard to tell but the
way Bengali works is a lot of things
combined together you use our character
codes that are separate and Unicode and
they form contracts together and vowel
marketers have to move around and stuff
like that so the specimen shows that it
works whereas a blank character table or
a list really won't do that and some of
the documentation deals with this this
is from another sial font called Awami
and it shows you how to activate the
different stylistic variants and you
need to know that if you're sitting
sitting this text so yeah we we might
have to actually create some specimens
and documentation I say let's do that if
you're a designer and you want a graphic
designer to do this let's make some
specimens if you're into typography we
could probably make some documentation
for some of the fonts that we have and
that we're packaging
there's been a little bit of work on
this in the past this was a book that
some people made I forget where but it's
on the whole it's a pretty green field
creating specimens these things are
important because of the next problem
that I want to bring up though which is
how we manage fonts and I don't love
that term it's a little bit unclear
that's sort of how you talk about living
with a chronic illness it also kind of
sounds like you're administering a
database and that's not really what you
want your users to be doing ultimately
your font management is about how you
get fonts in and how you get them out
like when you want to use them and okay
like I was saying the district package
is where we start with this this is from
a bunch of the software Center and
there's a few things there with some
information each font there's a sample
image and as you can see there's a
little bit of metadata at the bottom
it's not very specific it says you know
a developer which is KDE that doesn't
tell you who designed it and and
sometimes you care about that this this
font was designed by a friend of mine
who passed away recently and sometimes I
like to use his fonts in presentations
because he's a friend of mine and I care
about that and it'd be nice to have
access to that and sometimes these
software centers don't really work at
all so yeah just relying on automation
is not perfect but the bigger issue is
that once you leave the safe confines of
the distro package all you have is a zip
file downloaded from the web this is
essentially what everyone has to do
that's what you get when you're getting
something from Google Fonts they don't
have an API for serving fonts directly
to an application it's possible to add
that but that's a choice for them to
make we can't count on that happening
and when you download a zip file well
you're on your own you open that up and
happy hunting we rely on the user to get
them out and put them in the right place
and ultimately that makes it accessible
to the stack but we really wanted to be
accessible to the user there's a not
part of the official gnome stack
application called no manager that I
think
pulls data right out of the file so you
can see things like weight and slant
it'll give you a waterfall it's what it
looks like you can tell the wording this
pulled directly out of a fuels in the
font because it doesn't always make
sense this doesn't even show you what
you want to see because again any
scripts have to combine together so
automatic did that doesn't always work
for you sometimes it lets you down how
do you make a choice there the real
problem here isn't mistakes though it's
that no manager isn't aware of anything
outside the font file last year I spent
a lot of time we're on book designers
and information designers and seeing how
they select their fonts which is what
leads to my next suggestion is that we
think document first when it comes to
font selection and by document font
document first I mean any circumstance
for someone is choosing a fonts they
have a document they're already working
on first and that's the context and make
that decision in and that's more
important to them than the font is
eliminating
okay so yeah they're already working and
there's choices about meeting
requirements they don't have a choice on
and fulfilling some options those
requirements can be important like is
this an academic use projects can I use
any fund I want to have the subsetted do
we have to display English and Arabic
together I probably want to fly where
they were designed together so I don't
have to manually tweak the alignments is
it a business card or a poster what
looked I want the options or anything
else this is where you make your
decisions about I like this designer I'm
always happy with this foundry I have
some features like here about maybe some
specific glyphs in other words that's
metadata you know people don't really
ask about the weight with slope numbers
they want something like a Baskerville
font is what I want or I want something
lively semi condensed and honestly which
of these is what you would want to
choose from that's not a fair fight the
one on the left is automatically
generated but that's the point about the
specimen
it's a designed object created with
intent to show the font and use which a
character table doesn't do and when I
was thinking about why I don't think
gnome font manager works I decided we
should consider the way we do music
because music players are widely used
and tested and they're 100% about a
collection full of metadata that's
rhythm box most of that screen real
estate is metadata and you can search
and sort on it there's obviously other
views you can take this is no music and
you can always edit your your tags and
things I think this is a better way to
consider it there's some lessons we can
learn search and sort your metadata make
it easy to add music allow people to
edit their tags historically that's been
a little taboo in fonts but what choice
do we have I think if we're gonna
integrate services it would have to be
at the font manager level yeah
fortunately there's been a little
progress
this is matthias as work on the font
shoes are in gnome but i think there's
probably more pieces that we need to
think about how they fit together
when you're loading a font and when
you're choosing its
time is up it's just about accurate
there are other problems which I don't
have time to talk about but ask me about
any of them I am gonna do it a 40 minute
version of this next month in Los
Angeles at scale there will be video on
that if you don't want to come to Los
Angeles for you but yeah yes right no ok
so the question is the numbers that I
set it at the beginning of how many font
packages are in these different
locations doesn't take into account what
scripts are supported is there a way to
get that info it's always a little
tricky because someone can mark the font
as supporting a language and be wrong
the numbers that I pull were just the
base level packages so google fonts
sometimes separates things there's a
small cap version that's listed
separately from the main fonts I didn't
try to account for all that because
there's too many of them you could
probably do some data mining and get
script support and I think the Google
Fonts allows you to search on that and
but again it's a human error that you
have to worry about more than there not
being in filling the flan files there so
it's worth trying that anyone else
and well I don't know I think in general
okay reality and type design is that
people who are designing for Japanese
feel like they have to include Latin in
order to sell the font and it's not
necessarily true in every script but
it's generally true in Arabic and a few
other places it's just a globalization
thing when you get beyond that it's hard
to say if you need Japanese and Cyrillic
together it's gonna be tougher to find
but yeah yes okay yeah that's true yeah
there's use your context there the
question is how do you judge the quality
of a multilingual font if you don't read
one of the languages and essentially you
can't unless you get really outside of
what looks good and you see things
colliding or being spaced completely and
correctly but that's sort of a design
level problem I mean the correct thing
to do there is to fix the font not to
change the way you search for the font I
guess well actually Merryweather is a
great example because if you go to the
Merryweather homepage which I don't
think is probably linked to from the
package but you can find on google fonts
there's a how to fix your Merryweather
bugs forum is the top thing and that
designer have been Sorkin has really
made a concerted effort to reach out to
people and do that so it's not as nice
with some other fonts but in that case
they're aware of the need to get
feedback from people
[Music]
there's not an automatic way yeah and
when I mentioned the system integration
that's sort of what I was thinking about
is we could include that somewhere in
the Linux desktop environment or in the
package I don't want to act like I have
an answer for how that should be done
but I can tell you as someone who's
published open fonts extraordinarily
rare to get feedback from people you'll
get feedback from font engineer sync
something doesn't build maybe but design
things really really hard so any way we
could improve that we have a nonzero
positive impact I guess maybe else well
thanks
[Applause]