this year every year for
thank you
[Music]
which usually I do the augmentation
reasons or tutorials the next day
because of this you can find support
websites so that's easy today I'm gonna
use this ability to create something
that you will show otherwise a
historical perspective of why you
thought there and you can see that on
this this line
as going from team to team building
project leader for women for each of the
books a building and we end up with a
small library of books and maybe a tenth
of a shelf and it's not finished
maybe one day we have called for them
something else I want to get chocolates
something more recent that we see
interesting first projects that you spot
as we're going to encourage these of
course small talk about those that our
particularly so going back to the east
where spark it store tips long time ago
more than 30 now 1987 our company is a
great thing program validation widget so
the at least over indeed doing giving
warranties so this company went through
polish good meanings and the positions
now it's a nice to be some time they
they add right projects or one of the
first really big with these c-130j which
is a big military plane and the mission
the mission computer application is only
they are also security for the safety I
am
cpt palette I took in here which was the
project done by Ultron for the NSA it is
an invite and we'll talk about it a bit
later because in 2008 this project was a
contortion because of this because of
this event so ad front partners with Air
Corps and we convinced them that there
was some value in pushing the technology
forward you know this would bring a GPL
system so these be the fastest way I
won't cover much today if you are
interested there's this article by
workshop Rhonda really covered this
experiment so number of things evolved
and Susan 8 we started something new so
we started this project highlights small
sideline is simplifying the use of
commodities and what we ended up doing
in this project is we built the wall
painting so the previous technology kept
the good ideas and at the result was
this spot 2014 in which means so while
we were rebuilding the Kamaria
projects for similar things also two
notable projects are the iPads project
so hypotheses part
that's what we control over the UK so
when you travel to the UK usually my
clients use the shuttle you're using
this software which helps a traffic
controllers to foresee possible
collisions drive the decision making in
asking place some actions to avoid and
it wasn't for 13 the men say Percy alone
first version was issued and we'll talk
a bit more about this because this one
is open-source
an interesting fact is that these two
were initially the previous version of
part obviously and
in the past years they are both negates
its to Spartan support so you may say
well migration isn't it's a big word for
great for from success we have to
succeed enough because it's precisely
not as
so let's see an example so this was
through his vision of Scott it's not a
subset of it it's boys present its days
as really a different language it was it
was heretic to say that the cicada it
was using a subset of ADA as the
operational code on which it was
imprinting illogical adaptations logical
language the word to language and here
you can see an API about computational
ins and price of something with
something like that looked like the
first conditions these conventions and
says that when ads returns and it was
written something the Sun which has some
properties same turned off and and then
this one returns this exact value and
you can see that already they have
voiced some unit which expressions that
these quantified expressions that you
can see mathematics to quantifiable
question you had that thing in the tango
is a purely logical language we got
relationship to English so only for
consumption by the innate system so we
transformed it into that so maybe at the
first loop that doesn't prove so
different from virtual before maybe a
bit of syntax in fact so all these
things now our part of the language so
that
executable that's really code code that
expressing properties so we really tied
through the specific before this these
are the past conditions using Mitchell
properties and these are additions that
we thought were needed in spark ensue
outlets yet in Ada and we so here
without these contract disease why do
you think the company then allowed to
specify three paths by cases it's very
common services functionalities that
behave differently on the inputs inputs
or now sets up in post are only
available here ads it's saturating
addition so if the results is less than
imagery show the result will really be
the addition otherwise if the results
the expected result would be rather than
the threshold then it saturates so this
project is have this semantics that we
deployed in Putin and this can be
checked either so I'm just showing it
here with a really nice ER display of
symbols when you have a ligature in in
your monospaced fonts some of my
colleagues hate it but I take this
occasion to advocate very cool really
nice to display properties that makes it
easier to I so what we did during the
silent project is this echoes
tim of open source tools so we built our
own ecosystem based on the building
blocks away after go CB signals these
realities about all these are automatic
coolers here to the tech formulas say
who falls below interactive coolers here
today as super important help him work
out the food system and all of these are
communities some other sort of easy
portable as a useful dozens and dozens
of resistance those that are most
interest to us are these the atomic
tours and widely is this Altice favor of
approving so what we've done is this
product is really built from other
programs to this intermediates Wi-Fi
code so by 3 is or intermediate language
super code intermediate verification
language is the assembly language for
doing this kind of deep analysis of
products include the deliberate teaching
and from wisely there is something
called vc directives of ratification
condition generator all use with a
simple term formula that is problem java
code that represent the code here is
going to generate
and the other shells knob canoes between
the US and England out which develops
this possible because you've got spark
and white P so they have so that they
have a really great integration yeah so
this all these impacts is for the truth
analysis the responders there's a door
to analysis in fact the pyramid there's
proof I am there as flawless flawless
this is something simpler that checks
all the flows in program and this is
done at this level really at the level
of this lateral - so this is depicting
the harder more complex but in two
slides I will represent now what we do
Bispo analysis and true because I'm
going to say two stuff to take me come
true but just so that you have an idea
of raw analysis that here is the
signature of service and now we can add
to it with the L a 2012 syntax some
aspects there with and this has PEC
global is an aspect introduced or spark
so the tools that for this party was ten
it matters and here we are completing
the new signature of stabilize with the
new both are both are exists here it has
additional inputs are not transparent
micrometer and you guys and it show the
marble
butters might be more than one bar
bollocks
but you name it
which is partially and once you've done
that specifying FX that you want the
function to respect then the tool can do
this flow analysis and check that the
program implements this specification so
that's the exquisite specification you
might add also implicit specifications
name in terms of flows that's everything
that he computes serves a purpose
otherwise you will get watch here you
think that's a mistake typo or that's
everything that you read is in this line
is typically we check most explicit and
implicit specification so let's put on
our seats and the cygwin is proof so
proof using the same signature for
stabilized we can now specify functional
behavior what it expects an entry speed
condition that's the moods event we
should be off and kiss by first
condition so here is a bummer if
expressions condition well that's II in
the case of success then there should be
a relationship between the once these
specification are added to the code the
proof tool can check that the program
implements this resolution so this is
for the explicit from some specification
but there are in pisac ones namely that
there are no right time errors in the
good
so all axes are excesses or will in
bounce all the ivory is also within the
and respects the right checks of the
guys
so to talk a bit about how we got to the
grants solution technical solutions I
chose to present to you in terms of
objectives that we had for this revamp
of these particular G and so we had
really high level goals but technical
was like let's use these technologies in
our zombies so we had some of these but
the re-roll goes were these first
functional contracts can be executed
tested developed that because we want
them to be reconsidered as my coop so we
don't want to wait score promote proof
of these two activities for my name to
be replace less precise comments we want
them to be able to replace some of the
testing articles that you belong
otherwise in the separate artifacts at
the booth so yeah so that was one of the
things which the error subsets supported
things possibly as not as possible
indeed the main reason not to use the
technology because it doesn't apply in
your a so definitely people who see what
anything at Purdue we like people who
use era so that what that was I will to
more detail to that will be change the
user needs no addition to start to be
good without large levels at which it's
a pretty good I'm I'm using it here in a
large sense of eating warranties in the
code whether it's much Mondavi series of
my crew and in the booklets that you
will find the urine who's on the far
side on the right in my first night
indicate that number two studies we have
defined five levels analysis of proof
achievements and so at the lowest level
if you didn't have to know too much
should be yeah I have a program that
gives it a ten starts by me
he's funny bit you might want to go
further than that that's of course but
you want few other patients to fully
prove the group well we'll say about few
minutes but what we want really here is
that it's what super hard to get beyond
the initial steps
the last one will also little bit a
background is manual truth is something
very hard that couple that with the you
little too want to do unless you approve
me so we want money or food to be so
looking at at these one of these in more
details we all contract to be executed T
States and debugs so cool that's using
the eloquent about preconditions and
postconditions if you are here in the
produce Tokyo all about them as less
this aspect three and posture so really
our view now is that contracts are cool
you can do as as well with contracts as
we could in terms of usability
integration you can do probably as as
bad as in codes to pray these things
spark helps you hear more respective but
that maybe there's some additions to ADA
so we were very pushy with the energy so
that the including you gotta have some
of the features which we really need it
for proof qualify expression the ability
to states properties of a collections
expression functions the ability to
abstract properties that you don't have
to inline everything it's time or have
to go to the body to state something
that you will need in aspect will be
crazy and will be completely contrary to
this spirit of separating the spec and
the body in particularly when we want to
read to specifically properties just
pounds or or things
so so for these two will have we right
but we pushed in up the alt and
particularly so that this these two
features were part of the the fact that
the ADA are subsets is large there was a
departure from the previous technology
previous technology adds this correct by
construction mode that sort of if you
followed seven steps and restrictions
was far easier to verify formally your
program this is true unfortunately
that's very rare that so you can follow
all these constraints from the start you
have to be in the reach nice situation
where you start over and do everything
as you're told
from the start and you may need then to
completely change your ways of doing
things that's really your pick up space
so in the optic for something difference
we say all these constraints they're
going to be your colleague standard
other tools we are bringing some of them
are the troops we're gonna opt for every
feature that doesn't make for
modification across so we included
almost everything but we still excluded
to this day our pointers and exceptions
all the rest is it so the particular all
types these period types types with
dynamic bounds restriction no no
restriction from flows we can return
from doing the loop anywhere it have
complex hierarchy of packages that's not
our business we know how to make sense
of
this is a separate issue preclusion
again in many applications education in
some talented or otherwise you might and
that's okay because we can make
sensitive generates there wasn't a
template supportive generates in the
position of ADA which was quite limited
because the attempt was to change Eric's
once and for all
we will sit through allow any generates
that below so we have it for something
much simpler which is to analyze each
instance we support drinks but in a way
that may be less principled and before
but much more progressive so for all
these pictures or all types no
restriction or to perform occasion
particular the impact are there of good
reason why they've all that supported
because there are good reasons why they
were so not supported before they can be
quite difficult
and and when when we implemented these
we ended up with two birds along the
years in the interference of types with
dynamic ground particular complex
upfront flow recursion really subtle
bugs in how we generate the formula and
which ended up in possible and soundness
in the truth so when I leave today
that's we have a good exists for these
birds but that's that's one of the
reasons why yeah ideally you want to put
onto the hexagonal we made this choice
to know as much as we could do and to
focus on Sundays so of course each one
of these these few banks that I
mentioned were very very carefully to be
sure that today we don't add them or
anything that still the initialization
of squad 2014 did not support in the
markings so we felt when Dunham picked
up here
some people we're saying well you don't
support of concurrency
tags don't support data invariants at
work just so we're thus acting as well
if that's where you were doing a big
jump over this we were going to be
backward and oh honey you can see the
previous business part with support
things like leo
so no dispatching calls with time type
soon that will you over to a bit of
bagpipes
I was supporting some currencies in the
booth called the heavens watch so
restrictions of the rhythms card 4.0
but we opted for yeah let's let's get
the tool set out and
and we'll have a roadmap to ads these I
start goodbye
something else that's spark code from 20
starts after a few experiments were we
were looking at the solution to mix it
and for code we opted for something
quite fine grain and at the same time
prescribed by the user the reader can
say exactly in their code word despot
who leaves the tool can analyze this and
not that that's quite possible to mix
things that were supported with
exceptional needs so the ADA subject is
still expanding so we have a need among
the years go programming including these
patching combs and for this we use the
the best that Tamiya has shown it's
possible to do which is to show that
derived classes are providing subsets of
behaviors of the parent classes let's go
the new name is this curve substitution
principle for suppose that as that's one
of the means to comply with own in a
viola context now the do 178 is an
external allows for a special supplement
200 400 that I tasting by so essentially
this that's a true thing if I can
precisely to but on the proof scene it
means that when you derive the function
sakaram your precondition
must be weakened so you will accept to
be called in more comfort than you do
but you're potentially will be only
stronger you know tell you four more
deeply particular because you might be
cold through this patching call with the
static type that that is apology so that
makes the kind of erases that we doing
here
function by function possible we re
Circle protocol see the one year later
so again using what pinned only produced
energy so we support resins ribbon Scott
really even the extensive reading stuff
profile defined and contract to the
previous technology we insisted on not
adding host of annotations that you need
to put in a good so it's mostly generate
see all the things that are itself by
wound worry about if I which tasks how
to detect the podraces first I
sanitation but let's user work when it
means also it's it's next module so it
will it be else on the program to really
detect all possible support for type
radius packing variance so I'm going to
merge detail with our two types of data
and variance Elena I will be now support
those for why we have to do it one by
one because in fact ADA is
defining what this means you know time
predictable 10:00 tomorrow dynamically
which means that it takes at some points
in the execution that's some completion
of the required this is not enough
people type pretty kids these are the
things that should always hold true
vertical scrolling Marines and type in
various things that should hold outside
of the defining package whether we can
balance means that you're less good than
this phony right just means that
sometimes you have to break them when
you define operations over you object I
am to be able to prove them you have to
be much quicker and much cooler to know
these mentioned in any group of armed
all you have to be able to assume them
for couple when you enter a packet that
is responsible for other objects and how
painful that really these grantees are
strong always the Englishman and so that
we are to define stronger goals in
implementing I find in annexing exciting
one on which we are working now is the
support for Polish under ship access
parts in Iran inspire so era is really
which access types of pointers which
protect no more problems one which is
not regarded and is explicit when you do
unchecked to the allocation the in check
thing that can worry you is yeah but
thematic saved allocation management of
the brain and it's something that's all
the languages like breasts are solves
for programs by using this
ownership we're a Puerto really hold
really owns everything that the tree of
memory that that sees underneath with
mechanisms to borrow this this ownership
when you are doing a temporary
modification to move and so we have
experimented with that last year
we're lucky submissions have scientific
conference for the underlying scientific
mechanisms and to allow Europe for the
proposal for the future data center you
can also read the ADA issues 2014 if you
go to the language library so so that's
that's the thing that's cooking for I'll
say the next two years because let's not
be too ambitious the rules will be will
take time to be verified for ADA and it
that's a great technical work ADA in
Sparta moving in the same directions
although we we will certainly other
slightly different and suppose package
from the inspector than okay so users
are lazy where our users but we want to
have all result without in green work
and in particular when we starts and we
want to try out we rather just see what
but good is needed for us before we test
anymore it work that's why it was
important that we can you can start will
be Spanish in this book we know for the
Jews so every surprise nature in fact it
has a precondition and the first
religion which is implicit needs a
signature
but all inputs of the programming are in
there types and when you return all
outputs are in their time there are some
consequences in terms of what finish
lies of course the spot is a bit
scripted then either that when you
passing things around it they have to be
fully initialized in the pipes but that
gives it a very reasonable there are
defaults for sort of that then you need
to know what are I mean inputs and
outputs what are these down partners
that's is it dark in the signature and
give all marbles my D believe global in
terms of having the lifetime of the
program or syntactically scopes and so
these what we call these global
variables there are read and written by
any given surprise directly indirectly
suppose they are generated by Google so
here again this analysis nationally is
not modular it goes physical graph and
collects all effects so that you don't
have to do this work
now when you would want to go beyond to
your sphere satisfied with the tool you
want to achieve more and you have to
start do to work safely but what we
claim now is that you can you need few
or fewer annotations because Q is quite
relative to where you start from Q for
many would be no no no no agendas not
possible and again it depends where you
put your aim for something easy you will
less work for something harder more
party he was addicted so yeah poof and I
said is mostly Madeira so blue Google
analyzed using the very complex tools
very rich eccentric solvers so program
as a program which means that to analyze
coves Google needs whatever information
you give us additional conditions in
particular in some cases we can do
without because we have in line a
mechanisms so internals of programs that
have no contracts the tool unites them
some some loops so but because the sepal
for loops we involved so that you don't
have to add the annotations in simple
cases and things that that do not
participate in the API with a device we
leave the specification but things into
no we'd like to skip all of them if
possible you can factorize annotations
example they tied variants they were
really important to add to make support
for this type of a stock events because
not putting them means that you you
should specify then for every pre first
everywhere well many likes some of these
they so that there's maybe 40 party
relation here and now a lot also of
these these benefits has to do with how
we don't read formulas units I'm going
to that that's the technology behind it
completely replace with moji using
state-of-the-art and all this direction
of formulas you need much fewer loop
invariants
special kind of annotations daily
forward sometimes you don't need to cut
points so ways to simplify the the poop
work just to show it in practice an
example world you really need fewer
deductions
scheme that was contender for
Shockley and the Western standards
c-elysee permutation of death of Adam
and rut Chapman who was at the time a
leader of this movement
Itron create wrote the export
interpretation of that so this packet
annotation so there's a skill about it
and the spark ignition will be quite a
lot of what you had many annotations for
effects and appearances global amateur
and depends
there were many preconditions and
postconditions I don't come here just a
precondition because the precondition
could be tens of lines of clothes so I
counts conditions the things that you
end together with our new conditions and
there were lots of conditions in
appearance as well there are loops there
were a number of other patients to just
do with the limitations of the tool in
terms of scalability and even with
that's yet to complete and about proof
money so I was a huge effort for someone
revolver expert in technology that's
what some effort to prove absence of
retainers from this point that's the
situation to do today with different
technologies we achieve evolved by
anyone
and that's that's religion so to end up
with these supports manual proof so you
don't so with that that's why you saw
smoke on the left you have a formula
that was directed by
that could improve and some there but
there's an encoding of your of place in
the program of static path in your code
and this H 1 H 2 correspond to the
assignments calls or a state that were
this bad we are encoding of all the
other types and you have to prove this
to children that might correspond to
position or well when the estimated
voters of the time didn't do you have to
go through new module Pro possibly so
this is no manual speeds were on the
number of instructions to disprove that
by this book and read these instantiate
that and say from manipulating this this
so this we will do at least not in this
shape because these formulas are really
far from this is different language this
is yet another language obviously place
to develop language is so require too
much efforts for the two people protect
even though so what we do now is that we
don't get atomic Buddhist we support
more with the shape of the arcs I sent
you saw Bruce Oscar goes to be
supposedly and the whole platform really
targets all of these with adaptations to
the for minerals and this really
underworld art break and quantify
properties that arise from you code
the thing that we do at apart from this
specialization the natural and feeling
that we do is also terror in this is
Central Grocery we really focus on put
them in proof I not so much money
improve like before and the user has
some control over the strategy approve
antibiotic so I'm going to that but
that's an additive level when you use
the place okay so I've roughly ten
minutes to go over course projects good
thing is that there aren't that many
[Music]
druggies from there because here before
so if you are is your question that
gillnets party and he has this quite
rich library of thing that are useful in
two locations that is mostly quickly
this part one it chains reverse
containers utf-8 for sure that were just
and a few rappers on area code which
rappers there so that they can be cool
from Sporto typical also think that we
do if they must have been delayed a bit
make them another person certify is
software for thought for this room for
this or a smaller crazy playground
between value and source the platform
having the 30 fly is the software that
runs on top of it to do the
stabilization was coded by my colleague
Andy replace ReactOS on these by Ravens
car for pervaded every time I am the
establishing communication code by in
this part and the absence of bread after
the tiger poop so there is a cool demo
feature where you can let it fall and it
lands we can do in this programs like
that I choose in prototype in teaching
research web companies so release who
are using Chris apply for the pie thing
and the jovem from such as i we use in
teaching fully of I talking about Tim is
developing this right through the middle
world or aerial video architecture of
this tutor language there is a tool
generates area codes over Carina but of
course all the all these things need to
talk through this mail over
so this mineral was produced me in area
and now he's been moved to spark and it
tells a bit of this story in in the
prepare that you are going to find here
that is I think the last you I will
promise came from
and the cool thing Zoe didn't attend
several diverse group of some internal
contracts for her this middleware and
the coolest thing full of thing is that
easily at radically less sterically
history on you and they they went
through this process of developing the
this to adapting this familiar work from
era easy to use on one side part and on
the other side for the C equally
equivalent to Reaper see two more cool
absence of retires and possibly one
because thing is that he did much faster
and is colleague at some point that is
not to say that it's impossible but ADA
and spark marry make much easier will
source so still come studies still the
same people here it's true two pilots so
there's no distance yet the public code
repository but there will be but the end
of the year it's still in doing so right
now with the TVs in do two pilots is
manual stabilized flights and the flight
and really cool occupy
nice part of the project to achieve
really high level of safety for between
three so the highest evolved little a
Abdi edenic standards
so spark is one part of the process to
achieve that the reasonable cost and so
spark is useful some putting some of the
functionalities and also respect to X
glider by Martin Baker researcher from
technical invention it's so firm were to
control this and my big swing higher
model to collect the weather data its
launch from the balloon and replies how
will you get it go to file and we did
that over a very small period of time a
few months achieves proof on the target
absolutely there are impartial contracts
and so you can also see the results and
when I show here is that these are all
the units of code although the green
year has been booked for absence of
covers and so fulfill properties the
gray ones are the specs export and the
black ones and so yeah it's ongoing
projects already achieved a lot in the
virtual time now it took in year
eventually at the beginning is that was
led by Danny points and I'm from these
products a few months one year project
for the NSA today one face that it was
possible to develop very high security
software so VAR v is level
with formal methods at original cost and
so the cool thing is that all the try
the artifact statistics on the original
code are available from this webpage and
you have a version that completed the
translation to the spark 2014 the common
rule which is part of the test which
spoke was probably I which is the part
of the examples that we just read with
the reading now I'm ganna when is the
largest spot open source projects is
this a personal offer by again
investigator
kabuki so these two are researchers at
University of scale and the work with
sickness which is the CPG company in
Germany so you look at the website we
need to know all the details of the
multiple features that they've been
added since 2013
trains on x86 64 and the goal was got
these very very small code base of three
thousand lines of code with power three
and put in the code in assembly it's
very very secure software of mystic
proof at sorts of containers the cool
thing is that the legislation their
websites
it's unreal a choice of Copperfield so
it is really functional I mean on
delicate to use men functional supports
Mikado and to put the same which is true
is that the man is really a milestone in
getting this push open source that is
proof for absence of for covers X small
Y it smell that can be multiplied by the
others because of its small size and
easy sequencing so if you interested in
security
look at this one as I said before the
code was originally in the previous part
and they managed to market it
for cleaning and so now it's moving
domestically something interesting is
that's security is never ended battle
you have to defend against the eternal
realities of tomorrow
and how to how best to illustrates the
thing that we had with our approach then
to see how well they did with madam and
inspector before completely unexpected
by the corporate community now that if
you look at these emails that were sent
and so you learn Mel down is punitive
not visually by funded by the way that
they selected very very small set of
optimizations options to reduce
virtualization and aspect is really
mitigated and although it could be
memorable it's it's much less than
multiple possible other jumps so it's
both security is not to supporting the
system thing and in software is that sir
be sure to think that other language but
certainly the choice of simplicity and
win for strong parties like it's so very
fast spontaneity resources so there's a
committee release every year make sure
it will be bundled with nuts in one load
and if you want to get the most part on
this part there's a small difference
between its policy events purport the
number of two days deductions we only
ship one with right now with what we
call spec discovery so first degree is
push on through and
version for everyone but who is the one
that for people repairs but on on the
community version in fact you can
install CPC for ng3 easily documented so
please look at this to get the most of
truth and particular some of the
features that context apple will only be
now she want to learn sport now there's
plenty of online resources a top
university and five multi class there's
an another five thirty class which is
not taking the website which is you can
access it from the pepper and all of
these will move to a new area and spark
learning website from a recording dezer
block will move to a decor blog mister I
don't have plenty of resources to cover
this you will find them the waiting
that's some people on the community or
producing learning your materials only
and they kept using is part by example
for teaching nothing better off would
you say very nice the total it really
think this part so if you produce
anything like that let's do we are very
happy to a bikini there are community
events were we try to gather both open
sourced and other community of a
provision open in season one part so it
wraps and researchers spoken from se
days pharmacy has four days but I think
everybody's here which show cured for
the first time in 37 change little care
against this year at National Institutes
our sites are technologies in the US
27:28 so we're grateful ground which
because anybody tells you happen to be
there we have conditions upcoming
presentation at conferences so Alexander
simiiariy would happen to have presented
his work at the embedded mobile
intuitive just before me so if you look
at security will be net both conferences
in Berlin and they will be condition
that obviously
finally if you have to play this part
and you're too lazy to download cool you
can play with it this race winner it
will be also pop websites your checkup
all stick around so full by clicking
yeah so what's your first project
no solution is either
not impacted real time between