so we are finally ready to start its
little a very short now five minutes
show to talk about new features in this
race I'm Dimitri I'm mentoring of stress
for quite some time and today I'll give
a short talk about new features just
just a few of them because well most of
stuff we are doing is quite boring and
nothing to talk about
but very important for these features
and other new features to work but if
you're really curious you could have a
look at release notes and find dig out
all the boring stuff is there but today
I'll stop remind you about fault
injection I was talking about last year
and we'll talk about new features some
of them are already included and already
released and some are still being merged
so this is a recollection from the last
year hold injection if you just happen
to miss this new feature it's very
unusual for traditional strays that you
can tamper with system calls like in
this simple example or
you actually can inject any kind of
Fault in any system call you specify
like in those indications you want and
this is also from last year's talk it's
a real bug was found in Python that's
already fixed now but you can see that
it just failed to check its own code
from open Cisco and from recess call and
that resulted to sick falls because then
just exists and fixed upset from a null
pointer another bug was fixed in dynamic
linker and Lipsy pretty harmless back
but still was a bug was ignored setting
protection some portion of memory
expected to be an accessible but it fell
to check this and it remained accessible
this is not good
that it was fixed
also so this is just a quicker
correction from the last year's talk if
you are more interested you can just
have a look at it and play with it it's
very useful feature you can use it for
like regression testing we actually use
it in pursuit of a stress itself so
you're welcome we implemented more
features in the this direction so there
is a new option called inject that can
inject not just four stitches calls but
other kinds of things like signals to
school vacations or other kinds of
return codes that are not that useful
and also delay injection this is last
this is a quite new feature it's not yet
merged so you can inject delays in
vacations on entrance to school and then
exiting syscalls and like if stress
wasn't slow enough you can make it even
slower in specific cases as you can see
in this example like home or just
magnitude is so why don't you like three
orders of magnitude slower just those
specifics of course you want to besides
miss city examples where you can also
well silly I actually been asked several
times when people wanted to slow down
some Siskel's to throttle network
traffic for example and those tools they
that don't implement this like slow down
rates on or sense or some other Cisco's
another kind of use of this feature is
like in Port injection case is for
regression testing where you can
specifically slow down some process
that's expected to finish to complete
some operation very fast and if another
process or thread is waiting for it for
fixed time this will fail
so this way you can do that kind of
inject some delays that effect control
flow let's do this my talk consists of
small blocks and if you have questions
when you see this thing like 5/5 is the
end of block and you can ask them right
now if you want if not let's move on to
another block so this year actually last
two years it would be in a project mmm
it was a google Summer of Code
jin-seok project of two years that
implemented partial for network traffic
the first year was a magic ground very
groundwork and last year we implemented
the most popular knitting protocols
starting with route and you can see like
nine of them and more are going to be
implemented this year thing hopefully
how does it look this is a very simple
routing table to to make this routing
table you you have to create like a
basic container with no network
interfaces just a little back interface
if you create this it will have just for
Colonel Colonel routes
so how does it actually look what IP to
see is from the colonel
let's this is going to be a very
impressive picture be prepared that's
what's going under the coat you see this
is very structured output I did some
coloring its manual sorry I did it by
hand so but you can see that I mean the
tool it doesn't see any colors it see
structures
oh sorry it's just very simple you'll
see schools but without all these
structures it would be just string or
pointer depending on what kind of as you
if you know we've sent two it would be
instead of this instead of this
structure that starts here yeah
we carry barricades fields you would see
I'm sorry
it would see just in all the stresses
would see just a string a binder thing
that means nothing but here you see like
a structured output almost no but also
supported you can see on this none of
them so it's almost like a knitting
debugger without probably we can't
really inject all this stuff inside the
program but you can see all this gory
details something let's go on another
set of features to implement that is
related to Cisco specifications States
as you probably know have a lot of
children like it can filters is caused
by glasses this time we decided to add
some more classes but to avoid
collisions with system calls we edit
prefix so all new system call classes
started with perfect it's a percent sign
and all traditional system system call
classes are also have this prefix so
these are traditional and we also did
like four different start feminists
calls you can see in this example how it
looks like what does it mean to persons
get to the way to describe all start
process family just calls why so so many
how do how many F start system
the way - Linux kernel do you think 5x5
well 64-bit architectures usually have
to them 32 bits also - but different and
there is also an engine system call that
modern architectures don't have but you
don't have to worry about all these
details just use the system call cross
name and that's all as you can see in
this example on the trench it sounds
here of the project we decided but we
found out well we don't still have
support for regular expressions how
could that be
so we did this and you can see that the
same example from the previous slide
could be could be like using you can do
the same thing using regular expressions
I don't think it looks easier to use but
with expressions you can do all
different things
oh thank you the time is going back
another feature of system called
specifications is conditional
expressions as you probably know system
calls are added like every or almost
every gnu/linux carries and they're not
added to all architectures at the same
time it's not normally the case for
example the recent from a stat family
called statics it was added for many
architectures but not for all and for
example you write a somewhat portable
script using a stress it will get into
the situation that it works in most
cases but doesn't work on a Mohnish
architectures like italian where statics
up to this point is not yet right up so
using this conditional specification you
can walk around this and this is a real
case example you will probably seen this
or will see in future that BBC switched
from open to open it internally and also
to for implementing open library call so
if you used to trace by open it no
longer works starting with with Lib C
2.26 but if you switch to open add you
won't be able to trace all the blue
pieces it's not good so you can use the
list but it's not portable because open
is not available on some architectures
so how can write a portable straigh
script you can use a regular expression
or you can use the condition so there
are two examples which one is easy to
read do you thing a regular expression
or condition I think addition that's why
we added condition this piped with the
regular expressions you can describe the
same thing but it's usually looks more
complex yes
so it's it it says that this is called
specification it doesn't happen to match
any real system call so you can write
fubar
and it will States will not trace any
football because there is no four bars
is called if you just type a Cisco or a
ghost version that doesn't match any
Cisco a stress will not run it will
issue an error as you can see yes sorry
why not make a condition the default
behavior was the question first of all
you won't detect any accidental errors
people do errors sometimes it would be a
change of behavior and for the project
of 26 or 27 year old it's not a good
idea actually to change behavior in a
decorative incompatible way for not I'm
not really good reason ok the last topic
is advanced Cisco filters new syntax
this was implemented also as a part of
google Summer of Code project last year
and it allows even more flexible
specification of Cisco's for example you
can chase by file description number
without traditional syntax you can just
either trace by specification as you can
see you could see before or you can done
by description number now you can
combine all these things you can combine
sections default astray is Trace you
don't have to specify it it's written
here trace but you can omit it as you
can see on following slides you can also
combine different kinds of things like
you can as you consume this example you
can trace
reduce coal and dump on the walls sits
coal that access a specific file this
way you will see that in slightly a
typical example you can see that some
program accesses different things but we
dump on the loss of them but actually
interesting why dumping the zero could
be interesting living well I've seen
once it was not a device but a file in
real life it was not a good idea to
replace a zero with the file I think
somebody just with a suppressor
privileges or directed output there and
some did something like this stupid
thing and well you can use logical
expressions like and not brackets this
way you can do very flexible filtering
as you can see you can select only those
Cisco's that work with files but doesn't
take descriptions as arguments or and
doesn't return descriptions is written
within a return value or you can all
kinds of combinations illogical
expressions as you consume these
examples in the first example you don't
see anything just
as you could expect cut walks with a
file it opens it it does something with
it but you don't see all these sis calls
on the doors that are specified this is
another example of that kind of
combination you can use like they
probably see you you couldn't specify
what kind of Cisco's you want to stack
trace
so all these calls in traditional
syndics all cisco selected filtration
would be sector east if you request it
now you can select which of those Cisco
SATA trace it actually stack traced so
you can see this program accesses
description number one but we're
interesting we're interested only in
doors close is called to have a look
rate goes from as you can see it's it's
from exit hunter
so what cut probably does it installs an
exit angle that closes standard output
and it's actually what's happening as
you can see in this example so that's
most more less old this
who's this living this is a mascot Oh
stress up to last year had no mask so
we're very happy but we have one meet
our new mascot if you have any questions
gasp is
so the question was why one might want
to filter something in a stress hurdle
then parse a straight output right well
tracing makes things slow
if you don't need something then you
don't chase it you don't pass always
imagine how many she's hole see you you
have to issue to fetch all this memory
from Tracy if you don't need this
you just don't that's right
yes please
yes it's not really neat link tracing
its its advanced parsing of the traffic
that goes because by default if its
treated as a string it means nothing or
almost nothing it's a parsing it's not
additional tracing capability it's
additional parsing of things so this is
calls are the same
it could be any kind of Cisco it could
be just read right yes please for genus
protocols and I'm not sure because it's
not something you can distinguish from a
circuit for example once the circuit is
a knitting circuit you can would make
sense to some kind of plug-in system to
so one would someone would just
implement a parser for this chunk of
memory the state should fetch it and
give to plug into from tracing something
at the port that destination that system
for something use this plug-in for
it's no genie
it's what's going on the network before
your make for example a few things
yes this also could make sense yeah just
oh you're asking forgiveness yeah this
makes things not to replicate all this
work making Wireshark and speed amp and
what whatever else yep any more
questions
we can choose something for a name yes I
think it's it's charged yes
he's nice isn't it any more questions
no then thank you
[Applause]