[Applause]
okay my name is Jamie ravello I'm JJ
Jamie relevancy pan thank you very much
for being here this is what I'm going to
talk about this is actually a drawing
made by Paola who was a student in my
class this year in an undergraduate
class she's represented pretty much with
a feeling of my students when they were
submitting their assignments to the
system so this is a continuous
integration system it was a scanning and
they were Holly for dear life to get
have yes waiting for that for the
assignments who to get through okay
this Varenne good to talk about and to
talk about testing for testing so I'm
professor in the university and not
going to ten minutes I'm not very proud
of my university right now so let's just
say I'm in academia and and talk about
my experience of using continuous
integration in the in the classroom
right I must say in Granada another
bonus by we're going to have a workshop
after worshipping or another in a couple
of weeks so if you love going to sonim
Spain you know warm nice place it's
going to be an incredible place the
color paper is still open you're
interested just let me know this were
where am I have been doing it's a called
computing class
it's an undergraduate and also master
level called computer class this is my
actual class oh that's me so this is not
the class I have been given this year
was last year England the undergraduate
class saying having around 40 students
something like that in the masters
classes I'm having around 12:15 so there
are so it's it's it's a smallish class
it's not it's not that's too small but
it's smallish and anxious something
called flipped learning have you ever
heard about this never so it's learning
as people actually learn so there is a
saying all saying that goes you don't
teach people learn
so I think that it's pretty stupid for
someone to be standing in front of a
class for two hours flipping slides like
I'm doing now but the thing is that well
what you have to do for people to
actually learn is to make people learn
optimal learning so you give them a
series of objectives you give the
material you give them some some class
notes or whatever and then you let them
learn and you are there guiding them
helping dang or whatever so it's not
like I'm standing in front of the class
for two hours it's like I say a Buddha
slide with the objectives of the of the
particular session or or the week and
then I wander around the class telling
people how are you doing what are you
doing do you have anything to us do any
prodding I see them working with with a
material of a class I say okay I see you
are stumbling onto this please check
that out whatever so it's a different
way of giving class that's not that's
not really related with with the rest of
the thing that I just wanted to put you
a little bit in context so it's it's a
different way of teaching as far as I
know that's not many people in many
versity who's doing that there's not
many people know their universities that
from its it's been just wonderful and I
keep asking the students whether they
want this kind of class or what is
called magistral class the traditional
one and they keep saying 90% of them no
no we want this way of giving class of
course they can wander around they can
get in class I got every time they want
they can get out whenever they want so
it's I mean for the nice quite relaxed
it's not so stressful it's nice and then
another thing I want to do this to be as
free as possible so I don't want to to
give them assignments which are just
boilerplate things where they have to
fill in the blanks and they say okay
this is okay so they eventually end up
fill in the blanks and not learning
anything at all but trying to make the
thing as real as possible so not like
this astronauts who are in a carnival
parade but real people doing real
deployments in the cloud because it's
where I'm teaching right it's cloud
computing so at the end of the day they
will have to go to a company or whatever
to get their own company and they will
have to do deployments in the cloud so I
want them to do real deployments in the
real cloud right
I think that classist is going to be a
metaphor for real life so when they will
do deployments in the cloud line when
there are developments and developing
software in a company they're going to
undergo code reviews they're going to
use continuous integration they're going
to do all kind of that you're doing
in in in real life but why not use it in
class right so in class you will have to
use code review you have to to have
continuous integration all that kind of
thing right then I used to eat hub
having using it have for a long time so
like like seemed like four years or so I
mean in class yes please
you're gonna go not something okay so
this how is my learning management
system so everything they do it's in
github that's absolutely amazing and
it's very nice
so this is the actual page they use for
turning in the assignment so what they
have to do is they have all the dresses
in a river such like this one this this
is the actual page that I have been
using this year in master class so they
they put their project they do
milestones in a project Ito means means
it's not here yeah somewhere it was
milestone so they do milestones in a
project and this they submit each
milestone when they are going to submit
the milestone what they do is they they
change this particular file which is in
my repository it's in a procedure in
class and they are there the direction
of the repository so we same also the
version right version is support and we
will see that later on github is very
good it's amazing it's much better than
any other LMS you might think of and in
talking about this because I think that
everyone at one point of your life or
another German to be a teacher you're
going to teach something and since we
are in technologies is wearing
programming
we'll probably have to do something like
this we have to you know on board any be
boring or company we would just you know
we are between jobs and we go to some
Community College to do you class
whatever it's something that you have to
do so my intention was to use this kind
of technology and to see what kind of
things could be done to make your
experience a little bit better so I have
been doing this for four
quite a long time so the people were
turning in the assignment
and I was checking out this page and it
was correcting me all of a sudden I had
a new beginning 2017 you probably know
that was director of the free software
office in the University of Illinois
that took me around 24 hours a day 25 26
hours a day I was fired I still keep my
job as a professor because I mean fish
aware of this was was a man appointment
it wasn't a job all of a sudden had a
lot of time my hands at the same time
that appointment implied a reduction in
the number of classes I had to it so
before I had a teaching assistant at TA
right all of a sudden I had no theory at
all so I needed to do all the things
that that my TA was doing my teaching
assistant was doing nothing I thought
continuously intuition to the rescue I'm
going to use continuous integration
right so I'm going to use the milestones
as code review so I'm actually going to
review what people are are sending right
I was doing that a little bit before but
not very stenciling basically whatever
it was checking that there was no
conflict so when people were modifying
the file they were not conflicting with
each other maybe if I saw something
coming very very early I took a look at
it and told them maybe you should do it
this way or that way but all of a sudden
remember I had a ham no TA so the tea I
was checking things so I said mmm pearl
is my ta check so I was using pear for
doing continuous integration write all
the checks that were done before by the
meditating a system I'm going to do is
to do to do it using continuous
integration which I wasn't seen before
so amended before I was doing people
were in pull request accepted all of
them except there was some conflict now
I was doing something completely
different I was writing tests for what
people were so Mary right so my try or
not
it says objects ha ha fell I'm not
accepting
pull requests so that means that the
student has to go back to this
repository and fix whatever is what's
been done before right what are we
checking it's important take into
account that the project is completely
free so it's they can use whatever
language they want it's not boilerplate
is absolutely not boilerplate in fact
people were using most of language in
Python but even the people who were
raised in Python degrees in different
frameworks because what they had to do
was to deploy a web service to do it to
the cloud some of them were in flask
some of them were using had some other
people were using in ODS and they were
seen as press some other people raised
in Ruby and they were seen either
Sinatra or kuba I think that I'm not
sure I think that both of them were
reason one of them question go no frame
were all so he had all kinds of
different languages I didn't have to
look at whatever they were doing but the
effect the actual effect the real thing
so if you're deploying a web service I
want to see if it's working right so
what do we check the first thing and
this is quite important is that the
assignment is you have already modified
a single line in the file because they
have to modify file and sometimes what
they did you know they stumble or
sometimes they have an old version of
the file so they changed things and then
they then submitted the wrong file
so I had to check that actually there
was only one row in the table you have
seen before that was to be modified
right so I could instruct a single URL
from that from nothing and that that's
the first thing in the check so if they
have our own version of the file
whatever do it was caught right here and
so that the ripple URL is correct so
it's a it's a github repository and it's
actually correct so people sometimes
submit something you know with with
typos or whatever and it's not working
so that's the second thing I have to
check if it's actually correct I
whispered right this is the first thing
I do it's a first test they're passing
so first thing is I use this get
module which is it's a good thing
because it comes with git but it's also
in Sipan so etcetera it's a module let's
call it and I'm gonna do this I get a
diff so I get a diff between the
the version of the file and the version
I have now I checked that it's only one
line right and then I also check that
they have modified the correct file all
kind of things if if it doesn't it
doesn't follow that that regular
expression they fell but if it follows
the regular expression from the diff
file I extract the information on the
repository that I'm going to check later
on right right now the only thing I'm
using this is it second thing is it a
single line that that's important
because if it's not a single line
there's something wrong with it whatever
they might be a conflict that there is
another subtle error that is sometime
they change the qualification of the
file so when the when they get the file
they edit it sometimes it changed this
qualification for letting one to you
they you have utf-8 or the other ground
so they changed the whole file that
happens quite a lot and I've been some
times I have had to fix the whole file
and it's been quite quite quite really
bad worse thing was to find out who was
would be for that and you know maybe
take up some crazy whatever but
important thing is is it a single line
suit are they man different a single
line because that's kind of a sanity
check and then of course you have to
download the repo because this is all
being done in let's say the class
repository it's a single repository
contains a check and everything they
have to download the repo I'm gonna
start to do things on them so I'm using
the the system get a mission Travis also
desig in there I mean it's already and
well I start the user of the name I put
everything into a temporary directory
its Travis so I mean it doesn't really
matter well what happens I think about
this is something something as necessary
they will see and then eventually we
create the repository and we we start to
get all the files in the repository
using git commands right so first of all
follow me any question so far okay
they can use in tests more very simple
test module do you know it already to
probably have used it I could probably
use something else I even wanted to put
more things into the Travis because just
imagine people are physically waiting
for the outcome of the other thing to
get out so the more and the more modules
I use the more they have to wait and
sometimes I wait to so I get an email
telling me that somebody has done a pull
request and then I go there to see if
it's working or not if it's not working
I try to to guide them to the word so
you need a little bit but basically
those two things are the only parameter
I use for the time being right as I said
I am using Travis it's a relatively
simple configuration file it's not going
to it to get any better
No
anyway below that it's really proof -
see the only thing it does is it stops
that's more test harness get try the
slurp and some some other modules it
does prove because the test is included
in the repository it's not some external
test so that the the file they are going
to modify to make to some submit
assignment and the and the test they
it's a single script it's right there
right so you start to check this is the
actual history bill histories you see my
stone for fell fell pass pass pass fail
right so they submitted it first
sometimes sometimes it because what's a
hell of course when that happens if I'm
available I see it that say okay it
looks at the frost fell take it account
that I write the name of the test so
sometimes I realized that the name that
the test that has well is not too
informative so I go back to the - to the
script and change the message that it's
issue is saying okay this is DJ song in
your Ranger Joe Hall service is not
right
whatever I try to make it as informative
as possible right so that they know
exactly in which step they have fail I'm
also checking presence of files and
directors in the rebel they have to do
something like first they have to deploy
to a pass like like Heroku then they had
to deploy to to a another different path
using containers so I have to check
whether they stopped docker file for
instance then eventually they have to
submit something you seen you see some
deployment tool like fabric or
Capistrano or whatever so I have to
check whether there is an actual file
that does that I have to check with that
there is a bug on file I have to check
whether there is a real me not MD
all those files I check it right at the
very beginning I check three things
first things they have a real me second
thing is they have a license because
this is all free software so whatever
you do I tell them from the get-go that
it's free software so they had to
understand at age three and they have to
respec
the licensing everything so there must
be a license file and then they have a
they must have a dot get ignore file
because it's something saying and it's a
best practice for so that's kind of
essentially you can see all that in
there too
and then I get the real me and I tell
them do you have to tell me where is
your docker file in docker hub using
this format do you have to tell me what
you have deployed your your project
using this format right and then stacked
everything from that so if that if they
tell me I have deployed to Heroku in
this address so I struck that using a
regular expression from the readme and I
check it I go to Heroku I check it right
using other UWB simple right test fails
sometimes fails for many different
reasons first reason is that usually
people are not acquainted with this kind
of thing
for for your student they have never
used tests they have never used Travis
they have never used bit which is
absolutely appalling actually the first
assignment is they have to open an
account in github and modify the file
and do it with it so sometimes I had to
give didn't know what's a web service so
they are in the last year of their under
words they have no idea of what
web service so they tell me so it's like
the web I know PHP no that's not so I
mean they have all kind of things
besides you know this is a perl script
that's at Cena in a directory and you
can actually put the perl script into
your own thing right there is only one a
student has on that only one the rest
hasn't done a single thing they haven't
realized that there's a Perl script they
can check to see everything the house
anyway it's no big deal it's already in
the description of the assignment they
say you have to include this in rhythm
dreamy file you have to you need to have
this in this thing
but I mean at the end of the day they're
using this as an actual test for their
assignment so that they're actually
throwing it you don't like like
spaghetti today to the ceiling to see
whether it sticks or not right
I do scraping why do i do scraping
because at the beginning something they
had to do is they had to actively use
milestones and issues my son's issues
and comets so they had to put every
issue in a milestone they have to close
every single you see using a committee
so they had to organize the project as I
said in the beginning in real life right
so at the beginning I was I was
intending to use github API but you
probably know that if you are using if
you're doing a public was in Travis you
can't use environment variables because
this could be it could be a security
hole so I can't use any kind of
environment variables to use my API I
mean I'm a github API token so that I
check the github API so instant API
using scraping I check my stones and
issues and commit it's relatively simple
so for instance it got to my song info'
it's just very simple regular
expressions you get if it's the if it's
hopping of its cross or whatever then as
you can see this very well but anyways
it I mean this is in the in my
repository to anyway where I use also
scrape the milestone page I scrape the
issues page I scrape the comic page and
I extract whether it's actually a
weather or whether an issue has been
actually closed by a comet or not all
that using very simple regular
expression then I have to check I piece
I had to check rest api's I had to check
your elf as I said they have to upload a
docker file - to docker hub so I have to
check whether it's actually there
whether it's working whether it extract
actually been built this is actually a
la you see that we are cloning whatever
milestone wanna start to my cell 3 then
whatever I think this is actually
you see that you are else this is Amazon
URL this is a Seco URL
hello cou your atmosphere up there so
yeah all that is known you have to do
things like this you have to check what
I tell them is you have to deploy a web
service and what the West Services is
they have to they need to have a route
that status that returns okay of course
most people not not people but a lot of
people they do it is they deploy a
single server I was sorry that that's
only that so it's a web service a single
route so I I will have to think about
that next year so maybe maybe do some
kind of I don't know maybe maybe
describe using using what's the name of
that thing used to describe of services
that's not rough Collies that's open api
no open api so as water that's the thing
so good troll if you tell them next year
is angle to try to do a small Hakkasan
from the very beginning so that they
program the the web service could mean
different web services they test them
and everything and I would tell them to
describe it using swallow but for the
time I think they have to do is to
deploy it using a status which I mean
it's not easy it's not easy for them
they really have to do so they had to
really do do that and and for them it's
something that they have never done
before and I mean my subject my class is
not about web services it's about the
cloud so I have to kind of you know
teach them all kind of different things
I need to do to do it correctly and this
is something I do that was actually very
nice I they had they have to use Amazon
AWS or erasure for for deploying a
little machine they have to tell me the
IP of the little machine I have to check
that actually the vector machine is
working so I use net pink which is
incredibly nice just a couple of things
I use port 22 because that's support
that actually has to be running you need
to at least a port so that you can
connect from from
from outside actually but they have a
limited amount of resources on nature
and AWS and what they do is as soon as
it passes the test they turn it down and
that's it so they decide money and they
can use the rest of the money you know
to mine Bitcoin or whatever thing is
sesame a lot of time so it actually is
really really helpful for me when when I
get something that's correct I know that
it's got all the basic things that have
to be there so I can go to the rich 40
kilometers away from my home I can spend
the day there I can dip my toes in the
water actually this house over here
belongs to the former queen of Belgium
it's called Villa Astrid belong to the
today the former king of well you
actually died there and I have got an
apartment there and there I'm going to
do to be not moving because you know I
live in the in the city but I go from
time to time to check a fit it's
actually been built because it's not
built yet so I go there I go to the
beach spend a Saturday with my wife and
my daughters I couldn't do that before I
literally couldn't do that before I mean
it saves hours literally hours but I'm
the professor and the whole point of
doing this kind of thing is not for the
professor to do each could be but it's
not is it good for the student that's a
very important thing but whatever you do
something in class that's the first
thing and last thing you have to ask is
it good for the students are they
learning more this is a graph of the
number of students that have actually
turn in a milestone right this is this
year this and this were the two previous
year this is the number of students
right so in let's look at this one for
instance I started with around 55
students second milestone no sound third
milestone goes now last my son was even
Downer
I was a students were dropping out of
this of the case
there is a said another this is not for
me I can't I can't possibly do this so
it's not something I can do
last year it was like this I had less
students because of course some of
things not told me
subject is impossible I can't do that so
I got I got about half the students this
year this year I got even less but I
said okay I gotta do something you see
that the drop drop out rate the decaying
rate of the number of Satine is very
very very much you're gonna have they're
gonna always have students at drop out
for reason that are completely unrelated
to this target because sometimes they
are right this is the in Spain the
degrees are four years I got a student a
lot of them who still have classes and
subjects from first gear algebra physics
because of course you need physics to do
a webpage or to do a web service you
have to first you know put electricity
into the those damn chips and you know
all kind of things some of them have
some resume algebra is difficult but
they make absolutely not
I'm telling this because my daughters
are doing computer science in my same
school so I know from firsthand what the
what they do anyway I got some many
students who have subject from other
Jesus also they have to go to excellence
they have to turn in assignments and
they just say okay I just can can do
this we also we also have a telegram
group and I actively okay I'm going to
put this my V after every milestone if
if I see that the student has interning
his is my stone I ask him what's the
matter is something wrong with you do
you need help please come by get to my
get my office we can tell whatever
I can't even able to save some of them
and using that so I'm not going to say
that this is precisely because of what
have been doing but it protocols
funny thing is I also use pearl for this
do you have everything in the repository
so
what I have done I have published to sip
on this this module is called git repo
commits its release to to eczema in the
comments so what eczema is the author of
the commits the date of the commit or
whatever so I can get very nice a
statistic what's going on in my mind and
this is a in general this called
learning analytics it's something that
lots of people talk about but very few
people though do precisely because the
problem is that the platform that people
are using which is Moodle usually
doesn't allow you to do this Munna has a
very nice API most universities for
security reasons they close the API in
my university it's even better because
they closed the API for everyone in the
university but they open it for a bank
that has created the official app for my
university that's why I'm not going to
name it and not proud of that
just imagine no single professor no
single student no single staff in the
university can access the notes in the
Moodle using the Moodle API but the
database of grades of every single
student in the university is open to a
bank because of course that's not a
security issue because banks are back in
second anyway my point was that you can
do
learning analytics on Moodle at least in
my university I can do very easily
learning analytics using this Perl
module which is which is available in
Sepang I just I just release version 0.1
point 4.0 so I got for instance I
checked the my system which is basically
a file
I checked the Comets I see who is been
the commuter and I can't count the
number of authors I can candidate
whatever I see things like this how many
modifications of the file have been done
this year this particular year we have
do this this is in green the others are
are in are in blue and red so that the
two previous one what do we see here
at the beginning people were doing lots
of changes I mean every every person was
with lots of changes quite usually
because of conflict they were getting
and still getting the handle of the of
the of the system they did conflict this
year that didn't happen there were no
conflicts because remember I was
checking that they were only doing a
single line so conflict almost almost
impossible it can happen if there is
some grace condition so that that there
is a pull request and there are another
pool request another pool because I
haven't accepted the first one so the
third one might be in topic that usually
doesn't happen in that case usually I
also fix it myself but as you proceed
with the number of milestones this is
the last one
do you see that people this year this
particular year are doing more
resubmissions why because they are
submitting they say that it fails and
they are doing it again and again and
again until it works right that's good I
mean why not they are learning they are
learning in the process they're
submitting something they are saying it
this doesn't work so without
compromising their grade they are
improving and they are learning so
that's something I disappoint I want to
stress a lot for most people evaluation
is just grading evolution is learning do
you have to create the process of
evaluation so that people actually learn
with it you can just say I'm going to do
this action in October and then in
February I give you the grade that's
impossible you don't learn anything out
of that whatever you were doing there
you completely forgot in this case they
are learning while there that they have
this epiphany okay and do this wrong
in many cases they're purely mechanic
things like you know the URL is not
assert a curry but in some cases they
actually start to wonder snow good day I
was requested from from them and they
are doing that through the test process
and this is a little bit difficult to
explain but let me see if I get that
first thing once again Green is this
year red and blue previous years right
don't look at the dates the the calendar
has changed anything don't look at the
look look at the shape of the car first
of this year that meant that one day
before the deadline they started to turn
in the assignment it's a few of them the
day of assignment david bulk of them
were submitting it and then after the
Simon of course some people did it they
can do that
I am kind of flexible with with the
dates so if they turn it like a on
delayed to delayed whatever I say okay
doesn't matter if they do one week late
I say I will put a penalty of one point
but it's no big deal
but the shapes previously were very very
very you know sharp this year what
happened people and this is just one my
son it was the last one but it pretty
much happens everywhere what uses that
people start to submit assignments way
before the deadline
why because they want to have time to
fix it before it's actually graded so
they say okay I'm going to do this one
week before even two weeks before the
assignment I will just do it if it's
wrong I don't care the test is going to
tell me if it's wrong it's not going to
go through to the professor who is going
to tell me none of this fails so you
have to turn it Irene right check it out
I mean this is December 15 so that I
think that the deadline was December
21st so it's pretty much around here
then during Christmas people were doing
turning in things then eventually there
was another another pick here so people
were doing it whenever they they you
know so it fit so they were using it in
their they were incorporating the thing
in the learning process and they were
also trying to do things so that so that
they could have time to fix everything
they were learning much better they were
they were organizing their time much
better learning outcomes were for me
very very good and actually students
told me that so I asked them whenever I
needed they had to turn in a milestone I
always I always do a sorbet I asked them
what they feel what they feel about the
way of doing class what they feel about
the subject whether they think that it's
going to be useful for them or not but
in the last one I asked think what what
they thought about this system
this says it's not complete but what it
says is it helped me to submit something
that's correct
already you remember when you were a
student you put it so my assignment or
whatever you were waiting for the grades
maybe one week two weeks one month
whatever maybe maybe before the final
exam that was absolutely appalling
people were you know stressed out
because before the final exam didn't
know whether when they do this except if
they are actively trying to cheat they
know that they're going to get six out
of ten six or seven all right all of
them they know that in the very moment
that they have tournament so that's the
thing that they they like no they say it
complicates my life four of them said
that out of 20 students I can understand
that but sometimes it complicates a life
that you know it's no big deal it's
because they didn't read the
specifications correctly so they they
put the URL in a wrong place or whatever
it helps me think this one it tells me
to to be sure of the great egg hub so
that that's another value so they feel
they feel empowered with with this kind
of thing so I don't feel disenfranchised
like this is a machine a machine is
turning things because after that I have
to grab but when I grade I know that
pretty much everything is in its place
semester is over now it's not over
actually yesterday and today I'm still
getting because I expect we have a
regular exome and then we have a special
exam so some people who have failed
because they didn't turn him there my
son one time there are still so
yesterday I had to accept like four or
five pull requests and today also a
couple so I got stuff to do so I got my
assignments for for myself first one is
I want to create a simple module why
several reasons first reason is I don't
want the code we in the same repository
so that some some smart student can you
know look at the other code so that they
had to go another steps maybe to be able
to do today to to sit back and see
what's going on anyway
I have two subjects and it was all
hacked together so I have a lot of
common code for the master I have one
escape for the other shall I one escape
I was moving things back and forth not
nice I also want to do tests of the code
so right now the test was the first
student was submitting their assignment
I told him okay hold on there is
everything okay I need to check this
it's okay it's okay so I usually get
them bit a tester grade and also
stickers because everyone loves the
stickers the world loves great stupid
stickers and then I want to stand test I
mean think about it you can do pretty
much everything you can check you can do
spell check
I don't know if I want to do this
because spell check is going to be just
terrible
I can actually check the commit so I can
check whether they are doing the whole
thing like milestones commission or
thing I should check using swagger the
full rest API so that they have to
declare the roots or whatever check for
plagiarism I have found lots of a
students who cheat you know people do
that all the time
okay I'm out we do it on lessons learn
you have to innovate but only to improve
a student a student experience you don't
have to innovate to save time it's good
but you have to do it to improve student
students periods and you have to check
if it does know you look at the students
they see happy they smile you know they
like the stickers no no no you actually
have to ask them anonymously whether you
are doing okay or not
little scripting goes a long way and
that's it thank you very much
[Applause]