you know it's a
a path from today into the future and
it's not really clear what that path
looks like but of course we have some
hopes and some dreams I think just as
all of us did when we started an open
source and so today I want to talk a
little bit about thinking about the
future both from the internet and the
web and free software so in the future
it's clear floss is everywhere floss is
everywhere today and this is really
quite remarkable you know in the early
days of mozilla floss was sort of
radical and really sort of everyone who
wasn't involved in it knew that floss
was some odd thing that maybe developers
did but that really wouldn't have impact
and there would always be small and sort
of developer II like and in the United
States we were called socialists and on
American and such things so false
everywhere today seems maybe obvious
when you think about it but certainly
was not at the time and so I think a few
things have gone into that one you know
the right idea at the right time to a
deep need for real collaborative work
and development and three the early very
early work of license plus community has
also been a model and so not only is
Foss everywhere today but the open part
of it is everywhere from open source and
open standards where we started to open
data open government open science
citizen science and so some of these
core ideas from floss through the work
of these groups us actually has become
much more mainstream and has moved even
out of floss not always in the free
software moniker but certainly in the
open moniker and that's a really
exceptional piece to have accomplished
in 20 years or so and sometimes there's
a
the cost of success so today meet github
is obvious
it doesn't necessarily carry all the
values or the thoughts are the things
that go into foster care for some it
does for some it doesn't it's just the
way of working and so there are many
things about floss that are mainstream
today which is wild success and also
means that there's still more to do
because you know while floss is
everywhere closed systems are everywhere
- and so floss software soft cloth
libraries floss developers and
communities have gotten much stronger
but in the Internet today are really
encased and wrapped in and often
developed to the general consumer inside
a deeply closed system and so we can see
do you think about the online life not
so much of developing but of actually
engaging with activities and the human
experience
despite the layers of floss it's really
a small number of closed systems and so
on its own sort of without interest
without us without the other activists
for freedom and openness and choice you
can imagine that these closed systems
the human experience on the Internet
for most consumers will continue for
quite a while sooner or later they may
decay or some new technology or new
business model might come along but
that's not apparent in you know the next
few years and so the questions of floss
and what we can do does our work in our
projects here affect the internet affect
the experience and if so might we tune
our work our thinking to have more
impact and so of course that's the
intersection that Mozilla lives in I
mean born out of floss communities
standing on the shoulders of giants but
also very focused on the end
and so the use of floss software and
user control and choice and safe and
secure software in our case really aimed
at online life both the structure of the
network itself and the human experience
and so for this question of you know the
future of the Internet I want to frame
it today in three questions and three
responses so the first one how do values
that bill floss or build free software
and open-source communities how can they
get built or expanded and modified and
really built into the fabric of the
Internet more we see them in the
development methodology of much of the
software in the internet but we don't
see nearly as much in the human
experience and so one question is what
might that look like what might we do
what are we doing today if there are
many of us thinking about these
questions how do we join together and
become more effective you know second
question will the future be webby now
for those of us certainly have a certain
vintage we came online to the web or the
world wide web and the Internet underlay
it but the graphical user face and the
ability to navigate and to move easily
outside a command line was the web and
there are certain things about the web
that made it powerful and that reflected
many of the aspirations of flossed
software now today many people don't
know much of the web and certainly if
you come online for the first time on a
phone and in
the environments in the world you may
not actually know about the web actually
mostly what many people know about is
Facebook so that distinguishing
differences between Facebook and the
Internet are unclear but then when you
try to get to the web or what do we mean
about the web or the link or hypertext
that's another stage altogether and so
I'm not a believer it's the
responsibility of those billions of
people to understand what the web is and
why it's different I'm a believer that
as technologists and projects people
interested in this part of the world
it's really ours to make it clear what
is great it was great about the web
what's great about the internet and
where freedom lips like you can have
protocols that have more or less freedom
and openness built into them you can
have technology that's the same way and
you can have apps and human experience
that provide a better foundation for
more freedoms for more people and so
this question of will it be webby is not
a question of whether people will talk
about the web but it's a question of how
much freedom is actually built in there
and so we use the link or I do you know
as as one very clear example of what
that means i I see many technologists
cringe when I say this but but I view
the link as a distributed simple
mass-market data structure where any
human being can take the knowledge the
wealth of knowledge available online at
least in a webby format online and we
can make our own narratives through that
and we can make a path through different
kinds of data different formats from
text to video to voice to a RvR in the
future without having a to go to someone
and ask permission without having to
learn
underlying technologies and so the web
was linkable in a two-way fashion you
know if the information was out there on
a server connected to the right
protocols you could get to it and from
there you can get out of it back into
someplace else and so it wasn't
systematized into these closed lock
systems so the web is linkable the web
is interoperable and the web is set up
in a way that there's a piece of
software out there that represents you
not the website not the publisher that's
got content not whoever owns the server
but you and that's the browser and
that's why we build the browser I mean
we love the browser Mozilla you know and
we love Firefox we love the browser me
too but but we love it at its heart
because it is the tool that can
represent each one of us and and this
arcane piece of software can can
represent me a visa via web site
anything from as simple as I want all
the text bigger on every website I go to
to I don't want to see your ads and your
trackers can't follow me and so this
question of who represents you or who
represents me in an online experience is
an open question when we get outside of
the old world wide web and the browser
and so sometimes people ask Mozilla well
why are you so interested in the browser
and that's the reason because that's our
model to date of how we represent you
and how we might build a stronger and
more powerful place for you to exercise
freedoms in your online experience and
yes moving outside of the desktop
browser into the other areas or the
modes that we use is important to us and
but the browser continues to be
important I mean it's very cool and it's
it's amazingly complex technology and we
understand it but the other root of why
we continue to be deeply focused on it
as it is the model it's no longer the
universal client that it used to be but
it is the model for how we take freedom
and openness and start to put them in
the hands of consumers in some much more
easy-to-use fashion so question 2 still
quite open and you know in the 1990s
when we went through this the first time
there was a set of activity that turned
out to be illegal tying the operating
system into the browser blocking out
competition sets of rules so that was
nice and the EU was a leader in this and
this was true in the US as well so
that's not the case today
you know today all of the things that
were illegal because they were bad for
competition bad for choice allowed will
say monopolies are near millat not
monopoly control stifled innovation
today they're all legal but Apple
started the system Apple had very small
market share but now Google does this
Microsoft does it again
you know the edge browser will reset
your default browser almost every time
it updates so it seems so there's
there's a range of activities that were
clearly wrong in the first go-round with
the web and today whether they're wrong
or not is one thing but they're not
illegal as they were and so that means
there there is a lot of work to do and
the interest in the closed systems is
much more now in the closed system level
there's growing concern about especially
in Europe you know Google Apple Facebook
George Soros you know this week made the
connection between the size and scope of
these closed platforms and the loss of
innovation and business opportunity so I
think awareness as can
but we're back in us in a setting where
the things that we knew were
demonstrably bad for all of us in
society are all quite legal and they're
the norm once again
so lots of work to keep keep on there
and the third question how do we tackle
the new experiences that are clear about
the Internet today we have known for a
long time that surveillance is a problem
so I don't think of that as a new one
it's an issue that continues and maybe
gets worse now that we have sort of
commercial advertising based
surveillance that we participate in but
there's a whole new set of issues that
have become very clear in the last few
years
it turns out just having all the
information of the world at your
fingertips doesn't mean everybody
searches knowledge more it turns out
that we're all online doesn't
necessarily bring us closer together
that there's a lot of devices you know
it turns out that the differences in
communities don't go away
and class and status and gender and
ethnic issues show up in in many ways
unmonitored online and so that's a good
size set of issues and it's easy to look
around and say wow you know the thing
that we really loved the internet the
web it's got a lot of problems now and
that's certainly true and many of those
problems as best I can figure it out
come from the fact that the early
internet architecture was designed by
people of generally the same perspective
a they're all trying to work together
they were trying to make something that
was interoperable they were trying to
build technology and they were trying to
build a community and they were very
clear about the social engineering and
the nature of community that they were
building and they were wildly successful
we have the Internet today
taken eating everything but they were
not among themselves fighting they were
not playing out ethnic racial gender
political religious differences among
them in the things that they were doing
and so the system that was designed
works great and it doesn't yet have
mechanisms in it for when all of
humanity is involved and all of our
differences show up there's a fair
amount of freedom of activity and not
the same kinds of I would say
community-based accountability
mechanisms and so you see people free
feeling quite free you know to to say
and do really horrendous Thanks so yeah
how does start with a happy talk okay so
three questions and so one of the things
that we're trying to do what mozilla is
to try to answer some of these questions
not to have the only answers but to be
part of the set of people who are
actively trying to engage with this
amazing thing the web now the internet
that can connect us in so many ways and
needs attention so what how are we
thinking about it well Pat one the
starting point
you know floss freedom and openness and
collaborative development and what we're
increasingly learning about communities
and building healthy and increasingly
diverse communities it's a range of
values that certainly falls down
demonstrates how deep and how far and
how wide they appeal to people and how
you apply them in different ways and
every year there's new projects applying
these in places and
you never would have thought of so
there's something in the set of values
that build this community and we don't
quite have a way to express those values
in data because floss software
especially the really powerful software
sits at the heart of a lot of data
systems you name it Amazon Google
Facebook right but but we don't actually
address the questions of openness and
freedom in data in a cohesive way and
that makes sense you know it took a
while for the free software definition
to be developed it took a while for the
entire new system to be developed you
know many many years to develop each of
the components that ended up in Linux
and so is not surprising that when we
get outside of pure software and we get
into other areas that we don't have the
consensus or the cohesion about what is
open data how do you protect freedom how
do you protect individuals so that's an
area of real focus and at mozilla in
particular we have wrenched ourselves
around into dealing with data because
our approach for many years is we don't
want any data then we never have to
think about any data and it allows us to
have a whole range of privacy and
security practices and to stay out of a
lot of problems because we have no data
well turns out a it's very hard to build
a decent product and there she's in
quantum is so much better as we finally
understand it but on a deeper level our
mission to try and make the Internet
open and accessible to all and a global
public recent resource and a decent
place to live requires dealing with data
data is everywhere now and it's powerful
it's explosive and it's powerful so
we're looking into it and hoping
to find and connect with others in the
floss world who are interested and/or
already developing certain principles
about data same thing about cloud
services
you know since floss is triggered on
distribution the requirements of
copyleft don't really apply to the large
cloud services and so we don't have a
you know we don't have our values deep
in those systems so what does that mean
this has been you know a contentious
topic certainly philosophical from RMS
from way back so maybe we will always
have the same view that if you're not
distributing a copy of the code that
copyleft isn't acceptable and that
therefore cloud services go off on their
own but I certainly would like as a
community to meet to think about it and
look at that pretty carefully and see if
that's the full sum of our thinking on
those things and finally the experience
which is data that by this I mean the
human experience
which is these closed system pieces what
what can we should we be doing and so
you know there are many of you that are
more involved in some of these areas or
have been involved productively longer
than Mozilla house and so I and I and I
think a bunch of no zillions who are
here are pretty interested in learning
and hearing what your experiences are
and I think you will see Mozilla engage
more deeply on these sort of topics as
we go forward and they are hard
questions data and privacy and security
are hard to manage but I feel that the
mission requires it and it in some ways
it feels pure to say we're never going
to have data because then we never make
a mistake with data but I think it's so
a little taking the easy way out and I
think the state of the world doesn't
allow us to take the easy way out
so I also am sure we will make some
mistakes with data like I wish we could
be perfect but we don't or we won't
we're only human
so you will see us make some mistakes
with data and I ask in that case
you know let us know call us on it but
please try to be gentle as well it is
one thing that drives me crazy in
Silicon Valley where people will just
feel free to haul in and tell Mozilla
just how terrible we are while they work
at Google and are doing these like more
invasive things and then wave their
hands and say oh but you're a nonprofit
you're supposed to be better like that
frees them to go off and be really nasty
people so let's not do that to each
other if we can will the future be webby
I sure hope so
because the ability to have something
represent me in the world is really key
that needs interoperability it needs
competition these are a few of the
things that Mozilla is doing here these
are the technology side like will the
future be webby has a technology side it
has a community side and it has a system
architecture level side that last piece
is hard to crack in the mobile space on
telephones I mean because that's it
that's an ecosystem that's you know 10
years old and pretty entrenched we're
not done trying but in the mean time and
so you can see that the deep voice
essentially open-source library for
voice but you know those those may
become system tools but we also you know
continue to explore various technologies
that otherwise we think would end up
living only in the silos of the
proprietary organizations so we continue
to work on this and of course to look
around always both when we're here and
increasingly in general and see who else
is working on that and can we can
Mozilla do the things that we see but
can we better be better at supporting
the community of people doing others so
I hope you see these projects and find
them interesting but I also hope that we
see you and what you're doing and get
better at supporting and on the third
one this one's really tough because
those new issues get you right straight
into well who decides is it daxing you
know is it really violence do you get to
talk about X is that
censorship who decides what about free
speech and so those are really hard
problems and we certainly are big
believers in individual action and free
speech and yet the Internet experience
as it is today is not acceptable so we
can't do nothing and so where we are so
far you know Mozilla has a manifesto
that's what guides us that's what we the
set of principles that Mozilla is about
that we hope anyone who cares about
those can relate to and so we have begun
adding some aspirations to them they're
not hard core principles yet because we
don't know how to strike the balance
between human community activity that
some behavior is not acceptable and what
does accountability look like with free
speech and freedom and individuals being
responsible for themselves those are
very hard so we're not saying this is
the way life has to be but we want
clearly to set out some aspirations for
the world we're building I do not want
to build a web or an internet that is
good for government and commercial
stalkers and violence and hatred and
divisive misinformed beings trying to do
Tisa things so we have a few additional
aspirations and I'll just let you read
them here and then I'm going to close on
that
and so those are actually in a public
Google group but probably the URL isn't
well known so you will see the start to
come out in more easy to find places in
the next couple weeks and again we
realize you know individual control and
freedom and government censorship are
real issues so happy to engage on that
but if you can be gentle I'd appreciate
it
and and obviously the hope is that we
have floss everywhere as we go forward
but in more open systems generally thank
you
[Applause]