welcome to the unbearable strikes back
so it's a in French it's it's cooked
like vampire off to strike back and
obviously it doesn't work in English but
thank you for coming here so let's
listen tries YouTube I'm from a Skype
chocobos is not here he's a little bit
shy but so that's good we have a poem
YouTube is a Dominic you want to watch a
video for a scientific video for cat
video do you like video yes you go to
youtube first that's a problem and it's
it's a big silo of data in the
disfranchised web we want and love and
it has over bad site users paying ads we
like hide in the room raise your hand if
you like hat your life and Noble
problems and this is a vicious circle so
more eaters use a more it has videos the
more users go to youtube first and if if
YouTube is the most view view sites for
videos users goes first
here and make a video makers come here
first so this should suck up we need to
break to break with that circle I'm
French so excuse make sense
if you want to have an alternative to
YouTube towards an ontology to YouTube
you have two big issues first you need
to have a lot of disk space it's a curse
the last of storage and then the
bandwidth I think I have read but
YouTube use 27% of worldwide bandwidth
in a year it was in 2015 I think so do
you want to pay the cost for bad
bandwidth if you you may want but you
don't have the money
hey it would cost a lot lot lot lot lot
lot lot lot lot of money we are in the
last class community we have video
hosting software but if you if it solves
the storage prime because you only ask
your own videos or videos of your
friends so whatever if you have a video
that goes viral you have the bandwidth
problem you don't have there is a
youtube infrastructure to serve to serve
a lot of people at the same time and
there's another problem you don't worry
you won't be discovered who's around
excuse me it's very complicated to say
it even in French serendipity what is
around ability it's when you go to
Wikipedia and look for whatever YouTube
cut and you end with no weave on the
page of medieval story of her friends Oh
first I was here no I'm here I learn a
lot of things but oh did I go here
because it speaks about YouTube is a
media is quite medieval system varies so
one of the castle Google and we are the
servants of the Lord of the castle so
whatever you don't have the strong dp/dt
in in your own hosting software because
you only you are strong videos and
videos of your friends obviously but
there is not an recommend a an algorithm
and nation algorithm
it's like when you when you will go and
a video on youtube about cats it you
like cat
you may want to watch these videos we've
cut so you don't have bad let's raise a
new hope so
let me introduce Peter it's a
self-esteem video platform the servers
are federated through activity pub
comments and likes are ferreted through
a q-tip app to choose where to run to
see video I explain each points on the
history of Petri began a long long time
ago in the country not so far away
because we're in Belgium and France is
not so far in began to cut an
alternative to YouTube better returns so
Phe like to be a trivia
thank you it began two years three years
ago he developed it on his free time for
two years slowly like everybody does
when it does things on its free time and
in October 2017 17 from a soft which is
a nonprofit organization which is my my
bus hiring for four months to work
full-time appear tube because for my
staffed believe in peer trip we we saw a
potential of be a trip and
it need to go to go to you need to cut
faster we need to have a free walking
platform quicker so we are from the
beginning checkup Asante two things he
wanted to failure 8 the server so you
can have the serendipity since the video
of one platform available are available
and the other on the other server and
you want it to share the bandwidth
between the Watchers of videos so with
that you would cut the two money too
many programs but you have to know that
it change a lot of thing through the two
years of developer of developing pho you
begin with jQuery
no it's angular 5 transpired from web
sweeps photo 14 at the beginning it was
the whole plane not ggs javascript no
use type spec - MongoDB I won't say
anything about Monday they don't like 3
+ 3 square which is a great great way to
add data path and from election website
for for sitting the videos why election
on the server because used web
WebRTC and only browsers provides
weather TC API so yet we yet to use an
external process with an electron with
electron I had less electron to seed the
video and finally the Federation
protocol which was developed for pure
Japanese so peer tube can talk to Pia
tube and Piatt ribbony and now I choose
activity pub which say
which means that but anything that talks
any activity bub can talk to Pierre trip
well for the Federation server
Federation it's quite like Twitter
server a can follows ever be we through
activity per - Thomas - do you know what
I mean it index is video of several B
and display them on I mean on its own
homepage so he mixes the video by
fetching the metadata of the video
description likes commands and so and so
on when it builds its annex and you can
watch the video of the be server from
the interface of the a server that's
quite cool isn't it but they are still a
stream from the be server it like very a
server it just a proxy not the interface
it just a proxy it's embedded we will go
in that later for the command like this
like Federation say user on server a
canned comment like dislike a video from
another server B reaction can be can our
pushed of our activity pub to the B
server and then replicated if the C the
C server receiver which is which follows
the be server as the met the same video
it fetched the V it got the the update
of the like dislike and comments and
since its activity per beware so it
since its activity pub any activity by
beware software can talk with PHP and
mass to know right now can do that it
may require some developments since my
sternum has to to implement the video or
not
I'm not I'm not the developer so I don't
know all the technical details but a
little bit of of code and it worked you
can go to from at that link /pha -
master room to see it in action
some somebody and master noone can
subscribe to a video maker on pier trip
so when when the video maker publish a
new video where is the truth in master
new that says a new video here and the
math student user can comment from
master no it's awesome
go here if you don't believe me but i
finally over lack of faith disturbing
so now the peer-to-peer viewers side of
the tube
each time you're viewing a video you're
sitting it just like BitTorrent you're
donating you have something you're
sitting in here you're viewing you're
sitting so if if a video goes viral so
more people are watching the video the
more cedar they are so i sure it may
help a little bit from the bandwidth for
the bandwidth issue one thing but will
but will make network administrator
happy is that you if we find cedars more
close to you from a network point of
view you will reduce the traffic and
jigs jigs big hub of Antionette and big
this is
exchange point and if you don't have to
go to an exchange point to view the
video because we're cedars right next to
you you're on your neighbor it will
reduce the traffic and it's it's a good
thing for the person
network pho is currently in alpha stage
but we should have a beta version from
the by the end of March maybe mid March
I don't know ask him and there is
already a lot of cool features in it
some federated videos with tax
categories like abuse on video
if you are hosting a video a video
platform you may want you will want to
to have an abuse system here this video
is you copyright shield or something
illegal and you have to you have to have
a system to to call the administrator
and Stella it's bad please remove it and
for in a federation it's complicated you
will not ask every administrator of
every server from from several but
following the original instance to say
please remove it no you remove once it's
remove a program basic user can register
remove air cond cool feature bit image
it with a disc cutter so you can open
your open your instance say hey
everybody come here
but without hundred mega walls admin
moderator user follow maybe in the
future there we will have more Wars if
if it's feel very the need master new
user will be quite Nova master new user
know that system that's up for work here
it's it's called explicit content so you
can you can flag a video saying it's a
create content you don't show the video
on
and the front page or you hide it you
have to take connection to actually
display it and more I don't know them
because I'm not the developer and there
is a lot a lot of future developments of
features that that will eventually come
subtitles would be cool a recommendation
algorithm better venue to venue - but
there was a story of someone who what -
to watch a video about about alt-right
management and or just republican party
here and I don't remember and so the
recommendation algorithm of YouTube said
hey you may like that you may like that
and more and more so the more videos she
would she'd she watched the more
outright she goes she goes so maybe a
better recommendation ago it just just
suggests more and more cuts and maybe
kittens upload a video from a new L or
turn file because follow you just are
too
you
and you have a multiple servers and you
want to share the bandwidth from all
these murals because for now the first
CD of a video is only the server where
the video is so video mirroring equal
most mysterious from the beginning an
RSS feed and more even the developer
doesn't know how much feature many
people want I'm sure SK is watching is a
detailed assurance than a say of all
that
well not for not just rally of it but
having a good alternative to YouTube is
is already a good good one map rather
still a lot of work where you head go to
github.com / 2 covers /pha frizzy frizzy
frizzy come to the rock slide we can
download the slides and from a duckling
/ pier trip - em - mm HEA 18 do you have
any question yes
talk to me don't be afraid yes
what happened what happened if if this
if the video is on Becerra and you're on
e server but follows the B server and
you want to watch the video from the
interface you want to watch the video
from the B server what happened if the
video has been deleted and the B server
for now you're screwed
but with me video mirroring it may have
a cache but if the video is DT than the
B server if if it's a censorship problem
because if there is a video maker they
decided to delete the video it's it's
problem its admin of the instance GG in
the video because it was a an illegal
video or whatever it's a novel prime for
censorship with the the video mirroring
system you may have you may still have
the video but the video mirroring is not
ready yet but we hope to have it it
sends a roadmap it in so it's a feature
matter which is a but as a but have high
priority first of all thank you so much
for being so awesome and and really
seriously farmer soft is just
and I'm thank you in person for
translating some of my articles into
French that means a lot to us but a
question which platforms are the videos
support on because I couldn't run it on
iOS and Mac right now is that a codec
issue or Safari Safari is right now not
compatible with YouTube YouTube web
browser it's fits you we have to wait
but Safari the implements features that
are not available yet I think the
problem is the same for edge maybe edge
does it work okay head
okay yeah
is there plenty of different policies
for the different servers like they to
accept some videos and some surveys or
was a pre-approved videos it's quite
like the same problem same thing when
Mastodon instance you may want to have
an instance just for cards for everyone
just for dogs whatever it's the
administrator of the instance but but
tells the policy and for the Federation
if the a server follows a piece of the a
server serves have a video of everything
VB server only is on yup video of cat
and you may think why white video of
cats a way of video of B server which is
cat Sony you can see them on a server
well it's the Federation but you can
blacklist you can blacklist the server
you can say no you won't follow me
you won't follow my server and so you
can keep your your server private from
semi-private matching the Federation and
you can in either the administrator of
the instance choose who to follows if
you want to have only cats video on your
server you may say the administrator
will only follow instance of cats videos
or Sarah so does it answer your question
not sure
can anybody near me can repeat the
question because he doesn't have a mic
now you can't unknow ammad in the future
you said that basically the first CD is
only the server on which the video was
first uploaded well except for mirrors
in the future etc so if server with a
large storage space comes up and have
one viewer video which means a lot of
videos it will probably bring the server
to its knees right yeah you will have
the bandwidth program and I don't know
about the RAM or CPU issues when it sees
its top toaster performance
he said it's small so you may you it may
work but if you have a billion video and
billion people but one people when
people are one on each video yeah you
have to test it wouldn't that be a way
to bring down a server
I mean maliciously like if you have a
large server and you open one connection
per video after browsing yes you are
pretty much sure you will hit a lot of
videos that we are not sitting at the
moments
Thanks just we we may want to we may
taste it
launch launch test instance but right
now it's an alpha and before that we we
want a thing that works so my question
would be I think it's really important
that we get good performance in terms of
streaming videos if it's too slow people
won't use it what if I am the user on
the Federation so and I would like to
help it with storage and bandwidth so
even when I'm not watching videos or and
watching other videos than other people
I would still like to donate my storage
and bandwidth to those people can I do
that
like almost it choose web torrents and
some some torrents software's issues to
implement web torrent a web torrent is
not like the BitTorrent protocol exactly
so it'd have to be adapted and you in
the future you may be able to launch
transmission or deluge whatever and
download the file and see the file like
any of our torrents but you have to we
have to wait for torrents of softwares
to implement web torrent Tommy's up in
Seattle
[Applause]
you