so hi everybody and welcome to the gold
Avram Boston 2018 we have the same room
that last time which is too small and it
still prismo so thank you so much for
lining it up and like being patient and
I be nice to the people at the door
we're trying to be nice to YouTube which
is hard sometimes anyway so we're gonna
be and we're gonna start the talk we're
gonna start the dev room with the state
of Go which I've given a bunch of times
and we're gonna be talking about where
we are today which is almost almost
releasing go and attend we still not
there we so I'm Franciscan poet by the
way I used to be a developer advocate at
Google cloud platform and the go team
and now I work as a VP of the power
relations at source which are the ones
doing these t-shirts and all the cool
stuff and we're hiring now that I've
said that so go under Edwards released
one year ago here at fuzzum basically
and go what the nine is already nine
months old and if you don't know what
it's new and go under nine there's a lot
of cool stuff that I will not cover here
because there's already enough stuffing
or one no ten so we're gonna be talking
about go one not ten which is already
out kinda there's a release candidate
one that was released in January 25 and
you should check it out it it's very
easy to download also you can try with
docker directly if you want to try it
and we're gonna be talking about all the
things that will release and go under
ten which is not much but there's
actually a lot you will see why and yeah
go on the table release soon we don't
know when those lights are online if you
want to check them out it's comprado cat
/ l / SOG state of go one one zero one
ten if you go there the playground
Browns go under nine so some of the
examples will not work do not file
issues it's expected that is what
happens when you do these kind of talks
so the agenda we're gonna be talk about
the language the tank all the changes to
the language all the changes to ports
that so all the architectures that we
support the tooling the standard library
performance and the community so changes
to the language nothing
that's it there is some small changes in
that like basically changing the
specification for some ambiguities and
bigger is that we had but that's it
there's nothing new absolutely nothing
so that's easy go second section port
where what other architectures are
supporting that we didn't support before
none but here there's some changes so
for all the BS DS we are limiting to
what version we're supporting so if
you're using one of the B as these
please check the the constraints that
we're adding basically you need to use
us like something slightly newer also
for OSX we are gonna need to require
also us a medium so the next version
will require just a MIDI so this is
basically a warning go 1.11 will not
support your family so you need to
upgrade but being how aggressive map
apple is at a upgrading I'm sure you
will also Windows will not support
Windows XP or Vista
so if using those yeah sorry there was a
really good burn on a bug basically
saying if you using Windows Vista you
should not be worried about security
upgrades on go because it's Windows
Vista but anyway oh yeah this is the
this domestic burned so it said I will
not say who said these I'll just leave
it you can find it it says you won't get
secure fixes but if you're running XP
you don't worry about that so that's
pretty funny okay
changes to the tooling and here there's
way more stuff all of the changes can be
divided into two sections it's easier to
use and also everything is faster so
what is easier to use if you remember
gopath became optional in go on the rate
now go root is also optional and it's
basically deduced from the binary
location so that means that if you
download go and you run it it works
that's it you don't need to setup go
root go path or anything like that which
is pretty useful also we added a
variable to check where you want to
create your temporary
actor is its go got them there you can
also control it with ten theory in most
houses but it's being created if you
think it's useful for you other than
that everything is faster this is
actually really cool so when you do go
build then go install all of the things
that have been compiled that are
binaries because all the binaries end up
in the bin directory all the packages
that you compile end up in the package
directory that is not true anymore now
what happens is that those compile
packages are cached and only the ones
that you actually ask to compile so if
you say compile I don't know trying to
follow one let's say OS and OS requires
IO OS will be end up OS dot a will be in
the compiled somewhere but IO will be
implicitly compatible so you will not
see it the important thing is that these
caches are now kept which means that if
you compile again you don't need to
recompile all of the code that's what go
build - I used to do if you use C go for
if you start before you don't need to do
it it's already implicit and it works
faster all the time similarly you get
caches for testing so not only for the
building but also for the execution of
tests and these actually done in a quite
smart way so the tests are cached as
long as the old environment variables
that the code checks did not change the
the file system did not change and
things like this so your test will
actually run when necessary if you want
to force it to run you can say - count
equal ones equals one and that will
force to run the test once which means
no cache also we are at vet so when you
do go test if you have something that
for instance is let's say I print F with
a format that has more parameters than
the parameters you're passing your test
will fail which is do which means that
some files will test but your code was
wrong so that's not breaking go what go
one compared abd what else
cover profile supports now many packages
at the same time which is cool because
it means that you can bring your tests
faster too you can create one single
profile coverage for all of your
libraries
she's pretty nice also fail fast to stop
all the tests when one fails and
that - Jason so you don't need to parse
the output of tests anymore you can just
read Jason which is nice and that's
pretty much it so a small dieter how
many of you know what a three index
slice is not that many cool so that's
why I'm gonna explain it because it
actually it's actually something
interesting so when you write code you
have some text here which is a slice of
bytes that says hello Gotham if you go
desk I'm just printing the value of the
capacity and the length and you get from
zero to five and you get the capacity in
the length you're gonna see that you get
the length is five because it says hello
but the capacity is 16 what does Kappa
that capacity means then from this slice
hello I can access the rest of the slice
so if I append something I'm actually
overriding the original slice and that's
something that it's not something you
want to do many times if you're sharing
piece of slice you want you might want
to say this is your piece of lies
you cannot override outside this in
order to do this you just add this five
here that five what it does is to says
and getting the elements from zero to
five and the capacity also goes up to
the lemon five now if you do that when
you are pen you're actually appending on
that slice that is already full so you
reallocate somewhere else and you gonna
override the previous slice
there you go so now hello for them did
not change now now that we all know this
changes that have happened so go font
has changed the way it formats this
expression I do not think that many of
you use it but if you use that
expression and you're checking for go
font in your integration tests it will
fail it has failed for me it's just one
test so it's not huge it's only one
people failed but it might happen to you
there is some explanations on why you
should not be doing the go fund making
sure that the output matches
and stuff like this I think that well
it's kind of painful but that's how it
is also it's better now it makes its way
more beautiful I think you'll be their
God
now we're going to talk about the
changes to the Sun the library there's
nothing really big there is no new
packages how many of you remember what
was the last package added to the
standard library yes it's there you go
so yeah these you get a t-shirt I mean
everybody sure we we have not added any
more packages there's nothing in there
but off the packages we have we've added
some stuff and actually some things that
might be very useful for it code that
you write day today so let's go back to
the same example before so now instead
of saying from zero to five one's doing
is I'm getting fields which is give me
the first word basically in go under
nine does lies you are getting had the
capacity to override the previous one so
if you overrode if you run this on the
playground and the Wi-Fi works yay
so if you run these you're overriding
hello FOSDEM because the capacity is 16
if you run this with go under 10 the
capacity is nine five and you can order
right so that's a change that might be
kind of tricky so if you're using if
using fields fields Fung split or split
after and you're trusting this capacity
of being able to override outside of the
slice which is kind of weird it will
break so take that into account also
there's a minor reflected minor change
to flag that makes me really happy it's
incredibly minor nobody cares about it
except for me probably but I do care in
go under 9 when you had a description
that had thank you that had a line break
it would print it like this really ugly
that line is not well aligned now it´s
well aligned
thank you it's really important also
this changes to go doc these are change
that is in between the standard library
and also tooling it's a little bit of
both sides basically until now you know
that we're in the documentation when you
have a new food that returns a pointer
to food when you look at the
discrimination you see it tied to the
food type right you see food and new
food but if you were returning a slice
of foods that was not tied to it now it
is so in the documentation and go doc
you will see it slightly differently
which I think makes more sense but also
if you using the go doc package you will
see that those functions rather
appearing at the package level will
appear at the type level so if you're
depending on that that might break but
again I think the change I told make
sense so yeah before you would see funk
many things which is completely related
to the type thing now you will see the
type thing has two constructors one is
many things and one is new thing so it
makes it a bit more sense changes to
text and plate and this one is
interesting so you've all use range and
or a for loop I'm sure and you have
continue and break now you can also use
those in text and plate not on HTML
template and I do not know why but
that's how it is if you try to run this
on HTML template you will get an error
saying this has not been implemented it
I don't know if it is because they don't
want to implement it or because they're
like we don't have time to implement it
just that's it ship it so this i'm
ranging from one to ten and what I'm
saying is if it's even print even and
continue which means that it will not
print out or the Y's are broken Todd and
when we get to five will break and
finish the loop so every in this
we get odd even odd every done is there
any water no there's a bucket of water
thank you that is very useful very
useful people that's okay
okay this is the change that I care
about the most I'd say in all of go 1 to
10 I'm sure you've all use a bytes
buffer as a way to create strings
basically you created and seats it has
the right method
it's a writer and then you can use F
print or F print F or F insulin to write
stuff into the bite into the byte buffer
and then at the end get the string so
you get the byte buffer you get you
print hello first and go first to the
buffer and then pop that string will
print it when you play this you will see
that I actually also added how many
bytes we allocated we all get it 856
bytes to do all of these things which is
a lot but who cares it's mostly the
string but so now you have the strings
builder and the strings builder
basically is a specific solution for the
case of building strings so it does not
have all of the power of bytes but in
exchange it has more guarantees so one
of the counties that it has is that it
doesn't need to do a copy of the string
every single time you try to get the
string from the bytes from a slice of
bytes to a string you need to do a copy
because a slice of bytes you can change
it a string is immutable so you need to
do a copy to ensure that that happens
with the bytes with the strings builder
that bytes buffer is not accessible
therefore you don't need to do those
copies you know that those strings will
never change because you don't have
access to those so when is this good so
if you're doing something like this
where you're creating you're adding
emoji or anything really you are your
writing piece of string to by its buffer
and you keep on adding more and more and
every single time you convert that to a
string you're actually forcing a copy
and allocation of that string over and
over and over which means that if you
get a benchmark you're gonna see that
that's allocating ten thousand three
hundred seventeen
bytes if you change that to instead
being a bytes buffer to be a strings
builder you go to 22 bytes which means
that also it's way faster it's like 30
times faster something that which is
awesome now if you're not doing that it
is a little bit worse than bytes buffer
but these the case were you just adding
more stuff and basically doing that
allocation at the end only once so it
really depends on what you're doing but
I'd say check it out and two benchmarks
and make sure that it might be better
for your cup in some cases
so do not say Oh Fran says say we should
just use it no but check it out
unicode we have all of these beautiful
emoji so there's 56 need emoji I know
thank you it's not me it's Unicode I
think it's Unicode 10 or something like
that
it has 56 emoji you cannot see them but
I'm prepared like the top my favorite
ones so you have Chinese food which I
love so you have takeout and fortune
cookie
and also I forgot the name of that thing
gives a short gyoza also Argentinian
people say it's a empanada
sure curling because it is really
important a t-rex it is it is I think
it's pretty cool to be honest mind blown
and the most important one which is not
emoji but it's a utf-8 character that we
didn't have before and everybody was
dying to have it was Bitcoin yes you can
now write Bitcoin as a character in
Unicode and go on the ten supports it my
Mac doesn't oh so yeah it's a pity okay
performance changes I this is fun
because I should have prepared this
start with way more time but I did not
so I ended up doing this yesterday and
and by yesterday might be this morning
so I checked the benchmarks between go
on the nine it going on ten on run time
and they're pretty much the same like to
the point that I removed all of the
benchmarks that had actually significant
changes and all were gone so either I'm
totally wrong which is a possibility or
they're actually basically the same the
same speed which is not shocking because
I don't think there's been that much
work on performance for these pieces for
the compiler though I was completely
mistaken I thought that this was the run
time it was like this way slower but
these actually if you don't know how to
read it
it's not important the important thing
is the last number is how long it takes
for the go compiler to compile the
standard the standard library and all
the commands I go from covet and all
those and it takes ten percent less so
it's ten percent faster than before
which is cool it's not huge but if you
get in ten percent performance boost on
all of your compilations not running the
computations that's pretty good
also garbage collector every single time
I've done these toxins go on dot five
I've added the same tweet the same
tweets actually Brian Hatfield has this
thing from go under five when he's been
tweeting the the pause in the garbage
collection of his servers every single
time he was going to the new version
it went from 300 milliseconds which is
crazy bad to around 100 or so around 30
that was from go on look for to go on
the 5 that was one we actually gave a
talk about it because like look at this
then from going down five to go on the
ticks we went from 40 milliseconds to 4
milliseconds which is pretty amazing
from going that 6 to 1.7 we went from
around 3 to around 1 millisecond then to
definitely under one millisecond all the
time we'd go on the rate we go on the 9
it's they pretty much the same and then
we've gone to ten I was like hey Brian
you have not done it and give my talk
tomorrow this is yesterday by the way it
was like could you please do this and so
these on Flag and he's like hey so I'm
running a cannery now but you know it's
late so whatever and I was like oh if
you can do it and then I said can I use
this screenshot because you know I'm a
good person and he said yes and he says
hi and then I went to bed
and then this morning he actually
tweeted and he said yeah so he said he
looked basically saying it's not you
know amazing story but he tweeted so
he's a very nice guy so thank you Brian
he'll be in the video so thank you Brian
for this there's a couple more changes
you can read those you can go to the go
1.8 no 10 go under 10 release notes
they're already public just not on going
on the road they're embed a document or
org or tip going or same thing so it
changes to the community this is women
who go they have now 26 chapters which
is amazing they had 16 last year I redo
this slide every time and this time
actually made the map so I can reuse it
which is nice for the first time ever
I'm not just using paint
I was using paint so this is really good
they're all around the world which is
amazing so if you are a woman and you go
you should also they have a new board of
management I don't know how you call
yourself a new c-suites
I don't know what that means but oh yeah
cuz they have cease there you go yes so
March she's here and she's one of the
organizers of the room she is the CEO of
women who go
Veronica Lopez that she's still not here
but she'll be speaking later is the CEO
know the CFO and then
we also have the Nina Petre Zach and
Karen ethnic they're also helping with
view chapters and the head of support so
that's amazing so congratulations to the
four of them and then we have all of the
go meet ups and go meet up they're
really all around the world they're
they're really cool there's one in the
middle of Russia I was invited once but
I couldn't make it but if you wanna go
somewhere random go in the middle of a
Asia there's one go meet up there
then these this slide still fits in one
slide but it's getting really crazy all
the gold differences that are happening
soon so we have gold ever-important
which is today and here congratulations
you're here
go freakin India which is in March
Russia a March to go SF in March to so
if you want to travel March is a good
month to travel then April New York May
in Singapore jr. be a cubic the
organizer is some right there there you
go and Augustine Denver September in
florianópolis October in Florence and
then Dokdo has moved a little bit
farther away so there will not be 2018
there would be 2019 in not the other way
around
2019 I'm I'm mistaken with years that's
only 19 next year and and also we have a
bunch of talks today at the end of all
of these talks will have lining talks so
March I was working on will give the
link to a forum where you can apply to
give talks if you want to give a talk
there will be five minutes talks really
short but you can give something cool
some ideas or some project you've been
working on we're definitely interested
in leasing up listening about it and
that's it enjoy the rest of the day and
thank you very much
[Applause]
and