hello
so let's start we're going to talk about
package managers and I hope that's where
you're here for if not there's a door on
each side this is actually not too
catchy drawl this is a church it's La
Sagrada Familia in Barcelona which has
been under construction for over a
hundred years and they plan to finish
this by 2026 roughly that's the plan
today now before we start two questions
for you
how many of you use a destroy package
manager on Linux
pretty much everyone how many of you use
a language-specific package manager like
NPM pie-pie rubygems
okay and how many of you rely on the
distro package manager to provision your
language-specific packages this much
fewer which is where I was it because
some do but most of them do not and and
that's that's a bit the topic of the
talk so be a bit about me my nation and
that's what I do in and out of of work
is to make it easier to reuse free
library and open source software I'm the
developer and maintainer of several
packages the series of project called
the bots code that's my primary set
including something called scan code
which is a tool for scanning for license
packages and origins I contribute to the
Linux kernel become a Streisand and many
many other projects
so
the question that sinks that bothers me
is why each time so I run Linux on all
my machines why each time I run apt
install opt upgrade things works 99.999
percent of the time mostly and that
applies to to debian-based distros or or
RPM base distros and why when i do
people npm a bundle and sell things
don't work much more often than 999
right and you're laughing so obviously
that probably resonates a beat it's
since don't always work they don't often
work they very often don't work at all
and it bothers me because I was actually
bitching against digital developers says
why don't they give the latest version
of the packages I want and and why do I
have to not use the disrobe and adjure
which works and use another package
manager that doesn't work but get the
stuff that I want right that's that's
the problem so why did I call this to
cater all talking about category of the
catalog bazaar I don't know if any of
you were born last century I'm an old
dog the last century there were somebody
called Eric lemon I mean called yes are
the procures similarly say called the
cathedral and the bazaar and this is not
exactly the same cathedral and bazaars
we're talking about today but this point
was how come that the development
process has Macy at the development of
Lennox where patches are coming from
every places ends up being able to build
a system that works and that works
pretty darn well most of the time one of
the things that things we're really very
often on the one end a lot of betas and
everything was delegated whereas his
point was that another style of
development is more of the categorical
approach where
you architect sings nicely and you orbit
less up and about accepting
contributions now let's just just a side
note but I reuse this because it's
resonating in the world of package
management there's really two types of
packages package gated roles and that's
the one for for this rules and and the
bazaars that's the one for language
language specific packages so the one we
use for rust node Python Ruby and likes
and they're really not at all the same
packages they're very very different and
we call them all packages but that's
probably a misnomer the district package
works typically for a single operating
system right you're building for fedora
vivianne and so on you don't have to
worry much about your code running on
Mac and Windows most of the time that
may be a concern of a language specific
package whether it's built in C or C++
or in an OS agnostic language that
requires some natural differences the
the package management systems are
general purpose for this chosen and very
specific for sorry and very specific
when it comes language and as I heard
before you know okay Coenen is a c c++
package manager
can you build no java package with it
possibly and you can probably do that
put Java scripting in pipe I and Java in
NPM but it's simply a lot of hacking and
tweaking that's required it's not their
primary purpose the other thing is that
if you think about package if you're a
library halter or consumer it's really
about authors and individuals there's
one or group of person that provides a
bit of code that's supposed to be very
specific in terms of function in the
context of these throws we have usually
a team of maintenance which were colored
to not package one that package many
package that are related and of the same
family there's another context also
yours are a user or builder which
differs the testing is is is interesting
how many of you do know a project called
Apache Gump okay it's pretty obscure
project it's actually interesting in
weird they're taking all the head of
every project at Apache and try to build
them all the time with the letters of
hats which time does it come it they
reveal everything against the latest and
greatest obviously it's very often read
and doesn't build but what's interesting
to understand is that when you build
this troll you don't care about having
just the test of one packet but you want
to make sure that all your packages for
a given version release work with the
same version of lead sea and the same
version of this and that and you release
them together you don't release just one
sometime you release one that if it's
usually dot version it's going to be
always in the context of a larger whole
and the main this for release the other
thing on the dependency side the
dependencies we express most of the time
for language specific packages are
pretty simple whereas the dependency
language for destroy packages are
actually pretty rich there's a lot of
things which you look at them says
conflict the depends resolve absolutes
there's a very different context of
managing dependencies the other thing
also and most of the time when we
consume package from a language
repository we do consume these as ease
now you take a maven jar verbatim you
take an NPM 99% of the time you read it
as is the packages that are provided by
these trolls
in contrast our 99% of the time patched
modified deconstructed reconstructed you
take a spell which is spell checker one
nice d'arbeloff stream in this store it
ends up being possibly 50 packages one
for each language for the dictionaries
maybe one for the library one for come
on tool come online to you so we are not
talking at all about the same packages
now if you take the the the builder
perspective the bazaar is like the box
of Lego's and the catedral is trying to
build an actual thing with these with
these legos so now thinking about your
perspective as a user even if I'm a
developer so forget you're developing
software for a minute as a user you want
to system that stable that works that
installs and updates all the time right
that's what you get from it is true as a
builder I want the Lego bricks that I
can beat my cathedral with and I don't
care too much about the rest I want to
make sure they're really fit for their
function they have a single well known
purpose and I can use them as you break
as a stone and assemble my edifice
so now let's dive a bit again into
dependencies most language-specific
package managers I say most this is
always very usually two options maybe
three options on how you express
dependencies and how and when dependent
packages are used generally real setup
time or run time and that's pretty much
it it works actually quite well you
really need much more than that some
package manager I think it's PHP
composer expose kind of disre like more
richer language with a lot of verbs and
type of dependencies I'm not sure
they're very much used
but it's it's rare it's more an
exception the other thing is that in
most case language specific package
managers have a fairly simple way to
resolve dependency conflicts so
dependency config is when in your
dependency tree two packages require the
same package with a version that don't
match
NPM for instance has a sleek way to
resolve that by saying I don't care I'll
take all the versions which can be a
problem
I'm sure you've faced that at times in
contrast this whole package have evolved
to have fairly complicated and complex
way to resolve dependency using what's
called a Sat solver and boy and
satisfiability which is really something
that's very simple at the basis but
extremely complex in terms of its
implementation it's eventually an
np-hard problem and to the best
knowledge there's very few if any
language package managers that have or
that that use any Sat solver base the
dependency resolution one of them I
think is Conda in the Python scientific
world but it's quasi destroy light
package manager rather than being very
language specific there's no such thing
in bundler NPM or PIP for instance
usually that makes a big difference is
the kind of social contract that exists
between the language specific package
management environment and the distro
package management environment again in
the language specific world it's usually
individuals when I say individuals that
can be a team but usually producing one
break one Lego brick at a time you focus
as much as possible on a single function
there's no coordination that's required
most of the time with other package
managers you just consume their stuff
you don't care what they do
you don't care about their testing and
and their whole stuff you just care
about eventually in the confine of your
single project are my dependencies and
direct dependency result and working but
you don't care about the rest and it's
it's a bit having a utilitarian look at
things do you think about plastic breaks
Legos your care about you know the mold
injection molding the quality of plastic
you take in contrast when you're
building this row it's more like art and
architecture you go to the bazaar and
you pick the breaks the Legos you want
to make sure you know their
characteristics in terms of plastics and
else but there's a really extensive
efforts for collaboration and
coordination and in fact at some level
there's little code that's produced
reasonably speaking and relatively
speaking to the rest of the scope and
and a lot of discussions so that's
that's really a very important
distinction now let's let's turn these
things a bit around in fact you could
sing probably as each package that you
write as a library or an individual
project as a mini catcher all of its own
you care about testing you care about
ensuring that your code works in the
context of it dependencies and that
doesn't crash all the time and think of
it as if you were taking these small
cathedrals and assembling them further
up so it's really eventually not really
strict separation between under two but
it's it's Turtles all the way down
and and that's what makes eventually
things work so there's there's a way to
eventually reconcile that at some level
so what happens today really is that
there's really these two contexts either
I'm a user or the Builder and I'm
usually both at the same time I am
building components and package for them
to be reused and I'm reusing mine and
further package to build system and
applications and that's building of
system of an application is a system
integration job that's what we need is
shall do what thing that that that's
often overlooked is when you start using
for instance containers you very quickly
actually are becoming your own system
integrator you escape the confines of
the nice assembly and coordination work
that's done by these for maintenance and
you take the responsibiiity without
really knowing it is each container ends
up being eventually as complex and as
messy as a whole in X distribution but
usually there's not the same discipline
and efforts of coordination
collaboration that we put into it so
that's important and so I will stop
bitching and I think we all should stop
bitching about out of the distro
packages we should work with these rows
to help them in many ways one if we want
to make sure that our latest language
runtime or package manager is available
well we can help you don't have to be
the maintainer of the packaging tools to
help on the maintain I'm maintaining
that package proper and actually weirdly
enough there are very few upstream
package authors that are effectively the
maintainer of their own package in these
throws because there's one upstream
authors and many many distros eventually
so you can help this way
here's where you can help is when you're
building packages and I'm terribly bad
at that make sure that they are actually
easy to package upstream by these rules
and possibly you can provide a package
manifest for your favorite distros
whether it would be brew on a Mac or a
Debian or rpm package which can help the
work upstream and you can collaborate
the work downstream and you can
collaborate with the package management
distro to make your package easier and
faster to package and so really I think
that's important in sovereign over loop
these trolls don't happen by accident
it's a lot of hard work and coordination
that's needed and and we all need to
give a bit of love there and that's it
just a plug I'll be doing a talk on
tracing wheel with this trace in another
computing room now be back after that in
this room here
[Applause]
thank you
that's a complex topic so the question
is what about the repackaging of
language-specific packages and
distributions and especially the number
of packages that may exist which are to
be clean the tens or hundreds of
thousands in an upstream in a language
they speak package a repository
environment it's a difficult thing on
the one end this rose being software
often have direct dependencies on a
specific package and package version
take the case for RPM base de source for
a long time they depended on python 2 4
and then python 2 6 even though it was
long time since python 7 license 3 were
available so they have this need of
dependencies of their own to actually
run on the one hand and on the other end
they want also to provide some level of
coverage for language specific packages
I don't have an answer I don't know what
to be down there the reality is that
most of the language specific packages
are often considered that outdated
when they're in the disco even in the
latest release of a distro and folks
tend to not do system-wide installation
but always project specific or user
specific installation there's probably I
don't think there's a really easy
solution
one would be to repackage everything but
that's like double packaging probably
make sense to instead work with these
flows to ensure for instance to work
with note that you have letter snowed
runtime and NPM install same thing for
Ruby and Python and probably let go at a
disco level of language specific package
repackaging unless you have a direct
dependencies
and a need for system-wide installation
for it that probably would be the best
bet that probably would simplify the
work to the difficult vacations and lots
of applications yes it's not an easy
there's no easy solution so the question
is is it does do containers and docker
provide a solution to the problem of
destroy versus language packages
I don't think so they actually amplify
the problem at some level what is a
container it's essentially a slice of oh
it's a mini D through the slice of user
land do you have everything but the
kernel but you have everything what it
provides is isolation and what you give
up for isolation is immutability so your
container is immutable it's not easy to
update eventually you need to rebuild it
otherwise you're just accumulating
levels of our levels of other updates
the the thing is that
you have one benefit which is you can
trim down the set of dependencies to
just what you need so that's a good
thing you can isolate them that's also a
good thing but there's very simple ways
to do that
just putting using user level
installations it's supposed to help with
deployments on a massive scale so that
has benefits much simpler to deploy a
simple file single file on main machines
then then a lot of packages the fact
it's immutable it's good thing in some
case it's also pain when you have a
security bug and you've deployed 200
containers each with small variations
you have to rebuild 200 containers it's
not fun so it's I'm not sure it's really
solving any of the problems there it
helps in some case it creates a lot of
us or issues in the other and the other
thing talking about containers is that
when you actually redistribute
containers or deploy containers you are
de facto your whole stack Linux
integrator you took response via for the
whole stack above the kernel and and
there is much more ceremony that's
needed there in terms of compliance and
license backtracking security tracking
things that were provided to your
service by distros that you may no
longer benefit of all the time yes
some bizarre something due to the design
fashions of hope of the previous
generation of generating distributions
and now we are going to more agnostic
languages that are nest every word I can
run everywhere and then new designers
that design is packaging movement
so so the question is is this liquor to
me between bizarre and kathedraal
something of the past or will there be
something that small language agnostic
not the Cathedral of bazaars is the
opposite that's kind of true so the the
difficulty there is it's hard to build
package managers and actually there's I
think there's there are talks today it's
it's really hard I've tried a few bits
of time and I fail land on TV every time
so it's a difficult job I've built
distros not Linux distros but a long
time ago an eclipse-based distribution
which was called easy Eclipse and which
had at a very small scale all the
problems of that you can have in the
Linux distribution it's again the
problem between the bazaar and not the
bazaar it's not so much a technical
issue it's more problem of coordination
and and this coordination there's no
tool that can actually fulfill it you
have to have people that discuss and if
you see all the the efforts that's
deployed by distribution teams to have
package trackers and ways that they can
collaborate and track all the same
that's where the big effort ended now
there's maybe a bit of light on the
horizon there are going to emerging
things on the Digital side one is next
and on the package management side one
is back
and yeah well that's the problem you
can't the glue eventually when
everything is a package the glue is what
you and I do to actually take a bunch of
Lego bricks and Mickey to system okay
so times up we can take the discussion
offline or later I'm sorry thank you
very much
[Applause]
the alternative dimension onyx which is
a Linux distribution mix like me and IX
and spa se8