can you hear me
awesome thank you yes so influential and
from Bremen Germany and today I would
like to talk a bit about MDM browser
compatibility data for the last eight
years or so I'm working on MDM ambien is
Mozilla developer demos little dog it's
probably what's that closer to the mic
all right let's see like like this maybe
no all right where was I
good all right
so NBN is a documentation site where a
few tech writers and a large community
tries to document the web and that means
we will we are writing about HTML CSS
JavaScript HTTP and basically all the
technologies that the browser runs and
we do this in a wiki form on developer
at Mozilla dark and last year we were
after a long time also for it with the
price by slash data where they said okay
ambien is a really great site in terms
of developer satisfaction so it means
that you guys probably like the stuff
that we are writing about and we've
actually did a lot of work over the last
13 years when this content was first
open source so this is how it actually
started like a classic wiki in 2005 it
was based on media wiki Mitchell Baker
was able in 2005 to take a few of the
netscape contents where technical
writers from netscape brought about
javascript and open source that into a
wiki and this was the layout in 2005 but
basically all the Muslim people of has
put on all the stuff that they developed
about all the technologies they have
vented like JavaScript and support when
I joined the team in 2010 or less to to
write about what technology mdn was
actually drastically changing from being
like a wiki where everyone was dumping
content into something we're a small
team of passionate web developers that
were really also hired by all the html5
and css3 technologies that came up to
trade a documentation up for open web
technologies so the scope was kind of
narrowed down from everyone dumps all
the contents on mdn on the developer
Center - let's make a coherent website
where we document web technologies and
during the last year we have even
changed a bit more the layout of the
site so for example this is something
that recently landed and it is a bit
also inspired from w3 schools that's the
site that everyone is told you don't use
it use MTN because well we're having the
more correct content but but w3 schools
does a very good is delivering you know
quick sample code quite fast and easy
and we're trying to address this with
our new interactive editor that we've
put on the top of pages and generally
there's two types of developers test a
constant driven ones that really like to
read a lot of content and understand the
concepts behind a CSS property or method
but then there's also the ones to just
want to perform an action the action of
developers and they really want to do
one thing and that is copy paste code
and this is happen with that but today I
want to focus on one particular project
of the mdn team which is about
compatibility
and compatibility is not only important
for mdn but also for Mozilla we want to
encourage everyone to use a variety of
browsers and not only write website for
one browser which is to be the IE
problem which now probably turns into
the chrome problems and on env and what
we've we've done so far is we've
provided these kind of tables I guess a
lot of you have seen does this is a
table that displays compatibility
information about the CSS background
property you can also see if you sub
features of that same property like
multiple backgrounds and as treat each
image images as a background and it we
used to have this table in the wiki for
like I don't know five six seven years
now and if you've ever edited mdn which
is by the way easy as just signing up an
account and you can edit it's a wiki R
so everyone is able to edit and change
things on mdn and this is how it looks
like or looked like when editing these
compatibles this is a static HTML table
where you know the versions and you know
little helpers that we wrote around
those versions this is how it was stored
now there's a there's a lot of problems
with this so imagine this that's a table
being on all of the mdn reference pages
that we have and we're talking about
maybe 10,000 pages there's I don't know
400 CSS properties there's like an
amazing amount of api's and HTTP headers
and all that and all these pages had
static information in there about
compatibility so we couldn't mass edit
the data we couldn't mass at data we
couldn't reuse the data like convert
data is something many people are
interested in but it's kind of locked in
our wiki in those tables and when we
want to change this we have to go into
all the pages and and change stuff we
can also not validate data so as I just
said everyone can edit MDF
and put a say Firefox 6.3 version for
the CSS background property which is
nonsense as firefox 3.6.13 ever existed
and because of the nature of the wiki
which in the empty we are also
considering rethinking at the moment
everyone can just change things without
any further discussion which is which is
a problem when talking about you know
factual information like compatibility
there's not actually a opinion around
this it's just it has started to work in
this version or it has not and it's
another version or it's not supported at
all we can also have no automation here
like we could probably write some
scripts using sauce labs or browser
stick automatically generating
information on when something was
supported and finally the mdn team is
largely or the ambien website is largely
sponsored by a mozilla and we are we
have a few employees including me
working on the side but we want to
encourage and invite the other browser
vendors as well to document with us
together the open web and we've
addressed a few of these points the last
one for example in October last year in
October 2017 mozilla we reached out over
the last year to a few other industry
leaders naming the Microsoft Google the
w3c and Samsung and and they now form
with us together the product advisory
board for MDM what this means is that
all these companies are now helping us
to document the web because we we're all
doing things on the web we all like the
Microsoft and Google they are building
browsers the w3c creates the standards
that we are also documenting on amnion
finally after few years we came together
and and formed this board and this will
this will help us
with the whole documentation and also
with the with the combat data and then
what we what we finally also came up
with is we want to we want to get out
the company data out of the wiki when
you can up liberate its break it free
from the aesthetic tables into a
repository so what we came up with is
repository that you can find on github
it's get up to thumbs /m DN / browser
compare data and what we did there is we
start all this data that we what we have
in our reference pages in a structure
that looks very much like this so on the
left hand side you can see like the
folder for CSS properties so stuff like
align itself or animation of backdrop
filter and in each of those files you
have a Jason structure where you have to
you know some inter fires saying that
hey this is a CSS property it's the
background property you can also you
have a back reference to the MVNO URL
and then there's a support object for
the various browsers and diversions and
we also provide this as an NPM package
as it is just JavaScript or JSON data so
you can reuse this and nodejs as well
and then access it like it is shown here
and you will get back to the D Jason
that is stored in our comfort store and
know when when editing mdn it's it's a
lot simpler because we don't have to you
know we don't have to edit every page
anymore we can just mass edit in our
github repository and on our pages can
call a query like this and get the data
from the data store and thanks to this
we were able to recently redesign those
tables also so we got rid of the tab
switching from mobile to and desktop to
show all role and other mobile desktop
browsers at the same time because many
of the web developers should you know
having mobile first approaches and the
mobile data is as important as well
we've added node.js to the tables to
because well it's not JavaScript it's
not only in the brows anymore but to
test no chairs and so we kind of did
this redesign like I think it was last
week on me and you know very a lot of
the pages are now showing up with with
these redesigned tables and the good
thing is the French pages used to have
the static tables as well so in our old
world it could have been that the French
version had some but said some comfort
information the English page had some
comfort information that it always liked
different information and all across the
wiki which was terrible and now the
French version can also just call in to
the data store and display localized
comfortable so this is what what mdn is
done to kind of set free this data so
yes we are open-source already our
content is open source but the comfort
information was still kind of locked in
in the static tables now that is set
free it's open data and you can reuse it
so if any of you has a project or is
interested in writing plug-ins for atoms
supplying vias code or if anyone is you
know familiar with writing but some
github
you could imagine you know using this
data to write help us for your project
to check against compatibility because
the data has a lot of information on
what is supported in which version of
the browsers so a mozillian called
Eduardo boosts us heat he did something
useful with this data and you can use
this maybe for inspiration on this is
dev tools so I put steps tools and he
has written an extension adding a new
tab called compatibility and what it
does is it analyzes the CSS files of
your website and gives you information
on what kind of properties you have used
and it will display you you know similar
like comfort metrics inside dev tools
saying okay you've used this on that
property and it doesn't work in I
so you will not be compatible and a
percent there with with i9 for example
so let's have a little bit of a look now
that you hopefully feel a bit inspired
of what you could do with this data said
what's what's in the data right so for
now we're still not completely finished
in migration from this static table
thing into the data store about like
forty five percent done but right now
what we have is is a mixture of this
so there's CSS HTML HTTP javascript and
web extensions compare data in there and
this already gives you a bit of a sense
of how large these technologies are so
web extensions has a lot of API so there
are a lot of data points here same for
CSS all the properties to selectors edge
rules and so forth HTTP is a bit smaller
because we mostly have competative for
HTTP headers sitting here now I've
looked a little bit deeper into the data
for CSS and if you're into I don't know
data science these things you could also
you know analyze this data set and and
you know look at how CSS develops over
time so for example when we had Firefox
10 Firefox 110 years ago there were like
90 CSS properties and because this data
has all the others discovered a destroys
all the Firefox versions and and I've
looked into it when there was little
spikes so in Firefox 16 for example
there were a lot of new CSS properties
and I was like what's what's going on
there so it turns out they implemented
CSS animations back then or later
flexbox
or over the last like fifty or sixty
five boxed versions CSS but more complex
complex adding more features over time
so i'm and this was i could you know
make this child only out of our data
which was kind of interesting i thought
of these
one thing I need to mention though is
that the data is as we have just started
to migrate them we have not yet polished
them or validated a lot what's in there
so the chart that you've just seen about
the CSS data I was using the Firefox
versions because our data is actually
most complete for Firefox because on the
wiki well we used to maintain the data
for Firefox mostly and not so much for
other browsers so what you can see here
is a lot of the data is either the
version is unknown or the the
compatibility is unknown at all so but
as it is open data I can only you know
have a call to action here you can help
us making this data more awesome which
will make the tables displayed on mdn
more awesome which will make the two of
the NATO auto proud and f2 small sum
which will make the tool that some of
you may come up with more awesome so
yeah that is that and with that that was
browser combo data open data brought to
you by the md n team thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
any questions yes yes I know that
yes so we look into can I use Kananga
says about 300 features listed on their
page and that's awesome it's a it's a
wonderful site our dataset is it's a lot
bigger and we're not even done yet so
yes we're rocking together with Kenna
use and there might be some
collaboration in the future but right
now the data that we want to set free
from the wiki is just a lot more richer
about 10 to 20 times more richer and we
want to preserve that information and so
as the first step we're putting that
into a repository and but yeah future
collaboration awesome let's do it right
right so the thing that's the things
that oh yes sorry so the question is
about collaboration between can I use
and and this data set and you know
competing or you know double effort and
the thing is this data set is a lot more
richer because we have all the
information from over six thousand
ambien wiki pages and can I use this
only about 300 pages listed at the
moment and Bob's most projects are kind
of relying on us on on you know manual
pull requests updating the data but we
want to bring in here is we want to kind
of have official status using our
partners from the MDM product advisory
board putting in official version
numbers when something is supported and
also adding on top of the dates of some
validation and automation you know that
actually tells us to choose whether or
not something is supported but yeah I
open to collaboration ways can I use as
well and yeah sure
more questions
No all right then thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
you