Thanks hi everyone I'm Greg I'm getting
a talk today on Linux IOT botnet wars
and the lack of security hardening just
a fun slide to get us started little one
come to a very important part of our
talk so my name is Greg I'm currently
working on an interesting project called
mando it's an over-the-air update or
linux embedded devices fully open source
when we're using the dual a B route FS
layout scheme currently under active
development so my my original talk was
supposed to be 45 minutes and I
originally included three botnets but
I'm going to talk about Moriah which was
very popular in the media because it was
a very large-scale attack I'll skip over
hajima I might mention a bit about it
and then I'll talk about Bricker but all
three of these botnets had some very
common security problems they were
targeting LTE devices are very common
and similar security problems we'll talk
about that and finally we'll look in
solution designs of how we could have
mitigated these problems
this is my first pasta I wasn't sure
about target audience I'm pretty sure
all of you guys know what this are but
if anyone's unfamiliar DDoS is
essentially distributed einem of service
traditionally used to overwhelm a system
and prevent it from working correctly
you have IOT I was buying a heater
recently and it connected to Wi-Fi
basically billions of devices now are
connecting to the internet botnets I'm
sure everyone knows what this is but
just in case they're used to carry out
distributed attacks I might be using
malware worm but net interchangeably but
this is a definition so I'm just gonna
look into the basic anatomy of an attack
that you tend to see so you have the
reconnaissance which is you're gonna
discover a vulnerability and you're
gonna find a way to exploit it
you need an intrusion method to get that
initial access into a system followed by
inserting a backdoor you want to do this
in case you get found out and you want
to be persistent and reinstalling your
worm or bot on a device
finally you need to avoid detection
somehow most worms botnets malware
figure out a way to prevent the user
from understanding that it exists in the
system so I'm gonna talk a lot about
Mariah because it's the most popular IOT
botnet that caused quite a bit of damage
and a lot of interesting research has
been done on this botnet so was
discovered in August 2016 by a group
called malware must died that there are
pretty nice analysis on it one of their
honey pots honey pots detected it
Mariah means future in Japanese which is
very scary
if the IOT industry is gonna follow this
idea and it's infected the numbers are
pretty skewed so there was some
estimates around two hundred three
hundred thousands but some variants of
Mariah have targeted around 1 million
devices so you could think these numbers
as a grain of salt
it's quite a skewed range of numbers
that were infected but a lot were
infected the type of devices that were
infected is this is a good example and
one of the source code they actually
mentioned model numbers and models of
specific alt devices that were targeted
this one right over here I found on
Aliexpress selling for $62 a lot of the
Lua devices were specifically targeted
so the DDoS that were carried out by the
moriah botnets were extremely large
scale we'll look at Krebs of crabs on
security if you're not familiar about
Krebs and security he's a very popular
blogger that writes a lot about malware
DDoS attacks when this bot was
discovered he wrote a really long blog
post describing the botnet and also was
able to find out with very good
confidence who the authors of this
botnet was in response a couple days
later they DDoS them with 600 gigabits
per second what's really interesting is
that a camera I was hosting his website
already because he was we often we
targeted with DDoS attacks and it was
the largest DDoS attack to come I ever
witness and what they did is they
actually pulled the plug on his blog but
the Google project shield stepped in and
said we'll host your blog from now on
they have competing technology a CDN
that they promise to prevent DDoS
attacks are able to hold against them
next is OVH they were targeted with one
terabit per second DDoS attack what's
crazy about OVH was when I was doing the
research for this talk is they get DDoS
around a thousand two hundred times a
day which is crazy and the DDoS attack
that stood out by far was this video s
attack we'll talk more of why they were
targeted next was Dyna DNS they provide
DNS hosting solutions for all the major
IT companies I remember specifically one
evening when I was tryna browse Reddit
and the pages stopped loading restarted
my router
Randee to see what was going on and DNS
resolution was failing the next day I
found out that one of the largest DDoS
attacks ever was performed against Dyna
DNS so the malware has an upgrade update
functionality where they could they were
able to add new functionality to their
botnet it was only using DDoS attacks it
used around six different methods of
carrying out the DDoS attack for some
reason the authors of moriah
decided it was a good reason to share
their botnet source code online the
authors of moriah were pretty
interesting people they thought that
maybe if they would share the source
code online that they would kind of
reflect responsibility onto others so
the way the moriah bought networks is
very primitive you'll see a lot of
things here are very primitive so what
it does is it just Kansas the internet
looking for port 23 or port 23 23 which
is just plain text telnet it attempts to
brute-force login what ten random
usernames from a hard list of 62 so if
it determines that it could contain a
connect to this IOT device here we're
connecting to a digital video camera and
it determines that you can login with
admin admin it'll talk back to its
report server and let it know that this
IP address you could login with admin
admin
next the loader program I find this
quite interesting keep in mind that IOT
products are running a whole bunch of
different architectures so when you
connect a via telnet to one of these
devices you're not sure if it's MIPS
you're not sure if it's armed and what
variant of arm it is so via talat you
have to detect what kind of architecture
this device is running and then one out
of the eight downloaders or loaders of
the botnet will be installed onto this
device and installed or Mariah botnet
and in fact
the device uses some pretty basic
obfuscation nothing new randomizing the
process name so it's harder to figure
out if something weird is going on in
your device it deletes its own
executable so it doesn't survive reboots
but that's not a problem in the first 72
hours I believe 11,000 devices were
infected and these numbers were doubling
every hour so when you have that big of
a botnet being reinfected happens very
quickly and most IOT devices don't get
rebooted that often to begin with
deleted or removed competitive services
so telnet was disabled as a choice and
stable so you want to be able to gain
access to the device once it was
infected then it just continues being
about net to net connects to its command
and control server and listens to who
will attack next and of course it just
continues scanning for more victims and
going to botnet
so quick recap targets a whole bunch of
IT IOT Linux in their devices around 30
vendors were targeted but a lot of
vendors just don't a lot of vendors have
multiple devices so it's not only
limited to 30 different devices so it's
very efficient at spreading via brute
force over telnet and it scanned the
whole internet something interesting
that the authors sought to do was not
scan Department of Defense in the US the
US Postal Service and other American
entities for some reason they thought if
they didn't scan these guys maybe we
won't get the attention of the
authorities but then they carried out
the largest ddos attack ever so and of
course it uses an extremely primitive
attack vector username password and you
know all these IOT devices all have very
simple combinations so in I'm gonna just
talk about the motive which is also very
interesting the motive behind Mariah was
money and minecraft while reading about
Mariah I learned that if you were in a
minecraft server you can make up to a
hundred thousand US dollars a month
somehow and these guys had a pretty cool
business idea so what they did is they
set up a company and promised ddos proof
minecraft hosting and in order to get
people to come through their hosting
platform and host minecraft servers they
DDoS everyone so that's specifically why
they attacked OVH OVH is one of the
largest hosting companies that hosts
minecraft servers and they thought that
if they attack dinah dns they would
somehow bring a bunch of minecraft
servers found and everyone would come to
their hosting company and they'll make a
lot of money of course that resulted in
their arrests because then that was a
pretty big attack and they use no OPA
sec and wrote all kinds of things on
hacker form online
which is crazy so they caused the
largest internet outage in recent
history and the largest DDoS attack ever
recorded one variant of Mariah was
capable of infecting 900,000 Dutch
telecom modems and of course it
highlights a new threat that trivial is
or the you used to seeing botnets infect
servers or desktop computers but now
you're seeing that these Linux devices
that are connected to the internet that
are being infected and if the future is
going to have billions of them something
has to be done so Bricker bought
everything here is in the name I'm sure
you could figure it out what it does so
it was discovered in March 2016 the
author said he was really inspired by
Mariah and very recently in the end of
December he wrote a update to his
manifesto saying that his project was
over he claims to have bricked ten
million devices using his botnet and
wrote a grant that IOT security is
non-existent and to prove it he
destroyed a whole bunch of devices so he
carried out the permit denial of service
would essentially bricks your device I'm
not sure if you can see those commands
on the right hand side but essentially
what the bots did was once it connected
it just assured your device by running
random data to the memory and secondary
storage and then deleting the route to
the Internet and then rebooting your
device so essentially you're left with a
brick
again very Tribble a trivial attack
vector scanning the antenna for port 23
it also used other techniques but same
idea
proof for seeing telnet SSH and HTTP
authentication something that was
interesting is this author actually used
a zero-day that was eventually found out
that affected some modems and like I
said earlier basically delete everything
disable your network reboot brick one
thing that's very interesting is so
since this botnet destroys your device
you don't really have a botnet what you
have is a central attacking command
center and the way this worked is around
an estimated 10 IPs that were hiding
before behind tor exit nodes that were
scanning the internet looking for
devices and breaking them so that was
really not a botnet here so the author
wrote a manifesto he updated it and had
more things to say very recently in the
end of December of 2017 so you could see
what he says here
larger tax would force the industry to
finally get it back together
again should I mention this earlier but
it's mostly busy bug busybox Linux
devices ssh telnet hiding behind 10 IDs
cannot spread because it bricks and
username password in India there were
60,000 modems that were actually bricked
because of this bot and one of its 0
days I believe so a summary of the
botnets I skipped out on Hajime but I'll
give you guys a chance to read this very
quickly and I'll give you a quick
summary of how hajima was somewhere like
Mariah and somewhere like brick box but
bigger bought somewhere in the middle so
edema was very much like Mariah but it
didn't brick devices like brick robot
and Mariah didn't brick devices all it
did was connect to devices and get rid
of telnet and basically get rid of
Mariah's oxygen supply there was no
attack code in any of the reverse
engineering of hajima and it's central
it wasn't it wasn't centralized it was
decentralized in nature which was very
interesting so the author of this botnet
actually created a fully decentralized
botnet using BitTorrent protocols so I
used a distributed hash table to talk to
all the bots and he used UTP UDP over
TCP for trade transferring data amongst
this botnet
he's never pulled out an attack he
claims to be a vigilante that's trying
to just kill Mariah's oxygen supply by
killing telnet so very interesting
botnets happening in the IOT world
so why are ilt the rice is targeted so
the embedded world apparently has the
ship it forget it mindset where once you
ship your device you basically basically
forget about it ease of use coolness or
the product is always cooler for some
people and lacking security as a
side-effect of this so some people don't
want to think about their default
credentials are and just try admin admin
and too lazy to look at a manual or a
neat your device to figure out what the
randomly generated credentials are and
finally a lot of these devices were
extremely cheap unbranded and sold by
some random companies if you're selling
a very cheap DVR equipment for sixty two
dollars and you have no idea who the
company is there's no real identity to
protect finally they make great targets
they're sold in very large numbers and
all identical find the vulnerability and
one you own them all
so again you could see that the attack
vectors were similar another interesting
thing is as soon as you log in you get a
root login shell so you could do
whatever you want so how do we get
device manufacturers to actually create
devices that aren't is so easily
hackable we're looking at
vulnerabilities that we've seen in 1990s
this is like a Windows machine or
Windows 1998 there's no security in any
of these products and everything could
have been remedied very simply device
manufacturers should be held accountable
this is not always easy because if your
device manufacturer is somewhere in
China and you know nothing about who is
actually manufacturing device it's not
easy to bring them to court and say your
IOT botnet caused all this damage one
good idea is that the IOT cyber security
Improvement Act is hopefully coming so
we have a major player US government
that's trying to pass some legislation
what they want to do is have a bill that
has some basic principles that you have
to follow when designing an IOT device
like being able to update it signed
artifacts and whatnot so in case you
find a vulnerability in it or there's a
design flaw you can easily fix the
problem by shipping an update or maybe
we need more Bricker bots that just
destroy all the devices that are easily
hexed
so as we looked at the anatomy of the
typical attack you'll see here that
reconnaissance was just distributed in
passport scanning and looking for
especially telnet 7yz botnets leveraged
other things like SSH
but telnet was the most successful
attack intrusion very basic using a
password list and some of them used an
exploit one of them was a CW NP exploit
that is some routing routing protocol
I'm not really familiar with that had
some remote code execution that they
were able to leverage and gain access to
the device entering the backdoor just
requires detecting the environment
downloading and running the binary one
thing I didn't mention earlier is the
way they detect the environment that
you're running on you have to figure out
if you're running arm or MIPS or whatnot
I believe hajime's method was pretty
interesting what it did is it looked at
the first few bites of the echo command
and using that it was able to determine
what architecture this system was built
for and then download the loader finally
process name obfuscation and removing
binaries very typical things that
viruses and malware do
fixing these problems was again
easy these devices were listening to
telnet and ssh on your public interface
you probably don't have to do that you
could probably just close these ports
and have some other way of accessing
these device next for the last decade if
you look at a modem or router some of
them usually come with a random
generated password so you don't just
guess admin admin to gain access and
finally principle these privilege you
don't have to give someone a root shell
with default credentials and they can
carry out anything they could want to do
I'm gonna quickly talk a little bit
about an over the air update err which
is possible to mitigate all these
problems so essentially if you have an
an IOT device out in the market and you
find out that either your design is bad
for a new vulnerability is found and
your devices are all hackable you need
some sort of mechanism to update your
device there's quite a few update
mechanisms mender being one of them and
you would be able to address all these
issues by just updating the device and
getting rid of this design flaw or
vulnerability and over there the updater
means that essentially it's not the user
that's taking care of the update process
it could be managed remotely so some of
these devices that were attacked we're
very much like the firmware updating
that you do in your router you log into
a panel go to a website download
firmware and manually pick and update
the firmware so you're just passing the
burden on to the user
and one thing you have to keep in mind
when downloading a over-the-air update
tool is it's not always easy to make a
homebrew one and leave it up to another
company so they take care of design like
what happens if you hit power loss
during an update process you don't want
to be like brick or bot and destroy your
device you want some way of being atomic
and do some sort of automated rollback
if the firmware update fails then of
course you don't want to be able to do
any sort of man-in-the-middle attack and
the modify the firmware while you're
passing it over and updating your device
so you need of course crypto and finally
you want to make sure that the owner of
the device are the ones that are
supplying the updates so not anyone
could flash your device with any
firmware they will they want and this is
the last slide not much just something
you think about I'm open to questions
no questions if you have any questions
about my slides please if you have
questions about OTA update or zag mender
I just wonder if any of these buttons
are targeting devices from ipv6 I notice
that if I put mm-hmm that's that's a
good question oh yeah sorry sorry so the
question was if devices work if a device
is connected via ipv6 I don't recall
seeing anything specifically about this
but if I'm going to guess I mean with IP
VC ipv6 adoption rate what is it right
now like 20 percent less then your
attack vector would be reduced
significantly but it would be of course
nice to have as an advantage but I'm not
sure about that
yep closing the boat closing ports and
reaching it some other ways so I knows
oh yes sorry if there was a way to not
open port on your public interface and
use some other way of connecting to it I
know some d-link I think it's d-link or
some other manufacturer has some URL
that you could use to connect to to
connect to your device like some sort of
reverse HTTP proxy where they allow you
to connect to the device by not directly
connecting to the interface that's one
technique used I'm not sure if that's
the best idea but some routers have this
kind of technology but it is a hard
problem to solve as well
question here oh sorry are you aware of
any attacks where I mean not standard
like guessing a password attacks have
been have been used apart from the ones
you mentioned how likely is it so the
question was
besides the telnet and brute-forcing
what other attacks were used so the most
successful attack was the default telnet
SSH was also pretty good and HTTP but I
mentioned earlier in one of my slides a
routing protocol that some of these
routers were using that had a zero-day
that was being leveraged in Bricker bots
so the author knew of some zero-day used
it and checkpoint quickly found out that
pricker bot was using something that
hasn't been disclosed before so it's not
only telnet the color was very
successful and extremely primitive