[Applause]
those of
okay design is the creation of a plant
or Convention for the construction of an
object system or measurable human
interaction an open-source is something
that people can modify in fear because
its design is publicly accessible so
open source design is the design whose
design is publicly accessible
I believe it's much more than that and
I'm here to convince you about that
I am Michel de metrio I'm involved in
both open source and design for a good
10 years now and I believe that open
source design should help users to
exercise the freedom that open-source
provides current design trends do not
promote our freedom probably the
opposite the things around us are
designed to keep us out in the name of
ease of use security or good looks but
the user that uses something most easily
the most secure user the happiest user
is the one that knows that how anything
works so making something automatically
work will cause a few moments of initial
delight but the effects in the long term
are exactly the opposite I realized this
by showing the incredible advance in
seed in deep learning and neural image
manipulation to friends and co-workers
co-workers during the past few years
people that don't understand the
complexity of the system involved are
the lift impressed technologies magic
for them and can do anything there's a
story I read when I was little which
described the family indeed a family
dinner during which one of the adults
starts floating over the table despite
what one would think the children are
the one that are the least amazed they
are used to seeing amazing new things
all the time
adults on the other hand have know that
floating over the pet table is
impossible and are genuinely surprised
trying to make technology look like
magic help keeper uses child back which
is good this making that sound it's not
we might wonder why I mentioned click
wait and fake news during in the in the
notes of their presentation it's because
I believe that fake news calls for
universal universal backdoors and
conspiracy theories all have one thing
in common they stem from the inability
of the crowd to distinguish between what
is impossible and what's possible or
improbably the ability to do that
improves with a firmer understanding of
how things work unless everything is
reduced to a black box only the elusive
expert and the star Scotty see how
things work in fact nobody does all the
things are adjust some of ballot boxes
and any given expert can only know what
one of those parts does so nobody a
difference how the whole works but let's
go back a little bit to the design
movements of yesteryear let's go back to
other flaws and modernism and his
declaration on ornament is crime or to
the Russian constructivists that thought
all art was political and that building
the USSR was a great art project to the
Bach of smarted modernist the thought
that art should adapt to the new era of
the machine we can also go to today's
emotion durably an emotionally durable
design that aimed to save the
environment by designing things that we
that we will love more as time passes
through those guys and many many more in
the history of the art design thought
that they could change the world with
their creations they thought they could
make the lives of people better some by
promoting social status otherwise
diminishing it somebody promoting
technology and others by promoting mass
cannot consumption I believe that
today's design trend trends try to
promote an easy life but fail actually
promoting blissful ignorance do you know
what the biggest search term by volume 1
by volume is on Google Facebook why
because people can't distinguish a
search term from URL and number 3 is
Google I think this is our fault and we
have to fix it it has used security
implications and it's clearly a failure
of our design we are trapped in our
bubble and we've lost
the real results of our work we think of
anyone knows basic things about
technology because we do but the reality
is that many don't and since we managed
to get rid of manuals through intuitive
design now it's our job to treat them
there are many more examples of how
current design fails but I think the
most popular manifestation is fakes is
Facebook's fayed news problem they try
to reduce the unlimited complexity of a
thing called news to the princes to the
presence or not of this a small red flag
of course they manage to do the opposite
of what they intended it's deeply
ingrained in people in Silicon Valley
mentality simplify anything down to a
single click and that brings me to why
it fails it fails because our world
complex complexity is there and it is
inevitable the universe is complex our
solutions to the problems caused by
complexity usually involve adding even
more complexity in our effort to
simplify things as designers we end up
just hiding complexity behind usually
insane interfaces that make assumptions
by driving over the complexity with a
road paving roller machine of the UI we
destroy all kinds of nuances people love
to love just visit any kind of community
that loves a certain sampling feed
coffee tea audio equipment cars whiskey
gaming keyboards jeans desktop
environments whatever and you will find
that the discussion always gets down to
the slight nuances that make each other
each one's favorite thing unique to the
point sometimes of absurdity so let's go
to typesetting it's an example of the
results of UI in oversimplification
latter might be intimidating but
requires you to invest the time to learn
everything about typesetting before you
produce a very nice document word
processor comes to make this easy but in
reality they never allowed the masses to
produce work comparable to that of
professional typesetters why is that
because typesetting is hard work you
have to know all about kerning and
hinting and widows and orphans and poems
positive and negative space
and no amount of buttons and nice
interface element is gonna make that it
easier it just provides the false sense
of competence so all the CVS I receive
say excellent use of Microsoft Word in
the same paragraph in which the use
spaces to write a line assented we make
the effort to build a million different
options to your software and then we go
and hide them behind this this
essentially says hey I assume you are
too stupid to change the settings please
don't this doesn't mean that your hub
should have a 500 top settings dialog
but why hide things about config or
Android developer settings so hard and
then there are the options that aren't
even there
on one hand we try to promote open
source software as something that
provides freedoms and then we turn
around and take a look freedoms away by
hiding them behind compiler flags as we
know that our users cannot don't know
how to recompile our software
if this isn't two-faced I don't know
what is so I think it's our duty as open
source design to have a political agenda
to actually do try and change the world
to be something more than automated
operators of a/b studies and usability
testing to care not only whether our
user will do the tasks quickly and
effortlessly not only if she's going to
engage more with our item but also if
she will live the interaction happier
wiser and why not the better person it's
not a coincidence the deep end option
found that the computer skills of
undergraduates
dropped off between 1996 and 2006 it's
the period of gee Steve Jobs returned to
Apple and the dominance of just works
the same period so an almost religious
purge of anything is it that he
resembled the command line or
programming from computer committed
consumer computers they come without
anything dot-com of program ability they
are from their former primary purpose to
be fair this give birth to excellent
visual computer interactions and help
computers reach millions of people
have nothing against that but they took
it too far so what do I propose to force
everybody through coding assembler like
real men no of course not technology
must be accessible to everyone it must
have an easy on-ramp and not be
intimidating it is possible you talked
about typesetting a few minutes ago on
one end on one hand you have a letter
which is steep and intimidating in other
hand you have Microsoft Word which just
promote single ignorant I'm sorry I have
to take
is there a middle ground
I think stock headed the markdown is a
very good example of a middle ground it
doesn't look a hieroglyphics to an
untrained eye it is easy to learn and a
single row of buttons who allows you to
do most of the things you'd want to do
in a document while at the same time you
see exactly what the computer sees after
the few process of the B button in a
markdown editor if you're slightly
interesting to you and understand that
it all does it's around the word you are
typing with double asterisks and you'll
be able to do it saving yourself a trip
to the toolbar AutoCAD is another nice
example the closest it's a point it says
pointers click as amis paint but there's
a nice little command line on the bottom
that repeats every command you do even
if you click on it with a mouse still a
few times you start learning what their
commands are and you can tell them
yourself there's also a nice predictable
shortcut scheme that helps you work with
shortcuts without having to go to the
manual so let's break it down to simple
through some simple rules one teach you
know those Troubleshooters that never
work but why not instead of trying to
fix the problem you present your user
with the steps she would take in order
to on the stud wake is printed or his
internal taxes doesn't work teach them
the process of the elimination and why
you know while we are doing this explain
to them what DMS is and what and why
this is probably the problem when you
can reach the IP address and not do
google.com to ask politely to show more
information
I'm pretty sure that there are millions
of people that are curious with what
happens between pressing their keyboard
in the URL bar and seeing the web page
they intended to see so ask them
politely did you ever wonder what
happens behind the scenes well when you
type the here not only you get to show
all the fancy things you do on every on
every keystroke but also explains why
you ask if you want to enable such
suggestions and why the answer shouldn't
be of course why do you even ask by the
way I've seen people pasting past
the URL bar to see if they are correct
three use the jargon stop replacing
intimidating jargon with softer words
it's confusing to those who know it's
different in every brand a brand and
makes for an awful awkward situation
when you are trying to give or get help
these are the the words that Samsung and
LG use instead of colour subsampling
don't be patronized patronizing this is
not a good 404 page unlike the hip
language but what these spaces is
frankly there are no pollen
passing the computer searching for your
mistyped webpage check the spelling or
go to a wave of ACMA sheen and because
design isn't only software 5 make
repairs easy including repair manual
link to disassembly videos don't use
glue embrace wear and tear stop
cherishing smoothness and units
scratches and marks so use and utility
use that in your design 6 make it
replaceable interchangeable so it's a
show its inner-workings develop 3d
printers are a very good example of what
I'm talking about you can see and learn
exactly how they work you can infinitely
repair them and you can upgrade them
with parts you can buy off the shelf and
then you can go and build your own
contrast at regular printers which are
almost always simple to replace than to
repair checksum time is cheaper to
replace and buy new inks and because we
know nothing about them they seem to
never work
we have a certain focus on the tools
nowadays and not the crafts we have
fixed it with only digital tools that
allow us to do crafts and now people say
that they they know AutoCAD instead of
architectural drafting they say that
they know Photoshop instead of graphic
designer
digital for the development and that
this year's watercraft and the
equivalent open-source software making
them look inferior if you know how to
dig the brand of the shovel shouldn't
matter
so I think that what I described is good
open source design design should mean
but design is always controversial and
it should be and so in order to avoid
hijacking the term I would like to call
this approach transparencies I invite
you all to join me in to creating
examples of transparent design and put
these ideas into even more concrete
rules and approaches and influence the
future of design I have created a kit
lab a github organization which is still
empty but I'd like to fill it with
examples rules and other things that
would help future designers follow this
approach thank you very much
[Applause]
and if you have any questions I don't
think it's about the level I don't
that's why I said we don't need to make
everybody codon assembly assembly is
hard we don't have to make things hard
we have to make them easy but in the
process show the people what's happening
behind the scenes
so when something goes wrong which it
will go and we all know it instead of
just believing that printers came from
hell
we understand that it's the roller thing
in the printer that its fault and then
that we can go to a store and buy
another and put it in there and that to
be able to do that it it first means
that the whole community requires the
manufacturer to be like that so there
was a 3d printer manufacturer who
started putting filament into cartridges
like the like the regular printer guys
do and they they didn't manage to keep
that approach not even a year because
everybody else uses
interoperable filament and you can buy
filament from Weaver from everywhere and
put in your printer so nobody could
accept buying the proprietary thing that
would I'd like to see a design that
makes users understand what's behind and
that and then they want to learn and
because they learned they are empowered
to do things and not be controlled by
the whatever scheme is devised so that
manufacturers for examples can sell more
printers I don't know if I answered
a lot of effort to make that transition
so for users that just kind of see some
guide and say oh and then it changed it
perf and I can do this Pacific so the
question a few words was why I was
against the about config warning and
what about the users that don't want to
learn actually that page was put there
because I anticipated this kind of
question I wanted to talk a little bit
about that I think that instead of
having that page and then a bunch of
options that are in JavaScript
notation with thoughts there should be
no warning and then every option should
have two lines of text I'm sure that
this is very short time needed compared
to the time needed to implement an
option in the code and that explains
what is it and why it should or it
should not be clicked and maybe for some
especially dangerous options there
should be a warning near the specific
option because in the boat config until
recently it was the control tab switch
between the latest tabs option and other
options that were very dangerous and
allow disable encryption and everything
else so bundling them all in the same
basket and then telling a user okay go
learn and then come back is much worse
than describing what everything does and
why he should or he should not click on
okay that's that's a valid point
yes what is a valid use case and I
understand that there might be backlash
if you go and remove rough something
that people use yeah yeah that's
something that maybe you should be
discussed more or maybe you'll just
write anything else or do I have more
time alone okay okay I will do that yeah
sure it's locked I'll do that but it's
just credits for the accept accept the
gift cup report all the others there's
just the credits for the videos and the
artwork I used but I will put them into
paddleball
[Applause]