all right okay I'll start quickly
because I've already quite made ha
after the DisplayPort and actually also
the fundable mode failed to actually get
picture on this thing we're back to VGA
which always works yeah all right
my name is Christian I work for netted
in the desktop hard when in mind group
probably the next slide yeah what is the
fun about anyway I'm gonna be really
fast now it's according to enter the
u.s. PC that does it all which is
already very confusing because I said
something about the now I said use PC
and I think that's probably gonna happen
the next five years for a lot of people
especially supplements and stuff because
it's actually the same port this little
this newest port is also another
Nintendo switch and everything and it
can be a USBC plane use PC ports but it
can also be a fundable port and and
normally you can distinguish them if
there's a little arrow next to it a
little flash
yes hands like they're there if there
are ports or the ellipsis or there that
have only a USB C port that don't have a
fund of all right I don't know exactly
exactly exactly you can distinguish them
by little icon that has next to them if
there's space for all the icons anyway
so if it's an actual founder of Freeport
you would have a little bolt next to it
and if it's a funder for free port it
can it's very fast it can do up to 40
agreements per second it can support up
to three a four PCI Express Lanes
sometimes not on all chips there's also
this is also up to so you know it's also
up to eight DisplayPort lanes and it
always supports USB 3.1 it fits the
phone the both free device and you can
data change up to six devices and then
it's done it supports charging your
laptop and the devices can use up to 15
watts and their people
I mean the most use case I think for now
which the heart was most available for
is in stock stocks or talks like like
this guy here this Li it's a fund of all
three dogs from Lenovo but there's also
for example from Razer an external
enclosure where you can have a GeForce
graphics card for all your aetherium
mining the next thing yeah
so the confusing part about the
connection mode is that the one port can
be actually four ports and it can be in
OS the only mode which if you connect a
USB plug a USB device in it the final
port actually switches into USB only
mode and it acts as a normal USB port if
you plug in the DisplayPort device then
it can be also just a display port and
it can also be a combination of display
port and USB and only if you have the
right cable the cable also needs to have
a little flash thingy on it like this
like a little only if you have to write
thunderbolt use PC cable whatever you
call it then you get actually the the
Thunderbolt controller into its native
thunderbolt mode where you get the high
speed and the full you know PCI Express
bridges to the device and you get all
those super nice features and yeah
including of course because it's PCI
Express DMA which means that someone can
just read your memory or write into your
memory whatever right and it took until
apparently three revisions to realize
this problem and or they're CIA leaks or
something
so in thunderbolt free we actually have
security modes and the security modes of
like there's four of them and you can
set them in the bios in most computers
not all four might be supported I think
lenovo start started not enabling the
non mode anymore because none what is
basic legacy mode which means that you
don't get in security and then you have
DisplayPort only which only gets
DisplayPort if it actually working and
then there's to secure modes which means
that the user mode in the secure mode
and in both of these modes in userspace
we actually have to tell
the device to like work we have to like
you know to plug the device in the
device registers within the kernel but
we have to say like ok we want this
device to be activating and only then we
get the PCI Express Lanes and only then
we get the malicious attacks hopefully
not but maybe and the difference between
a user mode in the second mode is that
in the second mode you can also supply a
key to the device which then you can
later use to re-identify the device so
like if someone fiddles Swift with your
dock and install something in there then
you know hopefully this is get caught by
this better secure mode or replaces your
dog you know with a different one and on
Windows you know the land of dialogues
when you actually plug in a nude even
find out what device you get a bunch of
dialogues like ok there's a new
Thunderbolt device what do you want to
do with it you want to connect it don't
you want to connected and you know our
designers I mean ignore designers
thought that this was a very very bad
idea because but most of the time
happens people just click on it because
it will make your Bimmer work or it will
make you or whatever and you know a
person sensors already in a hurry
because nothing works and then of course
you click everything you click ok ok ok
anyway so how does how do we do this in
in in Linux land we have the kernel
which gain thunderbolt support what
wonderful support in for 13 and it
exposes the devices biases of s and
Yudof there's a smaller system demon
which gets activated by you def rules
and then we have the gnome shell and
pigrome control center talking to it
there it's a deepest API so other people
can talk to you too I'm not sure if it
actually happened yet and there's a
command-line tool if you want to
actually fiddle around just an
integrated stuff which I don't expect
most people to actually want to do how
much time of stuff can I slow down and
no no no I have to be fast up ok just
the kernel interface not so interesting
because you know I mean normally
shouldn't actually use it but you know
just of interest if you plug a device in
it will show on understand about and
there's one file called authorize if you
just put a one in there the device will
work you know it was connect the PCI
Express name
and everything and then for the secure
mode this is how you would on the
command line do it you know you create a
key you write it into the device the key
bit actually gets stored in the
non-volatile Ram on this on the device
and then your bits of one you actually
authorize the device and store the key
in the device and then on the next
connect you supply the key and only then
if the device responds with the right
challenge to the key the device will be
activated by the kernel just a very
quick in term internet so there's also
firmware for the funderbolt host
controllers and also for the devices so
I have a del doc to test in Munich and
also they are the cable actually has its
own firmware so you can update your
cables somewhere and it works all I mean
if it's all done it there's a plugin for
early November vendor service and for
FWD and it will you know you can
magically Vai agree update your cable so
the little demon that I wrote in the
last few months it's just exposing the
source of s where where it's a very
small daemon actually why a diva's api
and the main use of this demon is
basically for the photic gnome shell -
yeah thank you you know to speak to it
or for other clients to speak to it and
you can use it to authorize and enroll
the device from from user space it uses
poor kids and once the device initially
was enrolled it has a little database
it's just files in the filesystem to
remember them and then on the next time
you plug the device in there it just
automatically even before that notion is
longer than something with automatically
authorize the device if you set it
should do that exactly so that the Davis
IP is also very simple so it has only
you can get the devices you can enroll
the device you can forget the device
anymore and there's one little thing
there which is called the 45 mode so
normally this is not so super I skip
this yeah there's sort of the command
line which you know because that's the
same thing authorized devices Android
devices live devices money for 225
Changez but it the way we normally think
what he was going to do with it is that
it just magically works so if you are
locked in and your session is unlocked
and you plug a device in and you are
also the admin like you are in the wheel
group then we will basically ask policy
kit but there's a special policy Kosovo
check kids will have a check that you
are an admin and if you are an admin it
will just automatically authorize the
device and if not you will get a the
usual Polish secret dialog like you know
wanting to enter your password and if
you have the admin password you know you
can go and also will authorize the
device and then remember it for the
future if you're not locked in or the
session is locked then we don't do
anything because it might be someone
else trying to steal your main main
memory and you know about just plugging
a device in and and what we do is we we
throw up a dialog basically yeah like
this where you say oh there's a new
Thunderbolt device that has been
attached to your computer and what you
need to do is to basically replug the
device so there's not even like in the
GUI there's no way to actually
afterwards authorize the device why I
click on something what you need to do
is physically take the cable unplug and
replug it viola session is unlocked
which is what our designers came up with
the best solution to not you know have
another dialog that says authorize the
device yep there's also little users
like a little snake thingy I can when
when something's actually have another
funderbolt boss because for the dell dog
for example it takes up to 10 seconds
from you plugging the device in until
your network card in the dark is
actually working because you know
network mate has to do is magic and the
cable has to first be authorized and
after the cables authorized the dog has
to be authorized and this you know like
this takes forever yeah
so that the authorization you mean if
you if you're in second word yes you go
here so you give it a key and then it's
basically like hash hash something you
know you have to key in the device
thought and you challenge the device
with some random data and it sends you
like some HTML whatever thing back and
the kernel does the same thing and
compares the hashes and if they match
it's the same device yeah there you go
and then there's also a little control
center thing which basically allows you
to manage the devices so you know they
can remove the device again once you
have done it and it will also help you
like once if you if you're plugged in a
device right by the screen was locked
you would also you know find a more
descriptive hopefully message there like
and you click on the little notification
thing you can go there and it will tell
you that you have to reconnect the
device yeah and that's it there's not
much time for questions but I think yeah
yes yeah they have they have more the
the normal to em has support for more
than one key yeah but I think I haven't
tried it I used like four or five
computers and it still work but I'm I
guess at some point it will overwrite
the keys and but I three or four at this
work