so are you enjoying enforce them so far
okay I can do that because so this we
have not yet started we're just making
time for everybody to arrive so I work
for the Wikimedia Foundation I don't
know if everybody's familiar with it do
you know what I'm talking about did I
say Wikimedia people do you reckon
recognize better the brand Wikipedia so
we at the foundation or nonprofit
organization we are funded just by very
generous donors and our mission is to
support all the open knowledge projects
that are maintained by the community so
we are just the foundation to support
them with an own Wikipedia we don't have
a decision on what's being edited or or
not what we try to do is to support
financially in terms of software
development so MediaWiki mostly another
software related to run the wikis and in
particular our team is in charge of
maintaining the servers to receive a
huge amount of traffic that we have to
to be able to serve not only Wikipedia
with videos the most famous project but
there are a lot of other projects not as
one known I don't know if you're
familiar with Wikimedia Commons it's a
repository of files
mostly images sounds and video but also
other other files I've actually just
uploaded the slides to Wikimedia Commons
yes I configure this okay you got this
very good idea of disabling the touchpad
when a mouse is on and it doesn't work
I know there's another project and I
will start soon there's another very
successful player which I personally was
quite surprised which is wiki data you
familiar with it which is not just
having text and images on own wiki pages
but actually have a repository of a free
database that is of everything so it's a
structured data that can be queried by
anyone so if you're interested on
knowing more please visit there's a wiki
medial at all and the Wikimedia
Foundation dot or websites and you can
check all our projects and of course I
will encourage you to edit Wikipedia the
mirrors who who participate parse it
make some content or ready it's or has
ever edited on Wikipedia or any okay the
rest what are you waiting for
we need your contributions please please
it takes just a mobile phone to edit
something and with things like wiki data
photograph an image it takes very little
to to contribute at the other thing we
just before we properly start is we are
hiring on the side reliability
engineering team so if someone was to
work with us after even after everything
I will tell you please contact me or you
can go to to this website
yeah you can trust him on that
what's this my school enters in Navarre
and since goes to a table and says can I
join you as you can see I'm horrible at
I shouldn't even try okay let's go so I
did the long introduction before I will
present myself properly and find a
Crespo
I work as a DBA that resin illustrator
in the technology team for that would be
media foundation and I'm going to talk
about TLS TLS I will be talking
sometimes I won't mention in TLS
sometimes I will be saying SSL in all
cases I will really mean TLS but because
MySQL and MariaDB is still depending on
configuration and many other projects as
SSL sometimes I will say SSL and one of
the myths I have been found around TLS
is that it is hard and it is it doesn't
work because I have a lot of load so I
cannot enable it so I need to run in a
less secure environment for the first
thing which is TLS is hard I had to say
no it is not this is an actual commit of
our public pepper repository will use
puppet for configuration management and
this is a commit that I personally did I
think a couple of years ago and
literally this is everything that did
this to enable TLS is literally three
lines of code three this is on the
client this is on the server this is an
apt on the actual production
configuration that we use for for
MediaWiki and yeah well I added some
flour so we can enable and disable that
wheel but that's it so that's how you
enable TLS I'm done thank you very much
that's all
[Applause]
the thing is the rest of the talk I
won't be telling you about the others I
actually don't know that much I'm not a
security expert I'm not a traffickers
but we have people that knows too much
about knows enough about photography
about a security what I'm going to talk
about are the operational paintings as a
DBA to enable this on a relatively large
scale so I will focus now on the large
scale part I'm not actually sure if we
are that large let me ask you for
example how many of you on your own are
responsible for hunting at least one my
squirrel Maria do your work on a server
ok
keep your hand up if you have more than
10 if you handle on your own more than
100 more than 1000 ok we can see that
those people are the ones that are
really large scale the thing I decided
to call ourselves large scale is because
if I show you things like these
is that we one of the great things of
being able to work on the Wikimedia
Foundation is that I can actually show
you this this is my wiki installation on
over to data centers and we have a few
of these and I can think scrolling if
you ask some of those people that have
thousands and I know they're much larger
than us they probably can't show you
this I can show you in real time this is
actually real time of how many queries
how many servants so my actual what I
want to show you is how I failed to
actually enable TLS it's actually an
ongoing project because I can open a
speak speak openly about everything that
I did and I fell so maybe you don't have
to commit the same mistakes that I did
and this is basically a summary of
everything that we have on our tracking
system which is open for everyone to to
see the best or the biggest failure poly
was that we're asked to production I was
when I was working I was at the time the
only DBA I was in charge of maintaining
all those databases putting out fires
there was very little automation I will
talk about that later but we were going
to do a data center failover for the
first time we need encryption on the
replication channels only my Scott
replication channels so what do I did
what did I do
I did not commit I show you before I
naval TLS and I said well I mean this is
just for a test so I will just create a
test certificate what happens with test
configuration and
deployments that test things become
permanent but I was wise I knew I had to
for myself to know something that is
temporary to be permanent so what did I
do
I generate a temporary certificate for
it was just one year one year it will
expire do you know what I'm going to do
you know who was restarting servers in a
rest because the TLS was about to expire
yes that so that's a hell Essen TLS is
not difficult to do it but probably it
was my fault to not push back and say
hey if we need this to be done with a
specific schedule maybe we can do other
kind of encryption that is easier to
suis and do manage an SSH tunnel big be
an encryption anything that we can like
change quickly and later who will do
what I had to do which is in this case
work three times as much first to enable
things do a full fleet restart then undo
the things and then redo the things
properly the other problem was resources
and happily after that I got at least
some help to manage that I'm not the
other problem we face is orchestration
that's something that again at the time
we didn't have the proper resources so
we weren't able to do very quick full
fleet restarts and that's something that
I think is one of the other big problems
with MySQL and I will talk later about
things I would like I would like to
change on my skull to make things easier
and is that every time that you have to
enable for the first time encryption or
you
you have to change the certificates
which was the case on this second roll
over st. the certificates - in this case
we started using the our the same puppet
certificates that we were using for for
our configuration management we reuse
them for my school - but every time
there was an open SSL bar you were
supposed to also restart my spell in
this case not because of a change of a
certificate but also because well you
have to have read up on itself or in
open SSL is quite easy but my spell has
to read then you serve library and for
that you need to do a restart and there
was a problem in terms of server and
client coordination because at that time
we enable only encryption just for
replication but if we wanted to change
the CA it was always an internal CA that
crossed the see replication from data
center one to the desert - it was not
easy to coordinate that because if you
change it here now application is broken
so of course you could just disabled the
application but at that point the point
was no no once we have enabled replicate
a cryptid replication we cannot go back
to plain text so we had to do complex
the for teaching is to be able to
replicate from different from a replica
the hell difference EA the failover
Sorella
most of these would have been much
easier if we have what the tools that we
have right now in terms of our
crustacean to handle this easy you want
to know more about auto station
there is a talk on the conservation
management track right Ricardo and I
recommend you to go there and check what
some open source tools we have developed
I already mentioned this server support
[Music]
we hit box with encryption not working
literally some older versions were
incompatible with the newest standards
of TLS and I don't know exactly what was
the issue but the version that we were
at the time a couple of years ago we
were still on fire five didn't
absolutely work for the kind of
Christian that we want okay well yeah
subarray the other issue that we face is
that only open SSL linked packages of
MySQL works with modern versions of TLS
I'm talking 1.2 and in the future
1.3 which means at that time they both
the upstream packages and once that were
provided by our distribution either you
want to or Debian they didn't work in in
fact Debian considers open SSL license
the old one or the current one and now
compatible with GPL so it is not about
of another question of these dozen were
no they at least for what I'm told
they're don't plan to link it because of
some technicality on on the license
which I'm not against but we definitely
need strong encryption here if we're
going to do it so no that was not the
only reason we also wanted to have
custom apply patches security bug ports
and other stuff but we one of the things
we had to do is to create our own path
setting of MySQL well in this case
MariaDB work on introducing
mariely 10-0 and we're migrating to
MariaDB 10.1
more pain client support third party
support some of the developers may also
be here without problems with PHP 5/5
that wasn't fully compatible with open
ssl 1.2 and this is probably in general
the the biggest pain most client
libraries connectors etc have some kind
of support for open source re TLS but
not 1.2 and the problem is
TLS 1 0 & 1 1 has protocols that are
vulnerable to security problems to
security exploit so we definitely wanted
to go for the secure for the secure
protocol for the one that at this tank
doesn't have numbers at least the
depending on the and occasional written
the other thing is we have been starting
playing with things like proxy SQL and
that's something that Renee having
something involves and the brown with
proxy SQL for example which is not a
client or connector is that because it
was using an older client the client
that proxy SQL interpreted didn't
support or one point to and that's kind
of a blocker as you can see for for us
and then something that is a bit curious
people were starting to see that they
write colleagues MySQL and they that
stopped working and it says something
like TLS error or something like that
why was that well one of the biggest
problems that I have to work to make me
understand is that
Harleen TLS for my school is a
completely different problem to handle
or a name
DLS for something like a posse passing
has the concept of filter horse the way
you use a passage normally with a public
certificate that is validated by the
external CA in our case we handle the
whole stuff with our own internal CA and
typically you connect through an IP
address but the certificates are based
on a domain so you will through
localhost for example through a socket
and we have enabled validate the domain
you cannot connect because the domain
and localhost doesn't match so that's a
silly thing but something to to come
into account when anybody's there were
some things that worked well I have to
say one of the things that I think we
did well is running it when we related
to production with it opt in which means
that we enable the support but every
single client can be slowly enabled on
the use of TLS for example we started
with the replication channel because
it's truly Z if you want to use
encryption starting to enable TLS
through the replication channel it has
almost no performance impact I will tell
you later why but it's mostly that it's
a single connection that is ongoing all
the time there's no a lot of connects
and disconnects and the impact on
performance is almost at least in our
case no no no no purpose but the other
the second step is enabling for
administration channels or things that
are not pure client heavy-hitters things
like administration things like schema
changes things like things that don't
really need the performance it doesn't
matter if connecting takes one second
when the connection technology because
you know you can wait
also going from through TLS 2.2 because
if we've had to have enable it with with
non open SSL yeah SSL or one of these
products that doesn't provide you full
compatibility we will be doing again
even more work to now enable TLS dot you
or in the future Daughtery and well
support in terms of we are in a place
that we people are really concerned
about privacy and security so having the
support from management on you know yes
spend time on this because this is
important is something that you really
want to have you don't want to say hey
don't waste time on see that security
stuff because it takes a toll on you we
are not I mean for 100% coverage right
now when I created this proposal I was
hoping that we will already have the one
compared hundred percent coverage but it
will eventually come and most cases in
our case it it is due to application
changes that are needed and we are now
on to male from hhv a.m. to PHP 7 so
there's a lot of work that gets there
and you know there's only 2 GBS so we
work on this on our free time let's say
this is a couple of things I wanted to
show you for the idea of I'm worried
about how much of a performance feed
this will have on it and on us and I
think you can trust me that we have
quite some performance if I have time I
will show you our real-time monitoring
that is public of how many queries how
many you have this is some test that we
did on Idol host so it's not fully
representative of an actual full log
but what forget of about so many numbers
and I want to
you remark that the difference within
SSL or TLS connections is what is can be
problematic we are talking about 20
times 250 times slower of the time for
connecting but in terms of actual query
performance the impact is less than 5%
so what what does this tell us just fix
the client library so they use
persistent connection and that's the
whole point of our interest on proxy SQL
so we can have proper there's some kind
of producing of connections and
application level right now but we need
full prayer creation of connection so
that that overfeed is already already
for what and by the time you need
equally ready so you could do the same
thing in our case started changing the
architecture takes a bit of time and
everything is like proxy SQL we are not
in a rush because we wanted this for
mostly Carosa TC queries which right now
we don't do but we may be intently doing
but we may fix that in a different way
in which you only have we may only need
to do same DC queries which is what we
want to do as the last thing is okay
how could you ease my pain the rest of
you there's literally probably more
three bucks
the last one is mine the first one I
think is by Simon Simon here and the
second one is by Eric and this is our
box already - please allow us to change
certificates in a hallway so if there's
any people from my store
please have a look at those valves maybe
like Marcus duplicate from the people
that are not part of MySQL but that part
of the my school community support of
property LS would be right rene swing
for example in case of proxy SQL super
helpful in that things um proper open
SSL 1.1 support which I think it's
available in both MySQL and manually on
the latest versions but we cannot all be
on the latest my skull or Mahadev
inventions so it would be helpful to
kind of support older versions of of my
spell or mariadb well if you have matrix
you know our test please share them I
will that's exactly what I'm doing I
already talked about pending work silly
finishing the emulation one thing I
didn't mention is TLS is not only for
security from the point of view of
someone is in the middle trying to get
queries that are going or private data
the other thing is enabling more secure
authentication methods which until 8.0
it was only possible if you were using
TLS in the connection so that's it thank
you very much and if you have any
questions we must have one minute for
that couple of minutes
yes
so there's there's several components
because so I will repeat the question I
just want to show the this our load of
most of all the dice so the question is
what do we use for our crustacean so
it's a combination of things depending
on what you call orchestration one of
the things that has been introduced
recently is a custom-made tool which was
called cumin which basically is a
replacing a proper replacement for salt
which was what was used for executing
remote commands in a parallel way and
this is a much better replacement you
won't know about that that's that the
Tokai I mentioned in terms of my sparrow
crustacean we are kind of trying to
build a custom library because things
like Orchestrator it doesn't fit very
well our own crazy use cases in terms of
pooling and the pooling servers in the
past we were know that was not a tool
that was not something we wanted we had
to go through the database coal comets
which was horrible the the current work
right now is to have some kind of
dynamic configuration object server and
probably is going to be something like
etcd so we can change much more
dynamically the weights and the pool
servers once we have etcd and with the
help of cumin it will be some things but
that are left like automatic master
slave switch but that I think will be
much easier once the other things are
fully on on place I don't know if that
answers your question
so lot of different things they are not
something like commercial in terms of
something that already exists
more questions sir yes so our full stack
is MariaDB sorry
PHP Maria DB Varney's well there's a lot
of Technology there as a rule we just
use open source or free server around
the holes so we don't let any if
anything to be installed our service it
is not some answers I think there are
some exceptions like people in the
office may use Windows or something like
that but in terms of service yes it's
it's fully open source yes
yes so the problems that the the idea is
we'll have a double certifications you
can migrate easily yes and definitely to
be fair right now that's not a huge
problem because the problem was
migrating from the bad testing stuff to
the proper stuff and definitely there's
ways to solve that I may not be using
dava certificate because it doesn't
actually solve the possible compromise
of the CA Authority so you still have to
have a way to kind of restart the
separate to introduce like a new non
existing CA and in terms of for example
replication is actually much easier than
I said because the certificates and the
confirmation for replication is purely
dynamic already so it's not really a
huge concern it was just at the time
so me like let's talk outside because
it's the magic
[Applause]