hi everyone I'm max I work at github on
the Adam text editor and I'm gonna talk
about a parsing library that I've been
working on for about four years now
initially as a side project and now as
part of some production systems that
github it's called tree sitter so I'm
gonna explain what it is and why I chose
to write it and then I'll talk about
some of the things we're doing with it
today at github and then finally I'll
talk about how it works so first what is
tree sitter so tree sitter is a library
for parsing source code it's written in
c and c++ and it's designed to be used
in applications like github or atom that
have to deal with code written in many
different languages so the idea is you
can use tree sitter to parse files
written in a variety of different
languages and it'll produce syntax trees
that all have the same api and the same
format the really unique thing the tree
sitter does is what's called incremental
parsing so that means that once you
parse the file with tree sitter and you
have the syntax tree representing that
file you can then edit the file and tree
sitter can quickly update the syntax
tree for you to reflect that the change
that you made without having to reparse
the whole file so it'll take something
less than a millisecond so that this is
the feature that makes it possible to
use tree sitter in a text editor like
atom to parse in real time while the
user is typing so now I'll explain why I
chose to write this so there are already
exists
good parsing tools today that are
specific to any given language if you
just want a Parsi you can use Lib clang
if you want to parse go you can use the
go ast package and so on and yet I would
argue that most of the tools that that
we rely on the most as software
developers still don't have good source
code parsing capabilities so for example
let's take a look at some syntax
highlighting that you might see in your
text editor today so you're some go code
it's kind of hard to read but it defines
a person type the thing about this is
you can see here that the types appear
in three different colors in this
example the person appears first in
yellow and then in white and then this
other type string appears in pink for
some reason
this is a screenshot from Adam but you
can see the same thing happens in
sublime text or a visual studio code and
so this isn't a good behavior and syntax
highlighting is something that we all
use all day every day whether we're
looking at code in our editor or on a
website like github or Stack Overflow
and so my question is with all the good
parsing tools that exist today why isn't
this super-important feature implemented
better and so I think there's kind of
three main reasons why these
applications that I mentioned don't use
all these standard partials that we know
of the first one that comes to my mind
is for performance so in a text editor
for the editor to feel lightweight and
fast syntax highlighting should update
on every keystroke and it needs to take
as I said less than a millisecond or so
and so that rules out right out of the
gate most partners that we would
normally use otherwise aside from that
for a lot of languages to use the
standard parser that comes with the
compiler you need to know some other
information about the file in order to
parse the file like for example if
you're parsing C you would need to know
all the other source files that are
included via the preprocessor and the
what macros are defined and so on and in
an environment like Adam or github where
we're trying to work with the code of
strangers we don't always know this
information and finally each languages
standard parsing tool chain has its own
dependencies is often written in that
language and so for apps that need to
work with tons of languages
out-of-the-box having to integrate with
all those tool chains would be very
complicated for our system and so what I
set out to do with tree sitter was to
build a one parsing system that could
not only handle all major programming
languages uniformly but could also do so
within these constraints so it's it can
be fast enough to run on every keystroke
in a text editor
and it doesn't require any additional
information about a source file in order
to parse it and has no dependencies in
fact it's it's implemented the runtime
is implemented as a pure C library so
you can really easily use it no matter
what language your application is
written in
all right so that's the pitch and I'll
show you what we're currently doing with
Tree Center at github so this some the
latest beta release of Adam this month
will include some new functionality the
users tree sitter it's still I'm still
developing it it's a bit unstable so
it's behind a feature flag do you'll
have to check a box if you want to try
it but if you do you'll get this new
improved syntax highlighting that that
I'm showing here so this is the same
piece of go code that I that I pointed
to earlier but now you can see that the
problem that I mentioned has been fixed
really nicely all the types consistently
appear in this blue green color and on
top of that all the strut field names
are now differentiated there they're red
whereas before the syntax highlighter
couldn't even tell struct fields from
local variables so this is go we also
can do the same thing in other languages
like C C++ typescript as well as
JavaScript Python Ruby and rust and
we're in the process of developing
support for a bunch more languages too
so aside from those improvements another
benefit of doing syntax highlighting
with tree sitter is the handling of long
lines so if any of you've ever opened up
a minified javascript file in a almost
any text editor like vim or Atom you'll
often see a little tiny bit of syntax
highlighting at the very beginning of
the file and then mostly a black and
white file because of this performance
limitation of conventional regex based
syntax highlighters
so by reimplemented syntax highlighting
with tree sitter the layout of the file
no longer matters it's using a proper
lexing and parsing tool chain so we can
weaken syntax highlight files like this
and then aside from the handling of long
lines overall performance of syntax
highlighting is just dramatically
improved as well so on this slide I'm
just showing an example of parsing at
the command line
some 20,000 line JavaScript file like
the development build of react j/s and
it takes about 69 milliseconds which is
I want to say not quite an order of
magnitude but much faster than the
syntax highlighting systems used in
normal editors like Adam Visual Studio
code yeah
so aside from syntax highlighting I've
also reimplemented Adams code folding
system to use the syntax trees that's
provided by tree sitter so as you might
be aware in in most text editors code
folding was based on some combination of
reg X's but often indentation so if you
have a C function like this which is
very common where the indentation of the
file doesn't match the syntax of the
file exactly code folding doesn't work
as you would intend but now by by
re-implementing code folding based on
the syntax tree it now works regardless
of what you do to the formatting of your
file so if you copy and paste code and
this indentation gets messed up you can
still use folding as a guide to the
structure of your code and then finally
we have added a new feature to Adam in
this latest beta
it's called extend selection you you
might be familiar with it if you've ever
used the jetbrains IDE it's a it's a
command for expect selecting larger and
larger pieces of your code based on the
syntax so it's it's really powerful for
editing efficiency it combines really
well with multiple cursors in this
animated gif here I'm reformatting this
data structure in this really powerful
way using a combination of extend
selection and multiple cursors that
would be really time-consuming if you
had to individually move each cursor
around
so aside from Adam we're also using tree
sitter on github.com so some of you may
have seen a feature come out a few
months ago on github where when you're
looking at a pull request and you open
up the
of changed files for that pull request
now you can see within each file a list
of the functions that have changed and
this is done by a team in github data
science organization that is doing a lot
of cool research about algorithms for
analyzing and comparing syntax trees to
each other and they use tree sitter for
all of their code parsing because it
gives them this uniform way of parsing
many different programming languages and
so between the work that they're doing
on github.com and the work that I'm
doing on Adam we're developing this
larger and larger set of languages that
tree sitter can parse and I think that
once these Adam features that I showed
you a moment ago go R go to the stable
release of Adam then that set of
partials will grow even faster because
now all this community of millions of
Adam users will be able to contribute
support for their favorite languages in
adam and so the the dream is that you'll
be able to use this tool to parse any
programming language that you can think
of so now let's talk about how tree
sitter works so when you want to add
support for parsing a new language with
tree sitter as you might expect you have
to write a grammar for the language and
with tree sitter you write the grammar
in a simple JavaScript DSL that I made
and the advantage of this is that
grammars are represented as plain
JavaScript objects and so you can
manipulate them programmatically and you
can you can extend them so it makes it
really intuitive to write a grammar that
is based off of another grammar which I
do in order to define the C++ grammar in
terms of the C grammar and the
typescript grammar in terms of the
JavaScript grammar and then once you've
written your grammar tree sitter will
generate for you
the single C file that as I said has no
dependencies and has two main pieces of
data in it it's has what's called the
the tokenizing function which reads the
the sequence of characters from
beginning to end and groups them into
tokens as well as what's called the
parse table which is this data structure
that tells the parser when it's in a
given state what
to do when it sees a given token and
then you can use these parsers in
combination with this small pure C
library called the tree sitter runtime
which defines a few types that you can
use to parse files and then it gives you
the simple API for dealing with syntax
tree that's it's kind of like the Dom in
JavaScript
this is shows an example of using the
Rossi API but usually we use it through
bindings to either JavaScript or to
Haskell so that's what it looks like to
use the system I'll now talk about some
of the algorithms that it uses
internally so they're mostly based on
some research that was done at UC
Berkeley in the 1990s about IDE s in a
particular this one PhD thesis called
practical algorithms for incremental
software development environments that
outlines if you're building an IDE
what's the best sort of basic parsing
theory to rely on and then how to
augment that theory so that it works
ingor incremental II to handle these
fast edits and then it proves that these
this incremental version has these good
performance properties and so the basic
parsing theory that it uses is LR
parsing which many of you are probably
familiar with but I'll just go over it
quickly here since some of the more
unique parts of trees that are build on
LR parsing so the idea is with an LR
parser we we read the sequence of
characters from beginning to end without
ever backtracking and as we go we group
the characters together into tokens
using the tokenizer function which i
mentioned earlier in the generated code
and then we group those tokens together
into larger and larger sub trees which
we store on a stack and at every step of
the way we decide what to do with the
stack by consulting that parse parse
table which was the second piece of
generated code I showed and so when
parsing a simple math expression like x
times y plus Z it would sort of progress
in this way
we start out with an empty stack and
then we'd push the first three tokens
onto the stack but when we get to the
plus we would do a different type of
action called a reduction where we pop
three nodes off of the stack and group
them into a new parent node called a
product and push that back onto the
stack in their place
and then similarly we'd push the plus
and the Z on to the stack and at the end
of the file we do another reduction
which so we'd pop off the some are sorry
the product the plus and the Z and group
them together into a new parent node and
that would be the final tree so you
might ask like okay one of the stated
goals of tree sitter though is to parse
like every major programming language is
this one this one parsing framework
going to work for all languages and the
answer is no not quite so while most
languages are designed to be fairly easy
to parse using parsers that were
available in you know ten years ago or
longer and LR parsing is actually a very
powerful technique and that can parse up
a much bigger set of grammars grammar
languages often have some weird quirk
that needs to be handled via ad hoc code
and so let me give you an example of one
of those works so here's two JavaScript
statements and the first one we have
assigning to the variable X the value of
the variable Y which we have in
parentheses just because we can and the
second example we're assigning to X this
arrow function that takes a parameter
called Y and returns Z and so the reason
that this is a problem for an LR parser
is that like I said LR parser never
backtracks so before the parser can
process the the right parenthesis it
needs to decide what it should push onto
its stack in order to represent the Y
but it can't know whether the Y is an
expression or not meaning are we
evaluating Y or not until it sees the
arrow token that comes later
and so I'll show you the basic technique
that tree sitter uses to to deal with
this so it's called G LR parsing an idea
is these are some more diagrams with a
parser stack here but they're in a
different format now that that's
generated by tree sitter itself in order
to help you debug the parsing the idea
is though that the the stack can fork
into multiple branches in order to
explore multiple possibilities at the
same time without ever
backtracking and so in this example at
when we get to the right parenthesis
we'd have to fork the par stack and read
in a few more tokens until we see the
arrow at which point we can discard one
of the forks because we can tell that
which which one of the two is valid and
so this is the technique that allows
trees to do to be so general to handle
languages like C++ etc and then another
problem that I wanted to show to you is
how tree sitter deals with errors so
unlike most parsers that are built for
compilers that simply halt when they see
an error report an error message
consider can't do that because it needs
to provide a tree no matter what for use
in application like atom that needs to
be able to provide functionality even if
the users in the middle of typing
something and so in this example code
there's an if statement and then you
started typing a for loop before it and
so what Teresa de would do is produce a
syntax tree in which the if statement is
still fully parsed but there's just an
extra error node that represents the
fact that the word for should not be
there and then similarly if you had a
for loop but you started typing an if
statement in the middle of it
accidentally tree sitter could still
parse the for loop completely and
provide you this error node in the tree
that tells you that the word if
shouldn't be there and the way that it
does this is similar to the way that it
deals with the ambiguities that I
mentioned a second ago so upon seeing an
error tree sitter can can split the
parse tack into multiple branches in
order to simultaneously explore multiple
ways of recovering from the error and
then decide which one is the best
according to this cost metric and so you
can see here these two sequences of what
would happen when parsing these two
erroneous pieces of code that started
out the same oh and and as far as I know
that technique is novel I haven't seen
that in the literature and commercial
parsers but it allows tree sitter to to
produce these very natural seeming
syntax trees even in the case of severe
errors like the ones I showed
and then finally the last algorithm I
wanted to show you is how tree sitter
does the incremental parsing that makes
it performant enough to use in a text
editor so the idea here is say you had
these three statements in JavaScript and
then you edited right there so you
inserted an argument to this function
call the way tree sitter would process
that is it would walk the tree that it
had and any syntax node that contained
the site of your edit it would mark as
having had a character inserted into it
and then it would begin parsing as if it
was going to parse the file from scratch
starting at the beginning with an empty
parse deck but this time since it has
the existing tree as a reference it can
skip a lot of intermediate steps in that
parsing process
so after upon starting it can
immediately push directly onto its stack
the entire variable declaration that was
the first statement in the program and
then it can reuse smaller pieces from
there like this member expression that
proceeded to edit and the left
parenthesis right before the Edit and
then it can parse from scratch for a
tiny little piece where you inserted but
then it can resume reusing more trees so
it can reuse the right parenthesis and
do some more grouping here and then
reuse the whole the whole final
statement of the program and and group
that into a new root node that kind of
shares elements of the old root node and
in that way the the time it takes to do
this is not proportional to the whole
size of the file it's only proportional
to the amount of text that you inserted
and the number of changes that you made
so let's all show you next steps for me
is adding support for more languages so
there's about 10 supported right now out
of the set that Adam supports and I plan
to basically continue adding support for
these new languages until all the
languages that Adam ships with can now
be parsed with tree sitter and at the
same time the github comm team I talked
about is busy developing support for
other languages that they want to
support on github Thanks
[Applause]