the next talk is going to be by Yamada
Spinelli's from essence University of
Economics and business
hello good morning can you hear me yes
okay unixes will be 50 in a couple of
years this is more than most people in
this room a lot has happened through
those years in the 1980s and 1990s can
you hear me now yeah okay
a lot has happened through these years
in 1980s 1990s 2000s in this century
how has the architecture of Unix changed
this is what I will discuss today so I
will describe the ground work about Unix
I will describe the sources I will be
using important architectural milestones
evolution in numbers and evolution in
words I will start from Thompson and
Richey program in the pdp-11 through
teleplay typewriter in the 1970s to
build joy and the group the G team
hacking UNIX on the vats in the 1980s to
the century's modern open-source
communities UNIX was born in the AT&T
Bell Laboratories an amazing place home
to eight Nobel prizes three curing
Awards radio astronomy cosmic radiation
transatlantic cables the transistor the
charge-coupled devices being the cameras
and all our phones the communications
theory lasers solar cells the C C++ and
the oak programming languages fiber
optics and CDMA telephony it started its
life when another project called mop
multics
fire that was going on in the 1960s at
MIT with AT&T Bell Labs and General
Electric fold that didn't go as well as
AT&T expected and so ken Thompson then
is rich in that Makela and Johanna went
off and developed an unnamed system on a
PDP seven months smaller computer based
on their work which looked promising the
created a funding proposal for a word
processing facility of all things
because Bell Labs was typesetting
patents to work on a pdp-11 the history
of what followed
very long and very complex why is this
all important first of all because of
the exemplar design of UNIX its
technical contribution its impact on all
of us all of us have some device owners
probably running some sort of UNIX or a
system developed on its ideas the
development model it used and I will
describe that it's very interesting how
open-source came into that model it was
produced and in the words of that
material it's unusual simplicity power
and elegance as a competition of these
achievements developers received the US
President's Medal regarding technology
what does Unix given us first of all a
hierarchical file system compatible I
offer files for devices for networking
and for inter-process IO the pipes and
filters architecture virtual file
systems the shell as a user selectable
regular process anything that we can
change and use also number of
technologies were associated with UNIX C
and C++ parson lexical analyzer
generators software development
environments document preparation tools
such as tear event its cousins
declarative markup scripting languages
tcp/ip networking all around us again
configuration management systems they
form the UNIX systems form large part of
the modern Internet infrastructure the
world around us the volution I will
describe is based on three sources first
of all the availability of UNIX sources
that goes back to decisions and the
decision by caldera to open or early
sources and based on that material
created a repository that records the
history and evolution of Unix
I did that to record the evolution of
programming style to consolidate
artifacts that were I thought were
important to record his recent history
that is fading away and to provide the
place for any one of us can go there and
look at the history so this is a rough
diagram of what it contains this here
are snapshots of various editions and
this again at some point at Berkeley
they started using the source code
control system so there there was a
version control system code versions are
recorded but
snap shots and goes down through
open-source editions 386bsd
patch kit and then I continued the path
of FreeBSD I could equally well continue
on open BSD or net BSD the source really
goes back to the 1970s here abran did
blame on a fire specific file of the C
library you see there are changes that
happened in 2009 and you see that also
changes that have happened in 1979 by
Dennis Ritchie so on the same repository
if you run git blame on it you'll find
code that spans many decades in numbers
creates more it contains more than
13,000 days of activity about 1,000
people are contributed to it this is a
timeline of the releases so early on
there are only snapshots who don't have
precise changes because people were not
using a version control repository at
that time computers weren't powerful
enough but from one point afterwards we
have each change in each file and we
have specific changes if you look at the
how files come you see here with
different colors how files will
gradually get introduced and then the
contribution is smaller as new editions
are coming in the second source of
things I'm using I want to see the
evolution of facilities and this you
cannot see in the source code so Coyle
is a virtual node part of the system
it's difficult to find that so what I
did is I went through the documentation
created database that records for all
parts of the manual when each part when
each page of the manual at first
appeared and disappeared so you can go
and get up and find a trace of every
system call of every command of a
resistant ministration command of every
library facility and the releases in
which it is documented some parts of
course exist without being documented
and some parts are documented but don't
do exactly work but you can easily get a
rough idea of what happened when and
this is what I used for to discuss the
milestones that we will see today the
third source is a types type set a few
manuals that were amazing such as the
third edition in tear off in and off and
the fourth edition in error officer
could easily go through them
and find important things let's now
begin by describing the architectural
evolution I will describe this in terms
of milestones and also in terms of
numbers and insights and that will begin
with milestones so the things I want you
to get to take away from here is how
evolution happens in practice over a
number of decades this repository is
smaller than 1 gigabyte that contains
all the history of large important part
of Unix
history a project where you can
contribute as well if you want to
enhance that and also architectural
lessons to apply so what happened in the
past is important lessons about what
might happen in the future and good and
bad things we can do regarding
architecture architectural parties joint
work I've performed with Paris have Gary
so starting with milestones we said that
history begins in with an unnamed system
in 1970s and this thing it wasn't even
named Unix at that time contained a
number of very important architectural
facilities it has not survived in
digital form so a group of volunteers
have taken printouts
such as these OCR them type them in and
to verify that it actually worked
made them run on an emulator yeah I
think this deserves an applause
the kernel itself is extremely small
it's just twenty-five hundred lines of
code yet it can load and execute user
level commands it provides a file
abstraction so you can write data into
files named files it visualizes the
hardware interface you don't need to
know a bit about the paper punch the
tape punch or about the teletypewriter
and it establishes an ownership profile
so there are already file owners there's
also layering up in partitioning so
these are the files and you see that
there are different files for the kernel
different files for commands where
commands more than one file is needed
for a command they are grouped with the
same name the commands will call the
kernel the kernel does not depend on the
command so this clear layering here the
commands are not coupled together and I
showed you the partition file naming
convention everything is written
assembly by the way dot s right there is
process management here is the source
code of the fork system call that still
with us today there is the script or
manager so the descriptors that we get
when we open a file and we use when
right reading and writing to files are
there there is an F gets and then I've
put a part entry points where you can
obtain and release descriptors there is
separation of file metadata and file
naming recognize what this is its
definition of an I know the index node
which contains the metadata Flags the
user ID the number of links of the file
the size but not a name so that we can
link files together using a different
mechanism and establish a hierarchical
directories which were not there at the
time by the way devices as files so
there was a system directory what now is
called the dev directory that contains
links to the console the paper tape and
the second terminal that those were the
devices they had a not poor computer
there's also file i/o so they will open
read write see can't tell closed system
calls and the file system abstraction
which where you could create files
rename them link and unlink nowadays we
don't create file we open them with a
create flag flag but this is how it
worked at a time there was an
interpreter there at least two commands
and an indentation command an icon
commanded to convert things to lowercase
were written in a language called B
which was implemented through a threaded
interpreter you see here a main which
later became new B and the main we have
him see after that system the number of
research traditions came out that were
actually UNIX with named UNIX developed
on a PDP 11 the pdp-11 UNIX is a
complete rewrite of the PDP 7 unix so
because the assembly language is
different was written assembly they
rewrote everything from scratch on the
computer such as this this has also not
survived but there was a memo at Bell
Laboratories that contained a listing
again of the source code a bit better
form you see have various things like
the definition of constants link to
panic very important and so on and it
can contain many important architectural
innovations the architecture of the
system I have it in this diagram is
recognizable UNIX so you have user
commands administration commands a small
library a system call interface are your
subsystem process control subsystem and
some utility functions I will come back
to this diagram later on the system
establish a binary API by numbering
system calls so these are the first 10
system calls in the 1972 first edition
of UNIX and I've taken those system
calls again on the FreeBSD 11.1 you see
the same names and even the same numbers
and those of us were also using Linux if
could go and look at the numbering used
for the Linux system calls which are not
derived from the source code we'll see
the same numbers again it's remarkable
that over 50 years this there was a
binary API that has survived those many
years at that point the shell was
established as a user program this is
not something regardless as normal it
was not if you were working on IBM the
shell belonged to the kernel and the
kernel gods only could modify the shell
in UNIX you can see this documented the
password file contains the program to
use as a shell so anybody could go out
innovate and create new versions of the
shell it also abstracted standard i/o so
commands to read from any file and write
to any file not yet pipes and filters
and established interoperability for
documented file format so a section of
the manual documents some file formats
you can see here the documented file
formats and clients of which this file
format I find this very interesting
because it establishes the use of
conventions of a configuration so you
don't have a rigid mechanism of how you
communicate you document the format and
you allow anyone to read and write those
files with a suppose with the
permissions that are needed of course
another very interesting thing is the
section 6 of the manual which contains
user maintained programs some of these
programs such as sort are now with us as
programs that are part of the system can
anyone guess what these programs were
located in the file system yes in the
USSR director exactly user directory we
have is the the user maintained programs
directory and there was even a mechanism
to force their documentation there was a
cron script that was running and for any
command that appeared there in binaries
that didn't have a manual page it was
deleted
this is why we have so good
documentation things migrated from
yourself to other places and they were
documented it also established a tree
directory structure with the system
calls we know and to programs and a
number of programs that use them a
mountable file system interface this
seems like a luxury for a system had one
at most two disks but in the enforcer
single tree naming scheme and does away
the ugliness of drives and devices which
systems I won't name here are using
still to this day we have seen the
diagram of this system you have a manual
page here of the second edition now we
are moving forward if we look at this
the second edition established a
software library more than fourteen of
these subroutines that were there exist
as functions in the modern C library so
this demonstrates the power of well
chosen utility functions in the third
edition the third edition established
the pipes and filters architecture
interestingly as an idea this was put by
Doug McElroy many years before you see
here the date 1964 where he said we need
some way of coupling programs like
garden hoses so that each another signal
becomes another process and we can
message data data in this way this by
way of i/o also so she said that as we
plug garden hoses we should handle IO in
the same way programs at that time could
happily redirect the standard input and
output but only like that at that point
the people behind UNIX the team went and
transformed all programs that took
profile names as arguments into filters
it happened all only over a few months
everything was as many programs as
possible were converted into filters the
fourth research edition so this
coincides with fourth edition of the
manual brought with us a number of
things structured programming so
programs were not written on a lot of
code was not written in assembly
language anymore but into an language
called new
derived from the B language I showed you
earlier on about 6,000 lines were
written that and just 700 lines were
written in pdp-11 assembly the system
became more modular so it had about 105
C functions and 50 assembly symbols
compare that to 250 global symbols in
the first edition by using this language
it became more modular it gave also it
had the language independent API
nowadays we use UNIX system calls from
all different languages this the first
time this happened you see here the pipe
system call which is documented in two
ways as a system call you Cal call from
assembly the read file the script and
register 0 and write file the script and
register 1 and the system call we can
call from C with an array of two
integers we'll get the read and write
write file descriptors it established
data structure definition and the useful
header files up to that point anyone who
wanted to use some structure just copied
that thing into their part of the code
and reuse that form through header files
who have portability we all can change
the definitions and add introduced new
functionality introduced dynamic
resource management so two routines
malloc and M free this hub don't have
anything to do with a malloc and free we
have in the C library and these were
interestingly used for two purposes for
allocating things in the main memory
called memory and also in the swap area
so with two maps with these two routines
could allocate part resources in any two
of the two it was introduced a device
driver abstraction here you see 16
special files not many of those do you
see today but are many interesting one
such as a photo typesetter and the voice
synthesizer for example 1970s and the
device driver interface that is still
with us and is also something common in
Linux and even Windows this idea of a
strategy routine so we have open closed
and the strategy routine and things to
read open and write two routines two
devices introduce the buffer cache to
manage
to catch things from the disk into
memory these are some constants for
buffer for buffer cache elements and the
fount is again still existing with the
same name in FreeBSD 11.1 the fifth
research tradition introduced command
files so the idea that some parts of the
system could be written not in assembly
language or in Ruby or in C but as five
shell scripts so you see here an example
of a shell script that compiles some
data the sixth edition is famous as the
most widely photocopied and underground
transformed system through this
description of the sixth edition by John
Lyons at the University of New South
Wales in Australia it gave us the
portable C library so a different
version of the library aimed at
portability trying to be able to compile
in different systems which as you can
recognize where the names influence the
design of the standard c library that we
have with us today the seventh edition
brought many many important things with
us and was the last edition that came
out of Bell Labs for a long time so
introduces UNIX as a virtual machine one
problem we had is that they were moving
into new hardware and they were find it
difficult to port programs from one hard
word to another so at some point as
Steve Jordan describes dentistry she
came to him and said it might be easier
to port UNIX to a different piece of
hardware than porting each application
from UNIX to a different operating
system so they decided we will use UNIX
as a virtual machine as a way to move
applications from one different thing to
another from one different hardware
platform to another something we
commonly do today in to offer dynamic
memory allocation malloc and free at the
C library this became an instant success
20 C programs use it use it at a time
and to library routines use it as well
as well introduced static analysis so
the famous Lin
tool that searches through not your
pockets for lint but through programs to
find pieces of code that are not exactly
good was introduced as a separate
program because static an
resource heavy it puts a toll on the
compiler so they decided to put it
outside the compiler with the idea of
Unix each tool should do one thing well
introduced environment variables again
here this important part of convention
environment variables will item ASCII
equals value that's just a convention
there is nothing underneath that
requires that to happen
if we don't do it some things will not
work but it's not a requirement and it
was through modifications the kernel the
shell and the C library already at the
sixth edition there was yet a compare
parser generator it was complemented by
a lexical analyzer generator and this
brought the language development tools
it's completed the language development
tools and twelve clients twelve problems
were written using this idea that you
can easily create a small programming
language this evolved into the idea of
domain-specific languages special small
languages that can do one thing very
well do you want to search through the
file system you write a find predicate
you want to search for lines in a file
you write a regular expression you want
to transform a file you want reuse the M
for macro processor and so on and so
forth it also documented the file system
directory hierarchy so there is a manual
page quite long four pages long the
documents where each place is put this
is important for two reasons first of
all that we still follow this secondly
because it described the self-hosted
system so this hierarchy contains the
source code development tools the
libraries the documentation so the idea
that the system is self hosted you take
it and you can build the same system
from source somewhere else there's no
magic thing in the background the temple
where the gods built the system for you
and we utilize this idea day in and day
out today after the sixth edition UNIX
went to Berkeley a group where the
computer science research group got a
copy and started doing research on that
the first and second Berkeley software
distributions weren't complete systems
they introduced software packages so
using the
directory hierarchy and the idea that
you can build a program through a made
file they send out - such as official
the ex editor which later became VI male
Pascal into terminal library 3 bsd
through funding that was given in order
to establish a system that could be used
for running research to be run in
research facility introduced a virtual
memory paging up to now unix could run
on a box but it looked at the box has a
very large address space machine it did
not utilize its virtual memory
facilities it was a big effort 2,800
lines out of 1600 160 line kernel and
also introduced a number of special
system calls we read we write we fork to
take advantage of this this was a
violation of abstraction and you don't
see this calls anymore didn't at least
the two first ones before is discouraged
because it didn't live very long but it
shows how is it is to reel off from the
good way of architecture in for bsd two
important elements were introduced like
regular expressions this we think it's
very important and many scripting
language today live and die by the
regular expressions but it proved to be
a very hard sell at the time there were
five different implementations of
regular expressions but when they were
introduced just a single program more
was using it by 4.3 bsd another two were
using it DB x and artist today with a
lot of effort from the top programs at
grep said an expert al also using it
which shows that when you introduce some
architectural feature late in a system
it is difficult to make it catch and
make it adopted it also introduced
optimized screen handling at the time
there were a variety of termina so you
could use a teletypewriter which was
developed for sending telegrams but also
for hooking on computers to s glassware
t terminal each one had different
peculiarities so a terminal library was
built in order to standardize this we
still use this library so programs that
you are using screen handling program
still use it but
different purpose for backward
compatibility with older systems 4.2 BST
was extremely important because it
brought to us networking so introduced a
number of the internet protocol family
it introduced a socket interface for
local and remote
inter-process communication a number of
databases that were needed to make the
internet work and the pseudo terminal
driver so you can write program
something that looks like a terminal
from a program so that you can write the
terminal emulator and allow one one
piece of software to talk to another
computer as if it is a terminal the
circuit interface is controversial so
you see that it was extremely world it
introduced a number of it was used a
number of system codes all these system
calls and you see that not many of them
are widely used this is how each the
programs that are using these system
calls this shows that just being
throwing architectural elements in a
system isn't always a good idea the
arguments for and against shoehorning
the old system calls are using readwrite
open and closed but maybe this was going
over the top
another interesting version that came
out of Berkeley is that the whole
Edition which supported two CPU
architectures works and the CCI power
632 architectures it was not didn't do
very well in the marketplace but it
allowed the current to be split into a
device dependent part architecture
dependent part and architecture
independent part so this at the whole
code machine dependent code in the box
code this proved to be very useful when
UNIX was later moved into 386bsd the
reno edition introduced the packet
forwarding database that gave the idea
to Rooter vendors that could use the
operating system to write vendors and
the virtual file system interface or the
idea of Vinodh which means that you can
write different file systems to
interface with the system at the
winnowed interface so you don't need
special code above that layer all other
in fraternal infrastructure can hook up
to any different file system through the
winnowed interface
they need to introduce another
interesting facility the fun open you
know it has fun open cookie in lib see
how many of you know it not many you see
this is very interesting it allows you
to create a file abstract a file capital
file thing where you can read and write
and open and close and other nice it can
be something that you program with
something virtual although it's very
interesting because it was introduced
late it is not widely used you can use
it to read from internet things to http
for example also compressed files but it
is not something that's widely used for
point for one of the last editions that
came out of Berkeley introduced
stackable file systems again the idea
that you for example can stack on top of
a cd-rom something that you can write on
top for the Union filesystem and the
generic system control interface for
which you can modify the kernel with
this control will assist control command
function and a documented thing that
nowadays contains more than 3000 values
this is something controversial I think
it's the lives in architectural limbo
it's the interfaces undocumented it
could have been happy if it violates the
idea that everything in UNIX happens
through the filesystem directory
hierarchy and it shows that they're hard
architectural decisions that need to be
made and nobody may know the correct
answer as I said the split into system
dependent system architecture
independent parts allowed a group of
people Bill and Lynn jollies to create
386bsd which allowed system to be used
on very cheap hardware that was widely
available and on that a number of
patches were developed because bill and
Lynn George did not have time to
integrate all those things into the
system and establish the idea of
organized community contributions that
the community can contribute to the
system up to now up to that point people
at Berkeley other bell labs developed
the system but not a community so it
changed UNIX from open-source software
has become open-source at that time
because Berkeley had developed a lot of
code that as government could be openly
available to an open-source project
where people can
in tribute a group of people took that
pond and worked through FreeBSD this a
route that we'll discuss as I said open
based on net BST are also equally
important introduced a package manager
in in FreeBSD that allowed other
packages other compilers utilities and
so on to be introduced and used by the
system through patches in the source
code compilation instructions dilation
and installation and the handling of the
well of the dependencies this allows the
system to grow without burdening the
base system up to that point every new
utility was part of the base system but
nowadays with thousands of ports this
could not continue FreeBSD to introduce
the proc file system to see various
things of regarding a process again
tension here between system calls that
get process information in getting
process information through the file
system hierarchy and dynamically
loadable kernel modules in three FreeBSD
three we have a common access method
subsystem so I think a way to abstract
all the functionality needed to access
five storage devices a kernel networking
in user library net graph that allows us
to build protocols through a data flow
model FreeBSD four introduced and
brought the open SSL Secure Sockets
Layer part which is the idea to bring a
large collection of software this is big
so more than 1,000 files more than two
hundred thousand lines of code with many
lot of functionality in the library
level and the very rich user level
command that allows you to use it in
FreeBSD five you see that the version
numbers are going fast now we have the
modular IO disk request transformation
framework genome that allows you to
visualize and creep the grid add various
levels of functionality to file systems
in 5.3 we have a streaming archive
access library
miniport data driver in seven have the
ZFS file systems in 7.1 dynamic tracing
DDT trace tool kit in eighth packet
capture library was
introduce that allows user level
programs to manipulate packets and in
nine there was InfiniBand high-speed
interconnect library introduced can you
see quick succession of versions and
relatively few major architectural
additions I can discuss this later so
let's move now to our observations not
regarding our milestones but regarding
numbers and insights on the number site
we see a large increase in size from a
few thousand lines to millions of lines
what does has this meant in terms of
modularity we see that the modularity
has increased with code size so that
people tried to keep modularity at a
constant said through the introduction
of static declarations for example for
the use of hash include' directives and
so on at some points complexity rows but
follow the self collecting path so
number of fights with function increased
and then started decreasing the nesting
of statements if else then while and
another if in between increased and then
decreased again the density of C
preprocessor not include directives
which can make the code very difficult
to follow again follows this
self-correcting path even the go-to
function became less and less used there
is a way to count this called cyclomatic
complexity essentially the number of
branches that happen within a function
and they see this decreasing within the
kernel the libraries and the tools found
this remarkable because there is no
dictator there saying you shall decrease
your cyclomatic complexity it happens
through a very rich and varied community
as if an individual force is guiding it
perhaps
Lehman's laws of software evolution how
do facilities grow over that time as I
said that we could trace it by looking
at the manual pages so we see a
continuous growth in the number of
commands three phases in system code so
it seems that every time the system
moves from one place to another from
research labs to Berkeley and then to
open-source it changed the way system
calls will constant or increasing
nowadays the same with a C library so
constant followed by growth
a constant growth from the number of
devices this expected because the
hardware industry is constantly
innovating and giving us new device for
forcing us to buy new devices a stopped
growth in the number of documented file
formats perhaps they are no longer
serving as software's becoming too
complex today to document it through a
file format such as
password or etcetera groups a constant
growth in the number of system commands
so in system administration evolution is
still happening and the growth in the
kernel interfaces so things are
happening behind the scenes regarding
observations on the inside side so can
what can we say when the quality of
these changes not the numbers I see the
following things one very important
thing the importance of conventions of a
rigid rigid enforcement's there are
other systems that force you to go a
specific way they have API strict large
API is Byzantine complexity where you
create very very difficult data
structures to do something in UNIX the
preferred way of working is to establish
and confession and politely ask the
people to follow it we see that in file
and data file naming from the beginning
add one dot s at to dot s the
environment variables the C calling
conventions the idea of prefixing C F
and C functions with an underscore where
files are located continuous evolution
so evolution has stopped it continues to
this day I showed how things were
introduced over the recent versions of
FreeBSD however I have also seen a
slowdown and we've seen it of
architectural evolution so we see that
few major important facilities are added
over time maybe it's difficult to make a
big architectural change when we are
dealing with a system of tens of
millions of lines of code how do you
make an architectural impact or maybe
it's difficult to change a system it's
as if you have a ship a big ship that
you need to turn and it's difficult to
make it turn we see a wide influence of
its internal design so even internal
device designs features that are not
documented can influence and survive
over decades we show that with how
the internal device driver abstractions
have moved and are used even by other
systems the case of character and block
device which the strategy routine which
can be found in Linux there are some
features that can be added and not used
we saw we saw that with regular
expressions file streams the stackable
file systems so architecture is not an
easy task it can be a thankless task as
well we also saw that architectural
features change role over time these are
the bones of a human a dog bird and a
whale so we saw that the cursors library
for example was initially introduced in
order to provide compatibility between
various terminals now we're not using
terminals anymore we're using terminal
emulators and it's used now not for
compatibility purposes but for providing
backwards compatibility with all the
problems that were written for the valid
terminals there's also the idea of our
inadvertent technical depths
architectural decisions that appear
reasonable at a specific time can turn
out to be suboptimal when the socket
interface was established there was the
idea of socket streams and Datagram
abstractions seemed like a good idea at
the time but we know that the Internet
movement specific directions vendor
specific implementations are not used
and now we're using the open Internet
standards rather than the ISO standards
for example the importance of
portability as a shaping force so many
times along its history UNIX was moved
from one architecture to another and so
what then Israel should describe we want
a system that first of all is easily
portable unchanged but can also easy to
change to move it and take advantage of
different hardware architectures and
power of archetypal of hardware this
interests the design of the system the C
programming language and also the whole
architecture of Unix then we saw
competition between alternative
architectural styles so the competition
between system calls such as peat race
guitar usage and get our limit and the
file system interface that provides
similar access facilities we also saw
their preservation of architectural
so I showed you this diagram of the
first edition have a look at it now
squint your eyes and look at the modern
FreeBSD 11.0 architectural form has
remained stable especially in areas
where technologies haven't evolved the
colors you see in this part are still
available in this system everything
that's colored with the same color is
still the same or maybe the initial
architecture was very well thought out
could be a platonic architectural truth
the truth that that system our Dublin
and similar systems have adopted as well
the diagram also point us to the growth
of federated architectures for a number
of architectures now have their own
living their own boxes such as open SSL
yet giome comm net graph you no longer
influence the direction of the whole
system but you built your own Federation
of architectures and finally the idea of
having individuals with imagination with
creativity to come up with powerful
abstractions the taste to select the
most appropriate abstractions and the
energy to implement them this brings me
to the end of the presentation at this
point I wish you to go out and architect
something great thank you very much
[Applause]
you