so unique craft that's a new project
which is covered under well let's say
it's an incubator of resource project
part of the Zen project it also covered
by the Linux Foundation and it's all
about unicorns so let's see if I get you
guys convinced because my aim is to get
as many contributors to this project and
get this thing growing because it's
super nice topic actually so what so
what are they for and what are they
actually I don't know so but I think I'm
pretty sure that you've heard about this
container craze right everybody is
running their services in a container
you hear sentence like Google runs Eric
services container then you have some
day things like Amazon and Google
container engine and Ezer container
services and so forth popping up but why
are containers too popular currently the
thing is that if you if you deploy your
service with a container you get some
some benefits for instance you have a
really small memory footprint for each
of your container for instance the
docker container support which basically
depends upon the
that happen that box it enables you a
higher density like you can run hundreds
of thousands of container instances on
on a single host and if you take this
and look at the ends the ends look just
you know having way fat inflexible right
thousand thousand inches of VMs on a
single horse I don't do that but at the
same time when we talk about container
we need to also be careful about some
certain security risks I'm not saying
that they're there but it's a bit more
risky in terms of development the reason
is actually coming from that all the
containers they share a same kernel and
also the its API and the current API our
system calls and this isolation is
implemented by putting on checks and so
forth into each of the system cost and
you know if you see on my Oh control get
other system cause you can get quite
complex for each of the system core and
also if you recheck the latest mini
releases the system core numbers is
incredibly increasing compared to
hypochlorous numbers
Piper myself so of course I don't need
to tell you if one container uses a
system club which is not been protected
securely and you break out your whole
system is in danger so usually the
trade-off that you have today is kind of
a picking of poison choice right so
either you go for containers you know
that they're lightweight and you have
these super fast popping up services but
kind of maybe not well nice because you
know the isolation might be iffy when
you go to hypervisors of course they
promise you strong isolation because
they can see few features are doing that
but they're pretty heavyweight but now I
hope I can break the move with you that
VM such a heavyweight because we have
this thing like unicron's now so what is
it a unicorn so in the last time you see
a traditional VM right so you run your
service within your virtual machine it
has a general purpose operating system
underneath and some some kind of
features so what is different when we
run ourselves a unicorn so first of all
we're bonded also in the same virtual
machine isolation protection boundary
but instead of using the general-purpose
kernel underneath
we built a purpose-built thin kernel
layer under the application that has
only the features that the application
requires and then you can do even
assumptions like since you run anyway
one application in one machine domain
you could even wake up the isolation
user space and can start even optimizing
the interface between application in the
color because that kernel layers anyway
purpose-built for that application so
benefits you get even further from these
specializations that where you say ok I
have now optimized functions to enter my
car or my driver
so in numbers in this graph you see on
the on the horizontal axis number of
concurrent instances deployed in the
system and on the on the vertical axis
the deployment time and I start here
with comparing the numbers how long it
takes to break up a process and we are
roughly there in a bad part that mean
doesn't take longer than 10 milliseconds
to pop up if you use them doc and put
that process so I forgot to say that
process is doing nothing is like just a
black box his baseline so if you put
that in a docker that boot time
increases and we end up roughly in the
ballpark of 150 milliseconds to 550
milliseconds which is pretty good
because it still at least promise you to
give you more protection than just
running the process blind on your system
if we compare that with Debian boots
some meaning as a representative of
addition yeah that number goes up to the
six seconds in the best case and when
you have one person currently running on
that system going even up to 82 seconds
so here I agree if I see that graph yeah
traditional VMs are very happy wait for
it you know these agile services but if
you take now a unicorn
um this one is
is called mini mess this is part of the
Zen project was more for educational
purposes but if we just take that built
it and also do a no op in there we have
roughly already the same pod then
containers meaning it shows that
unicorns are similar as parcel as
containers so now you may be heard of a
recent publication that we did that we
call like the M so we are actually
tackling into that system then system to
figure out actually where it's all my
time spent when I pop so many BMS and we
figured that most time was lost in the
VM management code so we replaced that
puts put in with the complete own
management and ended up creating VMs
even if you go up now up to a thousand
concurrent instances between 5 4 2 and
8.6 milliseconds it's the same unicorn
as before and as a comparison docker we
run out on the same machine which has
actually 128 gigabytes of ddr3 memory we
run out at $3,000 instances so this
shows that there is immense potential in
unicorns which is not used yet
so the games of unicron's when you run
them in a virtualized environment are
fast intense iation so we know that from
doctor but we found even it can go even
to tens of milliseconds down we have
what's a low memory footprint the we can
achieve really high density as it just
saw on the graph and now the more pluses
come which is due to the specialization
that we can do let's say optimize our
kernel a as tall as the application we
can achieve even higher performance and
we had some unicorns built in the past
one for what was a static HTTP server
that was able to cope almost 40 gigabits
of who would and having said that had
only a single guest simply designed for
this and also the attack surface is
reduced because you have less components
are gonna come right and the unicorn has
also the color layers with it so you
don't have and the other exercises from
isolation that your virtual machine box
gives you so now you may ask me cold
where would I like use it and the thing
is depending on these technology
advantages that the use cases are quite
wide-ranging it kind of you pick pick on
one of the different changes that you so
to give you some examples first few
times with migration times you would
like to have it for reactive vnfs so
meaning you have a DDoS attack in your
telecom operator network and you pop up
on the fly of a blocking firewall in
front
that access and mutators is is gone
lambda functions as well you put them up
for running a single sink the function
and then kill them afterwards you don't
want to have some really heavy weight
that takes forever to come up the other
the other differentiator is the resource
efficiency which comes from this minimal
software stack there you can imagine
also for telcos you could imagine you
could run for each customer that you
serve your internet be enough because
you get run thousands of them one on the
second ports but also resource
efficiency gets quite important when you
go into embedded areas like IOT or you
know mobile edge computing but you don't
have that many resources that we
actually can waste high performance of
course a super hot topic for a network
function virtualization but also mobile
edge computing including other stuffs
too and then mission-critical so as last
said this is quite difficult to to get
your code certified of course we don't
have this development model yet seen a
unicron but at least we can promise that
codebase is small which makes already
all this you know the price for
verification much cheaper then we have
the strong isolation between our systems
because of the hypervisor and this is
really interesting for this decide for
automotive applications or any other
industrial grades between station
solutions so now you say probably cold
but why don't I have a unicorn right
white is not there and the thing is the
devil is in the detail such
optimizations that you saw
of these optimized unicorns for now
manual built and it takes usually months
and even longer to get it really working
that way and the the the biggest issue
is actually that it's kind of a
throwaway you go go through a process a
couple of times again for each of the
different application because you want
to specialize in Colonel Ayres
differently depending on the application
that you want to put in you anyway so in
practice this looks like when you take
for instance nginx and you want to have
a unique are probably starts to run it
on the trailer purposes and see what's
what's there
you'll notice that you know many
libraries many kernel features even are
completely unused and and not necessary
to run your service so what you then
would start is like building a system
just picking these necessary pieces
which is already lots of work especially
maybe when I say to get to get your
unique own but then the second
integration probably will start
replacing let's say some libraries with
different implementation because I
figured out that that application
performs much better than that or maybe
have a more resource constrained API so
you start tweaking and tuning the whole
system until you reach what do you wanna
what a half right and this unique raft
project is actually all about these
steps how can we simplify that how can
we reduce the amount of work that you
have to do
to get your nginx in the unicron box so
when we started with this project we had
we had the following motivation behind
first of all this unique on the build
framework should support everyone's use
case this means that some people are
really concerned about what what does
your network drivers do what sense what
does your cpu kind of kind of they
they're really picky in which way
network packets are scheduled to CPUs to
process we and others take care more
about memory and allocators to get
better performance for different
services so the framework should support
all of that it should for sure simplify
the bending and optimization as I
promised and we want to build this
unicorn framework also to get rid of
this throw away attitude meaning that
hopefully since you heard there's no
more unique current projects are
starting to build their unique health
based on unique craft so that all the
efforts they did to get their
application run is collective thing
based and may be beneficial for other
people and the designer process we have
chosen is everything is a library and
when I say everything is alive we I mean
even decomposed OS functionality like
schedulers memory locators and drivers
they are all libraries and unique crafts
for now consists of two components you
have a lottery pool which I hope we can
together increase it and a build tool
that simplifies in building and
optimizing your so when I talk now of
about operating system decomposition
what's the issue here the thing is that
let's say let's take Linux or the system
I use me monolithic and really tied
together but we actually want is like a
library for each of these components
like alive is just for supporting file
systems because you could imagine you
have unique owners that don't need all
systems at all or you want to have
schedules as a separate life or you know
this and so forth so so the challenge is
here to take some OSS and pick some
pieces out and redevelopment in a way so
that it gets that more self-contained
boxes plucking it out for your Munich
are built
so let's have a look to the light report
that I said as the beauty craft so we
distinguish currently between three
types of lightness first is the main
library pillar which includes OS
functionalities file systems schedulers
and network specs the goal is even you
know even to provide you alternative
implementations like it having links
with tons of different process and
implementations you pick the one that
fits most by use case we want to have
this for schedulers for network stacks
let's say you have the bsd network
supported and depending on the
application one or the other is a better
fit for you then we have the platform
libraries these are actually the
libraries that implements the thinnest
layer daunting a hypervisor we have
support for now for Zen we can run
Akkadian and there is space there's one
target for Linux user space for
debugging and then there are some
architecture lips that some CPU
architectures may require for instance
on arms a bit we had to provide 46 bits
are the arithmetic operations and
software for model or and divisions so
in the easier case now you pick you
select your app then you select in
config the lips with the build tool
which is shown in the next slide and
then the rest should happen magic and
you get here all your unique are images
that are optimized for these various
platforms so for instance would have one
unique Manuka image for kbm it would
have a different image for Zen
different drivers the interface is
different but you can you know you
specialize in present and the other 4km
and so forth so the build tool is for
now accounting based so you know it from
the next gun and has some big fun magic
so you have the same principle as when
you build addition you have a make menu
config then you select your your options
and I wish you want to have the
application you select your target
platforms where you want to have an
image built for it and save your
confidence I make and then that's it so
to make this a bit more clear also with
a bit more closed example let's say we
would build a Python Unicom we would say
we take the Python interpreter and take
that as an as an application you feed
that to the Uni craft system and then we
select like a network stack to get
socket operations you would select a
fitting but a memory allocator console
drive and so forth and you craft this
was in Unicode but another example maybe
some of you heard already about clickers
it is a small vnf unicron where you
actually use the click router software
and you do the same thing you select the
components you need and Unicron fills it
for you so
the unifix any question no the the the
unique craft open source release we
started the progression normal zero to
the codename titan so let me briefly
introduce what we have the the library
pool consists for now really of basic
functionality together thing you know
running and up and for people getting
their hands dirty as possible so it's
not full-fledged now so I expect much
more like this in the future but for
instance we have a memory allocated for
which we have libraries for debugging we
have a scheduler interface there soon
besides the competitive scheduler
there's a lobby coming up for
pre-emptive scheduling cloth homes we
supported Xen KVM and Linux for now and
most of them run on both on x86 and also
so when you build now with unique craft
something let's say a library you will
you will bind it to this core uni crafts
repository which has internal libraries
the main file system and the k-project
system so each library what you need to
do besides having the source code you
need to provide a country that UK which
is actually k conflicts and types to
provide your particular interface and
make file dot uk' which gets sucked in
by the make file system to do this build
for the library we can do at the same
time provide live yours externally by
using external repo the structure is
exactly the
as internal libraries and the system it
allows you that next in line we can
replace an internal library because it's
just a menu item value then select a
different one
and your application in this build
system is also just alignment so the
same thing the only difference is you
have an entry made part here which looks
like when you developed and Linux kernel
module of tree looks like like the same
thing it just you know calls to make
filesystem of unique raft ending of all
the parts of where your sources are and
then that system sucks everything in and
pursued the bigger menu and also mint
state the combination to give you a
based on example what we achieved with
the first build we could do that to this
is a Zen / virtualized guest that
actually just boots it comes down and
shuts down afterwards and print some
debug message messages that were up the
VM image or the VM kernel image actually
because we don't need this causes
nothing there it's just 32.7 kilobytes
of sauce in this pie chart you roughly
see how the space is distributed among
the viruses we had to select most of the
thing go to the platform that way that
implements the interface design
hypervisor and we can boot and print it
and since it's so minimalistic we're
also trying out how much what's the
minimum amount of RAM we need to assign
to get it actually up and even we had to
change
the tool sector in order to get them
because it's limited to four megabytes
four megabytes in size area we could
assign liquid food if 208 kilobytes of
RAM only so now I want you I hope you
are all convinced now so please join us
so the project as I said in the
beginning was accepted as an incubator
project under the Zen community which is
by the way a really great open community
and really supportive and we need you
now for our ambitious goals because that
library pool is so if you are interested
please have a look two hours and pages
for the Uni craft projects or drop us an
email on our mailing list or even join
our IRC channel so that our unit craft
team is shipping present there all the
time to answer some questions and if you
kind of in the mood like yeah I would I
would like but I have no idea what I
could do here we have a huge list of all
the topics even mentioned on InDesign
wiki so just get in touch with us we can
find something that interests you as
well okay then let's show you a small
demo of this hello world
so then
I prove that is real and online and then
we didn't go for our question rod
so this is not my development system as
you see on the bottom of the screen this
is like top but this is the Zen version
of topside lists you the virtual machine
that they're running in the system and
on the bottom you have you know your my
shelf
so as menu context to show you how to
choose between x86 since my platform you
select what you want to have optimized
or we take also one that runs in Linux
user space because then this is the
library tool for now here we can select
unselect or configure
the Alice's some are dependencies
selected by the application already and
also by the platform so for instance a
minimalistic newpsie is required by the
platform so you can't unselected but if
you have full-blown nipsey you can
replace that no deep-seeded whatever you
have a chin-up see new lip see you name
yeah they're all configurable sec ok
then you save your configuration make
you see separately together this looks
like so this is our image then it's
slightly bigger now because it adds some
memory allocator as well so this has
been more important on the slide that I
showed you before to prove you that it
runs I first show you an advance on
Linux in space here we go and now I will
create
so I have some scripts around it will
stick to simply find that with me it's a
sign you know and it's already dead so
meaning it was so quickly up and down
that we didn't see it down there so what
I have added to this example is a busy
loop so that I can prove that it's
actually so now the Unicorn is not going
down anymore it's now based in the CPU
why
just busy looping but at least you see
and now you see so the design rules are
not you know not not prepared for you
know VMs that come and go in two seconds
so now any questions I put you the
sources again for you know but you have
time to write the Dom right then it's
also possible to meet me at the Zen
booth I can show you also another demo
with another Unicom and yeah we can have
a chat so yeah please a person
yes I do what you mean and so then what
that image that we have for now is build
our idea the question was if you use
kayvyun tool to run that unicorn instead
of chemo for KVM the platform lobby that
we have for now suppose only the chemo
version and then can be booted with the
with the direct characters let's say
using a KTM tool makes definite sense I
think it will improve the good times for
KTM as well they I know there is a
project driven by the artist Unicron
guys and IBM guys which is called UK
Liam so they even give one go one step
further and provide a different abstract
type of ice interface but in principle
you can all integrate that into any
product what universe is concerned about
this only that the body needs to be
there
yes yes I know you could even you know
share the hosts tcp/ip stack and give
sockets yeah
any other question
so the question
in the party mode okay so the question
is about how to include when you're
bending you will know something like a
Python language interpreters how to
include like Python live isn't that so
for now my answer would be either you
kind of use an intermediate language of
the Python interpreter
you know if you don't run the
intermediate language in the Union
Colonel you would kind of compile it the
Python compiler and get these objects
files and build that together as as an
image alternatively you can also use the
Python interpreter at the file system
underneath attach disk image and run the
Python code directly interpreters
if
it's actually a good question so
microcurrent is actually so the question
was how is it different from my becomes
take many cars so the question so my
answer is it's it's a different system
design unique remnants are still
monolithic so it's a single kernel image
where you include the features that we
need so you don't you know decompose
into several server processes in the
file system support and so forth into
into other protection domains to keep it
included in the earth
so that was a question
so the question is what are the
ambitious goals and where do I wanna
wanna go so the target is really that
this is kind of built framework for
future Unicode projects meaning I would
like to see you KVM as you mentioned in
the first row also included as a library
there that simplifies you building your
application as a unicorn also I you know
maybe it changes the way in how you do i
UT you could imagine this is a neighbor
for multi-tenant IOT platforms where you
run a hypervisor a resource-constrained
device and then you know you deploy your
iot services as virtual machines and
since the resources are scarce a unique
level would be a fit if you don't want
to settle on so I would really want to
see that project going into several
directions kind of you know multiple use
cases like NF
you name it so it should be should
should be the starting base to simplify
your Unicron project exit yes
so the question is about the license
that we have chosen for Yoona crafts the
Uni craft is a VSD 3 cloth license so I
hope it's good enough for most of the
things so of course what you couldn't do
is now taking something from Linux and
put it in there because you might get
the license conflicts but you could
still take the bsd network second pilot
is Eliza and have something feature-rich
as
and other questions
so the question is about how to you know
select dependencies of how that works in
this build tool so all this dependency
handler is now built into this conflict
of FK parts so and you have your
engine's applications you kind of still
need to do a bit of analyzing stuff to
understand whether what are the
dependencies said that I need and you
would you would write them down as
library dependencies to the prop system
or feature dependencies that you need
let's say you need a socket interface so
the user would need to provide you a
tcp/ip perspective or you need the DFS
so you define I need DFS layer please
give me one and then you select
according arbitrate so that is all
bundled into this contact of you case in
August
yeah
so question is how is this different
from our lands then I can tell you alone
and then is minerals and other language
from how you maybe heard also other
unicorns like Mira OS which is
originally also minimus and you have a
camera environment and the new even by
the develop some divers you know camera
the thing is is not really different
it's like you know you could be on this
unicorns of this project to the thing is
that when these project started there
wasn't a single place where people
contributed and this is kind of you know
the issue that I was mentioning so you
built in unicorn I'll go through all
these optimization steps and so forth
but it's just for this use case right
and it's not going back to to single
places where other people and also a
flying saucer to get the same Iran's
running the unique craft but I wish
thank you very much
you