[Applause]
hello everyone I will be talking about
GStreamer update on what more in the
immediate side so it's really part two
of Tim's talk so Tim I would give you
like a general overhead and as GStreamer
one of the key use cases is people
making physical product TVs and stuff
I'm going to talk a lot about all these
so Who am I
my name is a diva kite I've been working
at kelabra for 11 years and the
gstreamer stack
Pharr stream which is a two-seamer based
framework a series of plugins to do
video calls that we worked on a bunch of
devices that is less exciting now
because everyone is doing the web thing
so I've worked on a variety of
multimedia and restreamer based products
from security cameras to TVs to cars to
all kinds of things so a very very
varied practice in the last study so
what kind of embedded devices use the
streamer so a lot of people have built
them but many many more people use them
and they've never heard that they were
using GStreamer so one of the most
common one our TVs set-top boxes I can i
light some of the probably biggest part
of the biggest gstreamer user on the
planet is Samsung and LG TVs all their
Smart TVs use gstreamer for everything
that's not linear television so any
internet legend they're probably go
through a streamer and a lot of set-top
boxes from the Bing vendors on the top
left you have the Xfinity box from
Comcast
in the u.s. they're kind of the biggest
cable company in the world and they
build their own open source stack for
that set-top box instead of buying a
proprietary one and all the mean media
tasks goes through through gstreamer of
basically anytime you watch TV on a set
in the US on Comcast you're using
gstreamer there's another one that's
kind of cool and the bottom right there
the few guys from you view in their UK
company and they also make a pretty cool
set top box they're involved in their
community so thumbs up to these guys and
they use the streamer also another one
that people might not know is that when
you watch a movie on the plane it's
quite likely to be using the steamer as
the both major vendors use camera on
Linux and one that I think is really
cool is on the space station there's
this a little thing it's a camera drone
and it flies around the space station
and it's been made by the Japanese space
agency JAXA
and it uses gstreamer for video so we
have this rumor in space in the air on
the ground it's everywhere in your car
or so maybe if you have the right car so
now that you know where gstreamer is
used I'll give an overview of some of
the features that are new and that are
related to embedded devices that are
more towards many devices well then give
you more generic ones so one of the big
ones and improved DNA buff support DME
buff
it's a Linux kernel mechanism to share
Hardware friendly buffers that have some
specific layout between different
subsystems of the kernel so without that
you needed either some kind of specific
extensions or to do a memory copy for no
good reason just because the different
Linux subsystems don't really talk to
each other otherwise they're building
silos and that helps you bring the data
between the different silos in a zero
copy way as especially now that we're
doing 4k people talking about 8k you can
tougher to copy all that memory on these
tiny devices than the big ones and so
that's really really important one of
the one of the big improvements this so
Justin ware has supported for a while
but we've been fixing all the little
components because this is really about
sharing data between all the components
so to make it work across the pipeline
we need to actually fix a bunch of
little things everywhere one of the big
improvement this year is that we've
added functionality to the T element the
element is when you have a pipeline you
have something that comes in and you
want to send the same thing to two
different branches and previously this
would almost always cause a copy if
because it prevented both sides from
negotiating the same memory layout now
we've had a very small amount of code
how about the way it's been intended
even though you send the same thing to
two to two places the typical example
would be you're doing a video call you
have a camera and captures you want to
send to the encoder and send it to the
display for preview a very very simple
use case that doesn't work with zero
copy without hacks and now it just works
out of the box that's a really huge
improvement next is my mega slide
about video for Linux a view for Linux
is the Linux kernel API that everyone
knows as the one for webcams but it's
also the API that is recommended for
implementing Hardware encoders and
decoders on Linux we have distress
pretty the most complete support for
this API where as far as I know ffmpeg
just had something merged recently but
as far as I know we're the only ones
that really implement all of the
features different implementations like
the ones in Chrome OS they actually have
one copy of the code for each different
hardware with different quirks we try to
avoid that and we tell the kernel driver
maintainer is to just fix their drivers
and follow the API so that's the big big
thing this year and that is the support
for
across different hardware's and now we
do so if you have a hardware encoder
this is using a bunch of boards at that
upstream support things like this snap
dragon dragon board
410 C but also the upstream
I am xx driver for coda and a bunch of
these other things actually just work
out of the box with GStreamer and the
upstream kernel without needing any
board specific hacks another thing that
we've changed since last year it's a
little thing but it's really improved
the lives of everyone is that we have
stable element names so with the way the
plug-in works is that once you start it
it looks at the hardware that's present
and generates an element for each block
of hardware and previously you would
have a limit be named 0 1 5 25 a bit
anyway that's feels a bit random to the
user now we actually decided the first
one that we find for each one we just
give it the the fixed name so that you
can say well you can say oh I know I
have a h.264 encoder I just do v4l to
h.264 Dec bang it works you don't have
to react it's gonna be called Dec 23 dec
25 and you have no it against that so
means just works with just launched
another big big improvement is that now
we have default to DME buff in the
decoder so that means that if you do
decoder display now it's zero copy by
default on most platforms so that that's
been a user in front otherwise you had
to change properties and twiddle it to
make it work it could work and people
shipped it but it was a lot of work for
nothing now we have all of the clean
negotiation so it should just work I
think it was merged very recently in the
last weeks is the ability to change
resolutions at runtime for the decoder
so previously if your encoded stream
change resolution you have to stop the
entire pipeline stop the decoder
particularly this is really important
for adaptive streaming type things like
dashing HLS because as they adapt the
bitrate they often change resolutions
these are the main ones on the video for
the next time next kms so kms is the
Linux API to display things on the
screen on the desktop we mostly use it
through a Weiland or to a compositor or
through a GL stack but on many embedded
board you just want to show video
fullscreen or show video in a rectangle
and you want it to be as efficient as
possible you want to keep that GPU off
or maybe not touch the GPU at all maybe
you don't have a GPU and so in this case
is you use the kms API directly and just
wear as a plug-in for that and it has
been improved quite a bit of last year
as it was merchants in last year two
years ago anyways and there's been a lot
of and lots people actually using that
one of the big improvement is that now
it proposes Hardware buffers from the
sink so that you can have a software
decoder write to a buffer that can be
directly displayed on the sink this uses
Dom buffers which is like the more basic
ones because we can't negotiate others
yet we added video every support that
means that you can actually say I want
something else than fullscreen it's kind
of a big thing so you can do things like
simple picture-in-picture which are
quite used in embedded boards it now
supports a lot more formats and devices
out of the box
sadly the kms API is not fully generic
across devices so we actually have to we
have a whitelist of device that are
known to work and what what it works so
that is a big one and also a lot less
bugs there's been a lot of lot of bug
fixes there because people actually use
that stuff now that it it's upstream and
that has been a huge improvement now it
just works one sort of time next one is
called open max open max is well try to
be gstreamer designed by a committee of
large corporations sadly none of these
corporations actually use it anymore
except for Android so open max is
as far as we know it's dead upstream the
committee has not met in five or six
years the last there was a draft 1.2
that was rejected by the Cronus senior
board and now it's not going anywhere so
just don't don't use it if you can
sadly we have to because embedded
vendors of proprietary code and there's
openmax plugins and often the only way
to access the hardware so we've been
working on improving support for some of
these the Xilinx one now it's quite good
we have pretty complex for kh2 65 use
cases with a lot of extensions with DNA
buff support and everything so that has
been something that the gear on there
has been working and we have support 40
Sonja - Sonja is an open source open max
implementation that is not as terrible
as the bellagio effects transition but
so what do they do that
I don't know why but someone is actually
adding support for this to gstreamer and
dystonia they've implemented some of the
features of the rejected 1.2 draft that
fix some of the worst problems with
openmax
and we've also added more open max
standard defines a bunch of properties
of the encoders have we had very few
industry we basically only have the
bitrate now a bit more are i've been
implemented I should mention this is all
about open packs il the intermediate
layer there's also openmax al and dl and
no one uses them so dl has never been
implemented the driver layer device
there and the al application layer is
actually from an android but i don't
know if anyone actually uses that so
basically open max now is the android
api and people just write open max
elements that do the very minimum to
work and enter it and that's it don't do
that and there's been a couple more
things on embedded OpenGL support the
big one this year is that we have
support for the Vivante proprietary
driver for imx6 boards that's quite
using automotive this allows them
have higher performance drawing on the
stream thing also as Tim mentioned the
OpenGL API and gstreamer after 10 or 15
years of development it's finally has a
frozen API so you can use it without the
fear that that's going to all be
rewritten next year that's also yes we
can also export DMA buff from the OpenGL
stack to push it into a different
application for example so you can
generate the DNA buff from a texture
inside the gstreamer pipeline and then
push that to it and the next process
something like over DME buff so Tim
mentioned this quickly I'll mention it
too because I think it's really cool
it's a mechanism to split the gstreamer
pipeline into two processes or more so
you can take a sink or bit of pipeline
that acts as a sink that's the end and
put it in a different process and have
it act as if it was a slave of the first
one so you this is really useful because
some proprietary api is for video
decoding this play need to run as root
basically they had it's been done there
basically if they could run make you run
put all their code in the curl I'm sure
they would but so they're there like
this is just a hardware with all of ours
so we don't care about security so some
people have care a bit more especially
now that you have internet video and so
you can have the part that does all the
networking and separate it from the part
that does the video decoding that
touches the hardware it's kind of mean
it's very easy to use some little thing
something I discovered this week when I
was reading the get lost preparing this
this talk is that the RTP issues
Explorer interface decoders can now take
the memory from the downstream elements
the next time at the pipeline and write
directly in it this means that if you
have a hardware decoder that needs
linear memory or some kind of
see ma are something special you can
have it allocate memory and just the DP
loader will just write directly in it
and RTSP source panel uses the regular
debugging system so in the near future
we have the RM modifiers are coming this
is another thing for zero copy is to use
memory that is like tiled or really
compressed so that doesn't know anything
about but we can atleast connected
between decoders and think I have an
intern working on testing GStreamer on
embedded boards automatically right now
our CI is only on PC we'd like to have
it working embedded and maybe before us
to stateless codecs any questions yes
others plans to improve balancing for
example to support multi-channel formats
yeah I think Nicola right behind you can
answer he's working on that so to
support actually multi planners support
in Whelan think we needed actually a
Whelan compositor that supports it which
was in the case and we just started
recently with that bit of a hack in
Weston but it kind of works we started
testing it and it does and it actually
does support multi FD if you have DMA
buffs or multi allocations so it's
already in place and it should it should
already be working in 112 if it if not
it's working in get master but we're
actively working on that any other
question in the back I thanks for your
talk and you mentioned openmax is dead
and I'm just curious what we but we a
replacement to focus on so it depends
what to use openmax for there's kind of
two things of man there's openmax as a
pipeline API and that's gstreamer and
but no one actually uses openmax like
that as a codec as an API for stateless
codecs that have a large u space
component and right now I've Hotel
there's no good answer
if wim the original architect of G
streamers is or constantly called pipe
wire and under there he has a plug-in
API and I hope that can be a replacement
but right now
software for your for your your your
codec if you need some userspace code
basically I would recommend either to
write the most simple API you can and
then be forced to wrap it in the
different things like gstreamer ffmpeg
yeah that's why I don't have a good
answer sorry
any other question
but openmax makes everyone's life
painful so please don't do that yes the
Raspberry Pi household they're basically
the hardware API is an IPC to a
different device that is almost I want
to want to open eyes so GST omx was
actually written for us repair time
all right any other question yeah yep
web RTC on embedded devices you
mentioned that there was some yes
just I haven't actually tried the new
web RTC bin but I suppose it works one
of us question know what thank you
thank you