[Applause]
hi thank you I'm very pleased to talk
today so in such a great room
there is so many people waiting outside
it's really honor thank you for to
Francis for making this possible today I
will talk about a project I really like
and I think that can change the way we
use the Internet
before that just a quick word of
introduction about myself so my name is
ville de cheveux I'm working in in Paris
for for a big French website Hong Kong
well we are doing good there but we're
not this talk is really not about about
what I'm doing there
so yeah just a quick overview of what we
will talk about so the the project I'll
talk to you about is up spin first of
all why talking about spin why does spin
exist right now then we'll have an
overview of how it's working and and
then we'll do we'll see what we can do
in practice with it just as a regular
user or as a good developer and and then
we will have a quick own conclusion so
why up spin so up spin is the new
project from Rudd pike
I guess most of you know who robbed my
kids but maybe not all of you is the is
the husband of a French the the creator
of the gofer so so last year there was
two passed about about ABS pin the first
one was on published on the Google
security blog last February introducing
the concept and and then in last October
there was the original manifesto that
Rob Pike wrote eight years ago
and that where I heard about it and
that's where I I found in love with that
with that project so the reason behind
up-spin really is the the information
side of architecture that we've fallen
into slowly the the promise of of the
modern world of the mode of the modern
web was remix ability and creativity but
actually we have been we have been moved
into you into databases that we cannot
access and that we cannot control we
have become dependent on the app and the
apps of the storage providers that that
we use and we are really dependent on
what these people are willing to to
offer us I think we have we have lost
quite a lot along the way just to quote
a few a few ones I think we should be
able to to use our data with any apps
that that we want especially the one
that we developed for example and I
think it should be very simple to share
any kind of data with with anybody we
want it's it's it's funny for me to
think that it's not easy like to just
create a public website just from a note
that you have on Evernote or anywhere
and from a couple of Google photos or
something like that I think it should be
it should be trivial another another
program is that is the the the actual
apps developing developing something
like google photo is really is very
something complicated and and yet every
new storage provider is trying to to
read you the the same photo viewer the
ins kind of thing and I expect them to
fail because they don't have the the
years of development of Google photo for
example
storage and application should be two
different businesses and we should keep
them separated so the model that up-spin
is is pushing is a model with data at
its core and and the apps are just
coming next the apps are just like
regular user playing with with data
reading and writing to it it's by no
means a new approach
it's exactly what local file system is
but it's something that we've never
truly had in remote systems and it's
something that we are being there is
being taken away for example on the
mobile devices so the two basics that
app spin is offering is a universal
naming and an access right so every file
as a global as a global identifier that
you don't need to to worry about sharing
with with other people so it starts with
you with the the mail of the of the
person that owns that file and then then
it's just a regular unix-like path and
and the the access control about it is
really something is is another thing
that comes with with I've spin and that
you should consider salt and stop
wandering the mouth so let's let's have
an overview of how it's actually what
works the most important thing about app
spin is actually the the protocol and as
you would expect coming from Rob Pike
it's very simple so it's just three
interfaces for for a total of eleven
methods and that's really all you need
to to know for building any system that
works with the rest of the of the up
spin world
you know there isn't still that yeah
there is a need for a for a for a proof
of concept for a reference
implementation and that's exactly what
the up-spin team has been has been doing
doing for the past for the past years so
there is a reference implementation for
all the clients and servers and also
there is a collection of tools that that
adds some sand functionalities some of
the basic functionalities to up spin so
up spin is built is really built around
go and the best reference is actually
the go code and for the for the
definition of the protocols it's
basically the the interfaces from the
app spin protocol so so very quickly so
the key server is just it's just looking
up and I'm dating a user information and
the store server is basically the same
thing but with with data the the dear
directory server is a bit more
complicated that I won't go through all
them but it's basically that's where the
that's where the solving of the name is
of the global name is is done and and
then you have some yeah other other
other function but so for example yeah
if you need to if you need to develop
well basically for the for the global
use you don't really need to really know
how it's happening behind what is it
happening behind but for example you if
you if you are making a server from
scratch then you will really need to
know how how it works behind but so
let's let's quickly see how how we can
get a file for example so the first step
is is with the the key server so you do
a leak look up folder for the user and
what you get in exchange is
the user public key and the directory
server address then so that folder for
the user part then the next part will be
the lookup of the file so then at that
point either previous the previous key
server is just one one key server for
the whole up-spin so that's unknown
known address key that up spin that IO
but then here here you are contacting
the directory server of the user the the
one the information that you had just
previously looking at looking up a file
would give you back his name is metadata
and references and stores server
addresses that's actually where the
first access control is is checked the
directory server at least in the
reference implementation will check that
you have rights to ask for the photo
store references and then you can just
get the reference so most of the time in
just it's just a hash or hash and and
and then the store will just give you
back bytes
most of the time this bytes will be
encrypted so you need to so on you need
to have the the key and you'll have the
key only if you can access this file
Yuja another example for example listing
a directory this is an operation that
you do only with the directory server
and thought and then it will return the
list of names and metadata and reference
to store just just as before what you
need to know is how to control the - the
sharing
so I've spin defines an Access file when
you place this file in in a directory
then
this access rights will apply to all the
fighters of that directory and also of
those files in the sub directory if
knows our access file is uncontrolled
this this access value store in the
directory server and is heavily used by
the directory server to to weasel the
information if the user that is
requesting the file don't have the right
and and then the the access control
father at the at the store level is done
through keys basically you create you
create a version of the secret key /
user that is there is supposed to to
access the file so just a note it's not
it's not a network protocol some
misunderstanding about I've spent some
time is that it provides a special way
to share your data from your from your
computer or this kind of thing like ipfs
would do for example but this is just
this is just a protocol it doesn't
define how your server should be
accessible so you need to have a you
need to have a public server and HTTPS
is mandate mandatory yes so let's see
how how you can use it as a user so so
there are two steps in the setup first
first one is is signing up the user so
it's basically creating your key pair
and verifying your email all of it is
just putting a new user into the key
server and then you need to deploy your
server so it's installing the directory
install servers on your hosts and make
them accessible to you to the Internet
and the best way to do to do is to use
app spinner UI
so you can download it from the official
website or just install it with go get
if you have a special system so the
first time you open it you will you will
have the the sign up without it so it's
very nice you can just type in your
email and stuff well then it creates
your key your keys and in send you just
one email that's the only time they will
use the email for for just verifying
that you own the email at that point the
second step is a bit more complicated
but there are some there is some some
nice without - to do it so in the future
well Epstein is very early stage so
right now this is this is quite it's not
very simple especially for wide audience
but in the future its most its most
likely there will be some some server
providers and there is already one that
is building it's called a jungle it
should be it should be live soon and
today you can you can just deploy your
server into one of your servers
or you can also use the Google cloud
platform it's really everything is done
from up spin UI and it's all deployed
automatically also you can just use up
spin as a read-only mode so at the end
of the setup this is what what happens
to your PC so you have you have this
configuration file that is created so it
just it's just the configuration of what
user you're using and what are your dear
install servers and and also in your in
your data SSH folder you will have the
the elective curves keys that are
created
so all these files will be used by by
your apps pin clients running locally
you have just a word about the the keys
the tantras kissa kissa ever
the logs are public so here are what you
can see on the on the on the website so
this is the first sign up you can notice
the new directories and store servers
and this is the second logs with with
the actual with the actual server that I
created so now just some of the tool
that you can use straight away the most
common is the apps pin FS so it just you
can just install it as as the all the
other tools and it just amounts a folder
on your machine so from this you can you
can access your own your own files but
you can also access anybody's file for
example road bikes says is easy months
is light from an iTunes library with up
spin FS and the goal is to mount your
old whole home server directory well
then these two other tools are useful
the you can install them the same app
spin UI is the you web file explorer and
app spin is just the general
command-line interface with a lot of
commands some some unofficial tools for
now there is really not a lot so when I
expect more coming in the future so for
example you have a browser and this is a
music player I I've done entire that I'm
using actually dating
so how does it play as a as a developer
so let's let's build a client app so a
client app is is an app that access data
through web spin it uses the client
interface that the the official that the
official library is using it gives you a
lot of helper functions basically can do
everything about reading listing and
writing data so it so it reads the the
conf and key file that that we've
created before and any you can it's it's
a the part of your app that will access
app spin so for example here are some
IDs for for clients may be something
that synchronizes the photos that you
have on your on your phone this one will
be right on the into your apps pin data
maybe you photo galleries you to to see
your files a sharing organizer and
conversing and maybe your photo editor
to do some little tweaks on your photos
so you know the the different steps that
you need for for creating it it's
actually very simple so for example if
you want to make an application that
just reads into apps pin and just serve
it into through HTTP then you just need
to to initialize your configuration then
create your clients and then in your
handle thank you we'll just we just open
the file and copy it straight away so
it's it's yeah it's it's very simple so
the best the best way for initializing
the configuration is to is to load it
forward from a file so just the same
file as the one I showed you before and
then the client just takes the
configuration file that was actually the
the the hardest part of the
of the code the rest is very simple so
this is just a classic HTTP handler and
the only thing is that you can you can
see the client that open and then the
rest is just known yeah of course there
should be probably some some more some
better error handling to know if the
because here it's just not found better
maybe that information is withheld or
maybe maybe it's a network error so yeah
listen and serve answer
so just with that part of code it
compiles everything and everything and
then you can just try out some of the
files that are accessible and yeah
straight away it will work with any of
the of the apps bin files that that you
can access so it's a very easy way to to
make application that that can play with
data and and yeah from from now on you
can you can already there is a lot of
other thing that you can do with it like
list all audio files maybe filter some
of the files runs code on the fly and
this kind of thing the other thing that
you can build our the server and storage
so a server app is something that
implements the directory install service
of the up spin protocol and that's all
the rest is the rest is you are just
free to do whatever whatever back end
you want so you can check the the access
control if you like and and then any
data source of your of your choice it
can be just a link to another app spin
server or maybe it can be the github API
for serving Geeta Geeta
issues all these kind of thing the
storage is also something that is that
is very well the the store the the
server is how to implement actually but
a storage is something quite easy to you
to do it just the low level
implementation of how to store reference
data so there is already a lot of
implementation with s3 Google Drive GCP
and scanner same if you want some
example of this kind of implementation
the best is to go to the official repos
so for example in the experimental repos
you have an issue server now you can see
the Dropbox storage for example so as a
conclusion never before we heard so much
of our life on digital support and I
think there are more and more projects
that want to use sensitive data for
example medical data I think we really
need to get back the the control on who
access our data and we should stop
trading privacy for for usage another
thing you know I wouldn't I wanted to
say is that the yet the computer world
has assumed that the wide audience is
just getting number and file system have
been hidden from from the mobile devices
and connecting and and the data and
services are just hidden behind limited
apps that are really focused on
consumption I think we should give back
complexity to the to the wide audience
because sharing while accessing files
and sharing data and this kind of thing
are not complex complex operation and I
believe everybody should be able to to
deploy their own way
right for example and and yeah I want to
I wanted to give great UX to everybody
and and I think the key point here is
collaboration doing always doing this
during the the service together and I
think I've spin can be a centralized way
to to have all our all our applications
using the same the same storage and
we'll just be compatible between each
other so if I think for example a photo
viewer of your application can be can be
really general and we don't care about
how the data is thought behind it just
need to use app spin and then we can
walk together I believe so yeah that's
all for for me share some questions
[Applause]
no I didn't hear about about Hinault
said the the project I realized before
that was cozy cloud which also had like
data as a center oh sorry
so the question was there are some other
there are some other projects too that
wants to do the same thing such as and
hosted right well that's a big
description in the in the spin community
there are there are some issues on get
about this the DF spinner team is always
answering that the the combination of
universal security and shareable aspects
of a spin are kind of UNIX where I what
I like is the is the ambition of app
spin and also the simplicity of the
interface
yeah I think the the the most important
thing is to to have some storage
provider while some some ups pin
provider that can create you service for
people that knows about IT or even
people none none none IT people too
and yeah I don't know how to have some
some some nice apps and so I think I
think an easy maybe a transition would
be to to to create some some up-spin
servers that can just plug on on through
already existing systems such as
Facebook or Google photos of this kind
of thing and yeah if it can be
transparent and if you can just access
your Google photos or your Facebook
feeds through web spin without having to
deploy your own server than this kind of
thing then it maybe it can be like the
killer feature that would that would
spark the widespread adoption or
something like that but uh already I'm
I'm just using it for myself right now
and it's already quite nice yeah
having every everybody here will be even
better on fashion yes
now giving permission is only for the
for the owner of the directory and then
you can choose what kind of permission
you want to give just like read list all
right but you cannot you cannot only the
owner of the directory can modify the
access yeah exactly
yeah thank you
[Applause]