yes oh yeah my name is Susanna
yeah I'm Stefan and we're working at
automotive supplier company which has
been doing a software for Marta for some
time as you can see some major brands
yeah and we are working in one domain
we're having different domains like
navigation and so on but I won't talk
about this right now we have got into
the main which deals with electronic
control units and electronic control
units who concede one on the right-hand
side it's rain and light sensor so very
simple device to control you windshield
wiper services rain so these are very
very tiny devices I mean in the past so
it's for example if we talk about basic
software runnings there which we develop
processes about one hundred and fifty
five hundred thousand lines of code and
we have roughly been developing this for
ten years now is about fifty developer
so this is if you talk about the codes
it runs on three why's this is about
three hundred lines of code per
developer so very small we know every
bit and we're doing updates only in the
garage so but let's get to the next
slide Sarah is some rules we have to
stick so in this domain like spies mezra
which is the sea routes and ISO 26262
it's about functional safety a very hot
topic at the moment and currently if you
look at cars that are here in the field
nowadays say if large networks of maybe
a sixty plus electronic control units
for motor control for braking for power
steering and so but we still are are in
this domain where we know each bit and
each line of code and there's no unused
code and for example our operating
system is highly configurable and it
will generate code which is optimized
according to the configuration yeah and
and one key thing here is that when you
have all these systems in a car then you
have suppliers working together and all
the standards had been invented because
people thought this is how we need to
organize the collaboration of a lot of
people and yeah so yeah those are big
questions how does this turbine this
electronic control unit Amane go
together with the open source so and
open source got into it many of you will
know that because I mean first people
used open source tools like Perl or like
Python and make to to generate code and
so on the code generation side they
started doing open source and then they
realized oh there are core libraries
that we could use inside the car and
then the fun begin okay I've already
mentioned Misbah misra is a guideline
for c programming and sorrell a few odds
and ends to it like for example there's
one rule which means basic view you must
not use go to on the right-hand side you
can see this is the one function from
some external and we also go to us out
there and another of my very favorite
favorite rules from this race
you must not use pointer arithmetic
that's the only valid form is array
indexing and of course if you look at
the Linux kernels and you're totally out
and the problem in this domain is
there's a house don't believe that you
must not have misra violations missile
violations feed it equally as a buck so
if you look at justice functions so this
is according to the point of view of the
automotive domain this is really tacky
software and once upon a time an
organization but was interested in using
some Linux car let's say have applied
this tool a checker to the Linux kernel
and you must note this miss what
checkers are really expensive stuff so
you've got five to cheat use for any
license for this tool as I saw oh yeah
let's applies when of constantly got
millions of parks such as I found as I
thought well we've got this
community and we are doing some a big
favor we have this red heart here with
all these boxes millions of facts we
give it to them so it will certainly
start fixing right away you can't
imagine what happens okay
another thing is if you're talking about
the automotive domain we are talking
about spies and about processes on the
right hand side you can see once in
service always together with spice up to
we model if you look at the left hand
side of soui model this very much looks
like a waterfall model and you need to
do all of the stuff at the top down to
the bottom before you can even start
with the implementation so once again a
big question doesn't work for open
source projects we have got the code
first yeah okay
finally there's also legal aspects
involved and I just thought was another
funny story and maybe some of you
elements of you or still remember SEO
versus Unix so back in the days has made
quite some waves and it even hits legal
departments of automotive suppliers say
heard about this and open-source
software our lawsuits going on and I was
falling for the one wheel from a legal
department back in 2005 or 2006 I don't
remember exactly and it stated pretty
much you must not use any open-source
software in all of your project you must
cease to use that immediately until
there is clearance possible from the
board of directors
yeah and that was also in the in all
departments also in the tooling anywhere
so but times have changed so anyhow
what's also a thing is that and that is
actually that is actually something that
we need to represent and source
community on is it so GPL 3 has these
antique Association clauses where they
say okay we want to be able to if you
buy a device in this open source
software free software in there you
should have to freedom to modify the
device so now I buy a car and then up I
in that card as a steering control
do I want every mechanic to be able to
modify this year in control not sure you
know because then the car manufacturer
can blame the mechanic and can say
anybody could have modified your car we
don't know we're out of the game so for
liability reasons you need to have
secure boot on such things and that is a
that is an area of tangent I don't have
a solution but there's a problem
and then also inside the company you
know you go they come from patterns and
they come from the intellectual property
world and you go out there and you say
folks we need a community license
agreement to be signed and we have our
we need to have clearance for our
engineers to just contribute we can't
have every single part reviewed so this
is painful inside the companies but it's
making slow progress and then your few
also have to follow the rules and make
the proper attribution for licenses in
so when you when you own your car that
you click in there and that you realize
oh in the engine there is some PSD
software and these are the authors but
anyhow this exclamation mark is
important we want to have open source
software more in the cars not just only
in in the middle console in the human in
the in the unit in the head unit but
also in in the deeper systems and why is
that well cos shall not kill people okay
and so there is actually in the in the
automotive industry there's this effort
of getting to getting to zero death so
this is a poster from Africa and they
have posters all over all over the world
like South America North America Asia
Europe different problems but the tenor
is with intelligent cars we can we can
solve this and we can solve this
hopefully and and so the cars
transforming into being like a mobile on
wheels and a smartphone on wheels
actually and
you expect it to be like that you expect
it to be current up-to-date the software
and how do you get that going and so the
open source community actually has a lot
of experience with that you know so like
getting security updates out Debian does
it
openSUSE fedora and and all the
enterprise linux distributions so they
get that the time from we identify a
buckin open-source community we get it
to the people doing the base operating
system we gave it to those integrating
it with functions we get it signed off
with the vendor and we get it out you
know they get that done within something
like two three five weeks then the
automotive industry goes like well a
software update we do it every half a
year at Mouse and and there are reasons
for that like the winter drive and
homologation so in the project that we
are currently working on we have to have
things ready before winter because then
they are built into a car and driven
around all over all over Finland in at
minus 30 or minus 40 centigrades
to show that the software works so we
also have these processes like spice
right where we said we have this
waterfall model and then there is the
O's idle where automotive founders try
to get the kernel approved for safety
functions in the car and the idea is you
look at you look at the kernel process
the kernel development process and you
realize every each of these things is
actually done in a current community
it's just a chronologic the chronology
they don't start with a design they
start with what do we need and then they
dig into implementation in rough
sketches and napkins and let's discuss
this and Trust for us back and then at
the end when you look at patch series
everything is in there and the patch
here is there's why do you want to do it
which systems are touched how do they
interact and then everything is
formally specified in the ISO defined C
specification language I love it so and
then in the cars we learn in the cars
what's also happening is that they move
together all the all the semi smart
control units they smooth they move
together all the intelligence into very
few central ones only the airbags and
such really live critical things they
remain self-contained and interconnected
in own Network an old-west actually
moves the intelligence into a central
computers and the sensors and the
actuators remain become less smart and
cheaper because I mean you buy them a
car some million times or sell it so if
if all these yellow ones become cheaper
than the whole car becomes cheaper and
that means that you need to create
virtual ECU's inside inside the inside
the complex one so you have these
systems on a chip this I mean you know
the socks and when you consolidate
safety-related stuff and classic the the
automotive operating system and then
Linux systems with an open source
hypervisor and well I didn't know before
I joined them so I worked with when a
company for years and then I joined the
automotive industry something like three
quarters of a year ago what I didn't
realize before was that companies like
Continental they buy more chips than
anybody else and and and build it into
something so getting open source this is
for example this is a also for most Adel
how do we get safety into Linux
functional safety into Linux make life's
depend on Linux and doing this is a
struggle at all ends but it's fun so
thank you thanks for attention do you
have questions yes oh well
so electro vit is is actually member of
yeah so the question was if an electro
that wants to join good question so the
question is if it like you would join a
GL and start to contribute code so are
all Continental so actually continental
any electro bit are members of HCl and
members of Jenny V and Selena's
foundation Linux Foundation as well the
Lewis foundation and when it comes to
contributing code we have one first
patch upstream in the kernel with an
electrode with email address five five
so it's slow and as I said I I'm n
shinned the legal part it's we we need
brains inside the company who help us
propagate the idea and we're working on
it
thank you there's a thumbs up for the
guy who asked a question yeah keep it
three and this is so the question was
GPL free only forces you to provide the
source but not to modify be able to
modify GPL three has an anti D ization
class which requires you to be able to
deploy your new software into the device
that you bought
yeah that I can do it yeah I get this
that's a that's a problem so thank you
very much time is out yeah bye
[Applause]