hi speaking Italian don't like panic on
pizza just to be sure okay let's start
there is the Dodge Fox of fire dodge
started in a serious talk just to start
with the good mood because is one of the
most famous things when there was
released by post one too many people
want to keep to use this icon there are
two wallpaper like this case so you can
find on the internet if you want
so next start fixing what Alex said
about me I want to do a little bit in
the production just to say that I am a
developer like probably many of in this
room so I don't know many people there
was the last year about following not
distort but similar about webOS nation
how many there was the last year but
once you tree okay so how many have
their JavaScript developers oh okay big
alpha dorm so when you come back at all
after the first M you can develop on
station without issue and now we
discover why it's so easy John back to
me
I am evolved in different offices
project and the from the fun part that
have my first extension let's a
development was for the WordPress
community to add them to improve the
translation process in the website so it
started with something that I was
needing another community with another
community so extension lets you to
improve the user experience also of
websites that are not yours
so I think that as Firefox user probably
there in this room I don't know and I
want to know but as browser users this
problem is true we know that in the case
of Firefox Firefox is famous for the
extensions and in the long life of
Firefox there was a lot of extensions
like in this example Firebug I think
that all the JavaScript developer use at
once at least because there wasn't
initially these kind of tools
the answer was running after Internet
Explorer 6 so was something oh my god
yes but now we have perfect developer
tools in turbidity the browser but then
we are about secession manager
integrated the browser - we have the
top-grossing
something cooler there in this that
period but one of the most interesting
things is the spy lot I don't know many
people know about Firefox the spy lot
but is very important why because in
Mozilla they add on ecosystem is very
important because Mozilla itself use the
technology to improve our user
experience so it's not so on the develop
an API and don't use it no they use it
so they improve it because they need it
so for a developer means that we are
using something that works and any
something partner for a developer
because we are we have we don't have
time to waste in something so that even
this point of view we know that what
Zilla use there dunce api to release in
fact of system add-ons like description
tool that started as firefox test pilot
and if you want to see other experiment
go to the website and install on your
firefox new experiments and one of the
most important things now that you can
also develop developer tools for firefox
that use the same API in the of chrome
for the chrome developer tools and you
can extend answer developer tools this
is something for a developer amazing
because developer usually there'll of
tools to develop better so it's like an
exception but is very important for us
another point that we are to enforce the
fact that in mozilla advanced a very
important is the marketplace as
developer we know that this important
web users to see if our work is good or
not in mozilla the code name is emma
that is not hammer in italian is the
word for law but we are is adorned
marketplace just to be sure and these
are official statistics about the last
year of the project so let's start with
few numbers we have that half of the
Firefox user at least has an add-ons so
means that we have probably a
marketplace with a lot of users
next point actually in the camel we have
26,000 adults and I can say again a lot
of adults and we have also a lot of
developers 9000 developers but another
point is very important is the 12
million monthly users on Elmo let's
again it's very more a lot I don't know
it but a lot a lot and this means that
when we are working releasing an
extension we can reach a huge number of
users but be customers because there are
a lot of services that do extensions too
so with these facts we can think that
right now that what we are doing
probably someone will use it so these
are example of my most famous escapes um
so it's always better to start with real
cases is a social share extension that
implement the tissue removal with
Firefox 57 as you can see there this is
I release this tension in September now
as these users and I am NOT a beast I
don't have a business
so I only uploaded on em oh I don't know
many people cannot understand why there
is this huge peak in the statistics yes
exactly in 14 of November there was the
release of Firefox 57 and there is a new
tool about 57 tests suggest to user to
try a dot so a lot of new users in one
day but that's in the next week and it
is funny and so this part because many
people don't understand why every week
there is peak and off-peak another peak
along peak because usually people on the
weekend that don't use Firefox because
maybe they have to work or they have a
family so they don't use the computer
then not all of the people is an air
that work and all the week so we have
that Firefox to know how many users as
an extension they resent the pinger too
heimo to say whether these are user as
this extension at especial there are new
versions so in that way mozilla track in
anonymous way of course the downloads
and these are the statistics inside
inside the hammer porta income these not
exist so but I'm gonna say that because
I want zillions Excel but these two
doesn't exist they also the interface is
the most horrible things that you can
see in the web is the chrome marketplace
in the backend is the most horrible
things that you can see now but is true
it's not me you is a issue then exploit
is that last year I started with these
quote in another way I say Firefox today
is the most customizable browser that's
exists but after the release of Firefox
57 I don't know many people saw or read
it blog post Twitter many people was not
happy about the application of many
things so many people will say I cannot
use my love Alice tension that I'm using
science forever because it's not the
relevant anymore or this API is not
supported so many people was good
getting back to a previous release
complaining somewhere so the question
now is for users as a sphere users fight
for Steve to be the most customizable
browser actually yes and now we will see
why
ok we need to start about thinking that
sulig sitcom our diet this the old
technology doesn't exist anymore for
developers that was boring complicated
difficult to understand now we have the
new technology that is as a parody with
chrome despite a big patch we finally
with opera of course different relevant
Asia because Firefox is most
customizable we have out to the multi
process of part on windows been a
different process working progress also
feel for the operative systems we have
the support on package for Android
Firefox for Android is the only browser
on mobile the support extension so you
can have a block origin as an example on
your Firefox so today we have this and
this is an extend screenshot of indian
documentation about all the hapy i there
are now available a lot of things and it
is not enough because i want to show you
the most cool API that we have right now
container started as firefox test pilot
project now is integrated in your
browser
what is the container api is something
pretty is useful to shower session
between a group of tubs in few words and
you have an api to integrate it in your
extensions next we have the paycheck
show I want to show a button in the
address bar that you can develop when to
show and the open a model I want to show
you an example again this is my
socialist engine pretty simple is Anna
frame we do something and you can use
all the JavaScript API and a bright as
you prefer
we have also one of the most Oscar
things and the Internet's I can do an
extension that communicate another
distinction yes you can do it there is
an API that enabled
then we have also the way to change the
new tab on page with something else the
difference is this cases on Chrome that
is different because reporters of bucum
are industry but in Firefox doesn't
exist a page for that so it's not
supported
we have another way to use for house
authentication from Firefox so we don't
need to use a library because it's as an
example this amazing extension that led
little you to access real time to
notification on github automatically do
the authentication with Firefox so for a
developer is very easy to do
authentication this one is the most most
interesting things because you can have
a binary on the computer that
communicate with your browser in a
privacy way we can say that is a JSON
the application is a binary on your
computer and we have the web browser
that communicate in that way these are
an example all part of us understand
what is the the binary what extension
can access and the JavaScript code it's
pretty easy for us to do an extension
that do that and want to show you a few
example this is me on my cup the
environment that communicate with my
phone inside Firefox is an extension the
results are keepers extension as an
example for possible manager there is an
extension that's enabled the MIDI API in
Firefox so you can find many of them we
have also support for Quint review and
riddle mode API if you want it have to
run because the time is not so much but
is very funny I don't know many people
know doom they've done a fork that when
you kill a monster killer process we
have a patient that killed tops because
the API enable to ask to do it not so
these kind of attacks and is an
extension is a a bunch of HTM HTML CSS
and JavaScript stuff all together we
have the indycar the displaying the data
and what extension can do like
permissions the files that have to run
called the scripts you can define the
pattern the file to load etc inside the
manifest next we have the background
scripts
these are scripts that communicate
behind your tabs your developer tools as
an example because there is a sandbox
you cannot have an extension that run
everywhere
you have an extension that you can run
everywhere communicating between
different fights so background scripts
are pretty useful we have contact page
that is one of the most users as an I
think that everyone there as a tally is
an extension that improved github
usually is a Java skill injected in a
page and this birth Dec to do an
extension like that we have the browser
action that is again his lack of each
action but is a button that is always on
the browser UI and me about so a list to
define a little cool on the manifest
about the fact that extension can access
so not the extension cannot I said all
the file on the computer only the part
that we define in this manifest so it's
safety for the users another point was
the last year was the review on Emma
because was manual so when we have to
release a new version at so maybe about
fixed we have to wait someone that
review the code and quite a lot of time
that in the web is something not
acceptable now is automatically for
specific kind of API is manual to again
but it's very fast to have a new release
and be very happy about this work
because was one of the most problem for
me was the de chrome is automatically
they doesn't care about anything about
strict code policy lint in the second
about energy in Mozilla and their mo you
have a lot of warning about what your
coat doing wrong so he said before so to
developers to see that this code is bad
can be better and it is a lot of things
that we have in fact ox 57 perfect 58
per fox59
and try to do it as one slide recap of
the most cool things that you can see as
an example the sidebar because Fox is
the only one that they can have a site
where you can get an extension that use
the sidebar you have as an example
now you can embed the web extension
experiment with an extension again the
result so what says one of the most
asking things was to add back the
vertical management for the tabs now
there is the VI in Firefox 59 that
enables developers to hide the clothes
then toss so there is a lot of working
and the best way is to check the dogs
blog to see what are the most cool API
that are coming and these are so there
are examples because developer had a lot
of things to do and now we add 45
example of complete extensions available
documented on MDM and when you are
opening an API you will find an
extension that using this API so you can
see the code working inside your browser
complete everything documented last year
was not that way now we have that the
conditioning one of the most things
boring to do for a developer but someone
has to do it for us so how you can try
this page about double dot debugging
enabled to you to the bagger to the
extension inside Firefox and what also
your development extension using this
button so it's pretty easy download the
extension open and automatically style a
temporary until you close Firefox next
we have a tool for command line for
people that love command like how many
loggers drop the command line there
there is a tool that enable to do a lot
of things
signed extension linking watch low
distinction of Firefox for Android a lot
of things in a tool so there is the UI
way common language it's your choice to
do an extension I've no not so speak
because as I said Chrome marketplace is
horrible you cannot have a graph about
the statistics or dollars add on a
script that scrape this data and cross
this data so with Firefox you can see
what is the best browser for you for
your extension and now we about an
interface on mo this is the adhan
developer hub with few extensions that I
made without so new logo graphic
etc and we have also the new have own
interface as we have our stickers asked
to us with the new octopus mascot that
is more mobile friendly and there are
add more easy to find sections I like it
a lot is that before and it works of
course also provide better than before
there is that's a website for people
they say ok after this Chrome extension
works with Firefox probably yes you can
applaud there automatically will say ok
it's working or not so pretty easy for
us to check out so easy to load inside
Firefox as an example the KDE connect
extension add the support on Firefox
because I open at the ticket the next
day was on the marketplace because he
has only to upload on the marketplace so
it's pretty easy to have to then
essentially from Chrome or Firefox there
is not a standard in progress yes they
are working we know that what you see is
very slow they are working
we got update on this course they are
starting working again after path of 67
because was like stop that because
complaint was busy and now they're
starting working again honest and I
think about it a standard to develop
extension for all the browsers if
something that I think 10 years ago was
C Phi I think probably yes and I want to
give you to you few links very
interesting this course this our
category is a forum with all the staff
all the project in Mozilla is doing you
can find common voice but ceiling etc
there is a section for development at
dawn so you have questions you can write
there so everyone will app you so it
also you can reach developers from
Mozilla etc and there are also other
links of course the advanced blog is one
of the most important research is to get
updated about what's going on and now
it's time for questions so I have to run
but there was a lot of things by Fox 57
is pretty cool
yes
actually there are different I think
personally there are work there are
different API working but it's better to
say about web experiments they are
trying but there is Jordi probably has
more information about the planning
because for a mozillian you have to
check out all the bugs ela tickets is
something complicated to do there is the
blog and dance you can check the new
release and personally I think that a
new implementation to change the browser
setting from an extension are very
interesting because you can do an
extension that interact more strongly
with privacy settings in Firefox as an
example than before and I think add to
the tab the tab hiding API was one of
the most requested with Firefox 57
because there was a lot of user that was
using the vertical system for tops so
personally these are for me the most
cool for the hand of the app in idea
what are the plan but there are a lot of
things to do to cover the gap without
previous API there are other questions
ok so I expect that when you come back
after the first M you will develop an
extension of course and release for us
because we are users and we need the
essential to improve our experience
pretty easily with the button to stop
understand so thank you for your time
[Applause]