okay laughs good morning my name is
Makena Henshaw I'm going to talk to you
about my work in the auto FTC
first a little bit about specification
ODF is a specification for file format
for office documents the version 1.2 has
been published as iso standard in June
2015 the subcommittee 34 and there in
the work of six is responsible for it
this sub committee health Cisco scope
document descriptions and processing
languages it deals in office open XML
and epub as well although the standard
is another responsibility of isone
actual development and maintenance is
done by Oasis Oasis is a non-profit
non-profit consortium with membership of
over 600 organizations and individuals
the participants work in currently 64
technical committees and one of them is
a project or aces open document format
for of his applications or short open
document
now I show you a little bit about the
disease itself the shot shows the
current number of participants of the TC
we have work in yellow regular members
they get voting rights by attendance in
meetings the table shows the members
which were actually active last year
despite the small number you see the
diversity and of the members and the
widespread field of experience from a
point of organization we have companies
here and here your associations Yadav
and human foundations we have government
departments that's the last one of
normals and we have individuals from
point of office application you will
notice colleague colleague Ron let's see
em numeric we have Libre Office and we
have Microsoft Office in this TC
yeah what what has this TC to do with
our first heart is maintenance the
specification has about thousands who
unit pages such large documents always
has typos or broken references and such
errors some semantics is reflected two
styles source of additional errors
furthermore special care health is
needed in using normative keywords and
keeping a schema and post text matched
the next ID items at rest content
problems which come into view by
comparing programs for example all
implementations use angle in Radian but
agree is specified this case is easily
solved we will adapt a specification
more difficult cases where the
implementations are different we might
solve it by introducing new elements and
attributes or by making one behavior of
standard for worth 1.3 what requires
changes in the others applications there
exist rules for voting
but of course which why to find
consensual solutions
I'll let let us have a look at the tools
are we use common tools like mating
these meetings and black troika the
public made mailing list gives
non-members means to report box or
request features or give other inputs to
the TC the member mailing list is used
for discussions and attachments and
agendas and meeting notes are routinely
posted there those lists have a public
arrived lady our meetings are held by
telephone
currently the TC meets on Monday at
starting at 17 you see for one hour that
is six o'clock in the evening for
members in Germany and nine o'clock for
member in California
Oasis provides JIRA issue tracker
unfortunately its global settings like
formatting features and attachments we
work around that shortcoming by using
mailing list attachments or wiki and
uploading documents to the repository
so let us look hobby work all starts
with an issue currently nearly three
hundred issues with target OD f1 dot
swim are unresolved the chair select a
group of issues for the next meeting and
early announcement after at agenda gives
the members time to prepare only few
issues can be immediately handled
finally example given obvious typos or
of topical quests in most cases shortest
cousins revealed own problems which
leads to some homework for the members
after one or sometimes more turns the
members agree on a basic Aleutians
that's that's here we therefore here the
circular panel member gets the issue
assigned and script a solution which
means changing the earth schema and the
text in a final run the team votes on
this proposal and only the issue is
solved but that is not the end of the
work all the changes have to be
incorporated in a draft for the next
version of the specification currently
the TCC has a backlog of nearly hundred
resolved but not included issues and
there exists no complete working draft
how is appreciated
of course the TC also considered new
features such come in in from several
sources so all the FTC itself has a
subcommittee to work on collaboration in
document editing including change
tracking for details please rock it'll
already mentions a few elements and
attributes were added to solve
differences between existing
implementations sometimes TC gets a
feature request we are of his command
list if it is indeed a request for file
format and seems useful then the TC will
track it in an issue the TC does not
automatically work on it but will wait
until someone is actually going to
implement it most restarts come in from
implementers they first put a new
elements or attribute in a private
namespace and test its ODF provides an
extended mode that can be used for that
purpose implementer to see member we
write down the needed changes for text
and schema if it is put in an issue then
and the TC works on it that way
new file format elements have at least
one realization but developers tend to
badly document the extension also makes
it's unnecessary difficult for other
applications to implement it there is no
automatism that proposal will be clearly
incorrect over exactly but implementers
might might need to change
the application when they are going to
support ODF 1.3 I have noticed some
problems in regard to file format in
LibreOffice other projects may not have
such problem so please do not rush legal
analyze that in them validity should not
be a problem because the check is simple
we have heard about validate data
however it is annoying that a developer
sometimes neglected aspect differences
speaker between applications are serious
for the standard if they are not errors
in one application
but accordion then that means trouble
for the TC it is important that the TC
becomes early aware of such problems
they exist a public mailing list open
document users which had been created
for that purpose but it is not used
nevertheless the communication channel
does not really matter as long as
developers consult with the TC in case
the specification is not clear enough
the last group is a bit tricky because
they touch the Attic
dude of developers one aim of my talk is
to raise awareness of file format and
encourage developers to a fruitful
collaboration with members of the ODF TC
yeah I have been member in the or f TC
for almost five years now you might
wonder why I work as it is volunteer I'm
interested in markup languages and I'm
used staroffice and his successors for
20 years now but more important I like
that
ODF is an open standard everyone can
participate in the development of the
standard the protest is anti transparent
and decisions follow democratic
procedures company phonetic
Hey that wasn't my talk I have skipped a
lot of details because of the tight
timeframe and thank you for listening me
do you have questions you can use
validator to attach the documents but
the problem was openoffice and
libreoffice is that code is in part over
20 years old and there exist features
which have been transformed to the
propriety XML format of Open Office dark
but are not transferred to ODF and this
is a lot of features which need to be
transferred to the f1 dot suite before
all cases can validate in again such as
a schema
at the moment it's not timeline the
problem is that we would need some
people more to do the work as I already
mentioned we have 302 unsolved and 100
soft and we need at least editor who
incorporates their already solved one
and when you when when the work is good
we can solve for issues in a week and
then you can count yourself that we need
how long it needs we till we have worked
on all the existing issues and there are
still some open in Indy profits where
there is not even issue - it's no time
no time no time frame yet
you can accept other questions
informally right yes okay yeah okay
[Applause]
I forgot the terrace and presentation is
by Foster you can download it and it has
a lot of information in the notes
including links and so on