good morning everybody my name is
Santosh Bala Krishnan and I work with
the French Network Information Center
I'm an hour on the engineer there
doesn't work it seems today I'm going to
talk about a tool called zone master
which is a torus for DNS validation so
this project has been it has been
working with ethnic the French registry
and the Swedish registry is they started
it like three years ago and we are
planning to maintain for another two
years
both companies have agreed to work on
this party for the next two years also
so to set it as a preamble I always
start with this slide which is which I
took it from the NHS our body even
though we have a lot of issues we are
alive but this lots of research has put
into in saying that different parts of
the body has different medical tests and
we have to do it to make sure that our
body is fit so I call that as a
comprehensive health check so it's
similarly for DNS we have different
parts for the DNS zone where we have to
test even though your website works
sometimes you will have issues so we
need a tool to have a comprehensive test
for the DNS what we do let's take an
example I did a test with our MLL it's
logician libro in france it's like the
first job in France so I did a test with
the tool that we all will always use dig
so what happens when I do a dig and the
site works but when I do the same test
using the master a comprehensive test I
use this one master CLI I'm not sure
whether it is clear we have issues here
that are one morning and two notices so
there is one name server that is not
properly
thing so that is why we need that we
need to have a comprehensive tool for
validating stone DNS zone but there are
a number of tools in there open source
paid and everything and why zone master
is different the zone must set targets
different types of people if you're just
an user you want to check your website
you go to the SAS the public green zone
master dotnet and enter your domain name
and have it have the results to see
whether you are you are zone zone for
your website or domain name is is
healthy then for advanced users you can
install the engine which is the library
which is that's the comprehensive test
and user interface the command-line
interface your you should also install
that and you can do various
customizations to see how it how we were
zone or of a domain is working then if
you are a if you're a guy who's your
registry or registrar or somebody who
has a portfolio of the my name's like
hundred thousand of my name's you want
to test all the domain names you want to
test all the domain names in a batch and
then you want to store them in somewhere
in the database see the history whether
it has worked in 2015 now it is working
what was the difference you can also do
that by installing the backend and the
GUI you can have your own interface and
then you can also use call the zone
master pearl library from your own
application so these are the different
target users that we be plant with its
own master so this is an example of our
ml l dot info which we test using their
gravity
graphical user interface at the web site
and you see there is an issue the yellow
color now how do you test from the CLI
so you install the CLI in your own
system computer and then you use the
method
- CLI and run your domain then there are
different it's not clear as you can see
that if
you have different levels of
customization for example if you want to
test one live with ipv4 if you want to
test certain tests and not others if you
want to change the level of the debug
you can have debug one two three there
are different prospects with its own
master so you can use that with the CLI
you can also use the results of Jason
OPC interface there's an API where you
can call from your application to run
and then get results so the first one
shows that you have a static test and
you got an ID and the second here shows
that midis ID you get the results so
this is the result in Jason how do you
run it batch just back when I call the
Backstairs you run like five ten hundred
thousand domains so similarly you run a
you call the JSON RPC you put the number
of domains you add a bad job you call
the method add that job and you have a
API and user key and then you run the
test you get a response with an ID and
you can use this ID to get the number of
results so this is for example where I'm
showing is that there are about 200
tests there are five test that has been
finished and I won nine different tests
running so there is an API documentation
in G tab which is being updated there
have been some feedbacks that it is not
properly documented so we are updating
that then you can also call from your
application from your own software you
called the library you can use commands
like this I I know you're more export
than me so you can use this to get the
results now this is how the top one is a
local implementation by the Swedish
registry where they are using certain
master and the second one is used by a
company called Pingdom where they're
testing all the government sites in
Sweden to show whether it is properly
using the NSTIC or not so they are using
some master so these are the two
examples if you've seen so much in brief
it is an opportunity under the all the
core is engaged
licensed it has been vastly documented
that is one of the main differences
between other tools and the zone master
I will go deep into that after
afterwards so it all the documentation
is used using the creative common
license so what our objective was that
however when I say our objective both
the finished registry and the French
registry to create zone master as a tool
that should be used by everybody to test
the zone validate for the DNS zone you
can use it for delegated and non
delegated zones when I say non delegated
zones it is not already there in the DNS
you can test them there are three types
of interfaces CLI web and the API we can
have different levels of output you can
have high medium and low levels of
output you can have the output in web
HTML text and Jason now we are
supporting four languages English French
tradition Danish and you can also
customize it according to niche I will
also go deep into that as of now we are
supporting for OS Debian CentOS FreeBSD
and Ubuntu it might not be all the
versions have been supported but we are
trying to keep it updated so I told you
earlier about the documentation so when
we started before both is the Swedish
industry and ethnic the French registry
we had our own
validation tool DNS zone validation tool
ethnic was using zone check and is was
using DNS check so both of them when
they wanted to update it with we thought
that we will create a new tool so the
first thing that we said was that there
was not enough documentation so we had
to have that inner documentation so what
we did was we took all the requirements
from these tools existing tools we we
removed them what the tests that were
obsolete we added some of the new tests
and every time there was a new
requirement we have a review and saying
that this is the test that should be
updated we update it like
requirements and then we put them under
a different categories so as of now we
have like 84 tests classified into 8
different categories and all this tests
are
documented like this for example take
this first test we say that why did we
do this test and which BCP or RFC says
that this test should be done then how
this test should be done so everything
is documented so once it is the opposite
that's why it is getting delayed we we
put the source if we write this was code
1 li when the complete documentation is
done and reviewed so in case tomorrow if
you want the develop your own tool you
can just go into this documentation and
use your own develop your own tool for
its own validation DNS zone validation
so what do we have as implementation we
have ball and JavaScript most of the
code is returned in pole only the GUI
part we have some JavaScript so there
are being some feedbacks about the GUI
that is not perfect so we are developing
a new GUI and it is being prospectively
it should be up in the May of 2018 and
we have a l dns resolver that we use for
using the net and anus another labs
library so there the results how do we
have the locks the locks we can have a
human readable form you can have in for
with the tags which you could use it in
your own application in raw format then
you can have it in JSON format and also
you can configure the results depending
upon what what you like to have like you
could we have different levels of
configurations in for notice warning run
critical so that you can modify
depending upon your requirements
so this is an example of how we have the
severity of the different tests tomorrow
you say that DNS SEC as of now is info
notice you say it should be create a
warning or error you can modify that
then you can also decide on which just
to run for example in syntax we have
eight tests you say that I don't want to
run syntax 6 so you can put it as 0 and
that test will not be running you can
also go into the configurations of how
the resolver should work whether you if
you want to test one with ipv6 or IB
before that also could be done
and for fine grain in the test we can
say for example if you want have a
domain and you know that one of the
names that we is not working and you
don't want to have a error on that it
can just put it as a warning so this is
fine
these are the different configuration
levels that you can do in zone master to
adapt to yourself and we have decided to
make currently there are these are
different files so we will have only one
file in the future which is called the
profile file so you can just change it
and use your master CLI - profile and
then you can run your domain based upon
your configurations so we have
configured the features in the GUI where
we have the like for example here the
IANA profile but it currently it is
obsolete so the new GUI will will update
that then regarding standardization
efforts we try to standardize it in the
IDF it didn't go well there are a lot of
feed positive as well as negative
feedbacks so currently we are planning
to push it as a best practice document a
tribe so it is in a doodle doodle thing
so who are all using join master is has
his own implementations rather
Canadian registry is using it d.k.bose
master their own implementation as I
showed ping them has that ripe ncc is
using it and I can associate Lee confirm
that it will be using so much tougher
PDT
and registrar's like GoDaddy and the
obvious in their web sites are linking
back to the zone master center the
Council of Europe international
top-level domains is planning to use own
master for statistics purpose
in you all too well tests on master give
us feedback and contributions so this is
the different references we have
everything is in G tab if you want to so
[Applause]
all this information I think you can
launch multiple engines yeah I have not
done that but I think you can do that
I think you can start an issue in g-dub
and then we will decide the team will
decide whether we need it or not then we
can I would be interested in having like
a short introduction
[Music]
if there are no more right now we have
five minutes the minimum value came from
the I think it's from the RC or it's
right basically I'm not sure that
something came from the point yeah see
that
thank you
[Applause]