so I would like to first apologize for
the old hardware but I think a retro
talk should have retro stuff working so
I will show it after it
so we'll start presenting this so the
agenda is basically to define the
motivation for doing this thing mainly
what are the DX cartridges what were the
objectives what were the challenges and
the solution the hardware
I designed the firmware and lately this
the software that I implemented ok the
motivation was basically to I started my
knowledge of computer programming by
starting to program as an expected in 82
I started by learning basic and from
that time I was not aware how to do
stuff in assembly so the idea was I
wanted to do something in assembly but
the time went by and then I went to
college diversity that a computer course
and a few years later like in 2015 I
decided to make this game in assembly so
I needed something to be able to do this
game and to be able to do larger games
because the spectrum is limited to 48k
ram right so this spawns the idea and
then there's someone created this
competition and I went to do a game
based in assembly but my real goal was
to make a part of this game
it's called powr prisoners of war that
was in the arcade it was called duk-soo
Goku in Japan and it was called prison
before in you in the UI EU szerik and in
the USA so what's the big difference on
these goals this is the genic spectrum
48k as you I suppose you all know and
this one is a picture of a ball that
of powa ANSI it has a lot of different
specs when compared to the mighty that
expected right so there is a big
difference either in cpu rom ram and
video capabilities so if you can see
there is this game uses something like
800 kilobytes of ROM and the spectrum we
have like 16 and we don't own it right
so we need to fix that and the rest I
think we can just fake it
and try to get to it so that's what we
usually do right so first test were to
find if it was possible to convert this
game so this is the arcade Mikey that
the top of the thing that is on the top
with a backlight over it and this is my
experimental images for the ZX loading
screen and this is the arcade first
level it's the prison area and this is
my idea what it will look like on the ZX
spectrum as you can see is not finished
and though the game is large
I haven't pinned the rest yet but these
were the goals so having such a large
requirement for wrong means that we can
get away with a simple 48k that we have
on the ZX spectrum obviously we could go
to 128 but it's not enough again so
maybe we could just use a cartridge that
actually replaces the internal warm but
the problem is that the ROM has a
maximum size of 16 kilobytes right it is
not enough again so and also it requires
an interface adapter but most of the
people from back in the day know that
there are at least these three ones that
were very well known that provides the
required interface to be able to use the
cartridge officially there were only ten
cartridges that were released there are
something like 10 more that were
unofficial or never released that you
can get online if you want to try it on
an emulator
so what would my objectives so I wanted
to create a cartridge with electronics
on it I wanted to support at least 512
kilobytes of ROM I need to map that ROM
to the 0 80 address space which is only
64 kilobytes right it's only has 16 bits
and so it clearly doesn't fit right so
obviously we have to do something like
paging or similar and I also wanted to
have PCB and chips must fit inside
original case the idea is to either
recover old cases and use a new hardware
inside or also support the cloning of
the or the old hardware and also the the
case so there are many of these small
cartridges out there but they are
expensive so if you can buy one or
replace one that is damaged it that's
also a goal of this project ok so what
were the challenges if you haven't
noticed already there are a lot of
physical limitations
the first one is 16 kilobytes right over
the red space so it goes from 0 to 3 FFF
and the connector on the spectrum maybe
I could show one sorry so this is one of
the cartridge so the connector is
something like this as a big drawback
because this was designed only for ROM
so Sir Clive Sinclair as his usual self
decided we are going to save some bucks
and not put the required lines so
read/write and i/o signals are not
present which is a problem hard to solve
and I also wanted to have the original
case or make the art where that fits in
the original cases as I said earlier and
the problem is that after measuring it
there is two point two millimeters of
space between the case and the board on
the backside and one
meter on the front side which is a
problem so issues to solve out two three
goodbye
maybe I'm moving too much okay so this
is the issue to solve and another one is
I need to find components that actually
fit inside the case and the only ones
that are available with that small
clearance are SMD chips and not always
in the chips pit so we have to find ones
for it okay this is probably the most
important slide so that you understand
what's going on if you can look at it
this is a usual instruction opcode fetch
on select JIT processor so it's always
as that four phases t1 to t4 and you can
see that always the spectrum always does
the instruction fetch with the PC on the
address space and then to support
dynamic memory also does a refresh
address that is automatic so every
instruction implies a refresh dress that
increments every instruction okay only
that's the first seven bits but it does
increment and the Refresh dress is
calculated based on two registers the
eye register and our register the
problem as I said is that this is the
interface of the the cartridge and we
don't have all the other lines except
this ones that are marked so we only
have address data and the memory request
because that's what Sir Clive Sinclair
found to be enough which is not for us
so what other things could we think
about maybe we could use the i/o request
and solve our problem right but circa
I've seen clear again decided no we
cannot have that we have to earn more
money by putting less stuff in the
machine
okay so what kind of solutions can we
find so that we can create paging
triggers when we can actually not
communicate with the thing right so one
idea maybe could be the fix address and
just a kit right
or maybe could do like repeatable reads
so if I read a specific address a few
times maybe I can I can get away with it
so or maybe use a pattern sequence like
an EEPROM so an EEPROM or a flash chip
as a sequence to protect against right
so if we do a sequence of reads in a
specific pattern it unlocks but that is
really complex and we would really would
need to know that is a read we don't
know right we don't have the read or the
right so maybe you can exploit CPU
features like what parts out of the
question right maybe could you see the
eye register it's messing up with a
refresh right and maybe you can use the
our register which also messes with the
Refresh or maybe do something like I'm
going to use an improbable address
something that will probably never
happen when you are running an
application is that possible I think it
is so I'm I went for it and the solution
I found is that if you remember
correctly every instruction does opcode
fetch which is an address and then those
a refresh address that indirectly we can
control right so if I can somehow define
that I can read the same address
three times in a row which it seems
impossible right because the other guys
controlling the registers and is
incrementing but it's possible and it's
possible because of this because there
are two instructions called the LD I and
LD d that transfer a byte from one
location to another location that does
does exactly this so they copy from one
to the other so they are two identical
and there are two addresses that are
being used and I can force them to be
identical and if I do that and then I
still need the third access right so the
next instruction is my next axis so if
the two and addresses that I use on the
first instruction are exactly the
instruction of the next address bingo
right I have true
three identical addresses so what what
do I need more to make this work I need
a way to inform the cartridge that I
want page X and not some random page or
the next page or something like that so
I can have better control so what I need
is something that will give me a
parameter any an input so what I did is
well the next instruction as an opcode
but what comes next the Refresh address
can I change it
yes I can with the I and their registers
so now I started thinking how am I going
to implement this right so let's start
adding up what we need so we need two
pins for VCC and ground
we need one bit for buzz memory control
line this is available in the cottage
right and I need one bit to control buzz
ROM so that I can disable the internals
that X internal one so that he uses mine
okay like the cartridge does I have
admit data lines 16 bins at both the
dress lines 3 bits that I need extra
because I have 512 kilobytes so it needs
at least 19 pins right
so 3 more than 16 and I need 3 extra
bits just to control the flash so chip
enable output enable and write enable
well if we had add all this up it's like
38 pins that's hard to get on a CP LD
and it occupies a lot of lines and as
you may probably know or I can show you
here is one there isn't a lot of space
in this right even by today's standards
so this is a chip that is glued with
epoxy and that's it that's why it's so
thin okay so I can't route too many
lines over there because it won't fit
okay so I have to do something right
what I can start cutting off stuff I
don't need do I need a data line no I
can do magic right why do I need that
well but I would like to cut those 16
bits also because they are too many
right I can't cut any of the rest right
I need them so I can cut the 16 bits
well kind of the problem is that I need
those bits to determine my special dress
that I can repeat three times so if you
look at the dress price or whether X 48k
it's actually 64 K because 16 kilobytes
is wrong and we know that because the
last bits of the address is 0 0 and all
the others is ramped so we can only mess
up with the first part right so what can
we do maybe we could force that if a 15
and a 14 is 0 0 you are we are in
business
actually we can't because every access
would give us that to run so maybe you
can have a special address and include
like a 7 a 7 to a 0 with the ice for a
15 and a 14
so like the UL ID does in a weird way so
what this means is that I would have
something like this which is a lot less
than 16 bits it's nine bits right well
not really maybe we can simplify this
okay do we really need this actually we
don't because we only need to know that
it's a ROM access but we don't need that
to control the flesh because the flesh
can read directly those two bits right
because as you can see so I didn't need
this let me go a little bit further so
if you can see this is the address space
of the flush so the last two bits of the
16-bit bus are in fact part of my flesh
page address right so I don't need those
to enter directly to my device that
controls the logic so they can go
directly to the flush I just need a way
to trigger from them so I cut the buzz
that aligns and but now I'm using the 8
bit both addressed lines to do this and
I said I don't need the data lines right
why why don't I don't need them because
I can pass all the information I can
using the Refresh address right so I'm
going to use the Refresh dress as input
so I don't need those lines so I'm
saving a lot of bits currently I will
map the a4 to a0 when I'm giving the
special instruction to change page to
the flash page area okay so I'm going to
use this part the a 0 to a 4 to give
that page address now this is a
simulation of the logic I created and on
top you see green it's the input lines
and then you see blue and kind of I
don't know that color because it's
different here but the other ones were
blue and this was like magenta or
something but it's different here on the
screen okay
so if we look on top we have a 15 and a
14 which are the ROM addresses right
what it identifies so in dark grey we
see that it's a ROM addressed
they are both 0 next we see that they
are swapping so it's RAM address so I
don't want to if you see here there is a
chip select ok that that's the one with
the magenta color that is only enabled
when I'm accessing wrong ok when it is
accessing Ram I don't want to mess with
it right so that it works and now here
is the special case if you see the white
line it's the triggered address so if
you look closely I had three clocks on
top where the address didn't change so
it's my trigger right and the yellow
line represents the input my parameter
that's the flash page I wanna select
right
then I have in green bars another access
to wrong but it's not special in any way
and then have another access to roam
again and this was just to try out if
mixed accesses would work and then here
we have another example this was I have
a flash right
and I can read it already with this idea
but could I write for it
could I find a way to make it work so
the idea is I'm going to use the 87
address bit to signal me a flag if it's
a read or write and that has a problem
at least on this version because the
flash ship doesn't like the chip select
or the wrong something I can't read it
right now from that it doesn't like it
to be swapping it must be stable so what
I did is I had still at space so I added
two more inputs with the advantage that
this will allow me to put the control
command in the I register which is the
Eiger part of the dress okay
so anyone's carry of assembly this it
really is it's commented right so the
the major that the most important thing
is down here so we have an LD I it's the
trigger sequence address and then we
have the load a with something so these
two instructions is what are going to do
the job the idea is that everything
struction that I do the our register
will increment so I'm going to fool him
and before I calculate the change until
I get to the LD I write to L di and LD a
and I will put minus two because as soon
as I write LD are V comma a I'm going to
do two extra instructions right with a
special twist here because I need the
are to be correct on the second
instruction and there is a twist L di as
a special instruction that increments
twice so that's why it's minus 2 so this
will implement this now the smart guys
in the room would tell me there's
something wrong with this there are
smart guys here right
well I haven't put it because it's a lot
of work to explain in detail in such
such a small area on screen but first I
need to set the high register which is
not there right but it's usually fixed
at a value but we can change it and
there is another important aspect which
is we need to disable interrupts right
or out there or else there will mess up
my timing right okay so this is the
version 4 right so it's very similar we
have to do increase here an instruction
that just swaps the a and F the flags
register so that you can save the data
while we change the our register but the
actual is just the same until we find
here which is a right and not to read ok
but it will work the same I've tried it
and it it was able to read the flash
type which gives me the size okay so
what do we need to do to make this work
we need to define a circuit diagram and
I decided to use wire wrap prototype
boards something from the past so it's
suitable that analyzer for debugging
define a PCB board and lately and also
design a case so let's go and do this so
this is a very simple circuit we have
here on top it's the connector that
represents the cartridge connector here
we have the CPL D which is an ATF 22 v10
C and we have the flash chip from at now
that is hard to find because parallel
chips parallel flash chips are currently
very hard to find ok so this is my
prototypes that you can see here and
that you will see working it was done in
three phases like three slots because
it's easier this what this mess you see
here in the middle is the wire wrapping
or a
to build a sick circuit without having
to pay for the cost of the PCB you use
something that is already made and then
route the rest ourselves but sometimes
this gets really messy when you have to
take one of those wires that will be on
the others and another concern is that
if the speed is very high every loop
that you do to fix those fire those
wires will make it work like a coil so
that's a problem okay this is hardware
debugging and you can see on top I hope
there are three identical addresses
because I haven't all the addresses here
but the most important ones so I have
three addresses and after in that green
line you can see that the green line is
triggering one position too far so it
should be one before why does this
happen because the guys from the
manufacturer from the cpld forgot to
mention that there were flip-flops that
were masters life so it utilize one
clock cycle so this was the first
version to see if the the board would
fit with with the chips
this was the version 1.0 with the planes
already find and this is the board that
was manufactured I have some here if you
then want to see so it has small LEDs on
the front so that you can see what's
going on and the ships is on the
backside where we have the two point two
millimeters space that is enough for the
ships so this is the original board that
I've shown you this is a 3d
representation of it so that I could
model the case and next step and then I
also want to do the part of the rubber
because there is
[Applause]
there is this red thing that is rubber
to protect the connectors okay so this
is my was my first version of the former
the idea is to run code and see if the
paging is actually working this is a
simple gift it's not running anything
right here but is to show that we can
use the 512 kilobytes not just to have a
bigger game but we have a list of games
that we can just dump them to ram so
that it the the deck beta can start
running the the old games this was a
page I designed to be able to debug also
the memory that is on the ROM that is
not implemented yet so what do we need
for software well we need to make a
proof-of-concept
Adept existing multilateral game our
type was my choice and I have to thank
Bob pipe which was the original guy that
transformed this from the arcades to the
spectrum he participated and helped to
do this and so I have to thank him thank
you very much Bob so what we do is copy
what is on ROM to RAM and run and when
we have the needs to loads because this
game has eight levels and every time you
play it after level one you have to
order level two and that means you have
to press the tape wait five minutes or
something like that and if you die you
have to go back to level one so back the
tape and do it again that's what this is
going to avoid right and we can do some
extra stuff when we do this so we can
implement invulnerability and load level
with this so we can try go and try the
game
so let me try and show you sorry for
being hidden it's top secret okay we
have to change the video sorry
oh by the way this is the link to the
github with code for Knox ROM for the
firmware and it will also have the code
for flashing the CP LD do I need to
change something maybe power up
great you know this is my special tool
it's a wand so if I can fit it here
thank you I told you guys it was magic
right so and now we saw you have to
bring down a bit but now we can play
this game right and it's a special
knocks round version the game is running
okay now if you press ENTER you can
select what you're going to do fire and
attach and it can start playing right
and I can see I can say to the other
world but I can't see what I'm doing
right right now so I'm gonna die
great so how do I fix this easy
I can boot again in infallibility mode
okay let's select some keys again sorry
up down
fire and this one right let's hope I
left the key pressed enough let's try
and die maybe down mmm
great so this is great if you if you
can't play you can go to the top level
okay but and now what if I want to load
the next level or the last level I never
reach the last rails right it was so
hard so let's try that
so resetting again and for example let's
load level three okay
by the way Bob was nice enough to tell
me the the coach to do this I didn't
have to search the code for it so I'm
playing level 3 directly from the the
cartridge and that can load any level
and this is great if you want to get a
good eye score because you can have path
to the same level several times for
example if you reach the last one but
it's working
so the concept works it's possible to
communicate with the with the ROM and
expand its size I'm also planning to I
did a few test boards like this ones
don't mind doesn't mine didn't break and
this is an original book okay sorry
and I'm going to just see if it fits and
it fits right it's still missing this
right but I'll get there and I have to
do the board likely be printed or
mass-produced or something I don't want
to make wait 50 minutes for a case right
and here is a warning for you all so I
made the design and trusted my libraries
so the layout of the chip should be
correct right we at least we hope so but
what happens I don't know you probably
can't see maybe I could find something
white the chip is here right and the
contacts are there can you see it
probably not but you can come and see
because I'm done so be careful when you
do draw this so that it doesn't work
like expect
any questions I'm a software developer
by profession well I like hardware a lot
and I started studying it on my spare
time for a few years back and you know I
have a background in programming so I
have I know what cities are like and
what all they work so I have digital
classes on the University right so that
was where I learned the more detailed
stuff but the
what you need to know is already on the
web so if you find it you take a few
iterations and you get there yeah before
it wasn't possible yet to go Harvey
probably stupid question that today the
image that you to both of those taken
off the our Commission why did you not
need to patch it whatever regions of
memory will do this game not the idea
though this game uses like 120 kilobytes
okay I'm planning to do POWs that will
use the 512 kilobytes okay but this one
doesn't use that okay no I did I did but
with the help from the guy that helped
view it helped me to split the code in
parts and then I implemented the part of
the paging and loading etc and
everything was untouched except the
small item that the ropes like not
strong special version okay so it was
the collaboration effort there is one
more here don't need to be all over each
other this is the original this is 15
one you can also print the rubber yes
you can it doesn't feel the same it
doesn't feel the same doesn't but it's
not too doesn't have the same problem
yes so it's just hacking right so we
have to work but yeah but this is the
expected it's the same
I have this one but this driver cuts the
image like two characters on the left so
I use that one but what's on both okay
okay I can show you actually I was
trying to see if someone would ask me
why haven't I used something like give
em MC or there are other interfaces that
allow you to load from s SD card right
so why can't we use that we can but the
problem is that you load games that only
fit in forty-eight K I can do a game
that is 512 kilobytes plus 48 K of RAM
right and I also can use this on dev 80
that X 80 which is the ship that only
has one kilobyte okay so the firmware
has to be adapted because the screen
rendering is not the same right but it
will work eight kilobytes let me let me
see if it works without the one no no
it's maybe maybe there is a small
connector on this board so sometimes it
does the web connection we just put the
magic one