hello everyone we have now here on stage
and rainbows E&O from chair throw and he
will speak about detecting drive-by
attacks by analyzing malicious
javascript in big data environment
thank you let's welcome him onstage
thank you guys how I will get straight
to the presentation I'm not released to
make presentations but the who I am I
let me introduce myself i was able to
separate security researcher for
imagination center for cyber security
incident response i have almost 25 years
of experience in the security
I'm a computer free from the days when
or there was no www no world-wide-web
just the BBS and the modern devices and
the anti-malware techniques were was one
of the my first hobbies
it all started when my friends and me
included the encounter the virus or back
in 1992 many of you might remember it
but it was a simple do nothing virus
appending it's goto.com files there was
no-one antivirus so i had to make myself
this actually open the test taste for
measuring devices but then I found the
polymorphic virus
what is a polymorphic virus every of
offspring every generation of this virus
is encrypted using the new key
therefore the code of the every new
generation is completely different for
more or the parents so to say this means
that extracting a signature is rather
impossible the only constant thing in a
polymorphic virus is the description
routine but is too small to extract
their signature sometimes even the
bigger description routine is
obvious cated so that it was the first
from one generation to another but still
there is a way here is the candle Isis
basically relies on the fact that even
though a signature cannot be extracted a
polymorphic virus has a certain features
like searching for certain files
searching for certain processes to do in
fact trying to open circle file scope
itself etc for accessing some system
functions the description routine of the
polymorphic virus is in fact it's
Achilles heel because this portion of
code is never encrypted only obfuscating
this means that the code is there but
you have the tools to understand what is
what is happening so basically it's
considered suspicious behavior if
process cycles through large chunks of
data the price transformation on data
read like one decryption function and
then tries to execute the data that that
bread when I speak about viruses my
presentation is about require
exploitation because there are quite a
few similarities between polymorphic
viruses and malicious javascript virus
needs to encrypt its own body in order
to avoid detection by your antivirus
signatures scanning javascript is to
obfuscate its own code to avoid
detection by next-generation firewalls
uTM's antivirus scanners etc to achieve
more execution of polymorphic virus has
to decrypt its own body therefore cycle
through the encrypted code the price
transformations to that code execute
that code infected user and detected a
cloud web exploit his supposed to do the
same
what is the web exploit kit it's a
donkey that automates the exploitation
of client-side vulnerabilities usually
targeting browsers and programs that are
web second vote for the browser you can
usually it gathers information on the
the Machine find the vulnerabilities and
determines the appropriate to exploit
delivered exploit which typically
typically silently drive drive by
installed Donald installs and execute
smaller more than seventy percent of
ransomware and banking Trojans is
delivered either by phishing email
containing a link to one URL with
malicious javascript or when a user
success on URL containing the militia
javascript in a legitimate website or
served by a third party advertisement
usually there are four stages we
identified four stages in a drive-by
exploitation the first stage is that is
the contact face where the user accesses
a compromise website access the spam
link or even a compromise the ad might
might do the same with the same effect
the resurrection face which is the
second phase the user is actually read
directed to the appropriate exploitation
server according to his own type of a
browser version etc in the exploitation
face the actual expert takes place and
the control or no victims computer is
taken by you by the attacker which
normally in the infection phase starts
to install banking Trojans ransomware
etc this is our how it looked like sorry
here is the contact face you see a
normal normal website with the militias
the advertisement for a compromise
website or spam link all resurrect the
user to traffic direction system which
are then the sensing to an expert
circuit which then installs ransomware
banging progeny or other kind of model
our focus is to detect the attacks in
the contact face the techs are performed
usually by inserting militias resurrect
which could be javascript direct
military fresh eggs I frames etc in the
p sorry in the HTML code or of the page
these are examples how it can be done
with the JavaScript with the matter
afresh or how can I frame or would look
like but signature scaling easily detect
malicious resurrect several criminals
came with a solution meaning javascript
on Fisk obfuscation how would the norm
or confiscated javascript look I don't
skate looks like this so it's pretty
readable the office Kate version i don't
know if you can see it here looks
nothing like this
therefore it's very hard to extract the
signature from more from this office
obfuscated code i'll show you a real
life example of obfuscate the JavaScript
which year we found in the wild
Oh as you can see there is nothing that
you can decide for certain that the
there is a malicious resurrect going on
here but but as soon as we be obfuscated
this code we can clearly see very normal
looking
javascript code this portion which I
highlighted here is where the actual
resurrect takes place namely it creates
an element in the HTML page an iframe
who's the size is one pixel display is
now and the source is an external link
this means that when someone will access
this page containing this this code will
resurrect will get redirected to this
link which is a unexplored side
expecting the the signature becomes an
impossible task as you can see the the
code is a very hard to read already
wrecked are created on the fly while the
HTML is rendered in your browser
malicious behavior can only be
determined by emulating the code but
this process is really time consuming
and not always reliable emulating the
code can sometimes trigger booby traps
which are put in place by the attacker
especially to deter the the the analyzes
well for instance how are the obvious
stated this this code it was rather
simple as you can see it's calling an
even function here which i replaced with
the print with the print function which
you simply display the code for me but
there are some attackers who can
redefine the print function inside their
script so when you were calling the
print function to display the the
obfuscated code it might to call their
own function which can I don't know do
some damage depending on the attacker so
the challenge at the Romanian national
center for several security incident we
want to continuously monitor the
security level of romanian websites from
the perspective of drive-by attacks
but there are overset 372 thousand
websites needing to be more toward and
ransomware campaigns are at an all-time
high
we need very small rates for false
negatives and the we need to be very
careful with you with this because false
negatives mean that Romanian users are
exposed to various types of words right
by your attacks we need to be accurate
clean and fast the problems we have
though is that we have a number of
websites a number of website pages and
then analyze this time which to us in
our circumstances translates to roughly
over 20 to 20,000 hours of analyzes if
you hadn't every response time for page
for like three seconds you get the like
51,000 the hours of analyzes if you were
to analyze every page in the honey
client we should be analyzing
continuously for like five years in 89
something like this almost six six years
and most websites have more than just
100 pages and the most of websites have
higher response response times
therefore the total duration of our
analyzes could take much more longer
than we then we expected
Plus most most exposed kids use
JavaScript obfuscation which means that
signature scanning fails which means
your favorite next-generation firewall
will not detect them even if your
browser is up-to-date you are still
exposed 20 there Tex what is a honey
client i was talking about honey clients
have any client is a full-featured web
browser to visit potentially malicious
web pages the environment in which the
browser runs is monitored to determine
if the visit resulted in the system
being being compromised
basically it records all the
modifications that are called during the
visit of a page such as files created
the or deleted the register Keys
newly-created processes etc if any and
expected modification occur this is
consider is manifestly manifestation of
an attack and the corresponding pages
collective malicious interaction client
honey client seems to be the solution
but it's not because they are very
time-consuming firing the single
instance could add three seconds two
three four seconds to every URL we we
analyzed but also which is very very
important they are detectable in
defeatable even from JavaScript we we
have found some some examples of
JavaScript code aimed of detecting if
the code is analyzing the sent box or in
a virtual machine basically there are
two types of a very fine if you know
analyzing environment first you detect
the monitoring environment either by you
are no mac address or a certain files or
other science
secondly there is did detection evasion
I would start with the detection of
monitoring environment i found in the
internet the no explorer a very nicely
but that would allow the hacker to read
the the market rest of the client
machine or the code does this because it
to use the Kinect server method of the
su dubbed out this wbbm locator to get s
wbm services exemplary method it carries
the world network adapter configuration
the class return the properties of the
network adapters on the honor system and
simply iterate through the valley
use under t for any values matches the
the vmware ouy another method of
detecting the analyzes environment is a
light on the fact that the most two of
the Shelf sandboxes or honey client have
a standard the screen screen resolutions
this can be easily verified in the in
JavaScript with the small snippet of
work of cold and so there is a
possibility of were detecting the the
honey client searching for specific
specific file names here if they request
the JavaScript engine load the source
clip from the client local filesystem
javascript the did not perform any
checks to see the fireworks the actually
as JavaScript source file if the file is
nothing that we expect the JavaScript
formatted throw or JavaScript runtime
error the script can be used even to to
detect vmware tools
the second method of attacking the
analyzes environment is delayed
exploitation and this can be achieved
the through even triggered exploitation
like using the certain javascript
methods that would require a certain in
environment for instance if you put the
the most prompter in a certain area of
the screen or if you click on that
certain certain area of the screen or if
you believe that certain area of the
screen also there is a method that that
add some more sleep time before
exploitation as most to send boxes and
the honey clients have a limited the
time for analyzes like a few seconds if
nothing happens the year they say
everything is ok but in fact this code
weights more than the sent box two weeks
a executed it small and payload also
there is something where I called
selective exploitation the attacker
decides to only target the certain
certain versions of browsers or certain
types of browsers or operating systems
also there is what i call the referral
attack which means the exploits are only
serve to request that originated from
one of the infected websites so if you
directly analyze it will do nothing
only if you come from one of the
infected website they know they they
have found so there are some more
real-life examples when the the attacker
doesn't to target the user the first
time or he he accesses the page but
rather it will not attack him on
revisiting like a cookie or when he
opens a link on a secondary page of the
website etc so we're not using an
existing solution existing solutions to
make make use of honey clients but
feeling every URL to a funny client is
very time-consuming we restore howhow
longer it would take us to to do this
publicly available honey client as you
have seen before have no fingerprint
which could lead to two detection
evasion or by the
by the attacker by the militias
javascript also we are solution has to
be quite scalable quite large because we
have a lot of data to process and
nowhere publicly available solution can
can scalp or needs this means that we
have to distinguish clearly between
banning and mailing URLs three sandbox
analyzes so the first step we took was
to understand the inner works and
dynamics of militias javascript so we
analyze like forty different models
javascript symbols found in the wild
sorry we found that they share a certain
set of common features so we were able
to compile heuristic set from the
expected features then we created an
artificial intelligence model using the
curious except to be using the normal
detection engine could be this is the
solution here you have the internet this
is the least or database feeding the
website who our our agents the agents
call the the internet and the for every
every website they analyzed every page
every script to see certain certain
features or everything is a central
message broker which you send everything
to an anomaly detection engine which
then sends the militia see flag the urls
to one of our two sandboxes one it's a
no GS sandbox or the other one it's a
user's the intel vt-x the equalization
method this is the reporting part where
the the analyzes and the all the results
are correlated before there is a problem
or with the any any discrepancies or
stuff like this
all the URLs are submitted for manual
analyzes so basically our militias jay
johnson detection engine was written in
c and the assembly it was multi-threaded
analyzes because we have to be very very
fast or it grows a list of websites
analyzing every script found on every
page using curious techniques it
searches the HTML code for the species
javascript methods and correlations
between them
we call them features and also we look
for different evasion techniques inside
the script code because sometimes there
are certain scripts or who are
interpreted in one way by one browser
and totally different by you by
different by different browser so
basically if they were to target the
single type of browsers they would
choose to only make code that would
execute for that the certain type of
browser we have a smart scoring system
in the in the way that we contextualize
the the code for instance the same
method is getting scored differently
depending how it is correlated with the
rest of the code he so basically there
are these are the set of work of
features militias javascript to shares
this is the first the most important it
has to silently resurrect the the the
user to the export side
the second thing is obfuscation in order
to evade signature detection of the
attack select you selectively execution
is the third feature the late execution
is the fourth feature and here there
what is obvious creation of education is
obscuring of intended meaning in
communication making the message
confusing willfully ambiguous or harder
to understand this is again our example
of woe of the skate with code this is
how it looks totally offer but we can
extract
some very important snippets of
information from this when we the
confiscated is disco'd we see that the
the year they create the the silent
direction in this part they have the
user-agent check here so only if it's an
Internet Explorer Oprah with TV or
Windows it will be exploited here we
have the delay the execution method that
was a mentioning earlier you see the
Creator the greater function that gets
executed after oh one second so that
maybe to deter the analyzes by your
bison boxes that you decided to execute
two after one second
so our feature set basically consists of
sense of obfuscation which can be second
features like instructions like a while
or for transformation features inside
and outside cycles like replace parts
into from charcoal an escape etc and
execution features name namely evolved
also we're looking for direction
features like HTML elements metal direct
x java iframe javascript set right at
the restaurant is a whole lot of
production features we are analyzing for
looking in
also we're looking for unusually large
variable content unusually large ever
content unusually large an escape
content delay the execution instructions
documents of white spaces inside script
code because most namely all the
JavaScript Marshall javascript samples
we analyze or contain like 20 white
spaces
guys were I guess what they were trying
to save space i don't know but this is
the fact that use very little white
spaces know so we're looking for signs
of concatenations which we considered to
be like more than to last science in
close vicinity so we ran a benning's
been scraped through our system this is
the square root it got as you can see
here it have recycling features we have
transformation features but zero
execution features 0 direction features
it has white faces so this would not
raise any alarms but as soon as we feed
our obfuscate the sample of code we see
that second features are 40
transformation features are 100 110 we
have execution features we have
resurrection features we have delayed
execution and no white spaces 08 places
to signs of concatenation here if you
can see we have the resurrection feature
which is a the world I frame inside the
script code which is a very were
alarming side of say we also see the set
timeout here highlighted which enables
the the code to be ran after or waiting
a certain period of time where we have
10 will our large viral content insider
this script code so the big data
processing for for the can as the the
name of of the two we develop basically
starts a multiple agents to analyze the
least given a list of websites the agent
calls the the website and analyzes every
URL found it seemed containing the URL
name and the score for each URL found on
our website is sent to a message broker
the message broker send data streams for
normally that the detection engine the
anomaly detection and uses random forest
machine learning algorithm for my
detection engine season normally the URL
who triggered it is sent to the OGS nvm
sandboxes in parallel formerly detection
was bigger than either samples reported
suspicious behavior HTML page along with
effective script are submitted for
manual analyzes because we want no false
positives and false negatives all the
results are all were no SQL database so
our anomaly detection engine uses a
random forest the regression algorithm
random forests are one of the most
successful watching learning models for
classification and regression because
they combine many decision trees in
order to reduce the risk of overfitting
so they do not require feature scaling
this means that we can add the on
limited set of four of features to our
anomaly detection at engine and the
iight model also do which is very
important
they're able to capture nonlinearities
and feature interactions like how these
a these features arm react in the in the
context of similar or presented features
in the button
we in the analyzed so see also there are
unfortunate set of the decision tree
separately so the training can be done
in parallel for for added speed or the
algorithm injects randomness into the
training process so that easy decision
three is a bit different
combining the bird predictions from
history reduces the variance of the
predictions improving the performance on
the test data 100gsm sandbox we crafted
it very carefully it's a its runs in a
containment environment it perform
static and dynamic analyzes of emulated
code it is the obvious k 2 co 2 2nd as
malicious GS detection scoring system
execute the JavaScript taking care of
certain anti anti analyzes tricks and
follow the directions it rested on the
binary and from this point we perform or
we can safely say there are enough
science to it was a drive-by attack and
the download the binary can be further
analyzed by your own Emmanuel analyst or
human and released or something like
this
ok the vtx and box makes use of integral
equation technology it's something done
from scratch each URL is analyzed by
your multiple vm in parallel each your
machine running the different versions
of browsers and different type of
browsers and the different type of
operating systems or in order to
understand how the the the code is a
reacting according to the to the changes
in there maybe what browsers it to end
the operating system at target so every
every instance uses custom screen sizes
generated the
randomly randomly on the on the fly em
so that the the attacker doesn't see
that we have predefined the screen sizes
so they don't know if you are a human
operator or a little machine analyzing
the the code so it was for animal's
behavior longer than 1 120 seconds we
have 22 minutes when we wait for her to
see the the code does something
malicious or not
also it emulates most movement and the
and clicks in order to defeat the
evasion techniques presented the
presented earlier and more tours all the
system functions not only some or
everything or the the everything that is
happening go in the operating system
after the URL is success including all
the functions success are re reported
and they try to understand the for the
the behavior was the malicious or or
equals false alarms or it needs to be
manually analyzed putin also it the
tracks changes in the webpages analyzed
to see differences made by you by the
attacker to extract the new technologies
of of attack and the methods used the
currently in the in the wild to infect
the unsuspecting users this was my
presentation thank you all
thank you
how do you find the URLs of the websites
that you didn't otherwise we have we
have a feed do we have a partnership
with the Romanian organization that
gives the URLs and takers of domain name
is etc and we will partnership with them
thank you know i am curious about the
precision recall score you imagine that
you have an anomaly detection module
there and you're trained to meet around
the forests and press about the score of
precision recall sorry about this corner
of precision recall her scoring position
is a continuously analyze we normally we
don't have false negatives everyone from
our test the star so to say but we're
constantly upgrading and updating our
our engine so there will be certain
situations when we need to adjust the
the scoring system according to new
challenges and another question i'm
curious about if you tried svm or a
night bias approach in that offer a
random forest or why why choose random
forest or I choose to run upwards
because the who it was a what I needed
for regression are you didn't need any I
don't know world or fancy analyze stuff
for stuff like this
oh I was only needed to see if we
certain methods are are called know
inside the JavaScript and the random
forest it was precisely what was needed
thank you think mama
also the common frameworks the new one
the new ones especially angular and
react
they're basically all of them
obfuscating you actually scan all that
office key code to see ya we analyze the
obfuscated code and we apply a scoring
system those frameworks you you
mentioned or based on oh yes they don't
fall on our alerts on on anomaly
detection or on our scoring system sorry
yeah we also analyzed the base64 and the
also or we will do this step the the
product is in the continuous development
yeah we're having every every minute so
see dude know what do you do with all
the malicious urls that you find how do
you how do you protect people are you
okay you identify all these malicious
urls what to do with them we call
kaspersky on the telephone rings the
next question are you using any kind of
white last thing
no not awkward listing we focus on
finding the set of methods that are
commonly used inside the militias
javascript and the also correlations
between those methods for instance if we
are you have were a coat that the has to
be deciphered the obfuscate the
unencrypted etc it has to run a few
cycles and transformations on that code
even though normal-looking normal
looking good scripts might have this
this kind of behavior or they do not
share the resurrection of features or
the
evolve features and the stuff like this
we don't need to do weightlifting
because at some point somebody could
identify our white least substrate and
the either a bypass it or or contrary we
can block or miss identify or college
teammate to script to as being girl
malicious yes I was rather thinking
about the scenario where the teachers
can my website you'll find a confiscated
javascript over there you have a manual
analyst to look at it
so basically you're kind of spending
money on me and at the end you determine
that this particular script is clean
wouldn't it be more feasible to let's
say take the SHA hash of the file into
put in a whitelist the table since
you're going with big data on the the
database would be rather huge because
making making a hash of each legitimate
the script the with the throw lots of
lots of scripts from google facebook
Carol but we think all the all the
scripts is a an approach i will I
wouldn't take I rather try to see the
behavior of the certain scripts you know
what I mean because the I never like
we're listening
ok thanks