so I'm i'm actually a net or guy so it
took very difficult to follow that
presentation and to go we even further
with my weaknesses
I'm actually not a natural security guy
so I'm just another guy i actually do
Wi-Fi architectures that orange and
sometimes last week at the end my
someone comes to me and save like the
you have to do a presentation for
difficult you have to propose the
subject you have to do the presentation
and you also have to present
ok so I said what can i what can I say
what can I say to some guys that are
expert in security what can i say two
guys that are spending their 80 plated
two hundred percent of their jobs
working on on security so I thought that
I can share with you or what is what was
my challenge in terms of security
what's might what are the challenges
that I'm facing you know developing
services because i think that like it
was mentioned before collaboration and
sharing its the way to making the world
more secure so I selected the fancy
title it's secured the openness the
operator challenge where I just say the
challenges that we are facing that the
operator now is the fact that we have to
be more open to our customers but in the
mean in the same time making it secure
so making them feel safe
what I will talk about it's just
presenting this challenge I already
skipped a beat and told you some some in
the intro i will talk about how water
our services on Wi-Fi how we are making
it secured for captive portal dedication
of sin based authentication you move
over Wi-Fi security what we are using
inverse of Wi-Fi then your service and
how are we localize doing the Wi-Fi
attacks in the
in the real world so we at orient you
have five fundamental values to which we
have to let a treat our customers
because we are service based company so
we have to have some values through
which we guide everything with you you
have to be simple
we have to be surprising we have to be
dynamic honest but yeah the question
comes how can we make this secure
because they have to be simple in open
surprising these are not threats offer
secure network which are not treat of a
secure secure service we live in a
hyper-connected society these are
something for graphics from my group
that internet users spent four point
eight hours online each day on their
computers and 2.1 hours online on their
cellphones so not only that you have to
give us secure service it's actually
that without you have to give a secure
service that the customers are using a
pretty much every hour every hour of
their life so it's not that
ok so we spend the five minutes doing
this we have to make it secure
no he spent eight hours surfing the
internet we have to make it secure
it's letting the service sucks he is
accessing most of them
in the network we leave me no like i
mentioned now we have to make it secure
for our customers but now we are not
living only in the people world is
people internet world we are living in
the connected object world so we have
connected TV smart tvs we have
smartwatches home appliances have
connected cars with your camera's we
have scales I know lots of guys don't
want to have connected scale so they can
tell you online your weight but now they
are doing it we have all we have
connected music players so you
everything is connected now we are not
making the world a safer only for people
who have to make it easier for object or
we have to protect the network from
object we are living in a connected
world that there are existing when
connecting diamonds and they are used by
spice so the BBC reports that the
Russian group uncovered an embedded
Wi-Fi card inside an iron apparently to
the attached to the nearby Wi-Fi network
and the insert the viruses so you see my
fight really great to that even spice
can use it so I think you know about
Wi-Fi some things now I go to into my
let's expertise
it's based on the 802 11 standards and
lots of people see like them there is
the new lower step in the maslow here he
so you have the fish just below the
physiological needs now it seems that
your need is Wi-Fi and it seems that
there is a new even lower my roommate
and it's the battery on your phone i
don't know i don't know about you but
when I am without battery on my phone
died i tend to i'm even more neighbors
that I am now when I'm speaking through
so what's the
your expectation about the Wi-Fi
networks because you know when you are
using a VPN you know you have to be
secure when you are using the mobile net
or service everybody know that it has to
be secure but for Wi-Fi no Wi-Fi
supposed to solve all problems it's
supposed to be free
it's supposed to be open it's supposed
to be always working always fast so
again this is the this was one of the
biggest challenge so how much involved
are we in Wi-Fi internet romania we have
5,000 access points we are handling over
30,000 simultaneous clients around
almost the three 300,000 monthly users
and the average daily traffic it's a
three terabytes we're offering go wife
operate a Wi-Fi operator the public
service that includes decided that I'm
going to talk about offering also
business services both b2b and b2c so
both for business customers or for
businesses that want offer some Wi-Fi to
their clients have business mobile Wi-Fi
where we offer or on-the-go services for
Wi-Fi have business retail analytics
worry do some localized localized
service some analytics based on the
location of the users and are ways of
Wi-Fi calling the service that from my
opinion city really great but you know I
don't know what your experience using
home Wi-Fi for me it's it's the now that
I'm started working but it's much easier
but i remember when i was a college
student that didn't know anything about
Wi-Fi i just know that when the Wi-Fi
wasn't working I just I feel like I
can't see it it's something that I
mentoring and I don't know nothing about
and what I wanted to do is just call
someone say hey come and fix my Wi-Fi so
this
this tranquility that we are trying to
offer to our customers we are trying to
make sure that we are offering the
service and they can use it always and
they can use it you know in a safe
environment so the first challenge for
us when we first started doing the Wi-Fi
or initiative for b2b client was to
create a public Wi-Fi infrastructure
that is secure and easy to connect so
what we created was a necessary idea
network that was open to our customers
so it was not not no password that you
have to enter but then the user will
connect he will open the browser and he
will be automatically really redirected
to a captive portal that like the one
that you are seeing that in the captive
portal there in putting the msisdn their
phone number they will receive an SMS
with their password road directly our
authentication URL they just push it and
they will have automatically
authentication so in more technical
terms and trying to put here have the
Wi-Fi control we have a captive for
portal platform so the device will try
to connect to an HTTP server the Wi-Fi
controller will redirect the traffic
that the tcp seen to the captive portal
the captive portal will then use the use
the existing the connection to
authenticate the user so these are will
use this authentication this msisdn but
for our business clients who have
multiple authentication methods we have
vouchers we have some password and
username authentication some customer
just want to collect collect some data
after that education happened to true
with the captive between the captive
port on the user the captive portal just
indicates to the user or redirect the
user to the controller URL where the
controller URL will
connect the controller the controller
would trigger red used to access request
to the ok so now I see that I their
horses this so this step one when
they're the ridiculous direction happens
then the user authenticates the couple
of Porto the captain photo will indicate
the control URL that the user will have
to access in Step three and step for
direct our address request will be will
be triggered toward the captive portal
platform to reach the captive portal
platform will accept the request of
course the education was performed
accordingly so this is what we came with
its legit standard the connection used
for for authenticating the user / Wi-Fi
it's using lots of places so we thought
it was good so let's see what we solve
from what we had to do and what we are
still have to work so the SSID was open
so the plants could always enter in and
authenticate only one information is
requested on the captive portal just the
msisdn which is pretty basic available
to both mobile and the stop PO devices
on the security part we were happy
it was not an easy task to do that we
could always make sure that the client
that are is using the network it's the
one that is a really having that
identity the msisdn so I cannot say for
i authenticated on it on the network
it must have my permission to use it
because it uses this phone number
verification but we still lacked a lot
of stuff that was required for us
because we had the problem that you know
you have to open the browser to
authenticate and some devices some
devices are just when they see a captive
Natur they just try to connect to the to
the network the network can try to
connect to the the captive portal
automatically but some devices just
you have to open your browser to use it
so that is still initial wouldn't they
are it's not making the customer really
feel like it's an easy night or two to
be used so it's still problem that we
have to resolve and also require some
manual configuration from from the user
has to input their msisdn and self and
also their password after receiving the
pass the SMS another problem is that the
fact that we have to really make sure
that I know that for a security
conference this is a some basic stuff
that I'm doing the traffic with the
captive portal its might not be
encrypted so we have to make sure that
we have a https available server with
domains so we are not the same
vulnerable to some hijacking of our
access points to some it's a black hat
guy i don't know this is the black hike
blackhead know the attacker some black
haired guy can always create an SSID can
create a of captive portal similar to
ours and can collect msds of our
customers wherever they like so the
solution for this is that we inputted
the HTTPS connection or captive portal
so we encourage our customers if it's
not the HTTPS and very fight you don't
to input your msdn there are also the
traffic network is not encrypted so
besides m doing quality
normal stuff using HTTP traffic
everything everyone connected to the
network and or just monitoring the
network would continue your your your
traffic and the like I mention there are
there that type of authentication it's
open to some attackers so we got the
change we have to be more open and
simple and more secure so I said oh
when they said that to me I said what so
you do want more secure even more
security higher security level and
making it even more simple for our
customers so they said yes you have to
we have to do it so from the simpleness
point so what what we saw that we have
to do we saw that we have to automate
the connection process so the clients
don't have to to do lots of steps to
connect and use our the some existing
credentials that everyone for clients
are using already from security point of
view we try to use the wpa2 encryption
and a hundred-to-one x identification
this is the day the most secure
identification and encryptions that are
available in the Wi-Fi world so what we
came up to
we came up to PFC min apo education
education that it's using the same
credentials already stored in your phone
the user doesn't have to introduce
anything just the first the first set up
or what the first the top of the network
just push it
select the network and select a greasy
more APR a que authentication and after
that the authentication will be
automatic
just like in your home wherever we go
and there's orange of Wi-Fi network
there is also the possibility true best
point a technology that we are
supporting that the devices will connect
automatically from the first point so
the actually the user doesn't have to do
anything ever just they are just
connecting mathematical the identity of
the user that will he releases for
performance authentication will be the
emcee that is stored in the in the sim
card and the key that will be further
use for encrypting the traffic between
the user and the network its is
negotiated through the IEP process so
for the security part we are like i
mentioned we are using the
w-who 801 XO authentication that is
using the soup Rican that is the user
the authenticator
that is the Wi-Fi controller for us and
authentication server usury of Tripoli
server the conversation between the the
controller and the triple-a server it's
using the radius protocol that is used
for normally authentication within the
network now i'm going to just go through
the basic steps of authentication so
what happens is the user will try to
connect to the control center identity
then there will be a response saying
what versions are available for doing
the authentication the device will
respond with an ounce an empty and
selective version that information is
transferred a cent further to the
triple-a and it also contains the AMC
the energy of the user so our triple-a
it has to have an inter connection with
HR HR that is storing all the security
inform the security information for
encrypting the trafficking and our 2g 3G
mobile networks so actually they are
using the same type of authentication
and it receives that three plates that
are will be used for for the
authentication I'm not going through all
the encryption details and other how the
Securities happened because it's it's a
little bit long to to go through but
after that the triple-a will retain some
of the information with a generator and
the value and send a challenge to the
controller that will be forwarded to the
to the device the device will perform
the gsm algorithm verifies 80 Mac derive
session key then it will response to
respond to the to the challenge if we
want to authenticate based on some
values like I don't know the user has a
AP env napn that
allows him access to the internet and
allow all only that users to connect to
the network the triple-a will also do a
profile retrieval based on that profile
the tree will give access to to the
client or the further conversation' will
be done on the asian session key are
pretty basically the same it's the EPK
authentication is just a step or skip
some some some of the stairs but it's a
more secure because the AKA will
authenticate both the server and the
user while in the e2e p seemed only the
network authenticate and the lab access
to the users so we are highly
recommending for our customers using APA
ke authentication because it also
authenticates that the network it's the
one that they are there one to connect
so how secure is it we saw that with we
already told that the 801 exit education
it's one of the 61 secure that we are of
we can use on on Wi-Fi network but it's
still there are still some someone of
vulnerabilities that we have to to make
sure that we are they are treated so the
basically protocol is not encrypted so
the exchanges between the APC nak in the
auto communication with the controller
and the access point it's not encrypted
this the MC value the MC of the user can
be a source in by a possible or passive
attacker so for that part the MC
protocol has already created of Sodor
name type of education where the episode
the name is derived by both the users
and the triple-a so for the after the
first authentication the ec is never
exchange between the network or so not
but the passive attacker cannot
intercept the actual MC of the user of
this is the solution but what can we do
we saw that the the devices are
connecting automatically to tormenters
so what can happen an active attacker my
create the same SSID or enjoy using and
request for a full identification ID
from the customer or the solution for
that it's that devices should implement
the conservative peer policy that only
response to the request for permanent
the identity when no sodium identity is
available so even if a passive attacker
will create a horse was an active
attacker create a hotspot for us or the
dividend will ask for the for education
identity the device worry for refused to
answer with a changeup
so this is all for the security on the
on our operator Wi-Fi challenge i'm
going to tell you a little bit about our
way to verify service
what is what the user experience you
just have to enable the Wi-Fi calling
from your device connect to any Wi-Fi
network not our own
of course we recommend to recommend is
our own when network when you are in a
hot spot run into any Wi-Fi network the
logo will automatically change from
voltage voice over Wi-Fi indicating that
now you can place of RFI calls and all
your traffic for VoIP services will be
done through internet now basically what
we are offering in this service
it's just a sip based calling that is
used for for voice over IP services
using our operator is infrastructure the
access to do is secure can i beset
tunnel to the opportunity keep on that
recalled a PG for authenticating the
user and allowing it access to our
network we use I creed two
authentication with the AP
authentication that i just mentioned
above on this time vpg without it will
use diameter interface to connect the
people that is performing the
authentication 930 authentication is
performed there will be a tunnel created
between the EPG and the mobile core
network that will grant access to our
EMS services
the procedure is pretty basic so you
just replace the authentication we take
with authentication but first there are
some more the basically initiating the
messages between any IP second or
creation so the kiosks are negotiated in
the first two steps then there is the
authentication request from the from the
user containing there are during see
then the PDG will use the diameter
interface to to retrieve the
authentication data from the triple-a
triple-a will retrieve the
authentication vectors from the from the
HS s HS there will be the challenge both
entities will perform the AK or a
protocol to negotiate the keys and
perform the authentication then there is
the next step that will be done for or
doing the mobile hankering after that
step the the user can just call using
that encrypted IP SEC time
so what we obtain we obtain that we are
giving making it our voice over Wi-Fi
service our ims services that normally
are available only over our LTE network
we are making it more open
we are making it available over any
Wi-Fi network over any internet axis and
while being even more secure while
encrypting the the traffic through an
ipsec tunnel
so the same question goes for your voice
of Wi-Fi so can an active attacker of
and find the kids in crypto they cannot
find the kids and encrypt and decrypt
the traffic but actually they can do a
passive attack to find out the amsa the
MC the the same value of the user so
actually that the EPG selected to
through the dns procedure so negative
attacker can make a fake free hotspot
respond to the dns equates request or
the fake EPG and get the user inseam
invoice of our Wi-Fi service we are not
using so don't even see it by the
devices there they are not using them
the solution for that problem is to use
the to deploy certificate-based
approaches like apt LS plus the KKK or
multiple you authentication exchanges
some recommendations were also followed
in this problem was also highlighted by
conference is the conference in black
hat london or by some researchers at the
University of funding but you have to
remember that still the information
might not be considered a sensible
information and that information and
alone cannot lead to any fraud or
decrypting the JPC communication so
important that apt will have a stronger
education policy so will not be
authenticate the existing users just
receiving the AMC of the often request
so let's say the there is already 0
tunnel setup then let's say an attacker
will try to or to delete our existing
the user or tunnel the apt and will do
this by requesting a new authentication
using it seems the apg will have to make
sure that it will delete the the
existing the ipsec tunnel only after the
first authentication is performed and
saying this because i was part of some
security auditor on the apg platform
one of the PGM not gonna say the name of
the vendor didn't do that so you can
just that just using knowing the nape
see you can just to make sure that that
user might not ever be able to use with
Wi-Fi service while got are taking it so
what other security stuff are we having
on our Wi-Fi networks Wi-Fi here with
our existing Wi-Fi infrastructure skin
detect some rogue AP and the they can be
classified or using roles like the SSID
the network name the power that we are
using if we want except protection on
this we can put some ap's only monitor
mode in order to do a full-time scan of
that possible wrote a piece also
containment of the rogue AP so what can
you do it's not to make sure that the we
do like a textured denial-of-service
attack for the road a piece we can do
this if you have enough ap's but it has
some legal consequences so actually we
don't recommend doing this what we can
do but actually it's using the location
services infrastructure that I just told
you about that we are using for doing
the business retail analytics it's
actually we are using the same
infrastructure's to locate better locate
the rogue rapier Oh client rogue
interference or attacks and this is how
map can look of showing different
attackers or ok peace or interferes and
what's the matter the magnitude of there
are of their influence also some basic
stuff that our Wi-Fi network it's sooo
of resolving it's we are implementing
the security mechanism called the
management frame protection or the
problem is that the wires management
frames are not encrypted not
authenticated encrypted or side so there
is a combination of vector for exploits
the beacons the program the association
so
the first part that the first messages
can connect to Wi-Fi network the
solution will be to insert the week into
domination frames so the AP can
instantly identify Robo or exploited
management frames
oh so I'm going to go again through for
what
how we started in how what your Wi-Fi
network and how is the the revolution so
we first this is our Wi-Fi network
architecture where the Wi-Fi ap's are
located in the ability customer location
where our location we have the wireless
controllers in our Center site then we
started to perform the the captive
portal to education we added the captive
portal platform with the solution for
just the authentication and its
respective to play for the AFC what
education we use the solution called the
Wi-Fi gateway that and of course all the
Wi-Fi traffic in the triple-a are
further we do we did the retail business
analyst that uses look localized traffic
and it's also used for localized wife a
tax we introduce a new service that
you're gonna hear about is the business
internet security last year that we are
all using it most overall Wi-Fi networks
and the last year also introduced the
the Wi-Fi calling so continue our
journey with orange we are the different
platinum partner but you should check
the business internet security threat
map over this so it in the previous
presentation app to own we have an appt
tone bug bounty you should participate
if you like really like hacking so today
will be with no security features
activated and tomorrow will deactivate
some of the features and some stuff that
you really need to know about is the
Wi-Fi pinboard i'm not one to talk at
all you actually what is it about what
family of you will probably find out
let's hope that the very few of you
ok so my name of my presentation is done
so I'm blood storytime part of the
development innovation team and I want
to thank you for your attention today
[Applause]