testers vs writers pentas quality in
assurance project and we have on stage
Gabrielle tenacity from kpmg romania
though just to
also be sure that it works ok good not
good
it was ok but so after a very technical
presentation will switch to a more
theoretical one and i will make a
parallel between pen test done as part
of a cyber security or cyber maturity
process and some paintings done many
times just to check regulatory
requirement so just a very short
introduction I'm kpmg for almost 15
years and the quite a long time ago I
set up the Penta steam at the beginning
with colleagues from other kpmg offices
abroad and starting to that 2007 setting
up a fully independent Timmy romania i
have a information system or deep
background so i will i will try to put
the dentist in the context of
information system or D and see exactly
how it was implemented in Romania and
make some references to a recent
regulatory requirements
yeah so it was a new new regulatory
requirement i don't want to name it
this can be applied to any security
requirement benign romania and not only
but what is important is that all
through it what it started very well
with the objective to bring security at
the heart of the businesses from the
markets
but from the regulated markets are
combining and then the analyzing the
parties from operational risk and how
the idea is impacted the operational
risk within within the entities and with
some different approach based on the
importance of the entities on the market
it did not continue it the end in the
same manner that requirement asked for
periodic based on the risk category of
the entities periodic information system
already and penetration testing and it
was required that the information system
audit or verifies and describe how the
pen test was performed by a third party
yeah it seems that my animation is not
working but anyway we can we can we can
continue like this so it was a building
ID auditors register and at this moment
there are more than 20 auditors already
in that register what is very
interesting is that some of them
original as individuals
interesting approach how someone can
contract and physical person individual
because there's no mention like a
special our some other type of entity
how they can contract in a different
manner than employing maybe for a
limited period of time but some of the
those auditors came back and also
registered as a company and as an
individual no requirements for the
Pinterest ya comin little bit back from
to the standards and I think that
everyone can agree that real
and the only standards which can be
applied for auditing information systems
and not processes and what other type of
objectives for the audience are the
isaca standards and here they are 22
documents one is the standard and the
other one is the guidelines which define
the way how the auditor should involve a
third party and rely on on that for
party work and meaning that's our
parting being an expert where the
auditor has no appropriate knowledge or
experience the standard define defines
the the statements for this the
guidelines going to win two more days
here that through the slides I don't
like usually with a lot of wording but
those with the the blue
from science before are applicable for
for our case and that they just want two
faces two things the auditors should be
the one who applies for an external
party help and should decide and should
sell at that party be sure that that is
independent that is not not
knowledgeable and can really rely on on
on the work done and of course decide on
further way to report that that
involvement
yeah preferring the the work done better
party or or just including in the in the
report so these these is also strange by
the the guidelines and then provide
informative information how to apply
this type of involvement also the
independence they are to type of
independent requirements organization
independence and professional
independence and while organization
independent it's about in in simple
words about the the auditor of the
professional company not being involved
in any consulting work for that that
company for the audited the personal
independence and for all professional
defendants got it comes to members of
the other team going from standards and
professional requirements to personal
relationship like not having relative
seen in the board of the audit entities
the requirements on on our gratitude he
says that the auditor has to be capable
to prove the independents independence
but in the same time they require the
auditor to review that third-party
report but what if the dentist is not
done by a third party because there was
no pen test on the
performed on the audit entity and the
order includes the Pinterest in the
audit process has the capabilities to do
that by the team members or by someone
as and perform this type of testing
inside the audit and of course the
results are the findings were abilities
and identified without going into
assistance to solve to address those
were gravity's is this is that this a
breach of Independence this is something
that it's from diff from some for
someone it's very clear for others is
not so clear they can say yeah it's a
bit of independence because the
responsibility is the entity the audited
entity to do the pentastar not the
auditor but if there is no pinterest and
the the pen test is done in two inside
the audience what do you think is there
and independence beach
ok coming to third-party pentest we saw
in in our room in our experience in our
projects different approaches their
companies which have a very much your
cyber security testing process and they
are doing pen test for for their own
will to test the Securities status of
their applications their system and not
because someone is asking that and they
are entities which done that for the
first time of interest anyone who'd been
tested can say that in most of the cases
on a first-time project there is no
report with low number of findings and
and the lowest findings
yes and most of them being loaded with
the lowest findings but still we see
such such reports and why do you think
is is this situation lack of experience
or maybe just trying to check a box have
done that and if you as auditory such
reports what we can do you have to take
it because the law says you have to
design the third-party provided by the
company and in the final step you have
to issue an assurance analyst opinion
that that system is somehow secure or
not or compliance with the regulation
but can you rely on such a report what
do you think
yeah but you need to check something you
know in a project where you knew from
the beginning that you will have a
dentist report from from someone else
and you do not play such activities
maybe the audit team which is located at
that project doesn't have someone with
the capabilities to perform somebody
testing on that and of course any type
of such tests have you have to be agreed
agreed and and authorized and so on so
it's not so easy to do dentistry testing
board or check on the spot just before
because its beauty one report which you
realize that you can not rely on okay
what we did we tried before this this
conference to to make a very short
survey and see what what is the the
response or the what are the responses
from different different person
completing the survey we have here some
some results if they the the respondents
said they didn't perform when I ability
assessment or dentist it was closed no
other question where for the show to
them what about 80% eighty percent said
that they did such a such project and
for vulnerability assessment you can see
that the respondents said that it was a
process to do one two three times better
armed parent per year and most of the
projects were done with internal
resources which is actually the easiest
way to do and kind of best practice you
can anyone can can buy a of integrity
scanner for applications or four
network-level do that
have the report from the scanners and
and this is it unless it is a different
the IT department of water security
department of internal resources are
very very limited in that organization
there is no need to take someone to do
this for you
what about pentest so there were three
main category doing penance for once two
to three times or even more most of the
times this project we're done with
external consultants and the reason why
the pen test was done it was for of
course regulatory requirement for almost
a half
yes or other requirements like group
requirements or internal procedures or
or just because they wanted voluntary
what you can see here is that they did
more than half with external consultants
they also did in this case internal
stuff it was also considered like group
entities your group colleagues and with
such a situation as an auditory few
receive such a vintage reports for done
by the group do take in consideration or
not
are you capable to judge on the
independence on the report are not
because students it's a group resource
and you as an auditor have to be
independent and as someone consider not
even do the pen test that you should
somehow rely on something that is done
by group stuff is this independent or
independence beach
I don't know it's still have to be
decided then and see in the future how
this would be treated because at this
moment I cannot provide you a very clear
answer if we take by the standards
you have another being independent you
cannot rely on that if we consider our
regulation in Romania you are even
mandatory to rely on that if the plant
provide the report
yes it's good
the regulatory had the objective not to
put someone to pay twice for a dentist
doing as a their regular process of
cybersecurity testing and also inside
the Nugget it's very true and energy it
was a very good approach and very good
idea not to burden the financial effort
for those those company but still in the
end what an auditor should accept for
for his work and not should not
necessarily be forced by by this even
not in compliance with international
standards other responses
what was the deliverables in addition to
the report and i can i can tell you it
took this very recent from the the
results just trying to gather as much as
possible the answers so it was proof of
concept technical presentation top
management presentation and other and
you can see that proof of concept that
that was a multiple answer possibility
and prefer concept is the the
from most-used case and others actually
there's no other person there's no other
deliverable accept these two types of
presentations and the more they prefer
concept and the methodology everyone
selected of ASP and also we can see that
there is the ice come methodology for
open open open source the system's the
suns and defense security other would-be
also other methodologies here there are
also these accursed question how do you
evaluate the Penta support and I don't
know if you can read
yeah but it's like a debate but based on
the number of reliability identified the
reality is exploited the highest quality
exploited the complexity of the
vulnerabilities exploited so not
necessarily only high risk but how how
it was how easy it was to explore those
based on the recommendation to solve the
vulnerabilities mythology and these
metrics so is expected number of
reliability exploited and the complexity
are the the most
I were selected by the most respondent
so no surprise here
what is your conclusion after report
with low number of finding central disk
if the system is secure the pen tester
did a poor job so you can see there were
a few which stated that the pentastar
the pure job or poor job
yes it is possible is not necessarily
something that we conclude only based on
on this but still there were some summer
ship responding like this so probably
they had more information on their cases
do believe that the third party can
evaluate our pen test was performed only
based on the report and more almost half
responded that yes you responded now
only if the report is huge
no one only the hapless to interact are
exploited and not only identifies liking
in a vulnerability case analysis in case
and if the report it's well-written
interesting response i was expected
almost no one to respond to that within
what does it mean maybe even for this
regulatory requirements someone who her
people who know to write reports to make
references to methodologies I confess I
did in compliance with the vast me as an
auditor or anyone else is a order to
repentance that can say our is not good
because I don't trust us or something i
don't think so
it's a worldwide recognize methodology i
was quite quite surprised by these this
type of response
where it may be will in the future I
trust will be hard and these people can
provide the assurance paper such a
report only on the best support more
than half says yes as an auditor I can
see depends but in many cases not but
still it it's something that maybe in
the future have to be clear clarified
and see how we we can we can continue
this because it everything started to
it's a very good ideas and very good
approach trying to segment the entities
not to burden the little ones and and
based on the various category but ended
up in something that can be not a very
not a technical approach but still just
having a writing team to try to good
report doesn't matter what is in in
those and then you can just take some
some type of an ability described there
and it's written so probably I can
easily say no than yes to design such a
report
as a conclusion or maybe start
discussing oh this is working now the
animation independence is the Panthers
conflicted with the audit service
what is the penalty is part of the audit
usually is not conflicted unless maybe
with the new e order form unless they
are special type of entities listed the
doesn't matter indeed is no point to go
into details now in terms of
Independence and and this type of
requirement but usually Prentiss can be
associated to a very technical audit
reliance cannot replace reliance on a
first-time report of a number of
findings low-risk can assess the quality
of the work done based on such a report
i don't know i can again just to be
positive i can say it depends what I
more attentive to be drastic on response
I'd say no it may be the case is when
you know that team who did that that
project and the only because there is
such a let's say like a situation you
can't rely on our report knowing that
those guys are doing a good job
yeah based on previous projects and and
so on you it may be the case but if is
no such a case can you
I think no you cannot assess the quality
of the work only based on the report and
usually on a pen test even the
the documentation on the back of the
report out the those which is done for
the city for the project file by the the
team it's quite limited is just maybe a
list of that test perform what worked
what didn't work and and this is it
because everything is independent
support cannot replace reliance on a pen
support received from someone that part
even done by the internal group internal
resources from the group again i can say
depends but I'm or 22 say no and it's
not because I negative person is because
if we take the standards and the
principle which represented is the
auditor responsibility to select the
expect to involve where it does not have
experience knowledge and and cannot do
the work and to be sure that that there
was sorry independent out so it's it's
his responsibility
how can the auditor conclude on such
case he can he can say yes it is i have
this report is on that it's okay that
finally it's his responsibility and
maybe he's forced to do something like
this
based on something that is not it and
well in terms of regulatory requirement
and the final point is that the driver
for dentist in this moment as a large
market its regulatory I know and many of
the
the guys doing pentest those companies
which have a process in place and are
doing penance for quite a number of
years
testing every change in your application
of course we are talking about two
important companies and not agree we
start up because for in such cases may
not be financial financial sustainable
but we know a lot of cases when big
companies are doing that as a
cybersecurity process but still those
which are still quite big companies are
doing just to check mark and I know that
also there were incidence not
necessarily going to public in in
Romania but because of this chicks so
I think that we we have few moments and
I the the presentation short hoping that
we can even try to start a discussion on
these matters at this point thanks
so questions or things to discuss
I how do you see in the situation of
outsourcing company with an independent
team of investors how do you see these
working in a company that always has to
be on time with releases for the client
or being at the clients always trying to
fulfill the client needs that sometimes
doesn't understand security at all or
doesn't even care about
ok so for this type of certain companies
that two situations
first of all usually the company's for
the clients that not request like Penton
support is more like a different type of
report is called SI 3402 that reports a
specific report for auditors and it
contains description of control street
or the procedures done and everything
present in the internet in a manner
where you do not disclose as a disorder
any confidential information and one of
those control can be yes been tested
perform regularly so this is usually the
type of report plans are requesting
sometimes there are situations for
special type of clients when they do
request Prentiss the
fantasy points and based on what based
on the example you you mention is that
with a good planning you can achieve
that and I do have an example even not
one even more from from our experience
where we we managed to respond on a very
short notice to such requests and but
from the testing in in in time
yeah and there are a lot of waste how to
that they make their how to make the
arrangements to be able to to respond
for the supplier and estero not only
penta stoop to respond in a very short
notice