that's one of our sponsors this year
Aziz night so thank you for coming and
sponsoring and also presented this talk
so sorry all right yeah good afternoon
guys thanks for showing up to our talk
and everyone hear me yeah thumbs up
right okay well so this is a adversarial
simulation testing its unconventional
offensive breach techniques so
essentially we're not going to be
dropping oday or anything like that
we're basically going to talk through
more offensive techniques that we run
into so just to really go into the
agenda we're going to start with
introductions everyone has the
obligatory of introductions then we're
going to go into a coffee break we're
going to go into an overview we're gonna
have another coffee break I need you
guys had barbecue so that's why I'm
saying this breach simulation why what
it is how does it compare it to
traditional testing case studies and
again another coffee break another
coffee break and that really the whole
deal is ask you know ask you know what
all the questions have fun with the talk
we want to really hear experiences and
things like that as well so when we get
towards the end and we're doing the QA
hopefully we have tons of time for Q&A
we definitely want to kind of have an
interactive conversation so without
further ado my name is chris patten i'm
actually a director for the advanced
services group at fishnet we primarily
focus on adversarial testing so you guys
may have heard it as red teaming might
get into that here and there but
essentially essentially do a blended
assessments so we leverage things like
social engineering physical security
basically logical pentesting those sorts
of things and blend all of these and we
an organization right we don't attack
individual things assets systems we
attack an organization my background I
was in the military so I was I was Air
Force I move to you telecommunications
been in the industry in various
capacities for 20-plus years been with
fishnet for four and a half years and I
primarily just been doing the
penetration testing etc and now we have
this group and damned I have been kind
of traveling around all over the place
public for the last last two years
performing these offensive engagements
like this thank you yeah my name is Dan
Cobin I'm a principal consultant with
fishnet I worked for the team that that
Chris here leads up i've been with
fishnet for about four years been
consulting for about eight primarily
focused on pet testing but you know
we've got more into these kind of
blended assessments we're getting more
demand for it especially with some of
the you know the high-profile breaches
that that we're seeing more of recently
so that's kind of why we've we've
developed a talk I think today to kind
of focus on some of that so okay okay so
really objectives let's define an
adversarial simulation and ate a breach
assessment or breach simulation and that
is kind of what kind of distill all of
this out here momentarily but that's
that's kind of what we want to do we
want to we want to understand what the
departure is from existing offensive
testing and transition that over to
these these more involved breach
assessments contrast traditional
penetration testing and breach
simulation I will talk about the pros
and the cons essentially why you want to
do it why you wouldn't want to do it
really talk about organizational
maturity you probably heard about the
capability maturity model I'm not going
to go much into that but it really does
it does feed into kind of the overall
reasons why we would want to perform a
breach assessment expected outcomes
these are the things that the
organization can actually learn from so
we definitely want we want to understand
some of the items that come out of a
breach assessment that are a little bit
out of the norm that we would typically
receive from s feedback from from
sacristan attrition test or something to
that effect and then really the rules in
a security problem are in the security
of program why we want to introduce this
sort of testing overall into an
organization security program so let's
talk about penetration test
organizations go through they have a
requirement to perform a penetration
test they have a requirement for a
system a host a network they have a new
product that they want to bet they want
to depend test so to bring in a vendor
the problem with the penetration test is
that you hear things like it should be
comprehensive and should target all of
all the things you know all the surfaces
all about all the operating systems
applications that exist on it that sort
of thing it should only leverage one
attack vector so maybe you get in and
that's the only thing you concentrate
what can you get after you make that
initial initial breach once you make
that initial compromise it should
leverage one or all of the attack
vectors maybe they're more concerned
about identifying all of the services
and then seeing if there's motor
abilities associated with both those
services and then attacking those to see
if there's you know see where they can
get rights more of a kind of a
comprehensive approach the other thing
that we we did quite a bit is leaving
the shields up or down so is IPS hids
hits that sort of thing depending on
compliance functions so say for instance
you've got like a PCI assessment right
one of the big things is you know to
perform a PCI engagement they want to
bring the shields down and assess the
underlying vulnerability so they get a
true understanding of the underlying
risk risk exposure or if they leave them
up then at that point you're essentially
testing the effectiveness of an IPS or a
prevention like a blocking system but
you don't necessarily know what the
vulnerability
sure is or the risk exposure is in case
those follower in case those those first
line defenses fall over somewhat nothing
more than domain admin right get in
there get domain admin show me impact
that's it that's what they're that's
what they're concentrated on the
customers concentrated on and then
others will say we want it all don't
leave until you have to get right we
want to we want to own everything right
and so really when it comes down to is
depending on who you ask they have a
different definition of what entrances
yeah you know some some people think
strongly about leaving you know the
shields up you know it's not a
penetration test unless you're truly
simulating what an attacker would have
to you know how you have to approach a
network so this all leads to you a
common problem we have an identity
crisis right and so this guy knows how
to be a hobby kind of awkward so all
right with that we have to ask ourselves
have we evolved so as as organisations
delivering the service and as customers
receiving that service we feel that we
feel essentially by with the services
that we provide and the services that
you know whether this is penetration
testing whether these are wireless
engagements basically adversarial
services there is this perception that
we're providing something with the
client once and at the same time the
client is purchasing something that they
think they need right but we still have
these problems where we're kind of
breeding assumption right as a vendor
we're breeding assumption as a client
you know our as a customer they have
these assumptions as well we market the
material they want that material vice
versa but no one's really listening to
what's going on in
right things that are driving the
industry would be breeches so we have to
we have to evolve we never give up right
so we need to create something what are
we going to create a breach simulation
this is what we want to this is what we
want to address we want to address all
of those use cases out there all those
scenarios where we've got various
breaches going on in the industry and we
want to emulate those those are its you
know advanced persistent threat to use
that cliche that you know buzzword
buzzword bingo solid and gently closed
with bingo so let's let's define brief
simulation real quick and that'll kind
of set the stage on what we're talking
about so a brief simulation focuses on
items or items that are designated as
critical soft hard targets a concept of
chain composite attacks is used
throughout the assessment the CCA or the
change in violent attack provides a
chronology of attack progression from
initial unauthorized entry to final
compromise the events are demonstrating
at CCA so the critical points of
compromise are identified while they
provide relevance about how each lead to
subsequent compromise okay that's simply
just a fancy way of saying and we use
this internally the chain composite
attack what we want to do in a breach
assessment our bridge simulation as we
won identify that first initial point of
entry and when we identify that first
initial point of entry we want to build
those associative relationships so if
that first vulnerability leads to
something else we want to build that
associative relationship all the way
through the entire attack chain and
that's what we're going to demonstrate
at the end right we don't necessarily
care about the breath approach where
we're identifying all of the points of
entry we're only focused on the most
critical aspects of the organization
getting to the things that actually make
the organization money intellectual
property whatever wherever it might be
and we want to build out that chain
composited attack and in the idea the
chain composite attack is
thing too because when you do a
traditional chem test and those of you
who are in consulting or have to write
up reports you know you have no context
when you're when you're writing up the
report itself so you may have an
information disclosure flaw and you
write it up based on what you think it's
actually worth however when we perform
breach assessment and we're able to kind
of chain together all these all this
information but we may find a piece of
information very early on in an
assessment whereas you know normally
would be a low severity type of thing
and it turns out to be critical that
it's exposed because we're able to take
that information coupled with something
else that we found marry the two
together and then it suddenly becomes a
critical finding on our network right so
it's essentially based in context so if
you have a standalone system that's not
connected it might be highly vulnerable
but if it's not connected to the rest of
the network where it's not doesn't
expose a lot of risk then we're not
going to rate that it's not necessarily
a high severity however if we have those
you know we have another system that
might have a lower severity item but it
leads and to you know maybe a unexposed
highly confidential or highly secured
environment that at that point that
severity could increase right so this is
a slide I said slide by HT more each
Moore's law this essentially says it
demonstrates really kind of where where
the skill is where you want to focus
really how different different
organizations are leverage their I guess
where they leverage their focus right
where they leverage their focus on so
we're saying skills first verse threat
actors right okay and this this is when
you have say for instance on to the far
left you have your auditor Assessor
right that's a low skill and it's no
offense to any auditors or Assessors but
you know that's that's kind of where we
live in like a compliance compliance
world as we move towards the right we
start getting into penetration testing
you'll kind of start to see this this
yellow line come down and and that's
fine because we're kind of siloed in
area we're siloed in say for instance a
system a host a particular network and
at that point we're performing
penetration tests say against those
items so at that point you know we have
we're kind of restricted kind of
constraint however we move towards the
right then at that point that's kind of
where we live in a breach assessment we
take more of the organized crime
syndicates more of espionage so far
right there where we have to learn a lot
of this information we have to leverage
a lot of the information that we learn
we have to assess a lot of the targets
but we still want to maintain Cobert
covert operative throughout the entire
the entire engagement to kind of help
that out and to visualize this if we
have if we have an individual like a
traditional assessment say for instance
up in the upper left-hand corner we'll
call that a logical assessment right
that could be again that can be a
wireless assessment that could be a
vulnerability assessment that could be a
penetration test within that that's kind
of a siloed context right you're going
to perform an assessment and you're
going to exploit those vulnerabilities
in a breath breath approach and you're
going to not really have much concern
for all of the rest of those those areas
those circles those physical assessments
those Oh sent recon the social the
social assessment etc right these are
all kind of performed in their own
perspective their own isolated silo now
when you get to the breach assessment
the breach assessment takes in pretty
much all facets of those different
disciplines so we have we have bleed
over from a logical assessment from a
visible assessment from the social
assessment and from ascend Rica and I've
broken them out like that because it's
typically what we run into for logical
we run into things like penetration
testing you know we have system
vulnerabilities we have network
vulnerabilities we have wireless
vulnerabilities etc physical assessments
we have vulnerabilities that are
associated with dwellings maybe security
security folks aren't man 24 hours maybe
they have ineffective entry points
egress points maybe they have you know
ineffective match provisioning systems
so we definitely leverage a lot of that
information and then social assessments
it's essentially the social engineering
aspect maybe we need to make a telephone
telephone pretexting calls in order to
gain access maybe we need to send in a
spear fish you know something to that
effect in order to gain that initial
entry point it's not just necessarily
the entry the initial entry point but
that could happen throughout you know
the entire network chain throughout the
entire composite chained attack now with
the ascent and recon you hear a lot of
folks talking about really you know what
that means so bow set reconnaissance
information gathering essentially we're
going out to public domain we're looking
for all the things that we can leverage
to target an organization whether that's
technologies that have been exposed job
resumes that are out there anything
that's in social media we can build
entire profiles based on a single person
I just did an engagement where I called
into a financial organization I built
the entire profile based on just this
this one guy's social media presence
right and when I called in the right
place to phone pretext call and I was
able to compromise the account three
different ways so it's it's like those
sorts of things that you're able to
build leverage that's good information
but there's only that sliver in the
middle that's useful and that's your
Intel that's your intelligence that's
actionable information right that's the
stuff that we want to look that we want
to leverage the stuff that we actually
want to use in the bridge simulation
that's what we're going to end up
leveraging to actually gain gain access
okay so this this kind of just puts a
side-by-side the traditional pen test
and the bridge simulation we want to
still have to run through all of these
but it just kind of highlights the
differences in approach or the
differences between the two so as Chris
mentioned the approach on a traditional
chem test is a breadth-first approach
right we're going to be comprehensive in
nature we're going to pretty much touch
all all you know in scope systems all
reports you know we're going to test all
the things basically whereas you know
breach assessment is more targeted will
really care we care about it's a depth
first approach we want to see how deep
we can get we don't care about testing
every single host on the network we care
about the one that's going to get us
access right and then beyond that we
care about the the next step that's
going to get us further access you know
we don't care about testing everything
attack vectors as Chris mentioned in
that last slide you know a traditional
test is really logical only whereas a
breach assessment is it kind of Mary's
all of those together let's see well the
ones are probably worth measuring our
worth mentioning so very measurable yeah
the severity measurement the traditional
will use something like cdss right
industry standard whereas a breach
actually uses demonstrated risk so as I
mentioned before you know talking about
information disclosure flaw you know
without context it may be low severity
maybe a three point O cdss core but when
we couple it with maybe I don't know a
physical security flaw maybe the two of
those combine to create a high severity
finding also worth mentioning the tool
sets we use are quite different
contest is really just a laptop and
breach we have a number of tools beyond
just that and then one of the most
important pieces as we've kind of talked
about already up to this point is the
context traditional contest has no
context really I mean you're just
testing you you know you don't know
what's most importantly don't really
care because you're doing comprehensive
type test whereas a breach assessment
the context does matter where you find
that vulnerability does matter
especially if you can use it to pivot
internally or couple it with a you know
another finding so the tool set is that
and I was like yeah we're going to the
bank another another really important
aspect of it is evasive pneus so with
traditionals so traditional pentose new
traditional techniques you might run
into those occasional smash-and-grab
type situations but from the most part
the traditionals are over in nature
right because you're more you're more
concerned about the overall vulnerable
state of those those subjects are those
those items that are subject to review
whereas in breach assessments we want to
maintain complete you know what
agreement anonymous we want to maintain
covert and then the other really really
important part when we are executing
these things and that's for anyone who's
doing red team's or think about doing
red team's compartmentalizing the folks
that know in the organization so you
have to have executive sponsorship
that's critical otherwise the project is
going to go sideways and when it goes
sideways it's going to be a really nasty
thing but so you definitely want to have
the executive sponsorship but you don't
want all of your executives to know you
probably need critical people like me to
your physical building your physical
maintenance if they're on a campus
environment you definitely want those
folks to know at least one person who
now points the best escalation you need
indemnification clauses so essentially
your get out of jail free letters right
so it tells you what's in violence
what's out of bounds your backup
contacts who's going to be performing
the performing the engagement etc these
are all kind of cover your ass sorts of
sorts of things but it's definitely
lessons learned so why would we do the
next slide really why would we do a
breach assessment because in 2014
documented 131 breaches some of them
when we didn't necessarily hear about
and then some of them are big obviously
big targets right we've got we've got
home depot jpmorgan ebay michaels stores
and then you know through throughout all
of those definitely lots of intellectual
property lots of credit cards disclosed
things that can things that can impact
brand defamation they you know maybe
there's not a monetary association
around that but you know if you if you
try to quantify that that's going to be
you know brand detonation stuff like a
bleep into that so you've got both cual
you can qualify those things you find
those things it just depends on how you
truly look at it one of the biggest ones
was obviously target right so there's a
this quite a cannula lessons learned
with with that but all right enough of
my ranking we're going to talk about
some case studies so this is kind of
really where the meat of it is this is
really kind of we've we've gone through
three separate scenarios the first
scenario is more associated with
financial organization the second
scenarios associated with medical
organization and the third is with a
large insurance so these are all big
fortune you know fortune 100 500
whatever companies yeah and we put
together case studies we think they're
kind of maybe the best basis for kind of
studying the advantages of a breach
assessment because we can kind of
highlight a number of findings and
you'll see some repeats between the
three different scenarios we lay up but
we can highlight some of the findings
that you know your traditional pen test
is definitely not going to find and we
can also kind of highlight some of the
points where you know if you're not
chaining together vulnerabilities or if
you don't think that processes you have
in place
important well you know we can show you
otherwise you know these are the types
of things that a breach assessment can
highlight it's not just a cute but they
make the really good stories you'll see
so the stores are very interesting okay
so before we actually get started to set
the context we're just kind of go
through some tools of the trade so these
aren't necessarily standardized tools
that you would typically see on normal
pen tester or normal normal engagements
so with these we kind of yeah so it got
locksmith locksmith inna tools so we
have like bump keys we yeah bump keys so
so essentially we have you know lock
that bump keys those sorts of things
those are basically just leverage to get
past you know physical access right we
run into situations where we need to
bypass the door this might be an
external perimeter door it might be an
internal for might be an internal door
so we need that to actually like gain
gain an initial access in order to get a
logical foothold in the organization we
want to place say Prince with malicious
device right so in that particular
instance we use things like that that's
a poem flood right and it's running a
full version of a full version of Linux
with metasploit on it you've heard of
the Pony Express right right up nigga
cost 14 bucks other advice on my dad box
you can build your own this costs 150
bucks I mean yeah so shoot before dad's
cheapo plug but yeah it's sweet st. just
plug it into the network you know looks
like a power device waiver plug it into
power plug it into a network jack and it
establishes a backdoor connection so let
me have it set up to establish a VPN
connection
to our labs yep cold beat software so
kon boot is one of those and that's a
that you know once we actually do gain
access and these are this is physical
access to the system right and we don't
really what we want to do is establish
that initial Foothill persistence get
out of the building if you stay in the
building too long you're going to get
caught right so we just want to get in
get out so with cold boot software
essentially we can accommodate it's a
perfect example we can actually boot
into the bios boot palm boot kombi will
actually rewrite or patch up the
authentication process and then at that
point we can just log in local admin
without password right and that allows
us to drop drop shell drop whatever we
need to do to establish a establish a
persistent connection the other thing
that we typically do is we we have RFID
badge planners emulators yeah so this is
just a kind of cool DIY Kickstarter
project our fiddler and that allows us
to actually basically clone a vast
majority of proximity carts so if we
have refined badges on employees well if
we find badges that our land around
something to that effect then we can
clone those badges recreate them and
then come back at a later time to
actually be able to gain access to the
building we talked about Road devices
the other thing that we kind of
downsized right we try to carry as much
power as we possibly can without having
a big form factor so we just use like a
little Nexus sentence that are running
colleague Manhunter allows us pretty
much a full-blown version of Linux we
can drop in a shell we can pretty much
do anything that we need to do we have
you know micro USB connectors that
allowance that you can access that sort
of thing that we're not looking around
Mac
around a bunch of extra dinner and then
other things that we end up doing phone
scooping we were in ass first pbx is so
we can actually expand impersonate help
desk maybe we can impersonate vendors
etc that might have a relationship with
the organization that we're attacking so
this is this might lead to initial
football or it might lead to an
additional foothold win where once we're
actually with them you know within the
organization which we have a little bit
of persistence and then finally I think
this is most important one most
important parts is just having having
you know skills in general but software
development skills if if you hire vendor
and they come in and they're like okay
we're just going to run metasploit on
you or something about in fact to try to
get an out bombshell and you expect that
to work in here you're you know you're
pacified with that answer that's fine
but in you know in our experience if
you're able to code and able to develop
your own see two connections you know
back to command and control servers then
you have a much better you have much
better probability of extracting and
actually exfiltrating data and all you
call you know in addition to
establishing persistent connectivity and
one of the things that I didn't include
and the tools of the trade is that we've
leveraged a lot of cloud-based VPS
services so we for our C to server
implementation a lot of times when we're
trying to send shells or send
connections once we've compromised to an
organization will send the shelves out
to these cloud based organizations that
way we can one stand up multiple see two
servers in the case in the event that
actually one does get compromised we can
move into a different region so I think
the pic on digital ocean a lot great so
but digital Asian block r.i.p you know
yeah customers can block our IPS left
and right and just switch instance yeah
right I mean it's a cat-and-mouse game
yeah yeah so like that way like it you
know if we've got if we have an eye
addressing VPS that's in San Francisco
no like okay what would block to you so
we just bounce over to say for instance
you know Amsterdam or over to over to
Germany they just turned up a new
hosting facility in Germany so now like
we can bounce all over the place and the
nice thing is that we can clone we can
clone our bps image and just move it
over we just basically just transition
it and bring it right back up we're back
in business we just shovel our
connection over to the new IP address
and we're good to go and have a nice API
to so eventually we're working on it but
eventually we should be able to do that
probably from a nap or something on our
smartphone so if we're physically on
site and we have trouble getting back to
our current instance we can spin up
another one you know based on just
client-side calls that you know we have
developed and you forgot to mention also
one mobile of the trade that has only
been used once on an engagement is a
grappling hook but it's actually
beautiful only use it once $25 of an
army surplus store that's $25 I've ever
spent I got that call that was a great
call yeah it's okay we need a good no
joke and I was like what the hell do you
need a graph way it was a legitimate
attack vendor and it worked ahem sell
yeah ok so the scenario will go in the
scenario but for the grappling hook was
that they didn't actually like secure
the the the first floor doors were
locked but the second floor they left
the doors unlocked right and there was
kind of like this balcony area grappling
hook right well in the weird thing about
it so the second floor yeah I mean they
have a picnic tables and stuff there was
no way no way up there from the outside
of the building but you could see the
doors from you know the ground level
basically and they actually have like a
deadbolt lock but it was on the outside
it was visible on the outside like you
know why can you unlock
outside there's no card reader or
anything so we could have just gotten a
ladder we could have rented a ladder but
the guy I was working with wanted to get
a VW Bug for a rental car so I don't
think it I calm ladder around hopefully
do things with the crossbow no I've
never to the one I was scared as hell I
was scared as hell thrown nothing up
there but I tell you what the first
throw it was perfect it was perfect but
I couldn't do it again so this is
honoring honorable mention because I
didn't feel like dealing with TSA they
wouldn't know what that is and I'm just
like eh whatever so I don't know there
is the use the company that originally
did this he changed their name yeah
Bishop box there we go so they
originally built this so it's basically
it's a hid hit bad reader right it's one
of the big ones so the ones that are
like out in parking lots or whatever so
Bishop Fox originally built this thing
it allows it allows people to come by
you know like unsuspecting victims to
come by swipe their proximity badge and
then it reads the information off the
proximity badge so you can clone it at a
later date right so you can either take
the tape information rebuild it replay
it on to you another car yeah so you can
replay it onto one of these so this is a
teapot 5x7 format which is a universal
format the other format is q5 key fobs
primarily found in the UK but they're
kind of moving away from that so this is
pretty much primary primarily the format
so this this hid reader you can
basically just place it up against the
wall maybe use rare earth magnets or
something like that to place on a pole
put it out there and as cars are coming
in their swiping their badges
just go and grab it later and and then
you have the information to dump it you
know dump it elsewhere and actually
recreate the cards so we built we built
one of these but we went a step further
and we added more power so it's got a
range of on a little over two maybe two
and a half feet something like that to
to be able to pick those up so you can
actually plan it against the wall and
its people walking through on a hallway
you can pick pick up badge you know
badges that sort of thing it has
bluetooth so you can accelerate the
match data out via bluetooth so it's
just got some it's just got some ideas
there to kind of help us not necessarily
again the whole idea is not be around
while the attacks are actually happened
or whatever try to remain completely
covert and if these kind of out of band
measures are will facilitate that then
by all means that's what we want to bake
into these tools bitch final yeah this
one's walkthrough let's walk through
some of the cases that Chris was talking
about so this first one is a financial
institution they have a lot of existing
security practices in place all of what
you listed up there it's all pretty
standard I mean really so the breach
assessments when we go about kind of
selling these that customers we a lot
most customers who think they need a
breach assessment aren't ready for one
they have to have mature security
practices in place they have to be doing
regular pen tests you know things like
that so I think you'll find that all the
cases that we have listed here they all
have pretty good existing security
processes you know things like de is
they have decent GPO
using tiered callous endpoint security
which is pretty pretty standard and
pretty useless anyway but yeah okay so
yeah and then didn't we on this
particular when we saw randomly
generated domain admin passwords right
yeah so that was for that was for the
tiered on this sorry this is an old this
isn't for the financial institution some
of these listed here this is alden
ignore the HIPAA thing this was for a
different example that we have up here
but so yeah so the initial composite
chained attack vector so essentially
this organization we gained access into
the organization through through the
building through the actual dwelling
through an egress door made our way
through into kind of this protected huge
kind of skype skyscraper type of
building made our way into the
organization and once we were in there
they had pretty much all of the
defense's that you'd expect turnstiles
badge access to doors etc but again that
all fails when you actually social
engineer your way into the organization
once you actually social engineer your
way into organization you're in there
right you're in there and kind of kind
of ready to do do the thing that you're
you intended to sew along along those
along those lines while we were in
performing kind of just going going
through and kind of evaluating like all
of the the different security controls
basically the entire environment one of
the things we ended up doing was doing
an inventory so we walked we walked
through multiple buildings with social
engineering buildings multiple floors so
social engineered our way onto those
floors and we went through with an
inventory checklist and essentially what
we were doing is trying to figure out
how we were going to one get some kind
of assistant access because while we're
going through
I think like the logical perimeter
review if we weren't getting a whole lot
of we weren't getting a whole lot of
leverage by doing that so as we're going
walking through and performance
inventory impersonating employees of the
organization we identified that a woman
had loved a badge unprotected and this
is something that we see right so she
left her badge unprotected on the desk
and in that particular instance we just
took that match right she was away from
Ray from her desk she had what it wasn't
protected on a person and there was a
couple things that we were trying to
evaluate their first was we definitely
wanted to have a useful badge that we
would come in after hours maybe in the
morning early morning hours like you
know 2 a.m. or whatever something like
that the other thing that we wanted to
understand is would they decommission a
badge if it was reported and or would
they be looking for any kind of event
monitoring alerting that would be
associated with a badge that was that
was important missing right so later on
that evening just a fast track we left
because we had this we came back and at
that point you know blink dan was kind
of kind of watching from a great
distance where I went up to the door and
we've swiped the badge to see if we read
gain entry to see if it would call any
of the you know invoke any Security
Response incident response appropriate
protocol would be yes we decommission
the badge but we're checking for those
badges and security personnel should
show up security personnel didn't show
up so at that point we knew we have it
we have an entry right so at that point
we gained access onto into the
organization went through all of the
offices we had access everywhere
primarily went to one of the floors that
we originally obtained the badge from as
we're reviewing another common mistake
surfaced so they had this particular
organization had locked down vdi systems
right they had locked down basically
Citrix virtue
by Stefan that's desktop system so it
was very very difficult to potentially
break out of those but they were it's
not difficult to break out the citrix
don't don't the realm it's that's very
easy but they had written down a
username and password so at that point
we had a working username password we
checked that water on there but because
they were using vgi if we shelled that
box out as soon as we logged out logged
off the box then we lost that shelf we
didn't have privileged accesses and I'm
privileged account so we kind we kind of
rolled in this blended blended attack
scenario so this is a Chan composite tag
thing we have the actual domain
credentials now that you got to tell how
we got that domain credentials so we
were in after hours right and we
actually found the credentials written
on a sticky note that someone's office
yeah did you say that yeah yeah so yeah
that's how we fun so yeah so at that
point I think I had to I think I had to
catch a plane or something like that
yeah it was grinding is like Friday up
and yeah so I was going to the airport
dan fires up since uses those
credentials pops onto their outlook web
access with that puts a malicious
payload sends it off to the help desk
and immediately calls them out and says
hey I'm have it difficult to open it up
the you know opening up this document
apparently convinces the the helpdesk
employ to you open the document it's got
a malicious VBS script on in the back
that's that's a that's loaded that's
going to execute and it's going to fire
back doors into server after some
convincing he gets them to execute it we
have access outbound and the help desk
employee like many helpdesk employees it
is kind of not he's not necessarily run
the VDI system he's running a standalone
a standalone workstation and it's also
running what was it we have it no he had
they had tiered accounts 14
non-privileged like everyday use and
then 14 more
privileged access so like the domain
admins out like a regular you know ad
account plus one just for like their
privileged activities problem that we
see more often than not is that it's
pretty convenient to just reuse the same
password for both cats and that's what
happened ok so now we have we have shell
on the administration box so that's our
first chain right that's that's kind of
our additional chain vector so now we're
going to chant we're changing the chain
composite attack all right so now we
need to because we have access to that
box now we have some level of well
because we have some level of access we
need to establish persistence so we
turned that point you want to talk about
what are you yeah so after we got domain
admin access so I mean we just accessed
a domain controller and interestingly
their domain controllers and servers
were allowed to talk outbound which you
know there's really no reason that your
server should need to talk out over the
Internet so what we do is we established
we basically use Windows scheduled tasks
and just set up like a basically an
interpreter reverse shell to run was it
like eight times a day across three
different domain controller
so we just got get me shells and you
know which is an awful thing to do don't
do it but at that same time it does like
tests to see if they're looking for
anything that's actually aggressive
leaving leading the network typically on
servers you would schedule tasks much
much less you know you might scheduled
task every every few days something that
effect if it's a workstation much more
you want to make sure that you know
workstation traffic is a lot more
frequent especially making outbound
outbound connections you know else work
so they're not necessarily looking at
work state workstation outbound egress
traffic as much as they would be on a
server so yeah at that point we have
persistence and that's why we say
patience is a virtue because we're just
going to sit on these the next the next
slide is basically chaining the chain of
the chain composite attacks so this is
basically taking our initial point to
establishing our persistence outbound
through a critical system and now we're
going to take it to take it to kind of
the final stage where we need to
identify individuals that are critical
we need to understand folks that are may
be associated with physical building
physical security we need to understand
folks that have access to you know in
this particular instance it's it's a
financial organization right we need to
understand how do they move how do they
do a CH transactions etc out of the
organization so we need to figure out
those critical those critical
individuals we don't necessarily care
about all of the the ancillary risk
associated with other things they are on
the environment we only care about those
specific items so we patch up the
network share login script and that way
when they login they're using a amounted
login script so when they log in it it
drops a flat file and it's in it gives
the actual physical machine we have
access to the network share so we can
pick up the actual physical machine we
know there we know they're using in
their accounting now we can redirect all
of our activity are
tension towards those those critical
systems right those systems that you
know if we need further building access
say for instance it's an entire campus
environment but we only have access to
one building now we can target those
those particular folks that do bats
procurement that sort of thing so we do
that we locate building facilities we
locate these are systems of great
importance pretty much and now at this
point if we've identified all of those
we've obtained really people that know
about ACH transfers we know people that
have this tribal knowledge within the
organization that you know we only have
a few days maybe a few weeks maybe a
month etc to understand so we just kind
of fall at that point we stay quiet we
go dormant and we research absolutely
everything that we can and that's that's
kind of a critical it takes the longest
part of the engage yeah that's
nationally just trying to find the
needle days yeah that's not sexy but I
mean that is like fundamentally what I
think overall assessing is it's
basically just research and reviewing
and understanding kind of kind of your
target understand what you're going
after right and in this particular
instance what we're going after is an
infrastructure we want to know how those
systems interact we want to know how we
can export rate money out of the
organization so with that we identify
the mainframes that the mainframes that
basically all the FDIC transactions go
through etc we identify the software
that interacts with those mainframes and
in order not to really truly exfiltrate
that data that's that's the point where
we pause we stop and we get a hold of
the project sponsor and we say hey we're
on your mainframe we have access to your
to your stuff right set up a shell
account for us so that's what they do
they set up a shell account they fund to
that shell account and we've done it
at that point that we can move money
outside of their organization and that's
good enough that's enough to show impact
yeah so that's that's kind of at that
point that that's where that entire how
long would these last about two months
yeah something like that so it's about
two months worth of work to perform this
this sort of attack but it demonstrates
that your typical penetration test or
typical traditional test isn't going to
necessarily identify that sequence of
events that's going to lead up to such a
great impact right that's the stuff
that's actually going to kill business
you know that you disclose your account
your financial data you you believe
money out of your organization don't
detect that that's that's you know
that's detrimental to to an organization
so at that point i think really you know
we we kind of talked to talk to the
project sponsor and you know overall the
outcome is that we want to protect want
to help organization protect those
critical assets those critical processes
and prevent that from happening all the
rest of the ancillary vulnerabilities
than the other things that we don't
necessarily we don't necessarily concern
ourselves during a breach assessment or
each simulation that maybe occurred
variant penetration test those are kind
of off to the wayside because those
might just be another point of entry to
get to the same destination that we got
to so we want to protect we want to help
the client protect that most critical
process most critical piece of data
lessons learned on that was that
incident response was inadequate they
did detect our presence on the network
at one point we as when we're physically
on site we plug the laptop into their
network this was after we stole the
badge went back on site at like 2am
plugged a laptop in Reineke port scans
to seal it you know what was there
whatever they detected the laptop you
know it was an
authorised device on our network they
dispatched somebody but they dispatch
somebody from the information security
team who lived 45 minutes away so you
know why why would they dispatch someone
who lives 45 minutes away why would they
dispatch an infosec person when it
probably should be someone trained to
deal with a hostile you know individual
you know depending on who it is so
things like that you know your pen test
that's a process thing yep in effective
v breast controls why are your critical
servers talking about you have domain
controllers you got databases why are
they allowed to talk on there's no
reason for that so yeah that was that
was interesting password were used
between tiered accounts there was no
identity and access management there was
no you know there really wasn't no
protection prevention from from someone
establishing a lower lower privileged
privileged account to a higher you know
higher privileged account and reuse that
password single factor off on both the
outlook web access and on applications
again these you know would complain the
first things that we do is we try to
compromise the actual email systems
right because email systems are critical
intelligence is critical surveillance on
what we're going through you know as
we're kind of moving throughout the
entire attack sequence we want to
understand what they've detected we want
to understand if they've dispatched
something to like mitigate our attack
whatsoever to maybe block us to notify
whatever we don't care will hack the
internet are the instant messaging
systems will hack the email if you
protect it with a simple user name and
password we're going to get the password
work on it we're going to basically just
squat on those systems and intercept
traffic we're going to identify your
again that's the real reason why we
target building physical security
because we want to understand that it's
the reason why we target infosec folks
because we want to understand what
they're doing is the reason why we
target information technology groups
because
understand that as well as all the rest
of the the folks that have the again
that intrinsic knowledge guard stations
physical badge on security so these guys
leave at a certain time of night and
they just leave it all you've heard of
cleaned US policy some of these guys
don't believe in that so they just leave
everything just kind of kind of laying
out or they'll take all the badges and
they'll throw them in a drawer and then
well they won't walk right they'll just
leave them or they'll just to put them
in some kind of minimal security
enclosure right that we can get to quite
easily right and it's just kind of out
there and open yeah what he didn't say
is we also stole let 20 vendor badges
straight out of the security guard desk
get one tonight yeah so and then you
know we have that adequate social
engineering challenge and we have weak
password policies so these are the
adequate social engineering challenge
thing that's kind of hard protect
against right there's a heart it's it's
difficult to meditate that but the weak
password policy if you got weak
passwords that's that's kind of first
defense right you need to employ
something that's complex and preferably
some kind of multi-factor authentication
we're running out of time to endless
bass track go to 3 here it comes time
again yeah let's just do three but if
you want to open up oh yeah that's good
okay so yeah so we'll jump into this
case so similar along the same lines was
kind of run through the whole attack
scenario so this was a large insurance
company again they had very good
existing security policies including you
know authenticated outbound proxy
network segmentation
most of this is pretty standard but they
actually have really good egress
controls were like none of their servers
were allowed to talk outbound so they
were actually doing that right and they
also had a very good physical security
we'll get into some of this but they
have turnstiles pretty much every point
of egress point in the building even
getting up in and out of elevators I
mean every floor had turnstile so if you
didn't have a badge then you probably
weren't going to be able to tailgate in
or anything like that let's see so we
kind of knew about their physical
security before we set foot on site so
while we were doing some of the the
remote testing you know the question
kind of loomed as we were kind of
planning our on-site portion of it you
know how are we actually going to get in
physically you know when we do these
engagements there's almost always an
on-site and remote component right and
so to fully test an organization we feel
like we have to have like a legitimate
attack vector in both so you know that
was kind of the question when we go on
site are we even going to be able to do
anything so we weren't sure so we
actually attempted three different
spearfishing campaigns initially so it
netted us two sets of domain creds but
they detected us fairly quickly with the
domain creds we got access to Citrix
environment externally that was using
factor off but they detected it quickly
they killed our sessions and I actually
force the people to change the passwords
but what this actually told us is it
disclosed their password policy it was
weak it was like you know six characters
something like that so what we were able
to do is kind of take that idea and to a
password guessing attack against one of
their authentication portals based on
like a you know a six character password
policy and so what this did you know
this was we use you know common you know
common pattern is to use like you know
the month followed by a year so if this
in this case it was like jam 2015 I
think we chose and we just ran it across
a number of different users it also
disclosed their their user account
aiming system so they didn't use like
first initial last name they use like a
predictable type semi predictable you
know alphanumeric template yeah it was
kind of alphanumeric it was incremental
you know so you could kind of iterate
through them and try to guess so you
know we just ran a password guessing
campaign using that password in it got
us I don't know 6 10 different hits so
we were back in in this time since we
didn't have to do a spear fish attack
they didn't detect us so we had access
to citrix we broke out citrix and you
know from there we we noted that one of
the credentials that we had pulled one
of the groups that have belonged to in
Active Directory it was listed as like
the machine name underscore admin was
the group's or like as an admin on that
box so we authenticate as that user to
that box and sure enough he was local
admin so you know we get system we
dumped the hashes he's using mini cats
if you guys used that so we dumped the
creds and on there was domain admin so
just like that we have a domain app yeah
so next slide okay but like I said they
had a really good egress controls so we
had to pretty much tell all our traffic
through
Citrix box expanding the network
presence was a little bit challenging
for that reason so we couldn't really
bounce around like we normally could
because we couldn't establish remote the
you know reverse connections but what we
were able to do is you know through that
access we were able to actually browse
network shares as domain admin we
bounced around and expanded our
presidents pulled other domain and
domain admin passwords and things like
that just so we have you know a better
foothold on the network and we did
things like from network shares and this
is pretty common you know we just looked
at an HR Payroll network share and we
pulled files that had all their
employees you know pay information
social security numbers since like
pulled customer details so we don't
really know most of it meant quite
honestly because it was insurance and
it's insurance but you know it looked
like it was in the sensitive nature and
so most importantly we spent a good deal
of our time actually focusing on recon
so we started targeting the actual
facilities folks from the network shares
we identified the name of their badge
provisioning software as well as their
security camera software we got access
to their security cameras remotely so
this is how we knew about their physical
security presence before we set foot on
site so we're looking at cameras in
their lobby more knowing all the turn
styles everywhere we noted that they had
a 24-hour guard presence right so we
were going to get in after hours and
walk right past the guard desk there was
nobody there but the guard
like we're going to see by it so that's
that's how we kind of wondered so we
spent a good deal of time actually
focusing specifically on weaknesses or
gourd you know how we could we could
actually provision our own badge so one
of the big things that we ended up doing
was you know I talked about gaining
access to webmail right once we
identified that there was a physical
security person and we understood which
system that that he lived on also gained
access to the web mail and then spent a
good amount of time rifling through and
just reading absolutely everything doing
targeted searches so we knew that we
knew that they did bad provisioning but
we wanted to understand specifically
what that meant so we've got the reader
types we got the badge types we got the
provisioning details for the badge we
knew that they had a certain facility ID
code associated with the badge we knew
that they paid extra money to hit to to
get Christian keys we had a wealth of
knowledge that we can leverage kind of
going into all of this and we didn't
actually have the equipment to create
our own badge for the specific type they
were using so we're kind of screwed in
that nature so we're kind of you know
Dan you can't create our own so you know
what's the alternative so we actually we
gained access to the badging software
remotely before we set foot on site as
as like their facilities manager the
problem is once we actually got on sites
our plan was you know we have access to
this badging software what we'll do is
we'll take an existing card that we have
that was kind of the same type we'll go
scan it or whatever and just capture it
in the system we can go look at the logs
in the software and then basically add
it as an authorized cart that was kind
of kind of our level of thinking there
were some limitations to that where we
wouldn't be able to get access to all
the floors that we wanted to because you
know you could only add a certain number
of card types for floor so we didn't
know if that was the route
to go so we had access we went on site
in the leg art well at least we have
kind of a foothold we have an idea of
something that we can do the problem is
when we got on site we no longer had
access to this this user's account this
the facilities manager he changed his
password there were a couple of
incidental things that we we could no
longer get his password through the same
means that that we had so we went to the
domain controller and we performed a
shadow copy of the NTDs did file tried
to extract it problem is extracting it
while tunneling everything through the
Citrix server was incredibly slow it
failed multiple times so I mean we were
kind of you know out of luck doing that
remotely now we found a different
weakness that normally you wouldn't
think is necessarily a big deal but
their wireless signal bleed was
incredible I mean I'm we're talking like
two blocks away from the facility you
have full wireless strength to their
their corporate network so we went sat
at a starbucks one night and downloaded
the file in 10 minutes time you know
like as Starbucks was closed and we
downloaded the file then you know we
used the entity is that hit file crack
the passwords got the guys pass we're
back got access back to the badging
software so again you know we we
exploited like the wireless signal eat
something you wouldn't normally consider
as a big deal to kind of gain access
also what we were doing info while we
were digging around their network shares
and and their email we actually found
documents about their processes for
issuing badges to employees who had like
left of my own and the interesting thing
is okay so they required like three
pieces of information so you know
employee shows up two words i love my
badge anam nice Union temporary badge so
they required the employees name their
network ID and also
there they validated a picture in the
software that we had access to they
validated that picture against the
person standing in front of them and so
yeah you don't want to go with this so
what we did two o'clock in the morning
picture him is fantastic he looks like
help like a wish cosmic yeah and we were
out drinking before that so it's like
two more than that was a good idea to
take this picture oh yeah you know you
look professionals like your first day
of work there yeah so we take this
picture and we actually figured out
where they store all all the employee
photos and we just randomly picked out
an employee and like our you're going to
be this guy for the day we put his photo
in there validated that it was his
picture when he pulled up and we're like
okay yeah so you're just gonna walk in
tell the guard your this guy and you
know see if they'll issue you a
temporary badge once he gets a temporary
working badge I mean it's game over we
have access to the software and we can
grant it God rights to the entire
building and stuff right so just you
know to make it more fun i sat at the
starbucks next door because of the
wireless signal bleep oh no yeah so part
of the process that's been the issue
well let's talk about like the reason
why we had to give a bad real quick so
the badge the facility code on the magic
of its proprietary we couldn't recreate
the actual I class badges that they were
using and the actual readers that they
were using would only allow and because
it was like a multi-tenant building they
could provision up to eight separate our
individual facility ID codes and then
after that you can provision anything
else so you actually had to have like
one of their ballot matches or Chloe
ballot badge with about a facility code
now because they were all maxed out if
we drop one of the facility codes
associated with an individual reader
that means that we're performing the
denial service essentially on the tenant
no one's going to be able to get into
into the building via that so that's
definitely going to set off a lot yeah
so that's the reason why we needed an
actual badge we needed an actual I class
batch with a facility code and also we
noted from the documents that we were
looking at for provisioning that part of
the processes when when an employee's
issued a temporary that they disabled
the employees previous batch right and
so his badge won't work until he returns
the temporary badge then they ran able
to write it's just so that he only has
one working that at any given time and
they also had a note in there saying
that this employee was issued this
temporary badge well although so anyway
he walks him into up to the garden and
tells him that you know he left his
badge at home and would make sure that
we did this first thing in the morning
before the employee got got in you know
we didn't want to raise any alarms or
whatever this employees in the building
trying to swipe and he just can't get
anywhere you know because it's
temporarily disabled so first thing in
the morning 730 or whatever he walks in
goes and explains to the guard that he
left his badge at home sure enough you
know he gives he gives a fake name and
the the the LAN ID account that we knew
and then they validate the picture again
picture that he looks like hell in yeah
so if I yeah so before so this is kind
of a social engineering aspect of it
right so when I when we took the picture
i look like hell i've got a full beard
right I've got like 2am bags under your
eyes yes yeah it's I give a showered 19
days yeah so so then when I walk in I'm
you know dressed in
really nice business attire right I'm
clean shaven it looks like it gives the
impression that a lot of time has
elapsed right so that was back when you
know fact when I first started rears
back when i was at boeing i got my first
job out wherever and now at this point
you know i'm an actual respectable
person working in an insurance at a
company so it was it was very it was
very good believable so he gets issued a
temporary badge just it worked out
flawless like right so he's in there for
all of a minute gets the temporary
working badge you know walks out of the
building he comes over to starbucks
before i even have a chance to like open
up my laptop I'm like your back all
right it's like yeah they think they got
me the badge so I'm working frantically
you know trying to reenable this other
guys badge before he gets in so I get
the bad jury enabled and then he's like
our long ago test it out so well Irene
able the other guys badge you know
remove all the history the note that was
added in there so there's really no
record that the second batch was
actually issued to this guy you know he
just walks into the building and you
know authenticates to the turnstile hops
on the elevator goes up with 20 context
you know floor and walks around so you
know at that point it was a weakness in
their process you know like how do you
validate an employer left his wallet at
home you know you can't show you
government ID because he left his wallet
well they need to think of a different
you know validation means you know
somebody has to look at you come down
and escort you or something like that so
and the more the story is it's that as
it's just that
oh yeah so this is yeah just kind of the
review you know some of the findings
that we have we're running out of time
so we will go over these but you know we
talked about these and some of these are
repeats from the other scenario we
talked about so you'll see common
threads are really single factor off we
see that it's one of the most standing
issue so that kind of leads to the next
slide I think yeah we can't compile the
list of you know what i like the most
most serious flaws that we actually see
and you know if you can fix one thing in
your organization if you could dedicate
you know money to like one thing well we
would probably i would probably push for
two factor authentication like
everywhere nothing realistically I
happen but you know what I'm saying
improper egress controls on servers
outbound those two things alone I think
would make our jobs a hell a lot harder
and you know in spending money a lot of
times for organizations so you don't
have unlimited amounts of money right so
you just try to spend enough money that
you can delay an attack or long enough
that you can detect you right that's
kind of the goal that's the work that
that should be a realistic goal so yeah
so reasons for a lot of these
vulnerabilities will just shoot through
these real quick mergers and
acquisitions people people lose track of
their with a trap what the question what
they truly have in their environment so
through through merger and acquisition
they obtain a whole lot of different
assets different resources and they
don't have a good inventory right so it
introduces vulnerabilities in effect of
asset management they just don't know
what they don't know so they don't
perform asset management or asset
inventory throughout the entire
organization they have they have
outliers they you know don't know that
they have you know servers that are
controlling a sprinkler system elsewhere
that's actually still connected to the
network ok it's just introduced a
vulnerability employee turnover that can
what happened you don't maintain that
continuity when you have a dedicated
employee and that employee leaves and
you have turnover we kind of lose that
tribal knowledge that then but once once
had right disparate change management
processes so you might have good change
management new window systems but you
don't have to change management on your
you're Nick's environment you don't have
a good change management on your network
elements your switches your router's
your DLP devices it doesn't matter you
know it's just you have all of these
these kind of answer devices out there
what Dan was just talking about
inadequate budget so you just don't have
the budget you might not have the sea
level support you might not have the
support from board of directors to
allocate funds associated with upgrading
security that's a that's another thing
is just no executive support you can't
get anything done if your team doesn't
support you I mean so if you're trying
to make big purchase trying to try and
mitigate risk and you don't have the
necessary means you're kind of I
look so lack of trained skilled infosec
pros we know that is definitely a
problem in the industry can't get enough
skill skilled resources that not only
are skilled can talk technical but can
also groups that gap and understand how
to adequate business acumen to be able
to talk to you numerous numerous target
audiences and if it's not a priority
that's going to be a problem so I just
hope the lawyer lawyer up and get lots
of errors and omissions insurance
because that
that's going to be a problem later on
down the road and I think one of the big
things that can point to evangelize
really kind of what a security vendor
does in that entire relationship is to
use it as a vehicle to to help help
obtain your agenda right so if you need
more funds leverage your security vendor
to to kind of direct their attention
towards those things that are critical
that impact the organization help them
help you build a case so you can go back
and you can get the necessary a lot of
times we actually get requests I mean
the issues that maybe we wouldn't call
out specifically or make that big of a
deal the customers will ask us so can
you highlight that we've been pushing
for funding for that can you highlight
it yeah yeah you know we have no problem
doing yeah it helps most bang for the
buck yep I didn't and this is kind of
just reiterating that but I think so
some of the the most critical things
that you could probably put in your
environment that I think that would make
our job multi-factor authentication and
authentic and outbound proxies egress
controls this is identifying your
critical servers that shouldn't be
talking about bounce securing your BIOS
not prevent devices from connecting to a
lantern Wi-Fi that would prevent us from
actually gaining passwords and you know
going to starbucks and authenticate you
and being able to compromise your
network monitoring alerting and auditing
a batch provisioning that's another big
thing obviously because then at that
point when we deactivate an employee's
badge re reactivate
reprovision we change privilege levels
associated with a badge all of those
sorts of things should trigger events
and there should be investigated and
then critical file integrity checking or
really some of your most important your
most important resources on zipper
instance servers and things like that so
if you know that you've got transaction
software that may be moved money into
you maybe another batch process or
something like that you definitely want
to implement integrity monitoring
because if someone comes in there to
change it changes the hatch the the
overall signature of that file you want
to be able to fly on something like that
right and we're going to have questions
where ya at a time I'm Amelia depa so
and that's that's it that's cute I
opened up the chumosh ok any questions
comments yeah
yeah they were using people yeah yeah
there's peep it was a famous people we
have domain prints I mean at that point
so I think just weren't doing any kind
of like clients or validation right
anyone else all right