thanks for having me I'm Ben Johnson
here to talk to you today about modern
cyber defense the new buzzwords that
matter we all probably are sick of
buzzwords but they do have their place
excited to be here is my first time in
Des Moines my wife's actually found
Dubuque so I go up there once in a while
but I've never been over here a good
friend of Ken's there I'm not the
Sprinter if you're familiar with 19 88
Olympics with the Sprinter who did drugs
and lost the gold medal but there you go
so you know try to keep it moving pretty
quick I know it's early it's eight
o'clock or 20 or whatever now but please
make it interactive so I also want to
say this is the first time I've done
this talk I just through these slides
together for this presentation so I
really want feedback I'm excited about
it but it is the first time so you know
there's always tweaks that kind of stuff
so today I just want to go over uh you
know just some stuff that you can take
away right I do work for a vendor this
is absolutely not a vendor pitch so
we're going to go through goals real
quick i'll tell you a little bit about
my background and maybe you know why you
shouldn't just you know run away
screaming saying this guy's an idiot
we'll talk about those buzzwords and
then takeaways so the goals I want this
to be interact with if you have
something to contribute something to ask
please do so and I also want you to do
some contemplation some thinking how in
this apply in your environment some of
the things I'm talking about are
probably years of years ahead of where
your companies are or at least you know
it's just going to be really hard
logistically to get there I hope not but
you know a lot of what I do is talk to
companies and I know it's a hard problem
to get you know funding get IT on board
that kind of stuff so my background I
started at NSA on the left here NSA and
man tag after going to say I did some
work for multiple three-letter agencies
and Department of Defense that's why I
wanted to
in text so I could do more than just NSA
I put it in red because I was really
doing offensive things stuff that I
would have done for free but I happen to
get paid for it and by offense I mean
use your imagination but stuff that took
executive orders to be able to do now
because it requires high levels of
approval you can't really do that in the
commercial world so as I started moving
through my career in to Kairos um you
know we started doing more defensive
things rying to stop foreigners stop bad
guys we came up with the idea for carbon
black formed that went through the whole
roller coaster of building a startup
getting funding and then the you know
selling our company's a bit and now at
bit 9 i'm chief security strategist
whatever that means but basically i kind
of act like a CTO I travel around a lot
i did 40,000 miles in the first three
months so i'm on a lot of planes i got
platinum status already but I meet with
a lot of customers a lot a lot of
high-tech companies every vertical
Energy Finance Silicon Valley I spend a
lot of time out there so I hope you have
some good QA because I've talked a lot
of really cool companies I went to UC
and Hopkins in case any of you have
connections there I always liked
building relationships please if you
feel like there's any value to AUSA have
a relationship add me on LinkedIn or
follow me on Twitter so does anyone
think we're doing a good job did anyone
think we're winning how about that one
all right so we're on we're on the same
page so you know there's this thing of
you know cyber resiliency being able to
withstand an attack you're basically
taking a punch and keep going um you
know a lot of problems are also when
we're doing monitoring when we're doing
incident response we're doing cyber
defense there's a lot of thinking like I
think this is the case or I think this
is malicious but not a lot of knowing so
that's another problem we also have too
much data you know alert fatigue just
you know millions of alerts millions of
events that kind of stuff and then how
effective are we as humans security is
about human
detecting and responding to breaches
with tools to support you right it's not
about technology doing all the work it's
about humans doing work and hopefully
being more effective because of
technology so it's something to think
about so the first buzzword and this is
actually multiple words right but risk
hunting so is anyone here doing threat
hunting okay maybe a little so it's
right hunting is a little bit more
advanced where you're not just you know
responding to alerts you're not just
looking at a sim you're not just
scanning for IOC's you're actually
mining data actually hunting but my sort
of passion here is we got to move beyond
threats we got to move to risk risk is a
higher level concept and friends right
risk is actually threat plus you know
what's vulnerable what assets do you
have what are your countermeasures we
got a thing about risk so you know when
we're too focused on compromise and
things like indicators have compromised
you know we typically aren't really
focused on improving our posture we're
trying to put out the fire as fast as
possible trying to clean up and just get
back to the next alert but we're not
really focused on where the problems
will be focused on where are the bad
guys now or even just mass malware that
kind of stuff and that's too hard to
keep up there's too many bad guys and
it's a lot harder to know what bad
behavior looks like then what risky
behavior looks like because of intent I
can say you know what this guy keeps
being the first one in my environment to
hit new domains or to install software
okay that's I'm going to define him as a
risky user but malicious or you know bad
behavior is much harder to define it's
like credit card companies how do they
detect fraud they don't look for bad
they look for known good like a fuzzy
box and then once you're spending goes
outside that box too far out of your
profile you know they profile all of us
then they call you and they say hey are
you actually buying something for a
dollar in Singapore or whatever right so
we have to think about that as we're
doing our strategic planning
also our off day to day operations and
there's this notion you've probably
heard it if you read blogs or talk to
analysts a lot of times with a
firefighter in the cyber defense world
right something's going on we're trying
to fix it but now we're trying to move
to the beat pop who is also responding
to 911 calls you know cyber incidents
whatever but he's also out looking for
problems getting to know his environment
write anything about the county but we
can't stop there and this where I'm
talking about risk we got to move to a
fire marshal as well fire marshal is
going to go and say you know what this
structure this is going to cause
problems or if this thing breaks right
here it's going to collapse enjoys
people think about that in your
environment if something gets
compromised some part of your network
some segments if this machine is hit
what can have think about risk so you
know just to give you a few concrete
examples here and I already mentioned
some of this what users are being the
first to hit a domain you've never seen
before who's opening all these
attachments what happens if someone just
walks into your company and plugs into
the wall what access do they get a lot
of times the security team doesn't know
and you know we've done back when we did
some end testing commercial work we
would just go set up an interview and
then say we have to go the bathroom and
then just plug something in the wall and
say oh I don't feel well I'm leaving we
literally did that all time do you know
what access we would have maybe maybe
not oh we're you know where the
misconfigurations you know there's
plenty even with a small company there's
plenty but large companies are chaotic
you know organic environments and
ultimately oh yeah this dot works but
think about what can an insight or do if
they're on this system or else on this
system or if they have access to this
data what can they do that's where you
really have to focus your your attention
because the bad guys will become
insiders they'll get credentials or
they'll land malware you know just one
little phishing email and they've
parachuted over your perimeter if you
even have a printer so you got to think
about that so we have to detect and
respond quickly but we want to get ahead
of the game we can't keep off we don't
want this anymore we don't
bombardment right just getting crushed
by bad things and oh by the way a lot of
companies don't even know probably you
guys have seen this like you don't even
know what's going on cuz you want the
visibility right so you're probably
getting crushed in it's like you don't
even know that you're being bombed but
we don't want this to happen so again we
want to be able to conduct risk hunting
that's where we want to get to so a
couple other buzzwords I'm going to talk
about are trying to get you there
because how can you conduct for hunting
if you don't have time if you're too too
burdened with the number of alerts the
number of fires to put out false
positive except you could never even
think about or something hardly anyone
raise their hand of the threat hunting
and to me that's not even advanced as
risk hunting now risk hunting is part of
compliance a little bit but it's usually
not a very active ongoing thing you know
to me risk hunting is you can take a
person in your environment and they go
and look for a Miss configuration or you
know machine a should not talk to
machine be and as soon as they find that
you act as if that's the compromise you
say okay crap what if someone exploited
this go to an instant response I hope we
get there not many companies are doing
so buzzword number two analytics this is
really hot buzzword right now it's not
necessarily new but it's it's it's much
hotter 24 2015 that it was 2014 2013
going to RSA tomorrow for the week I'm
sure every company is going to be saying
analytics right and analytics there's a
lot of definitions for it you probably
have your own thoughts I have my own
definition which isn't necessarily the
same as you but I think you'll
understand what I'm talking about so
what is analytics lots of things right
like I just said but to me it's
extracting data extracting extracting
value extracting intelligence from data
from relationships along that video
right but really when I boil it down
it's about comparing current behavior to
historical behavior and comparing car
against other current behavior and you
boil it down even more it's about
finding things signal versus noise
where's the signal in this noise and
when I talk to some customers especially
the ones that are kind of have their
stuff together they're actually trying
to figure out what story does the data
tell where do they have to apply their
resources where does their budget need
to go where does their strategy and
planning need together what story does
your data tell and analytics also that
so when you talk about analytics and
comparing behavior comparing events if
your environment is like this versus
this guess which one's a lot easier to
do analytics on not this what's normal
where's your baseline how can you find
anomalies how can algorithms pick out
what's normal how can even humans pick
out with some and I was just in India
and experience this yes um so you've got
to think about this you got to work with
IT you gotta lean on IT to clean up your
act you know base images network
segmentation all this simple stuff which
I know is not simple in practice because
of merger and acquisitions as new
machines coming online you got to get
the you know ship a product or keep the
keep the lights on or whatever I
understand but you've got to at least
try to get here so to give you a few
examples of what I consider just simple
analytics people might not even call
these analytics but I do are you just
recording every time net dot exe is
month or something similar that might be
abused by a bad guy and probably not use
that often in house are you watching
when PowerShell is being used even
simple stuff like are you mapping which
user logs into which machine why is it
only admin on that HR persons box well
it's probably not the domain admin it's
probably some bad guy and then other
stuff too like is it Dropbox that makes
zero
or is it some unsigned binary running
out of a temp directory named XYZ exe so
there's a lot of stuff to think about
but some of this stuff is really how you
catch malicious humans and you know
malware too little is just humans and it
comes down to you know visibility in
analysis you've got to be able to see
these kinds of events or this kind of
data before you can start pulling out
anomalies looking for patterns comparing
behavior if you don't have any
visibility if you don't have any data
you have nothing to do with analytics
right and so real quick this is a
passion lines a whole separate talk just
on advanced threat hunting but the bad
guys truly live off the land and what do
I mean by that well malicious humans
especially an especially like
state-sponsored or advanced you know
like cybercrime mafias that kind of
stuff they get credentials and then what
do they do they live off the land they
use FTP they use PowerShell they use
command shell they used robocopy they
use all these tools that are building
that's just windows mac and linux other
other unix style systems have tons of
utilities they can do everything you
want compression you know SCP all this
stuff they don't need to drop malware
fit its log in and use signed and
Microsoft or whatever Google whatever
binaries that's how they do their job
and there they do it well so they blend
it target everyone still likes picking
on target you probably can't read this
but attackers mostly use general IT
tools procedures and protocols seldom
did they use hacker specific tools and
malware now they put up RAM scraper
malware or whatever but it got on all
the machines through the the system
administrator tools the software
distribution okay install this on all
our point of sale systems and then
collect the data and then just use FTP
to go out it's literally ftp all your
very eyes so it's occurring all tom and
analytics right
just show me where net dot exe is
running and the command line okay all
this crap that's not useful but then all
of a sudden you know with a human eye it
just jumps out like hey someone's adding
a user here and someone's not even share
even just simple recording of things
like net debt exe or other tools like
that you might start finding stuff maybe
insiders of using things or just
mounting shares you don't think they
should be mounting etc or malicious
humans so analytics again this is this
is really how I think of analytics you
might have your own definition buzzword
number three and my favorite and oh by
the way I thought I think analytics is a
number one buzz word of the year I think
orchestrations number two where's
contains i'm not sure where that's going
to fall but remember we're trying to use
analytics and now orchestration to save
you time so that you can maybe get to
risk hunting or threat hunting so
orchestration anyone hear much about
orchestration anyone doing orchestration
awesome so you can also think of it like
automation integration I like the word
orchestration and I think that's really
catching on um you have people like
DARPA saying look the attackers just
have to find a single fall defenders
really have to try to predict anticipate
and deny every flaw so the economics are
not in your favor not in our favor so
it's due automation through
computational power that we can
hopefully level the playing field or
maybe even get ahead although that's
that sounds a little crazy right now
when we're completely not winning so you
have all these different parts of your
stack you're trying to protect you know
identity or you know users user accounts
etc you're trying to protect data from
teksystems
Communications but all this stuff is
related and all has to work together and
to put it another way and I don't know
about your spending or your stack your
security staff but you really need stuff
on the endpoint on your network you need
some form of analytics and you need some
threat intelligence buzzword flash so
you need all this stuff to work together
and you have companies there's a bunch
of them now that are coming out this
isn't our company this you have a bunch
of companies that are coming out with
its kind of like sim to point up where
it's trying to give you a single pane of
glass where it's incorporating all the
different you know detection alerts from
your different products and solutions
but then it's trying to pull in context
when you get that alert and it says hey
this malicious binary connected to that
IP and that domain is that alert also
tell you like when the domain was
registered how often that that IP has
hit in your environment what user
account is that user on vacation where
is that users is what else has been seen
in my environment related to this are
your alert saying that yeah really fails
because most these attackers the
sophistication they go ahead and they
distribute these bombs out there
really clever writing it the same by air
they are switching to multiple types of
binaries from multiple IP locations are
completely distributed there is no
rationale acne easily derive unless I'm
very hard so those kinds of modalities
of view only will give you a little
hanging fruit type of the Tigers they
will do anything right so it's it's also
it's also about showing what else is
occurring in that time frame what else
are those machines doing thats related
so I agree that IPS and stuff change but
a lot of times attacks will hit a bunch
of boxes at once and they will use the
same IP at least for that one attack
like that day right and then they might
change okay so um so but it's still all
about pulling information together when
you're responding to an alert do you
have to go paste your domain and do who
is or things like that having all this
information at your fingertips but not
just not just pulling information
together but being able to talk to
systems in your environment that can
take action oh this thing's bad and
according to multiple sources of thread
and tell ya I'm sure it's bad okay let
me go ban that hash let me turn off that
switch port let me send off an email let
me and automatically enroll that user
and fishing training or whatever so
orchestration is really what I'm talking
about for that stuff and you're seeing
especially companies like in Silicon
Valley where literally eighty percent of
their security team are coders because
all these products now have AP is so
just put coders to it you still have
analysts but put coders to tie all this
stuff together and now you're starting
to see companies come out with actual
products it's like a correlation engine
right that's what I'm talking about with
orchestration so you know really trying
to unify your products a lot of you buy
different products they might have a
connector they might not I'm a vendor
full disclosure we provide connectors
but you know it's it's one plus one
equals two point 2 2.5 when you have an
integration but it's really the dream is
one plus one equals three or four right
so these two products if you have them
both it's
better than just know the sum of the
parts so trying to do all of this stuff
so you know I mostly talked about this
but pulling together different sources
of information so your humans don't have
to spend time on this what's the
geographic location of the IP that
should just show up in your alert what
purpose does that user have in the
organization because that's context you
can use very quickly it might change the
severity of the alert if it's the sea
level guy or if it's a you know entry
level person it's about data
understanding not necessarily data
volume so you might have a lot of data
volume if you can boil that down to
better understanding you can have tons
of data but the humans only look at a
little bit that's the goal right and
orchestration feeds analytics because
you're pulling all this stuff together
analytics and feed into orchestration
but orchestration can feed into
analytics it pulls all this different
information and then it does some
analysis on it some algorithmic
decision-making you know for example you
might detonate a binary see what domains
it connects to and then a human has to
go do all this extra look up where else
is is my domain see what does the boys
information who registered it and then
again you have to manually go take
action like banning hashes blocking IP
sync holding domains guys with me trying
to automate some of this stuff really
try to get one plus one equals three
automatically take action you see a bad
thing hit that endpoint isolate that
machine from the network until you're
really sure that it's not malicious or
until you can re image or whatever
that's where we're going still need
humans in the loop absolutely but
there's a lot of actions you can take
that are automated that's really what I
think about when I think about
orchestration so analytics and
orchestration feed each other and
they're both outputting risks they're
trying to surface risk to the actual
threats or could just view risk this is
risky behavior I'm not sure if it's
malicious but you should look at it so
takeaways
good watches keno if you haven't seen it
Bruce Schneier doesn't doesn't even work
for our company but i love this talk
right 2014 black hat keynote response is
the closest thing we have an i-team is
all fighting I just love that makes dog
fighting school right um but you know
it's about budda loops this notion out
of the military whoever can observe
orient decide and act the fastest is
going to win well if you don't have
visibility you're not really observing
until finally something says hey there's
an alert go look it might take you too
long to orient if you don't have the
right context right really the right
context around that event how quickly
can you make a decision are you
orchestrating everything so you have all
this information to make quick decisions
and then act we just talked about maybe
quickly banning ip's ending hashes
calling user real quick taking a machine
off the off the network that kind of
stuff if you can't move that quickly
it's going to be a losing battle that's
really where we are right now is the bad
guys move faster than we do they often
get into these environments they map out
your environment and they know it better
than you do that's the reality and
you're trying to go through this right
the NIST incident management lifecycle
faster and more effectively that's the
whole goal but really the goal is to go
through this before there's malicious
intent malicious activity try to go
through this when it's risk and it's not
actual threat that's the goal right risk
hunting go through this try to fix
problems before they're actually
exploited or taken advantage of so I
talked about a lot of different things
what are the underlying themes i
basically mentioned them but feedback
loops something suspicious comes across
your network can you validate it with
endpoint or vice versa something runs
that's strange on your computer what
does the network device tell you about
it what is dlp what
other security products you have tell
you where to start intelligence study
and ultimately it's about saving humans
time we're all understaffed we all spend
way too much time on stuff that's not
really useful doing manual lookups
chasing down some malicious binary came
across the wire and detonated and no
it's really bad oh but by the way it's
destined for a mac and it's a windows
exploit you should spend zero time on
maybe if you have time you want to go
reverse engineered or whatever we should
not jump out of bed you should just know
that oh that's not going to matter so
just to give you an example to think
about a lot of times we're looking at
data like this individual events could
be binaries in URLs where individual
events like in your sim or log mechanism
right a lot of them basically look the
same when you start you know to do your
analysis but it shouldn't you shouldn't
start there you should have stuff like
for an intelligence stuff like
reputation information I'm going to
start on the dark red at least because I
want my humans to be more effective and
have better priorities right so I'm
going to start with the red and someone
thinks that's bad but don't stop there
either make it relevant to your
environment things like prevalence
frequency how often is this occurring
right that's where again really where
analytics comes in if it's very frequent
and thought to be bad well either my
threat intelligence is wrong or I'm
screwed but either way you're in a
better spot knowing that but finally
relationships this is where it really
comes together if some unknown binary
starts running but everything it does is
known good prioritize that below some
unknown of binary or some new binary
running that's doing some things that
are unknown about prioritization saving
humans time right focusing your time on
the stuff that actually is risky or a
threat so that's where we were this is
where us as an industry or trying to get
to doing some good things but you know
there's still always more work to be
done and a real concrete example is 0
svchost room
oh great a crown on every Windows
machine or if I tell you svchost respond
by an unsigned binary under strange user
account and made network connection I'm
going to jump out of bed on Christmas to
look at that so remember orchestration
analytics risk hunting remember the
goals hopefully we get a little bit of
discussion I think we have a little time
we started late get some Q&A and
discussion going right now but think
about how you might apply some of this
in your environment and I want to tell
you a true story after the Home Depot
breach I got a I got a call saying your
credit card was compromised and it
turned out they used my credit card at
target so it's like the cycle is
complete and a true story us I don't
justjust strange coincidence i guess all
questions discussion comments please
yeah so I'll repeat the question for the
video or whatever so the question is
kind of it's hard to define known bad or
it's hard to you know define what that
is and I was kind of one of the things I
talked about earlier was it's easier to
define risk like risky behavior than
malicious behavior and it kind of comes
back to the thing about the credit card
companies they don't know they don't
know what bad behavior looks like that
yeah sure they they basically black list
some merchants and stuff around the
world but they profile you into this
fuzzy box and as soon as you you're
spending goes way outside that then they
call you right so they're looking for
known good and then as soon as it's
outside of known good then they call you
so I think you need to do stuff like you
know so I'll just ramble for a second
ioc's have marginal value there's four
billion ipv4 addresses if you're looking
for a few hundred IPS that's not a very
good ratio for billion possible you
looking for a few hundred it's a little
bit better odds because you might you
know have subsequent usages of those
sites or whatever but you want to
automate looking for those you want to
automate looking for strange behavior
that's typical of malware TTP's like
running out of temp directory or
unsigned binary trying to manipulate
some windows service things like that
could be signed binary but it's signed
by some little software vendor they got
hacked or whatever so automate some of
that but then just start looking for
abnormal behavior and trying to again
flip it where you can put everyone into
remember the like the NASCAR thing if
you can try to get closer to a base
image like less drift less entropy from
the base image then you can start saying
okay there's enough consistency that any
time there's a new process no one has
ever seen before or a new connection no
one has ever made before that's in
frequent enough that I can look at that
so that's that's kind of my advice there
yeah
governmental cyberinfrastructure not
actually carrying a perishable wait to
actually defend the country from cyber
threats we are all here as private to
the street but my understanding is the
Department of Defense was supposed to be
designed kind of country and yet we get
invaded continuously from outside of the
country with these threats I
specifically so many facts two gentlemen
about this with no response at the NSA
probably 10 years ago we could easily
determine reputation thread through the
NSA database we had availability for our
own infrastructure for liga stop that
border routers that coming out of hybrid
they have intercepts on the first place
yep so I think they have you done so why
are they doing something why are they
lazy blogger is lawful learn an ugly
girl to country so so the question is
kind of you heard it i'll say it for the
recording oh why isn't the federal
government especially and Department of
Defense and Intel community doing more
right like if your business gets bombed
they're going to respond for you it's
more I think it's more of a political
issue of trying to apply too much
federal oversight and whether it's real
or not the invasion of privacy is still
a huge like battle right the whole
privacy versus security um yeah i don't
i don't know i don't know exactly i mean
there's a lot of like NSA is swamped
with overseas stuff right and they're
really focused more on overseas i know
they do listen phone calls and stuff
right but um it's a it's a completely
valid question and I think we all have
the same question why isn't and I think
the government is moving to do more it's
just slow right like it's just slow
they're starting to pass legislation but
even that which you'd think everyone's
on board with is a little slow but I
think we will see the federal government
having to step up more at least in terms
of
sharing Intel you know doing some
blocking that kind of stuff but I think
they're still for a long time going to
stay hands off on your corporate
security and a lot of attacks come from
within the u.s. like you just bounce off
an amazon box or Rackspace or whatever
right so no no i don't i mean i was at a
networked at isp some years ago it was a
simple thing you could imagine somebody
hacked dns for a chinese isp they
repointed their mail exchanger writers
to the barracuda box of federal
facilities that was in our data center
world and obviously you're immediately
down when you have that was mailed to
the traffic that's false your system we
have no idea why we eventually obviously
cut all the data flow but just that
basic heuristic which is this more see
on the lower level suppose you're
spending your film US government had
that visibility on the border routers to
see that traffic coming to the united
states that russia packets they could
stop at the border it's an invalid form
of traffic there's no see there's no way
that I'm Alex
china the u.s. they could stop it right
away at the mortar yep there's no
privacy of all your privacy I think I
think the generals I think really are
here like a duty step down and people
are doing yeah i think i mean i think
it's i hear ya let me let me take some
more here the statement was he wants NSA
to stay out we could talk government
after blue shirt here so so the question
is what do these look like an
implementation well risk hunting is more
of having the right access to
information to have a human go look for
problems and it could be automated a
little bit right but it's really like
I'm going to go find where our
misconfigured like it's it's really the
hunter mentality I'm gonna go find where
we have misconfigurations or like figure
out what boxes can talk to each other
but shouldn't that kind of stuff so
that's more of a human thing
orchestration is um there's you know
it's kind of like integration and
automation so some coding some scripting
but some vendor provided tools that kind
of stuff really just pulling together
you know even just simple things like
you have a next-generation firewall that
detonates things you know something on
your computers they should talk to each
other like you detonate it and then in
your alert it also says oh by the way
not only was this bad destined for Ben's
machine but it ran just saving time
right and then analytics is also like
kind of collecting data and there's a
ton of new companies and products that
are saying analytics and you know I'm
not saying that they're not doing it but
there
so it's you know it is a hard problem to
take all this information process it
find anomalies another buzzword that I
don't talk about is machine learning if
you go to like West Coast Bay Area it's
like everyone's third word other mouth
is machine learning but it's really
about finding anomalies and then like
remembering those and then you know
improving your algorithm based on that
almost like a i right but it all comes
down to these are more concepts and
trying to figure out how you can apply
these with your tools with your people
with your skill sets like programmers or
whatever that's really where
implementation is yeah so was regards to
analytics there's always going to be
some users that are really really hard
to profile one of it comes to mind is
developers I haven't sure a lot of
people here have worn the developer had
at some points and even in a very large
corporate environment developers look
really sketchy just when they're
normally doing their job be that you
know random Python scripts running day
in day out port 22 connections to random
git repositories on the internet to pull
something down how would you tackle the
problem of profound a user that's very
hard to profile I still think they're
easier to profile then you might think
but yeah there's definitely so the
question is there's developers and other
people that are very dynamic right so
it's hard to profile you can still
restrict what they can do so yeah you
can go to anywhere on github com
anywhere and github / whatever like
allow them to do that but if they go to
other sites they have to get permission
or whatever I understand there might be
work flow issues or effectiveness where
if it takes too long to get to a special
repo then they're going to not do their
job well or throw a fit but you can
still figure out like hey they normally
have on visual studio the norm around
pycharm or whatever intellij pick your
tools right so they start installing all
this other stuff it should be infrequent
enough that you can go say hey why are
you installing this or make it so you
can only install stuff that's out of a
shared directory or some sort of
approved installation folder and just
again make the process fast enough so
that you need approval or i can get it
within 10 minutes or so yeah it's harder
to profile but i think it's easier than
you might think and none of this is like
easy I mean no one's raising their hands
when I ask who's doing this stuff right
um but it's it's not impossible and then
I guess so a fault so that is how we
balance trust against that because at
some point there are users you need to
fully trust you need to foil a trust
your domain admin says that means at
what level where do you feel that should
be higher than what we normally new or
yeah so the question is kind of trust
and especially people have like root or
domain admin access that kind of stuff
I'll think about feedback loops when
they make changes does that get logged
some where does it get audited that's
you you have to trust your employees you
have to keep them happy but you're
there's a huge push a kind of globally
but nationwide on insider threat a huge
push all these big companies have
official like budgeted programs an
insider threat they're trying to figure
out what tools or what processes can do
that the government has said you know
each department or each organization has
to at least be making progress on
insider threat because I like Snowden
and stuff like that um so you're seeing
a huge push and it's a hard problem to
solve but ultimately if you're at least
doing feedback loops and saying trying
to profile like okay the domain admin
should only login like I count you only
log into these four boxes if it's are
plugging elsewhere either someone's lazy
or it's compromised or whatever so you
do have to have trust but you do have to
do some sort of monitoring some sort of
auditing as well question I think we
have a few more minutes yeah
so the question is where is the line
John bafite between sort of openness and
enforcement or lockdown right hardening
that kind of stuff um which is funny
because that's what our company has to
deal with all the time because we have
two products and one is about watching
all the time and letting you do anything
you want I'm gonna trying to be a
product pitch here and the other one is
about enforcing and like locking it down
so literally like every customer I
talked to has like that question and
it's it's cultural fit first of all um
like I see places in the west coast
where they're like dude we could never
block a process like never stop someone
from installing I just want to see I
just want to know and so a really
visibility another buzzword more from
last year but visibility is key so like
maybe you give them a little bit more
freedom to install stuff but you're
you're literally you know recording and
being notified every time someone
installs something and if that's too
voluminous maybe you you filter out like
signed by Microsoft's on by Google son
by whatever so that's what really where
some of the analytics and automation
come in but I don't know I was a coder
for forever I still write code right and
like the number of things I actually
install like daily or weekly is like
zero basically right like over time
maybe I need a new I IDE your new
package never had before but it's not
like all the time like it kind of the
question like it sounds like there's a
lot of dynamic activity going on from
these users but really if they can't
install stuff except for a specific day
or specific directory or whatever I
still think most of the time they can
get their job done just as fast a few
more questions discussion black shirt
you
holy automatically a peaceful solution
but then possibly that machine should do
as much as possible Polly kind of lower
that threshold you don't have senior
analyst at it you know a junior analyst
can still figure out what's going on
yeah so it's um so the question is like
there's there's too much data we still
need a human in the loop when does it
just become overwhelming um so again
it's boiling it down trying to automate
like this one company in Silicon Valley
um let's just say they probably stream a
lot of videos and shows to you and stuff
um they literally each of their alerts
because they do all this cool
orchestration stuff literally they're
alert has a recommendation so it's like
Oh based on all this here's like a score
here's a recommendation reimage or kill
these processes whatever but a human
still makes the decision and it has all
this information like like this is where
a lot of these themes came from like oh
it's this user oh by the way they're on
vacation this week so why is that box
receiving something or this is the
domain here's the country here's other
attacks from that country or other
connections from that country we've seen
this week so trying to boil it down but
really if you can get it simplistic
enough so the entry level guy can at
least figure out if it's worth
escalation not necessarily make the
decision just try to filter out stuff
that doesn't meet a certain escalation
you know threshold that's really where
you have to get
I think we're actually going to get
better at boiling it down I think we're
really bad at boiling down it's like
those dots we're all like these black
dots right now and the entry-level guy
is like I don't know what this is like
um you know it's just some random you
know like google com is being alerted on
and stuff like it so I've seen that and
I'm like why is that alerting like
that's your not good questions over here
got to be more questions come on yep
another thing I hear all the time sadly
there is no silver bullet for that
either oh the question was I've done a
lot of good things have pretty good
posture how do i convince upper
management that it's not enough or you
know to actually implement what I laid
out as a plan um so boards are waking up
CEOs are waking up you have some big
companies where literally every time
their board meets like half of their
board meeting is about cyberthreats on
the flip side it's about risk so I've
had really large companies say look my
CEO said I don't care if it's a tsunami
or a cyberattack I just want to figure
out where's the risk and how do I
mitigate it and so we all think like Oh
cyber attack they have to be focused on
it but no there's like all these other
risks to your business especially global
businesses um but I think showing how
you can implement it relatively
painlessly or quickly is you know part
of the problem or part of the solution
you know showing that you're going to
provide some sort of measurement right
if you don't measure it you can't
optimize it so saying look we're going
to implement this and oh by the way in
three months we're going to provide you
these metrics now metrics is a whole
nother can of worms that could be good
or bad showing you how to do that and
then trying to put it in terms of saving
time and saving money you know it's hard
to use scareware and stuff like hey
forget breach it's gonna be five million
dollars or whatever but the news kind of
does that for you so if you keep it a
little bit more specific to like hey
look this new product we come out if we
get hacked then China is just going to
produce it for a nickel and cost us a
hundred dollars right I don't know so
there's no there's no silver bullet
there but trying to make sure they
understand the risk at least and then
show simple things you can do to at
least improve a little bit or maybe a
lot and we can talk more after two final
questions anything come on
this guy likes an essay actually new
general Hayden to it you know I was
nothing you know I was a entry-level guy
but um I don't know I don't know we did
a lot of interesting things it was
during Iraq and Afghanistan so there's a
lot of work a lot of supporting the war
fighter I don't know places like that
really make you grow because you can't
just google for the answer you might
even not even have internet access you
might be in a closed environment where
you just have to like figure out how to
you know break something or you know
install something covertly or whatever
and you just have to work your butt off
to figure it out so you really grow as a
person or as a you know as a
professional you learn all these skills
and you might be doing some windows
thing or Linux thing you know one day or
the other day and they might doing a
cisco thing or looking at some specific
application or doing some reverse
engineering or stuff so it's it's pretty
cool work and there's a lot of it going
on I know that wasn't really anything of
substance but it's pretty cool if
anyone's interested there's a lot of
work in cyber both offense and defense
in the DC area
my favorite is actually a four-letter
agency called JSOC Joint Special
Operations Command I was leave it at
that look it up awesome all right any
other final questions the one thing I
want to point out is we have a hard
problem we have all these tools but a
lot of times it still comes down to your
culture to human error to human or you
know user education so remember
analytics orchestration risk hunting but
just all I want you to do is think about
how can you get to some of this stuff
like how can you think about this when
you're procuring tools or when you're
building out your team or when you're
putting your processes in place last
chance any questions all right thank you
guys