[Music]
so our next speaker is Marc lipstick and
he's going to talk about silly boxing
North Korea's weapon of mass detection
mark is the malware research team leader
at checkpoints and he deals with reverse
engineering and malware analysis both as
occupation and as a hobby so a huge
round of applause to Marc and Krystal
[Applause]
[Music]
let's begin with a short video
ha Gyung
so touchy onesa Vonda and on Education
Sciences attentio me some possible
chilling don't go partying io sono don't
chew on the onion on top or hexam's
again woody hypoxic is retarded again
we're going to California avatar
[Music]
ladies and gentlemen for those of you
who don't know this lady pink
her name is reach on he a good friend of
mine a North Korea's main news presenter
and she just turned 75 years old this
July let's give her a warm round of
applause for her passionate introduction
to silly vaccine of course I'm lying
she's not my friend nor did she even
speak about silly vaccine in this video
but still kudos to her for grabbing your
attention and again hello thank you for
joining me for this talk titled silly
vaccine North Korea's weapon of mass
detection before I actually tell you
about the research story here I would
like to introduce you to the two
notorious dissidents who are behind this
infamous research you see them right
here on the screen one of them actually
happens to be me my name is Mark left ik
as previously mentioned I'm the Malheur
research team leader and checkpoint and
my partner in crime for this research is
named Michael casalotti unfortunately he
couldn't be here today because he's in a
vacation in Hawaii probably drinking
some smoothie from a coconut so I
thought this would be a better picture
to Michael have a lot of fun in your
travel come home safely and beware of
Koreans who stare at you suspiciously
now we both work at checkpoint as
mentioned and without further ado let me
give you a little bit of a background
for this research so this whole research
actually began at one point this year
around March when I was looking for
something to read and Twitter
and then I stumbled upon this article
you see right here titled inside North
Korea's hacker army by Bloomberg and
it's actually a pretty interesting piece
I recommend you to read it it discusses
a particular North Korean defector who
was drafted to work for a government
agency in North Korea and ended up
raising money for the regime through
hacking and an interesting thing I noted
throughout this publication is that the
author tried to portray some kind of a
narrative of North Korean
state-sponsored cyber operations and in
particular in one paragraph he gives a
representation of what seems to be the
North Korean government's official
comment to various hacking allegations
made against North Korea by the West and
here's a quote so formally North Korea
denies engaging in hacking and describes
accusations to that effect as enemy
propaganda it says its overseas computer
efforts are directed at promoting its
antivirus software in the global market
the country has for more than a decade
been working on such programs including
one called
silly vaccine now looking at this you're
probably asking yourselves what the hell
is silly vaccine well as you may
understand by now
silly vaccine is an anti virus that is
developed and used exclusively in North
Korea so this is basically a North
Korean anti virus or how I like to call
it the kim jeong-hoon T virus
now obviously this is a very rare
product you can't find it on the
Internet you cannot download it anywhere
it basically resides only inside the
DPRK as far as we could tell in this
research it's actively developed since
2003 and the version that I'm going to
focus on here today is version 4.0 which
was released in 2013 just as a caveat we
are also we were also in possession of
another version from 2005 which was one
of the early versions of sealy vaccine
and I will mention it a little bit later
throughout this talk now if you know
anything about North Korea then one
thing you should note is that there's
actually no internet inside North Korea
right instead what they have is what's
called an intranet which is this highly
restricted glorified local area network
and having that in mind you must be
thinking why the hell would North Korea
use an anti-virus in the first place
well there are a few interesting
explanations for that one the more
exotic one is to actually protect
against threats that might reside within
media that is smuggled to the country
and for this matter as an example it
turns out that there is actually a
phenomenon of USB sticks with Western
media that somehow magically find their
way inside North Korea and then they get
sold in the country's black-market to
citizens and I know it sounds totally
fucked up but remember it's North Korea
and to convince you a little bit better
you're invited to go to this website
called flash drives for freedom which is
actually a crowd-sourced funding project
for USB sticks that get written with
content from the West and smuggled into
North Korea so just a fun fact
if you have any kind of problems with
your local IRS don't worry
the smuggled USB stick is 100 texts 100%
tax refundable
as for the content inside of it well it
contains just all kinds of information
entertainment content from the West like
Wikipedia articles and South Korean soap
operas which somehow managed to threaten
the North Korean regime but anyways
there's also another explanation for the
existence of this antivirus
and this is the fact that actually
stated by North Korea itself is to raise
money for the regime by selling this
product in the worldwide market as a
matter of fact to corroborate this we
can refer to the 2005 version of sealy
vaccine that I mentioned previously
which you can see here on the screen was
written both in Korean and English which
might hint at the fact that whoever
wrote this version tried to make it more
appealing for english-speaking users as
well as Korean ones now you also must be
asking yourselves how the hell did we
get our hands on this software in the
first place well the answer to this lies
in the Bloomberg article I mentioned
earlier it linked to a blog post by this
guy named Martin Williams Martin
Williams is a journalist who covers
various kinds of news items related to
North Korea and he actually got this
particular software through I would say
a slightly suspicious email from a guy
calling himself Kang Yong hak a security
engineer from Japan who wanted to give
it to him as a journalistic lead and
remember this email we will talk about a
little bit later
now of course Martin was kind enough to
share the software with us and it's the
place to thank him for making this whole
research possible now what did we want
to find out in this research so first of
all we wanted to understand the
technical structure of the saw
how's it built to which we hope to get
somewhat of an anthropological view on
some of the practices employed by the
North Korean engineers meaning how
engineers with restricted resources
tackle a big project like building an
anti-virus from scratch also we wanted
to see if we can find any kind of
abnormal behavior inside this antivirus
some things that could have been left in
place and exposed some hidden agenda of
the developers and in particular we try
to locate any potential backdoor that
could have been deliberately put in
place as means of surveillance against
the citizens so with that in mind let's
take a short overview of the anti
viruses architecture and for this matter
let's start with the software libraries
that comprise it the first of which is
called SV shell this is just a basic
shell extension that introduces this
entry in the context menu which you can
see if you click the right mouse button
and this is basically meant to just do a
manual scan on a file using silly
vaccine and you know what let's just
test this feature and see if it works
so here we have an malware we
right-click we press on this feature and
nothing happens
which is really just some kind of a bug
that we see right from the very
beginning of testing this antivirus
spoiler there are more but nevermind
let's move on the next component we see
here is one called
SV Colonel DLL now this is in fact the
file scanning engine of this antivirus
and this is really the core component
that contains the logic that implements
a virus scan of files this DLL exposes
roughly to any export functions with the
names as we found 0 0 1 through as we
found 0 20 a very ambiguous naming
convention
and they are of course used in
conjunction with banners or signatures
which is the content that allows the
software to decide if a given file is
malicious or not then we have another
group of components which is pretty
self-explanatory these are the GUI
components the first of which is the
stray menu you see you can see on the
right corner of the screen and this
little menu allows you to execute any
other GUI menus in this antivirus for
instance you can see the following menu
where you can do a full scan on the file
system you can play around with some of
the configurations of this antivirus
it's also possible to do some white
listing and black listing actions and
basically this is a GUI one-stop shop
for all of these of this antivirus
features another Oh before talking about
the other components as the main
actually communicates with a driver
called SV hope that sis this is a driver
that is meant to convey some information
to us the main from the kernel space we
will discuss this driver a little bit
later then we have the update mechanism
of the antiviral of the antivirus which
will basically download any kind of
update binaries and components or update
signatures and we'll verify them with an
external component called as VD fu PD
that XE and of course as I mentioned
everything here resides inside North
Korea's intranet so this update client
will communicate with a server inside
North Korea and it will do so using a
custom update protocol which works on
top of the HTTP protocol and here you
can see some of the messages exchanged
between this update client and server
and one thing I would like you to notice
is the vast amount of information
conveyed through this update protocol
you can see feels like a serial number
kind of an interface ID and IP which is
for the most part kind of suspicious I
mean why the hell do they need all this
information just for an update mechanism
but since we don't have any access to
this server or any kind of way to
understand how the user communicates
with it we can't really tell why this
information is collected so we'll just
leave this fact as is another
interesting thing is that the whole HTTP
protocol was manually implemented by the
developers and along the way they did
some interesting mistakes for instance
the content length field of the HTTP
header is written with an underscore
here which is kind of a mistake it's not
the way it is intended to be used also
the authors wanted to convey the clients
the update clients identity to the
server and they did so with the user
agent which is a pretty typical way of
doing this but instead of only using the
user agent they added another field
called user dealer which I have no idea
what kind of dealer they had in mind but
obviously this has nothing to do with
the HTTP protocol and speaking of
dealers there is yet another component
here called sv dealer eggsy which is
actually the real-time scanning
component of this antivirus which you
can enable through the training as well
and this particular component will use
another driver called sv filter dot sis
which is a file system filter driver
meant to intercept all kinds of access
to the file system and issue the
underlying file to a scan prior to
actually doing any kind of action on it
and again we'll discuss at this
particular driver later on at this point
I should mention that the two components
here that actually do any kind of
scanning tasks are as VD Lorne sv main
that you see here on the screen
obviously they would have to use the
file scanning engine for this purpose
and also a bunch of signatures which are
represented through a series of files
called the pattern files another thing
here that we have as a driver that I'm
not going to talk about at all this is a
driver called STS TDI 2 dot sis this is
basically a TDI Network filter driver if
you don't have any idea what I just said
is perfectly fine because this driver
does absolutely nothing it just resides
inside this antivirus and collects all
kinds of information about TCP
connections and it should be queried
theoretically by other components but no
one ever queries it so it seems like
it's just some kind of a residue from
previous versions of silly vaccine so
we'll just leave it be I guess and
another interesting point here is that a
lot of these components you see here
were protected with a legitimate
protector a commercial protector called
C media which if you've heard of it you
probably know it's a pain in the ass to
reverse engineer luckily for us whoever
used this protector did not enable a lot
of its features and we could unpack it
with moderate efforts this is the full
architecture of this anti virus I'm not
going to go any further in it you can
read about it in our publication for
publication about this software actually
I want to focus in all of this
complicated scheme on one particular
component which I already discussed this
is SV Colonel DLL I remind you this is
the file scanning engine of the
antivirus this is really the heart and
soul of this whole software and this is
why we're going to talk about it next
and I would like to begin this
discussion about this component with
what every good reverse engineer looks
at and these are strings of course and
the first thing we did was to open this
file and look at its strings and like
every professional reverse engineer we
look them up in Google
and here's ladies and gentlemen where it
actually gets interesting because it
turns out that if we look at in Google
we come to another file called vs API 32
DLL now what is vs API 32 DLL as it
turns out this is yet another file
scanning engine actually it's a fast
kangan engine belonging to a big
corporate in the security field and that
is Trend Micro which we thought was kind
of surprising and looking at this we
thought does it mean that this dll is in
some way incorporated inside Syria
vaccine did they use any kind of
interesting way of incorporating its
functionality inside their engine well
let's find out
so here on the screen you can see what's
called a binary diff this is a binary
comparison between those two engines on
the left side you can see the Trend
Micro engine and on the right side you
can see the silly vaccine engine and
actually you can notice a few things
here for one there's a 100% match
between more than a thousand functions
of those two engines a thousand
functions like a quarter of sealy
vaccines engine code and then you can
see also that there's a 100% match on
some of the export functions in fact if
you look at all of the first 18 export
functions in C vaccine you realize they
somehow map to functions of Trend Micro
and as an example let's just take three
of these functions and look at their
call flow graphs in Ida and we can see
that they're pretty similar for the most
part but I would say it's more
interesting to note at the small nuances
or the small differences between those
particular functions and as an example
let's take this pair of functions vs in
it and as defunct 0:05 when one
interesting thing we noted at the very
beginning is that
while Trend Micro's engine uses mostly
Lipsy functions like command set for
instance the equivalent in silly vaccine
would at some points in line those
functions and would use function
inlining to convey the same function and
that essentially hints at the fact that
the developer of silly vaccine could
have recompiled this particular Trend
Micro code with some kind of a compiler
optimization that was not applied on the
original engine you can see another
example for this right here with the mem
copy and QM copy the it's in-line
equivalent and let's look at another
pair for this matter so we have vs get
vs see info and as we fungal 0:04 once
again function inlining but another
artifact that was left here are these
numbers you see right here so it turns
out that this particular field that is
populated in this struct you see here is
actually the engine version of this
antivirus and it turns out that the
engine version used inside civil vaccine
is eight point nine hundred and ten
which is an engine used by Trent or
released by Trend Micro back in 2008 now
recall that this software is from 2013
so basically whoever wrote this I was
using a five year old engine inside his
coat and finally let's look at another
pair via squid and has defunct 0:06
once again you can see a call to a
proprietary silly vaccine function
inside what used to be a Trend Micro
function this is just some kind of a
cleanup function for a driver called s
vio
which has nothing to do with Trend Micro
and this again strengthens this kind of
speculation that when compiling a CD
vaccine there was some kind of a use of
a proprietary resource that belongs to
Trend Micro
well I would like to mention at this
point that this was not the only
instance of Trend Micro engine we found
in CV vaccine so in the 2005 version
which I mentioned earlier we actually
found a trace of another component by
Trend Micro which is called T and filter
dot sis this is actually a kernel-mode
equivalent of this engine called VSA
pi32 and this really shows that this
whole sort of copyright infringement was
not a one-time thing
it has been possibly going on for quite
a few years now we reached out to Trend
Micro to get the response and basically
just to sum this up Trend Micro says
that yes silly vaccine I used ten year
ten plus year old version of their
engine in their code they said like what
the fuck we did not do any business with
North Korea also they're saying we have
no idea how they got our engine but they
do hint at the fact that they worked
with some vendors as OEM back at that
time and maybe it's possible that one of
these OMS leaked their code or whatnot
so who knows
so other than you know looking at this
other than saying that this is a very
kind of secretive antivirus that's
developed inside North Korea we couldn't
help but notice that there are quite a
lot of mechanisms used by the authors to
conceal the fact that they're using a
third party product and again I remind
you we just realized that CD vaccine is
essentially using a Trend Micro engine
and we thought if they're using the same
engine doesn't mean that they're
actually using the same signatures as
well so if we compare this on the
surface then it seems that no because CD
vaccine has multiple of pattern files
while Trend Micro has one single large
file and also there's seems to be no
kind of
similarity between between them on the
binary level but if we look a little bit
deeper then we can find the place in the
code where those particular pattern
files are being loaded this is this
happens in SV kernel DLL and a
particular function called as we found
19 and what happens there is that the
name of the particular pattern file of
one of the pattern files is being
calculated or generated then handle to
this file is obtained the contents of
the file are being read then this
particular file is being decrypted the
decrypted chunk is appended to some
buffer in memory the ID of this chunk is
incremented at this whole process
repeats so essentially what this
function does is to load the pattern
files one by one decrypt them and append
them all together
now before I talk a little more about
the encryption here let's talk a little
bit about the encryption key because
there's something interesting here so
this is the encryption key used there a
seemingly random English string we
thought does it mean anything in Korean
it doesn't mean anything in any language
actually but an interesting thing
happens when we take this particular
string to a Korean English keyboard and
we try to type it while accidentally
forgetting to switch to English so we
get this Korean string and if we
translate this Korean string to English
turns out that it literally means
pattern encryption
[Music]
thank you so okay so we we decided to
look a little bit deeper now regarding
the encryption itself we sell a lot of
encryption mechanics inside some have
some cryptographic artifacts that
resemble the sha-1 algorithm for
instance and all kinds of other stuff we
basically didn't really bother
understanding this whole mechanism very
deeply because we were interested in the
decrypted pattern files which we could
simply dump from memory and that's what
we did and after dumping this from
memory and comparing the two signature
files one one to another we can actually
see a similarity in the header and if we
scroll a little bit down we can also see
that there's quite much of a similarity
in strings actually there's more than
90% match amongst the strings in those
two files and the very the difference is
probably due to the version of those
pattern files now that's not the end we
decided to test this thing
so we scanned a bunch of files with
silly vaccine they were all detected we
scanned them also with Trend Micro they
were also detected but there's something
interesting here although they're using
the same signatures and same strings the
detection names are totally different
and others ladies and gentlemen
suspicious so it turns out there's a
reason for this and the reason is that
silly vaccine actually renames the
signature names before displaying them
to the user and here is how this works
so basically silly vaccine will take a
Trend Micro signature name for this
purpose George underscore steal - one it
would then replace it would then a strip
it off the underscores and dashes and
then replace the prefix with some kind
of word based on a string based on a
predefined dictionary it will also
replace the suffix from a letter from a
number to a letter it will modify the
casing append everything together with
dots
and this is how you get a silly vaccine
signature so looking at all of this it's
interesting to note that the author's
are probably trying to hide something so
just to summarize all of these hiding
mechanisms let's just briefly take a
look at what we've already seen so
basically all of the files or most of
the files and this software are
protected with the media commercial
protector which means that the binary
files does not have any kind of string
artifacts that allow a researcher to
understand what he's looking at also the
pattern files are encrypted so we don't
have any string artifacts there you can
understand from those signature files
what you're looking at and finally the
the malware signatures are renamed in
real-time so it means that even in real
time you cannot tell what was the
original signature where it came from so
essentially the user and a researcher
won't have any way of knowing that this
product is using the engine of Trend
Micro which is all puzzling
so moving on let's talk about more of
the fishy things that go inside of this
product namely while analyzing it we've
seen a lot of the following instances of
this string malt new crib dot F and we
realized that based on its format it's
probably some kind of a signature name
so we decided to understand what it was
we ran our algorithm in Reverse and we
get this following detection named ma
underscore new crib - v but what's the
deal with the signature why does it even
stand out from the other ones well here
are two instances where this particular
signature name is used so here you can
see actually that what happens with this
signature is that a file is being
scanned to detect if it's malicious or
not then if it was found to be malicious
then its detection name is compared
against this string and if that's the
case then sealy vaccine will simply
ignore this file
which is suspicious now of course we
wanted to test this thing so we ran six
files that were supposed to be detected
with this particular detection name in
Trend Micro they were all detected then
we decided to run them and see the
vaccine and nothing was detected and
actually this is quite surprising
because we did a little bit of QA on
this and turns out that for the most
part it's okay but then in one instance
they made typos and they whitelisted
something called mal neuro crip CF which
has no equivalent in Trend Micro's
engine which begs the question what the
fuck is new crib and according to Trend
Micro's encyclopedia which is the thing
apparently mal underscore new crib - v
is described as some kind of a signature
related to some old malware named new
war tips Zilla we checked all of them
they have no relation whatsoever to
North Korea but deeper inspection of
this signature name reveals that
actually the smell prefix you see right
here means that this is a generic
detection that flex files based on some
heuristic which in essence might detect
a whole spectrum of files so
unfortunately based on only on this
information we cannot know what malware
was exactly detected here or really if
it was malware at all but we can still
speculate on why this white listing was
done and for one the most obvious
speculation would be that there is some
kind of an existing North Korean tool
installed on citizens computers and the
authors didn't want to trigger an alert
about it being malicious it's also
possible that the authors wanted some
option to develop such tool in the
future and they inserted this signature
in order to conceal this future
component with this particular
whitelisting mechanism it's also
possible that since the authors used a
third party engine the Trend Micro
engine
that this signature mistakenly detected
one of CV vaccines original components
as malware which they clearly wanted to
avoid and of course it's also possible
that this whole thing is some kind of an
idiotic false positive management fix
but I would say this is unlikely all
right let's move on and talk about the
kernel side of CV vaccine and remember
silly vaccine has three kernel-mode
drivers but actually only two of them
are utilized as we filter in as we hope
that says so let's focus on them and we
started snooping around and looking at
these drivers and the first thing we
noted as some fishy stuff like the fact
that its entry point resides in the real
log section and that it's supposedly
packed with some kind of a packer called
bot crypt which we never heard of and we
looked around Bob crypt turned out this
is an old Russian PE backer that
supposedly contains some common
protection features such as anti debug
measures and polymorphic code now this
is not really good news when dealing
with the kernel driver because who wants
to debug polymorphic code in the kernel
so we thought wait a second before we
dive in and do all of these stuff maybe
we can actually find some kind of an
answer
by looking at this file again from the
outside and turns out that our answer
was right there and our answer is 42
actually it's hex 42 so evidently
this whole crazy protection scheme here
is that the text section that contains
the actual driver is sort with a single
byte of the value 42 hex so with this
insane protection mechanism which we
were able to bypass we were able to look
at the drivers themselves and the first
one of them as we filtered out says I
remind you this is a file system filter
driver this is loaded and utilized by SV
dealer this is the real-time scanning
component and it has two main
functionalities one is to actually scan
files upon access so it would intercept
any kind of activity with the file
system and we take the underlying file
and would issue it to SV dealer to
conduct a scan on it and also it's
actually used to protect the antivirus
as binary themselves to avoid any kind
of malfunction against them by the user
and it really took us quite some time to
realize that these are the only two
things that this driver does because the
code for them is really a mess and I'm
going to save you some time and explain
the flow of this driver by simplifying
it a little bit so this is how as the
filter that says works in a nutshell the
first action it does is waste time so it
does a lot of redundant checks that seem
to have no effect on this code
whatsoever then it moves on to see if
the file scan here is actually binary
related to the antivirus itself of
course if it is then it will deny access
to it then it moves to the very
important action of wasting a lot more
time by doing what seems to be pretty
much garbage code and finally at some
point it will take the file it will scan
it and if the file seems to be malicious
then it will deny the access to it
otherwise it will allow the access so
this is pretty much everything to say
about as we filter there was another
driver called as we hope that sis which
is utilized by the main GUI component
has remained a taxi you look at this
name you think yes it probably hooks
stuff no it doesn't actually hook
anything it's actually used to query
some kind of process object data from
the kernel and really it's quite of a
confusing
driver because it seems to have like 13
iocked ELLs only three are ever used and
it's highly highly buggy there's a lot
of bugs there so for instance we seen
the following function where where
there's an I octo issued to this driver
and it really seems that those two
components as the main and as we hook
were really developed by two different
developers so here we can see that this
drive this programmer who wrote this
particular eye octal call actually used
a buffer of size 12 now you would assume
that those two developers have agreed
that this should be the input buffer
size right well evidently the second
developer was not really notified about
this and in fact checks explicitly that
the buffer size is 12 and if that's the
case nothing happens
which really is a piece-of-shit coat
that does nothing so while looking in
this we we try to dig a little bit
deeper and understand why those bugs
happen and we think we have an answer
so just throwing around we see a lot of
this if you look at this you realize
that you're looking at a lot of debug
prints used by the author and you see
that one of the parts of the strings
referenced here is sub underscore eight
zero zero something which is an Ida
auto-generated name which to me ladies
and gentlemen seems like instead of
looking at authentic code we were in
fact reverse engineering a reverse
engineer driver
so essentially what happened here is
that the developer of SV hook took some
driver decompile that copied the code
and added a bunch of debug prints in
order to try to understand why he was
what he was copying and it seems he
didn't only fail to understand it but he
also forgot to remove this trail of
debug prints that demonstrates his elite
coding skills so we are nearly at the
end and we talked quite a bit about the
technical parts here but to get the full
picture I think it's a good idea to look
at the development story behind the
software so in essence who is behind CV
vaccine well to tackle this question we
resorted to some version info that can
be found inside the antivirus as
binaries and there we found some version
manifest that pointed at several
companies the first one of which is
called PGI pyeongyang gwangmyeong
information technology it seems to be
some kind of a North Korean
establishment a known one that
specializes in network security software
but really the more interesting company
that we found there was called SDS tech
service which is really this kind of
shady company that has no trace of its
activity online we couldn't find any
kind of artifact that shows what this
company does or
what is its main field of occupation so
we still can't answer some questions
about SDS tech service for instance we
can't say that SDS tech service is
highly likely based in the DPRK in North
Korea and that is due to this brochure
you see here on the screen which is
taken from trade fair that took place in
Pyongyang back in 2006 and in this
particular trade fair this company SDS
Tax Service they participated we
contacted the organizers and they
actually confirmed that SDS Tax Service
did come from North Korean side still
some questions remain is that a private
company in North Korea is that even a
saying is that a government entity is
that the same thing in North Korea which
we don't know actually
another source told us that this might
be this company might be a subdivision
of the KPA where K P stands for Korea
People's Army but we have no way of
corroborating this and you remember
Trend Micro stated that their engine
will could have been leaked from a third
party could that third party beat this
company well we don't know actually but
what we did see and which was really
interesting is a particular connection
between North Korea and Japan that
repeats throughout this whole research
so for one we've already seen that s V
kernel is basically some kind of
modified version of Trend Micro's engine
but then we also seen that SDS tech
service at some point cooperated with a
company called Silver Star Japan on a
particular application as a matter of
fact it not only cooperated with them
but also with another company called
Magnolia which also resides in Japan
actually Silver Star and Magnolia reside
in the same address in Japan just quite
interesting and then in a particular
instance all of these three companies
Magnolia Silver Star and STS Tax Service
cooperated with the KCC
very famous North Korean research
establishment the Korea computer center
on another application and it's
important to say that while we can be
very easily drawn to some conclusions
here and speculate on some very wild
scenarios especially given the fact that
North Korea and Japan are not friends we
need to remember that this is just a
crazy web of connections that we
unraveled here and actually we cannot
say much about this other than pointing
out the connections themselves
still I can't say that we did find some
traces of maliciousness in this whole
package and at this point we thought all
right
we are done with the research could it
be that there is no malware or backdoor
here well turns out that if we look back
on this email sent by this supposedly
Japanese engineer Kang Yong hak and we
inspect the Installer provided in this
particular email then actually it has no
metadata and that's not surprising
because this installer is in fact where
this file is in fact a self-extracting
archive which contains the real
installer of silly vaccine but then it
also contains another file called as the
patch 4.0 which will okay but when you
look at the metadata you see it's
supposedly related to microsoft
automatic updates which is again highly
suspicious now we decided to look deeper
in this file and it turns out that
actually this file is a signed binary if
you look the issue up in Google we come
to a Kaspersky report about the dark
hotel apt very alarming and then we
decided to dig deeper and analyze this
file so we did some analysis we realized
that this is actually the stage 1
malware from a known campaign called
jakku uncovered by force point in 2016
now what is jakku jakku is it was an
ongoing botnet campaign i targeted main
North Korea and Japan and while it
infected a lot of victims the later
stages of the malware stages 2 & 3 were
only used against a select group of
individuals with North Korea and
Pyongyang being the common theme between
them now another interesting connection
that was outlined by force point is
between jakku and dark hotel which is
really further evidence - this kind of
an interesting connection on top of what
we saw with the certificate used
previously
now who could be the target here it
could be the case that every silly
vaccine installation is bundled with
this malware
but we really don't think so we actually
think that the target was Martyn
Williams who deals vastly with North
Korea and it is possible that this
particular malware was used against him
so this is pretty much the end I would
like to before I let you go like to
summarize everything that we've seen in
this talk and let's look back and see
those things so for one we have seen
that silly vaccine has been illegally
using Trend Micro's engine and it is it
was not a one-time thing it has been
done at least two times and probably
over multiple versions and for several
years then we've also seen that the
authors of CV vaccine tried to conceal
the fact that they used this engine with
some interesting mechanism then we've
seen that there's an explicit white
listing of a particular signature and
that the installation of sealing vaccine
comes bundled with the malware called
jakku
now while having these understandings we
still have some unanswered questions for
instance we've seen that there are some
artifacts that point at the fact that
the code of silly vaccine might have
been recompiled with some other
optimizations that were not in trend
micro's engine in the first place so
having said that how did the silly
vaccine authors obtain such an access to
a proprietary source we have no idea
also this whitelisted signature
we cannot say what it represents
it's a heuristic signature so we cannot
really tell if it was trying to
whitelist malicious tool or a benign
software it's not very clear and then
also this yaku malware since we only
have one instance of this particular
software from 2013 it's hard to say if
it's bundled with all versions only with
this one and while I can't answer all of
these questions concisely I do want to
point out that throughout this research
we've seen a lot of effort done to
develop this particular product and
through this effort we've stumbled upon
quite many illegal and shady practices
employed by the DPRK to develop their
own homebrew software a software that
remember may be some time another time
and in a perfect world could have been
totally legitimate and with that in mind
I would like to thank you for your
attention
and hope you enjoy your time at CCC
[Music]
[Applause]
Thank You Mara that was wonderful
we have plenty of time for questions and
we have two microphones one is in the
middle of their own and one is to the
left side of the stage so please queue
up if you want to ask questions and we
already have a question on microphone 1
2000 in the other engine excuse me could
you repeat the question and raise your
hand because I don't see you do you have
any idea if I say truth 20 micro and not
any other engine like an open-source
engine for example do I have any idea of
Trend Micro's tools is what I'm sorry do
you have any idea by 20 micro was chosen
by them ah why try your heads so
actually I have no idea I really thank
you if you know then tell me please yeah
microphone - so have you look at the
fact that this anti viruses and XE so it
runs on Windows but North Korea runs red
star s which is the UNIX well as far as
I could tell from people I discussed
with who do know a few things about
North Korea actually red star OS is not
the most common operating system there
in fact it's barely used because well to
say shortly it's shit but they do use
what seems to be some kind of Chinese
versions of Windows XP and Windows 7 so
this is intended to run on these
operating systems thank you another
question from Mike 1 how did you get the
2005 version of the antivirus come to me
later and I'll tell you
mic one please yeah I just wanted to
know if you check that the bondage a
coup Myra was not part of this whitelist
problem oh yes we checked it actually
this was not the whitelisted signature
it was actually not detected by silly
vaccine but it was also not detected by
Trend Micro it was not detected by
anyone actually so it was not the
whitelisted signature thank you that's
all
thank you Mark thank you
[Music]