[Music]
yes it's not an amazing avoider
so this is to talk about archeological
studies studies in data wastes given by
Caterina no Kong a blogger author but
many of you will know her as a privacy
activists and the one full letty warm
applause to these two speakers and
welcome to the English translation of
this talk we are always glad for your
feet back under the hashtag c3t Twitter
account is c3 lingo yeah thank you nice
how all the hells are performing
something with the French announcement
question I would like to ask at first
how many people here have bought their
Christmas presents at Amazon I would say
roughly half please keep your hands up
because we'll continue who of you who
did only do the research at Amazon and
then bought elsewhere are there people
were there then would we get people that
more people would people add to that so
not many people were added but I think
there's a far more than 50% it's hard to
see but those that showed up will surely
agree with me when I say and it's quite
comfortable to do terribly comfortable
to do to research or even order anything
with one single supplier and you imagine
this as a very comfortable thing anyway
and I don't know who at the edge L made
the decision to have their ads on
Formula one cars but I think that person
has a great sense of humor because in
reality it's quite different right
those really well-paid drivers and fast
deliveries that's not
what you get in practice and with Amazon
I would say not at all
and one or rather will probably know
that you will then get these notices
that's the package would be given to
your neighbors or as this note says I
hid it in the trash so there's no and
that's if it was no guarantee that it is
really their best offer those that
haven't read it this was seen on in the
Tigers Topeka newspaper I hate the
packet in the trash in a blue paper
contain the blue paper container yes
what could possibly go wrong and that
really makes you happy when you think
how can we solve this problem and of
course Amazon has a product for that at
least for their US customers they can
now as a Prime customer decide that I am
using Amazon key and Amazon key was then
is it's an intelligent lock system for
your door for your apartment door and
you can say well the Amazon deliverer I
trust them and they can place their the
packages in my corridor they can unlock
my door and appropriate for that there
is a video surveillance system for you
to control when the children are coming
home drunk or something and I don't know
would you feel like but I think that's
fairly creepy I would never do that
terribly creepy and I would I think very
hard who I should give access to my
apartment but as a privacy activists
I wondered isn't the insight that Amazon
gets into our lives through our clicking
behavior even more intimate than
harmless glance into the entrance of my
flat
those look into my flat my may know
something about how I live but there was
a know my online behavior they know when
I click well they could clean the way I
think and that is much more intimate and
[Music]
therefore in the last of the year of the
year before in 2016 I decided to conduct
an experiment I wanted to know what does
Amazon store about their users
and as part of that I've started to
order all my Christmas presents and
other presents from Amazon and to
research everything there to have a to
generate a record that would be as
complete as possible and my target was
my aim was from the beginning that I
want to have access to this data I want
to cut through it I want to see exactly
what Amazon stores about its users
because its customers because I don't
know if you know this but according to
article 15 of the European data
protection regulation gdpr everyone in
Europe has the right to always go to
their online service providers and ask
them for a free copy of all the data
they hold about you and they have to
deliver that in practice howdy no one
does that
and with Amazon's far as I knew no one
really went through with this to get
something usable out from them so I
decided I am going on a hunt for that
data what so what did I do
I bought a lot what did i buy well
almost 60 books within 14 months and if
you then wonder yes by now I have read
at least half of those yes I have I've
also bought practical things speed such
as chalk in a spray can a button machine
in my purchase profile we also had
strange things such as the lavender
spray that you can spray onto your
cushions if you're going to go to sleep
you may have heard about this what
unfortunately is not seen in the picture
is the home trainer that I bought it was
so successful that after three months I
sewed it on and I bought some usable
useful things - a mouse some files and
shoes and through Amazon I also became
the owner of the most beautiful house
shoes on the planet in 2017 I thought
well the estate user is now fairly well
fed with clicks and purchases so I'm not
going to
retrieve my data and unfortunately I
have to say that was the beginning of a
long and intensive Penn friendship with
the fifth departments at Amazon because
at first I did not receive what I wanted
but I kept asking questions and sometime
at some point they had sent me CDs so
first I had to go to my basement to see
how I could read out these antique data
volumes and on the first city
unfortunately I only had what I would
had expected a copy of the data that I
had already accessed online plus some
extra information not really what I had
wanted and I then kept nagging them and
received a second cd-rom actually I
received three the other was lost in the
post in in the trash probably and yeah I
looked at this last CD and wondered
what's on there and there were things
there like PDFs there where I could see
what searched queries I had used what
advertising him as I had responded to
and what in what time to the second and
what ads on you know on the website I
reacted to the interesting thing was an
excel sheets and that sheets had the
innocent name clickstream I opened that
sheet and it took a whole while to load
and at one point I saw all right
this sheet has fifteen thousand three
hundred and sixty-five parts there's a
lines and each of these lines have 50
columns fifty items of extra information
I went to the supermarket to visualize
this that's the amount of paper that it
would be printed out I had intended to
put this into one pair but that would
have been larger than me with theirs the
size of height of 170 because because
that would have broken down shortly I
put it into two piles and when Catarina
asked me whether I wanted to reevaluate
their data I first thought about my
database lecture the relationship
between customers and and of suppliers
what they buy but the data at Amazon is
not just purchases they basically save
everything we do on that website it does
matter whether we just go to the start
page or search for products or look at a
product indeed
they even store if we expand an image
and every interaction that we have when
we use our online profile with Amazon
because we have a foundation stock here
I thought I'd like to take you with me
and to the in the journey of the unknown
data and the things you can do with such
data in an exploitive analysis to really
understand what's in those data and what
you can see so as I said there are 50
columns called dimensions as well
because I kind of list all of them all
of them I try to broadly assign them to
categories we have time of course we
have account details such as whether you
are a Prime customer a business customer
a location information Amazon stores the
IP address not the last byte but
everything else but they also stories
which country which federal states and
which service provider you're in or use
to visit the data though there's the
website and also of course the URL that
you visit is stored and if it's a
product they also store the Product ID I
forgot about the session details the
session details are things like what you
see in the cookie as well so that you
see which session you're in and also
there is another ID that connects you
through all the services from Amazon and
identifies you with all these services
and regarding the navigation details you
can see where these things are going
they see where you come from see where
you go in the site and where you to
where you'd leave all that is stored
somewhere not just the history but also
what you do what kind of interactions
you do do you add something to the
shopping cart do you look at an image or
do you save something for later also
lasts you have we call Amazon internal
you see which web server the clear was
sent to and whether that clear Korea had
an internal IP address within Amazon but
you also receive a long list of all
these dimensions and explanations on
them what's behind them and sometimes
Amazon's does not store the clear text
but codes and codes things
zero might mean they put something into
the shopping cart so you think great
there's not so much to pass there but
then I realized when I looked at the
data in more detail that Amazon doesn't
tell you what they encode some cases are
simply unknown to us so let's say that
this pen friendship is continuing
because I had more answers regarding
that so if you look at this set of data
with those 50 columns you have 15,000
entries by used to to show you as an
example how they are set up you have the
date and action such a search or
purchase you have the URL the a
federal-state where it came from the
internet service provider the time it
took to load the page and not just for
those two entries but all the 15,000 365
ones which time period are we looking at
it starts on the 1st of August 2016 and
ends on the 31st of October 2017 so
that's 196 days with about 78 entries
per day if you have such an unknown data
set and work with it then I would always
use Python because that has more or less
been accepted as a standard for
analyzing data set like that so as soon
as whatever amazon says i will look at
those dimensions in detail how many
dimensions are there and how often were
they used some of them are always used
such as the date and time but other
dimensions aren't often used and we have
we had one dimension that was never
actually used something about images no
idea what's in there I then looked at
every dimension in detail what's in
there and how frequently this happens
and if and then I was looking at the
time this and I realized that this was
supposed to be to the second with second
precision but I cannot understand how
you can have 45 injuries in a single
second so then I thought ok let's look
at another column let's see what's in
there maybe that's just an outlier or
something you never know and then I
looked at
a single day you can of course aggregate
for a day and you can they get a
relative distribution and you have three
outliers which are very conspicuous as
they are high above everything else and
one that is 710 entries per day and I
don't know how intensively cata was
using Amazon on that on that day from
from early to late well that was quite
an achievement anyway so I looked at
that day in detail we have 710 entries
for the day and I wondered what's the
time range it's 20 minutes 35 seconds so
that's one entry every 1.74 seconds then
would have had to look like this so if I
would manage that at least at that point
I would perhaps consider a campaign
kicker as a pro-gamer and then I went
further into the data and do you have
these value accounts that would be used
in a histogram or something and and this
function I are really good friends by
now I really looked at this very closely
and see where things come from and I
realized that these actions are always
well defined it's actually stated about
four hundred and six four thousand six
hundred times and perhaps I thought
maybe it's not always easy to classify
and then there are other two interesting
things I just noticed a request and lazy
load these things I didn't consider much
of an interaction I am a web developer
so I thought maybe something else is in
that data so I looked at the URLs that
is connected to these entries and at
least with Ajax which is a web
technology I was only user interaction
let's look at the browser as I said I'm
a web developer as well and the browser
will tell us a lot about web sites and
the traffic was happening in the network
and you do that for Amazon as well and
just selected an image and looked at
what is loaded as you are on that page
and yes of course every page loads a lot
of stuff and as soon as that is finished
I think okay if that list I will search
for the URLs that I wasn't able to quite
understand earlier and yes surely these
are all images of things
that the buttons reviews that are loaded
later which in my view isn't reviews
interaction but it's all part of that
the critics Creek stream data so if you
look at the real user interactions from
the fifteen thousand and X entries I
assume that a single interaction has to
have a page action otherwise it's no
really user interaction so in its sick
those at first and then I don't want it
to be a request dialer because that
doesn't look like a user interaction
other and not a lazy load either and if
you take all that and just take it out
of from the data you have eliminated 75%
of the data and you're left with only
three thousand seven hundred and forty
seven entries that are real that I would
assume to be really user interactions I
don't know how many of you I use github
but I love this graph that shows you
interactions that you have do with
github and the same thing you could do
with Amazon I don't know if I would be
as so happy about that please every box
is for one represents one interaction
and the darker ones show the many
interactions you have on a single day
for example just before Christmas right
they are brave well-developed it doesn't
mean that every interaction leads to a
boy and I try to find out how Amazon
classifies purchases for example hey we
could look at page actions of course
Amazon would have nicely formatted data
like orders of purchases but nope
for some reason Amazon has a load of
data that you have to manually filter on
your data to get an idea on which
interactions are purchased and which are
not I couldn't also could not find out
in this enumeration of place orders if
there's any interactions between them so
I could not find that out from the data
set if you compare interactions versus
purchases from the 196 days
that I interacted with Amazon I only had
24 days and which I purchased something
but you can also see in December cata
bought four days in a row something and
you can also see that it was a lot of
books for example in December she bought
32 books in 4 days ok we'll leave the
topic of interactions and purchase and
we'll go towards the locations in which
Qatar was when she was browsing Amazon
the first thing I saw is that she was
mostly in Berlin when she interacted
with Amazon okay maybe she lives there
you also have the state of Brandenburg
and the circular Stein I don't know what
her interactions with mr. Kaufman are
she also had interactions from Northland
respond and a Lower Saxony and I don't
know how you guys do it but if you want
to leave Berlin you have to always leave
via Brandenburg and in the time where I
did this experiment I sometimes had to
go to elastic whole shrine so you can
see that and not rhine-westphalia is my
family and when you go there you have to
drive through Lower Saxony and I think
that I can see from this data set when I
visited my parents but we will see so
this was only the the column of the
states in which we were in so how does
Amazon no from so how does Amazon know
that my parents live in North
rhine-westphalia
well think about it just before
Christmas I visited them so that's how
Amazon knows so even though so you can
find out very private data about me so
then I looked at the Internet service
providers and one thing is something
that I've noticed some of them tell me
about what I do
for example cutter uses the fry phone
internet service provider in Hamburg and
then I saw something from 2017 vets when
she was on the Bahamas
not what you think about that was
holiday and in July 2017 she was in
Poland yes I was on a family holiday
where there was something else that I
noticed and I think that you have a
relationship to universities or
libraries
well yes I actually do like to write in
libraries some of you will know the
Doris forums nuts the German Eddie realm
this is a internet service provider for
universities and libraries and you can
also see that in the earth hundred
service provider data so what Amazon
does is you Amazon only allows 50
characters for the storage of the
Internet service provider name and the
Deuter is forums notes is too long to
store their what you can also see in the
data is how long is then a library
sometimes you're only there for a few
seconds maybe a bad bad conscience when
you're in a library and go to Amazon
sometimes you stay there for for a
minute and sometimes you're on Amazon
for 13 or 14 minutes maybe you're
procrastinating there but also on
Sundays you've been on Amazon for over
an hour
well that was only research you know so
something that I've also noticed in a
data set is that at some specific point
in time
Amazon tries to find out whether the tap
is in the foreground of the browser on
the background of the data since the
data set of Katya is limited I can't
find out beverages intentional or how
good it is I can't find out right now
with the limited data set whether Amazon
tries to improve this detection and
what's very interesting about the data
set is also that you don't need that
much technical understanding of how how
stuff works you can for example see and
column V and column V is about referrals
so that means where you're coming from
well
the page you visited before since you
come to when you come from Amazon and in
my case I found a specific website from
this media website Spiegel Online within
specific article and I was visiting that
page before I visited Amazon so that was
in my click screen so Amazon knows what
news I read maybe what political
affiliation I have I also found another
website on this
telepods list website this is a very
critical report about Sita so you can
think about Amazon knows which
politicals political articles I read
because that's in a referral so Amazon
can know my political affiliation and in
that case I actually did a campaign
against Sita and the circles name and
you can hardly I can't over stress how
threatening the difference between
products so boat and and products
clicked is for this talk I put
everything I had bought in that pair
time on my kitchen table but if I were
to list all the products so put all the
products I have looked at on a page in a
photo I wouldn't have had just to clear
out my kitchen table but my health flat
it just wouldn't put a pear fit in there
because there's so much more and what
you also saw in that data is that cata
more than 500 times were searching for
certain items or terms and that she
visited product pages a lot of times so
you could say that it's a lot more
because these are the more obvious
things but if you go into that dataset
manually and look for certain patterns
you can see that they're even more
products that we looked at and I then
wondered what does someone see that
doesn't know me personally but does know
my data trace what kind of person do
these people see and do I think that's
all right and I then looked at it
certain things I clicked at and looked
at it from different viewpoint
let's take the issue of life planning if
someone would ask themselves well what
how does Catalina know can imagine her
future what are her plans and then looks
at her clickstream what do they find I
bought a book that is deals with
arguments in favor of having children
but also another one that deals with
alternative partnerships and polyamory
and of course also a book about someone
who exited the economic system the
consume society and turned his back
turned her back on that and if you look
at these three products and maybe a few
more that are in there then you would
think okay well this is an extraordinary
very individual maybe difficult life
plan if you put this all on one hat but
how is this actually this book about
children I looked at because I was made
aware of the author because I like the
blog public and wanted to know what this
guy is also writing the second book is
one where I knew the author and was
invited to the reading and I wanted to
you know what the event is about and the
third book simply is one in with the
same publisher that I am using so I
wanted to know what the publisher I'm
going to use also publishers so that
means that click streams or the image
that generate is generated from that
click stream and the person who I am
that I really am probably two very
different things
let's take the issue of health that's
much more clear I looked at snaps
there's a single category for that it
with Amazon alcohol and you could
imagine why I have an interest in
schnapps well maybe I have some health
issues and I would like to self medicate
I also looked at a book about arthritis
a very severe disease and what's even
more shocking
I didn't just look at one two or three
but many books about cancer
one as an example Healing cancer
naturally and if you look at the creek
stream that way you would imagine that
Catalina no cone is a wreck in terms of
health but what is the real picture I
have to say that this tagine is really
good I really like drinking it the books
about severe diseases I looked at
because I was doing research I wanted to
know what the part of esoteric nonsense
in the Amazon bestsellers list is
concerning health and this intention you
cannot see if you just look at the click
stream I have neither suffering from
cancer North rightist and I have no
signs of that either and another
interesting thing is political opinion
in mic extreme there are there's a huge
number of books about the right-wing
alternative for Germany there are books
against the AFD but also books by write
extreme authors and conspiracy theorists
and if you just look at the click stream
you wouldn't you would probably consider
me a very strange or even not very
likeable person and you would think this
is a right-wing person but what the
thing really was I deal with the AFD
critically in my blog so I did research
and the research you do yeah well no one
can really support the a of da you
really have to say that and of course I
wanted to see what the other side writes
what do they publish what do the
hotheads publish and how high is this
placed on the best sellers list and if
you just look at my data you don't see
that you might consider me a right
extreme person myself
and this gets interesting if you
consider who would have an interest in
this data where there's data there is
interest and of course there are
authorities that would be interested to
query such new survey data everything
that's there and if the killke stream is
there it will be queried and imagine a
police officer that might think this
scatter person might be a cyber criminal
or maybe a potential threats there is a
potential threat that might emanate from
her and let's see if there are any
others have any any evidence to support
that thesis at that that theory what do
these people see well first of all they
say on my list is so-called killer game
and that looks extremely nice doesn't it
extremely likeable as if you look at
this from an authority point of view I
also looked at a black t-shirt with an
imprint that says chemists only because
superwoman is not an official job title
you could then wonder that I have
interesting skills and hobbies and
consider think that a next a suspicious
cooking device pot and a balaclava mask
and I don't know how users but from the
point of view of a government authority
that was not not look good at all if you
look at it through that kind of but that
kind of mindset you could consider that
to be a dangerous person and at that
point I think it would be high time for
a visit but of course there's a
completely simple and harmless
explanation for every product exactly
anyone could say that of course someone
says in the audience that would be the
counter-argument of course and that
would leave me in a very bad place but I
don't know how you feel but I think to
just have to think what kind of
consequence that could be from that kind
of data trash and worst case scenario I
find that extremely threatening
and cutter then gave me her trust to
look at the data and keep it
confidential but how does Amazon see
this Amazon is large Amazon is very
large about 300 million users and I did
this analysis for just one person Amazon
can analyze this for all those 300
million people and they can use see
patterns in that and they can see what
which products come together in the
shopping cart for example and what does
it mean for something to be in the
shopping cart amazon knows what do
people buy that buy this product and the
simplest example is the precise scale as
a cook you may want to know how much
goes in then how much have I put in
there already and if you buy this then
you immediately get these great
suggestions you watch all sensational
food of events that is a clear sign that
there are other uses for precise KS and
you're laughing but that could really
lead to serious consequences for someone
if they without their knowledge put in a
certain kateri that has nothing to do
with them for example if I look at a
device to cut glass a glass cutter I
will get recommendation for a balaclava
mask what do you get with right
equipments you can imagine yourself that
is a problem because I don't know do you
feel but I want to know which categories
I'm put into and I would like to have a
say if those categories are unpleasant
to me and I may think that some
categories simply should not exist and
the problem is that when querying my
data I just get this minut mosaic piece
of the whole data and the whole the
action information the possible
evaluation of possible insights or
conclusions I could only fully
understand if I know the whole thing but
Amazon will never release this and
Amazon will never release the algorithms
that they use on search queries or
something because that of course is a
business secret and trade secret and
that of course are the really
interesting data that we
need to really get a full insight in the
way this company looks at us and how
they manipulate us in a targeted way to
tell us to buy more for example once and
I don't know what you think about this
but the name Amazon is very fitting so I
don't know who thought up the name but
it's great because the Amazon the Amazon
River is the biggest river in South
America and he is he has a lot of little
rivers that run into it so it's similar
to my experiment I only used one one
Amazon um product but I could have also
used a lot of Amazon products what would
have been for example what if I looked
all videos with Amazon Prime video what
would have happened if I decided to
include Alexa also Amazon echo for
example if I put in Amazon echo in my
bedroom I think my dataset would have
been a lot more interesting and I for my
part decided cognitively I do not want
to do that that is too much I will not
put an Amazon echo in my bedroom on
foreign power for homebuyers and a few
weeks ago I was very happy that I did
not but I did that decision a few weeks
at that time because I don't know if you
if you notice it was in the news another
user asked his data from Amazon about
his Amazon echo and he received an
entire different data set from another
person so that's something that you
definitely should not put into your
bedroom
just to reiterate if you use a lot of
these services you use the same Amazon
ID and that is true that is also what is
being stored in the Amazon dataset so if
you use other Amazon services with the
same login address it's definitely in
the same cookie it's in the cookie which
ID you use so now you think well it's
great you have your data but what about
my data how do I get my data there are
different ways on how to get your data I
can tell you how I did it so first I
read through the AGB the terms and
conditions and I read it in its entirety
which was a unique experience for me and
I also looked through the data privacy
statement and in both of these and
documents their categories listed so I
can see what I will also I used my
common sense and to just consider to
think to consider what I could actually
expect from the terms from the point of
view of logic I am at Amazon and one
week later I get an email whether do you
really want to buy this product so they
have to have have stored for one week
what I bought or didn't buy and when
they say we don't do that that's of
course a lie because otherwise
technically it would be very hard to
implement this and from that information
I built a checklist with my expectations
of what a full statement should contain
and only then did I formulate my request
to access my own data and I cannot
stress enough how important it is if you
apply for your data to always set a
deadline without a deadline nothing we
move the gdpr
does have a time frame in which they
should respond to you that that is one
month but it's
never wrong to explicitly state this
deadline in your statement and remind
them when that deadline is passed and
what can also be motivating if you put
its things like in there if you don't
reply then I will ask the authorities
the controllers and that query of sadly
is not enough if you put in that
application you have to expect a pain
friendship that might be nice thing if
you get this put in this request for the
high property you first received the
answer well look at into your profile
that has all your data that is koffice
of course there's nonsense that only
contains a small fraction of the data
you want so send them a friend reminder
next then there you may have letter an
email saying yeah we have your data here
and you look in there and think okay
someone just printed out the profile or
copied it and and put that into a PDF so
not what you want to have you shouldn't
accept that at all
so another friend reminder then you have
reached the next level and at some time
there will be some insight and oh
there's we found some data here and now
we'll send them to you that's the point
where that CD arrives and at that point
it gets interesting because the
probability that they play this kind of
game for that you have to repeat it for
a while is quite high and if you repeat
it often enough that then you will have
your whole data set and that data set
you can now search at will analyze and
believe me it's worth it because it's
one thing to abstractly know that you
are being surveilled by every step and
click and a completely different thing
to see your own broken sleep rhythms for
a whole year in front of you and that is
something is something I would not
interest to any retailer
and I then asked myself do I want this
and everyone that sees the state said
will surely ask themselves the same
question and in my case the decision was
that in the future I will buy my bought
books directly from the supplier not via
Amazon Marketplace and at one time or
other I even saved money this way and
the information about that is being
stored will probably enable us to say I
am going to use the service differently
or I may not use it at all and if you
don't use it at all then I would
recommend you can actually hand in
request for deletion might also lead to
a pen friendship and we in this talk
considered that we do not want to say
that this is an individual problem by in
by users that are using Amazon no the
problem is that Amazon acts just like
many other services to be honest
surveillance has been has for long
become the norm and what that means for
the individual we wanted to make visible
but we still think that we all together
have to fight that privacy data
protection security has have to be the
standard the defaults
young dumb at something yes and that
gets me to the end to get us that gets
us to the end so you have all kinds of
information on my blog on how to ask for
your data and if you're interested in
the data analysis I have published on
Amazon no on github there's a repository
called Amazon where everyone can look at
the data and see their own broken sleep
patterns yes thanks a lot
huge applause
[Music]
you