[Music]
so Janice biomass is a software engineer
and he started tinkering with Commodore
64 when he was 8 years old
and he was kind of a teenage hacker of
games as well and now he's in the
security field and he got interested in
the fax machine together with his friend
al it kin who is also a security guy and
malware researcher and together they're
gonna tell us about the fax machines and
what the facts were still using people
those machines and it's gonna be really
interesting I think and the title is
also hacking your network like it's 1980
again and really excited please give a
warm round of applause to those two guys
[Applause]
thank you thank you guys
hi CCC you probably know this sound
right and now get to know us so my name
is Jenny Varmus I'm a security
researcher I walk a checkpoint research
and with me here today is a Aladin also
a security researcher also it's a
checkpoint research and let's begin with
talking a bit about the history of facts
so I guess that not many of you know
that stack started it was first invented
in 1846 by a scientist called Alexander
Bane fun fact this was this happened 20
years before the invention of the light
bulb and then it had some more advances
to it this is the actual first thing
that looked like effects machine like a
standard fax machine and again this
thing was invented 20 years before the
invention of the telephone
so humanity was sending faxes before we
had light or talked over the phone and
and then there was some more
advancements like radio fax and another
report important point in time is 1966
were a small unknown company called
Xerox invented came out with the first
commercial fax machine this is the
advertisement for it and in 1980 strange
organization called ITU defined the
current standards for fax name leads
teetered 84 86 and those standards are
still the same standards that we use
today basically with just minor changes
to them so this was all in the past but
what's happening today I mean today we
have far better ways to send electronic
documents from one to the other right
you know let's compare fax to just I
don't know off the top of my head just
you know one method like let's say email
and just to you know remind you we are
comparing this to this okay so let's
look at some of the features here in
terms of quality yeah okay in terms of
accessibility I'm
be sure that all of you here you here
have 24 by 7 access to emails not so
sure you're carrying around your fax
machines with you in terms of
reliability well you know when you send
a fax you don't really know if it got
received or not yes there is this
strange confirmation page but it doesn't
really mean anything I mean if there's
no paper in the receiving fax you still
get it if the dog ate the date you still
get it so there's absolutely no
reliability in facts and regarding
authenticity well we can argue about
emails if it's authenticated or not it
could be forged of course but we do have
public key crypto cryptography and stuff
like that that will help us when talking
about emails what we don't have we don't
have nothing when it comes to fax
absolutely no authenticity so if we're
looking at this table one might think to
himself okay so who the hell still use
this fax today it's 2018 I mean it
deserves a place in the Museum of great
technologies and that's it
so nobody is using fax today right yeah
wrong everybody are using fax today and
and you see fax is used like to send
this very critical maritime maps to see
ships that open seas 90% of the Japanese
population uses fax according to
Wikipedia at least and if you google any
kind of combos like contact us and facts
or stuff like that you will come up with
something like 300 million results 300
million published fax numbers in Google
and that's not counting the unpublished
numbers right that's a huge amount of
numbers but it's not all about numbers I
mean it's not how many fax machines are
out there but it's also who is using fax
you see if you're a small cooperate and
medium cooperate a huge cooperate you
have fax not necessarily anybody is
sending fax to this number but there is
a fax machine sitting there waiting to
for effects to be received if you're a
bank you simply love faxes this is Bank
of China the biggest banker of the world
in the world and that's the fax number
of it and I think most importantly if
you're a government
you simply wake up in the morning and
you want to have more facts so this is
Donald Trump's fax number if anybody
wants to send in the fax go ahead that's
it it's not a secret it's from Google so
we should send him something by the way
yeah so yeah and the thing is that you
know those banks and government
institutions they don't only support Fox
allow you to send fax the funny thing is
that actually most of the time it's
mandatory to send fax there is no other
way you can either post I'll mail it or
fax it they didn't hear about anything
else so we looked at this state of
affairs strange state of affairs and set
ourselves you know this looks strange I
mean it can it can be true the humanity
came so far and we are still using these
old technologies so what the facts and
like we decided to try and do something
about it and we started a very long
research to try and find some security
vulnerabilities in fact and before we do
that let me just you need to explain how
fax looks like today you see today if X
doesn't look like it looked 20 or 30
years ago then it was just standalone
fax machines right
today fax is mostly all technology
embedded within newer technologies so I
mean we have fax to email services or
email to fax services we have like as I
said before radio facts and facts over
satellite and stuff like that and I
think most commonly we have these these
machines all-in-one printers like you
buy them they scan the print and they
fax it actually comes with a phone cable
out of the box so you can connect I
guess most people connected and I also
think that this is the most common
faxing solution today so we decided to
take a look at these machines these fax
machines and if you look at these boxes
from a security point of view you can
imagine them to be just black boxes
right and those black boxes has
interfaces so in one side of the box we
have interfaces like Wi-Fi Bluetooth
internet stuff like that these
interfaces connects the
printer to the internal network the
external network basically it connected
to the world right and on the other side
of this box there's this little
interface here that connects the this
black box to somewhere to the 1970s I
would say so yeah that that's pretty
funny and and you know if you remember
that at the end the end of the day these
printers are basically nothing but
computers I mean they have CPUs they
have memories they have operating
systems there are computers not standard
ones but they are computers and we were
thinking to ourselves imagine this
scenario right there's an attacker
sitting somewhere in the world all he
has is access to a phone line and his
targets fax number what will happen if
this attacker this guy would be able to
send a malicious fax and with this
malicious fax he will be able to exploit
the printer then he's completely as
complete control over the printer right
if it does that he could then maybe
pivot through any one of those other
interfaces let's say the internet and
jump from this printer to the rest of
the network that the internal network
effectively creating like a bridge
between the external world in the
internal network through the phone line
that's 1980s a game so we thought that
this is a really cool at attack scenario
and we decided to accept this challenge
and go for it and try and actually show
this thing happening in reality we were
really excited about this but then after
we slept a bit and drank a bit and sat
down and talked about it we kind of
found out that there is like a lot of
challenges really hard challenges in
front of us and it's we're not really
sure how to deal with them let me name
just just a few of them so one of the
challenges is how do we obtain the fewer
the code that this printer runs it's not
like you have it everywhere and after we
get it how do we analyze this framework
have to analyze that we need to
understand what operating systems are
those printers running and then we need
to understand how to debug a brick I
never debug the printer before and I
need to understand how to debug a
printer and after
we do all that we need to understand how
does Fox even work we only know the
beeping sounds like most of us I think
and after we did all that we can start
talking about where can we find
vulnerabilities inside this big big big
ecosystem and today we will try to take
you through these challenges one by one
and explain how to do it and till we'll
be able to actually do the thing that we
just the scenario that we just showed
you so let's start with the first
challenge how do we obtain the fever for
the printer yeah so meet our nice
printer it's an HP printer printer and
an HP Officejet printer we chose this
model for first of all we chose HP
because it has like I think 40% of the
market share so it's not that we dislike
HP we really like them but unfortunately
for them they are just the biggest
target out there and this specific model
well we have a lot of reasons why we
chose this printer but basically it's
the cheapest one yes so we bought that
we didn't have a lot of budget we bought
it and we abused it for a lot of time
and our goal was to break the plain the
break facts right but before we do that
we had to break the printer and I mean
literally break the printer so yeah that
was the fun part of the project we broke
it and inside the printer we find this
thing the main PCB the brains behind the
printer and it looks like this let's
snap the critical components of it so we
have here a flash romance pension some
model and then we have some more memory
here this might look like not a lot
because the PCB has two sides to it
of course and on the on the other side
of it we have the more interesting
components like USB Wi-Fi electricity
SRAM battery probably for the memory but
who knows
and now we have two very interesting
components here one of them is the main
CPU it's a Marvel CPU and it's probably
manufactured for HP so we can't you know
tell anything about there's no available
specs nothing we can just find bits of
information here and there and then we
have the fax modem it's located here and
it's a it's a CSP 1040 and what we need
to understand now is how does these two
components operate and what is the
relationship between them if we do that
we one step further so that's what we
try to do and as I said the challenge is
to the first challenge at least is to
get the femur of this thing and when
we're looking a bit closer into this PCB
we find this very - very interesting
interfaces one of them is a serial debug
the other is JTAG so if you familiar
with them so you know that they give you
like debugging capabilities or at least
memory read memory right exactly what we
need to get the film were so we're
smiling to ourself saying huh that's
gonna be really easy but unfortunately
it's not because the JTAG of course is
disabled completely we can do anything
with it and the serial port well we
managed to connect to it and we get this
terminal that for almost every
instruction we type gives us this evil I
don't understand well we don't
understand either but it looks like this
terminal is not gonna get us very far so
we dropped this pet and and try and look
for other ways to get the film work and
obviously one of the most common ways is
to try and get grab the film or upgrade
and we after looking a bit in the inner
Internet we find this jewel this FTP
site by HP that contains every finger
version for every HP product ever
produced in the history of HP n and the
internet and a lot of other stuff and it
actually took us like about I think two
weeks to find our theme were within this
mess of favors but once we did we had we
had a few more upgrade file yes thank
you it's still alive so you can go there
look for something there's a lot of
interesting stuff in there and now we
got ourselves a file this file is a few
more upgrade file it's not an executable
file it's just the binary and now we
kind of need to understand how do you
even upgrade the printer fumer I mean I
never did it before anybody did anybody
upgraded this a few more lately good
good for you but for you anyway the
answer to this question is surprisingly
funny I would say yeah you just print it
yeah that's because you see a printer
receives a few more upgrades
just the same way as it receives a
normal print job then that's that thing
it's actually pretty nice and it's
defined in HP protocol it's called PCL
Excel future reference protocol class
2.1 supplement that if you are still
sane after reading this like 300 pages
of insanity you understand that this
thing defines something called a pjl a
print job language if you ever scanned
the printer to the network you see this
port I think 9100 something like that
open that's the pour that you send print
jobs to and that's the same port that
you send the film or upgrade to and
that's that's nice so when we look at
the file it actually confirms this
because it actually begins with the
words pjl printing print job language so
that's nice so now we know it's a
printer of language but unfortunately
this document doesn't document anything
about the few more upgrade a protocol or
anything because kind of HP proprietary
so unfortunately we had to like do it
ourselves and analyze this thing now I'm
not I'm not going to take you through
the entire process of unwrapping this
fumarole because frankly it's quite
boring but I'll just tell you that it's
composed of several layers of
compression one of them is called an al
decoder the other is called TIF decoder
and another one called as a row decoder
and the thing is that these things do
something like you know if the previous
line was all blanks then if this line is
also all blanks just write one instead
of the line so that gives you some kind
of compression and it makes really a lot
of sense when you're talking about print
jobs because you know print paper has a
lot of spaces in it but when you're
talking about binary file
it makes absolutely no sense to do it
this way but still you know it just
works this way so we often understand
this that we were able to decode
everything they compress everything and
we're talking to us selves and laughing
that you know when you're a hammer
everything looks like a nail and when
your printer everything looks like a
print job so yeah that was nice and now
after we did that we have a big file
that hopefully now it's our framework so
how do we analyze it so looking at this
thing right at the beginning of the
filer something that really looks like a
table and it's not doesn't really only
look like a tablet it is a table we
define it it looks like this and what
this table defines is like a loading
address section name and location in
binary so what did that means that our
big file is actually split into several
sections and this table just defines
those sections so now we are able to
split this big file into several smaller
chunks and inspect each chunk and the
most important chunk the most the one
that looks most promising looks like it
contains our framework so we took a
closer look into that and that's what we
saw I mean it actually looks like our
framework that's because you see that's
like one of the strings that we see in
it yeah we saw we all saw that before
right it's a oh I don't understand but
it's not completely Aero I don't
understand right there's some missing
bytes in here and we actually those
missing bytes are pretty consistent
throughout the entire chunk so although
we know that we are looking at the code
we can actually see the code until we
have those missing by its field we need
to understand why are they there and
what were they replaced with so let's
try to analyze this thing together
quickly now but first let's start to
understand what is this thing we have a
lot of things in mind everyone looked
seem crazy but I think the least
craziest option was that this is yet
another form of compression a really bad
one again because when we try to
compress this thing with dilip for
example we get like 80% better
compression than it currently is so and
we know that the printer has really
because we see
zip strings in there so why not use a
lip I don't know
but still we are left with the challenge
so this is one snippet of the code that
you just saw and let's try to decompress
this so first of all you need to
understand this thing is composed of two
types of characters one our ASCII
character stuff that you can read and
some other stuff that you can't read non
ASCII characters and those non ASCII
characters are actually those missing
bytes that we have so we need to
understand what they are so let's take a
closer look at them and if you stir this
thing long enough you will start seeing
some kind of pattern and I'll save you
the trouble and just show you that it
codes composed of like these one single
bytes and then those double bytes in
there and if the distance between the
single bytes looks suspiciously pattern
is 8 bytes 9 bytes 9 bytes 8 bytes over
and over again so what does this mean
where is the pattern here if you look at
this from a different angle
maybe the pattern will look a bit
clearer you see the F 7 and F 7 they
look the same the FF & FF they look the
same something here looks really
patination in order to understand this
pattern you need to sharpen your binary
view of it a bit and if you understand
that FF is just 1/8 one bit and if
you'll do this consistently for all of
these chunks then you'll start seeing
the pattern you see the pattern is that
the zero bit always falls within this 2
byte hole and what this means it's
consistent what the file what this means
is that the first byte is just a bitmap
describing the following 8 bytes after
it there what it means and that's
perfect because now we understand what
is this single byte but we still don't
understand what are those double bytes
and they will be placed with something
but with what so if you know anything
about compression you know that there's
not a lot of options here really it
could be either a forward or backward
pointer it could be a dictionary of some
sort or it could be a sliding window now
we can pretty easily confirm that it's
not a forward backward pointer just
because we try to follow the references
in the file we see nothing that we
should be there same goes for dictionary
we can't find anything that's consistent
enough to be a dictionary so it leaves
us with only with the option of sliding
window
and once we were equipped with this
information we go to our favorite place
to Google and try to find some similar
implementations to this and luckily for
us in some very dark corner of the
Internet we find this wiki page defined
something called soft disc library
format and I would I won't ask if
anybody knows who what something is soft
disc is because probably somebody knows
here it's CCC after all but inside this
thing it defines some kind of
compression algorithm that looks very
similar to ours it looks actually really
really like ours actually it's exactly
our compression algorithm so so yeah
that's nice and I think the funny thing
here is that this compression algorithm
was used in the past somewhere and only
there can you guess well yeah somebody
who didn't see the I didn't see this
presentation before yeah it was used in
Commander Keen and soft disk is the
company who produced Commander Keen so
the compression algorithm from Commander
Keen made its way somehow into the HP
the entire HP a line of products
how I don't know you can check if there
was anybody who was fired from salts of
this can hired in HP probably that would
be my guess but we'll never know so now
we understand exactly what is this thing
and how does this compression work we
have the missing data that we need and
this data means that those two bytes are
actually composed of window.location and
data linked and that's all we need and
let me show you like really quickly how
this compression works so we have an
input text output text and
sliding-window we want to compress this
string over here and let's try and do it
so first byte is the bitmap I remind you
so we leave it empty for now and then
second byte we start with a so we place
it both in the output text and in the
sliding window and then we go to B same
thing C same thing D again and now we
get to a but a is already present in the
sliding window so we don't need to write
it in the output text you know we can
just write just do nothing and then go
to be same thing is just the following
character in the sliding window and then
when we get to e we just write 0 0 0 2
that means go to the sliding window at
position 0 and take the first two bytes
that's what it means and then we
continue to e FG after we did that we
put our bitmap here and now we know the
bitmap bitmap value and that's all there
is to it that's the compression
algorithm it's pretty easy looking at at
it this way right looking at it it
reverse is a bit more difficult but yes
now we can do that and now we completely
open everything and yes we have our
frame where we can read everything it's
actual code and now we need to
understand what does this code mean and
basically first of all we need to
understand what architecture is this
what is the operating system and so on
and so on
so it took us quite some time to do that
but let me give you a brief explanation
first of all the operating system is
called tread X it's a real-time
operating system the CPU the processor
is armed line big in the end and then it
has like several components to it like
stuff that's related to system some
common libraries and tasks tests are the
common the equivalent of processes in
normal operating systems so in the
system stuff we have like boot loaders
some networking functionality and some
other stuff common libraries we have a
lot of common libraries and tasks once
we are able to isolate them we can
understand exactly the tests and once we
do that we now know that we all we need
to do is like to focus on these tasks
because they are the tasks relevant to
fax protocols we can leave everything
else aside it will make our work much
more easy and we don't we want to start
doing that but just a second before we
do that looking at this we see something
that looks not really I don't know it
doesn't make sense a lot and this thing
is SpiderMonkey the printer every HP
printer contains a SpiderMonkey library
I don't know if you know what
SpiderMonkey is but basically it's the
JavaScript implementation by Mozilla
it's used in Firefox for example and we
were thinking to ourselves why does a
printer need to render JavaScript it
makes no sense I mean yeah it has a web
server but it's not a web client we
couldn't think of any situation in which
a printer needs to render JavaScript it
looked really strange to us so we
decided to like try and see where is
this printer exactly using javascript so
we went back a bit and checked and we
found that javascript is used in a
feature called PAC proxy
auto-configuration
it's apparently something no it's it's
pretty common it's a common thing it's a
good protocol and it like defines proxy
when you're doing a DHCP or something
like that the thing is that the top
layer functionality of this entire pack
functionality was written by by HP and
when we were looking at that we see all
this functionality and we see this
strange thing here the printer
once it does this patch functionality it
tries to connect this domain fake URL
one two three four com just connect to
it and do nothing with it some sort of
sanity test I guess I don't really know
why but the interesting thing here is
that do you know who owns the domain
fake URL one two three four com no it's
not HP
a check point is kind of yeah yeah I own
it yeah it just wasn't registered so we
registered it for $5.00 and now every HP
printer is connecting to my domain so if
anybody wants to buy the domain I have a
very good price for you more than five
dollars and now I'll hand it over to Al
to continue okay thank you
after we finished messing around with
spidermonkey it's time to focus back on
facts or t30 t 13 it's full name its
itu-t recommendation T 30 he's the son
of the defines the fax protocol actually
it's a very very long PDF more than 300
pages but defines all of the faces and
messages we need in order to send and
receive a fax document it was for design
very long ago 1985 and was last updated
more than a decade ago some from our
perspective that's a very good idea
because we want to find vulnerabilities
in an old and complicated for the call
we are most probably going to find some
after we read through the standard we
started to dynamically look at it you
open it in Ida and look up on the t30
task and you can see that the state
machine is quite huge as you can see
here in Ida and actually that's a small
state machine because most of the code
blocks you can see over here contains
additional state machines inside them
meaning that this is going to be a very
very huge and complicated state machine
to reverse and if that wasn't enough it
turns out that HP really likes to use a
function pointers and global variables
in their code meaning that statically
reverse engineering this huge task is
going to be very complicated although I
personally prefer to statically
reverse-engineer this time we had to
choose a different tactic we'll need to
dynamically reversing
this thing and for this we need to have
a debugger and I didn't even mentioned
earlier nobody knows how can we debug it
polenta we already tried the built-in
JTAG and serial port and that failed we
then searched for built in gdb stuff we
could use but I couldn't find any such
stuff at this point it's very important
to remember that even if we could
control the execution flow no one can
put a debugger without controlling the
execution flow and we can't do anything
that's a black box I can send papers and
that's it and even if I could control
the execution flow and load my debugger
the pointer uses a hard will watchdog
and this is an external hardware
mechanism but monitor is the main CPU
and whenever many CPU enters an endless
loop or halts the watchdog reboots the
entire film window and this means that
since essentially a breakpoint halts the
program whenever will hit a breakpoint
the watchdog will kill us so we need to
find a way around this thing and this is
this way we could find out is to speed
this enormous task into chunks if we
could find any code execution
vulnerability we could try to execute
code over the printer and load the own
debugger and the disease stage we had
luck and we believe that luck is an
important part in every research project
Stanley on the night of the 19th of July
central publish the vulnerability called
David's IV David's IV is a remote code
execution in G soap and many embedded
devices and our printer included tend to
implement a web server for management
and configuration and in our case this
web server uses G soap and it even uses
a vulnerable version of G so so we now
have our vulnerability and we'll need to
exploit it for others of you are not
familiar we have Devas IV here is the
code and here's the vulnerability itself
devil's IV is an signed integer
the flow of vulnerability meaning that
we'll need to send enough data for the
variable to go from negative back to
positive and that means we need to send
Rafi to jjigae bytes of data to the
printer
so HP really pride itself on the
printing speed of the printers but not
on the network speed after many
optimization rounds we managed to reduce
the exploit time to roughly seven
minutes so you start the exploit you
wait and after seven minutes you have
your exploit and here I'll stock of good
luck ended because we had the side
effect in our exploit and after two to
ten minutes
the printer will crash and this means
we'll need to wait an additional seven
minutes we'll have two minutes to debug
it and then it will crash again so we're
waiting a lot we waited a lot of seven
minutes in our research if we recall we
wanted a debugger so we could
dynamically reverse-engineer the film
well we wanted to read memory and write
memory and now we have a debugging
vulnerability so we could load a
debugger we need to execute this
debugger so we'll need execute
permissions and to load it and the most
if noted thing is that we need to
execute our debugger without crashing
the funeral because we want the debugger
to run and in favor to debug and we want
them to blend inside the virtual address
space of the printer living happily
together we couldn't find any debugger
that achieved these goals so I did what
my brother usually tells me not to do we
actually wrote our own debugger so this
is Celt Scout is an instruction based
debugger it supports Intel CPUs and arm
CPUs because we have an album printer
yeah as a prototype we had a Linux
kernel driver and this time we're going
to use it in its in embedded mode
embedded mode we compile it to be fully
positioned in the parent because we
essentially throw it somewhere inside
the framework and we expect it to
execute
we equip it with useful address spaces
like mem copy socket by listen we find
using Ida and whenever twice to call
these functions it goes to its own God
finds the address and jumps to it so
after we compile it we use it in our
exploit we jumped in we jump into this
blob and it starts up a TCP server we
can now connect to to send instructions
to read memory to write memory and
whatever we want you can find Scout in a
github with the examples for Linux
kernel driver and embedded mode and
we're actually using it for some cities
now so it's highly recommended now that
we read this point in our talk we
haven't yet described to you how effects
actually works so we with we've scaled
we dynamically reverse-engineer the film
we're and now we can actually describe
to you how effects actually works in
order to set of facts we need a sending
machine we need to send it to some modem
the packets form the modem will be
processed in the CPU and afterwards the
data is going to be processed and
probably printed let's see how it starts
we start with network introduction
probing and raging take over Eliza echo
canceling more training and you actually
need to be quite familiar with these
steps because they sound like this
with these beeps we actually created an
HDL seat tunnel through this tunnel
we're going to send our t30 messages to
the cpu in T 30 you have faced a we
which we send the caller idea which is
this wing in phase B you negotiate the
capabilities so I send my capabilities
and received apprentice capabilities
tracy is the important step because you
actually send our fax data line of the
line page of the page in phase B we
finish I send an ACK I receive an ACK
and that's it let us now see how a
normal black and white fax document is
going to be sent for the protocol so we
have our document is going to be sent
over the hdl-c tunnel using 230 messages
over phase C and the received document
is actually the body of a tiff file
compressed in g3 g4 compressions
from our perspective that's partial good
news because there are many
vulnerabilities when parsing TIFF
headers and we only control the data of
the file the headers themselves are
going to be constructed by the printer
itself using messages from phase a and
phase B so we partially control a tiff
file and after it's done and ready that
the file is going to be printed like
every good water call and here's gums
very interesting t30 supports many
extensions can you guess what
interesting extensions there are in the
protocol so it was a security extension
but no one uses it so the other
extension is color extension actually
you can send colorful faxes and the
British use it in hospitals for some
reason let's see how a fact that you
have a colorful fax works we send a
document for hdl-c tunnel over face C
and the received document is actually a
jpg file this time you control the
header and the date of the file and we
can do whatever we want with it and send
it for painting now that we know how a
fax actually works where should we look
for vulnerabilities in it well we have
complicated state machine
withstand strings though several fine
layers but the most convenient layer is
duplicative one and most importantly
JPEG because we control the entire file
we can if we look on a JPEG file it
mainly consists of markers we have a
start of market application market we've
lengthened data more markers we've
lengthened data and so on and so on
if we zoom in on one such marker we can
see that in this market we have a
compression table a four before
compression matrix for the exact
document we send we have a header length
field for before matrix and the data
itself if you zoom in a bit deeper we
can see that here we get the matrix we
sum up all of the values this matrix
should be rather sparse with zeros ones
and twos the accumulated value is going
to be a length field in this case six
bytes and six bytes are going to be
copied from the data to a local small
stock buffer like this so if you can see
the vocal ability at this point we were
like what effects because what doesn't
make sense we control the entire header
if we put huge values in our matrix like
so we'll have a 4 kilobyte length field
copied into a stack buffer 256 bytes
effectively having a stack-based buffer
overflow in a pointer it's a trivial
stack buffer overflow we have no bite
constraints we can use whatever we want
null by its non ASCII by its whatever we
want and 4 kilobyte refusal control
later that's moving enough to exploit on
this point we had to bypass several
operating system and security
mitigations now and not exactly it's
it's an outdoors fixed art spaces no
Canaries it's the ideas it's really
simple we've got the CVS from HP 9.8
critical you should really perch up
Windows now and here you can see the
response received from HP after we
worked with them to catch these
vulnerabilities which is a good time for
our know
[Music]
taxes on slope yeah yeah
so from even a taker of course we can
forge this easily and now the printer is
receiving the fax and processing it and
now it's obviously a color colorful fax
and now we have full control over the
printer so it's ours but that's not
enough because we want to show that we
can propagate to another computer so our
tax our malicious facts contained
eternal blue in it so once any computer
is connected to the network that the tax
now will recognize it and we try to
exploit it and here you go
yeah yeah yeah so so we've made it after
all it was a long way some conclusions
we have to tell you first PSTN seems to
still be a valley the tech surface in
2018 facts can be used as a gateway to
internal networks then olden outdated
protocols probably not so good for you
so try not to use them if you can what
can you do to defend yourself against
this catastrophe a lot of things first
of all you can patch your printer's as
we all said this link will you know just
tell you if your printer is multiple by
the way every HP inkjet or obviously
printer is vulnerable to this thing
that's the biggest line of printers from
HP over I think 200 300 300 300 models
are vulnerable to this thing so really
going update another another thing I can
tell you is if you don't need facts
don't use it and also if you do need to
use fax after all try and make sure your
printers I cannot segregate it from the
rest of the network so you know even if
somebody takes off with the printers it
will just be confined to the printers
and won't be able to take over your
entire network so guys these are really
good suggestions all of them but really
the best suggestion I have to give you
today is please stop using sax
thank you thank you just just one second
before we finish this was a long way a
long journey and through this journey we
had some very good friends that helped
us a lot along the way physically
mentally technically so we must mention
them these are the guys here some of
them are in the crowd so they deserve
some some claps and one special guy at
the telecast is Ian I live now and he
also deserves this and that's it
basically guys so if you want to follow
more of a warp you can find us here
follow us thank you very much
we have five minutes for Q&A so please
line up at the microphones if you wanna
leave now please do it to your right
side so this side from the stage is the
left side but for you it's the right
side so please line up at the
microphones
I think microphone so basically those
services use t30 as well we look at that
frankly we had so much work to do with
the printer that we didn't look at any
other printers or any other services but
I can't say for sure but if you're
looking for vulnerabilities I would
recommend to go look there as well
great microphone number five please
what can you disclose about the data
that's sitting URL can you disclose
about the machines that are knocking on
your Royal to take you want to perform
there are a lot of HP printers out there
[Laughter]
that's all I can sorry
so we have one question from the signal
angel please we try to use the data we
think it's disabled from the factory
lines it was too much work so we decided
to use the VINs IV it's a good
vulnerability once we have devil's IV
and we can use scout scout is more than
enough for debugging essentially after
we used the JPEG of vulnerability and we
loaded up scout scout survived for weeks
on the pointer without any crash so
that's more than enough great we go with
microphone number two please yes so
thank you for the nice talk and I think
you're completely right we can't have
many problems with legacy protocols we
only think I do not really get was the
part how you then can automatically
successfully take your laptop on the
network my point would be my laptop is
as secure as I'm going to the L so you
would not be able with your HP printer
to start the calculator on my Linux or
even my Windows well hey yo wait your
laptop might be secure I'm sure it is
but many others are not we try to show
this using the eternal blue exploit as
you know wanna cry stuff like that you
know this thing created a lot of and
there were patches out there and still
it was so we're not here to attack
anyone we're just saying that
theoretically if somebody wants to get
into the network and he has a
vulnerability that you're maybe not
patched or secured fax would be a bad
idea but it was not it was nothing which
was part of torrent of it sorry
unfortunately we don't have more time
for Q&A so thank you again very much
thank you
[Music]
it's really nice
[Applause]
[Music]