[Music]
in the cabin next to us I've ever been
onstage with so many people yeah yeah
you can't beat that paper can you I've
tried I think you've heard me failing
twice she please read this out this is
lingo Praga good French now where they
announce the English translation in
English or were they now you have the
chance to say hi to your mother well
that's not really teaching Spain all
right
Spanish greeting to mother and Spain
delivered thank you oh one was actually
hauled a it's exciting is it I've got a
pulse so how about you do old men also
have a pulse one of them does the other
well right shall we play a small game
you know the defragment fragmenting
thing why don't you just fold down your
table computers because one over other
of you may have to stand up and if you
have a rucksack next to you because you
can leave your girlfriend will make it
please now stow your luggage below your
seats and put up your hands if there's a
seat next to you free seat next to you
how many of you have set sat down before
the break and waited all right we get it
so we can dispense with the
defragmenting right and go to the fun we
have some facts for you shall we do the
exercise for the closing it worked very
well in Hamburg whether it will work
here we'll see you take this half and
I'll take the other half so we'll split
it down the middle where the cameras are
you are my half we would like to have an
Ola a Mexican wave with you because it's
been such a long time and the crashing
Mexican wave please would like to stock
there and now please come on get going
yeah yeah great and the other way round
with sound - hang on hang on hang on
really loud 1 2 3 like Mexican wave
[Applause]
I have goosebumps right and now to the
facts facts we have done some research
with the angels because as you know the
angels are the people well you know them
all and we'll tell you why later these
are the people that organize everything
huge opposed for that to start with
it's all for me and now all call me all
right someone who's calling me always
the same jokes right
is that a joke or is something happening
somewhere
oh now all you know we have the figures
are quite small actually 1043 could have
been 1042 to make it sound better right
but we have 1040 three-person days
that's two thousand nine hundred and
sixty nine angels with at least one our
leaders divided into forty fifty nine
angel types fifty nine NGO types so
different tasks to do from collecting
bottles to standing up here and
entertaining you and I've gone with a
nine fifty minimum minimum wage and
multiplying this I know that we'd get in
trouble for that I'll get us out of
there right so with a minimum wage of
950 you get seventeen 9268 euros but
that is minimum wage but you are IT
people right and I did it with say 99
euros per hour the friendship rates and
that gives it gets us to how much was
that two hundred and something thousand
can I now build the CCC for that and all
together two thousand and four hundred
three thousand four hundred people is
signed up to register to to angel was it
five thousand four hundred so half of
those who tried we're only able to make
it into helping out so thanks a lot for
that
it was definitely more than 4-thousand
I've seen that all right now we are
prepared now who this year had this
moment of i-told-you-so who had this had
this at least once
come on people that can't be right okay
now they're coming out with the family
the company ah of course
hang on yes how knows who knows someone
who has had that moment that's the way
to ask who knows someone who's had that
one at least five times well not so many
less but then the next talk isn't that
bad for you we'll give you some new
photo from these two security nightmares
Ron and Frank in the 13th edition an
applause I think it's the 19th edition
it's one three in hex we'll see what
they say
[Applause]
buta hello thank you welcome to the
security nightmares hello like sick
hello territory of the unknown nice to
have you all here the 19th edition on
the 35th Congress and that of course is
a certain limit for the Congress because
I think two or three years ago we told
someone that everything that's older
than 35 can actually go to a museum so
that means that next year the Irish to
the burger house the oldest location of
the Congress I wasn't it the oldest it's
going to go there we'll have to research
that by the way alright who's here for
the first time all right that's good
less than previously I think that's a
good trend and who of you can explain
the basics of tcp/ip and who of you has
done it I've learned it at this Congress
hmm no one all right now we'll dig
deeper who knows who can explain the
basics of SPX I SB XIX IR 15 well not
too bad SNA
[Music]
layer 1 and 2 of Wi-Fi we've got a few
Wi-Fi cable experts here and Laura one
interesting is always the same people
showing up remember these guys they are
the ones we will need before the
apocalypse and those that will have net
after the apocalypse maybe what's always
funny is I I always put those numbers
into my converter and and then see in
which number system and nice number
turns out and this is the 23 23rd event
in octal that's nice
so 2 3 in octal and you see the notation
there 0 O 2 3 and that reminds me of
something and then I thought yes that's
the way I saw it anyway ok also the
actual image of the year I've just seen
a moment ago on Twitter and with the
gdpr and the European regulation the
santa claus jokes have taken on a
completely new dimension he makes a list
of children that are nice in those that
are not so nice or naughty and of course
he will receive an official letter with
return envelope in half suit of comment
and how he's going to delete the data I
think those information requests those
gdpr information requests are great the
the delivery process the most parents
have these funny games where they either
rent a father as a Santa Claus
or if they find something today
improvised and suddenly the sack with
the presence is there and they father
Christmas has gone and Santa Claus and
how do you then deliver that do you how
do you deliver that request for
information do you attach to the sack
and hope that the sack will be collected
so that and will that be valid over that
period of time from one year to the next
ah chaos posts that works yes chaos post
would work it arrived I received
postcards yes and next year we can start
with the twenty year review but for now
we would like to continue with the ten
year review because otherwise we'd have
to do it last ten years all over again
now ten years ago we had the topic of
better testers for new surveillance
technology and it would be nice if
Germany and peas could have been obliged
because they always passed these laws
but apparently at least as far as we can
see it they don't actually notice what
they actually cause what they unleashed
because they may not be affected and if
you would change if you were to change
that then maybe the attitude would
change as well and something we had this
year is that not the MPS but the meanest
ministries try had innovative
surveillance technology at least there
was a Trojan that take of a command in
control of an email which I found in off
diff because there's not so much new in
command and control there so you send
something there's reply it's very
comfortable this way I think probably
next year it will be existent as a
chatbot as well so hey choten just yeah
and the other thing that's missing is
that spam will be in stick stick or nog
Rafi or special cookies or something it
will be actually in innovative control
system too
I get advertising cookies leave
Children's Act when you clicked on
advertising and and the rodent the
cookies then actors if they were the
content you want a or something in the
same category there was the issue of
public data retention for all German
members of parliament and that did work
within limits because the first whatsapp
groups were leaked the the contents of
those that started last year didn't it
so it didn't take ten years but nine but
this will only move on from continue
from here and we may have been a bit
early there but there's still hope the
trend is right and louder the rota issue
ten years ago was actually the US
authorities 3,500 faked voters when
Cisco logo louder
we they want to talk louder about the
router to using American pronunciation
ten years ago the US authorities had
3,500 fake twitches with Cisco logos and
they removed them and were concerned
these were not Cisco routers they just
looked like they were and this year we
had the hardware backdoor debate which
is kind of comprehensive we've got
Hardware implants in motherboards by
Super Micro that several cloud operators
were using but they didn't prove it and
they didn't bring forward the evidence
these images were all photoshopped I
think it took a week to come out that
the images were all works of art and my
assumption is that they heard about
something that actually happened but
that wasn't what they actually reported
on and the discussion is interesting
when it went on and kind of created the
background for who are way because the
Americans have been causing a bit of
stress around the world to get who are
way out saying that Chinese vectors were
in there and then this third session I
found amusing because there was this
comment saying that the backdoors in
American products weren't actually that
rare and it the question now is whether
the politics that are being conducted
which vector supply would you like to
have
exactly I mean you can pick little games
where you first think do they kick those
out first
where they had a backdoor but didn't
excuse me them but who they've
kicked the back door out first where
they think somebody else has it and to
you is that joke viable you need three
scanners and American to catch the
Russians a Russian one to catch the
Americans who was the third one a
Finnish one for the Swedes yeah
equal yeah equal opportunity backdooring
is the world I mean there's always space
between a firewall or firewall to air
another firewall they're back right I
heard we're back doors where another
theme in the tunnels this sort of
they're sealed and the question is does
the implant come off the line or is it
installed in service so there's a sort
of decide we got away them this year
they found out way wait Wayne doesn't
help because they they make them so
small that there is no difference and
now they know and they know that they're
being wait and so they just add the tear
it out or reflects it out take a little
bit out so the additional chip is does
not it's not addicted so the next
countermeasure is to
see if it's rotational balance or not
and you put it on a rotational tablet
and find out if you shouldn't open them
anyhow because if it the seal is broken
they're not compliant and so they have
to open one of them when they're
completely sure that it's okay I'm just
looking at one final check and then make
a baseline from that and say that's the
way all the others should act and when
are you gonna rotate your service around
in your oh when you start rotating your
service they're gonna lose all the
screws to roll them together
oh they're all SSD yeah but still you
got all the SSD chips lying in one end
of the server yeah that's a don't want
to think about it oh yeah then they're
there the the the 10 years ago they had
these spam mails for Commission kill
estimates
I am your killer today I have got the
order to kill you but you can buy your
liberty or your life would you just
please send the money or buy me some
iTunes cards or maybe some packages that
was 10 years ago there there were no
bitcoins around them it was like now hit
man spam else hit man spammers that's
right that was the word thank you
what well when the bitch kids were
theater bought one ten years ago you
bought one hamburger for them well in
the meantime even that sort of has
developed there was there was this
article in Wired about somebody who
knows somebody and did some research
who was this who ran assassin where you
all of them sort of you know get a
website to order your assassin and they
got different friends I think money for
it yeah
Bitcoin of course and talk about ESCO
and and it would go over an escrow
account and if you send them some
Bitcoin and oh yeah the killer is
informed and two days later and he's
he's on the way two days later and there
was a slight just calling with the
delays in operation operation and he
stuck somewhere and would you could you
could you please send some more bitcoins
because he ran out of petrol or whatever
and another week now I didn't work that
well but he's got the money and and a
little slightly higher price we could
add somebody professional to make that
job oh there's loads of stories there in
the end
and he tooks his way out of it and he
still in the end he just steals time and
money from those who want to others
killed and that would be morally
completely complacent but that's an
interesting you can make a nice a story
out of that yeah let's go on with an
extra ten years ago we said what will
social networks will be for data crimes
the best part and we should look at that
in ten years time so social data crimes
in social networks oh GSM safety leaks
the hulls don't have to say anything
oh there's an interesting question how
many how many different versions of
opening a GSM base station Wow come on
the boys are from China they're
completely safe and secure
yeah let's exam
yeah the National filters were up in
that and the browser plugin for suits
who compared attitude national and a
national basis we could of the VPN or a
browser plug-in to how the internet
looks from another different perspective
or national boundaries or what the
others think about us the view from the
next-door country never know and in the
meantime that seems to happen already
and and to upload download filters
obviously and seems to be more
interesting what it looks like from the
other country becomes more in ads sort
of virtual reality for all of us on a
national state base
nation states the interesting is what
does this website look like if I don't
quote it with my cookies and I think the
plugins for that are still lacking
there's still work to do there at least
there's a market because of location
based pricing and some people realize
that when they empty their browser cache
and throw their cookies away and then
ask again what the flight from A to B
does costs suddenly the price is very
very different often cheaper okay oh the
normality update for the internet for
2018 partly from figures from nineteen
twenty seventeen because we still don't
have the figures this fault for them
that is definitely the forty Android
phones with the Troian off the rack
that's rather efficient and yeah you
have to make your money somehow there
was a paper that well I thought that is
really weird that's Captain Obvious on
his way when I have tip ups and and I
explicitly put another dev sick up I'll
be faster than normal that's not note
that not surprising but it's what
surprising is maybe that your eleven
point five times as fast
if you use if you deployed 20 times
faster and that means you have to you
have to fix your security level at least
10 times as often to keep the level
skimming attacks damages from one point
new two to two point two million euro
now attacks on ATMs that's not so
interesting the figures worsened
slightly but not that much and what was
interesting that behind this headline
and a few others I didn't really notice
it during the year only when I try to
look back across the whole year and in
within the time space of about one or
two weeks suddenly you see that many of
these headlines say that these 2.2
million euros damage only really 15%
only 15% of those occurred in Germany
because there are international Accords
now moving the damage to the country
with the lowest security level and there
are other items reports saying that the
damage was this and that figure and this
amount had to be paid for ransom
where and and then behind you see the
movie that the insurance paid for it and
ok international treaties insurances
interesting I would have expected that
the secretary level would be raised
because insurances expect things like
that well if you look at those ATMs
those cash points the efforts you need
for skimming you can just get the money
out directly right borehole into it he
was be poured in and convince it to spit
everything out where to talk it doesn't
work with the wireless keyboards I think
it does I think every cash point should
have a dominant for a wireless keyboard
that would improve the service quality
considerably
Google removed 700,000 evil apps Apple
removed many so Google said that they
had removed 700,000 evil apps from the
Play Store they at least give you a
figure Apple it's a bit like the Eskimos
and the snow they have many words for
snow and no precise figure well the
thing is that apps that are evil and
particular when it comes to tracking and
data exfiltration have become quite a
business area and it's obviously not so
easy to recognize these so that as soon
as they enter the Play Store they could
be sorted out so it will be an
interesting battleground also with
devices that the makers they buy
components from all kinds of suppliers
and if particularly if you buy these
cheap Android tablets you can run across
an adware that was pre-installed and
Lenovo for example stopped that this
year actually that was last year but
this year they had to pay for that and
quite a lot 7.3 million that doesn't
seem like a huge amount for a company
like this but surely it is something
that internally could be used to improve
things right now another figure more
than twelve petabyte company tighter
unprotected on the net online so someone
put this figure out and said I've been
scanning v4 ipv4 and found 12 petabytes
of company data so because data are the
oil of the 21st century this kind of
nice data wealth the oil is on the
street it swims on the lake it swimming
it swims on the like you kind of splash
around in there and most of that
interestingly was in some open s3
buckets or FTP servers
and it was the case with Lucky Luke
wasn't it where they just pinched the
ground and then you had this oil gushing
out and everyone walking around with
blackened faces and that's not the case
with data otherwise the researchers
would look so different right but it is
funny isn't it - to have data both
looked like toner explosion well then I
would be something would happen to me
quicker than it does right tech support
scams grew by 24% that's this model
where you call somebody and somebody
calls you this is Microsoft calling you
have a virus on your computer and we
would like to repair that together with
you and I always had the impression yeah
but that doesn't happen in Germany for
the language barrier and actually it
seems to be it's it's growing no
question there the reports show that
this is happening in 180 countries but
their cases in Germany so let's ask to
the public do you know somebody who's
who's had a virus call for Mac oh hey
yeah some at least a few
and who had the call in German and what
the call in English Oh half enough well
we have a theory we'll talk about that
later
interesting
applause for an applause let's encrypt
more than half of all publicly reachable
certificates 50% of all publicly let's
encrypt and Microsoft trust this Oh
since August's Microsoft isn't a careful
company they don't trust anybody at
least not immediately things about that
never stop like who then the next year's
will go on for another ten years
yeah what's really fascinating is the
dimension of this these IP addresses
there's some sometimes they were up to
5,000 those it's way bigger I had one IP
address infected by want to cry how can
you how can you attain such infection
rates maybe we need an old-timer
hardware registration black outside you
know old-timer in Germany you're allowed
to drive where other modern cars need a
special license
if an Ultima 30 years old maybe would
have to lower that for 10 to 50 years
if it's a 15 years old and then what you
do with it
with the the server how do you handle
that a single cell that in Germany if
you have an old time when you get an H
on your registration plane and that's
they call it a Hannibal Lecter's sign
let's look back at this year the
Parliament act in the German Bundestag
was the interior minister said
technically complicated sophisticated
sophisticated that's right the tax money
that was invested that was invested to
first clean up they were invested proper
because it was sophisticated
sophisticated use of tax money yeah that
was where when our interior ministers
think something is sophisticated well
yeah okay the British came around
general Hancock central so if there's
something around and everybody knows
we'd like to know and because all these
mouths the people's are encoding and
encrypting and we can't so we have to
open their computers and use a mastic
floor so we've got to be able to open
with as many computers as possible they
want the right and of course the means
ten hundred fifteen hundred thousands
computes to open them proactive
just without just for the sake of it
let's listen to what happening and
expensive they need this chick punch
trying a Jack point joy and searching
yeah if you if you stole it properly
then people start telling everything in
the night three o'clock at Monday
morning they don't defined it's a dog
laptops or pcs but that includes the
television sets and tomorrow maybe the
Bob probably the Barbies Moffat LLC and
annex Barbie dolls and a know election
let's not forget elixir oh and the home
board and the cook with the the Google
device what it's called what's it called
right the yeah a communication systems
discovered using Google now of course
normally we have many of what report is
technically very sophisticated that and
there was this story this year that had
been around a few years ago but it
always comes back up and that is that
the communication system that they use
for making arrangements with their
sources and different countries using
web systems that they had bought for
millions of dollars from American an
American government contractor and only
that at some point the Iranians had
placed a double agent in there and that
so the Iranians thought the website
would look like that they used for
communication and then you could Google
use it for similar websites and found a
few dozens of them and then monitored
the people connected with that and and
took them and then talked to the Chinese
that could contribute something as well
and that led to the CIA to as a proof of
its amazing a government competency had
lost its whole agent networks in these
countries and some actually died so you
see that eat governments
is a difficult task still even if you
have technical technically it's
sophisticated things to defend against
the technical term for that is a Google
Doc you could google it right the next
thing is an absolute screamer because in
Australia a law was passed about the
quality assistance and access bill
nicely abbreviated as an ass bill by its
fans and there are great explain through
videos which are just amazingly funny
and these then would like to introduce
backdoors want to be able to be allowed
to introduce backdoors and they want to
go really wide they want Australian
citizens they want to motivate want to
be able to motivate to put backdoors in
the companies where they work and all
that from a country that has another
scandal going which is called the
Cabinet files what was that about you
asked well the answer is a newspaper had
several covers of files received those
which had been on the second-hand market
for those
for those pieces of furniture but with
content they obviously forgot to enter
them before they put them on the market
so I would now ask why were they sold
with content because we lost the keys
right great so let us repeat what we
said last year this is a new business
model people under hypnosis you could
help them to using hypnosis to remember
they're all past phrases that will come
amazing one of the large debates this
year was TLS 1.3 where various
participants in the debates were of the
opinion that it is too safe to secure
because you can't look into it anymore
at least not so easily and well you have
to remark the old security models where
it was said you have to look be able to
look in said we have a inside network
that we can trust and then the trusted
the encrypted connections arrived and
because everything is safe within the
network we decrypt it at the entrance
point but that didn't quite work out in
practice if you look into these formally
a cryptid data streams if the Trojans
start communicating via via email it
gets difficult so therefore they say
trustless network should be built so
even internal networks are built so that
you don't have trust to service only
encrypted communications and that's what
this TLS 1/3 was actually intended for
right we will see how this will develop
it oh the e-field
attack on sm i am an open PGP yeah so
called
a failure attacked
the details are interesting because you
should read this if you've got the time
we didn't quite include it here to bash
it even further but I don't know how you
feel but this year I met two people
already who I thought would officially
be of the opinion that they cannot get
this okay get to get their grips with
the EEMA encryption in that company so
they gave up and does anyone else know
anyone that's gave up ah only so few
well there's still hope then mm I
believe we'll have to turn out the
lights and then ask the question again
right who is Anna company where they
didn't ever start using Peter let's
explain right who this year to explain
let's try and explain this whole thing
of encrypted email to their colleagues
or heads superiors well that's not too
bad right we had to sort of quickly go
through a couple of quite remarkable oh
this denial of service for the GDP are
let's I want to we wouldn't
who who thought there was that that
thing with gdpr was with all the stress
was not worth it
who likes it who thought it was funny
okay most of you we're just abused what
word then we please please keep Cuse me
click here so you can keep receiving
them all the news on the most amount you
know innovative views and nobody random
or most of you never ran up to a lawyer
or right into a lawyer know who has
something to do with rotating I haven't
seen a time events in eighteen GDP ours
keeper gone wild of the best headline I
loved serious fault in a plugin in a GDP
our plugin for WordPress I like that
Microsoft's BitLocker trusts the firm
work of the company that does the firm
were on their hard days as the
encryption on the hardest encryption on
our disks their Microsoft is a company
that handles OAM requests and jobs every
day and they listen to
OMS every day and look at this new
driver and look what this is coming and
that ISM and then and then they believes
the hardest as an a I'm handling this
completely yeah yeah
everything is poisoned we had the topic
and bad app - centralized apps and
browser plugins and downloads dll's
whatever libraries
sometimes from people that are cut off
from outside like soldiers and and
everybody has internet now and at least
I put the finger get their fingers on it
and they get the bandwidth and and they
go to the dating apps and and and and OH
fitness apps yeah the army goes to the
fitness apps yeah
where do they train their super-secret
Special Forces
all you have to go do is look look
worldwide where where the fitness data
comes in sickly where nobody lives and
this is probably where the Special
Forces are training at the moment oh
there's this question how do you
guarantee data encrypted integrity
integrity of open force of the source
software sorry because the better the
security of the distribution
infrastructure is the higher above the
chain the attacks will go also the bugs
thing isn't the same isn't just there
with the normal suffered also malware
itself there was an interesting case
where something happened in Saudi Arabia
a children was found a more complex kind
of malware that didn't work because it
was buggy it happens no testing is hard
let's go shopping
Oh
HP I love Troian that's a new milestone
in the integrated lights-out in turn
calls it into management a nation IBM
calls it integrated that is vulnerable
you know they integrate the Ransom
trials and HP was the first one there
were the first mother could for their
system there was G's man unlocked the
first ransom trying around ransomware
ransomware on yeah yeah and then yeah
the in the context of the things that
have been smoldering for a long time we
had in OpenSSH
a nineteen-year-old security hole was
fixed in OpenSSH that was used to better
guests valid usernames and in that
context we wondered if you look at other
things such as the OpenSSH Ebury rootkit
thing of what was that from 2006 13 or
whatever the that has now 21
sub-variants and it's as it is with
normal windows viruses do we make too
many windows jokes and mmv at still
isn't switched off all do we actually
have to look at old versions of Linux
and target those and the answer is
obviously yes
who of you still knows a running system
with a kind of one the one version
kernel okay two kernel version - oh yeah
we'll stop here because I think this is
old time of registration yes that would
be a thing that will be talked about
that yet yeah
so with the oldies IOT devices that you
would have to throw away because no
current of course happening this would
get funny who if you are still
maintaining an OS - installation another
three war still three right oh the
browser wall seems to be over then
Google one sort of looks like it
Microsoft gave up that's not such a good
news but that means that means Google is
defining for the next time for the next
year's how much
Apple is gonna invest in that we will
see
the monoculture click in the this is
quite remarkable just as remarkable this
Google assistance that booking
restaurant tables by found which one of
you heard the audio demons um that many
but not all fast anything the
fascinating thing was not H cause and I
said this is the Google assistant I'd
like to book a table the crazy thing was
what he answered when the other side
let me look when the other side down
said I have to look and he said mmm okay
yeah the leaners simon's intermediate
informations that aren't really remarks
but just sort of transport yourself
understood what I said and keep on going
the nonverbal Turing test for us humans
yeah if somebody calls you and does not
clear his throat slavery throat and
don't trust him is probably a bottom you
should put some test stretches in and
yeah
yet something add like great deviation
lead and what and if the other side
doesn't say here move if it just is near
then you're probably mmm talking not to
the guy the question is whether we do
this ourselves or whether we need is
this an assistant for that right then
that gets us to keywords for the next
year evil heart and software networks
data is the headline sometimes we are
off by a few years but the trend that
everything that you could imagine
possibly now will receive a
microprocessor and of course it needs a
microprocessor a microprocessors are
always needs software that runs on it so
that's why hardware is never just
hardware but also software every time
and this software wants to betray here
actually it doesn't want to do that
thing doesn't want anything it is
capable of it is compelled to what's
this about is well everywhere you have
processors now whether it's useful or
not whether it makes sense or not every
light switch now cannot be imagined
without a CPU in it so you have to
actually almost things think that it
will be the exception that nothing
calculating will be in there as soon as
there are some IDs that blink or display
something at least a battery controller
is there that will do its calculations
and have a firmware and then there is
data that's generated and these data
will be stored somewhere and then they
will get lost
well leaked and that is due to the fact
that software quality simply is bad and
compliance testing you don't need
at first you only need that later but
just for it to work or that to make
people buy it you don't need that and
that just brings such a flood of things
onto the market made by people who are
doing it for the first time and
therefore that that's the way it has to
go and then there's something else I
read a very nice article from a penned
someone that was the headline was
something like thinking about AI so how
you should think about AI and he had a
nice analogy which was that artificial
intelligence these days or machine
learning that is somewhat advanced is
like a four-year-old oh yeah a
four-year-old child of either gender it
never tires doesn't want cookies and if
you need them more another 30 you click
once right and four-year-olds can do
things that your computer cannot yet do
pattern recognition is there a rabbit in
this picture
how many unicorns are those those things
and
of course it's a fantastic analogy
because do you know how four-year-olds
deal with family secrets
exactly just like that
[Applause]
I saw your kid nagging you it's said
that there are kindergarten swear you
have signs saying if you don't believe
everything that your child says in
kindergarten it happens what what child
says in kindergarten then we don't
believe anything that your child says
happens at home so the question is what
the analogy for that well they are just
the same so hey Alexa not everything I
say is actually true
Oh Alexa mm-hmm yes okay okay but not
everything is bad right there are things
that do improve technical advances in
defense and attack leads to phishing ai
and anti anti fishing area so Apple is
working hard on improving hardening its
operation for PCs sandboxing has been
introduced at a large scale the things
that are normal for smartphone and
tablet operating systems because it was
in there all along and this all this
whole IOT thing is all terrible but what
people directly interact with that does
get better if it is kept updated and
what happens is that the attacks against
all that IOT stuff are still happening
with brute force brute forcing old
software vulnerabilities and so on but
that middle range the PC less is
possible there all these locked up end
product systems such as tablets more
less modern hardware where you cannot
install your own operating system
anymore where you have a few apps and
the security of the system is supported
by hardware security chips
now these are a bit more a bit harder to
attack and for that for us the question
therefore was what is actually happening
because evolution is going on of course
and we never had the situation where the
criminals were were stopped by any of
this so the logic logical consequence is
that security more and more becomes a
layer 8 problem the problem is behind
between the screen and the chair and we
had a few ancestors we've seen a few
ancestors of this there was an
interesting Trojan that in a particular
Bank using an exploit in the table next
to the current one was opening the home
banking and told the home banking oh
you've just received in a transfer
you've just received 750 euros in a bank
transfer and unfortunately that was an
error and would you please like to
retransfer this so this wasn't a
security attack it was only an attack to
what would be happening to you because
you'd like to be an honest person so
people were transferring this year and
have 750 years that they never received
back somewhere and there is no security
measure that can help because the people
who want this then and I think that
exactly this is where the future lies
for attacks that attacks more and more
target the human brain and the technical
attacks are just supporting measures and
the question then is how do you do this
and humans are very tively impatient and
well often at least distracted I
wouldn't say it's stupid but distracted
a lot and that means that a nice task
for a horde of 10000 four-year-olds a
fishing AI you could imagine you I want
an ice cream
you can have your mobile we want we all
want our pocket money right yeah I think
yeah the I love you iris one when was
this 20 18 years ago also so someone
need a betting tap told me that I said
I'm I installed a Windows just for that
purpose to open that email because it
came from my girlfriend so people go a
long way to hear the message if the
message that message is right so and the
next thing is that every data accident
that happens out there is fodder for
that AI so every little bit of data that
gets lost helps some kind of AI to send
you even better phishing emails and the
question is who will have received it
first or have the AI first and because
everything is connected and it's not
actually evil as such because phishing
is just a form of marketing do something
now not by me but click me so marketing
is motivation and motivation is
education education is happiness so
that's where we've come full-circle this
is all dual use and the question it will
be a very moral one what is still ok and
what is not okay at all not ok it all is
to convince me to buy itunes car
to kind of pay off my tax debt or
something stupid like that but maybe I
would like the software to press all my
buttons so that even today I can learn
five minutes of English I would like to
learn five minutes of English okay who
do we give the right to manipulate us
and with what motivation and if you say
learning English you believe that you
want to learn English the question is
why do you believe you want to learn
English what software manipulated to to
that state of mind that you want to
learn English
maybe that software wants to sell you a
journey to a trip to London or something
and anyway you have translators running
Frank and the question is which kind of
manipulation of the moral ethical or
moral basis them and where do we draw
the line as a society that will become a
security issue it's a question of seek
your personal or mental security because
we are dealing with AI then that can
press our buttons and we do see very
well what that could lead to with
Facebook and Co if on the other hand we
have machine learning systems on the
other side that make us get excited or
angry then it's foreseeable that this
whole debate cannot be postponed that
much longer
[Applause]
how do you translate this into sports
and business sections we think you gotta
you you lose the overview where which
data got lost today or this week on me
who knows this does everybody knows my
mother's maiden name yet did I avoid
this chick which one of these answers
are already known there the services
everybody should know them Harold have I
been pawned that's a website that
collects all the the registration and
and and pawned fast words and I can send
in my email address and they will send
me back all the passwords that have been
associated with this in some leaks and
then all these other leaks should be
stored in different safe places like
that
otherwise if somebody else finds all the
palm passwords in one place that might
be another problem
and and we need a sort of duck sing
manager that we need that like a
password manager where is my stone data
storage in the in a safe place
how do we go oh this going the wrong way
Shannon says yeah exercise to the will
ignore it and garlic and the bandwidth
for getting larger and the quantity
improves sometimes and the world is
moving away from telephone conferences
together to towards screen sharing
conferences and more and more people
find out what means that uses the
telephone consciousness and still open
up the camera more and more people how
many of you think that is raising that
number I think that was quite pure
telcos suddenly now become video
conferences to speak of the bandwidth is
there and who thinks that's helpful
who thinks is awful I'd rather snore
without being noticed I can understand
that the you could you could you could
monitor your pulse or your breathing
frequency
there's my that did you start easy
starting breathing heavily because I
said the right or maybe the wrong thing
it might be a good idea
maybe he just had too much coffee before
you listen but if that is a growing
tendency you can add this additional
data you can use to pull that but you
should be able to defend yourself
against that as an in-app purchase you
can you can defend the gains you can
click what you want to be today the cool
one or poker face to poker face to 50
complacent pika
happy co-workers $5 if maybe sometimes
you want to get annoyed about something
that has annoyed you for ages and for
your health it's a lot better you know
please computer can you go and complain
for me because I don't want to be
bubbled whether these emojis that you
can steer with the way you look at them
there's there could be intelligent
avatars that adapts to what you how you
look at them or there's this room for
more in there yeah and finally we
believe the question of the year
you in tax with something is it a script
is it machine learning is it our AI we
can't be human won't be was there what's
the difference if it's five points is AI
and if it's fight this machine learning
he has power point engineering is that
and if they put some quantum computers
at some quantum computers yeah it's
definitely powerful in engineering yeah
you have to handle them and you know and
you don't you don't ask in whom I am I
talking with well how can I solve the
problem
well userscript do I need machine
learning or I still have to wait for AI
right yeah in that sense in that sense
this time we are very much on time or we
would like to wish you a happy
transition into the year 1984 the image
is of Leipzig then it's a straight
beautiful typo that's a nice type of yes
I like that one
[Music]