[Music]
and I'd like to welcome welcome you to a
talk titled media disruption led by the
blind which is by Daniel Sevilla Daniel
originally from Puerto Rico is now a new
media artist and other things he
probably will talk about as well in
Berlin and one of the topics he will be
talking about this infinite observer
which is this the first narrative VR
experience designed from the ground up
by the blind for the blind
hi I'm sabbia or the glad scientist and
yeah there's my full long name and yeah
I want to talk to you about some of my
projects but first I want to to try a
little experiment with you guys so I'd
like for everyone to close their eyes
and as we all close our eyes I would
like for just 30 seconds to listen and
listen deeply to the room around you and
as you're listening create an image of
the room around you create an image of
how many people you think are in the
room an image of all the people who may
be walking into the room right now where
they're coming from and just do this
okay now you can open your eyes and as
you open your eyes
imagine those 30 seconds as 30 minutes
or 30 hours or 30 years and then imagine
this as your status quo perspective of
the world now imagine the thousands of
years spent attending to visual
persuasions and how you'd personally
interpret everyday computing with this
newly gained perspective now hold on to
that for a little bit because we're
gonna go on a tangent no I'm so real
quick I just want to give you a long
story of my life it's basically like
three conversations um so permission is
granted please you know if you feel like
you need to interrupt you can do that um
so when I was five years old I told my
mom one to make video games she was like
okay whatever um I was just super into
duck hunt and you know ten years later
she's like what do you want to do in
life you know it's that time I said I
want to make video games so that led me
on a crazy path and I ended up going to
Georgia Tech studying computer science
and then I ended up in Barcelona I met
this guy who changed my life who I
literally saw in the hall earlier and I
said hey man you changed my life and he
was like yeah okay
no but basically what he taught me was
that I could make art with code
um and that literally just blew my mind
and I realized that everything around me
was code and that everything around me
was you know manipulatable and
everything could be an art project or an
art anything whatever you want to call
it and it was like this crazy
achievement became unlocked in my life
um so I spent about eight years after
that
no I'm didn't really even care about
video games and just wanted to make
stuff with code installation art VGA
projection mapping blah blah blah all
that stuff and then you know we're
talking about VR though so then I
realized one day oh yeah there's this
immersive art that I'm making all the
time I'm making this crazy projection
mapping
there's all these logistics involved
what if I just make a VR experience and
put people into this Wow
and it hit me so late that they'd also
blew my mind and then I'm also a
musician so when I got the VR headset I
wondered if there was a way to make
music in VR so I figured that out
um and I laughed a lot while I was doing
it and I've performed on stage a ton
doing this um but that's not really what
I'm talking about as I was doing that
people would come up to me after every
show and say hey you make music for VR
right I'm like no I make music in VR but
I realized that hey I had to learn a new
skill set because people are gonna
continually ask me about this so I quit
my job I moved to Berlin this is a bunch
of stuff about how to make stuff for
sound in X our technology if you're
interested slides will be up all that
good stuff and I moved to Berlin and I
took a course with someone who's
actually sitting in the audience and
learned all these different technologies
about producing sound in a spatial audio
system and I had this question of how
does a group audio driven VR experience
look so I created an experience with a
group of amazing people where we had
four people blindfolded and they're in
the mono space which is in Berlin and
it's a 40 sound center so there's
spatial audio and you can walk up to
sounds and they exist in the space
around you and you can really interact
with sound in a different way and it was
a good opportunity to take people into a
sound focused and tactile focused VR
world so I did that in that setting but
the issue with that setting is that it
lives there
it lives in mono and you can't take that
space anywhere else but what happened
during that and lots of gratitude to
everybody that I worked with is that I
realized something that I just kept on
thinking about what it feels like to be
blind and how I could never really fully
empathize with that experience and so I
want us to close our other eyes again I
want us to just try one more time
but this time as you close your eyes I
want you to just feel I want you to feel
your fingertips wherever they're laying
I want you to feel the bottom of your
elbows the insides of your knees the
bottom of your feet and I want you to
see if you can detect vibrations around
you and see if you can feel the actual
reflections of those vibrations in the
room
okay now open your eyes and you can
imagine the same things again and again
and again that these are minutes and
these are hours and these are years but
at the end of it all what we come to is
that that's our perspective from our
limited experience in this and that we
need a deeper expected perspective so
people often tell tell me what VR is
people in the VR community try to shove
things in different places say that VR
has to be this VR has to be that and
well honestly I'm kind of like f that
noise there's a lot of different things
and we're creating our own paths in this
world um so it's not really virtual
reality or visual reality it's virtual
reality so if you think you need a
headset necessarily to create a virtual
reality experience maybe we could think
about it in a different way and I came
back to this question again and again
and what I realized is that it
transformed into what would a VR
experience be like for the blind and can
this experience actually challenge
visual culture and that led to the
creation of infinite observer so if an
observer is a VR experience designed for
the blind and as I started this project
I thought okay I'll make a VR experience
that's for the blind but also can be
experienced by the sighted as well um
and you know people in the VR community
are just sitting there calling me crazy
and on stuff and I'm like okay so now
we're gonna get to a lot of slides with
just text because I actually feel like I
want to embody more so a less visual
tone for this part um so there's a lot
of research to do as soon as I really
seriously decided to pursue this project
I went to so there was that realization
I went to actually live with a
couple in the Netherlands Vianney and
tina Visser and they run a foundation
called the Walken Foundation and they
actually bring people into a dark
experience which we could say is a
multi-sensory enhanced version of the
glimpse that you guys participated in
during this presentation and so they
have this multi-room experience that you
go into there's literally no light your
eyes try to search for it for the first
few minutes and then they literally just
get tired of firing the the cones and
rods or whatever that is and then you
give in and you start to use your other
senses and you start to discover all of
the powers that you have beyond just
sight and so I spent about five days
living with them just you know night and
day really learning so much um and what
I ended up learning from them was first
of all these people are incredible um
Yanni and Tina were both firewalkers
teaching people how to walk on coals
Tino's teaching people you know ancient
songs for years and Yanni actually was a
hacker he you know is building his own
ham radios and has built multiple Linux
machines and also has his own distillery
in his house which his liquor is really
good and as they shared their experience
in there they're blind experience with
me I also shared with them a ton of VR
experiences which you know I thought
okay I'm gonna take the best audio VR
experiences on a show home to them
they're gonna have a response they're
gonna say yeah this is good yeah this is
bad um honestly there's zero UX
accessibility for people who are blind
in VR at all there's like nothing to do
with voice menus there's no thought
whatsoever and yeah it made me it made
me pretty sad at first no but I also
realized that there's a there's a great
opportunity to to make a change and I
think that as I was with them I really
got inspired for the narrative of the
piece as well because of the the
background and as we were talking they
were saying well what if we had this
of you know underground hackers who are
interested in overthrowing the dominant
visual culture and that seemed to
resonate a lot so yeah there's a little
reminder so that really sparked the
story building and this is a you can
barely see it and cool that's fine so
this is the the basic image that sort of
it led our guidance in that it's smokey
there's a unknown figure and you're
welcomed into this group of hackers who
want to subvert these dominant forces of
society and they want to use vibrational
forces to do so so instead of you know
typical ways they may use echolocation
to navigate they then use molecular
vibration to actually teleport and then
they use by mapping the tectonic
shifting because they're actually
underground as well um they're able to
detect movement above and also detect
things which sound can actually disrupt
visual vibrations in the visual spectrum
so these were some of the things that we
talked about and actually became parts
of the game and were able to implement
already some of these into the into the
experience so as I mentioned
echolocation we also have a frequency
matching gun where you're able to hold
it up to different materials and match a
frequency and that's able to explode
open up new pathways in this underground
world and really what what the narrative
is about is kind of telling a
meta-narrative and how how can this
actually include a real Society of blind
hackers potentially through just this
experience in this art so how can we
take a site specific installation for
instance that takes place at a specific
festival or at a specific community
event focus on the blind and have this
merging of
okay at the end of the experience
someone in the narrative is inviting you
to join this group and as you leave the
experience maybe maybe you have a text
on your phone with a link to a website
that now is access to this community on
these sorts of interactions and then how
is it feasible to create an audio-only
group community platform that would be
easily navigable by the blind so these
are a lot of the things that we're
thinking about in this project now so
the technical side of things is pretty
interesting so I teamed up with a audio
designer who specifically specializes in
spatial audio and he works at magic leap
and with him we've been building out the
audio environment and so we're using
wise which is a popular spatial audio
sound engine for very unity and unreal
and because of the plugin that they have
it's able to actually detect the
real-time game geometries and create
realistic reflections of the sound in
the space so as we test this we're you
know looking very strangely at how
realistic this sounds for the blind like
is this passing you know the test and so
far it's it's been questioned um and
we're wondering you know is technology
not that be it is this something where
we have to continue deeply researching
more and more and maybe use some
cutting-edge research institutions to
reach that point and yeah as I mentioned
we're working in unity and originally we
were focused on deploying it to headsets
but I think that with a small enough
market of the headsets that blind users
actually have access to it makes more
sense now to to look at both PC users as
well as mobile users and in using some
of the the wise plugins in a game engine
setting it's easy to be able to to
deploy it to both now I'm going to be
flexible in that way
so those are a lot of the different
things that we're considering and can an
audio version only exist no can we
create custom solutions that can travel
that maybe combine all of these into
installation formats as well no these
are all different things if you haven't
noticed this is a in progress project
and so this is the team that's Yanni and
Tina and that's kadar and this is Chris
who's been guiding a lot of the the
interaction and creative now all along
with me and really the goal of this
project is to empower the blind and
create a heightened appreciation for our
senses beyond sight and through the
narrative hopefully it will instill some
clarity around the dominance of visual
culture and the ways that all of these
tech giants have been using visual
culture to greatly manipulate on people
and it may inspire some new ways to
circumvent this um and on a bigger sense
I would love to create a voice for the
blind as we develop new technologies I
really do see immersive technologies as
being like the next big way that we
interact with computers for the next 10
years and I would love to see this you
know be potentially a wake up call or
along with a slew of other projects be a
wake up call that this needs to be done
ahead of time of projects coming out or
sorry hardware and these these cycles
coming out and then yeah creating a
community for for interaction between
real life line hackers to be able to
discuss anonymously and even maybe
practice some of some of these
techniques together that are inspired by
the narrative um yeah and I do have a
video so a minute I'm gonna show that
now
so this is a video of an early prototype
[Music]
our members usually find us track us
through the echoes but you you're
different
here for something special
paprika
I know you're wondering why we're all
here so let me break it down for you we
have never had a voice who are always
just and after that and they think we
are powerless and until now we believe
that
that's not a problem
that is our advantage they've made us
invisible so they'll never see us coming
we'll start with the US by finding their
single point of failure we can break
down the greater infrastructure
the u.s. controls the entertainment
market if we are able to filtrate the
system and corrupt it without detection
and insert our beacons we can start to
find others like us and accelerate our
bigger initiatives across the world
[Music]
so it does a video um so yeah I I'm
happy to open up to questions now and I
actually have a few questions for you
guys because I know that probably just
say all of you are smarter than me
um so very I'm very interested to know
if anyone has experience using sound or
noise in the context of hacking and what
people think of the community extension
of the piece and if there's a research
out there that could possibly help this
project that I'm not aware of if you
have a question please vote for them I
have one of the microphones no no no - I
have you given any thought to the fact
that currently as far as I understand
you need a big installation right so you
cannot have this experience at home
where if you just you know if you do if
you're visual you can just buy the
headset and that's it have you given any
thought into building a audio VR headset
yeah so this is something that I was
trying to actually talk to oculus about
doing um and basically extrapolating
like the sensors that they have into
using it for head tracking because when
you're in like an a Masonic world the
main thing that lets you interpret it as
a 3d audio is that the sensor is being
able to know when you're when you're
turning your head or when you're moving
within that space um they kind of just
brushed me off and didn't didn't give it
much thought no but it is something that
I'm considering and also that's that's
kind of why I mentioned um looking
towards like some some a are focused
libraries where it has the same spatial
audio features and you're actually able
to scan a room um with your phone and
that may just be a more readily
accessible to where okay someone's
wearing headphones and are able to scan
their room with their phone and then get
audio cues and also have voice
recognition where they could guide their
character through the space as well
which is something all of these people
are super familiar
is talking to their phone and having
those interactions thank you okay so
thank you very much for doing this and
for the talk it was really interesting I
have some experiencing of listening to
3d noise 5d music they call it as well
which is easily done with Ableton in a
normal headset and my question to you
would be since I I think it's not
developed yet you don't have a final
product if you ever thought of doing
something that actually blind people
could learn how to listen the reality in
a better way increasing some ways to pay
attention to some kinds of noise or
feedback that would only require a
normal headset because closing my eyes
once and listening to to the sounds of
the guy shaving your head like that if
you are experienced of that it's quite
amazing what you can do with normal
headsets you know yeah that's a really
interesting idea to have like an
educational element in there um yeah
that's super cool and I love that you
brought up the the by neural barbershop
example because I actually showed that
to Yanni and Tina and it was one of
their favorites you know beyond all the
the VR and a Masonic stuff they're like
that one it was crazy
um so binaural definitely has has its
place and even talking with like kadar
is like this expert and you know spatial
audio he's like I don't they've been
trying to explain it but there's some
psychological phenomenon with the way
that binaural works with our brains and
it just kind of psychologically fakes us
out in a in a cool way
yeah so thank you thank you and if you
never watch watch the barber shop for
experience audio experience on YouTube
again microphone number one
what kind of equipment have you used for
haptics or have you played around with
haptics yeah so although we've used so
far is just the the basic oculus touch
controllers I've applied to a couple of
grants with with haptics research teams
to look into that more
no I'm we were going to talk too hard
light and then they went under hard
light hard light is like it's like a
full suit for haptics which also has its
its pluses and minuses especially in an
installation setting like switching over
between people that can be like pretty
crazy
um but something that are looking into
is something more simple it's like a
wristband that creates um basic
vibrations um that actually like send
impulses to all of your hands so you
feel like you're feeling things um and
then the ultrasound stuff looks super
cool have re do you have experience
working with haptics yeah I played
around with like hat traders they
basically create an illusion on your
skin that you feel like something's like
for instance dragging you through the
air there's a psychologist who's working
with visually impaired people called
Vincent hi wart here's a lot of really
crazy experiments basically it's like a
vibrating motor that it's hard to
explain you have to feel it but if you
hold that thing it just like kind of
drags you through the air and you can do
a lot of really crazy stuff with it um
but yeah just Google uh Vincent hi ward
just crazy guy awesome thank you before
she's a microphone number two there are
questions from the Internet
okay Nick my angel
yeah definitely um
that's why ideally um this is an
installation based experience where you
are able to integrate even real-life
objects as haptics and also sent
possibly taste known which is something
that I did explore with the the
blindfolded experience and I would love
to bring into the installation format
but yeah a lot of it is technology
becoming more accessible like with the
haptics um and the more that those
devices become more prevalent the more
that they can kind of enter into the
work microphone number two hey thanks a
lot a really inspiring project and I
would really love to hear a bit more
about the collaboration you have with
the street as are people how do you work
together are you at in one place and can
you share a bit more these experiences
yeah definitely um so we had the the
initial idea which was kind of in my
brain and then I emptied my brain to
Yanni and Tina and we really started to
go crazy on the conceptual side of stuff
um and I talked with kadar
um about it who had made a VR experience
um for the blind a few years ago um and
then we started developing he lives in
in San Francisco um and so we would work
over the internet together and then
Chris I knew from living in Atlanta and
pulled him onto the project and it's
kind of been me traveling to all these
different places for really intense like
hackathons um and then us working
remotely as we can yeah the next
question again for microphone number two
because you asked for research that
could help you with your project and you
probably know but just to be sure there
is an existing community of
audio games and people who make those
and there's a researcher in Vienna who's
called Michele Urbanek who does research
on them
that might be interesting for you cool
yeah - we'll come out thank you okay any
other questions
Sigma angel do we have new questions
from the Internet do you have new
questions for the audience I I just want
to actually get us to do this one more
time if you guys are up for it so this
time as we as we close our eyes I want
us to to really take a moment to imagine
ourselves having been this way before as
we have experienced this before and I
want us to use feeling and listening and
scent and taste and to try to create an
imaginary world around us and to have
that feel as real as possible
okay thank you so much for your time and
all your everything and enjoy all of
this
[Applause]
[Music]