[Music]
and now for to announce the speakers
these are Jagan are ano was a senior
policy advisor at a dream and on their
Balu whose campaigns and communications
manager also every every stands for
European digital rights which is an
umbrella organization of European NGOs
active in the field of freedom rights
and the digital sphere CCC is actually
founding member of it and they were
talking about citizens or subjects the
back of the control our bodies speech
and communications the floor is yours
[Applause]
this one this one here this is my phone
there are many like it but this one is
mine my phone is my best friend
it is my life and I should master it as
I master my life this is my phone but
what makes it mine I mean it'd be might
be quite obvious right now that I'm
holding it for all of you what is not
that obvious though is that my phone is
also holding me
on one hand we use our phones we use it
to connect to the internet get online
with our friends exchange opinions
coordinate actions on the other hand we
are used we are used by third parties
governmental private who through our
phones through our devices monitor the
monitor our location our bodies our
speech
the content we share at ear level right
now there's a sort of a pattern there is
this tendency a trend almost certain
laws like the e privacy the copyright
directive the terrorist regulation have
this very central core that we call the
body and speech control it looks like it
is really the driving force in the
moment so in the next 40 minutes or so
what we will do is give you short
updates about these laws talk to you a
bit about what their impact is on us and
what do they mean pass the article X&Y
and hopefully convince you to get
involved in changing how they look right
now we are human rights organizations
from all across Europe we work on all
sorts of human rights in their online
environment so called digital rights we
work on data protection net neutrality
privacy freedom expression online and so
on and Andrea and I are glad to be for
our very first time here at 35 C 3 now
to continue that quote from that adapted
quote from full-metal-jacket my phone
without me is useless without my phone I
am useless we spend most of our seconds
of our lifetime around devices that are
connected to the Internet
whether phone a computer fridge or
whatnot this means that these devices
pretty much become attached to our
bodies especially a phone tracking these
devices therefore is equal to tracking
our bodies controlling our bodies
for the purpose of this presentation we
will talk about online tracking in terms
of location tracking the tracking of our
devices the behavior tracking of users
on websites how much do they spend on I
don't know what part of a website where
do they navigate next how many clicks do
they give and the tracking of
communication sent between two devices
first location tracking they are or
Navarrete more screens on most of the
households than we have people we carry
some of these devices in our pockets and
they have more personal information than
most Diaries used to have before our
phones need to be tracked because they
need to be able to receive and send
calls messages data and but this hope is
of course new ways to use location data
for commercial purposes but also for
estate surveillance when it comes to
behavioral tracking the tracking our
behavior online provides a lot more
information than just location it adds
on top of it right a user can then be
targeted according to that tracking and
the more this targeting track not
tracking targeting process basically
represents the business model of the
internet nowadays for this reason the
more complex and detailed someone's
profiling is well the more accurate the
targeting can be done the more effective
and efficient most of the times and
therefore more valuable the data about
the profile is you can see here a really
cool infographic from crack labs axiom
and Oracle profiling of populations
you see the amount of variables and the
amount of information and the depth
where it goes and you get that business
model cash flow and this business model
is quite interesting I I wouldn't
imagine a postman going to my physical
mailbox at home going through my letters
and then putting some leaflets for
advertising in there according to the
world he reads right now Gmail many
other services they that's what they do
they leave out as you well know reading
your emails to sell your stuff that you
don't really need Facebook conversations
and now are through the API are an
option they want to to read those
conversations in order to find patterns
for example for intellectual property
and infringement
especially for counterfeiting but not
not only also for copyright now so the
Watson metadata is used by Facebook in
order to know who you who your friends
are who you contact who who your family
is in order for that social media
services to gain more more power more
and more data and more and more profit
of course the life of others quite a
good movie if you haven't seen a movie I
guess everyone has seen it if not you
should is basically a para Stasi agent
who follows the life of an individual
through a period of time after there's
no the revelations this movie has
changed in a way from drama to a soft
comedy because the the capabilities of
surveillance services to train all of us
to get so much data also for companies
to get so much intimate information from
us has doubled tripled or perhaps
exponentially
grown compared to what the static will
do plug them and all of these to some
extent is is going to be regulated by
this regulation with a very very long
name I guess you have or you have fell
asleep already right by going through it
but I'll go through it quick little to
let you know what what is this about why
do we need to know about a privacy
regulation why this is important for the
control of our bodies and our devices
the privacy is about online tracking and
you might have heard of the cookie
directive that one bringing all those
cookie banners on your screens in
parties but and due to a bad
implementation of this and directive it
is also about your emails who is going
to be able to read your image to use the
data from your emails to sell you
advertising or not now how come eh a lot
information can be it's all about your
chats how do you communicate nowadays
with your whatsapp signal wire or any
other devices and finally it's also
about location data who can track you
why why can they track you and what are
the safeguards that that needs to be put
in place in order to safeguard your
privacy and I can imagine many of you
saying well don't we have already these
gdpr thingie of the emails every 15 may
yes we do have that but the gdpr was not
enough have more than four years of
discussions to achieve this general data
protection regulation we have saved a
lot and gdpr was the best possible
outcome in that current political
scenario and there's a lot to do
regarding the implementation though we
have seen problems in Romania in Spain
and we expect that to happen in many
other places but we still need a
specific instrument to cover the right
to privacy in the electronic
communications including everything we
mentioned before metadata chats
allocation data the content of your
communications and so on so a privacy is
basically meant to complement
pyaare and be more focused on exactly
the topics that Diego mentioned what did
we advocate for and still do privacy by
design and privacy by default should be
the core principles the pillars of these
regulation
moreover politicians need to recognize
the value of maintaining and enhancing
secure encryption cookie walls I mean we
should be able to visit a website
without having to agree to being tracked
by cookies this is another topic that we
strongly advocated for and finally
content should be protected together
with metadata in storage and in transit
and we actually succeeded
last year in 2017 at the end the
Parliament adopted a very good text a
very strong text it it supported most of
the problems that no it addressed most
of the problems that we pointed out and
supported the values that were going
through but this has been quite a right
I mean it wasn't easy as Diego said
we're Network 39 organizations they're
not just legal people or tech people
it's a combination of both so when we
provided our input in the shape of
analysis or recommendations some
bulleted there all sorts of skills were
combined and this displayed a big part
of our success the fact that we were
able to provide a comprehensive yet
complex analysis of what encryption
should look like of what cookies should
act like and also a legal analysis of
existing legislation the diversity of
our skills became productive did we wing
we are on our way after the you
Parliament adopted its position now it
needs to sort of enter into discussion
with the member states in what is called
the Council of the you so the Parliament
with a strong position is now to talk
with the rest of the member states right
currently the negotiations around the
privacy are not really moving forward
they are being denied delayed by the
national governments they claiming that
there are issues that I need to be
tackled that is very technical that we
already have the gtp our we need to see
how it is implemented and member states
fear that another layer of protection
may impede that some businesses grow in
the European Union and if this was not
enough they also afraid of getting bad
press from the press who right now it
depends a high extent on behavioral
advertising they say that without
tracking you all over the all over the
internet they are unable to sustain
their business model and of course since
the national governments the politicians
are afraid of that bad press from the
press then they are quite cautious to
move forward online we exercise our free
speech in many ways but one of those
ways is the way we produce share or
enjoy content online our opinions the
people with whom we communicate can be
seen as a threat in a given time by
certain governments we've seen the trend
in certain governments at in Poland
Hungary and to a certain extent as well
in Spain it can be all of these
information can be as well very
profitable as we see with the mainstream
social media platforms we were
mentioning before so they are political
and economical reasons to control speech
and and that's why the best way to
control speech is it to control the way
that content is shared online right now
there are two proposals that raise a
huge threats to freedom of expression
online both pro both upload filters
by increasing liability for platforms of
making platforms companies responsible
for the content which they host one of
them is they are famous or infamous
article 13 or the copyright and
directive proposal and the second one is
the regulation to prevent the
dissemination of terrorist content
online both of them as you will see the
ideas are another way to make private
companies the police and the judge of
the Internet this is the first one the
proposal for electric game with a long
name just stick to the to the short name
the copyright directive and this
copyright directive is based on a fable
the fable goes like this they are a wide
range of lonely and poor songwriters in
the real attic trying to produce songs
for their audience then they're these
big platforms mainly YouTube but also
others that allow these uploads and game
profit and these platforms give
something is some small amount of money
for this outdoors and the difference
between what they earn and what they
should be earning is what they call the
value gap the fable though conveniently
hides the fact that the music industry
keep saying year after year after year
that they increase the revenues to a
high percentage every year and that
keeps growing especially in the online
world what's the solution to this
problem well as you can imagine is a
magical algorithm that will solve this
problem and this algorithm will filter
each and every file that you upload to
these platforms will identify it and
match it against the database and will
block or allow the content depending if
it is licensed or not and if they like
or not and there according to the Terms
of Service in the end as we will mention
there are some technical and legal
problems with upload filters in essence
if they are implemented it will mean
that YouTube and Facebook will
officially become the police and the
judge of the Internet
the other big fight that we have is
around terrorism or to be specific of a
terrorist content online after the Cold
War we needed a new official enemy once
communism fell terrorism is a new threat
is that real very real to some extent we
live trading in Brussels recently but it
has been also exaggerated and inserted
in in our daily lives we see that in the
airport controls surveillance online and
offline restrictions to freedom of
assembly and expression all over Europe
and whenever a terrorist attack occurs
we see pushes for legislation and
measures that restricts our freedoms
usually those restrictions stay even
though the risk of the threat has
disappeared or has been reduced again
there we go with a long name let's stick
to the short name Derek is there the
dysregulation to prevent the
assimilation of content author is
content and this proposal literally aims
at reducing terrorist content online
note not illegal content terrorist
content in order to reduce risks of
radicalization this avoids any what we
have seen through the experience that a
lot of radicalization happens outside
the online world and that radicalization
has other causes which are not online
content it seems that the politicians
need to send a strong signal before the
elections we need to do something strong
against terrorism and the way to do that
is through three measures three measures
three as yeah we will see in a minute
first a Speedy Gonzales takedowns my
favorite platforms will need to remove
content based which has been declared
terrorist content by some combatant
authorities and this definition of
terrorists contest is of course vague
and also incoherent with other
11 pieces of legislation which are
already in place but not implemented all
across the EU this removal needs to
happen in whatever this is sort of fast
food fast food principles applied to
online world to all the visual material
and they give you some sort of complaint
mechanism so you do have any problem
with that your content being taken down
you can go and see this in content is
legal please say take it back
but in practices you read it you will
see that it's likely to be quite
ineffective and first of all also the
upper block it will not be penalized so
if they over block legal content nothing
will happen if leave if they leave one
piece of account which is illegal on
their platforms day they will face a
sanction the second issue is the dose of
measures for voluntary consideration
according to this second measure the
states will be able to tell platforms I
have seen these terrorist content your
platform this looks bad really really
bad and so I really felt I had to ask
you could you be so kind to have a look
just if you wish of course I mean no
worries and the plat of them will decide
according to their own priorities how to
deal with this voluntary request third
good old upload filters as the third
measure they are proposing upload
filters or general general monitoring
obligations in legal jargon are
prohibited in EU legislation but anyway
let's propose them we'll see what
happens and in order to be able to push
them in the legislation let's give them
an Orwellian twist to our filters let's
call them in a different way so we call
them proactive measures platforms will
need to proactively prevent the certain
content is uploaded
how will they prevent this upload
filters of course I meant proactive
measures
and whether it is copyright or terrorist
content we see the same trend we sees
you see these one-size-fits-all solution
a filter an algorithm that will compare
all the content that is uploaded will
match it against a certain database and
then we block it or not we will need
many filters not only one filter we need
filters for for audio for images for
text and also one specifically for
terrorist content whatever that is
defined so this is basically the
principle of lawmaking today we need
really want filters what can we went to
have them we've got an issue with
filters well quite a few issues but in
big an issue first of all they're
illegal the European Court of Justice
said like this a social network cannot
be obliged to install a general
filtering covering all of its users in
order to prevent the unlawful use of
musical and audio-visual work in the
case subong versus network despite this
it seems that automated content filters
are okay not general filtering covering
all of its users of course there are the
technical issues yeah there's some
technical issues I one of my best
example that magnificent examples of how
filters do not work was a James Ross the
pianist that we a few weeks ago try to
upload a video of himself playing back
in his living room the algorithm
detected some copyrighted content owned
by Sony Music and automatically took
down the content of course he complained
he took the content back and baby stop
use that it's a good example of how
filters do not work because one piece of
back we who died around three or four
hundred years ago is of course out of
copyright
this video of a famous artist is taken
down we can imagine the same for many of
your content so not only that filters
don't recognize what is actually
copyrighted and what is not but they
also don't recognize exceptions such as
remixes caricatures or parodies when it
comes to copyright filters can tell and
this is why memes were a central part of
the protests against article 13 and this
is why we will show soon why this filter
has a huge potential for a political
tool another issue with automated
content filter is that they don't even
recognize contests contexts either when
it comes to hate speech or terrorist
content they can't tell nonces a girl
decided to share her traumatic
experience of receiving a lot of
injuries and not injuries insults
insults in her mail box from this person
who was hating her a lot and threatening
her so she took it and copy pasted on
her on her Facebook account made a post
and her profile was taken down why
because the automated solutions can tell
that she was the victim not the actual
perpetrator right and this is very
likely to continue happening if this is
the solution put forward then it's also
a problem for for SMEs of course because
these tools these filters are very
expensive YouTube spend around 100
million dollars and to develop Content
ID which is the best worst filter that
we have a now online so we can imagine
how it is going to go for European SMEs
that will need to to copy that model
probably getting a license for them I
can imagine in order to implement those
filters online in the end this will just
empower these big companies who already
have their filters in place so they will
just keep doing their business as usual
then this new company that we would like
to develop a different business model
will be prevented from doing so because
they will need to spend a lot of money
on these filters then there's the issue
of privatized law enforcement the
privatization of law enforcement
attributes change past state attributes
are now shifted over can you take care
of it two entities that are not really
driven by the same values that a state
should at least be driven by I'll just
give you one example from a project
called Diamond dollar project a study
commissioned by the Parliament to look
at hate speech definition in different
EU Member States their conclusion their
huge disparities between what it means
hate speech what hate speech means in
Germany compared to what hate speech
means in Romania to what it means in the
UK so in this context how can we ask a
company like Google or Facebook to find
the definition I mean are their terms
and conditions the standard that we
should see as though one influencing our
legal definitions am I the only one
seeing conflict of interests here and
there's a problem there there was we
have these filters for copyright the
preachments or any other purposes like a
terrace content we of course will have
it as a political tool once we have this
fork abroad why are you not going to
look for those dissidents in every
country with distance change very often
I see I see that in Spain but is it all
across the EU and nowadays so once we
have them in place over one thing one
small sign like copyright why not for
something else for something more
political there is a really interesting
example coming from Denmark some year or
year and a half ago the Social Democrats
announced there
immigration plan they made the video in
which metal-free dickson talked about
how great their planets and territory
some people are happy some were sad some
of the sad ones decided to criticize the
plan and made a video about it it was a
critique during which they caricatured
her but they used to audio bits from
their announcement video social
democrats sent a letter to the NGO
accusing them of copyright infringement
and threatening a lawsuit
obviously the NGO thought yeah we don't
really have enough money to go through a
big court case so we're just gonna take
the video down they took it down now why
is this case important if a automated
content filter for copyrighted material
would have been in place the Social
Democrats wouldn't have to even lift a
finger the job would be automatically
done why automated content filters can't
tell exceptions such as parodies and
this is a very clear case on how
copyright infringement can be
strategically used to silence any
critical voices in the political sphere
so we see a few threats to fundamental
rights first on privacy that we need to
scan every piece of content yes so they
can discard this information then we
will live in a sort of black box society
and that will affect the freedom of
speech we will face also over censoring
over blocking chilling effects and these
tools which are going to be repurposed
as a political tool in a nutshell rights
can only be restricted when there is a
prove the necessity when the measure is
proportional and when it this measure is
also effective these filters are
necessary for the ends they they want to
achieve they are not proportional as we
have seen and they are not effective as
we have seen as well so this in effect
they are unlawful restriction of a
freedom of expression and privacy right
now obviously we were also unhappy about
these and I mentioned before how we
organize within our network to fight to
get a strong privacy when it comes to
copyright this fight went out of our
network it it got a lot of people mad
people like librarians startups the UN
special report or all of those they're
basically and more and even YouTube in
the end who thought about endorsing are
ready to campaign what we learn from
these fights is that we really need to
share knowledge between us we need to
team up coordinate actions be patient
with each other
when it comes to different skills it is
important to unite them when it comes to
different perspectives it is important
to acknowledge them if we're separate
individuals by ourselves were just many
but if we're together we're one big
giant that is where the impact plays now
this is basically a call to you if
you're worried about anything that we've
told you today if you want to support
our fight if you think that laws aimed
at controlling our bodies and our speech
should not be the ones that should rule
us and our internet I think it's time to
get involved
whether you're journalists writing about
privacy or other topics whether you're a
lawyer working in a human rights
organization whether your technical
mindset whether you have no clue about
laws or anything like that come talk to
us we will have two workshops one only
privacy one on upload filters we'll be
answering more questions if you have an
you can't ask them today and try to put
together an action plan we also have a
cluster called about freedom that you
can't see there but is right by the info
point in SSL and do you have any
questions or comments thank you
[Music]
there's ample time for Q&A so fire away
of your questions vocal microphone wave
your hand signal Angela are the
questions from the internet microphone
number one so the question is if the the
country is encrypted how companies will
be obliged to implement these filters
good question I don't know I don't think
that's gonna be possible they gotta find
a way to do that because either yet they
ban the encryption in the channels or
they they it doesn't matter because they
will make you liable if you have a
platforms with very encrypted channels
and you have everything on every there
but by any reason they find any
copyrighted content which is not a
license we do not paying money for that
will make your liable perhaps in
practice they will not be able to find
you to make a lie but because they will
not be able to access the content but if
they find a way to do so they will they
will make you pay
ok microphone number two thank you very
much for the presentation it you've been
talking a lot about upload filters a lot
of the telcos and the lobbyists are
saying that the upload filters don't
exist
the try log mechanism for the copyright
reform is as I've heard ending in
January and there will be solution in
the European legislation process how how
will we be able to inform this process
and influence it to try and make it
better before the European elections
what we had still have done that's why
we're here one of our main goals to be
in 35c 3 apart from enjoying the
conference for a very first time is to
mobilize all of those who have not been
mobilized yet
thousands of people have been active
they have been tweeting they have been
calling their MEP that the members of
the European Parliament they have been
contacted in national governments
besties with we still have time then
vote will be sometime around January
February we still don't know we we are
afraid it's going to be sooner than
expected but this is the last push the
last push to say no to the entire direct
it and say no to upload filters and
that's why we are here because we still
have time
worst case scenario will go to to the
implementation phase of course we go to
national member stadium say do not do
these these goes against the Charter
fundamental right and then we will stop
it there para either now which is my
hope in the worst case scenario we will
stop it for sure in in member states
[Music]
microphone number one the companies have
to do with that because they could get
but we are in a team you are all company
in Hungary and then goes our bond and
tells you you need to block this because
I think this is terrorist call it comes
from a home address my accession movie
would you do if you are an SME that
depends on perhaps not on the government
but on the general structure you could
get bad PR from the government you could
be perhaps to you because you're not
acting promptly on this service content
but it's true that is only for your
voluntary consideration again mark for
number one
thanks for the talk I also think when I
see a problem oh there is a technical
solution so it's hard for me to admit
maybe not but it does look it's like
it's the case but also when you mention
in the workshop maybe more with I mean
anybody can come but more eventually
with a legal background I don't have it
I'm a developer but I want to understand
how a system is working and I understand
a little bit about the European process
and the regulatory process but so much
so much so what's the most efficient way
for me as a developer to get a better
grasp of how this system all those laws
and regulation or getting implemented
and all the different steps well yeah we
didn't come to the lawyers computer
Congress we came to a chaos computer
cars Congress or house you can make
chaos out of it we need developers we
need lawyers we need the journalists we
need graphic designers we need people
with all sorts of skills as Andrea was
saying before and we need the developers
to develop tools that work so we are
capable of developing any calling tool
and tweeting or any sort of tool that we
can use to transform our message and
take it to browsers take it to the
members of the European Parliament take
to the National Member States we really
need you if we need something as
developers we have enough flow you're
seeing this world I think we have too
many engaging with myself already so so
we need you tomorrow and the day after
tomorrow ok any other questions
in that case our husband myself
Andrea what will be good start at a
member state level to start campaigning
if you've never campaigned before a good
start if one wanted to campaign at the
member state level and never campaign
before
yes campaigning for dummies well we've
got a lot of organizations in EU Member
States so as a person who has never
campaigned before and was looking for
someone to campaign with two years ago
in Denmark I was advised to look for the
Danish I'd remember so I did and we
managed to organise a lot of great
workshops in Denmark where nothing
existed because I tip all the Danish
member had a very complex grasp of the
political environment and most of every
members understand how this is how the
dynamic is working both politically but
also journalists also what the the
interests of certain nationalities are
so I would say that find your first
every organization is the first step and
then unite with the rest and if there's
no way to remember you can always
contact consumer organizations you can
contact directly your members of the
Parliament you can organize yourself
with two or three friends and make a few
phone calls that that's also already
enough that you can do so there are many
ways for you to help out of course make
sure you contact your country's mep at
european level we are being represented
and we get to actually elect the
parliamentary is there the only one who
are elected by us and not just proposed
by governments or other politicians so
if we want
to be connected to our country member
states but influence a law at European
level like the ones we talked about it
is very important to let our EU
parliamentary is know that we are here
and we hear them and they came from our
country to represent us at EU level a
thank you
any other questions signal angel do we
have questions from the internet well in
that case we're finished
thank you all for your attention
[Applause]
[Music]