[Music]
either
Esqueda home is anubhava home start or
is the snoreless - we'll be examining
whether or not Austria is a surveillance
state or whether this is just a mature
digitization so welcome to the stage
Tomas dunya and angeleka Adams our math
scribe is candy to my mind I can't even
read my own writing
she's a policy adviser so something
naughty lawyer is that right applause
[Applause]
has to come hi and we have been
introduced we're practicing in the
speaker's room and he's he heard us the
entire time we want to talk about
Austria and the things that happen in
the past year with the very conservative
government first let's talk about who we
are we worked for epicenter works
we work in Vienna that have a lot of
European work as well it was founded in
2010 - as a as a society to overthrow
this massive data storage and that
worked the European law no longer exists
but
have similar forms of mass surveillance
even today 2,000 2015 we approach in
using that was an internal secret
service in Austria that was being
founded there and we were sure that
there was potential for abuse with such
broad privileges another thing is net
neutrality we started the campaign's
save the internet dot EU and after many
many lobby campaigns we've reached some
rate protections for net neutrality in
Austria there's no talk on this subject
by me this year but next year there'll
be a reform in the of net neutrality in
Europe and something people are very
concerned about in Austria and in
Germany is the state Trojan so
state-sponsored viruses state built
viruses that are used for surveillance
let's look at what happened in Austria
in the past year finally we are back on
the world stage the busting codes the
the Austrian Chancellor managed to get
on the cover of Time there are not many
Austrians who managed to do that and he
was being heralded as the new face of
the right the federal government in
Austria is the key parties and here's a
symbolic image of what that means for
democracy unfortunately that's real and
of course we have to do with a mass of
topics here and we are going to leave
the core area of net projects
but everything was easier back in the
days look at the Hindu Rashtra in the
background and giddy cars first reaction
was my favorite this is where they want
to get back to him it was easier back in
the days because the politics didn't
understand the internet and it was
something that was easy to ignore but
today it's a it's a core issue we looked
at this manifesto in the first 24 hours
and probably this published color-coded
version of it this version summarizes
that there's a new surveillance package
there's a broadening of surveillance
powers internet politics is essentially
industry politics there's still no
transparency law and European law is
being broken in a few places the
European Union was also important
because we had the present president
presidency and this meant that many
European topics that should be done but
usually be treated in Brussels were now
being discussed in Austria we also were
president of the European connection
board and visiting flag we really had to
reach European consensus we had very few
privileges they also had the presidency
held the peasant entity of Barrack we
had a lot to do in last year one topic
that was a huge subject was the
surveillance package
that was the same as last year
a half moon up in Campania King this is
my kid and after eight months of
campaigning against this we were able to
to overthrow eight of these twelve
proposed measures and we celebrated this
as a as a success and Minister resigned
and the but that was when the when the
right extremist right-wing FPO was an
opposition party and opposed these
surveillance measured and also opposed
the F P who proposed these measures now
both of them are part of the government
and they've evidently changed the mind
the surveillance packet has returned
here's a short as a small overview of
what's in there on one of the measures
is state-run spy software spy when the
broadening of CCTV use of MZ cat Kappa
captures use of license-plate
recognition about data storage that is
slightly different because there was a
very low threshold the registration of
SIM cards is going to be obligatory and
the changes in letter secrecy and we
went to protest in -20° we were very
unlucky with the the weather at our
protests the there was a lot of
criticism even in 2017 but
was normal obsolete oblivion when these
were proposed again just a year after
that was we really went to took the
streets again and we also arguments
about the hearings which were supposed
to be non-public and as is a Viennese
tradition we when we met with the
opposition in a cafe we flew in
Constanta courts and our lawyer
explained our criticism to the all the
opposition parties in front of the media
just to just to get it out there so on
the Wednesday the following week the
security package was passed in
parliament and how should we be
guaranteed that in Austria where the gap
in the law was that the gap was left
open deliberately an internet a security
hole a back door for children's is left
unpatched so that you can query and
research and that's because I'm asking
how can I guarantee that this won't
happen in Austria well I can't really
see the connection between IT security
in the public sector and the security
package I have to study but the I think
these are two very relevant but
different topics so as ten quotes is
about my age he grew up with the
internet he should understand these
things and you see what our job is we
they lack technical expertise
politicians of all parties and
particularly regarding the federal state
Trojan that there are complex issues at
stake the knowledge there is a
six-year-old is required that a Trojan
can be installed and that such holes can
always be used by a third party
is something that in most countries
doesn't occur in the debate and we
managed to get this information up to
the Chancellor ahead of government and
as soon as the software will be in use
in Austria I think the debate would go
on sadly it won't be the case that RT
Security will be better in Austria than
in other countries and the person that
made it most clear was our technology
Minister Norbert Hoffer well if I'm
hacked I will then be hacked yeah but
actually this surveillance package isn't
that bad kicker the interior minister
says about it that it's targeted if if
effective proportion 'it's surgically
precise and equipped with a package of
legal recourse legal securities we
looked at whether this is true and we
look at legal securities and you have
different measures here in this graph
and the measures against them you see a
red dot so you see that these are points
where legal protections are missing and
within looked at whether this is
surgically precise and not a mass
surveillance measure and then we thought
well if we are talking about
surveillance in the Paris public space
that's something you can hardly evade
and a data storage that can be used
across the board
registration obligation for SIM cards
these are mass surveillance measures and
a bit of mass surveillance that was
already too much these measures are now
going to come into force one after the
other the first ones are in force the
ones with the red frame are in force
since June 2018 the others for the
others there's a bit more time the state
Trojan has been postponed until 2020 it
is the lowest pass but it will only be
applicable from 2020 there is
development going or work going on and
they see whether anything is feasible
and it is to going to be extended in
2025 automatically unless Parliament
votes other or otherwise and we consider
this a
measure that is illegal against the
Constitution but unfortunately we have
very little ways of recourse we hope
that the opposition parties as one of
the MPs has already announced that they
will go to the Constitutional Court and
have this checked
what else is was very important this
year was the BVT affair the the Secret
Service will be known to some people now
this year we have been dealing with it
for a bit longer but from the time when
the legal foundation for this interior
Secret Service was created and we
already then said there is hardly enough
control and transparency and to cap it
all to crown it all there is we have now
a search or home of the into this
interior Secret Service because of
corruption and North Korean passport
templates and in that search data about
the right extremist scene from the head
of the right extreme Department were
taken this is someone who wasn't
actually accused of anything in this and
what does this have to do with the
Interior Minister well his highest civil
servants that he selected himself he
went along with witnesses to the court
and told them to enforce the accusations
so that this search will take place and
so we have a FBO politician involved in
this search and there are minutes that
say that they took a plastic bag of hard
disks and surely this is something that
the Investigative Committee that exists
for the for this interior Secret Service
will have a lot of things to clarify and
it's good that this committee looks at
both scandals the one that happened
under the Interior Minister by the FBO
the right-wing party because there's a
lot to look at what this service
actually did since its inception to in
2002 and then the 2nd affair
and the interior minister kick all this
rebranding and we know that the the
search that was conducted was illegal
that's what has been resolved a judged
by the court ruled by the courts but
then tactics were changed kik is no
longer trying to rebrand this using the
home search but they looking at secret
services as a whole because we have no
separation between secret services and
police and the threat that head
positions will be rebranded is very
strong another thing where security
apparatus is being upgraded is the
police and justice but also the police
11,000 new jobs are going to be added at
the same time inter mystical is lowering
the hurdles concerning concerning
reading and writing capabilities and so
the police ranks are they are trying to
fill and we had this campaign has gone
yet that was a sad no but for a long
time but these days you can sign a
petition there for the resignation of
mr. kicker Hobart kicker
this site will stay up as long as I have
it kick it is in office so he can pass
it on tell your friends about it it's
not politics review would be complete
without the GDP our that went in force
that came to force in May and the panic
of course was was huge with large fines
that could be imposed and with
requirements to change national laws
that was a very long process in Austria
as well even though this was known two
years beforehand but of course there was
a was a flood of changes in laws in the
first quarter of 2018
including the fact that sanctions or
fines should the enshrined in European
law shouldn't apply initially that's a
fun idea but it it doesn't work that way
people think that we don't have fines in
Austria but that's just not the case
another thing that's very worrying is
the fact that surveillance is used
disproportionately against minorities
some examples of this from the past year
this is an algorithm that is for
unemployed people to help them find work
and these are being split into three
groups that's the first of these is
group aid that's highly educated people
who don't get any funding there's a
group be they get they get group a does
not get any funding Rapide gets most of
the funding and ripsi is fairly hopeless
and again gets no funding at all and
this algorithm downgrades people have
many children or live in the countryside
and they're therefore more likely to be
part of Group C that does not get any
funding at all and the justification was
that this simply mirrors the
discrimination that already happens but
of course this simply furthers
discrimination there's also a dragnet
investigation in health data
insurance companies you have to use risk
assessment tools - and have to screen
how many people call in sick if this
happens too frequently too long all this
has to be double-checked and all this is
supposed to make these companies more
economical and get I gave her mentioned
that many things crossed our desk in the
past year we went the extra mile and
read all of them and there was one law
where we had to had to act immediately
and this law wanted to open all
databases all public databases for
research and that can be financial data
but also health data and that can be
used by universities but also by
Cambridge analytical that just lay about
as a law nobody cared but we discovered
it and showed this to a physician party
is to the media we tried to raise
awareness but nobody was interested and
we finally met a journalist who ran the
story and suddenly it was in in all the
papers and now there's an ethics board
and everything has to be cleared by the
individual ministries there's no longer
any it's not wrong it easy as easy to
sue but and these data have to be have
to use pseudonyms but
there are it's very easy to discover -
to discover correlations just last week
there was a draft social welfare reform
that with access to all kinds of data
for on household data and the data and
what was also planned in this measure
was that the nationality of the
biological parents were supposed to be
accessible so that gave it the name that
we not we but others gave it the Arians
paragraph because there's no way that
you should understand understand why the
nationality of biological parent should
be of interest but that of course to
shows you where this all is going and
also with asylum procedures which has
been severely restricted again basic
rights were massively restricted also
concerning privacy rights so authorities
were allowed to ask asylum seekers to
hand over their mobile devices and have
them read out completely that's a much
stricter measure than those effected
affecting the accused in criminal
procedures Criminal Court cases at the
same time medical secrecy rights were
restricted so doctors have to now report
or give information on those that seek
asylum or that those that are going to
be reported and we in this area network
with other NGOs that are not just from
that net politics field that has been
very valuable and the fact that we could
add our expertise on privacy and net
politics bring it together with
expertise in the social securities and
and and Asylum procedures these sorority
pacts was a
Packt of ngos kind of that we funded
with other end years and one of the
largest in Austria is involved and sixty
others have now joined as well and the
idea is that when attacks on civil
freedoms happen you would stand together
and join forces and if some NGOs
themselves get attacked which in times
like these does happen this is very
important
another thing that had to be implemented
this year is the passenger data
processing directive and this is about
storing passenger named records and
surely this directive is in violation of
EU basic rights there has been an ECG a
judgement about exactly this data
between Canada and the EU Austria didn't
only implement this directive but also
even they what they called gold plated
it and passed stronger medicine than was
required on the at the U level the
comment was that flights into the U or
out of the huge underlies storage but
not interior EU flights but that's
what's included in the implementation
Austria it's about the whole record that
is very broad everything that's
connected with a flight so that is of
course departure and destination through
the places and and the names of the
people involved booking details the time
of the booking the method payment method
and also information on the seats
assigned the meal choices which of
course gives you an insight into
religion at some time and this will then
be passed twice to national authorities
and that's before Department after
arrival and that of course is excessive
and that has been confirmed by the ECJ
and we will be going to the courts
against this together with the
gesellschaft for fights later in Germany
so we are
optimistic that this will be abolished
just like data retention in order to not
have to clear up things nationally after
things have gone wrong at the EU level
is important to deal with EU topics
early on because you are most efficient
as a small organization in the you if
you are there early and a topic that has
been engaging us is the copyrights
directive we warned against these upload
filters as early as 2016 saying that
there are nothing but the censorship
infrastructure that we know from China
because people's contents are checked
before they can even appear and that is
creates a very dangerous precedent and
we warned that upload filters as soon as
they existed just like every
infrastructure will be extended and we
were confirmed by now you have the
terrorism regulation that even before
the copyright directive is finished once
used to use apply filters against
extremist content but there's more in
this copyright directive this is an
answer we can sinner a copyright for
publishers and this is dangerous in
times of fake news when the task is to
to spread and coach journalists content
and not prohibit it we've been on the
road against this law for a long time
and we want to take actions of different
kinds to show that this is a one-way
road for the Internet as well as for
society as a whole and a networked life
that we that is going to be threatened
in our democratic times it's very
important to have these rights and these
actions have not just been taking place
in Vienna but also in carts and in spoke
and the last we did was how the press
conference with the head of the
Wikimedia Foundation in Vienna because
Wikipedia of course is particularly
affected by this they have hardly any
copyright violations because they have
an active community but they quote press
content a lot and maybe soon they will
not be able to continue as they have
been acting before when this ancillary
if this ancillary copyright happens
so first the reporter was very happy
when when he got his file passed in the
parliament but this laughs should not
make you resign or should not make you
give up because there is a chance after
the trial log negotiations will this
will come back to Parliament and also
the EO constants where Member States
decide Italy with its new government has
been in confrontation tough
confrontation and even if we lose this
we can promise we will keep working at
the national level and Angelica's
already said at Pienaar we do this even
if a law like this is passed when it
gets implemented at the national level
you can still do something and the
highest courts are still there for you
[Applause]
seems evidence either and how that sum
up a year of presidency in the European
Council we have we have debated a lot of
things one thing we didn't manage to to
from which we didn't have any time was
the privacy directive your father had
safe stuff began the European flag
committed suicide I don't want to end on
a depressive note it's also the last
talk of the day and I don't want you to
get too drunk the the successes we had
that nobody would have noticed otherwise
simply it's the law the implementation
of the NIS t directive law didn't catch
what it was
so things have been copied from our
papers it's good if people listen to
small organizations and we were very
happy but what stays in place with this
law is a certain two-faced character
because the interior Secret Service the
PBT is now the authority well respond
scible for the NISD because that now
tells us that they are important
responsible for keeping us safe from
hacking but also responsible for the
state to trojan so there's a kind of
conflict there also in Austria you have
a right for three years you have the
rights to complain if you believe that
your privacy has been disrespected and
the Interior Ministry wanted to abolish
the period for police access
two years I would have been a gap and we
went to the interior ministry in the
snow here and gave them a hard disk with
some starch space because the reasoning
that protocol data could only be stored
for two years would be storage
minimization so we thought okay we can
solve this we'll send them a hard disk
and yes great that has been extended
again to three years another nice thing
the telecommunications law in Austria
was changed we earlier this year we
looked at all the sanctions for net
neutrality violations in Europe and
created this overview of where the
countries are apt in some countries it
cost it's it can cost up to nine
thousand euros but in others it can cost
up several millions and we showed the
countries how or how good or bad they're
doing at this and these of course are
enshrined in national law euro Austria
was in last place together with Portugal
and Ireland because we had no sanctions
at all but this year we're in first
place
with 10% of global revenue and that's
more than the GDP are and we were very
happy about how much Europe improved
over the course of a year we are very
happy the same law goes through another
round of input people say whether they
think it's good or bad and before this
happens before it's sent to Parliament
and after this the law includes a new
form of data retention dynamic IP
addresses that everybody was users would
have been subject to data retention and
they would have been easier to use in
copyright infringement as
sanctions as well and we reported on
this and were thankfully able to prevent
this new form of data retention together
with easeful yet so I'm not good in it
let's take a short look at the future
there we know about a few things that we
already know about a few new things one
thing is going to be the real name the
obligation to use real names on social
media where people supposedly will be
required to sign up with a registered
SIM card or an ID card there will no
longer be any anonymous SIM cards in
Austria starting from the 1st of January
you can also create you also have to use
a have to use real names in social media
and this is supposedly to deal with hate
on the internet with but this is of
course not not going to solve that
problem but it's going to create huge
privacy headaches there's also going to
be Network Network law after using the
German example in Austria and we're go
we already aware we're looking at the
proposed implementations of this we are
also going to publish a new version of
our handbook of anti-terror measures
which is which is going to propose
evaluations of of anti-terrorism
measures and
proposed ways to reduce and to to
abolish measures that are not
accomplishing their goal and we already
did this a few years ago but we want to
update it and want to encourage
encourage amateurs to - to take part in
the literature to process ok not much to
add but I would just want to say that we
don't all do this in our spare time
these days although of course it started
as a hobby for a for many of us we are a
team of 10 now working in our office in
Vienna and we have much more work to do
at the European level but we have many
plans for the at the national level as
well and the more support we get from
civil society the better we can work so
we try to be as efficient and
cooperative as we can just about every
document and every data record that we
use can be found on our websites there
are meetings every month the net
political evening and the coordination
meeting and at the end it's also about
the contribution by supporting
memberships and donations that makes
this possible and particularly there's
regular donating memberships make it
possible to plan in the long term and
that's very much necessary these days so
supporting members now we'll get a
welcome present from us from t-shirts to
the camera covers quite useful stuff
sometimes and look at this and see we
want this kind of size that we've
reached - we have to want to maintain
this and for that we need people to
support us and in otherwise it will be
an unequal fight and we would I would
hate her to have to tell you that the
other side will win if you have more
questions we have a Q&A but we'll also
have an assembly in the freedom cluster
near the addressed and we will be there
from 12:00 to 5:00 tomorrow thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah Dunkin food in photography or our
bite thank you for the talk and your
work and you know the drill we have four
microphones we have the Internet and
we'll start with the internet for having
fun desert you mentioned the has tickle
yet petition but that's non-binding
petition why why aren't why didn't you
start a petition on the on the
government website that would have to be
treated in Parliament well experiences
with these service citizens initiatives
were kind of bad at the time of data
retention we started the largest civil
initiative that we ever had in Austria
led to nothing and the addressee of this
message is not the Parliament anyway
it's Sebastian costs the head of
government that can in dismiss Hickel
and Parliament can only dismiss the
whole government such as well as fund
appellant the president so you have to
address the Chancellor and and tell him
to be responsible and at the same time I
have to say that we designed it this way
so that the data of people that
critically speak out against this
government will be given to the
Chancellor but aunt only will be handed
over to the president's office because
we believe that funda Belen the
president will deal with this data in a
responsible way but in a parliament that
has an FP a right-wing Parliament
president and with such Department I
wouldn't be so sure that the data will
be treated well
[Applause]
Nikifor no mines patron should not run
key in Britain it's whiticus actus alpha
leak heightened infra heightened a sperm
count which you said that that health
data was being analyzed to what happens
if I'm never sick that was a bit a
gyrate if this is about a non typical
medical situation so normal sick time
behavior will not be conspicuous and we
do have the Congress disease that might
help you mentioned that doctors
confident confidentiality was being
weakened what were the reactions there
yes that did occur there was a review
process where you can read the position
that it was handed in and yes many
levels this is the problem because
doctors just supposed to be looking
after their patients well-being not some
other external legal process so to put
them in this position and and involve
them in this kind of procedures is just
really very bad and it has this chilling
effect that you feel that do you wonder
if they whether you should go to the
doctor at all anyone else no vengeance
alright then have a good evening to all
of you
very good nights and thanks for
listening to the translation as well the
interpretation
[Music]