[Music]
so welcome to the second lightning talk
session I'm going to briefly explain how
the session works for the audience and
the speakers for all the speakers please
sit in one of the front row so you can
get on the stage quickly to deliver your
talk you can do so by talking into the
microphone that's very important so that
people can hear you do not turn around
to see your slides because then you can
yeah you can't hear me even if I talk so
you can see your slides down on the
screen here maybe it could be that you
are too small then just move it to the
side and you can see them use the
clicker to advance the slides stay calm
talk loud and clearly so that everybody
can hear your message finish on time
which is very important because we have
so many talks and we don't want to use
more time than we allow to then get your
applause and leave the stage yeah thanks
but I'm not and I'm not going to leave
yet I'm going to explain for the
audience how to listen to lightning
talks so it's pretty simple just be
excellent to each other
keep in mind all the announcement
digests all the announcements I just
made but also watch the time keeper the
time keeper is right up here or you can
see it on the screen up there which
helps us to track the five minutes that
every speaker has Alex would you take
over
good morning everybody with the last
talk yesterday with pedalin we tried we
decided to try a more speaker friendly
and more appreciative approach to
cancelling a talk you know more of high
four three two one our sounds we want to
loud ate them out so we try to use some
applause to stop the talk this is I
think more awesome for the speakers and
maybe for you as well for the speakers
as long as the timekeepers in the green
area you are in the first four minutes
of your truck you have plenty of time
when it goes up like this now you have
only about one minute left when it
starts turning yellow you have form it
left these are the last 30 set seconds
of your talk when they start to get red
so if the red turns up something like
Dustin you have not much time left so
and we tried in your approach 5 4 3 2 1
I think this might work yeah I think so
too because we noticed that most
speakers are already on their contact
slide and when we bust them out it's not
very nice so we just yeah send them away
with an applause all right I think
that's it I'm going to mention the
translation so a very awesome job by the
translation team please give them a huge
round of applause
we we will have the German talks
translated into English the English
talks translated into German and also
everything translated into French see
the website up there so HTTPS c3 lingo
torque for information on how to listen
to these translated streams yeah well
then I think we can start let's go with
the first speaker
[Music]
so good morning everyone thanks for
being here so early
I'm here to tell you about a little
project that I'm working on Saturday I'm
going to tell you it's a one-day
conference that I'm organizing in Berlin
next year which is very soon and I'm
going to tell you a little bit about
what the conference is about which is
the art programming language a little
bit how I ended up organizing a
conference and why I think it's
interesting to you maybe it's philosophy
which is open and open-source so let's
get started
so our is now one of the main languages
for data science and statistical
programming it is a great tool for data
visualization as well and it is free and
open source it's supported by the our
Foundation and it is widely use it's
just celebrated its 25th year this year
and it's used both in research and in
industry companies like Google Airbnb
you can find it just about anywhere and
I'm Noah I'm from Berlin and how did I
end up dedicating all of my free time
some of my best friends free time some
of their colleagues and some of people I
just met through Twitter because I
announced it a few weeks ago so it
started with our ladies I've been
organizing and our ladies meetup in
Berlin for the past two years and our
ladies is an effort by again the our
community to try to promote women's
involvement in our code to get more
women to contribute to code and to be
active and to feel like our is the
language that in a community that is for
them and we do that by offering meetups
and mentorship programs and I've been
really I think it's some of it's like my
side project and it's still some of my
best work I think over the last two
years and along that I also started
volunteering so it looks a little bit
like this I think it's really fun and if
you are interested in our I highly
recommend it's open for everyone
only the organizational roles are
reserved for women and a long around
that time but later I also started
volunteering at forwards which is the
task force by the our foundation to
promote all sorts of diversity and
inclusion not just for women so it's for
LGBTQ plus it's for people with
disabilities it's for different minority
groups and we're really trying to do all
sorts of work around that and this year
I had the opportunity to get for the
first time outside of my local bubble so
other than slack and github I've only
known our users around me and then maybe
a few data science conferences and so I
went to the European are using our user
meetup in Budapest this year and they
actually two years before that in 2016
organised the first Saturday event at
Budapest and I was really inspired by
the vibrant community and by meeting a
lot of people that I only knew through
slack and github thus far and a lot of
sub communities that are not
location-based in the our ladies in our
community and I really thought well if
if you can do this in Budapest why can't
you do it in Berlin I'm sure we have
enough people who use our to create a
similar conference so I thought why not
that's organized Saturday signed up on
github and that that's how I ended up
doing that so why did I like so much the
idea of it so it's very much relates to
my history with our ladies and forwards
it's the philosophy behind Saturday so
it's not let's just have another
conference for our and it's not let's
just have another event for people to
come and share idea it's really about
let's make sure that as many people as
possible can come and share idea ideas
so how do we do that we make sure that
it's completely volunteer-run we are
not-for-profit and if we will have any
leftover money we reinvested into
scholarships for the community or events
like bringing speakers and so on it's
low cost we cap it at a minimum wage
and we try to make sure it's both for
beginners and for advanced users and we
really make a lot of efforts to include
women minorities LGBTQ and people with
disabilities how do we do that so we
don't need to invent the wheel
thankfully and this might be the
interesting part for you there are a lot
of resources about how to make sure that
your events on your communities are
suitable for as many people as possible
and that you can use disk by annum focus
group you can use the great resources
from other conferences and I guess
that's it this is our great organizing
team if you're interested in more
information and if you want to help us
out then please be in touch
[Applause]
[Music]
bubbly sector information directive
yeah good morning lactic in one second
so I will talk about the fancy topic
public sector information and in case
anybody wants what that is that's
basically the open data legislative for
whole Europe which is at the moment
right now negotiated in the coming weeks
in Brussels and what does that do at a
Congress well basically ideally from the
headaches of lakita Knudsen about the
shoots in' or use public data protect
private data is like one of the core
fundamentals and I'm working at
Knowledge Foundation so we do a lot of
like data stuff like a fact and start
off energy sector which was recently
launched and you can hack the code for
Germany OTP or a year di and so what is
open data encasement nobody knows it's
basically data you can freely use modify
or shear by anyone for any purpose
meaning also you can make a business out
of it and this will you see here that
part is right now negotiated that's also
like open data or data which should be
open data held by like public
institutions or government owned
enterprises and that's the list what we
are demanding and to keep it short
basically everything which is funded by
public money should be also public good
or in Germany there's a campaign by a
big media which is called a work
friendly he's good he's killed the other
way around
so that's standing on December I was in
ETL shows devoting and right now the
negotiation and what is import because
also like in German in this legislative
period we should get a new open data law
at least that's like in the coalition
contract and I want to illustrate that
why that is important on one example and
that is like public transportation data
which is like right now really bad set
affair in Germany and why is that
important because for example we want to
increase mobility less co2 and it's a
big sector so that's the current state
where it's green we have open data in
the transportation sector here we
learned lab tech and everything else is
like not comfortable with 2018 I would
say and when you're missing data you get
second weird routing issue our like
bodies can see here and that goes around
all over Europe so by the end of the day
or like
in the long run we first have a human
being on the mass before we have like
public open data in the transportation
sector and we want to change that and
there's actually hope so when we use
open standards open software data
there's a great example coming from
Finland which they created this platform
just for Helsinki but it was open so it
was modified before anybody else so
there's like mirin which is a tiny town
in Italy at the epithet model like for
just 15,000 euros and you have love life
map where the buses are going and that
was done by one developer because
Helsinki was so awesome providing the
platform is open sewers and tables data
standards so what that means basically
you can move from like data shoveling by
your hand to like industrial rollout and
that means like efficiency words like
just also many think about what could be
done or across Europe when we have
stand-ups and that's the directive
should be the effort and it's not just
like this case transportation it's also
like for a transparency when it comes to
beneficial ownership of companies over
example of proper public broadcasting
stations are doing that this can see the
content are and use it later
so that's a detailed list I don't know
how much time we have basically what you
should think about it how awesome it
would be it'd be like public data as an
infrastructure and what can be done with
it and so please bug your local
politicians or whoever is in charge of
it and local level and if you're
interested contact us the slides are
online they are linked because it's I
think it'll be timely and I think that
was from my side so we still have time
for a Q&A
[Applause]
[Music]
and increase Christians right now yeah I
don't see any hands but we're always
happy if we have bit short on time
because yeah what's my pleasure
yeah check you away next up is password
strength meters
okay good morning we are talking here to
talk about passwords and it's it's 2018
and we can say that passwords are here
to stay and we're going to see them for
a long time now and we also can admit
that passwords actually can be quite
good considering it's like a
knowledge-based a single factor
authentication mechanism but passwords
are only quite good if we select
suitable passwords and that brings us to
the topic on how do we actually measure
the strength of passwords this is a big
topic
it's called password strengths meters
there a lot of them out there actually
there has been some progress in the
hacking community in the academic
community but you are still a lot of
debate of what strength meter is
actually good at what is to be
considered good I have two examples at
the bottom on the left hand side you can
see a github and this is the password
strength meter that starts out with like
a policy that is displayed in red and as
you start typing this policy is kind of
validated and if you match the policy
it's made cream on the right hand side
we can see GM X I try to try to create
an account yesterday for emails and I
started typing a password like one of
the simplest ones I could make up like 1
to 8 the digits and actually the media
made it quite green which is surprising
that this is considered to be a strong
password by G mix in 2018 now we are
trying to improve on that so we are
proposing a new password strength meter
we are planning to open source it like
earlier next year and it's a fuzzy logic
based approach that combines multiple
indicators for a password strength so we
can have like policy stuff in there like
lengths and so on but we can also have
like lists of like passwords we can have
Levenstein distance and further
combinations it's supposed to be really
lightweight so that it can be integrated
in every browser and every website but
it's only an approach and we have to
make sure that it is really good and
this is where my colleague Nick hunter
is going to ask for your help right so
basically there are a lot of things you
can use in the password strength meter
but when we thought about ways to
evaluate one we said oh we have a
problem you see in in science a way to
evaluate a hypothesis is to do an
experiment and that's why we need you
so we're launching the password hacker
contest with a goal of evaluating aspera
strength by trying to break and we want
to crowdsource your your knowledge to to
help build new better strength meters
what we did is we collected lists of
human generated passwords from people
with trust like our mothers etc so no
unfair competition there and this
contains a mix of weaker and stronger
passwords we hashed them with a 512 and
with a common salt to reduce the
overhead of expensive machinery for more
hashing and what we want from you is to
work in teams or alone
use your favorite tools do whatever you
like and try try to break them what we
want at the end is the plain text which
is the proof that the passwords were
broken and a short report saying how you
did it and which passwords were easier
to break and which were more difficult
to break of course we offer some amazing
prizes like Amazon gift cards a lot of
surprise work like t-shirts polo shirts
and so on I think but W 500 which is the
the old IBM design so you can also use
it as a break nerf guns and basically
you can come at our office and take a
lot of stuff that we don't need anymore
we we ship freely a hold of Germany but
we will really like to see you at our
office in Darmstadt so what you can do
now is go in on this address and there
are instructions there there's the first
batch of hashes and you can start
hacking yep thank you very much
thank you next up would be Ned link and
go hello everyone good morning today I
want to talk to you about netting angle
my name is Lauren and I'm very
interested in network stuff and if you
take a look at the web servers around
the world this is the kind of code you
will see nowadays it's basically in this
kind of example go web server this is
just showing you a simple website and
there's always a one big question if
you're in reliable service how many
numbers of sessions do we have how long
are the durations of the sessions and
what about the number of amount of
traffic that is transferred for your on
your web service there are couple
solutions you can use and you can blow
up the code completely and make it
really hard to understand it if you want
to make sure that the next person you
are hire can also understand the
business logic of your web server keep
it simple and try to move the monitoring
part away and there's one solution I can
offer you we add them all in a moment we
have the web server in the user space
and the UNIX kernel and the kernel space
and the kernel itself has good some kind
of tracking of sessions and why don't
you use this kind of kind of API so you
can use this for monitoring there is the
so called net link family the net link
family is a socket based interface for
users space processes to communicate
with the internal kernel API and you can
get various information about different
kind of stuff in total at the moment
there are 21 different sub sub groups
that are based on internet link protocol
for example yes net link route net
crup crypto where you can change crypto
settings in colonel crypto settings of
your computer there's also Mettling XR x
frm for IPSec stuff as a Linux and a lot
of stuff as I'm most interested in
networking I concentrate on net link and
net filter and there are divided into
three parts basically and a flock and of
queue and contract maybe if you're
worked with IP tails you heard of them
and in go you can now basically use this
by this binary based protocol to
directly communicate with to kernel get
information out there get a number of
sessions how long they take how long
they last and just use this information
is already there and don't and don't
have to blow up your own code and it's
completely in a separate way so you
don't have to blow up your your web
server and it can be done in a quite
easy way the byte stream that you get
from the kernel via the socket is
basically only a byte stream
indifference to Mouse by streams the
combination is the length type and value
not the type value a type length and
value so this is a little bit different
to most protocols you may be you know
and but it's basically all the same so
you just have to take a look at the
length check the type and then you have
to value value can be anything can be
from byte sequences to strings numbers
integers times times everything what the
kernel you can provide and for
conversation going has a lot of features
so you don't have to make sure so for
example if you want to monitor your
replication this is a quite simple
example with IP tables you send
everything through and a flock group 100
then you open the socket with analog
open in this example I set a timeout for
30 seconds just to make sure that this
will stop at 30 seconds otherwise it
will run forever and then
can get old and flock messages so you
have a quite good overview and what is
happening on your web server and you
don't have to change your web server
application this also works for
different kind of models if you for
example provide your web server in Java
if you do something like this or a PHP
so thank you for attention the most
information most reliable information is
to the main page and number seven net
link you can try to get a github repo or
check out the Linux kernel source if
there are any questions I'm around just
ping me I'm Florian and I'm happy to
answer questions thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
again okay hello everyone my name is
Frederick Albert of Quebec and I would
like to present the freaking based
project this year it's our I think seven
Congress when we are around we have been
starting with 27 C 3 it was very
interesting for us to get involved and
during the years basically build up with
the community around food Bo and drinks
I have to say that the last Congress 30
43 when we actually were inside compared
to 33 seats even if we could I see us on
a roof of the whole H was much better it
was warmer and we had a warm water we
have a big place where he could come and
do stuff I know how many of you have
been actually visiting through the
became hiking base during the years can
I just ask for the hands up who has
popped him also it's starting to get in
be happy with the place bit tight at the
end of the Congress I have to say when
people finally found us but this year it
got better we all go to that small
overview of the year which we are just
not finishing we have visited in the
spring you know again this is the poster
for the next year we have found out is a
project that actually when we are
invited and we can help you know kind of
you know promoting project from local
host it really kind of make it possible
to kind of cover the expenses of the
even for us we are a donation based
group so kind of you know what we put in
we put in if you support us good if you
don't well we have to basically cover by
ourselves we have been in fright cap and
Belgium which was firmly run even where
we didn't do extra crowdsourcing for a
bigger kind of compiled yet for us which
we have found out it's difficult after
to cover so experience another one I
don't know how many of you have been at
a EMF it was my first one basically in
gribbet on it was very nice we did a
kitchen free environment because getting
our stuff from Europe to the UK was with
complicated caustic transportation but
it worked quite file so it's good now
this year we did at 35 c3 it's where I
am you can find us in the whole lot -
between the door 2.6 2.7 as you can see
this is already our first evening
tasting and we are completely full so we
have been actually really nicely
surprised with the amount of people who
are showing up and also with the dynamic
of the group because I have to say it's
really maybe like you know one of the
first evens when we as a core group
don't have to do so much and people
actually doing this stuff they just come
and use the place which is nice and we
just Morris you know keep an eye that
you know things are magically appearing
photo shops you know which you know has
to be used so this is very nice
now we'll be finishing the Congress I
hope all goes well we hope to be between
A+ you know so we can actually fund our
project for the next year which are
again you know community kind of based
you know and open we would like to be at
the camp of course that would be
coordinated with orga very again we will
do our tasting events workshop events
you know kombucha making beef jerky
making incubators etc we would like to
do fermentation project fermentation
mobile which already presented before
which is basically you can imagine a
food truck but plain thing which is
legalized then can go to the different
events where we can really kind of you
know do workshops and stuff and I kind
of I would say hire protected level so
that is a project which I would like to
lead and which support of the working
base otherwise I believe we are open to
invitations so if you talk to us just
send us email food agreement of or you
know just you write for a team base you
will find us and you'll get
response eventually sooner or later and
we are interested to come to different
happenings we have been an mr MCD we
have been in the Balcon
we have been in the new sign so
different events we enjoy it it's
something what we like to do and promote
and we hope that more people get
involved and supported these activities
also in the Roma hackerspaces because
during the years I have to say and it's
my experience is my feel that taking
care about yourself from the point of
view the fruit drinks a bit of exercise
it really helps especially for most of
you who are sitting most of the day at
behind the desk try to keep a bit a
healthy in this side it really makes
your life more easy I would like to
thank all of you for listening to what I
have to say please come and visit us at
the frickin base and that's all thank
you again
[Music]
these have this github is they'll
pronounce that correctly get a basket of
you you see
hello I'm here to present ghetto verse
which is a resource preparer research
project and open-source project for
solving software engineering problems
and free simple steps and these steps
I'm going to present you so first step
is we collect a lot of data about your
software project this can be a lot of
things we used JQ assistant for that it
provides a neo4j graph database and with
a lot of plugins where you can combine
and link different data sources
currently we support five different
programming languages to version control
systems and many other data sources like
github issues maven build reports share
unit test reports and then as a result
we have a huge database with a lot of
information about the software project
and this is the data's worse for finding
the solution to your problem and to help
this we utilize the data a lot of
visualizations available there are
classical dashboards with three maps bar
charts and all those classical stuff and
more fancy visualizations on the right
side and here for example you can see
analysis for anti-pattern
this is antler we find a lot of cyclic
dependencies there for example and yeah
these realizations as opposed to help
you to understand your problem which is
the last step because as you know
understanding the problem is almost the
same as having the solution once the
ends to the problem the rest is rather
easy and for this we provide a complex
user interface for exploring and
analyzing the visualized data and get a
better understanding of the software
project in general that's the point that
I usually would give you a live demo
which is not possible here so you have
to do it yourself that's the official
blood checked URL or just go to
bittley's let's get it was gay you find
cases and online demos you can use in
the browser yeah and there are the three
steps give it a try if you are working
with software in some way and but
there's a fourth step you can contribute
to it
I'm currently it's a small broad check
with academic background but we hope to
build an open-source community around it
so you can contribute to any programming
language because we are going to extend
it to support more data sources with JQ
assistant or more visualizations and a
better user interface forgettable and as
in 2018 we are going to apply for google
Summer of Code next year so an amount
resolved so if you are student there's a
chance you can even get paid for this
yeah thank you next up is Z Rock
okay hello everyone my name is Ervin and
I would like to introduce you to a
secret project as you can see on the
table here we try to support all kinds
of devices especially everything kinds
of test and measurement related you can
see like multimeters or still a scope
logic analyzers all kinds of stuff we
currently support over 200 devices and
the question is how do we do that if you
look at the software stack of our
project you can see that the core
component is lipstick rock it is a
library that encapsulate all the drivers
for all the devices we support and
provides a unified API for all of them
so you can access them having only one
API to deal with and getting all the
data from them below that you see like a
lip USB lip serial port leap FTDI one
and leap GPIB lillypilly and these are
the libraries but we need to actually
access the hardware below on top you
have the lipstick client Vettes verse
software actually it tries to
communicate with your device's and
display the data or process it in some
way we will see in this in a minute of
what actually is going on there but next
to it you see valley particular decode
library it's a library bitters kind of
on the side of lipstick Rock it's
providing protocol decoders which I will
also talk about in a minute it's using
Python and Libby Libby the first client
I would like to talk about is the
obligatory arm command-line interface
it's usable for acquiring data
converting data decoding data
essentially it's a very scriptable tool
so we can do some kind of test
automation or whatever you like to do
with it
another client we have is sea crock
meter it is tailored for use of
multimeters so you can have all kinds of
multimeters and measure the data data
log it whatever you want to do with it
it is quite feature which already but
currently needs a maintainer so if you
feel interested please come to us and
talk to us
another client but it's a relatively
recent addition is as am you you it's um
a program that tries to emulate a source
measurement unit using a power supply
and electronic load I haven't used it
personally but I have I have heard it
quite good so please give it a try a
very even more recent addition is the
crock mini server
it allows you to access all your devices
supported through lipstick rock using a
JSON interface for example here you can
see node-red and interface to provide
access to a power supply and electronic
load finally we have pulse view which is
our most feature-rich and also the most
popular client that we have it is
available for example for Linux Windows
OSX and Android actually so it's quite
flexible in what we do with it and here
you can see some standard set up you
have two signals SCL SCA but have been
acquired through some logic analyzer and
we have added a protocol decoder for I
square C to actually visualize visualize
the data in some kind of meaningful way
okay now this is pretty standard you can
do that with any oscilloscope really I
understand that but what we do is
actually we go one step further and
actually allow you to have protocol
decoders written and Python that you can
use to make even more sense of a data
that you have in this example we have
attached a DES version or seven
real-time clock so you can actually see
what the data means to the chip and what
the data means to other chips that comes
in and out of chip but it's on the bus
so this is pretty cool because
essentially allows you to have any
oscilloscope that you have on your bench
if we have a driver for it or any logic
analyzer that you have to have all kinds
of protocols but it doesn't usually
support and we can have a driver for it
and provide you of all the protocol
decoders but you already have
[Music]
also what I would like to point out is
that various the Cypress effects to
development board available for less
than ten dollars or ten ten euro here in
Europe which you can use in combination
with zig rock to actually have a 10 euro
logic analyzer which is quite
feature-rich and since we have currently
over 100 protocols available you
suddenly have all kinds of utilities
available on your workbench for only 10
euros so that's quite popular and also
the reason why the secret project is
very popular in these kind of circles I
would like to give you some examples of
what exactly we have also it's Army TM
as a decoder oh I have to speed up ok
which you can use to trace and have code
this is USB also of pcap output and what
it owns takeaway is that we try to be a
unicorn we have lots of decoders and we
can give you lots of opportunities if
you want to contact us come to our
assembly or come to Twitter Mastodon or
just check nose Chad report on IRC
thank you very much
[Applause]
[Music]
and then next up is that Clark via
London on new it's going to be a German
talk so you might want to check out the
translation page on C Street lingo dog
for translated streams yeah good morning
- were initializing massive auf Deutsch
my name is either fighter ich bin meter
vital and relevant feminist powerful are
confidential Spartanburg on each axle
inves inves some tea Martin Schultz yeah
I wrote realized he not Vida mala
Madonna loser
software I know hardware ana website or
Abbas of Emma the hawkish Dawson
scientists thoughts it's a mad at me but
Rock'em trims intimate relation in
charmville
I was rivets fair and good Nora and
Asian homogeneity phlogiston is Dustin
we were hopin out noon nine how a fish
is a snitched allowed then coats cos act
that an owner give each second order the
I'm Villagomez nuts are sue salmon is -
after that which was gone for me ideas
give her one solace each film flashy
hurt you should clean your children on
the air nation space and do middle
median gained as Alice own fook-la s
kept readers often vote yeah offers to
in current name leash Yuen Tai Shan Shan
basis of the Asia hardware Vasia Zell
some dark avatar common hopped hunt yeah
cooking pasta machine all youngest son
by feel happen via inflicts adoptions
Isha height in articles find rice each
date Samajwadi fresh fruits long
expedition as a whole fish Eastern
translationally sawdust first we offer
shoeless wrongful and as our siege to
the herder on VR afflicts a privacy by
design and privacy by default the agency
shows article in Spanish they are
insured scone for nog by felon feel joy
sir fresh juices entry Hammond baton
rothenburg disaster boo scared in
deutschland
and I know film are forgiven inform
Pavan thus King Dharam das thought on
antonyms and users and a user and a
banana swept instace de Tottenham
clarify that Ansari pass water power
charge me she had seen the home disposes
and relative clients postcode Pokemon Z
Z a cooperative an ontology flyness
owner named by the hunter named Candace
tonality of toy avian in schism to
Invalides give her office to Sir Francis
million cost an order via port centers
worldwide in Java zones axis yeah
unfortunately that and take out Spanish
leagues for shipping order of note box
Tochigi in turn warehouse so adverse
vassman an encounter order in our
context Muslims in our I'm Shana via
regular message to millions into that
email for shaked without problem McLean
taking on a miracle motivator gather for
neutered and literally Facebook custom
audiences is of now a undermine
relations veto HST by ovation colleague
harm darshan or Tyler for garage doors
go for yeah that's common tool you can't
naturally over over-regulate opticians
of those cattle house reason the sift of
a new origin as well finish the
enlightened II system it nice at all our
skin you couldn't about off period by
the dividing of six period ionization by
their officers Authority for in here
shallots establishes order for infantry
poor in fact in Johnston fans volition
women event daddy tartan summit order
the oxy spyridon Vinod
alpha enterprising to meet super machine
or square links missed hounds now that
insured's off sister Harada bundesland
on the Infiniti at us we exact who
buscetta Candace again don't deliver the
muslin austerity she hadn't as when we
use our hands ever oatmeal a Ashenden
can be a charity Shri Hanuman via the
snitched songs via Mahon above any and I
never marked missing vhat sphere that's
come about signed us via our Spartan
welcome back just an unbelievable or -
lacy culture and up game when dot
defiantly sure list which dish is free
sources are exactly children Boston
Massacre Fulton hoped at least we know
retired Snellen Indian officers burdens
it's insertion site not eval who to
Technica Dita's alpha stain as a
missionary or isn't the technique teams
and mice insulative Klein Byzantine
Florida in Stuttgart in
baden-württemberg Abba and Watson's and
alloy to the pristine vicita and shaked
as often and TCP dump or John's to us
it's just only in Luton and big live you
know exactly shield on moot least fitted
a child's name in current us of an
aluminum now as when he had some actual
mission on a do it software energies yet
samba Antony man our budget who exact
escape my other hope nish was here
pursuit on - chef Sevan a shellfish
duster snitch
Nogales entire voyage a snitch item it's
hard country of Ananias whistleblower
Selena of 61 come on inflation
9 Garmin kleiner tip Merkley student ina
contact mukesh kite intelisano efficient
beard and off look fun by mishima
Allison or potent class Austin wish we
had no taranga yeah
dosmo it's called post mortem flag
whiterabbott keeps non-reserved
organization in home aimed right such an
absolute rescission transition doesn't
mean alloy to divest from tama
Dartmouth's at sale in the 50m annuitant
blurtin Ratish outshine have this animal
that owned - ah mama optin oh when my
fans Endora
Veniamin embrasure resort on problem
adventure or any such action dry season
or member i harmed
[Applause]
[Music]
and we have one of the usual suspects
pork pickup
so hi I just wanted to give a short
update about pork pickup and on the
first few slides I have some overview
for the people who don't know it yet my
name is Thomas and let's see so quick
the features of birth backup it's a
backup tool and you usually use it on
the command line so it has a CLI
interface like our single like it or
whatever but recently there were also
some people working on the GUI so if you
have non nerdy friends that rather click
around then you can also use it now we
have quite good architecture and
platform and file system support and the
main features are we are doing DITA
application we are doing compression or
ten decade and encryption and the usual
way you use it you you you read the data
from a locally mounted file system and
then you store it to another local file
system or you can also store it to a
remote server over as his age and the
one board will talk to another board on
the remote side a nice feature is you
can fuse mount your repositories your
backup archives and ok if you have if
you do not have a remote server it's no
big problem there are some service
providers meanwhile that offer such
services like for example our sync
dotnet or head snow and a new one is
pork-based comm it has quite nice web
interface and the port base guy is also
programming this nice Greek client also
if you don't want to rent a server you
can just search for another node and you
can do mutual backups they are encrypted
so you don't have a big trust issue
because the other guy won't be able to
look into your backup another way to use
it if you rather prefer to have
something in the cloud maybe
additionally to your local repository
you can first create a local repository
and then push this complete repository
to the cloud for
example using our clone and of course if
you have your own server you can just
use SSH the greeter will I mentioned is
called Volta and it's implemented in
Python and Qt currently it's tested on
Linux and on Mac OS but it might be even
possible in the future maybe to adapt it
to Windows and as I said you can show it
to your friends
another tool is pork Matic it's
basically a configuration layer on top
of Borak so if you prefer a config file
like any style you can use this tool and
there are lots of other tools and
scripts and integrations and we have a
special community repository and if you
search additional tools you can just
look there in general it's a community
project so if you are coding in Python
or C or seitan join us please
currently we are bit low on developers
but you can also help if you can't code
for example look after the docs or just
test it we have a good test suit and
using continuous integrate integration
and for platform testing we use vagrant
also we need support us for different
platforms so if we for example Usenet
bsd or something also come to us the
current status is there is all steep
stable release out since quite long I
think you can find it in about every
distribution and the currently release
is 1.1 so this is the newest stuff and
the next release maybe 2019 will mostly
have code cleanups refactorings and some
internal stuff and also a new repository
compaction handling it will be separate
not automatic like now and for a bigger
changes on the bottom for the helium
milestone we need more people because
the crypto changes will be a lot of work
and also the multi-threading changes are
a lot of work we also need community
supporters so for example if you can
help people because they use bark
yourself you can also help and look
after github and the mailing list
a security review would be also good we
have some known issues but also somebody
could look over the code and we also
need more sponsors and donations because
we do bounties using bounty sauce so I'm
here at the Congress
find me at paes164.com of the slides
visit the schedule and so on alright
next up is to exam
[Music]
that's why I prefer PDFs so if you want
to give a talk here
you know you do best with PDF it's
portable it's a document format okay
let's go how's the TF place is a PDF
laughing - attention attention
what accounts could sort of expression
they actually would see a gruesome
swiftrage improvement yet if we hadn't
that's what all announcements a goon
vlog for this one there's no plea for
Android on through early informatics
better shouldn't under t1000 Princeton
Haakon VII in Towson and that's why
we'll move along this is in the Nets
entry on of crops and houses bikini I'm
for my mom you have to be on their harm
tried house in ten months of sex and
rice he's title of carbon to Korean this
is the other ones first year in the
thousands even the 1500 yen and are and
that's where it's good off comes genuine
factor to Corey Jensen that wouldn't
quite correct through our bond diseases
yeah I know that 50,000 dine severe 20
have no issue in listen Julian Salam pop
years is basically wrong in ovens one
see thousands I can pop you does locked
are on the sphere I'm from good service
or compact eros template with Lamar in
Woodson now for Jesus yeah it's fine
5000 Christian multiple choice quizzes
opt was why the rx100 Isaac kind of
comes in when via 13,000 pop co-signed
on so the damage here at acuña Farook
severe and I ever Abba insights white
housing food Sanjana migrants kinda
close ones who seem Norman's to mix em
you ever seen the on garden with queer
Coates individual area codes
yacon soup soy de Musique odeon by the
Chiron are often close women are often
hardened yes Ken because one dollar sign
on the fasten dbvar 20 time on changing
student on the close one online so ions
itself you go being the synthesis guns
can oven juniors their conditions the
night import photos will turn uncool no
actually undress yet religion of
consequence relying in most exciting
guitar not this soon the art insight on
here in the 2010
exam room that's this heart set on
getting that tonight on between the
harmone from Korea codes of data matrix
codes give accidental failure booster
and flexibilities in your template no
more complete no implemented in our test
the Dalton Bank no implement years he
had some Postgres elements into enough
toy and documenting scanner how oft to
prevent in scanner VN I agree I mean
item talk we at the metonic is the
matter of Isaac install but incredibly
software it was a Holocaust move it
inside inside boom camera outlying
platform through the online ionization
site ended food housing section and we
can be an web interface which was move
over to some touch from sniffed
unguarded the hardened unfiltered Hans
it's a nice romantic harp finger closer
concept integral innocently it has an
indifferent fully Infiniti missus new
concept for besonders compact a
mathematic crew for when the stood small
weddings Christian palatable choice
beautiful men
special my robots 5,000 zips and receive
my height closer in to see me as transit
ranch dollar when it was esteem up
convicted government seemed to be
destined Thunder is taking forums over
this worked side ended 4,000 be shaved
ignorant self meter integral C 1 1 4 GB
time through fluent in to mix em the
hormones even being the problematic
MacLean Scanlon Agnes kinda front and
implemented in the web interface is its
side unfunded CRS and 6.1 enough
transition over a time when all the
modules included soon with the NZ splat
form implemented our Ganesha temptation
our Piper chef Texas tournament iPad app
so for DD time for a crew from Khufu in
V understood snow Eddings our friend
equals new phone on the image to owns an
artist templates event on to our hotel
mama we done lighting talk mean the SEMA
and Richard Constituent Assembly for my
comment on this conundrum smartly alibi
come on sign from one base ghost housing
on the inspector in triggered flash guns
or monument for notional soon
[Applause]
[Music]
all right next up is Yama
I reveal my attributes there's a if you
click the left oh I I'm already supposed
to click the link ok let's see what
happens you have been owned no ok that's
that's a PDF right
yes appear you can also just okay you
can put it on food ok this work ok I
want to introduce air mat to you it's an
open-source project in which you can
privacy friendly secure and these
centrally provide authentication and
signing so for the user and the most
central thing is the app that you see in
the left side is from iOS and Android
and the project is intended to
authenticate and sign statements about
yourself with attributes you collect on
your own mobile phone so for example you
see a login to Emma to our demo
application that there's also in the
Netherlands a few attributes from
governments which you can collect and
you can then later prove those that
information to to others in a way that
they can be sure that the information is
correct but also that those people don't
learn anything about your interactions
online that's a key difference between
how authentic ation is done nowadays for
example when you click a log in with
Google or a log in with Facebook link at
this moment you have a user identity
provider and you want to look in on a
web store for example at this but at the
moment you first go to the web store
that has a page that says I want to log
in with Google so you go to your the
identity provider to Google and then the
identity provider reveals the login
information to the web store so Google
now knows what you're doing and
that probably isn't maybe it's the
problem if you want to order something
but if you want to log in in your
doctor's office for example you don't
want all those companies collecting that
information so what we want to provide
as a different solution is that you
collect all the statements that allow
you to log in somewhere on your mobile
phone so you first go to an identity
provider you collect those statements
then you reveal them to the web store
without communicating with the identity
provider anymore
and you can do that again and again you
don't need to contact that identity
provider again to do another login or do
another authentication so the security
guarantees we have is that the the
attributes the information in the app
that it is authentic it's signed with a
digital signature and it's well you can
prove ownership there's a you need to
prove knowledge of the air map pin so
you need to fill in a pin code to say
you have knowledge of that there's a
secret key stored on your mobile phone
that also says that you own those
attributes so you have a two-factor
authentication and the disclosures you
do are also in another way and linkable
we use their credentials an attribute
based credential scheme called et mix
which if you do two disclosures it's
makes it unlink able so it's a multi
show and linkable credential scheme and
that makes that if you as long as you
have attributes and that don't reveal
anything about yourself for example if
there's an attribute that says I'm over
18 or I'm a German citizen for example
if you reveal those attributes to
someone they can see that you're the
same person two times so the attributes
are not linkable as long as the
attributes themselves are not
identifiable and there's kind of
automatic automatic that data
minimization because you only reveal the
attributes that he really needs to that
the the one who's who approve in them
two really needs to see so you only show
relevant attributes you need to give
your consent if you want to want your
hand into so typical session goes you go
to the website of the web store here you
scan a QR code or you click on a link
the air map then opens it as
hey in this web store wants to know this
in this information of you you then
either consent or you don't and then go
ahead proof those attributes without
involving anyone except you and the one
on the other side the webstore in this
case we also do signatures so there's
also in since the 90s it's also it's
been a problem to give people access to
to proper signature so you have to
create a public key infrastructure and
people have to collect their own
signature have to manage their private
keys we also with this have attribute
based signature so you collect those
attributes for example your government
numbers BSN in Dutch and you can sign
any message you want so for example here
I can send to share data with my doctor
you can sign that date sign that
statement with an attribute and then we
have proof that you have you have
retrieved that attribute from from the
government in this case so in the
Netherlands we do this with a DP de you
login with DP day and then you collect
your your information it anyone can do
this is the D central
there are some more information about
this we're an open source project you
can see in our github the course in
written in go we're transitioning for
the server part to go as well it's a
Java server at this moment you can see
some more information if you want to
join a slack in which we communicate
about this you can ask for an invite and
a well you can download the app please
do so
[Applause]
[Music]
last talk before the break it's going to
be in German punch a home via triathlon
wikibooks Hospital Tom yeah hello Evelyn
uma my tie latest internet source
talking on understand Medina platform
from Vicki box prepared and as I get
nurse had in the here to spoil
surance the in hook form following the
Vicki box dead site in henan the speak
epoch capacity of the item is matter
finished freaks can dust superhuman
okay doffing path what miss he is
inmates on this new part is designed for
known some design at a steel design
factors months to then the hopeful
mathematic first English we were playing
on that sofa vent and behind abetted the
median builder hum dissemination
satellite or on leash dog of statement
sauce definite zones box known survivor
on demonology patently of video sign
this was Vicki bookplates go hurts a
dining outside so CLO does now under the
lien platform Yoganathan and after avid
motive multimedia ger abated
on women's it gives initially in high
totally abuse on and off government is a
layer of fire for football sue Martin on
the organizers own sports as a
transparent undemocratic to harden whom
Sanitas cancer that gave into next MIDI
notes at Sian raised so hereafter not
house and notes of Isaiah low Antoinette
7000 by matter finished freaks and
afters both water intrusion missus or
10,000 my haven't a girl on the SPO yet
Cielo insisting worst English invention
laws had such a Brandon let's jnana-yoga
doctrine for itíd vision it's also
denotes Akopian tres Nava often barely
known moons definite man exhibition
stand order
you know voluminous wikibook our skilled
work time commoditized fortune we have
alternative it through convincing then
advisers Artois and lyrically I shuffle
the spoken is often the big vertical
movement into finding the Froggers nor
the album Hamid affiliates why haven't
evolved our manager in 50 Viki
articulate respond or contraband and
boo-yeah cancer emphasis need some iron
Hamby as fu the Manchus markup for
officer Rhoads and Aladdin's convey this
being nice and far corner hyung's to
leap and off event invite us for years
target and as also internal too much
plain PDF for in via definition one
order of media nanostation azimuth EMF
it's wiser some and on the gambia of no
fighter dependencies nationally article
in height gives it Madison warden
pumpkin diameter
thus is the angle he book and Allah
undergone pointers into dependencies
this is greener dr. maschwitz in tempe
comedian that Hein also hopes to his
videos on beta this gay but only the
acres and Tyler was articulately and
Alan are chicken we defer Bennett van
won't indecent highest Viet Minh Tyler
phone in other words it man the article
visi
has been quite exfoliant recent convert
here at via in an insertion format and
she is an expert yet we are not done to
move to some graffiti and that's cancer
this team is an app it's the same as of
make passiert various version or
asteroids off of Nami tansy dozen homes
Oh hours we have on the wiki platform I
am pastor that's what net switch to the
person that's all anesthesia export env
don DET his nautical owned Bahama of
Nova and literary owns an auto on
automata chinoiserie game can thank
Rosco nervous cancer and often browser
law firm doesn't sue Kennish
Wonderland's Biden platform the decision
better for I'll owned
than at which offers of ang bayan thus
being is the seal be inside informative
finished freaks in iterative episode
zones were few and de metrio compatible
is of the ambassador's with and in
Denton Plymouth en current advisor
export August and two-finger and must be
evokes V entire shoe industry needs to
feel portholes and under harm you know
Vania mittens on contact calm world
would have a here under a human heart
wizard of
the endless yet unfortunate for divine
dad Vikram that platform when take
insurance industry owns for I'm escaped
here the email addresses phone zero
eigen mile when year or grad a few days
in Phyllis's export project interfered
Oda own was in the nephron recent site
owned and the Elantra society owns
Kentuckian and Johnston Ghana or here of
M congressman Finnegan's Mountains AHA
fish and their ideas and assembly or
roof 24 Han yang
next up is open H and we already have
the slides on the screen so we can just
go ahead
hi everyone and we're a small part of
the open edge development team we are
doing a we we implementation of Age of
Empires - I'm Jonas and I'm Michael so
what we are doing we are we have been
developing a free engine clone for H of
M pursue the conquerors expansion we
started in 2013 and since then we have
been doing it our game requires the
original game assets so you have to like
own a copy of the original game but we
have been writing a completely new
engine with unlimited possibilities for
modding and so on the original game
engine is quite limited starting this
effect that it only runs on Windows it's
a short overview of the technology which
we are using the engine core is written
in C++ but there is an extensive
interface to core most of the engine
features from Python 3 we are using size
and as clue and see Meg of G or Vulcan
isn't even mentioned here STR QT and we
have our own data description language
neon but more on that later so on this
is what it's currently looking like and
in the last year we have had three main
advancements VTech wrote new render
then we've got a new world simulation
engine which is completely event-driven
which was done by tomato and we have a
new modding API which was designed by
heinessen all of those advancements are
mostly in the background so there is
little stuff which is actually visible
which has changed in the last year but
now we are ready to integrate everything
together and basically finish the game
so the new central component of the
engine is an entity component based and
this is the game and entity which has
abilities abilities are now in green and
boney
boney are things like the unit is
standing on a hill and therefore has
more attack damage or in the abilities
are permanent things entity can do for
example exist move die attack whatever
in practice in our own description
language this in a simplified way is a
villager that just exists with 25 HP and
can move and die the definitions of move
die attack are not here now but with
that way it's possible that any entity
can do everything and so tweeze for
example can train new units or animals
can convert villagers or well relics can
even start to chop wood if you like so
this API overview here is the whole
thing that is able to
simulates age of vampires to the Queen
boxes are again all the abilities we
have new things like actual inventory
management so the monk transporting ala
relic is implemented properly and not a
new unit that is a combination of the
garlic in the monk for example and our
system supports nonlinear attack trees
so you have kind of arbitrary conditions
chained together for advancements in
discoveries for your technologies and
this is implemented the following way so
a technology is again just an entity and
the entity the technology has the most
important parameter the updates all at
the bottom which is a set of patches
petrus are a special feature of our neon
language that allow to change values on
the fly in the database so in this case
the update is on line 9 which is the
more HP patch that updates villager live
by adding 15 new health points so
whenever this technology is activated
then the database is updated with the
same trick we can do things like attack
and defense so that for example ranged
attacks and ranged armor are matched up
and produce the correct amount of damage
and we can do very complicated things
like transforming the trebuchet into a
packed and unpacked and the whole thing
is fed into the event engine as I said
which basically is a history of
everything in the game in past and the
future and what the engine and what the
what the client only does is playback
that view so it's just a snapshot so
next is funny new things like data
conversion and that was it already join
us and help us developer to
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you next up this crypto payments
in hyperinflation countries and beyond
[Music]
hello everyone thanks for being here
my name is Felix I'm from the - Embassy
Thailand and for the last couple of
months we were very busy basically
trying to bring cryptocurrencies from a
high level talk to street-level reality
and it's really a challenge and I want
to share some experiences with you also
experiences the other teams had on the
example of - so cryptocurrencies
basically have been the most famous use
case since we talked about blockchain
since we talked about Bitcoin but still
almost 10 years later nobody basically
sees any option to pay with
cryptocurrencies in the real world and
it's really a challenge to do that right
you were always talking about the
freedom of banking system at the same
time so many cryptocurrencies are there
at the moment and I just read a new
study saying more than 60% of all these
tokens are basically cryptocurrencies
compared to any other utility token or
something so for the example of - you
can see quite a big increase of
acceptances worldwide so we had reserved
with 500 this year and up to 4500 if you
look at Bitcoin numbers and all other
currencies it's not that much higher
actually or even even worse it's very
hard to get good statistics because
there are some maps you can register
your company your company if you accept
bitcoins or whatever other currency but
it's not really that you can go anywhere
and get a proper number of how many how
many crypto currencies acceptances are
in the world so far - especially
Venezuela turned out to be use case
number one if you look at it it makes
total sense Venezuela has an inflation
rate of 1.4 million percent for this
year
so people are really struggling if you
go in the morning buy some eggs you need
some money if you go in the evening you
need to quite much more money so -
managed to get really growing and
healthy ecosystem in Venezuela
so that we can basically say if you have
the hyperinflation country
cryptocurrency is a fabulous use case
right and there's not only Venezuela we
have turkey with some some countries in
Africa there's more and more countries
coming up but this totally makes sense
but of course for me I mean from
business perspective would be very sad
to say we focus only on the
hyperinflation countries we want to go
beyond that right of course you have to
have everything in place you have to
have the regulator's you have to have
texts you have to pay your taxes you
have to do everything and if you talk to
merchants and that's especially the
point you will find out they have many
questions and the most important thing
they don't really care for
cryptocurrencies what they care for is a
simple solution which fits into their
business process and they don't want to
have any investment right for additional
software for additional hardware for
additional stuff training so that's why
we go to the merchants we try to really
understand what they want and how we can
help them setting up a system and
afterwards also giving support to them
and answering questions right because if
you start with crypto payments and you
really go to the street level there will
be more and more things and questions
popping up from Texas to regulations
to how to integrate it into POS systems
so there's many many things and it's
ongoing questions right one other thing
is we started with the low-hanging
fruits for us in Thailand going to every
single Bitcoin shop there right who
claims to accept Bitcoin has a sticker
on the door just realizing everybody
just forgot it right so we go we went
into these stores and people look at us
say be what so they they don't even know
what Bitcoin was right because the stuff
in there they forgot it already a long
time so that's why I say it's really
important to give them ongoing support
and to help them basically solve a
problem and the biggest problem they
have is they want to make business right
this is what they really care for they
want to have visibility they want to
sell their products they want to
get more customers and at the end of the
day they want to get happy customers
because happy customers will come back
in their stores right so that's why our
approach for the example of Thailand and
also vanilla is going but in that
direction is growing healthy ecosystems
that means you have to have to the whole
set of things together one thing is the
exchanges you have to get your your
money back you have to manage a cash
flow as a merchant right so basically
you have to choose do I want to keep my
cryptocurrency for speculative reasons
or will I sell it instantly when I get
it right you have to have the payment
providers you have to have of course you
have to pay your taxes at the end of the
day just to one side and the other side
is the customers coming in right you
need to a community coming and paying
with that stuff only huddling is really
not paying with it right so you need
people who come in stores help and all
that so at the end of the day it all
boils down to sustainable ecosystems
thank you why I'm here for questions
thank you
next up is Park on
good morning I'm Jelena from Balkan orga
team I'm here to present our conference
small hacking event that's happening in
Serbia Novi Sad so for the next year it
will be seven times seven times the
three organize this event it's welcome
computer congress the dates has already
set up so it will be second week in
September 13 14 15 September Novi Sad so
remember it
what exactly is Balkan we got an idea
10 years ago and CCC to start organizing
small conference in Serbia because
there's a lot of students in Novi Sad
there's a big Technical University I
want to we wanted to share with them
this experience that we have here and we
want to introduce the young people from
that Balkan region with the hacking
culture so that's the reason why we
started organizing this and now it
starts to being annual event we are
doing with that we are saying just for
fun because we have a lot of fun there
so here you I think you to join us next
year if you weren't there yet so this is
the important dates the place is not
Asad Serbia and the CFP will be open
from February somewhere and the complete
list of speakers will be somewhere end
of July and yes we also have the CTF we
are organizing every years so if you are
not able to come you can also join
playing the city else and have fun with
us and who was this year's with us we
got some also famous speakers Travis
Wood Pete was a couple of times in on
Balkan virus from us Mitch Altman was
there also with soldiering more then Rob
from us so there is a long list so if
you are interesting what we are doing
previous year's you can also check our
website
and there is a complete archive with the
videos that you can watch so that you
know what how it looks like and what's
important yes we have there a lot of fun
we have some let's say that's tradition
on second day we in the evening we have
rakia tasting or rocky alex so if you
don't know what rocky i want to try
different sorts of rakia you're welcome
to come also if you want to try here i
key on our balcony assembly you can come
and try it just in advance to be
prepared what you can expect so i'm just
informing you so balkan
why now aside it's our hometown so we
started organizing there but now assad
is on the list of Lonely Planet I think
somewhere in the top 10 to visit next
year so it's a nice city cheap food is
very good incredible you can ask other
people's who already visit us how its
food and how it's a cheap accommodation
and the travel is very easy to come
because it's only one hour from Belgrade
Airport so it's very easy or three hours
from Budapest so you can choose it if
you have questions what we are doing and
why we are doing that you can also send
us an email we are responsive very
quickly and you can also visit our
website or you can track it as on the
Twitter also here on Balkan assembly
here near in the cows mess hall you can
find us we have some stickers we have
some cool stickers also this year and
also some flyers so you can come or you
can just talk to see what we have also
what we have we try to bring there also
hacking community to build a community
we also have hiking space area so if you
are from some hackerspaces you can
organize like um gods also some assembly
so it will be nice to join us because we
also have some blinking stuff and we
want to
bring it more and more to make it more
shiny so remember next September 13 14
15 please come join us to have a lot of
fun thank you thank you now next up is
exploiting WPS PBC on Windows Tim all
right hi guys my name is Jorge I'm the
author of Wi-Fi feature or Wi-Fi surgeon
open source rogue access point framework
so today we're going to talk about
exploiting WH PVC on Windows 10 this is
a Wi-Fi Association attack how many of
you know the Karma attack please raise
your hands okay I see some hands so
karma is a very popular Association
technique what it basically does is
getting money in the middle for the
attacker but there are others in this
talk we're going to talk about one
attack by exploiting WPS PPC that
actually achieves the same result money
in the middle over Wi-Fi so WPS PPC I
guess most of you already know it it's a
feature that allows you to associate a
device with an access point very easily
just by pushing a button
on the access point side and then
another button on the device side it
doesn't matter the order right you can
push the the device first and then you
can push the button on the access point
later but you need to do that within 120
seconds so other no other authentication
mechanisms in place this is how WPS PPC
words so you see this is the station it
could be a laptop it could be a mobile
device you push a virtual button there
then within 120 seconds you need to push
the button on the access point and these
two the association happens and the
station is now connected to the access
point what's the problem here the
problem is that someone can push the
button faster than the than the operator
of the access point right so it will
achieve a man in the middle position
because the station will connect to the
rogue access point instead
so this is a way to achieve a man the
middle attack over WPS BBC in order for
this to happen of course the victim
needs to push the virtual button on his
station
the thing is that even if you don't use
WPS BBC actively you are still
vulnerable on Windows 10 and let's see
why this happens the problem with
Windows 10 is that if you select the WPS
Network then you automatically the
Windows 10 pushes the WPS BBC virtual
button for you even if you are not
actively using it you are eventually so
this is actually usability over security
feature that Microsoft introduced for
another usability over security feature
which is WPS BBC how can we exploit this
first I will show four steps right so
the first step is that let's say that
the victim is connected to a wpa wpa2
network we do nothing here everything
that the victim is happy of course the
victim uses a Windows 10 laptop so what
we're going to do first is disconnect
the victim from the network we can do
that we are common methods we can craft
the authentication frames for example we
can leverage jamming techniques there
are many ways to do that so we want to
disconnect the victim from the network
that is currently connected to as soon
as we do that the victim we expect the
victim to manually click on the network
to re-establish the lost connection but
at the same time we advertise the same
network same SSID with a random password
if it's a wpa2 password but this time we
also offer WPS PPC capabilities so can
you guess what will happen the victim
will click on the network and the
virtual WPS button will get post from
his side so what what we need to do now
we simply press the button from our side
as well and the victim will eventually
connect to our rogue access point the
victim will probably have the impression
of the auto connect feature do you know
the other connect features the feature
what would you go back to work and you
see that your device is connected
automatically to the network even if you
had to
to do it like a week ago this is the
other connect feature so that it will
give the impression to the victim that
it not connected because of this feature
so what is fun about this is that the
network can be closed it will have the
same SSID it will be wpa2 protected you
will just click on the network that you
want to connect but still you will
connect to a different one and again the
problem here is that Microsoft has let's
say tied clicking on a network with
pushing the WPS BBC button on the client
side this hasn't been disclosed before
it's the first time that I'm disclosing
this and you can do this attack by using
the latest version of Wi-Fi feature
we're gonna put an update soon so you
will be able to do this attack for your
penetration testing thank you very much
thank you
[Applause]
now next up this human connection free
and open source social network for
active citizenship
okay hello everyone my name is Robert I
am one of the developers of human
connection which is a free and
open-source social network for active
citizenship now I want to highlight a
problem let's say you are a user of
social network for example Facebook
Twitter YouTube and you use the social
network as a primary source of
information then you are not in control
of your newsfeed anymore why Facebook
YouTube are private companies the source
code is closed source and the algorithm
determines what information you will see
what content you see if they run ads
also what ads you see and that's why I
demand that social networks should be
free and open-source software the
definition of free software the users
control the program non-free software is
if the program controls the user that is
the case for Facebook YouTube and
Twitter therefore we are developing a
free and open-source social network
which is funded by donations and we are
almost sustainable we need 30k per month
for a team of 10 10 people and I'm
showing you this chart because I want to
show that this works this market let's
say for the nation from that software
also I want to highlight that free
software is it is very important that
free software is funded by donations why
Facebook and YouTube have their
advertising customers and they will
probably implement features that are not
in the interest of the users right free
software is community driven and since
the users control the program features
should always be in line with the
interests of the user so
Facebook Senate will show you ads that's
definitely not in your interest Facebook
will collect your data it's also not in
your interests
whereas free software will not do that
human connection is free and open source
software we will not send show you any
ads and also we are not collecting your
data or if we do we do it on certain
certain purpose and you can see our open
source code on github and see how it
works so we are currently in a
technology transition you can check out
our current staging environments
it's called Nitro you can see and link
on the right side you can also see the
login credentials on the right side you
can go there right now and try it out
since we are in a technology transition
I will tell you what we are using for
this vision we are using vgs in the
front-end and we're using nodejs
on the backend side both parties
communicate through graph QL as an
interface and on the backend side we're
using neo4j as the primary database the
former version we have 4000 users and
2300 of them are active donators yes and
probably you have heard about similar
initiatives like that you probably know
Mastodon you probably know diaspora and
there are many more and it's we want to
collaborate with these we there's good
news there's a w3c standard which is
called activity pub it's a like a
language how different social networks
can communicate with each other that is
they can exchange content and from the
user perspective it's it doesn't really
matter which social network you should
join well that's the dream and we are
not implementing it yet but we are
intended to do so and we have bi-weekly
meetings with other social networks
including connector
we change and even next cloud they all
are interested in implementing activity
pub and we're trying to learn get
familiar with it and eventually
implement it if you want you can join us
use the chat for our let's say we call
it the open apps ecosystem the network
of the networks and we are also having a
weekly meeting for the open source
community and that's the link on the
right side we have weekly meetings and
we try our best to onboard open source
contributors we do Patrick programming's
we do video conferences feel free to
join us that's all I have thank you very
much thank you next up this iOS privacy
hi so quickly if you want about me Who I
am I am both the Apple guy at sir gates
security company but I'm also activist
and politician and things like refugees
and and they trying to save a forest for
a mean environment for a mean energy
company so a build a sample app called
my privacy where I'm going into it's a
very simple simple simple app where I'm
showing you the different stuff that are
important on iOS and that developers
should do and that users should also
look at and it's things like the
contacts API to kill in their API
location and the ID ID era and
surprising enough Siri I was surprised
the first time that I was researching on
this because Siri turned out to be
something that was appearing in by
default for every app so it's simple
it's a opt-out it's and the app is in
settings Siri but and Syrian search is
not always in the settings app it's so a
bit confusing and it says as you can see
over there on the on the screenshot it
says that it's it may learn makes a
decision based on how you use the app I
was wondering what it actually means it
based that's basically what they mean as
shortcuts obsessions which is a good
thing but at the same time also kind of
a pain in the ass as user the most of
the stuff actually all the stuff is of
Siri is on device so it's good to know
the the speed speak to text now is not
on device so that's something you should
know the gist of all the stuff on iOS in
terms of privacy is that it all goes
through a set of permissions you get for
the photos it's kind of the same as for
the events or the contacts it's it's a
lot of time just an enum which gives you
if it's all arise denied or if it's not
yet asked if it's restricted to you're
out of luck because it's mean it's
either parental settings or something
and something else in an enterprise the
Hat the app will crashed luckily if you
haven't done this which is adding what's
called
a description you use such description
this is something which is going to be
shown to the user this is that's to
visualize your photos on a map and it's
also going to be checked by Apple it
should be checked at least in the review
process that you were telling to your
users what you are actually doing with
it so please tell the users what you are
actually doing with it and don't don't
lie on new users so there's a bunch of
those which are basically in a in your
info.plist it's start they all start
with privacy and you have to explain
whatever you're going to do with
calendars or Bluetooth or whatever you
can also ask again that's something good
to know by calling this URL which is
basically the open settings URL string
it's not gonna pop up the the permission
settings and anymore but it's gonna be a
the users going to be able to land up in
this page which is basically in the in
the privacy over there so you have to
always check the authorization status
obviously and there are ways that you
can retrieve data from for example from
a metadata for if you get for example
the the location over there so this is
going way too fast please use the
Pickers that's very important because if
you don't use the Pickers then the
people will have to add gift access to
the full thing also if you want to be a
good developer please only pick up a
cell a set of data and don't take
everything else because that's what a
bad developer would do and that's take a
lot of information that's why the ugly
developer would you take all the
information for all the server uploaded
on the thing so please don't be that guy
have a good karma and just also you
don't need to ask the permissions a lot
of time you can use against the picker
there's something else on the contacts
API as well you where you can only have
one of the Pickers also the contacts
have a location even if they don't have
a latitude longitude because if they
have a postal address you can retrieve
this and so with like geocoding so this
is something to know you can also the
other thing that I wanted you to know is
that the location API is interesting
because map kids already knows where I
even though I didn't allow him to tell
him you might think it's because of
region settings but it's not it's most
probably the IP address I would prefer
if they actually asked me before they
centralized this map on where I am
on the location API when you request the
authorization you have to use and when
in user always please do not directly
ask the full monty ask first this and
then you would be able to avoid this guy
because the second time you will ask you
will have only dis and that's basically
I'm running out of time there is
something on the calendars which is
taking all the thing if you want to know
more about this just get in touch with
me I will be happy to show you this
[Music]
right next up is three area network
hello my name is Ingo I wanted to share
an experiment with you and it earlier
this year it's called 10 3 area network
and when I put up this presentation I
basically said well it's actually a
bunch of holiday images to share with
you but before I do that what is
capacitive coupling there is technique
to transmit or transfer information
through capacitive coupling which means
you have information you go into
something you encoded you amplify that
you send it into a biological conductor
like a human being human being is a very
good conductor like a capacitor has very
low resistance in internally and a skin
which is high resistance so it does
capacitive coupled to another part of
the body or another body then you can
take this information out and decode it
and get information back that works with
humans that also works with plants so
what I did at the diner con digital
natural naturalist conference in 2018 in
Phuket in Thailand is I wanted to try
out capacitive coupling devices are
built for a textiles in the first case
but the experiment was to use it on
trees and if possible to use it to send
information from one tree to another and
then use the jungle as a network and
send one bit of information from one
side of the channel to the other side of
the channel so I wanted to try it out if
it works at all that was the first
experiment I just stuck these capacitive
plates on some plants and you see my
face it didn't really work I don't know
if you see the oscilloscope it's a bit
of very very low signals that was the
second attempt I wrapped around
capacitive electrode around the tree and
it worked much better you see that in
the signal picked up very good signal so
I can decode information again what
could I do
I could transmit data for five point
four meters from one tree to the bottom
of the tree
that is how the schematics looks like
the transmitter is simple resonant
circuit transmitting a Kara wave of 300
kilohertz receivers basic radio stop
amplifying and filtering basically that
is how it looks on a tree left is the
transmitter with a sensor it transmits
the data over the tree picked up by
another part of the tree on the right
side and sent to a computer set the data
is sent over serial to a computer to
read out that some details what it can
what would implementation can do is
implement on-off keying the next step
was the costume town tree area network
for tree huggers so how do we pick up
information from trees we can hack the
tree it does capacitive couple from the
tree to the human body we can then get
the data out of the human body and
that's what we did we decoded
information we don't understand what it
says so the scientist is reading the
signal from the probe from the human
probe getting the data from the tree
right so if you want to try that out
yourself everything is up on github and
on my web page try it out have fun thank
you very much thank you
[Music]
next up is gnu/linux improved yeah hello
my name is Tim Hans and as you have seen
two talks ago it is very hard to make
the security right in iOS and Linux is
not a problem here because all the
features aren't there exactly so and I
think that is wrong and 2018 OS should
be able to restrict applications from
modifying each other's data and restrict
applications from spying the users
habits so yeah situation is that all
applications have the same permissions
USB drivers are fetched automatically
Xbox is a whole security nightmare and
processors can read any data in home
user and also their interfaces it
doesn't need to be exposed to each
application you are running so there are
a few developments yeah we always have
the ability to make UNIX POSIX users
groups we have up our movi f as in Linux
we have KVM we have namespaces we have
USB guard dock Express there are some
Linux distribution projects like cubes
OS or subgraph OS which are trying to
improve the security as well so I have
still some questions left for example do
you remember that there is a policy in
Debian that there has to be a man page
for every UNIX command on the system so
also why do we still have XDM why do we
have still
those graphical display managers so it
it doesn't make sense to have a
graphical display manager if you don't
have to switch the the display
resolution in in the display manager if
you don't if in that that's the case
with new Weiland and new frame buffers
so the kernel all already runs at a at a
reasonably disparate resolution so we
don't have to we don't have to do this
for for proper login so also there are
things in the Linux world so why do I
have to become an expert to get a new PG
key layout I mean this is an application
thing that we reasonably why why do I
have to be an expert to get an
authentication key so I would like to
make a first start by creating a small
but functional based system that
actually boots up without taking
resources from Seche us are like most
like thing is if FreeBSD things are
doing adding an up-armored profile at a
package manager that can be used to
install apps create a quick and dirty
installer push the thing on separate
Quetelet instance for backtracking and
building and yeah i would like to
discuss those ideas with you so let us
meet at 11:30 today in lecture room m1
and you see I have a few bucks and in my
slides I also have a I have created an
improved matrix channel as 35c 3 Linux
improved where you can meet me there
will be an email address Linux improved
if not called a year where you can
contact me and you can meet me at the
meteor lab in Vienna
if you want to discuss details and I
think that's it thank you next up is
navigating in Linux kernel security area
hello my name is Alexander Popov I'm the
Linux kernel developer and security
researcher and I want to tell you about
navigating in the Linux kernel security
area Linux kernel security is very
complex area there are various key
concepts there there are vulnerability
classes exploitation techniques web
detection means and various defenses
some of them are in the Linux kernel
mainline some of them are still out of
tree some of them are commercial some
differ defensive technologists need
special hardware or to work and all
these items have complex complex
relations between each other and it
would really it would be really great to
have some graphical representation to
navigate for easier navigation in the
documentation
so I created such a map it is available
at the github it appear AIT's the key
concepts which I already described and
the connection between nodes represents
some kind of relation this map is about
the Linux kernel self protection it is
not about cutting the attack surface so
this is a map it is very complex you I
guess you can't see anything but I want
to show some part of it
so the RAM those are vulnerable 'nor
ability classes stack depth overflow
initialized variables
usage information exposure they have cwe
common weakness enumeration numbers for
easier search and throw is a pecks
memories technique feature from jar
security which provides some mitigations
against those kinds of attacks against
those guys kinds of vulnerabilities and
there is and stay click port which I
prepared for the Linux kernel mainline
it is in it has merged into kernel 4.20
and there is a game sin debugging
mechanism it is not for protecting you
in production it is for debugging and we
can combine such technologies enable
them and fast the kernel to find the
bugs and zero days and I really hope you
are interested and I encourage you to
experiment with your kernel and read
those information sources there are
there is a really nice list of jar
security features there is a Linux
kernel security documentation in the
main line which is a really nice
document describing the whole picture of
Linux kernel security which tasks the
hell which goals we need to achieve
there is a list of recommended
recommended kernel settings from kernel
self protection project which can if you
enable them your kernel can be more
secure and there is a mitigation
checklist which shows the current
progress in upstreaming jar security
features into Linux kernel mainline
and to Android Open Source project then
and it is really not very funny to
search in your config file for the
hardening options enabling them and so
on
so let's computer's do their job and I
created a script which can check your
kernel config file against the hardening
recommendations and you can just run it
with your config file see the
recommendations and if and then go to
the map and see where in the
documentation you should read about this
particular feature so thanks for your
attention
you can catch me here at the Congress
you can write me emails Linux kernel
developers really like plaintext emails
and the main point Android the Congress
thank you now next up this past the
cookie and pivot to the clouds
hello everybody my name is Johan and we
security engineer and professional
penetration tester and today I want to
talk about pass the cookie which is an
attack technique that I've been using
for a long time and I want to kind of
share it it's not really totally novel
but I think we need to talk more about
this to protect infrastructure better so
what a cookies I think we don't have to
talk about that much everybody knows
about cookies they are used for security
for authentication it's establishing a
session between a client and the web
server and it usually is a single key to
the kingdom which means if you steal the
cookie then you get access to the web
application there was a lot of talk
about four five years ago with Firesheep
that was really really good but we kind
of the entire industry stepped up and we
kind of deployed SSL much more widely
which is very very good and everybody
should use that but what I want to talk
about now is sort of other technique
somebody might deploy or leverage to
steal your authentication cookies so
think about it a cookie might be the
single key who here uses AWS or
Microsoft Azure a cookie might be the
single key to your entire data virtual
datacenter so if you have like a data
center building you imagine right the
cookie is the key to that building or
personally if you have cryptocurrency
your finances right or Facebook the
cookie might be the authentication coke
token to get an attacker in so what is
past the cookie so if you can tell it's
very much similar if you familiar with
past the hash is the same concept you
have the token you pass it and you pivot
through the environment so an attacker
might be after valuable assets valuable
host injuring infrastructure where there
might be powerful cookies available and
I said I've used this many many times
during adversarial emulation to achieve
mission objective so how can you kind of
gather the cookie in the first place so
pass the cookie is sort of an a post
exploitation technique which means the
hosts that we talk about is already
compromised so imagine
phishing attack there's a beachhead
established in the organization and the
company that and then the app
he restarts pivoting through the
environment right maybe even compromise
the domain controller so that point you
have full capabilities within the
company but they still have not pivoted
what I call the pivot to the cloud so
now we can go find an administrator of
the subscription or the AWS account
compromise that machine and then they
can pass the cookie they steal the
cookie
using some of these techniques here and
then the pass the cookie to pivot to the
cloud infrastructure the one thing I
want to point out is process them which
is sort of the very very simple tool but
cookies are not just stored in process
processes of browsers right or on the
disk from a browser perspective cookies
you can also find any other applications
to do authentication so somebody might
use process them to kind of dump all the
processes in the machine and look for
cookies so yeah and then how do you pass
the cookie in the past like four five
years ago right you had to install some
extensions and so on now it's really
simple you use the developer console you
just go in the console and set the
cookie for days even UI like chrome has
a nice UI to set the cookie yeah I want
to point out cookie crimes which I just
right now I work at a place where we
have a lot of Mac's so I had to look for
techniques on how to do this on a Mac
and there's great research done and
there's something called cookie crimes
that uses headless chrome to allow you
to steal the cookies so here's a simple
example how you might cover my skin up
but you go to the github web page
refresh there's no cookies
you're not authenticated there's a
single cookie called user session you
paste it in refresh the page and you're
logged in and now let's move this to the
cloud just sort of really what I want to
kind of highlight is the organization
might have or Google Cloud compute for
instance another like one of the three
big cloud infrastructure providers write
an adversary might have stole two
compromised the administrator and then
they steal a cookie and pave it into the
cloud so sort of a three-step process
sort of part of my own like work I
started building out this cheat sheet
for myself so I thought I'd share that
which kind of cookies you might be
interested in depending on the client
you work with and always make sure that
you have
for any of this kind of work right
that's so if some I've put it in the
very beginning as well so here you can
see a sample of interesting web pages
and the cookies that you can steal or
that somebody might steal an adversary
might steal to authenticate and
similarly the breach talking about
detections right there's things that we
kind of have to do is like monitor for
process dumps monitor for access and
homilies monitor for unusual activity on
websites and i want to move forward and
talk about mitigations also right
deleting cookies on the machine
regularly is very important delete the
session cookies right if you this is one
thing I want to highlight life if you
are not the only administrator on your
machine it is not your machine anything
on its own it belongs to everybody else
or any other administrator on the
machine also right that is very very
important especially if you work in a
company never use a company laptop to
perform work thank you
[Applause]
thank you next up is more on drugs
[Music]
[Applause]
hello the full title of the talk is war
on drugs and doing 50 years of fake news
and propaganda you need to decide for
yourself what do you want to do what is
your core set of values and me
personally I am pro-choice freedom and
education there are many different
scientific research this is about the
fat the fat and sugar the sugar industry
blamed fat you eat fat you become fat
but this is not true you need to provide
fat to your body because it's a part of
a healthy balanced diet this is the
cigarette advertisement from 50 years
ago of course your doctors smoke camels
the Marlboro guy who was advertising
cigarettes he died from lung cancer and
this is probably one of the most
important quotes that 50 years ago then
the Nixon presidential election and
basically you cannot make it illegal to
be against war so what they did to keep
the war in Vietnam going they
criminalized the drugs the war on drugs
is a direct consequence of war in
Vietnam they couldn't keep up with the
peace movements so they had to find a
way to put them into prison and then we
have a private prison system the moment
you make money from putting people into
prison you just you are incentivized to
keep the system going and this is
basically a vicious circle it is a
complete and I'm encourage you
to just think follow the money if you do
not know what's going on just follow the
money
and all these pervert incentives create
a situation when judges are bribed by
the prison system to put children into
jail however now we have a little change
in the law because of the Internet
Internet allows us to communicate freely
this is the legal map of cannabis in the
u.s. in many states cannabis is illegal
or legal for medicinal purposes it is
changing rapidly
the human perception is also changing in
the United Kingdom and the medical
cannabis was legalized first of November
in Mexico it is also changing in South
Africa it is changing it is pretty much
becoming legal so this is just the
cannabis okay this is about the business
model of pharmaceutical industry they
get money if you are hooked on their
legal drugs and they don't have
incentives to use the drugs that are
actually helping people this is the
ketamine that is testing for depression
MDMA for PTSD epsilon siding for people
who have terminal diseases and they know
they will die but using psychedelic such
as psilocybin allows them to become more
okay with death like okay
I am dying but this is only my body my
soul will survive so it is they are
reducing the data anxiety and this is
like a second level research that we we
already know that psilocybin is
effective so now we are testing which
type of music for this type of treatment
so this playlist is amazing highly
recommended books about the DMT this is
this is a metaphor that we have the
telescope to look into the Stars we have
the microscope to look into a very very
small objects but we are still looking
for the microscope I cross scope for the
brain so here it is
of a scientific research of scanning the
brain various connections in the brain
here is the wiki where self-medication
psychedelic retreats and this is
probably if you want to stay connected
psychedelic community you can meet with
like-minded people you can learn more
and always do your own research thank
you thank you thank you thank you
now the next talk is not going to be a
talk but rather an experiment and one of
the rare occasions where we surrender
our hardware to someone else this is the
last event in this session so if you're
not comfortable with any of this you can
just leave without missing out on
anything yeah I don't know I just I just
go away and let them do their work
[Music]
[Applause]
all right thanks so big round of
applause for these guys and let's the
end of our session today thank you for
being here thanks to all the speakers
who participated and a big round of
applause for everybody who stood on the
stage here for the translation team who
did an awesome job translating the
lighting
[Applause]
[Music]