[Music]
[Applause]
we look for translations in the wiki you
will find them and you will be provided
with life translations by our awesome
translation angels deeds fighter
including the installation a position in
14 yeah galantis exists you meet Rashad
Adams and dad via phone here foreigner
I need exists oh that's efficient for no
benefit
nah Tim opening in spite of I'm here for
Nana banana for me then Aladar
battalions and chunk Midna fauna bring
cranberries guaranteeing us one small
and nice me astral garnished over give
this day
yeah quite big isn't it
well yeah it's kind of big warm welcome
to all of you the ladies and gentlemen
listening in through the streaming from
home and to participants who are
watching and listening from their
desktop PCs at home or any hackerspace
over the world and we're gonna try to
get this over with as quickly and
painless as possible kind of like a
band-aid ripoff at the doctor's all
right so some of you had a brilliant
year we don't want to take that away
from you I mean but all in all oh well
if you kind of look at the modern
broadcasting systems this year kind of
seems like another additional that we
kind of I'm going to put this carefully
that we are in a bit of a difficult time
we had the state Trojan the police is
buying tanks I mean who doesn't want to
drive attack we all had kind of our own
personal pain points with the that we
had a few things happening in the chaos
community that were happening under
difficult circumstances and that we also
had a bit of a taste of what the new
police laws are actually going to be
meaning when they're implemented the
protest right now of course is something
that we are trying to like that's very
loud and that is very colorful and it
happens in chaos meetings and effort and
you did a great job on that and these
protests are seriously taking up
creative shapes and forms and we love
seeing that and I have to say that I
kind of was a bit sad that the
institution that
in the last year was the most public
about their position against the right
usually sells coca-cola so though this
year is over thankfully the family
festival where we have to fix other
people's computers is over no now it's
Congress great this year's theme is
refreshing memories this would be a good
point in time to start in a lovely
lecture of history but because Tim did
that last year we kind of want to give
you an advice how about you just look at
it at media CCC and I'll just say this
much the first Congress happened in 1984
quite fittingly in Hamburg we had about
200-300 people participating now think
about it and and look around look around
this room 200 300 people and today we're
here 35 years later we are still doing
it and above all we are doing it more
colorful more diverse than ever before
the Congress is becoming so much more
diverse and so much more thoughtful with
every year and the community is
developing in the exact same way and the
family and the thought and and all that
still exists and it's it's handmade with
love and all the angels that are here
and they're still volunteers that are
all contributing their time and their
free time and they're not getting paid
and without them this Congress would not
be possible and we're making this event
happen where everyone for for very crazy
days are allowed to basically do almost
everything and anything and we're still
doing this together
[Applause]
for what for you
this will hopefully we brilliant
Congress with very unique experiences
and memories that you're making with all
the blinking lights you can focus for
maybe five minutes that's at least what
it is for me it's the accumulation of
fascinating crazy stupid people who
gather in this one place the space for
four days will create the most crazy
over stimulation that I've ever
experienced and this is what we do every
year together reminds them back and
together we're growing I mean obviously
also we're getting taller no I mean in
size we're obviously not 200 people
anymore but we're also growing in really
interesting directions we have for this
year new themes and topics the
foundation talks which is a lecture
series which gives a space to people who
are absolute professionals in their area
and who will present an understandable
yet very deep way like for example it
starts with the internet and it goes to
the hacker ethic so I think that covers
something for everyone and there's a lot
of experts and then giving them a space
on a stage to read the people who really
know what they're talking about to give
them a platform that was the goal and
and beyond that we also have other
topics that we are growing into as a
chaos' family quite well we had a couple
of mediate weeks ago for about like a
month and a half ago we had a conference
called bits and trees were parts of the
hacker community came together with
environmental activists where we trying
to find the intersection between these
two fields to work together and figure
out how to create a society that's more
sustainable to create more sense for
this world and how
can make this planet okay that get it
maybe a little bit away from from
doomsday and I find it great that
there's people that are getting together
and who are looking into new direction
and who can we talk to and maybe work
with that is not within our bubble we're
growing in stages I mean there's another
another stage all of the sudden just
grew last year four big stages this year
five proof where there's great talks in
amazing amazing contributions that were
put in all these five stages I mean you
can see them in the in the Far plan and
I mean that's just only the official
program I mean this wasn't enough this
year so they kind of bypassed us on the
right side we have a selection of
decentralized stages maybe five at least
don't admit that we've lost largest lost
count and the overview I only call them
small stages so that you can distinguish
them from the main stages I mean like I
was standing in front of the stage in
front of chaos yes and that one isn't
really very small and it's so impressive
that from within the community there's
so much quality that's being brought and
content that's being put out that these
stages were formed that's just brilliant
to see
[Applause]
and I mean beyond that we're also
growing and on a very personal level I
mean obviously all of us are obviously
growing personally but also as a chaos
community in the past year we took on
the question how within the chaos
community we can deal with conflicts and
people that have been part of the
community for four years got together to
guarantee the security of the
participants and they got together and
contributed so much of their time and
strength and discussion and telephone
conference calls yes conference calls
you know they're the best way of
communicating with one another and they
worked out a plan of how we can go
further from this point out and from all
of these discussions and this like
discussions and close circles there was
two things that came about there's a new
team for the Congress that's the sheet
Stella or the arbitration board you can
read up on it on the help dot CC C dot
de u it also introduces all the teams
that for years have done a lot of work
that said there's all sorts of teams who
do a lot of work for conflict revolute
revit resolution just read up on it on
the page if you want to get informed
please inform yourself for your sake and
for others for the people around you
because if somebody next to you in hole
three is all of the sudden collapsing it
would be great to know what you should
be doing next inform yourself it's a
great way there is a lot of posters
around informing you please and while
we're on this subject of giving you
information and rules we can also maybe
tell you off a little bit please
remember our
policy if you don't know it you can find
it in many many posters distributed we
have a particular team that is
plastering these posters everywhere
before time and time manner before you
take a picture ask the people that are
in the picture that are visually
recognizable in the picture if it's okay
for them if it's a gigantic massive
picture where there's lots of people in
it maybe I don't want to talk to all of
these maybe don't take that picture then
we understand that you want to take
pictures it looks great here we are
every time blown away by the aesthetics
of this event but please remember this
policy
[Applause]
yes all right so the the moral the moral
swing was done we can move on I realized
that whoever you talk to afterwards we
asked a hundred people it wasn't a
hundred but depending on who you ask
about this event people tell you
completely completely different things
about Congress that you could come to
the conclusion that I've been at
different events more like five than two
stories one person told me that her
Congress most Congress experience was
that she brought a server and a friend
of hers took it as a option to break
into her Sava and came up to her
afterwards and said to her mmm - we
could talk about this and another person
told me about the sandbox with the
projector and top of it I don't want to
spoil this too much you have to check it
out and she told me that that thing and
the person who created that thing and in
miniature explained to me excitedly how
this thing works at 3:00 a.m. and the
more in the night that was I mean what
else would you find time to do that that
was great and a lot of people shared
amazing brilliant stories it's about
listening to talks about doing talks
together learn from each other in this
process and have fun together and there
was another person that also told me
that it's kind of about driving in the
most crazy way through the holes and
stop at all sorts of stopover and and
look at and then get a drink at another
berth and then you kind of end back in
your own assembly
and a wider girlfriend told me that the
exact time frame in which you can be
sure where another person is at Congress
is exactly 30 seconds so if I were to
leave I would be able to tell that
you've left for about 30 seconds but
then you might be in heaven getting your
angel badge it could be at the barn cows
West or in the hall for at the lock help
desk I wouldn't be able to tell and I
love this rule so much because I have
been so desperately looking for people
so many times and unable to locate them
for days at the times when I needed them
most but the beautiful thing is that I
always found somebody else who could
help me just as well even though I
hadn't been looking for them and they
helped me at least as much and that's
what makes Congress for me now helpful
people are one thing I don't know how
you feel maybe you're all very social
people who love interacting with others
at large groups and that's no stress and
no problem for you but I I know that
some or maybe even many of you don't
feel the same way I remember my first
Congress not that long ago fact in fact
I met loads of nice people I'm sure you
know the feeling when you meet people
are so different from yourself that you
learn new concepts and new ways of
thinking and it takes time to to
understand this and I learnt a lot from
them
because people always teach you things
and they partly do that by simply living
them because they do things in a way
that differs from your own and you start
to think maybe I should try that as well
and I tried a lot in youth a lot of new
things all of them of course completely
legal and very few of them started at
myself because at my first Congress I
was busy looking around feeling
overwhelmed being a bit amazed but also
being intimidated because it's it's a
lot the nice thing is people want to
talk to you that's how I got to know all
those people all those years ago they
want to tell you about the hackerspace
and what they do there what they've been
doing for the past year what they
brought with them selves some never want
to stop talking seriously they want to
talk to you and you hopefully want to
talk to them too because that's why
we're here and the worst thing that
could possibly happen to you is that
somebody has no time nobody has died of
that in either and if somebody drives
past you on a sofa that's blinking and
that has a Cotter bot in the back and
looks robust enough to push aside the
next police tank then maybe stop them
and ask them hey how did you built this
what gave me the idea what other things
but what inspired you because how many
happened what went wrong which
is the best question you can you can
possibly ask somebody the day my sofa
burnt
do it talk to people of course if
somebody sits behind the computer with
headphones then maybe take that very
subtle hint and they might be busy but
in all other cases talk to each other
and create memories that you can take
along with you if you feel the same way
that I do and you struggle to talk to
people when you see something cool then
become an angel it's the best way of
getting to know people go to anguses
team dr. de make an account to say hi at
heaven and look for a shift it's not
difficult it doesn't hurt and two hours
later you might be checking people's
wristbands but you'd be doing so with
the person you haven't met before and to
whom you start talking I met some of my
best friends that way it's an enormous
help and people walk past because then
you get to know them as well because
nobody's in a particular hurry here and
you'll help volunteering you'll get to
see Congress from an entirely new
perspective and you help make Congress
what it is and this might be a good time
to say thanks for all the angels that
are here now and that have made all this
possible it wouldn't have happened
without you
[Applause]
every opening needs the traditional
question who of you is here for the
first time alright that's quite a few
welcome nice to see you good to be here
and I'm a bit jealous of you because the
first Congress is something really
special
my first Congress was amazing because I
was quite new in the community it was my
first Congress it was my first chaos
event and I can't tell you how
unprepared I came I I was struggling not
to get lost at CCH and when I arrived at
the hack Center in Hall 3 I had I fared
the urge to just just stand in the
middle of the doorway and process what I
was seeing and it was everything at the
same time everywhere and there was
something there and there and there and
I I just couldn't stop being amazed I'm
being fascinated and the thoughts ran
through my head I started asking myself
how did you end up here who are all
these crazy people and I did this until
somebody came along and told me to get
out of the way I felt like a small child
in a toy shop but this feeling didn't
stop for the entirety of my first
Congress there was something behind
every corner that caused me to stop and
wonder and the year after that I came
back and thought I was prepared you know
what's going to happen I've never been
this wrong in my life so it's been the
same feeling essentially every year even
though I helped build this event from
the very first day and drive through
these halls for weeks every year is so
exciting and so crazy equally crazy as
the year before
and something new happens that excites
me and overwhelms me like you're small
go in the toy shop especially because of
all the things you bring and that's the
thing we want we want you to do go
through these holes and talk to people
and have them talk to you make new
friendships and create new awesome
things let's create memories that we can
return to next year and let us do that
every year let's let's make our first
Congress as incredible as the first one
and letters make memories that we want
to remember forever have fun
[Applause]
[Music]