[Music]
isn't only about techie meetups
it's about personality it's about humans
and what happens when blockchain and
social connection meet each other and
have a baby
well scuttlebutt the decentralized
social network may result and zina or
self will introduce scuttlebutt to you
thank you very much more may be known in
scuttlebutt as elf that's my profile
picture I'm not just trying to put
anything out there but yes arms l4 Zanna
and I've got a background of seven years
in digital fabrication
Asajj the Fablab scene and I'm a grant
writer for scuttlebutt that's why I'll
be talking about scuttlebutt today so I
might take this off because I was making
noise
so what scuttlebutt can we get a really
really quick how many people here have
heard about scuttlebutt before whew
that's pretty good okay second question
how many people got on scuttled by okay
that's not all of you those of you who
had heard about it but didn't get on and
yes so the rest of you will be telling
you what's good what's about so
scuttlebutt it's a really strange name
right that's like the first reaction
everyone has so scuttlebutt originally
it's a sailing term for for water
container
it's slang for gossip which is also why
scuttlebutt is creative whoops it's
called the gossiping protocol so
scuttlebutt was created for by Dominic
and when he was living on a boat and he
was like huh I'm living here on a boat
but I want to talk to all my friends
what should I do
well I'll build my own protocol of
course that's the first thought everyone
has right so he did and scuttlebutt was
born so it's a peer-to-peer gossiping
protocol so some of you might be curious
what specifically is that it's not a
centralized system
most people here should recognize this
casual one actually oh wait let me check
you yeah okay
it's more like whoops double this so
it's distributed network with
distributed not decentralized if any one
case but that difference or this or
which is by the way a picture of Andre
stalls actual network and this is a
picture of mixes Network simply put it's
kind of like this you got your friends
you got your friends friends this you
can see and you can store on your
computer then you got your friends
friends friends this you can't see but
you can store except if you're using
patch Bay then you can also see it but
and beyond which you don't even know
exists so that's how we communicate
so to point this out this also means
that no one else knows you exist which
makes it very difficult approximately
right now we're around ten thousand
users on scuttle but the thing is
afterwards the thing is we're not sure
that's the exact number because it's
impossible to actually be able to tell
how many people are out there do you
really want it okay so this means there
can be communities using these in a mesh
network village somewhere for example or
it could be yeah
something else and that's like
physically impossible like it's not
possible with the protocol so that's
like the basics of it but there's also
pubs and pubs are basically okay what if
I want to know more people than the
people who are within my friends friends
friends reach you know what if I want to
know someone else videos with the
shrooms
not sure mushrooms such as a shout out
to glyphs out there who does that then
we got pubs and pubs is a very very
green analogy is actual physical pub so
you go there you meet some people that
are outside of your Friendship Circle
you talk you hear their gossip about
their friends that you are not connected
to and you tell them your gossip about
your friends etc and essentially the
scuttlebutt protocol is very much
replicating how real human interaction
actually happens rather than a
centralized system which would be more
like huh I take everyone's data and then
I tell everyone what they need to know
I'm sort of very generalized ok so
there's a few quirks with the
scuttlebutt and similar kind of
protocols sometimes
so there's communal data privacy it's
impossible to see the others data unless
they are in your network proximity
that's what we mentioned previously
right
you've got offline usability so this is
one that surprises most people because
most people think internet oh I need a
connection
well you don't so it's completely usable
in much communities and over for example
a snake or nut and third Cork you've got
free listening this is more of a design
quirk but it's still one that's very
important I think and so rather than a
top-down censoring there's a choice of
blocking so you can choose to not listen
rather than mm removing revoking
someone's right to speak then we got the
fourth cork which yeah it's in the air a
little bit but it's hardware bound so
the SSB accounts are tied to the device
they're on no passwords and more
difficult to swim which yeah it's um it
could be discussed but still it's
Hardware bound so no passwords which
currently means you if you have an
account you can't like log in with the
same account on mobile and then use it
on your computer as well you have to
have like two different ones
yes what if you lose your device though
if it's Hardware bound that sucks this
has happened to me so that's where Dark
Crystal comes in and I hope Dan is okay
with this because we've done this before
but he's gonna explain a little bit
about Dark Crystal
[Laughter]
interacting with the protocol is the
sole custodian of a private key try and
imagine something really precious which
if you lost it you would lose access
capacity and affordances so I'm not
talking about a possible or a bank card
those things you can go to a central
authority and you can replace them if
you lose your password to Facebook you
could go through some process I chose
showing them an identity card or some
other identifying feature which they
would determine binds to you the human
who's the owner of that account in
peer-to-peer systems that there is no
company there's no central authority to
whom you can go and jump through
whatever process to regain access so if
you lose your private key you are
screwed in p2p world this is your
digital identity and if you lose it
you're screwed that's very fragile
password managers are hard about 17% of
all bitcoins which I will ever be minted
have statistically looked like they've
been lost if you literally can't pay
people to keep this stuff secure I think
it indicates that it's right problem to
solve and that's really what we've been
working on with Dark Crystal
if you're a Harry Potter geek think
Horcrux if you're not Harry Potter geek
it's a mechanism which leverages human
relationships and trust and you weave a
spell saying of my five friends let's
say my mum my dad two brothers and my
best friend as long as three of these
people out of the five confirm and grant
me access then you can regain the
original secret in this case it might be
a private key without themselves holding
the shards the piece revealing anything
to them so it's pretty exciting it hope
that helps
Thank You damn who's right here actually
no oh oh sorry about that
let's say you're what okay
another Kiwi that was I have yet to
actually meet Dan and person and there's
a lot of people out here that is like
the first time we meet because we work
online only so it's it's pretty exciting
to be here like running around Skyrim
scouting who could be that person on
scuttlebutt yes so yes this is Dan he's
a founder of black AIDS and acclaimed
crypto girl so how do I use scuttlebutt
the actual usage of scuttlebutt could
look like this this is patchwork
patchwork is the recommended one to use
in once you start using scuttlebutt and
but there's many other because remember
scuttlebutt is only the protocol and
then you can place many different
interfaces and applications over it so
you got many verse which is the mobile
client which Andre stalls released like
two months ago and we got patch Bay
which Dark Crystal currently is being
run via and it's more experimental
easier to change than patch patch work
tic-tac which is like a blog stylish and
and then you got more specialized
applications because obviously you don't
only have to use like a social media
interface you could also for example say
chess that's you or you can make book
reviews applications or skill sharing
applications and it goes on and on and
on pretty much anything that has to do
with connections between people
so this is when we get to the second
part how the scuttlebutt sit into the
future
oh what a yummy question before oh did I
not add that oh I had this gif is that
coming soon wait
yes okay let's just jump to the gift
because it's fun let's do the waves
before because we're gonna get like
shift a little bit now you've heard
about scuttlebutt you know what it is
now we're gonna kind of talk about like
more futurists so could we try out quick
wave starting from over there spreading
downwards going up here spreading
backwards is that possible
are you guys capable of this yes yes are
you down person over there stand up if
you're already okay we got it it's ready
okay it's song we're going yeah
[Music]
good job people okay so instead we'll go
back of it because we're switching we're
talking about the future and we're
talking about solar Punk
so Solar Punk is a common futuristic
approach it started as a sci-fi genre
which many people in this kind of
community also very much enjoys it's a
way of looking at how we can shape the
future and it's also an aesthetic um or
gifts sometimes so there are very very
many different views of how the future
could be
so we're I'm talking right now so
obviously I'll be presenting my view and
what maybe some of my friends and I talk
a lot about but there are as many
different future views as there are
people so none of this is fact swish
but mmm yeah take it with a grain of
salt so obviously I put this in the
wrong ways thing we're will be coming
from the perspective of digitally
fabricated society so Solar Punk also
kind of merges very much technology with
ecology and how to live sustainable in a
world without ravishing it but still
utilizing the developments we do have in
the knowledge we do have in a good way
so there are a few ingredients that I
kind of like cherry picked for this so
it's sad City machines building machines
open source ecology and electronics home
production
or home electronics production whatever
you want to put it so we start with fab
city fab city is an initiative
it's an offspring from the Fab Lab
movement it's globally connected city
for local manufacturing and this is kind
of a map ish with a few of the countries
but as you can see I'm not gonna read
all of these cities out but you can see
that there's many and they're all kind
of connected in this big network of
cities who have proclaimed themselves
for local manufacturing so you got Paris
in there you got Barcelona in there you
got Sousou you got Oakland and Detroit
etc etc that's one ingredient these are
just flavors then we got machines
building machines machines building
machines is kind of the component that
can accelerate this movement cuz sure
you want local manufacturing but are you
gonna buy all the machines yourself like
is everyone gonna spend a bunch of money
to buy them no that's unsustainable but
if you get the machines to build the
machines who can then continue building
machines get this rapid movement going
on right so machines building machines
is a movement that was also started
philippic started you know slow together
with MIT so philosophic started is a Fab
Lab sprung out of bit rough the hacker
space in a strong beautiful place and
they've built the first large-scale
open-source CNC machine that's
completely parametric and parametric
means Excalibur and you can build a
small-scale CNC machine with the same
design so a C&C a good one is all you
need to build all the other machines so
we got the first key which is pretty
damn cool
so what else kind of machines we want to
build well we want to be able to
saying ourselves right so we got open
source ecology right open source ecology
is amongst one a project where they're
building 50 I think agricultural
machines and in order to locally produce
the food you want and also because the
way the industry around farming works is
a little bit corrupt and we also have
projects such as Romi
Romi project is robotic micro scale
farming and they've just received a
bunch of funding from European Union yes
to develop small-scale farming in
Barcelona here's a brief map on
different farms across Europe which have
started or in the process of actually
becoming digitally fabricated bull
farming spaces yes another one which we
mentioned previously this morning was
libre silicon which is really really
cool
it's first time we've kind of completed
the kit now we can build computers from
scratch and you can do it in your
basement um but this one specifically
was for semiconductors which was like
the missing link and this is another
it's an isp programming board which is
standardized by MIT which they use in
fab Academy which is hosted all across
the world and yeah it's just yet another
example of how easy it is to make
circuit boards alright so all that is
cool right but what does it really mean
it means shoes no but so to wrap this up
we're gonna use an analogy so the
analogy starts with shoes so let's say
you want your shoes because that's
something we all use it's something we
all need right let's say you want shoes
but you don't want to buy them so you
decide to learn how to make your shoes
fabulous right but let's say the
neighbors around you they're like huh
I want shoes too and previously what we
had to do was obviously well if one city
learns has like a shoemaker well then
another city has to have one person who
spends all their time learning how to
make shoes that's a lot of time
consumption so you have this one city
they learned how to build shoes you have
another city they learn how to build
shoes you have another city they learn
how to build shoes that's a lot of
learning of how to build shoes that's
happening right so what if you just have
one person learn how to build shoes and
then they share that information
open-source llena so many people can
build shoes Wow it's incredible and then
what if you have like villages spread
out across the world building shoes and
making open-source designs from maybe
even like toilets or like houses or like
showers or kitchen equipment and they're
connected in a network then they can
share together and continuously develop
the resources and the knowledge on how
to actually live which is a knowledge
that's somehow managed to be forgotten
in modern society so yes a quick side
not to this I recently heard from
Europe's future research director I
don't know if there's the thing that
somehow that was kind of a title the
ideas I think are currently getting into
the market of building micro factories
instead of stores so you can go in there
with your old shoe
they'll reuse materials break it down
and then you can buy the new design you
don't actually have to buy the material
for the design so that's kind of their
new thinking concept of how to develop
these stores so shout out to hackers out
there
but yeah yes so for this we need digital
files right and how do we spread digital
files well our means our roads are kind
of being compromised in current society
which is sad and so this is kind of how
I ended up on scuttlebutt I was talking
to Alex he's sitting right there cold
lane on scuttlebutt and here's a I was
like oh you know it's billed as new
society and like if we're actually gonna
do it and have a change make a change in
the world we really need to have like
means of communications that can't be
compromised but and here's like huh
haven't you heard of gotta buy or that's
that's project shout-out or ipfs
shoutout as well and I was like no I
haven't what is this and then I got on
and yeah story continues but either way
to get back what we were talking about
digital files and we need to be able to
spread them um and in order to move
freely
we need new protocols which is what dr.
ipfs and scuttlebutt can do and new
protocols could be in Freedom of
Information and scuttlebutt could mean
Freedom of Information so that's why I'm
on scuttlebutt yes
welcome to the scuttle verse that's it
for me thank you
[Applause]
thank you
do we have questions in the room please
go to the microphone number one or
number two because the people on the
stream also have wants to you so who's
first one to what I think number two was
the first so your question please
so how does couple BOTS actually work
what's the transport layer
what's the transport layer do you use
Wi-Fi use bluetooth to something custom
previously I think you can use
sneakernet
you can use we're actually developing or
some people are I don't know who exactly
but I've heard rumoured using Bluetooth
and you can use mesh networks you can
use regular Wi-Fi choose your means you
can use a radio if you really want to
yeah so what is implemented right now
currently there's been people
researching Bluetooth as I mentioned I
thought I heard a rumor was radio
something that's been in the air no yes
yes then we've had I know
mesh networks actually like protocols
built for mesh networks have also been
researched upon personally that's the
one I'm looking into the most yeah
obviously regular Wi-Fi as well yeah
thank you
microphone number one please you stated
that information spurt via scuttlebutt
won't travel more than three degrees of
separation but what about pops of
someone in your network John's a pop
won't he flood all his network to prove
a pop yeah and because pop usage is
common you should get a fully connected
graph
yes and now so what's pretty common now
in the early stages that's kind of
what's happening we think obviously we
don't know but that's what we think so
mmm since the community's small enough
fish that a lot of people have joined
similar pubs there's a pretty cohesive
use case of the pups but you're also
very capable of just joining your
friends pub for example or setting up
your own pub or not using pubs which is
not super recommended but it's possible
yeah I think that answers the question
ish do you want to add on through it no
thank you for that and microphone number
two please hello I have questions so you
know how people use me do you hear me
now yeah okay so you know how people use
social media it what talk to your
friends they might like okay
talk to your friends so why key weight
for example white person Wow so I forgot
my question okay so if a person like
wants to talk to their friend of a book
they don't that their friend has a
Facebook account so that you just use
Facebook so like and you said like skull
that has become our community so how do
you ties people to join if there's not
many people use it yet so how does this
cover address this problem
hopefully I'm just my question oh
actually I think Andres thoughts would
be better at answering this question
because he's more into the whole
bringing scuttlebutt to the masses
personally I think we're still in a
phase where there's enough things we
need to set mmm more stable and before
it reaches the massive public let's
personally but
I think as any other network I mean it's
the biggest question for any social
media ever out there how do we get users
you know it's it's what they always ask
and you could say we could use the route
of echo villages and echo villages using
scuttlebutt or we could use the route of
showcasing how much better it is with
data privacy or we could use the route
of waiting for society to become
infringing enough on people's privacy
that they have to use scuttlebutt or etc
you know but yeah I it's not a goal of
mine so I'm not the best person to
answer that
and results would be much better to
answer that yeah do we have a question
from the interwebs no so far is it yes
no okay
so microphone number one please hello my
name is matyoo
I'm already member for scuttlers for two
years and it's more like question for
audience since we don't meet in real
life can we have some family photo
people who are on scuttle but if you
come up here we can take a picture
together it'll be one of the biggest
crabs made nice connecting in real life
I love that microphone number two please
so before even centralized social
networks or it won't exists and people
were kind of worried about what happens
if someone creates lots of fake accounts
and there's a simple attack now because
scarlet box is distributed and how does
that work the scuttle blasters do use it
do you just have to manually block those
accounts or is there some centralized
system that blocks fake accounts so
there's no centralized system to start
there
if someone creates a fake account I mean
define a fake account if I use an
account and don't use my real name is
that a fake account well I mean just
like if you you
yeah three degrees of separation and we
just add lots of bots to your edge
Network through that degree of
separation and then applied your feed
with nonsense okay well there's two
responses there number one there's the
whole hardware thing but usually when
you create an account it's kind of tied
to the hardware it's hard to run
multiple instances of scuttlebutt from
the same computer but mmm that could
also be round about it eventually if
research comes on enough the second
answer would be the whole you can block
people so yeah it's a little free
listening non censoring thing okay the
last thing and you said that I think you
mentioned that the grass on the first
layers it was it was distributed but not
DIYs Oh could you repeat three easier on
there well if the first layers you said
it was distributed but might be
centralized could you kind of expand on
that a little bit horn or had a great
fight about this I did a talk with him
recently and it's there's like if you
actually search difference between
distributed and decentralized there's
this beautiful picture you can get where
it shows like the mapping of a
centralized system it's like the whole
node in the middle that's giant and
those like small peaks and then you have
a mapping of a decentralized system
where you have the big nodes and you
have like everyone kind of criss
crossing but also very much on focusing
on the nodes and then you have the whole
distributed system and the distributed
system it's more direct between peers to
peers to Pierce appears to peer-to-peer
spirits but some people may argue
what about pups that makes it
decentralized right obviously yes and no
because you don't have to use pups so
yeah
so in this case I think we're done
thank you very much people on a 1 + 4 z
[Applause]
[Music]