[Music]
okay so he's an integrated citizen and
knows his way around IT security and
data processing okay and here's the talk
thank you I'm glad so many people are
here at this late hour so this talk is
about your health data records it's more
safe than online banking well let's have
a look if this is actually the case so
maybe maybe some of you have heard about
this so a couple of months ago this
showed up as the electronic health
record you can exchange x-ray pictures
you can track which vaccinations you've
taken so all these health-related
information you can exchange with Vivi
and you can send documents to your
doctor and the doctor can provide health
data diagnoses and so on to you so these
are three screen shots of this iOS and
Android app it was published on the 17th
of September a large media echo that was
because so many private and public
health insurance companies was adopted
by this system so 13 million insurers
more by now basically paid this app in
the end so typically this costs about 5
euros per month but the insurance
companies basically paid this for their
customers
one day after the release there was
another large media echo regarding
privacy issues with this app so somebody
looked at this app and it turns out that
telemetry data is sent to different
servers in the US and Singapore and well
this isn't really kind of what we want
to hear from nap that is health record
data so that was when I got interested
and download this app to have a look at
it so this is the result
a month later this was the result even
more news coverage about all the
security issues patient data in danger
serious security issues and together
with Torsen Schroeder I published my
work so we're gonna have a look at the
things that went wrong in this V V app
so VB is for exchanging mainly for
exchanging documents between a patient
and the doctor so the patient has a
smartphone has some x-ray pics the
various documents and wants to send them
to his doctor this goes over this VV
cloud platform like this so I send my
documents to the cloud VV generates a
session this is a 5-digit
session ID made from lowercase
characters okay a few already got it
here in the audience and I'll continue
for the rest of you okay and now the
doctor gets this link maybe by email fax
telephone personally and the doctor can
then look at this document in this
session so because a lot of people left
here okay so five digit session ID
that's not really kind of the level of
security people want to see here so five
digit IDs from lowercase letters you can
basically brute-force them in one day I
mean not by hand obviously you write a
small
tripped and then you run this and just
to check if there's a document and yes
indeed so when you actually find a
session ID that exists and then you get
this here as an answer this is a set of
metadata so the name of the insurance in
short person address of the doctor age
gender language and so on just metadata
but of course I mean this is still data
you don't want to have public right I
mean especially with if you go to doctor
because of a sensitive topic say an
abortion or or just anything related to
reproduction or maybe if you go to a
psychiatrist so basically everyone can
look at this metadata on this VB
platform if I want to actually see the
document that was transported in this
session I actually need to enter a
four-digit pin okay so I see I don't
really have to explain this how many
tries do you need one thousand right
okay so okay thousand tries and then I
got this document and then I got this I
will have to be faster than the doctor
and then I have this document okay there
were more problems so fishing for
example you don't really expect this in
a health app so it allows to exchange
documents between insured person and a
doctor so we see here an invoice two
invoices and a prescription from a
doctor and if I open the lower invoice
then what happens here oh I need to log
in again this actually happens a lot in
VV so that's a security feature session
expires fast but in this case here when
I enter a password it actually doesn't
go to VV it goes to me so it turns out I
injected HTML code in this webview and
basically could build anything I wanted
in here so yeah phishing is
not what you expect from this health app
thank you very much but if I got the
password I'm still not in the app
because it's a two-factor identification
yeah you froze with with you know that
fishing in a two-factor identification
doesn't work that easy I don't have it
yet if I don't have it yet I get a
following requests HTTP use a password
and a code that's a totp code and need
that code if I don't have it what do I
do
let's try brute-forcing big topic it's
as simple as that but all metadata of
this platform are open I could
circumvent to factory identification but
this is not the end it'll go further
Vijay has an end-to-end encryption if I
as a user sent my documents not directly
via the air the doctor opens this in his
browser and this browser generates a key
in JavaScript and it's stored in the
browser the browser sends this key to
the patient on the apt of the patient's
the app uses this key to encrypt the
document and then send it sends it to
the doctor okay problem is this is in
local storage in the browser if anybody
in here knows what this is about and
browser apps are crossing scriptable
attackable and Vivi was attracted by
three different
all I had to do is shake it said excuse
me send the link to the doctor and if he
clicks on that link I get is very shaky
I got 15 data with a high critical
content I published that together with
Thurston Schrader
he just presented himself thank you very
much for that because coordinated
disclosure thank you very much for that
so this is how it should have be done we
on the 17th that was published on the
21st we found the first security hitch
there was a telephone conference next
day on the 22nd we had a meeting for
this later with Vivian the Alliance and
the 3rd of October we had the final talk
and the reaction of Vivi to our
publication was a real risk for the data
is not perceivable at no point I think
you guys are gonna see it differently
net politic dot auric published this and
said the makers to publish false data or
fake news and everybody said no it
wasn't me I can't do that you gotta you
can't do that yes it's not true
at least there was some people at least
at net politic org that published what
happened in the background Vivi was
trying to correct reporting from this
and correctly contents ths was called by
a crisis PR manager and tried did we
practically test brute force and then he
was trying to threaten us with radical
consequences from our point of view
we've really tried proper disclosure
follow proper disclosure rules and I'm
so I'm gonna go on like this
maybe Vivi has realized that it doesn't
work that way and this is the way it
should be done and not is the way they
see it what lessons did how many people
believe that within 24 hours all the
faults were corrected I looked for you
I looked for weeks ago there was a visit
funny no not funny it's an attack no you
shouldn't say call it funny send a
document as an insurance clients to the
doctor I can send him a malignant
document and see what happens and get
that document to JavaScript countries it
has an applet and it'll run the applet
and it'll send other documents to me
that is critical from my point of view
within 24 hours let's see on the one
hand the attacker and he says the
attacker says is a vivid user the
browser on the right side is the doctor
and he's waiting for the link I have to
show this as a video I have to change
the app here luckily there sorry where's
my video app there it is here we go if
you have the doctor in this decision
Eddy
now it's not for it's five digits now
they've yeah they've corrected he enters
his pin yeah I'm a melon user I give him
the pin he loads now he opens the
document in the browser what happens the
document contains a Java Script applet
and it's just took Peters diagnosis and
sent him to me all two Yogi's in that
accident
belong to us it all happens in the
browser of the doctor I'm still the
attacker no not corrected
okay so something else that works so one
thing they fixed you can't really just
grab the key it's now read protected but
it's not right protected of course I can
just overwrite your private key with
that one of the attacker because in the
future if I ever get some documents I
can decrypt this with my key that's a
problem with end-to-end encryption
without Identity Management for a doctor
without being able to identify the
doctor this way I really have to accept
every key I get I can't verify the
authenticity so what there's thousands
of broken up wise VB interesting so
let's have a quick look at this
eHealth law it was passed in 2015 so
this introduces the kind of video
doctor's appointment in 2017 in
baden-württemberg this actually exists
you can visit your are a doctor by video
call and actually also get kind of
remote treatment in 2018 we had the
bonus I Natalie her medications plan and
in 2019 the first electronic patient
record should be available and by 2021
it should be available everywhere so the
electronic health record exists since
2004 insurance companies may actually
use this it runs on the existing
infrastructure and doctors may use it
but must not and the electronic patient
record needs separate IT infrastructure
as a minimum requirement and it's also
mandatory to support for doctors this is
starting in 2019 so there was an update
this year for this eHealth law because
IT infrastructure and health card it's
not really running smoothly so we need
to do some
thing so our Minister of Health said
tablets and smartphones that's the way
we want to access our health records and
this Gesundheit Scott is old-fashioned
so he also said online banking is kind
of our or a good example in terms of
security and all these changes they we
can't really afford to push this out any
longer in three months this all needs to
be ready to standard so this is the
background and Vivi is kind of the the
test case of the insurance companies for
this electronic patient record because
both the public and private insurance
companies are interested in a lot of
users using this because surely there
will be also savings related to
introduction of this infrastructure so
what I mean so we looked at Vivi
now how about some other competitors
so there's CGM live Vita book that's
kind of the dinosaur and then there's
the TK safe that's still in beta and
also regarding kind of the video
doctor's appointment there's a doc
direct and made by doctors themselves
there's mine arts direct so who can do
it better than Vivi
that's a question I ask myself okay so
kind of one a quantitative ilish
analysis here so Vita book exists in
2011 I already have experience here they
were the first customer of Microsoft
cloud Germany so they have privacy and
data protection on the highest level so
this is what it looks like
this is Susannah kind of a test account
you can look at it here same with Vivi I
can save documents here share it share
documents with the doctor enter my date
data information on vaccinations I can
manage my whole health with this
it's called health account so kind of
like a checking account but if for your
health okay well since 2018 you don't
expect this but okay
SQL injection you can access unencrypted
documents you don't have yeah
unencrypted you have unsalted sha-1
password high surges yeah so serious
data leaks so if you test this and log
in there are test documents where do you
take test documents from well you
photograph them from your desk so for
example the emails that are lying on the
desk of Vita box employees here about
security in the app okay yeah so this is
kind of some findings from IT SEC
analysis and well yeah so Susana has a
this document for you
so Vita book flatlining in terms of
security yeah okay so never mind
Vita book one thing interesting here
they were the first one who retweeted
the VB yeah so here lo que vivir yeah
you shouldn't do that yeah I mean we we
weren't really about schadenfreude here
that was kind of another intention okay
yeah so typical tech startup I think
that's a foreign system manager not sure
I mean that's just speculation well
typical them never mind okay so let's
see let the doctors do it they know how
sensitive this data is I mean they also
they are personally at risk if they
disclose patient information so let's
see what happens when doctors
co-sponsors such development
okay so there's mine how's arts direct
that's a general practitioner that
started this project so if we don't
develop the digitization of our world as
Doctor
we lost okay so let's see what this
doctor is doing so this is mine arts
director hey this is what it looks like
so I try to access an invoice here rates
forbidden since obviously I can't just
access other people's invoices I mean I
just wanted to see if I can view this
view ID i won as you can see in the URL
okay so okay what if I don't want to see
this in the browser if I want to print
this oh there we are
what's that
ok never mind let the professionals try
it we are building it ourselves
ok tele clinic okay so it's the Board of
Directors is one doctor one IT
specialist lots of money behind it state
baden-württemberg that's here the video
doctor's appointment here ok so you can
try this on doc direct ok that well not
with real data I hope okay yeah so login
I want to talk to a doctor get a
diagnosis here ok here I mean those
insurance companies here also support
this so we have maximal data protection
and prevent abuse on every level we have
a four stage security system which
offers the highest data security in
Germany applause please for tell aclinic
ok so if I want to change my password at
tella clinic it looks like this you have
in red here my user ID and in yellow my
password my new password and I sent this
HTTP request ok so I asked myself what
happens if I change my user ID here
though yeah your password has been
changed
this isn't funny this is the highest
data security standard in Germany small
people
let let the big guys do it the really
big guys you know the people that have
the money the big company yeah let's we
can laugh about the small companies but
let's look what the big guys are doing
kike safe good example take care of
end-to-end encryption I didn't look at
it here's a key the key is generated
within the app for the user if that is
if that key if that key disappears you
lose it exit should be barred completely
if you lose your handy if you lose your
handy all your data is gone so you don't
want that so you export that key we're
not that good with key do we know
exactly how to handle passwords in keys
this key we gotta export and save
somewhere how do you do that is it's as
a QR code in your gallery oh yeah in the
gallery here's the path that's an
android screen there's the QR code yeah
that's in the public gallery and your
handy Oh Google pictures will have it
and all the other apps can if you if you
if you replace the key with a passport
and it says please store your password
in unsalted clear text in your gallery
and if this shows how difficult is to
implement this it's tikka safe it's only
beta they're not live on it yet you can
go and try it you know smoke errors
happen let's go to those that people
that are LeBron have been around for a
long time Compu group 5,000 people six
million turnover in 55 countries they
got a platform these people gotta know
how to handle it it's a secure medical
cloud all many many different apps many
different apps run here and use the CGM
cloud and exchange data by this these
some of these apps use two-factor
authentication if you're with AXA
witticism insurance I'm privately
insured that exa don't don't you should
know don't show it is you need an
Authenticator code yeah you can't prove
force is that it's a platform I maybe I
use exa but I could use somebody else I
go see Geum I use CDM cesium life for
access and I don't need to factor
identification that's a bit stupid
I mean what's what's the use of having
two doors in a house one is saved and
the other one is this open or you can
you need open it with a single team
that's the same happens as with Vivi
probably Vivi copied from them and not
because they're the only ones I can six
digit PIN I got a six digit PIN I give
this pin to my doctor and the doctor
uses then he's the six digit pin to
access to my file six digit PIN is brute
force pretty easily
okay here we go again and I got all the
access to the security to the health
data and
take it all off okay but there's another
Pyro's the big problem of this platform
is it makes everything properly and
rutan but it got an elliptic curve
encryption implemented a is on the
client side
there's no passwords exchanged via the
crowd you just I just hid my pass my
email address I'm getting my family key
back and whoops why do I get a secret
code but if I just send my email it's a
key derivation secret I got a tee the
race infection I keep my password I give
my secret that I get here oh I get
client-side offline my private key Wow
access to all that if I got the proper
fright if I took the proper password I
get my private key or the other guy's
private key and I log in the same even
if it's not right I'll have to try again
if I'm not mr. Maier I just try as long
until it works I got his public key and
I have a secret I I don't have to I can
do it offline like
download this choose me and they painted
the whole thing including that era don't
don't copy it it's not worth it I looked
at if it's relevant
oh they took Dropbox
oh I'm not backing yeah same thing and I
took all the email addresses of the
Germans I found there and I found who
was recorded with CGM I took a
dictionary and let's see how many
passwords I can take out of there and
they're not very creative I would have
expected more from the Germans that are
so I've nosed with their three percent
of all Dropbox users where CGM uses and
I had them on my little notebook three
years ago I could handle that I mean
this is only an example we sort of
looked at no not yet that they're not
quite as they say that oh there's
there's there's um the prescription
account that CGM bates as well there's
dr. ik tena click the tikka save all
those they all they all not not quite
make it and it's and we still not
talking about online banking sorry okay
so what I mean there's no perfect
security you will never each that so I
mean you have to you know this is a
numbers game you have to look at the
probabilities so let's look at the
numbers I mean companies like CGM they
have to publish risk sellers IT
processing risks that's in their
financial reports so the customers of us
use our products to manage very
sensitive information about their own
health so if there are security problems
this could lead to damages we need to
pay and so on and so on
so it's a risk for CGM because there's
financial financial damages
so let's see towards the customer a
paramount priority security is
everything that's what they tell the
customer and here is say we expect four
million euro of damages per year on
average and well the highest we could go
in a year 18 million and with five
percent probability there's a higher
unexpected risk so I mean it could be
that their whole ID goes down a trained
IT goes down rain but it's also possible
that all the stuff goes public so I mean
let's just take this 95 percent and see
what happens in one year 95% probability
you're safe
second year 90% third year 86% the
problem with health data is they're
around for a long time and I mean I can
really change my health data you know if
I had a hereditary disease back then
then I still have it today right so
except of course the future brings a
definitive solution to my ailment but so
after 50 years I have an 8% chance yeah
so I mean that's not really what we want
so but maybe these 5% are just
unrealistically high or or maybe that's
not also just patient records public or
maybe they made a mistake let's have a
look at the US so in the US on average
per year 30 million patient records were
stolen and those are just the ones that
had mandatory disclosure so yeah that's
10% of the US population I mean I just
estimated 5% before so I mean that's a
reasonably close then we have Norwegian
in 2018 so it's not just the Americans
here we have 3 million affected
documents this year
yeah so um you're now very well-known
towards an unknown attacker in terms of
your health a current then in in 2016
there was another case here to see these
with with almost all medical records of
the Danish population accidentally went
to the Chinese visa ministry in
Copenhagen well I don't know if they
actually sent those CDs back but maybe
we should double-check that okay but
we're in Germany here so we can just
test this we can certify this we can
create new standards so do these
certifications help these here are all
from the apps I've just shown you so we
have various certification agencies here
to trusted privacy then there's the
ministry for data security of foreign on
faults and so on and so on
so apparently certificates can't solve
the problem okay so they might be good
for something but not that there are no
bugs let's go back to V V they had a
they got certificates got a an exam and
a chip certificates to different pen
tests from two different companies those
unpublished I could say well they got to
again complaint pen tests and after that
as we had the that was the result was
what I showed at the beginning all this
certification blah blah for nothing and
now what do we do now basic problems all
electronic health apps
that take and keep security is is is
it's bad for concurrence you have to
certificated because most of them used
to tend to think there's no proper
architecture if you have to go and if
you if you report security you found
there is no proper security responsible
on the side of evey all the apps that I
showed to you now there has there are no
disclosure procedures if I hadn't
if I hadn't recorded in myself nobody of
you would have know then if if I'm an
attacker I won't make it public and now
in 2019 the patient data specification
it's online since a couple of days it
should be completely safe specs in three
months they will add specs for mobile
and tablets look into those they should
really be safe who knows it's not
relevant
basically if why should I offer a
patient if I can you if I can offer a
health paper and I don't follow all
these Vivi's is a as a health act and
not a patient act that nobody will
realize a difference but if they follow
two different laws and have two
different security specs
this is not this is not bank data I
can't have a risk analysis and say okay
I'll lose 18 million pay those and
forget that it's okay you can't do that
Health's health data are permanent you
lose them or to make public then Europe
there is there is no secure long-term
storage place for that if you're
infected with certain diseases you can
there's nothing as I showed this is not
a financial but it's a generation it's a
social problem we don't have no
information if there's anything happens
at now but if I if I save my health data
in the app I can inherit that to my
children professor buco from Darmstadt
two weeks ago that's a cryptologist in
germany just published we just published
the fact there is no safe data storage
available that will keep safety for 20
years all encrypted data that you
collect now that is a that's a long term
broad problem if I collect all your
health data they they they have the same
value 20 years later on if I collect
banks later today in 20 years nobody
cares about them though that's not me
that's professor Johannes Bookman of
Darmstadt and if he says that he should
know what he's talking about about the
future the newspaper world debate fear
of data misuse patient must know that
data misuse is not only punishable by
law but really difficult to do whoever
if whoever does not want to join Russia
who everyone does not want to join
should not have disadvantages but will
not be treated quicker or faster and the
resume is if you long-term lack of
confidence will result in a lower
quality of medical treatment now there's
a lot of positive things to be said
about electronic data I can I can follow
the I can store it all together I have
it all under one I can I can avoid a lot
of problems there is a lot of advantages
for such a digital Act and if you decide
that you do not want for your kids
such an act do you have do you have the
responsibility that your kids will wait
longer or have a less qualitative
approach to their health if 90% or 95%
of the population uses this health app
and you don't and it's it busy your
disadvantage and that is the reality
this is the end of the talk are you you
have more questions I just wanted to
show what it is what's coming and I want
to start the debate now because now we
can send influence and we can still
enforce some kind of update
to the law or whatever now we can still
write to our representatives we can
still fight back and we can still think
about what happens to society where all
health information is opening is that's
what we're whatever this is what we do
here in general at the Congress go ahead
questions suggestions I'll be pleased
[Applause]
since long has some internet also meet
there from an funky smell so so about
using VB and how does it work there with
identification systems or can you use a
throw away email address or something so
if VB you need to record a video of
yourself with your actually photo ID and
you know I have a twin so I wanted to
test this with him so and basically the
doctor then checks the data on the photo
ID and and records this in the VB system
there's also different methods for
different insurers so I have a question
here so this awesome software how much
did this cost VB so bit mark developed
this was I don't actually know but this
would be a project for frocked inch dot
ok microphone 8 hello so I just wanted
to give comments of a phrase it as a
question few talks ago we had images you
know my biometric identification I
missed - product and devein beautiful so
minister in the Darklighter way to
publish those images of a famous mister
I mean we really need to patient record
of a minister so this is my question can
we do that
yeah probably not
this won't be well respected in society
at large I think so but I mean other
people have another opinion on this but
yeah microphone for
Tommy and in May 2014
so we had news articles in the last few
days that miss Doty bear that the the
problem of digitization in the
healthcare system
there wasn't Oh a CD report where we
came second last and the problem is data
protection and kind of we knew it we
need to remove barriers there I mean we
can't say we compared Germany to the
rest of you because we all have the same
legal framework in terms of privacy so I
don't really understand argument ever
everybody has kind of plays in the same
ball court here and as I said nor
Norwegians they had this problem so yeah
I'm not sure about reducing the privacy
here I think the opposite should be the
case next question from the internet so
you just talked about public insurance
companies
how about private companies now actually
there were a few private ones
Taylor Clinic for example I mean yeah
that they have the kind of on-site
doctors of companies ravit Ella clinics
egm dieter Punk'd they are both private
and public health insurance companies
and they work with private insurance
companies together so do a little bit
more research there okay microphone 3
so it's the possibility to do something
with the reader and the health card I
mean everybody of us has this chip which
could manage keys and I mean couldn't we
build something on the basis of this as
a cure authentication system now that's
a good question
I mean yeah we have a trust anchor this
card that actually already has a private
key on it yeah
so the problem is of course you don't
have an USB card reader that you can
attach to your smart phone and the idea
is that you can do it with your smart
phone
just like online banking otherwise
nobody's gonna use it then there's no
benefit to the health insurance
companies okay so another thing in the
current version of the standard for a
few days I think it was a week ago so
the electronic patient dossier is
specified like this that the access is
only possible through the electronic
health record but of course nobody's
ever gonna use this except a couple of
weirdos that yeah attach their cards to
the PC and run an Android simulators
nobody's gonna use this so basically
they already said that up to March 2019
there will be an update and that's a
patient health record one point version
1.1 and it's going to be specified how
you can access it without this health
card and yeah so but the problem is the
only safe way to do it is with this
health card they're gonna be providers
like vbe we're gonna say well we can do
it without the card so you know just
come to us and then the majority of in
in short patients will use the easy way
so yeah it's it's really a competitive
disadvantage the the safe specific aid
specifications vary
will not be used microphone six okay so
a comment it's going to be interesting
when quantum computers I exist that have
enough physical qubits to actually
simulate real qubits in in a realistic
way so that we can actually brute use
brute force attacks on different
encryption standards yeah so it's going
to be really interesting to have keep
data like this secret I mean especially
if you've seen reactions like how slow
these issues are taken care of so as
soon as it's public that that the
quantum computer exists that can crack
this equation we need to switch to a
different encryption scheme that's safe
from quantum computers yeah I mean sure
you need to fall back on to quantum safe
crypto obviously I mean we had an
introductory talk I mean who was there
actually maybe that guy can answer a
question
the problem is in we can't really say if
now Gordon we have today still is safe
in 20 years even if it's a quantum safe
crypto algorithm so we really need an
idea how to save patient records for
twenty years into the future and I think
we should think about distributed
storage system is splitting up documents
I don't know how exactly this could work
but I've read a paper about this mmm
yeah I mean so there are approaches
without changing the cryptography that
might still make document secure for 20
years and beyond the problem is the
specification requires a central data
storage microphone five
[Music]
so you mentioned general data regulation
policy and the financial risk so how
many affected people need to actually
take legal action or maybe join a class
action or something for privacy issues
so that the companies really get hurt
financially so that changed something so
this is actually not my area of
expertise but yeah I can't really say
anything maybe someone from the audience
knows this the problem is how do you put
a price tag on the damages I mean the
there's no personal kind of risk for
that that your data gets public and then
there's something 10 years down the road
that that happens to you that's bad I
mean how can you prove this in court
how can you put a number a dollar number
on this yeah I mean so yeah when when
your health record is is now public for
maybe the next 70 years of your life or
so depending on how so with the issues
you discovered in these apps you there
probably won't be we don't have to wait
for 20 years until the data gets public
and this statement there is no no medium
to save documents safely for 20 years
into the future that's based on a
centralized data system and all these
management system we have now for for
data you can make a very similar point
and I mean I'm surprised we think in
terms of 20 years yeah so these 20 years
I got from a newspaper article so maybe
you should actually check the literature
so for the moment the documents are just
distributed between all the doctors and
clinics and so stuff is being leaked
from one or the other place but but if
we have a centralized storage then it's
really more easily attackable
if it's all in one place and yeah it's
also gonna be used more and and there's
a single place where I can actually
steal a whole lot of documents or where
is this question going
so you mentioned CGM they have several
competitors that they bought and they
offered to their doctors that they can
convert data from the other products
since they don't offer those anymore and
then your data basically from the doctor
gets converted so there there is already
it's somewhat centralized yeah the
problem is of course the this is not
very public yet
we're leaks actually happened I mean the
thing that I showed from the US those
were all cases where it was legally
required to report this and in Germany
we haven't really heard a lot about this
microphone for so these health data
records should be used for research in a
pseudonym iced form can you say
something more about that I mean I then
put it in the talk that's kind of a
whole topic on its own
well VD also saves data in a
pseudonymous code but the sensor
two-factor authentication code with that
yes so basically when you log in to VV
it also locks you in into your pseudonym
account so there's a shadow profile to
every real profile and you're locked in
two times and so yeah with your device
with your token so on sides of the VV
platform it's really easy to to identify
you again so you really have to trust
the service provider here then there's
the idea that you can actually kind of
donate your data maybe that it can even
be enforced legally to provide data to
medical research
I thought the exchange of encrypted
documents or or just sensitive data was
solved in in the places I can look into
we managed to exchange data safely I
mean my C files after can do this why
can't doctors do this is there maybe a
solution that doctors could use that we
can propose to them I mean I don't know
about post quantum cryptography and and
what they can do in Nevada but yet a
problem in specification is not always
that which is implemented I mean for
really there's a very white paper where
everything is specified nicely but but
it's not necessarily the thing that was
actually implemented so they don't
actually check that it was implemented
the way it says so in the white paper
and so what was the question again
is there an alternative we can offer the
doctors now to exchange documents with
the patients it's very very difficult
try to have it as decentralized as
possible I can't really recommend
anything
I mean print it out and and and fax it
to them yeah I don't know
and the problem is you know he's right
so if we have end-to-end encrypted
maybe with PGP then you need to exchange
keys you need to verify the keys this
needs to be automated somehow and well I
mean this is missing now so we have the
IT infrastructure for the doctors now
there is identity management on the side
of the patient and there's the
electronic health card but nobody wants
to link these two things because there
there's no utility number four what's
the difference between health data and
patient data so the health record and
the patient records so so when you have
a patient record the doctors have to
save within that the health record uses
optional so another question to BB so
the private key was saved in as a read
encrypted read protected in a browser of
the doctor so the web crypto RP allows
you to mark a key as exportable or not
so there's an object it prevents access
if as long as the JavaScript engine is
implemented correctly so you give your
data in there and the engine does a
crypto yeah yeah so you have an object
and you have a method encrypt and
decrypt but you can access the key
[Music]
okay wanna share an idea here that's not
really on a technical level but yeah so
all health records are sensitive
especially things like abortion as I
said or my HIV state or psychological
disorders and I mean an idea would be to
that we X network with interest groups
that actually are in these domains just
to kind of see what they want or what
they have mean technically in the end
this type of information is going to be
public and it's more question of how as
a society will we deal with it when that
happens this is actually what I want a
same with my talk so we have I mean the
technical things I've talked about but
we as a society you have to ask
ourselves how do we deal with this now
okay another question
so another comment so about a year ago I
got a mail from CGM I found this one
again so from a doctor I got a link it's
HTTP first of all and I was supposed to
enter my personal information on this
site and I said well I'm not actually
gonna do this I mailed them I would
rather have HTTPS and I got the answer
regarding the encryption so so they said
they have an internal secure connection
and data is transferred in encrypted
form and that's legally required so
that's the answer I got
[Applause]
yeah interesting comment yeah so that's
the kind of quality we can look forward
to
[Music]