[Music]
the extra contents are off this talk the
talk is called the dirty sign empiric
science it's unfortunately not a perfect
method but still the best methods that
we've found so far and if I say they're
still beyond the fridge then you can
believe me
but if you actually look into the fridge
then that's science because with science
you basically test hypotheses and see if
these hypotheses are actually true okay
sounds good but where's the problem
but psychology can cause some problems
with that approach because there are a
lot of studies that show that there is a
certain effect but if people try to
replicate these studies they get a
different result
so can we so we actually can't try to it
trust the study set being released
however in this talk we will hopefully
learn how you can figure out if you can
actually trust a certain study or not
and please give a warm round of applause
for our speaker good morning everyone
welcome to this talk I hoped I would
first talk about what I can't do which
is drawing and you know that's a joke
but I would rather talk about my
motivation why I want to give this talk
and I hope you can read what's written
on the slides and now I will read what
is written in the Bible
Wow so many people here I'm dizzy and if
I fall over I'm sure there will be no
one who will help me and then another
person says why why do you think that do
you know the bystander effect if there
are a lot of people then no one helps I
threat this in a study that proved this
this can't be I was at the Congress and
someone already helped me well that
can't be true
the study of box and pendra has found
out that people in groups to help as
much as people who are not in groups
well yes as the saying goes don't trust
any statistics that you haven't forced
yourself and we want to talk about how
empirical studies actually works and how
what constitutes studies and what makes
study a good study and how you deal with
different results and in the end we want
to talk about what kind of problems
there are in science in general first of
all about me I'm Anna Kling golf I'm a
psychologist I work in at the University
of Kassel in in the section of human
machine interactions or systems
techniques so we do a lot with
technology and interface with humans and
to make keeps us entertaining I brought
I I'm showing you a study where we can
basically go through everything by
example and this is about facial
feedback and and the hypothesis is that
it's not only our faces and our facial
gestures that influence our our emotions
but it's also the other way around
and
and here we want to say that smiling
increases the positive attitude and
if you don't smile then this decreases
the positive attitude and when the study
was released there was first one
approach that said this is all based on
cognition this is on self-awareness when
I'm looking at myself when I smile then
I conclude that I'm happy and this makes
me more happy and there's another
approach that is psychological and they
say that the muscles that make you smile
I connect it with the emotions and now
the question is how do you figure out
which one of these two approaches or
explanations exactly is the right one
and and there's a study that
investigated this where they try to
figure out which one of these two
hypothesis or which of these two
approaches or explanations is actually
true and and as I said previously Trust
is something different than
understanding if I say yes you can trust
empirical studies but then we don't win
anything but if we actually understand
the studies then we have a better
understand and better understanding of
if we should trust these studies and to
clarify I only want to focus on
quantitative research here and that
means testing a hypothesis that we
already have but there's also other
approaches like qualitative research
where people first develop hypotheses so
what do we need to do empirical research
first of all we need hypotheses for
instance smiling increases positive
emotions
and how does the experiment work or how
could it how could an experiment work so
first of all we have to find some study
participants and we have to manipulate
them that sounds bad but it's not bad
it's just a regular term to regular term
that we make sure that people do what
they need to do for the study and in
this case it's smiling or not smiling
and then we have to measure the effect
of the manipulation and don't worry
they're honest formulas in the slides
and in the end of course you have to use
statistics to compare study populations
and in the ideal world who would of
course test all people so we would need
to take everyone on this planet to make
our tests of course this is not
realistic and that's why we need to have
a huge sample from the population that
should ideally be representative of the
entire human population and the sample
should really be representative of
everyone we're interested in so you
should have young people old people men
and women and this is all not always
realistic or not always feasible to
achieve and that's why you you basically
have to make assess yourself if it's
still reasonable reasonable to perform
the study if you don't have ideal study
populations and I have to make some
assumptions if this study would still
work with an an ideal study population
that's really business that's really and
it's also important to consider that
we're doing a random sample so if I have
100,000 people and I only pick 10 then
there is a certain influence by this
random pick and depends on where within
the population with well within the
distribution I sampled people for my
study I will get different results and
in this study we had 92 students that
participated and here we wanted to
investigate the effects if smiling is
really causal for the effect and it's
real important that everything else is
the same
because if there's anything else it it's
different between the groups
then these differences could be causal
for whatever we observe and and it's
also important that you don't directly
instruct people to smile because this
could influence people to think about
their actions but we would rather have
them do it implicitly or intuitively so
that we don't have so that study
participants don't fully understand why
they're doing certain things and and of
course how do you trick people and one
way is to say okay let people just have
a pencil in their mouth and so for those
in the audience if you want to
participate you can take a pencil
between your teeth and then you can try
to move your move the corners of your
mouth and if you take the pencil through
your lips then you will notice that your
muscles will be affected
and you can't smile anymore
and this is a way to get them to to get
the people to smile or not smile without
telling them how scream can we hit abide
until we drift
Anglet and the good thing is that with
this manipulation we can sort of find
out which of the two theories works
because because cognitive theory can't
be can't be reused here because when you
think of why am i smiling right now your
idea would be not because I'm happy but
because I have this pen in my mouth so
if people still are more happy if they
have this smiling massive construct
contraction then it's definitely the
muscles that are related to their to
their mood so now we have to measure so
one thing that's very important here in
psychology that is always problematic
because most of the things we want to
measure you can't measure them directly
you can't measure emotions different to
chemistry or something like that you
can't actually measure it directly
usually by asking them or by questioning
them and to make it comparable between
two different people there's a scale how
happy are you on a scale from one to ten
for example and because our hypothesis
is that emotions are hate heightened we
need to make them happy before so they
were able so in this study they watched
a funny cartoon of course we tested the
study tested the cartoon whether it's
actually funny and one term that I that
this is often needed is
operationalization that is I make things
measurable I make that so that I can
measure things that are not measurable
directly and using this questionnaire is
one way of make one way of
operationalization and
important is that measuring is always in
exact every sort of measurement that you
can do even the way you think it should
be exact with measuring like the length
of your table you still have a little
bit of a difference so there is always
something in exact about them and this
is this is even more pressing when I
can't measure what I actually tried to
measure but instead I have to
operationalize it so this makes it more
more random mistakes now let me
summarize the mistakes so that everyone
understands so trial subjects were
invited they should hold a pen either in
their lips between their lips or between
their teeth or in their hands the hand
is basically the control group which
shouldn't have to do wouldn't have an
influence at all then they should watch
a cartoon and all of them watch the same
cartoon and then they should sort of
guess what is the better or like what is
my mood right now and we had to tell
them a cover story and we told them well
it's for disabled people
how does writing with your mouth make or
like influence your emotions now methods
comparison and this is important to me
now we don't have you don't have to
actually be able to calculate the
statistics here but you have to be able
to understand how such as statistics
works and what we want to do is compare
the two groups in particular we want to
compare how funny did they find the
cartoon and how happy did it make them
and because we had more than one person
we used the average of each group now
can I compare that this directly can I
say well those that held it between the
teeth had a higher average this is how I
I basically confirmed my hypothesis but
this is too easy I can't do that why
because there's these random errors
first of all those that come through
measuring and second of all those that
come through sampling because I haven't
asked every one but I've only asked a
sample and then there's I have two
different random influences and now I
have two values and I want to find out
are they different in a real way
is it just random that they're different
or is it real so this was the original
table from the stubby and mean funniness
where the averages that were compared
now we have to basically choose a
statistical method and there's a lot of
different statistical methods that are
useful for some users the most
well-known is the t-test which is
basically a way to compare two two
medians or to two medians yes but that
doesn't work because we have more than
two groups so this is why we do did a
variance analysis which allows us to
compare more than two groups and this
the the way of thing that we used was
planned contrasts so I can choose what
kind of what kind of pattern do I expect
and then I can choose whether it works
or doesn't so I'm hoping to be able to
explain it to you now a little bit the
basic question is do the values that I
have differ from each other in a real
way or just randomly so how probable is
it that I'll get this pattern by chance
now I made this graph and you can see
the three groups they seem to be
different now the question is is it
random or not
now what I can do is I can calculate the
variance the variance is the difference
between each of the each of the values
to their mean to the group mean and then
you basically use a formula it doesn't
matter how the formula looks but then
and then you get a value and this is
what we call within group variance on
and what we do next is we do this for
each group or each cluster and then we
compare the middle as a the mean values
of the different groups and then we can
take in another variance to calculate
the difference between the different
groups and these two variances I can put
in a relation to each other and and see
if the variance would in one group is
really huge so that there's a great
diversity within one group and I can
also say that can state whether the
differences between different groups is
huge or small so is there a huge
difference between the teeth and the
lips groups and if I look at the
relationships between other relations
between these groups I can determine by
using a table or by using a statistical
procedure if the observed result is by
chance or it's actually a meaningful
result from a statistical standpoint and
the most crucial thing is that you
basically compare how how random lasts
how random does my result look so for
the plant contrasts
if I had so if I see okay there's an
elevated level for the teeth a lower
level for the lips that's what I would
have weighed well that's what I would
expect and then I can compare my
expectations with what is actually
observed so you want to see how likely
is it that something is just by chance
and of course 100 cent certainty is an
analytics objective or aim for what
we're doing here but usually we say okay
if something is only about five percent
likely a one percent likely to have
occurred by chance then we say okay it's
really unlikely that this just happens
by chance there might be some effect and
we call this probability for for saying
this is just by chance we call this P so
this is the p-value and we see that this
value is so unlikely it's like less than
5% then we say okay it is significant
and we see in this specific study we
have a p-value of 0.03 so it's 3% and
it's really unlikely that this happened
just by chance and therefore we can be
more confident in saying that there is
probably a statistical connection so
what can we do with the results so we
see okay the test is significant we see
this is most likely not random and we
see that the difference that we observe
is most likely caused by the
manipulation that we've done and because
we did not
so because we didn't do any cognition
cognitive processing it's more likely
that the physiological theory is more
likely so the body and not the mind
theory is more likely but this is still
not a proof in the sense of a
mathematical proof it's just a support
for the hypothesis because this proof
can still be disproven or this result
can still be disproven by other more
more elaborate true proofs or hypothec
statistical experiments so now of course
we want to talk about how can you trust
the testicle how can you trust empirical
studies so how does empirical study work
in principle and what makes a good
clinical and what makes a good study
okay so what do we have to keep in mind
we have to have standardized tests so
that it's all established and it has
been tested by other people and what I
really appreciate is when I get an
explanation why people use certain
procedures to test so when they explain
why they chose specific tests and I can
really understand why certain decisions
have been made and to suspend your
studio and manipulation checked and so
something else that is also very
important it's very helpful is when
there's a manipulation check to make
sure that people are actually smiling
with the pencil in their mouth if the
methods that were applied actually
achieved what was intended to be
achieved and it's also helpful to
compare this to other studies or compare
methods of other studies and see what
what kind of approaches they use
and something that's also very important
is that you have a good sample so
usually it's a rule of thumb you want to
have like 30 people from a group which
is of course not always possible but
this is something you should strive for
and a comment and the reoccurring
problem is that most studies just used
students as a sample because they are
more available for those studies this
can be a problem when you and this can
be a problem when you want to measure
things like political opinions then
students have a different political
background than the general population
this is something that you really have
to be aware of and if you but if you
look into something like smiling then
this is most likely not a problem and
it's also important to see if people
have if the experimenters have tested if
the students have or the participants
have understood what the study was about
because you wanted to trick them into
believing something else and of course
you want to have a proper statistics you
need to have the right statistical
procedures for instance if you do a lot
of small tests then this is not good
because you have a greater number of
false positives because you always say
like 5% for each test but all these five
four tenths
five percents add up and this one this
is why the probability for wrongfully
saying that something is significant
when it is not increases and
unfortunately it's quite difficult to
understand and if the statistical
procedure is the right one for specific
particular experiment or for a
particular study and
and usually what you can do still is
look at what kind of things are being
reported what kind of metrics are being
used and correlations and causality I
guess most of you noses so you have to
look at what kind of conclusions are
being drawn so a correlation is just a
relationship between two things but a
causality is a directional relationship
we say a modifies or influences being
and so if you for instance see that
stocks and babies could cure then you
might conclude that there is a
relationship but if you actually do the
experiments you will say okay this is
nonsense of course and and it's really
important that you look at what kind of
conclusions are actually allowed to be
drawn and if if there's like a temporal
relationship that is exactly the other
way around and of course B can't change
a okay one hint something that you want
to look at is it is to figure out what
that study is good or not most studies
are actually published in journals and
journals have peer reviews and peer
review means other other researchers are
actually kind of reviewing the the
research the study that was submitted to
this journal but of course this is not
uncontroversial because sometimes there
are some researchers that kind of give
better or worse results to specific
people but in general if it's a if it's
a journal that does not have peer review
that's a bad sign similar impact
fracture is basically the impact factor
belongs to a journal and it basically
says how often is have studies from this
journal been cited this
can be seen as a criterion of quality
but you really can't but it's really
important not to overstate the
importance the idea is the more
well-known a journal is the more choices
it gets because more people will submit
their papers and then it will choose
better better studies but again that
doesn't mean all studies with the high
in journals with a high impact factor
are great but it's still a good hint for
you so if you found a study that you
found very interesting or something you
can see an impact factor so everything
with an impact factor of one you can
cite what about you okay I tried showing
you what is a good study study but now I
want to ask what do I make when I have
different results what do I do
completing training especially if the
results are completely opposite to each
other now I'm gonna go back to the
bystander effect example and this was in
the comic and it said as the more people
are watching an accident the less people
actually help the by the basis is a case
of kitty Genovese who was murdered and
there were about 40 neighbors that heard
her crying out and that basically knew
what was happening and none of them
actually did anything about it
so then Jon Hamm Darley he thought well
I really want to figure this out so he
did a couple of experiments he basically
simulated an accident and then varied
how many people were watching and then
he measured how long would it take them
to help and this effect was actually
found quite often and it's been
discussed a lot because it's pretty
scary for everyone but there's a lot of
different different results so some
studies found this and some
didn't and what are we doing so first
let's look at it more exactly
sometimes when studies look like they're
opposite there's just differences in the
design that make the that explain the
results the the difference is sometimes
only seem opposite for example sometimes
the samples are different if you use
children versus example where's adults
it's possible that there isn't one study
that's wrong but instead kids and adults
are just different or you can look at
the operationalization so how would did
it look whether mayor more trial people
or like people that were not in on the
experiment or was only one person not in
on the experiment and everyone else was
in this can be a difference so what can
we actually do we can do a meter
analysis or a moderator analysis this
these are analysis that basically try to
find out does it make a difference if
it's children or adults about meter
analysis now these are basically
summaries of more than one study in a
journal article now usually the author
of this meta-analysis reads a lot a lot
of studies and does and tries to read
all of the studies to a specific topic
in between a time frame and then he or
she will put them in an article in a
journal paper and then he will also
describe the differences and try to
calculate the power of effects so these
are power of effects is basically trying
to say
how how much are these are these two
samples actually different
so these power of effects are basically
a measure of how large an effect is and
they're standardized so they can be
compared between different studies if I
look at the mean then one person might
have used a different scale so I might
not be able to compare them but I can
always compare the effect size one
example of that is Cohen's D and there's
kind of a rule of thumb so a small thumb
would be 0.2 a medium effect would be
like 0.5 and starting at 0.8 you would
basically talk about a large effect size
so and if you look at the effect size
then you see or you better understand
how impactful the influence actually is
or how you could better understand what
kind of question was asked and I found a
meta-analysis of this bystander effect
and you see that this is actually quite
a lot office because these literature
reviews are very take a take up a lot of
work and you you're encouraged to look
into the study because it's actually
very interesting because they also talk
about contradictions and make it more
easier to understand what the results
actually mean then there are also
reviews which are also papers that also
try to summarize the current knowledge
or the current theories and hypotheses
in a research area and usually it's from
researchers that work in that field and
they also try to talk about
contradictions based on what based on
the knowledge that the offers have
and and people try to us explain why
there are contradictions in different
studies in these reviews and that and
these are the pieces of advice that I
give you to basically better judge
scientific results and plant if ik
publications and in the end I would like
to talk about what kind of problems the
science or as a scientist says and I
don't want to show you just a positive
side of science because there are more
problems in science and then shown here
then these three problems that I'm going
to talk about but these are very
important so first of all I want to talk
about P hacking replication the core
application crisis and the publication
bias so what is P hacking it means that
you manipulate data to obtain the
desired result so the aim is that you
decrease the p value below 5% to obtain
significant results and so that you
obtain significant result and this way
you still you still basically trick the
test to still say okay what you found
out is statistically significant and the
bad thing is this is really hard to
detect for other people and only very
few offers published their raw data and
even then if you have the raw data it's
not always possible to replicate all the
work that people have done to obtain the
results and there are different
approaches to deal with this one is
replication studies for instance I look
at one study and I try to replicate it
and see if I get the same results which
of course is not always
and this way you can basically reveal
p-value hacking but even if you find
something different it might not be
intentional that the offer has done
anything bad it might have been that
there's a mistake and you have to
contact the original offer and talk
about why you get different results and
this is just an approach this does not
so these replication studies it's
they're just an approach they do not
solve the problem itself and then
there's also this replication crisis
which is kind of strange because I just
talked about replication as a method to
basically combat p-value hacking um but
there was an actual crisis in the field
of psychology that a lot of scientific
studies in the field of psychology and
some of them were very important in
well-recognized could not be reproduced
by others and what are the approaches to
deal with this and the only real
approach real strategy is to have a
better plan for the study to reduce the
number of potential bad influences and
do a4o planning in advance and sometimes
it also makes sense to change the
significant threshold so I talked about
having a threshold of 5% of 1% but
sometimes it makes sense to reduce it
even lower to make it less likely to get
a false positive but even this problem
is still not resolved or soft the last
problem I want to talk about is
publication bias and the problem is that
significance results tend to be more
published
non significant results so if you don't
find anything new or anything
significant it's unlikely that papers
will be able to publish in journals and
if you basically have the spies of most
publications that only should positive
results then you can get different
different impression on what is
happening in the field if you knew more
about okay so another approach is meta
analysis so you do research on existing
studies and try to do Corrick tation and
corrections on the calculations to
account for different to account for
different factors including potentially
non published studies that had no
results and no significant results and
when I create meta analysis I also call
different office and different
researchers who who might have studies
on the topic but that were not published
and the more I do this and the more
responses I get the better I can assess
an estimate how many non reported
effects there are how many non
significant results have been observed
that did not make it into a publication
and so this problem is not resolved now
there are of course I would like so I
hope that I have answered the questions
further so the last has a last couple of
questions answered but still the one big
question remains can we trust clinical
studies and the conclusion is that yeah
some what you can do that but it depends
so different studies have different
levels of quality and
it's very important that you assess the
study quality yourself and that doesn't
mean that everyone should be a scientist
but it's worthwhile to to to not only
use the summary from popular popular
science articles if you want to use this
in a conversation but it's also
reasonable to really go back to the
source and try to look at the original
publications and try to get an idea of
your own while going to the original
sources and it's really real important
that you understand probabilities and
that's why I included this method part
in the beginning so because many people
say ok a study found out that something
is like this so it must be true but this
is a common misconception because in the
end this is all probabilities and this
is all about being certain about some
things so and there most study are
basically no study is like 100 percent
certain and then of course there are
meta-analysis that can basically give
you better overview over what has been
published in which also applies to the
reviews and of course we still have
these open problems in science and
scientific work and this is something
that you should not disregard or ignore
and well the conclusion is really like
said in the beginning science as it is
right now is what we it's the best what
we have right now but it's not perfect
and it's important to stay critical and
right now it is society's are the best
thing we have and but we should still be
critical
Glenna comment awfully to map schloss
small comment maybe so it's the end even
also looking at locked up signs all the
studies that i cited here are freely
available on the open on the internet
and you can actually watch them if you
read them if you want
okay thank you very much now we have
time for questions please go to the
microphones and i will try to the
questions the internet the internet okay
me do it would send us intro significant
or London via end by P here where does
the P come from okay so I didn't explain
this exactly enough it's important that
before doing the study on which
significance level do you want to work
do I want to achieve five percent do I
want to achieve one percent and then
this is my aim and then I use the
statistical methods and I get a value
and this might be like three percent and
if I say I want to be below five percent
and I observe three percent then yeah
everything is fine I have a significant
result and if I had set one percent and
I observe three percent then well
unfortunately
it's not significant and that's exactly
what I'd say if you say if you set
higher aims and that means then you can
be more well yeah exactly exactly this
is what you calculate you compare the
one variance with the other and you get
one value and you see and you look up in
a table if that value is significant or
not
unfortunately this is too complicated to
explain in detail how the calculations
are being done and I recommend that you
look into a statistical handbook to see
how these are being done okay people
just do one part of the work and other
people do other part of all the work
that's possible and that that's
happening sometimes so most of the time
it's not the researcher himself that are
actually that is actually doing the
study with the trial persons instead of
it's the assistants and also it's you
and also you can give it to different
people to do the statistical analysis
you could probably do that
and I've seen it often that you ask
someone to check your results and I'm
guessing your idea would be possible but
it might be a lot of work yeah done
thank you fill in Xia before it's really
nice talk Binda and virus problem is in
complete war
results and yeah that was my approach to
encourage you to encourage the people to
look at the original studies and to look
at them themselves in though many of
them are kind of off-putting to many
people if the stimulus in planning in
for feltrinelli penalty are there's
possibilities to look at details of the
study and choose basically publish them
before you do your study at 0.1 but we
actually got 0.3 yes it's possible and
it's actually gaining more adoptions so
that a lot of papers actually say they
actually a lot of journals say okay
before during the study you actually
have to send in an abstract and then you
have have to make sure in advance of
that you commit to a specific plan and
to a specific threshold and I think this
is a very reasonable thing but it's not
done enough at the moment
do you is better I will know my coats
off to significance neva constables
uncia
is not really something that shows
quality but instead is just a
manifestation yes that is correct so if
if this results are significant it
doesn't tell you if the study is good or
bad or qualitative of high quality and
because they found publication bias yeah
how do people deal with it well you
still need to publish to have a good
scientific career and I don't know if
any good approach to deal with this
it's really unfortunately that
scientific studies that find something
significant are more likely to be
published if I knew a solution to this
problem I would be very happy I'm sorry
that I can't offer a solution
Thank You tension public Thank You mr.
Whitney's father let's a tie I'm into
scientists for me it's interesting these
re problems there was a real problem
using in actuality
LCDR interrelated and they're related to
houses walks today also suffered Iza and
problemas de la cough yes so of course
there is a connection between these
three problems P hacking is peeking can
be reduced by replication and then of
course replications there are problems
and and of course we can talk for a long
time about this and I can also recommend
the other talks about replication paper
replication bias that are currently
running are currently being presented
but I I didn't understand why I should
say to the publication bias you have to
publish studies you do peep hacking
absolutely that already answers the
questions and if only studies are being
published that have a significant effect
then of course people are as scientists
are much more incentivized to change the
data and to induce phe and to create p
aking to have publications but the
problem is that publication bias to
resolve this is really real difficult
because we as we are scientists because
as a scientist we're also not that
interested in reading in journals that
with there are so many things that don't
have any significant relationship it's
not 1223 the Internet World Cup and has
a question
so how do you deal with errors that you
can only see after you've published it
as an author so in the ideal case you
should state that something was wrong
and of course do another follow-up study
to see see if this incorrect measurement
or whatever has actually a negative
effect on the results and so far I have
the experiences myself and I haven't
seen this for other people they are go
for my vote on conduct the study more
than once before publishing so I'm not
aware of any requirements to do a
certain studies twice but there are some
scientists who by themselves want to
publish their data and they publish the
data in the Internet but I'm not aware
of any Jones that really require that
the data has to be published but my
impression is really that it's the
scientists who want to publish and who
want to support science as a whole with
publishing the data oh it's empty
have you seen that people like to
basically offer a wrong topic so you're
actually look is that just too much
participants act and this gaydom cup of
intervention for example Oh for example
it's about disabled people but instead
it's about video -
opting in the synopsis look even in
psychology that many people would think
that you actually don't lie to them no I
don't think that they're anything like I
mean so these cover stories during the
study so you want to dilute the study
participants about what the study is
actually about while the study is
ongoing but in the end you will tell
them what the study is actually about
and it's oh and also in some studies the
researchers actually asks the people if
they can guess what was actually tested
and if people realize what's actually
going on then it might be reasonable to
leave these people out because their
understanding of the tests can influence
the results there's a question could you
please say something about funding bias
so basically who gets the funding and
how it influences research yeah that's a
big topic for research unfortunately I
cannot say so much simply because
because I was only at the University and
and I didn't have to deal with specific
donors of money because my research so
far has been completely funded by the
government
yeah as a man of kaga via the deep
distress of us from our contamination
among and the vetting system through the
nasty motto the sphere under
transponders okay mady's our future
comes as shown teaser on the end vision
shaft lab safety
in study and seen that it was done right
yes there is something and you can look
at it at the citation count if a lot of
people have cited the study then
hopefully everyone has read the study
and you can somehow conclude that and
the study is probably good but the
pressor if you would establish a rating
system then how would you agree on what
kind of ratings to give to papers it's
like very subjective and so of course we
have the peer review and it goes into
the general direction but I don't think
that a rating system is something that
you can objectively set up this is the
last question now so is that good or bad
it depends on the field if the research
field is relatively new then of course
there are not many studies and we cannot
use many studies for your meta studies
and but the bystander effect is
something that has been researched a lot
then of course I expect a lot of studies
to be part of the meta study so I don't
think there's a general guideline that
you can use to say how many studies
there should be I would rather focus on
how did they select the studies for the
meta study did they call the office what
kind of research terms that they use
and in these meta-analysis they usually
state this what kind of strategies are
used to find studies to so that I can
see for myself or I can assess for
myself if they actually use the valid
stretch yours for a strategy to find
everything that I deem relevant okay and
now this
[Music]