[Music]
and I have one last announcement before
we begin this talk this is a personal
announcement to whoever slap the sticker
saying for recto use only on to my
microphone microphones are not supposed
to be used this way
please trust me I am very familiar with
microphones I know how they are supposed
to be used however our next speaker is
going to tell you about things that are
supposed to be used this way and about
how to secure and protect those things
so please welcome Jana and the talk you
all came here to see Internet of Donn's
a round of applause
okay so hello everyone my name is veena
I'm working for a second salt as an IT
security consultant
and besides penetrating all the things
that the second salt availability lab I
have been studying information security
for the last five years at the
University of Applied Sciences and
pelton back in Austria and about a year
ago I was I was facing a massive
challenge
some people might know this challenge
this challenge was to select a proper
topic for my master thesis you you might
know there are always those predefined
topics by the universities some of them
are quite interesting they are taken
yeah most of the time quite fast but all
the other students and you are left with
the boring topics and I thought to
myself yeah I don't want to stress
myself I just want to define a topic by
myself and that was the challenge so the
first thing I did to get a better
overview of the topics was to take a
look at the topics my colleagues have
chosen I created a word cloud out of
that so we have basically all the
interesting topics there we have
bitcoins we have GD P R we have cyber
cyber cyber we have DevOps management
malware but some of you might have
already noticed it there is one topic
missing at my colleagues thesis which is
very very important in the year 2018 and
that's the Internet of Things so I guess
it don't have to explain here at the
Congress what the Internet of Things is
it's basically the interconnection of
all the devices which were analog a few
years ago with each other and even worse
over the Internet and I thought yeah
maybe I can combine the knowledge
together it's a consult and conduct the
penetration test in this Internet of
Things the problem here is still there
are like millions of products and I just
have to ride one thesis so I had to
select one subcategory in this Internet
of Things to conduct the penetration
test on and of course the first thing
which came to my mind were smart home
devices we already had a lot of
interesting
about smart home devices there are like
smart coffee machines smart lawnmowers
lightbulbs thermometers and stuff like
that but this category has two problems
so first of all there is already a lot
of research done and the other problem
is the impact so I don't want to
downplay the vulnerabilities which were
found here but when there are
vulnerabilities found I mean yeah if
there is a DDoS on your lawnmower you
can just go out to your garden and mode
alone yourself it's not that big of a
deal
so I thought they have to select a
subcategory where the impact is a little
bit more critical and I came up with the
following devices so for example dolls
smart dolls there was this tall Kiowa
some of you might know it someone found
out that it has a built-in microphone
and the data was sent to some to be a
service in some dubious countries and it
was even declared it's an illegal
telecommunication device it had to be
destroyed or there is a lot of
interesting research at baby monitors a
colleague of mine wrote in very
interesting blog post you should take a
look at it or devices which affect our
body so for example smart pacemakers
they were developed by as tube medical
that's the biggest manufacturer of
pacemakers in the world and they built a
pacemaker which is programmable via
bluetooth but yeah they forgot
authentication which is quite a big of a
problem when everyone is able to
reprogram your pacemaker so as we can
see those at this categories the impact
would be quite critical but this again a
lot of research done so the deadline was
coming closer and closer I had to hand
him some kind of topic for my master
thesis I was doing a lot of
brainstorming with with myself and then
suddenly it came to my mind there is one
category out there where the impact
would be very critical and there is not
a lot of research done and that's the
Internet of dildos so it's basically
it's basically the integration of sex
toys into the Internet of Things
where we interconnected dildos with each
other
and over the internet but before I'm
going to show you what I found in this
internet of dildos we have to talk about
history because you you might think now
did something new but it's in true
because the internet of dildos as we
know it is existing for about fifty to
sixty years and this always when there
are new inventions or interesting ideas
the first appear in movies and that also
applies to the internet of fuels so
those are quite old movies we have for
example Bob Aquila of Flash Gordon or a
Cosmo and in those movies
those are real movies it's not a joke
the Internet of deals
it appeared first in this movie so for
example at Papa gala the evil guy used
the device called the orgasmic on to
cause so high levels of arousal in
humanity to kill people so basically the
internet of dildos was in the 60s and
70s a weapon of mass destruction
and not the weapon of mass pleasure as
it should be
so a few years later a whole research
area was formed this research area is
called teledildonics and it that's also
another joke again and it was first
mentioned by Ted Nelson he is a
technical philosopher and he coined
quite well-known terms like transclusion
virtuality and intervene hilarity and
teledildonics and he mentioned this term
it first in a book called computer lib
dream machines very interesting book by
the way you should read it and in this
book he did interviews with people who
had yeah innovative and interesting
ideas for the time but the technology
was not just ready yet and it did an
interview with a guy called how Express
and how Express developed the device or
had the idea for a device called awed
attack when you google for out attack
you fight find a quite an ancient
website called ode attack calm and when
you dig a little bit deeper you can find
out that he's still looking to find your
manufacturer to sell this sonic
stimulator sounds already quite
interesting and and even has a patent
and a small graphic for that so it's
basically a radio with one input and two
outputs one input of course the the
antenna and the two outputs are one for
the headphones and the other output is
for the sonic stimulator which is
inserted from below in the human
life-form
you even can find the patent on Google
patents and he writes there
I mean it's abstract random or
controlled electronically synthesized
signals are converted to sound waves
that are directly coupled to the skin of
a life-form you have such as a human
body for example to stimulate the skin
or internal portions of the life-form so
as we can see the ideas were there but
the technology was just not ready in the
1970s and 1980s but now we are in the
year 2018 and we are definitely ready
for a penetration test in the internet
of dildos and before I'm going to talk
about the test devices and two
vulnerabilities I'm going to make a
promise now I will try to keep this as
serious as possible I will try to keep
the the the I will call it the IPM
stinger and those per minutes as low as
possible yeah and now I will just want
to talk about the test devices because
those are very important so I selected
three test devices for my master thesis
on the right side we have the that's not
a choke we can be producing more Penta
Buster that's the real name in the
middle we have the magic motion flamingo
and on the left side we have the real
love Lydia so the devices on the left
side and the middle have one thing in
common they are manufactured in China
and the device in the red right side is
manufactured in Germany so I have to
admit I was a little bit biased because
I thought I'm going to take a look at
the Chinese devices first because there
will be a lot of low-hanging fruits
question to the audience now who
believes that I found most of the
vulnerabilities in the Chinese devices
raise your hand
who believes that I found most of the
vulnerabilities in the German device who
believes that I found vulnerabilities
everywhere yeah you're basically all
right but when I took a look at the
German device I found so many really
really critical learner abilities that
the image immediately stopped there and
wrote my whole thesis about the penta
bus stop okay so the Penta pastor itself
it's just one product out of a whole
product line I just bought the Penta
pastor because it was the cheapest one
it's they're basically using all the
same backends the same iOS and Android
apps and yeah the Penta pastor is
basically device which is connected via
bluetooth to a smartphone and it can be
used for example for long distance
relationships but there is way more
behind those apps because they are just
like a whole social media network built
in you can make group chats you can
create image galleries you can maintain
friends lists
yet that's real it's real it's not a
joke yeah and now we're going to to
analyze this Penta Buster and take it
down to the last parts yeah we're going
to analyze the software I'm going to
tell you a little bit about the
transport layer and the hardware of
course so I'd like to start with the
software so the first vulnerability
where we have to talk about this is
so-called information disclosure so you
might think not boring just some random
version numbers yeah that's true most of
the time information disclosures are
boring but in this case it's really
critical because I found a so called you
store file in the web root at the store
file is basically a metadata file which
is created by the Mac OS finder and it
it contains a lot of metadata like files
and folder names so when you find such a
file in a web brute you have basically
side-channel directory listing this new
store file is a proprietary format but
this for all problems in life there is a
Python module to decode it yeah and the
decoded the D store file and I was
presented with the following contents so
that's basically a side channel
directory listing of the web route there
are a lot of interesting files and
folders so for example old page example
I have no idea why it's there in the
productive environment there is a
database folder but the most interesting
folder is the config folder so when I
navigate to the config folder that was
redirect URI listing enabled and there
was one file in there and it was called
config dot PHP dot Diane C with the
following contents
so basically I had not had my access to
the database hostname they did his names
usernames and passwords the problem now
was that as we can see the database host
is just localhost so there might be a
chance that it's not yet directly
reachable via the internet and we have
to find the so called exposed
administrative interface to connect to
the database yeah of course the first
thing I did was to do a port scan
[Applause]
a lot of interesting ports
sadly no no SQL ports but some of you
might remember this let's call it weird
brown orange web application called
phpMyAdmin
and they found a sub-domain which
contained the PHP myadmin installation
and I was able to use those credentials
to connect directly to the database and
get access to all the data
so I basically had access now to the
real-life addresses to messages in clear
text which were exchanged images videos
and a lot of other stuff so yeah and
what hurt me the most was the following
slide because the passwords were stored
in clear text and that's really not
necessary in the 21st century okay so in
real life about 30 minutes have passed
by
and they tried to do a write up as fast
as possible and submitted to the
chairman said pooned and yeah a few
minutes later I got a really interesting
call from the chairman said bond
they told me that they already informed
the manufacturer and they already trying
to fix those problems so my problem was
now that they still had to write my
master thesis and it just have content
for about 30 pages now and I need like
hundred pages so I did a little bit of
more research and found way more
vulnerabilities of course and the next
tool or ability I'm going to talk about
is a so-called insecure direct object
reference sounds cryptic but it isn't
it's basically always a vulnerability
which is consisting of two sub problems
so the first problem is when someone
uploads resources to a back-end those
resources and most of the time renamed
to like an random string which shouldn't
be guessable the first problem would be
if it would be get simple but the second
thing is there should be authorization
checks in place so if someone is able to
guess those unique identifiers there
should still be some like process which
should check if the user should even be
able to download these resources and in
this case yeah it was just really easy
to guess the identifiers and there was
no author it's a authorization
whatsoever and I had to learn this the
hard way literally there is a feature in
the smartphone apps called galleries so
you can create galleries you can set the
visibility to no one is able to see it
just your friends are able to see it
everyone is able to see it you can even
set the password on those galleries and
yeah and just for a test I created a
gallery with a few cats and when you
request this gallery you see the
following requests user manager PHP blah
blah blah username password
and some ID and I thought yeah maybe I
should change the city and I was
presented with a dick pic so
yeah the problem behind this is quite
easy everything which is stored on the
server is renamed to a global counter
the global counter is incremented by one
after every after every upload and there
are no authorization checks whatsoever
because the images are just stored on a
server so it doesn't matter if you set a
password or set the visibility that's
just nonsense to do it okay so the next
vulnerability yeah I called it improper
authentication to be honest it was just
a weird authentication so it's a consult
is already a lot of different ways of
implementing authentication some are
good some are bad but it can be fixed
but in this case it was just weird I've
never seen something like that it's
basically like HTTP basic authentication
but a little bit worse
so normally authentication works as
follows you're sending a username and
password to a server and if this process
is successful you get some kind of
authorization information like a cookie
or an API token you can use this cooking
API or API token for to authorize all
the other requests in this case every
request contains just username and
password in clear-text to authenticate
the requests that's just weird to be
honest and also if if your password is
compromised it will also mean that you
have to change your username because
it's part of the authentication
information so weird weird
implementation okay the next one ability
is called the remote pleasure version
1.0 it's Mondas Europe because there is
a 2.0
yeah there is a feature in those apps
where you can create remote control
links they can be sent to your SMS or
email and everyone who is in possession
of possession of those links can
directly control the devices there is no
extra confirmation needed we will take a
look at the email now there is a button
in the email called quick control and
there is an ID again
yeah the thing is yeah it's just a
global counter again and what an
attacker can do now is download the app
creates its own quick controlling
decrement the ID and pleasure just
random strangers on the Internet
[Applause]
[Music]
okay I will show you guys if we do you
know where I'm doing exactly that so
when they witty is going to start this
going to start perfect on the right side
we're going to see an attack device
which is just connected to the normal
mobile network and the attacker creates
its own quick controlling and decrements
the ID and on the left side we can see
another smartphone which is connected to
Wi-Fi to have internet access and via
bluetooth to the smart six toy and this
attacker device should now be able to
control yeah see that now in a few
seconds that's just what I explained
yeah
hmm
yeah there is no confirmation whatsoever
sir you can directly control all the
devices okay I have to stop talking
about software now there is a lot more
like cross scripting HTTP problems
outdated software but there's not a
little enough time left now so we have
to talk about the transport layer before
I'm going to tell you something about
the vulnerabilities are identified I
will tell you something about Bluetooth
Low Energy
in general the security basics and how
authentication and encryption works on a
very high level so you can imagine that
Bluetooth Low Energy basically works
like a Web API so that's a very high
level explanation you have API endpoints
those are the service characteristics
and you have properties where you can
read and write to so for example the
device name can be read or written to to
change the device name and there are
also a lot of other characteristics
which will be very important when it
comes to remote pleasure
version 2.0 a little bit later so that's
a very high-level explanation to know
but we don't have enough time left
talking about the security basics
Bluetooth Low Energy is using a CCM
that's count the CBC with Mac that
basically considered secure but as we
know security also depends on the key
material and the key exchange and at
Bluetooth Low Energy the key exchanged
is defined as the pairing methods for
Bluetooth Low Energy we have five
pairing methods we have just no pairing
so yeah we basically throw packets into
the air and if a device is nearby it it
tries to do something with those packets
we have just works we have out-of-band
pairing tasks in the Mara comparison I
don't have to tell you that it tell you
the details now we you all know those
it's not very comparison very compare
numbers to exchange the key material you
have the pass key which is yeah like
always your zero zero one two three four
we have out of pain pairing where the
key material is exchanged via NFC for
example and we have just works that's
really secure where did the key is just
set to zero and can we of course brute
force to
these but it just works of course so out
of those five methods what what do what
does the audience thinks that the sex
toy is using is it using no paring raise
your hands
is it using any of the other more or
less secure methods yeah
it's using no paring it means that the
Android and iOS apps just a throw the
packets into the air and if a device is
nearby it starts to vibrate and that's
of course easily exploitable you can
just sniff the real traffic and repeat
it I did exactly that
using a so called Bluetooth line which
is sniffer I'll use the bluefruit device
it works very well and they placed it
between the sex toy and the smartphone
app and there's nifty traffic using
Wireshark and it found some interesting
endpoints or handles there is the 1f
handle which is like an initialization
handle and there is the handle 25 where
you can send values from zero to FF to
set the vibration intensity yeah and now
it's time for a little bit of war
dueling
I wrote the small pipe and proof of
concept which basically scans the air
for Bluetooth low-energy devices if it
finds the device it tries to or try to
find out if it is a sex toy and if yes
yeah it basically turns it on to 200% to
FF so the next thing I want to talk
about is not that funny so please don't
laugh now because when we release this a
lot of people on Twitter asked is this
rape so serious topic for example the
evil attacker is using my for dealing
script in the in the metro in the new
Bond in vim in Vienna and you would
pledge it just random strangers it's
this rape in Austria we have two
different things we have rape and sexual
assault and they have two preconditions
so that's violence are three
preconditions we have violence threats
or deprivation of Liberty which is just
not the case in this scenario but we
have a special paragraph called pewds
regard to translate that it's called the
polka paragraph and the old it's a
little bit different in Germany and I'm
not a law expert so it just kept the
Austrian laws which get verified by
tourists so and according to this
paragraph this would be an unwanted
sexual act via third party object so
it's not rape but it's an unwanted
sexual act okay
the hardware last but not least the
biggest problem is that firm updates are
not possible that was confirmed by any
manufacturer the problem here is a lot
of vulnerabilities can just be fixed by
doing infirm updates and the
manufacturer came up with the idea that
the end users can send in their smart
sex toys to do a firm wrapped it and I'm
quite sure that nobody's sending in they
use devices to conduct the firmware
update
and the other problems are debug
interfaces the other just forgot to
remove the or deactivate they are serial
interfaces on the the sex toys it's just
really easy to extract the forever and
to a little bit of more research on the
firmware ok so you might now think I
still want to use smart sex toys what
can I do
yeah the tinfoil is not working
but there are a lot of interesting
open-source projects out there so first
of all the most famous project is the
Internet of dongs project there is a
really interesting person behind it he
is called render man you can find him on
Twitter he invented this project to make
this whole internet of thongs a little
bit safer and he's doing like
penetration tests and stuff like that
and he's even even handing out DVDs so
that's the equivalent to CVS then we
have butt plug to dial and Mehta fetish
they are developing open source firm
versus for a lot of different sex toys
and they are independent from all the
manufacturers and there is also
something called onion till tonics with
which which has the goal of rerouting
all the smarts extra traffic over the
Tor network to make it a little bit more
safer
[Music]
okay there is one more thing I had a lot
of calls together with the manufacturer
and the chairman said pund and one call
was outstanding because we were
discussing the remote pleasure
vulnerabilities and we tried to explain
the manufacturer that it's not good that
you can basically out of the box
pleasure everyone on the internet or if
you nearby we told them that it should
be at least like an opt-in feature where
you can switch on this feature in the
apps but the manufacturers said no
that's not possible because at least
they believe that most of our customers
I read smear clips and you don't know
beforehand who is in the swing a club so
there is just no opt-in in a swing club
because you're basically always in yeah
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
taking questions we have five
microphones two in the front and three
in the back so please sign up and ask
whatever you want so apparently people
on Twitter engaged in a drinking game
where they were drinking every time you
said penetration in the meantime we have
a question from microphone number two
yeah did you come across anything with
the patent trolls in teledildonics I
came across what sorry patent trolls
there is a issue with teledildonics
patent and some companies have been
threatened to go out of business because
of frivolous lawsuits yes yes there was
I guess it was called teledildonics
appreciation day in august because the
patent ended so you can basically use
the term wherever you want or yeah thank
you microphone number three please
so this was very funny of this leap and
you showed us the really low-hanging
fruit on the website in the database you
would have been able to see the social
graph of the users I don't know if you
have managed to look at other devices
can you elaborate a little bit more on
something that I believe more serious
which is the profiling of users behavior
social networks and so on so of course
it didn't took a look at all the data
because it was a critical map unions
that directly contacted the chaplain so
I can't give you any information about
the data of course I also took a look at
like things like tracking and stuff like
that and in this case there was not a
lot of tracking going on at the German
sex toys but when you compared it to the
Chinese sex toys there is way more
tracking and stuff like that going on
but it didn't took like a detailed look
into that okay thanks thank you
thank you again for their educational
and entertaining talk and hopefully
[Applause]
[Music]