[Music]
hello everybody a warm welcome to our
friend Nicholas Madrid from this
innovation talk they are making
contemporary art with research and
hacking to question the positive
ideology for technology to stimulate a
past growth technology narrative so I'm
quite interested and give him a warm
welcome
hello everyone how does it work
can you hear me hello and together with
Mayakovsky we initiated this new vision
tour collective and our collective
intent reveal and challenge the dominant
ideology of technological innovation and
circulate alternative narratives so I
will show you a selection of projects
and mainly it's a few project selected
to resonate with the CCC and the topics
here so we do basically creation so we
organized a festival and we create art
species in different surveys of project
around basically at the rhetoric of
technological innovation and the effect
of this dominant ideology on society we
also work on the publication in books I
will get back to that in a minute
and we do artworks and site-specific
projects but I will present in the
second half of this talk so the first
part will be focusing on our curatorial
practices around this idea of content
narratives on technological innovation
so I will introduce three works and the
first one is the pirate
so it's a book we started to compile in
2014 and 2040
it's a computational of stories about
sharing and distributing distributing
cultural content outside the boundaries
of local economies politics
laws religions and so on so with this
work we try to explore the notions such
as the diversity of necessity the idea
of new originals and I think it's
interesting to go back to this project
to come back to this project in the
context context of the Anthropocene and
the potential imminent collapse because
I think there is a need for non
technology honest and non-technical
stories at the moment and somehow I need
to develop post growth narratives so we
will see what we can learn from the
following examples taken from the book
around concerns like repair care
maintenance and creative appropriation
so the first excerpt from the book I
would like to focus on is an example
from Mexico given by our contributor yet
I see our dough and basically it focuses
on the stories of craftsmen that works
for improving the practices of street
vendors in Mexico so we'll I will play a
quick excerpt of it
[Music]
so it cannot smoke a moment that's
because a kid I borrow and I will say
those realistic kicker person today's
the last class Mussina's como una otra
vez de tiempo
it's a spiritual venus de las personas
que que temos Ignotus she was Kate oven
and in Metro K kilos coupon para Kanta
it was IE p salon de del movimiento de
las docenas a chi mexico location el
sistema de transporte
colectivo Metro it says nosotros in
every instance Luca drama drama
Lamas practical Damascus in present oh
listen always given a service tenant of
today's sales usuarios
[Music]
the hundreds of illuminated Hamas and
Fatah camo since 2002 when the servicing
of those posters in this ocasion
rectangular beta disco compact oh and
for mass of mana disco from particle
contain everything on the state marks da
Vinci cocoon
cover multiple stories in the sword we
just focus on a couple of those the
second one is based in style it's a
contribution by Christopher quickly and
it's presenting basically a big part of
music distribution in style is down
through copies between the dumb phones
using bluetooth so it's a way somehow to
create a circulation of contents by
nearest-neighbor dynamics basically and
the third example I would like just to
introduce his alpaca to Simon now
basically it's in the context of Cuban
lack of fast internet or Internet at all
basically alpaca test seminar is a sort
of substitute to the Internet in the
form of a package it's not right as you
can see here and this harddrive also
circulates one copy at a time and it's
basically compilation of all the
contents that is considered to be
missing for people so you can see on
this hard drive TV shows books movies
music and all the sorts of content you
could expect from an internet browsing
experience so you can find this book
online for free and we cover many of the
stories but tonight I will just present
those and connect with this last
contribution by klimova know he did long
term six years research in China and he
shared with us this story about a
Shanghai technology production it's
basically something between piracy in
hybrid ation in a Chinese manufacturing
and I will focus on this one a little
bit more so in
article climber Renault described the
specific local tech innovation named
Shanghai the Shanghai culture is a mix
of piracy DIY and anti-establishment it
literally means a mountain fortress and
it comes from a novel from the 13th
century that tells the story of a group
of outlaws that that hides in the
mountain to be outside the system and
outside the regulation of the state
basically so in a more Western context
Shanghai refers basically to
manufacturing it emerged in the 50s for
instance in Hong Kong to describe a
small-scale factories that we're
producing cheap low-quality items and
mainly Cointreau fate products of famous
brands like Gucci or Nike and they sold
those product on markets that will not
buy the fancy expensive originals and as
electronic manufacturing emigrated to to
Shenzhen in the early 2000 this informal
network of Shanghai production found
perfect products in the mobile phone so
our first acquisition in this collection
was basically the gonna phone and we've
been very intrigued by this this device
so basically this device is has not been
conceived for its superficial design but
it's it's been conceived to fill a gap
and need or a niche market so this phone
is a power bank basically to fill the
gap of the frequent power cuts in Ghana
but it's also so it has a battery that
can last for a week you can also charge
other devices with it recharge a
computer know the phone you can also use
it as a light
so that's why you have a hook to connect
it on the on the ceiling and basically
it's a wall package of functions and
properties that were designed
specifically for local markets
that's know any brands we're paying
attention at so we were very interested
by this track of research and we wanted
to dig some more so we started with a
simple protocol we started to collect
hybrid phones that were combining
multiple functions and design for those
niche markets all over the place mainly
in the global South but not only you
will see so you can find lots of fancy
and weird devices the table show and
those devices we've been collecting them
in markets in changin like what's on Bay
and also online like on Taobao
Aliexpress and so on so one of the
reasons that we wanted to focus our
research on mobile phones because some
giant production is not only about
Mobile's it's about every kind of
technology I would say but we we kind of
want it to stick to one sort of device
to have this continuity over 20 years
and also because somehow a huge contrast
could be seen through the mobile phone
between sort of nor FEMA sphere culture
or just somehow the standardized culture
of the the black rectangle we all have
in our pockets here and this kind of non
normalized technological imaginaries
that were emerging there and somehow it
reminds us a thing that other
technological possibilities always exist
beyond the ultra normalized industry so
I will dig into a few of those so each
of those example I think tell a specific
story and we will
specific uses and cultures so here you
can see a lighter phone so it's
basically founded those cigarette
lighter this one is a I would say
working cigarette pack that also
includes a mobile phone or perhaps the
other way around
mr. Silvester policy here
yeah
[Music]
and this one is a race of fun so it's a
phone that includes a walking shaver so
since 2015 we've been collecting about
hundreds of those hybrid phones and I
will zoom into a few of very interesting
specimens and stories so here you can
see the card phone is the size of the of
a credit card it used to be the cheapest
on the market it cost about $12 and it's
made of a single board so basically it
can be very easily replicated and
optimized modified and so on and so
that's why it's been called the Ganga
phone which means open source and you
can find this board in multiple versions
in the later generation of phones I will
present in a minute
so this one is called the Buddha phone
it's been designed as a digital
alternative for Buddhist prayers and
related religious activities so
basically it replicates for instance the
ritual components like the burning of
incense purification rites meditative
music and more so all of those features
are included in basically the uux of the
phone
[Music]
so this is the sound system phone it's
been designed for mainly the elderly
people so the favorite one of the
favorite activities of the elderly in
China is group dancing on the big square
in evenings and this specific phone has
been designed for this purpose so it
comes with several gigabytes of
old-fashioned communist songs that
Chinese pensioners are particularly keen
on it it has a huge buttons I mean it's
really designed for elderlies so the
device is like that size and there is
also supports to stand in front of the
dancers and a powerful light torch to
ensure a smooth return home after the
dance about twenty in two minutes
because they available in most of the
visit halls you can't take something
that might not be there because if you
do is they're gonna notice it different
I'd say that there's probably 75% of
prisoners have fangs in in jail I'll
take that in I'm a person and places
that you wouldn't get searched your
front of your trousers in your bra so
this one is the prisoner phone or it's
also called bit the bus the bus is a
device for scanning prisoners so it's
actually it's it started on the market
as the smallest phone on the market but
for some reason it became popular among
prisoners mainly in the UK because of
the it's small size it's the size of a
finger and because of the factor so it's
composed of 99% of plastic so it's Bolly
detectable doing the checks in prisons
and you can easily smuggle it inside
food inside the body obviously but also
in weird ways like inside using drones
carrier pigeons rats and so on so we try
to exhibit all this collection of weird
devices in their natural habitat in a
way so we built a reproduction of a
street market kiosk where we basically
showcase this collection of hybrid
phones and together with that we have a
couple of video documentaries like this
one that kind of tells the larger Shan
Zhai culture and focus on Chinese
ecosystem of technological device
production and distribution so that's
how it look when it's shown
yeah that's it for this one and the last
cultural project I'd like to introduce
is a work in progress it's called the
Museum of failures and I will start with
a quote by Paul V radio powerlessness
before the upsurge of unexpected
catastrophic events forces us to reverse
the usual trends which exposes last to
accidents and inaugurate a new kind of
news ology and music rafi one which
consists in exposing or exhibiting the
accident all accidents from the most
commonplace to the most tragic from
natural catastrophes to industrial and
scientific disasters including also the
kind that is too often neglected the
happy accident the stroke of luck the
coup de foudre or even the coup de
Grasse so as you could guess with this
quote this project is about uncovering
and compiling continuities about the
history of technological innovation and
our project is basically to compile
those under-represented stories that can
help us to disrupt the dominant
positivist discourse on innovation and
help us maybe to think about technology
in post growth era so the project takes
the shape of workshop conferences
add-ins and we share it as a database
and exhibitions so this symbolic museum
is structured in two floors they go in
negative numbers there are somehow the
underground counterparts of usual
technological museum so each floor is a
potential sort of entry or perspective
on the museum sorted by topics so you
have like intentional failures fiction
in dystopias risk and disasters
unexpected outcomes and so on
so the first part of this future book is
a collection of about about that project
flops errors malfunctions business
failures ethical rejections disasters
and the somehow reflect the outlines of
our society from a historical symbolic
poetic and cultural point of view the
second part of this book though will be
based on interviews and contributions
and we are open to proposals so if you
have stories or research on post graph
technological missionaries and content
narratives on technological innovation
you're welcome to submit ok so the
second part of this talk will be about
our artworks specific selection to
resonate with the CCC as well and we
grouped it into this idea of
psychoanalysis of the hyper-connected
era so the first artwork I will
introduce is the pirate in the mouth
basically the copy culture got
mainstream with BitTorrent and the
Pirate Bay in the early 2000 and it
became an essential part of culture for
a world generation and at the same time
as this process since the early days of
peer-to-peer it coexisted with an
intense level of Serbians
so this surveillance was conducted by
universities cooperation states
sometimes for statistical purposes just
for you know to know how much is
consumed from different type of contents
and so on and most of the time for
copyright infringement and we got very
interested in how we could disrupt those
systems of network surveillance
basically and use it revealed dynamics
and the materiality of peer-to-peer
file-sharing so basically to expose the
Mauri
materiality of this process and
geographical dynamics of the content
that were consumed and shared
so we'll show a few excerpt of this
project
[Music]
so we programmed the server to use a
BitTorrent and to synchronize every
morning with the top 100 videos of The
Pirate Bay
so it's sort of a man-in-the-middle
attack where we see what people are
sharing through our server so it's a
it's a way to view the global dynamics
as through one node of the BitTorrent
Network and as you can see on the video
it also reveals the user IP address and
the countries and somehow it's a way to
depict the geographical dynamics of
media sharing and consumptions the next
project I'd like to introduce following
this idea of continuities it's serious
about illicit contents
it's called blacklist so we got
interested in basically controls and
decides what should be visible or not
online or what should be blocked or not
and all those lists are built and used
and somehow how maybe it can be
something that reveals the value system
we live in so there are numerous
blacklist you can subscribe to more less
efficient and up-to-date squid blacklist
shallowest cisco and so on and some
other reminds us literally of the index
of forbidden books that used to exist in
libraries around the globe it was a list
basically of publication considered
heretical immoral or anti-clerical and
you know in an internet blacklist
nowadays you have pretty much the same
so addresses that can be blocked they
are organized into categories as you can
see here and as a season mean you can
decide what type of content you want to
block so in such lists are used by
University
towns airports companies individuals and
so on and it helps you basically to
restrict the access to a specific
specific content on your network so you
have categories like copyright porn
pharmacy and so on and you can see weird
stuff like feminists for instance and I
guess it reveals the the for-profit
nature of this list and the fact that
anything can be requested if enough
clients are asking for it so this work
took the shape of sort of innocent
encyclopedia in certain volumes of 666
pages
it's basically an encyclopedia of
illicit and filter websites when it is a
structure like an order phone book it's
sort of ready-made that reveals the
mobile sort of portraits or framework of
the web the directory of the
prohibitions of the internet deployed in
the form of an encyclopedia in 13
volumes of 666 pages each it is an
extensive collection of restricted
websites used for the automatic
filtering of traffic considered a listed
on licenses
just like the intent of forbidden
libraries the black lists project points
out the sidelining of online content
that could be dangerous for the very
survival of the system with around 2
million websites extracted from
commercial content control software's
this collection reveals the cultural
social and ideological model of our
society through what has been deemed
unfit for consultation by specific
groups and institutions around the globe
so I guess you get the idea
all right so this next work is a
predictive at-bat and I will need to
contextualize a bit so basically we live
in the era of hyper-connectivity
and the time we spend on phone and
social media has radically increased
over the last 10 years and this has a
strong effect on us online news and
communication tends to monopolize a lot
of our attention and it does as a
growing influence on our types of
concerns and priorities so we know about
effects like filter bubble media key to
echo chambers and to some extent the
influence of social media and hyper
connection tend towards a sort of
uniformization not only of our concerns
but also somehow of our innovation and
creativity and it tends to have the
higher chance of predictability of our
behaviors so stunning basically
sustaining from from the art field we
started to notice somehow similar
patterns amongst the artists around us
so we spotted numerous similar
imaginaries similar trends in each
interest groups and we started to
observe similar topics similar ideas and
even similar ways of realizing artworks
and answering to ideas and concerns so
at some point we're like do we really
need artists to simply follow the trends
and we need artists to to just
illustrate the latest technical
technological bells may be now so that's
where the project started with this
simple question and we decided to
automatize the process of mainstream
creativity we could say and to push it
toward sort of of the absurd so to do
that we created a but and this but
basically subscribed to hundreds of
Eris's feet that's the sort of feeds we
will get ourselves on our Twitter feed
you know
so we basically subscribed the but to
the same
and then the butt is using some PM
library to try to identify the most
significant keyword in the headlines and
those keywords are stored and then we
organized using Treasury in a sort of
general tree of poetry to create
potential concepts for art works and
those concept are we posted on Twitter
and different places to basically create
a new weird inspiration machine that's
what you will see now that turns the
latest media headlines into artistic
concepts in the age of hyper
connectivity the perverse implications
of media echo chambers are becoming more
and more obvious groups of similar
behaviors are being partitioned in
filter bubbles while the few massively
reposted topics tends to monopolize most
of the available attention such insular
echo chambers strongly affect ways of
thinking resulting in increasingly
homogeneous imaginaries within groups of
like-minded people
predictive art bought caricatures the
predictability of media influenced
artistic concepts by automating and
skirting the human creative process but
beyond mere automation it aims to
stimulate unbridled counterintuitive and
even disconcerting associations of ideas
to do so it continually monitors
emerging trends among the most
influential new sources and fields as
heterogeneous as politics environment
innovation culture activism or help on
this basis it identifies and combines
keywords to generate concepts of
artworks in a fully automated way
ranging from unreasonable to prophetic
through absurd each prediction becomes a
thought experiment waiting to be
incubated misused or appropriated by a
human
host okay and we also commissioned a few
artists to interpret and I realize those
projects a few times
okay the last project for tonight I see
that it's almost time for me so the last
project is a map and it's a work in
progress for a future long term project
and basically it focuses on the fact
that the web has become one of the most
impactful vehicle for the propagation of
ideas and culture and hyper-connectivity
did intensify the rise of online
politics and made it way easier to
manipulate public opinions and I mean
this happened as a sort of unpleasant
unprecedent at the scale so you know
we've seen the emergence of political
bots fake accounts for farm and so on
but today I will focus on the cultural
aspect of this battleground so one of
the important aspect of online culture
wars that we were trying to map is
perhaps this notion of transgression so
as one of the Trump supporter million
applause used to say conservatism is the
new bank and think about how the culture
will change and change very rapidly and
and in a very short space of time the
dissident element in culture Punk
mischief irreverence is now better
representative politics bio make America
great again hat then buy anything unless
if you want to annoy somebody you want
to piss your parents off if you want to
eject it from polite society as this
poor angel has been there is no better
way to do it than to cast a vote for
Donald Trump this is the new pump
Republican is the new cool thank you for
coming
[Applause]
so in the context of the political
correctness and self-censorship too big
shaming that we're curing a lot in the
the left this obscure style of sort of
iconic cynical mockery emerge as a sort
of counter force and frustration made
the alt-right attractive in a way in
this transmissive online culture is well
presented in the book of Angela Nagel I
call the kill or no means all together
in their obscurity was a love of mocking
the earnestness and moral self flattery
of what felt like a tired liberal
intellectual conformity running right
through from establishment liberal
politics to the more militant enforcers
of new sensitivities and from the
wackiest corners of tumblr to campus
politics so basically this this culture
of transmission aligns pretty well with
what is called a weaponized meme so a
weaponized meme is when internet memes
becomes part of political in the
ideological propaganda it can be done by
the right but as well by all the
political spectrum like here to fight
homophobia in Russia and as a starting
point for this new series of project
went we wanted to create a kind of 9 map
of the emerging online culture wars so
we use this classical political compass
as a framework I mean it's a framework
that has been criticized a lot but
nonetheless it became popular as a
format to exchange content on online
forums and on the memo sphere and it
often integrates non-political
characters and pop preferences and so on
so after studying numerous critical
researches on the topic like the
computational propaganda project on
Jelani girl florian kramer and so on and
also were on investigations we started
to assemble a sort of category of
weaponized meme elements with the help
of baruch got
the online culture wars project offers a
provisional cartography of weaponized
meme elements using a speculative
political distribution taking the
political compasses of framework this
cartography offers a symbolic
representation of online ideological and
political debates in the context of a
growing polarization and ridiculous
ation this sever volume chart is the
result of a superposition of hundreds of
politicized memes found online in
addition to influential political
symbols actors and influencers it is
designed as the discussion starter
intended to expose and contextualize the
present battlefield of online culture
wars so we are currently continuing this
map as an interactive contributing
webpage well this was a quick selection
of our all the new works that somehow
resonate with the CCC and thank you for
your attention
a big Sangma class
are there any questions to necklace
there is microphone one hi
Congrats beautiful presentation Thanks
I'm curious what's what have you never
dared doing what's your next step
I think it's correlated somehow yeah
yeah yeah so as I said this last project
is a sort of a starting point for a new
series of investigation and research and
at the moment we are accumulating a lot
of document on online propaganda and
online influence and we're starting a
new series of online performance using
and basically challenging those
strategies for the manipulation of
opinions so we are yeah trying to
develop our own propaganda strategies
basically are there any questions from
the internet
No yeah then a big warm applause for
thanks for Niklas
[Applause]
[Music]
you