hello everyone my name is yuyu wang
i'm from uestc our title is
impossibility on tampa resident
cryptography with uniqueness properties
it's a joint work with takashi master
first we record the temperature model
improving security of a cryptographic
scheme we usually assume that the keys
are perfectly protected
however in the real world an anniversary
may change the keys by executing
tampering attacks such as heating up
devices
and injecting votes and the adversary
may
observe the cipher texts or the
signatures
generated by the tempered keys
then the anniversary may get some extra
advantage to breed the security
there have been many examples of
successful tampering attacks
such as the ones on rsa
des and aes and we want to consider the
tempering model which captures these
attacks
there have been several positive results
which show the existence of temporal
resilient primitives in the common
reference stream model
in this model the adversary can temper
with both the public keys
and the secret keys in any way it wants
but
it's assumed that there are tamper-proof
common reference strings
however it's still unclear whether we
can have secure schemes in the plane
model
where we do not assume any tamper-proof
crs
in this work we show that it's
impossible to derive the temporal
resilience of
a broad class of primitives from any
karma assumption
by black box reductions
before going to more details we first
defined two extremely
weak security notions the first one is
weak comfortability
which holds if the adversaries cannot
forge a message signature pair without
seeing any use for information
even including the verification key
one can easily see that the security
notion is
weaker than the standard security
notions such as the cms security
the rms security the one-time cma and
the one-time rma
the second one is weak one winners which
is the same as standard one witness
except that we don't give the public key
to the adversary
and it's obvious that this security is
strictly weaker than standard one
witness
now we give more details on which class
of primitives we consider
first our negative results capture two
types of signatures
which are unique signature and signature
with the unique signing keys
here we require that the signatures
should satisfy the weak
unforgettability but this requirement is
very natural since the security is
extremely weak
as we explained before
for unique signature there exists only
one valid signature
for each pair of verification key and
message
and for signatures with unique signing
key
there exists only one valid signing key
for each verification key
it captures many instantiations such as
the elgama signature and
the dsa and the signature
we also obtained negative results on
injective one-way functions
verifiable random functions and also pke
with
unique message satisfying weak one
winners
similar to the case of we comfortability
any meaningful pke should satisfy weak
one winners
here by pku with unique messages we mean
that for each ciphertext
all the value secret keys of the same
public key lead to the same decryption
result
as examples we showed how it captures
the grammarship scheme
and all the unique key pke schemes in
our paper
and in this presentation we will focus
on the negative results
on unix signature for simplicity
we now define temporal resilience in the
plane model
since we consider negative results in
this work the weaker the security is
the stronger our results are
an adversary in this model consists of
three parts
which are temper brick one and brick two
they are not allowed to communicate with
each other
temper is a selective tempering function
which takes as input a public key a
secret key
and outputs a temper key sk prime
brick 1 takes as input public key and
makes a signing query which is m
brick 2 takes as input the public key or
signature generated by a temporary
signing key and
tries to forge your message signature
pair if the probability that the
forgery is valid is negligible and
the message in the forgery is not the
sending query
then the temporary resiliency in the
play model is set to be satisfied
one can see that the security is very
weak
since we only allow the adversary to
temper with the key once
and make only one signing query but
again
since we only consider the negative
results the weaker
it is the stronger our results are
we now recall the blackbox reduction
from comma assumptions to temporal
resilience
the reduction has black box access to
the adversary and can make queries
adaptive
in any order to the three components of
the adversary
if by making use of a successful
adversary the reduction breaks the
underlying assumption successfully
then we can conclude that the temporal
resilience holds
under the assumption
we now give the intuition on how we show
impossibility on
black box reduction for temporary
sealing to unix signatures
to show this we just have to prove that
the reductions do not
benefit from having access to the
adversary
we consider two cases in the first case
the reduction gives correct keys to the
first component which is timbre
in this case the reduction already knows
the sending key and it can forge the
signature by himself
and due to uniqueness this signature
computed by reduction should be the same
as the one generated by brick two
thus the adversary does little help to
the reduction
and the reduction can break the
underlying assumption by himself
which gives us the conflicts
we now consider the case that the
reduction does not give the valid keys
to the adversary
in this case the keys may not pass the
verification by the adversary
and then the adversary does not have to
give a temporary key
to the reduction in this case
the reduction will learn no information
on sk prime
which is the temporary key
then due to the weak comfortability of
the unique signature
the reduction cannot answer the signing
query correctly
since the reduction cannot simulate the
view of the adversary now
the adversary does not have to give a
valid forgery
to the reduction as a result the
reduction cannot use the adversary in a
meaningful way
this is the intuition of our idea and
to show the strict proof we have to take
care of two points
the first one is that the reduction can
make adaptive queries to the three
components in any order and the second
one
is that we have to find a way for tamper
which is the first component
to check the validity of the keys
to give the formal proof we use the
framework of simulatable attacks by
weeks
in this framework we first need to
construct a computationally unbounded
adversary to break the temporal
residence
then we define a simulator which runs in
polynomial time
but is indistinguishable with the
adversary
notice that the simulator doesn't have
to run
in a legal way it just have to simulate
the anniversary it doesn't have to
follow the game
the distinction can make adaptive
queries for any times
and in any order
and if the simulatable attacks exist
which means that if we can construct the
adversary
and the simulator then there exists
no black box reductions from standard
assumptions
the reason is that if there exists a
reduction
that breaks the assumption by having
black box access to the adversary
then it can also break the underlying
assumption by having access to the
simulator
which runs in polynomial time this means
that the online assumption can be broken
in polynomial time
which gives us the conflict
we now show how we construct the
adversary
the three components of the adversary
share a random function
in the start of the game and cannot
share any common state anymore
all the three components compute fpk to
obtain the random coins
which are rg rs m star
and m rg is used to generate the
tempered keys
rs is used to forge the signature
m star is the message in the forgery and
m is the signing query
tamper will check the validity of keys
by checking whether the signature for m
star generated by using the random coin
rs and the secret key sk can pass the
verification
if the check works then temper generates
sk prime by making use of the random
coin rg notice that
pk and sk do not have to be a valid key
pair
for any message they just have to be
valid for the message m stop
then break two checks whether the
signing query is correctly responded
if the check works it uses brute force
to search the value signature sigma star
which passes the verification
due to correctness the adversary must
be able to break the temporal residence
if the challenger runs in an honest way
we now consider the communication
between the distinguisher
and the adversary if the key is given by
the distinguisher did not pass the
verification by temper
then the distinguisher will learn no
information on pk prime and
sk prime
in this case no matter how the
distinction makes queries
it cannot answer the sending queries due
to unique
unforgettability and then break 2 will
not forge the signature by using brute
force
this means that we can simulate the
adversary easily
in polynomial time
we now consider the case that the
distinguisher
has given keys passing the verification
in this case to simulate the adversary a
simulator does not have to use brute
force as well
it just uses sk which is given by the
distinguisher
to generate a forged signature
the forge signature must pass the
verification
the reason is that we have checked the
validity
of the secret key which is skb4
also the signature which is sigma star
generated by the simulator will be the
same as the one
generated by the adversary by making use
of brute force
this is because of the uniqueness of the
signature
and this will hold no matter in which
order the distribution query read
as a result we can simulate the
unbounded adversary
in polynomial time anyway which means
that
the simulator attack exists
now we give the conclusion this
presentation shows that
there exists a simulatable attack for
unique signatures
this means that it's impossible to
prove temporal resilience for unique
signatures by black box reductions
in similar ways we can also construct
simulatable attacks for signature with
unique signing key
pke with the unique message verifiable
random function
and injective line with functions which
means that
it's impossible to derive the temporal
resilience of these primitives via black
box reductions
thank you for your attention