hi everyone i'm henrik walter and this
talk is about multi-client function
encryption for superable functions which
is joint work with michaela chumpy and
louisa finiscalci
let's start with some motivation let's
consider the example where we have two
encrypted documents
and now we want to allow two different
parties dave and aaron to do some
analysis over these documents
dave wants to know how many times the
word pkc occurs in both of these files
together
and aaron wants to learn how many times
the word crypto appears in both of these
files together
additionally we want to allow two other
parties alice and bob
to be responsible for providing the
different documents
so alice would be in charge of providing
the first file and bob responsible for
providing the second file
we additionally require that the
evaluation of aaron and dave
happens in a privacy preserving way that
means that they should only learn how
many times their requested word appears
in both of these documents together
and nothing beyond that in the next
steps we are going to see what
cryptographic primitives we can use to
achieve this goal
one primitive that might be useful in
this scenario is public key encryption
in public key encryption a setup
algorithm outputs a public key and a
secret key
the public key can then be used by alice
to encrypt the message x
and bob can use the secret key to
decrypt the ciphertext and obtain the
message x
the problem of this notion with respect
to our use case
is that it is not possible to allow for
any fine-grained access control over
x bob either learns x completely or
nothing
a notion that allows for this
fine-grained access control is the
notion of functional encryption which
was introduced by bonesahi and waters in
2011.
in a function encryption scheme the
setup algorithm outputs a master public
key and a master secret key
the master public key can then be used
in the same way as before
by alice to encrypt the message the
master secret key though is not directly
used to decrypt cipher text but to
generate so-called functional keys
every functional key is associated with
a function f
and if bob uses such a functional key to
decrypt the cipher text
he learns the function evaluation of the
function associated with the key
applied on the underlying message
security in such a scheme ensures that
bob learns nothing beyond the specific
function evaluation
this notion can also be considered in
the secret key setting
where the setup algorithm only outputs a
master secret key
that is then used for the encryption and
functional key generation
functional encryption provides us with
the fine grained access control that we
need for our use case
it remains a problem that only single
input functions can be evaluated
a more generalized notion that allows
for the evaluation of multi-input
functions is the notion of multi-input
function encryption
introduced by goldwater all in 2014.
here a functional key can be generated
for example for a two-input function
and bob can use this key together with
two different cipher texts containing
the messages x1 and x2
to obtain f of x1 x2 these two
ciphertexts are generated using
different encryption keys output by the
setup procedure to alice and carol
a problem with this notion is that if
alice and carol create more
ciphertexts of for example the message
x1 prime and x2 prime
bob can not only compute f x1 prime x2
prime
but also f of x1 prime x2 and f of x1
x2 prime a notion that prevents this
leakage is the notion of multi-client
function encryption
in multi-client function encryption
alice and carol use encryption labels
for every ciphertext that they generate
this allows bob to only obtain a valid
decryption for two cipher texts that
have been generated under the same label
otherwise he learns nothing we can see
that this notion prevents the previously
mentioned computation
since bob is not able to compute f of x
1 prime x 2
or f x 1 x 2 prime if the corresponding
cipher texts have been generated using
different encryption labels
in this talk we mainly focus on the
specific function class of the parabola
functions
separable functions are functions that
can be written as the sum of any
individual single input functions
applied on all the different inputs so
in this case bob receives a function a
key corresponding to the separable
function
such that he can learn f1 of x1 plus f2
of x2
this function class is a good match for
our word count example
and allows a function evaluator to learn
the desired information
in this work we show how to realize
multi-client function encryption for
separable functions from secret key
single input function encryption
in the setting of multi-client function
encryption a drawback still remains
the requirement of a trusted party that
is responsible for the setup of the
parameters
and the generation of the functional
keys a notion that operates without a
trusted party is the notion of
decentralized multi-client function
encryption
introduced by shotar at al in a
decentralized multi-client function
encryption scheme
alice and kerola interacting with each
other to generate their own encryption
and secret keys
they can then use their secret keys to
generate functional key shares
that can then be combined to obtain the
full functional key this functional key
can then be used by bob in the usual
manner
in this setting the computations of the
trusted party are completely transferred
to alice and carol
and therefore the trusted party is not
needed anymore
in this talk we are also going to show
how the multi-client function encryption
scheme that we present
can be decentralized now we recap
previous works focusing on
transformations of single input function
encryption schemes
to multi-input and multi-client schemes
the first work in this area is the work
of prokaryote from 2016
in which the authors show how to turn a
secret key single input function
encryption scheme
for general function class into a
multi-input function encryption scheme
with a constant number of inputs this
result was extended one year later by
komargotsky and zegf
allowing for a polylogarithmic number of
inputs
in another line of work by abdullah al
the authors show how to lift the secret
key single input function encryption
scheme
for the inner product functionality into
a multi-input scheme
additionally it has been shown in
another work by abdallah and al
how this scheme can be decentralized in
a follow-up work by abdullah bin hamudah
and gay
the authors extend the previous
construction and allow for handling
labels
instead of a secret key single input
function encryption scheme the authors
here need to rely on a public key scheme
their scheme can also be decentralized
as previously mentioned in this work we
show how to transform a secret key
single input function encryption scheme
for general function class into a
multi-client function encryption scheme
for the parable functions
we also show how our construction can be
decentralized
additionally we introduce a new notion
of multi-client function encryption that
allows for distributed execution of the
decryption procedure
now we present our construction for the
specific case of four parties
a trivial solution that someone could
think of to obtain multi-client function
encryption for
variable functions is by simply running
four different instances of a single
input scheme
and whenever a key for the separable
function is requested
a key for the individual function under
each of the single input instances
is generated the final functional key
then
consists of all the keys of the single
input schemes
the decryption procedure for the
multi-client scheme then executes the
decryption procedure of all the single
input schemes
using the different keys and sums up all
the resulting values
the problem with this solution is that
we have an instance-wise leakage of the
function evaluation
that means that the decryptor not only
learns the evaluation of the separable
function
but also the evaluation of each of the
individual single input functions
so for the case of the word count
example the decryptor will not only
learn how many times the requested word
appears in all of the documents
but also how many times it appears in
every single document
therefore we need to adapt the
construction to prevent the individual
leakage
by hiding the evaluations of the
different single input functions
to achieve this we can rely on a secret
sharing scheme of zero
more detail instead of letting each
function key simply output the
evaluation of the single input function
the key generator generates a secret
sharing of 0 and hard codes one of the
shares
raf into each of the individual keys
when the individual keys are then
evaluated they output the evaluation of
the single input function
plus the share rif summing up all of the
outputs of the individual keys
then gives the desired separable
function evaluation and as long as the
decrypter does not have any knowledge
about the different shares
nothing about the single input function
evaluation is leaked
a related problem occurs for the
generation of the ciphertexts
in the current construction the
encryption labels are not affecting the
decryption
in any way which means that it is still
possible to decrypt ciphertext generated
under different encryption labels
one might think that we can also solve
this problem using a secret sharing of
xero
but the issue is that the different
clients need to agree on the secret
sharing whenever they want to encrypt
the ciphertext
under a new encryption label and there
is no single party that can sample this
secret sharing
therefore we need a non-interactive
solution such that the parties can agree
on a new secret sharing of zero
for every label on the fly to do this we
borrow a technique from abdullah bin
hamudah and gay
this technique works in the following
way we start by considering a more
complicated way to generate a secret
sharing of zero
where the clients have different shared
values with each other
in more detail the client c1 shares rl12
with client c2
rl13 with client c3 and so on
we can then display the shared values
between the clients in this
anti-symmetric matrix
to generate the secret shares of zero
one simply needs to sum up the shared
values in the columns of the matrix
so client c1 for example computes minus
rl12 minus rl13
minus il14 to obtain its share t1l
we can see that this is indeed a valid
secret sharing of 0 since every value
occurs only one time positive and one
time negative inside this matrix
we can also see that summing up only a
subset of the columns of the matrix does
not yield zero
to allow for the non-interactive
generation of several secret sharings we
need to
allow the parties to agree on such a
matrix for every label
l on the fly abdallah and i'll achieve
this by letting the parties share
pairwise prf keys with each other
which can then be used to generate the
different r values
by executing the prf with the
corresponding shared key applied on the
label l
this solution results in a quadratic
blow up of the keys
which means that for any clients we
require n times n
minus 1 divided by two keys overall
using this technique we can now generate
the ciphertext containing the message x
i and the value til generated using the
prf
evaluations of l under the different
keys
to make the scheme work we additionally
need to modify the functional key for
each of the single input instances
to not just output the single input
function evaluation and the hard-coded
secret share
rif but also the value til
furthermore we also need to add the
shared prf keys to the secret keys of
all the different parties
to enable them to generate the t values
for their encryptions
this completes our construction of the
multi-client scheme for separable
functions
the security of our construction can be
shown by relying on the security of the
different primitives
we give a high level overview how the
security of the scheme can be proven
we start by relying on the security of
the prf to argue that the
non-interactive secret shares til
are computationally indistinguishable
from randomly generated shares
in the next step we program the
ciphertext and functional keys in such a
way that they only contain the sum of
the individual function evaluation
the random share raf of the function and
the non-interactive share of the label
til
these program values can then be seen as
a one-time pad encryption of the
individual function evaluation
using the sum of the random share raf
and the non-interactive share til
as the key since the values raf are
different for every function f
and the values til are different from
every label
we obtain a fresh one-time pet key for
every function and label combination
which is sufficient to argue the
indistinguishability of different
ciphertexts
to decentralize our scheme we need to
define function key shares that can be
combined to obtain the complete
functional key
and we need to separate the master
secret key into different secret keys
that can be used to generate these
different functional key shares
the separation of the master secret key
in our scheme is very natural
and the clients can execute the key
exchange protocol
to agree on the different prf keys to
separate the functional key into
different functional key shares
we need to remove the local sampling of
the secret sharing of 0 for every
functional key to achieve this we can
rely again on the prf technique of
abdallah at all
and let the clients generate the secret
sharing for the functional key shares
by evaluating the prf using different
keys on the requested function
this concludes the decentralization of
our construction
in our work we also introduced the
notion of outsourceable multi-client
function encryption
an outsourceable multi-client function
encryption scheme allows to distribute
the decryption procedure
to end different servers that all output
different decryption shares
these decryption shares can then be
combined by the function evaluator to
obtain the final functional output
security in this setting ensures that no
one learns anything about the final
function evaluation who is not in
possession of all the decryption shares
this notion is particularly useful in
use cases where the decryption procedure
is quite computation expensive
more formally in an outsourceable
multi-client function encryption scheme
the key generation procedure outputs
different functional key shares for the
function f
these shares can then be used by the
parties bob and charlie
to execute the partial decryption
procedure and to obtain different
decryption shares
it is noted here that bob who is in
possession of the first part of the
functional key
only needs to execute the partial
decryption on the first cipher text
the same holds for charlie with respect
to the second cipher text
the resulting decryption shares can then
be combined together to obtain the final
output
security here ensures that if not all
the shares are known
nothing about the function evaluation is
leaked
our presented multi-client function
encryption scheme also allows for
outsource ability
by separating the functional key into
different functional key shares
that allow for the generation of
decryption shares
in more detail we output the different
keys for the different single input
function encryption instances to the
different servers
and define the partial decryption
procedure as the decryption procedure of
the single input scheme
the output decryption share is then
blinded using the secret share of the
functional key and the secret share of
the ciphertext label
for the reconstruction of the final
function output the different decryption
shares can then be summed up by the
function evaluator
it is also possible to combine the
notion of decentralization and outsource
ability
to get a decentralized outsourceable
scheme we can decentralize our
outsourceable scheme in the same way as
we decentralized our multi-client scheme
using the prf
generated non-interactive secret shares
in summary we first showed how to obtain
a multi-client function encryption
scheme for separable functions
from a secret key single input function
encryption scheme using
a non-interactive secret sharing scheme
additionally we showed how our
construction can be decentralized by
removing the trusted party for the setup
and key generation
and we also introduced the notion of
outsourceable multi-client function
encryption that allows for a distributed
execution of the decryption procedure
and showed how our construction can be
modified to achieve outsourceability