and you're welcome to get started we're
on youtube now
okay um all right welcome everyone to
the session on functional encryption and
attribute-based encryption
our first speaker is miguel ambrona
who's telling us about generic negation
of pain
encodings yeah thank you
for the introduction
it's been seen properly yeah so
in this work we we propose a generic
negation of pairing codings
and variance codings are a primitive
that is used to build attribute-based
encryption so you know in
attribute-based encryption
everybody can encrypt and when they
when they produce a cipher text out of
their message they are thinking of
certain policy
and the system is such that only those
users who own a secret key
with attributes satisfying the policy
will be able to decrypt the ciphertext
and this secret key has uh been
requested
and has been pro has been provided has
been produced by a master authority
so okay more generally when you encrypt
when you produce a ciphertext
you associate the value x to the
ciphertext every secret key has a
value of y associated and decryption
works only if a predicate between x and
y
holds and there are many techniques
there are many works
for building a full security base
encryption systems
and the the one i'm interested in is
this technique called parent codings
which was introduced by a trapdoor in
2014 and it's a very nice
very nice idea you can focus on building
a pre-encoding
for certain predicate and then
there is a a compiler that gives you a
full security-based encryption
system out of that encoding and this is
very nice because analyzing the encoding
is much simpler than analyzing the
attribute-based encryption
scheme in this talk we focus on very
encoding schemes
and a very natural question is whether
you can transform or combine parent
codings
these are for example some combinations
that that have been considered in the
past
so given a pairing coding scheme for a
predicate p
you can build a paren coding scheme for
its dual predicate
the dual predicate just swaps the rows
of x and y
or if you have two predicating two
pairing codings for two different
predicates you can make one for the
conjunction
this was done by a trapezoid and yamaha
five or six years ago
and you can also do this junction this
junction is very easy but how about
negation so negation seems uh
a lot harder and this was not done
before i have to say that this was done
in a
in a different framework very nice also
introduced by hotec by the way
uh predicate encodings so in this
framework we knew how to generally
negate
a predicate and calling but in the
framework of parent codings which are
believed to be well they actually are
more general
we didn't know how to how to generically
negate them so this is what we do in
this work
so our main contribution is a generic
transformation that takes any parent
coding scheme for predicate p
and produces a new print print coding
for the negated predicate
so along the way we propose an algebraic
characterization of pairing codings that
i believe
can be of independent interest and we
also explore
other other consequences of these
results and this is what i want to
talk a little bit about in the rest of
this presentation
so first of all we found new encoding so
there was this parenchyma scheme by a
trapadon
for the w special encryption predicate
which is this one
and it was unknown how to build
a parenchy scheme for the negated
predicate so negated doubly spatial
encryption
and we can use our transformation we
have it for free
and in fact we can have it for we can
have a dedication of a
any uh parenchy scheme without having to
design it
so i want to say that i'm very grateful
to atrap adam because he's the one who
pointed out that this
this problem was open and it made my
paper
uh much stronger so thank you thank you
so much for that
okay other things i want to mention um
the expressivity of parent codings i
think our new result brings
new non-trivial information about the
expressivity
that can be achieved with parent coding
schemes so for example what i mean
is that the the set of predicates that
we can handle
is closed under negation so one of the
consequences of this
of this observation is that maybe
building a
encoding scheme for context free
languages is harder than we think
because you know context-free languages
are not closed under complementation
so if we could build a brain content
scheme for a context-free language
we would have also apparently scheme for
some for some
class that is strictly more powerful
than context three languages
so this suggests that maybe it's already
hard to achieve
against languages or maybe it's
impossible or with
parent codings given this observation
and other other consequences that we
explore in the paper are potential
performance improvements so
our transformation i didn't i didn't
show how the transformation looks like
but it gives a very specific structure
on the produced encoding and it actually
shows that any encoding can be expressed
in this form
and we explore several ideas that
exploit this
structure to produce a faster
implementation so for example you can
pre-compute
some part that does not depend on the
predicate and and only
perform an unlike online computation on
the part that uh
actually depends on the predicate so it
will be a very interesting direction for
future future work to
to implement and really test whether
these
ideas lead to something so yeah that's
everything i wanted to say thank you so
much
thanks a lot miguel uh we have time for
like a quick question maybe
okay uh so we have a question
from on the chat it looks a bit long but
maybe we can
put it to the end of the session uh
or maybe i can try to read so
right so if you apply your generic
negation transformation to the
uh say the unbounded kp abe formula
constant programs
for uh in the ultra paddle shield 2019
paper
do you get the same scheme as the one
for non-monotone
or is your generic negation different
i guess it's probably different
but i'm not sure
i'm not very familiar with the
framework of dynamic composition
but my guess is it's
very different
okay maybe we can kind of take this to
the left no idea
that's all right i can look at that and
and
and give an answer in a few days to go
over
okay all right uh let's thank miguel and
uh let's proceed to the next talk
uh do we have uh shinran phong around
yeah okay great uh so our next uh
talk is uh master key kdm secure abe via
private
encoding by shinran from and
uh and shinri will give the talk
okay thank you oh let me show my screen
okay so thank you hello everyone
uh i would like to share our work about
the framework of attributes based
encryption with
master key kdm security it's a joint
work with xinjingong and json
and in this work we study the master key
dependent message security for the
find function that is the the encrypted
message
is a file function of a master key and
the
adversary cannot distinguish the key
dependent message
and run the message even obtaining
multiple mismatched
civil texts and secret keys and we use
the notion
of predicating coding which provides a
similar description of the underlying
predicate p
like ib hib abp for
ap for abp so
by concrete encodings we propose the
first m ktm secure hiv schema
and the first mkdm secure abe
schema for abp under standard pairing
based assumption
thanks to the expressiveness we combine
the
classical chk cpa to cca transformation
and obtain cca security
and in the context of ibe
we can also derive an ib schema from our
framework
it enjoys constant size master public
key
and achieve mkdmcca security
um as a start point we first revisit
ggh20 schema and next i will show the
main idea behind our proof
so uh both our schema and ggs schema use
three basis simulating three subgroups
in the composite order
groups and here is the gh20 schema
they showed a clever combination of ktm
secure
pke and tight secure ibe
by the type reduction of ibe lets a
variant of geosystem technical
they can extract the entropy by this
entropy
they can carry out the ktm argument as
in bbh08
but however their proof relies on the
structures of
secret key and cyber text so it's not
general for our schema
in this work we employ another variant
the system technical is slightly
different to the standard using
technical
we first change secret keys and then
change the server text one by one
with another list argument and in final
we change all cyber tags and secret keys
at this point one can control the
leakage of
master secret key and england message
using
the entropy and then carry out the kdm
argument
for pke okay let's all thank you
thank you very much that was a quick
do we have any questions for the speaker
uh let me just quickly check tune it
um maybe i can ask a quick question so
are there specific applications where
you need kdm security
of those schemes oh sorry
my network has some problem can you
repeat your question so do you know
any specific applications where this
property is needed
to gain poor web security
oh i'm not sure about this
sorry anyways yeah i mean it's good to
have but i was wondering whether
it really kind of arises out of specific
applications
the other questions
um okay then maybe we thank thank for
the questions at the end of the session
so i'm going to hand off to my fellow
session chair to introduce the next
speaker
thank you okay so
um hello everyone so the
third talk of this session will be in a
client functional encryption
for separable functions and there are
three authors to that paper
ikelicampi with a siniskal iskalki and
henry corner
and the talk will be given by enrique so
andrix of the
the screen crs thanks for the
introduction
so yeah this talks about multi-client
function encryption for separable
functions
joined with michaela chumpy and lisa
siniskalchi
and in this work we consider the setting
where we have different parties that
provide encrypted documents so we have
alice and bob and both of them provide
some some encrypted documents
and now we want to allow dave and aaron
to do some analysis over these
these documents so in this setting we
want dave dave wants to learn how many
times the word pkc occurs in both of
these documents
and aaron wants to learn how many times
the word crypto appears
in both of these documents and while
allowing for their evaluation we still
want to
preserve the privacy of the encryption
so they should really only learn
their desired word count and nothing
beyond that
and the cryptographic primitives that we
can use to achieve this
is multi-client function encryption for
separable functions
so as a parable function is an n input
function
that can also be evaluated if you
evaluate
n single input functions and applied on
the different inputs and sum up the the
results
and in a multi-client scheme we have a
setup algorithm that outputs
several encryption keys and the master
secret key the encryption keys can then
be used by the by the different clients
to encrypt
their messages together with an
encryption label
and the master secret key is used in a
key generation procedure to generate a
functional keys
and if bob is in possession of such a
functional key
he can compute the function evaluation
of his key applied on the
the plain text encrypted by alice and
carol
and this de decryption only succeeds if
the
the cipher text he uses are generated
with respect to the to the same
encryption label
here in this in this work we show how to
realize multi-client function encryption
for separable function from secret key
single input schemes
and this is basically a similar setting
where the setup algorithm only outputs a
single key that is then used for
the key generation and the encryption
yeah there also exists a decentralized
version of this notion where the
where there's basically no setup
algorithm that is executed by a single
party but
alice and carol do this together
interactively
and then for the generation of
functional keys they can both both
generate different functional key shares
which can then be combined to obtain the
full
functional key yeah in terms of
transformation from
single input function encryption to
multi-client functional encryption there
have
already been some work the first work is
by broadcast get all where they show how
to turn a secret key single input scheme
into a multi-input scheme
the notion of a multi-input is very
similar to the multi-client notion they
have a different security definition
and they don't incorporate encryption
labels
and they do this for a general class of
functions
then there's some some other works on a
more specific function class the inner
products
and there's been a work by abdullah al
where they show how to lift the secret
key single input scheme into
the multi-client setting without labels
and in another follow-up work it has
also been shown how this
scheme can be decentralized
then in another follow-up work the the
previous construction has been extended
to
two labels so it also incorporates
labels and they have to switch from a
secret key single input scheme to a
public key scheme
and yes already mentioned we focus on
the transformation from secret key
single input to
multi-client for separable functions and
we additionally also introduce a new
notion that allows for distributed
execution of the decryption procedure
which we will
see later so yeah how does our
construction
work our construction basically runs in
different instances of a single input
function encryption scheme and when a
functional key for a separable function
is requested
functional keys for all the individual
functions are generated
and these functions then output the
evaluation
together with them with a secret share
of zero so this secret share is used to
to hide the individual function
evaluation
and to prevent the combination from
individual keys with other individual
keys from a different
separable function and we need a similar
property
for incorporating labels in the
ciphertext such that we cannot combine
ciphertext
encrypted under different labels and
here the issue is that this
secret shares cannot be generated by a
single party but the clients have to do
this non-interactively on the fly
and we can accomplish this using a
specific prf technique
so then in the end the individual
functional keys will output the
individual function evaluation
plus the encoded share inside the key
plus the
the share incorporated in the ciphertext
and if all these values are summed up
together the final output can can be
obtained
yeah this this scheme is not yet
decentralized since we we say we
generate these r values
by a single party a single party does
this but we can simply use again this
prf technique to
to also do this in a distributed way
so yeah let me say something about the
notion of outsource ability
so an outsourceable multi-client
function encryption scheme is similar to
a multi-client scheme
with the difference that the key
generation procedure outputs different
functional key shares
which can then be used in a partial
decryption procedure
to generate decryption shares which can
then be combined to obtain
the final output and security here
ensures that these
seek these shares these decryption
shares do not leak anything about
the final function output and this
notion is particularly useful if this
partial decryption procedure is quite
quite heavy such that it can be
outsourced to
someone with more computational power
and our scheme
directly realizes this notion by
justifying the partial decryption
procedure as
the decryption procedure of all the
single input schemes
and then the combination is simply the
sum of all these values
thank you for listening
okay so thank you andrey so um i had a
question for the speaker
um maybe a quick question can you go
back one slide for the where you do the
with the partial decryption so
so i think there's a there's a separate
partial encryption for every
encrypter um i'm curious
what happens if you kind of apply the
decryption immediately
after the encryption but this gives
rises to some
some encryption scheme that that already
exists like that that allows you to
instance to aggregate the results but um
so i wonder whether there's some
relation to existing schemes when you
just combine your encryption decryption
for these individual parties
have you thought about that does it not
makes any sense at all well the the
thing is that then you're already like
kind of
committed to the function right i mean
the advantage here is that you can
uh yes i see that but i suspect that
there are some constructions in the
literature that
that kind of commit to the assumption
for instance are computing just the sum
of the inputs
and that that so that you are a special
case of those constructions
um and i was wondering whether for
instance there are some kind of
aggregation scheme private aggregation
schemes where
which which you would now be a special
case of
yeah probably i mean if you know the the
function previously i don't think why
this should not
should not work
okay any more questions
oh okay so thank you enrique
so let's move to the to the last talk of
this session already
um so the title of the paper is still
composing
computable story hardware based state
full and randomized function encryption
um there are four others so promote
pathothea
archival ways lorenzo martinico and
janice siliconis
so i'm sorry if i did not pronounce your
names correctly
and the tool could be given by lorenzo
all right
thanks mark so let me start with a
motivating example
let's take the problem of classifying
encrypted messages as fake news
of course we could try to download a
heavy data set of fitness articles to
mobile client but that's untenable so
the best approach seems to
send the message unencrypted to the
cloud let the cloud run its
classification algorithm
update the data set with the new message
and then return
the classification to the client of
course the disadvantage of this is that
we reveal the client's correspondence
so what we can do is run a function
encryption scheme
such that we can run this analysis
function on the encrypted ciphertext and
still return
a classification our work expands the
class of
functional encryption functions that we
can compute to include
stateful and randomized functionalities
and we instantiate a protocol
that can implement them securely proven
under the uc model using
a trusted execution environment in
pasadena's
formalization and then finally we relax
the model from basterdal pst to capture
additional adversaries
so our protocol is called steel and like
the title says
is composable hardware based and
implements stateful and randomized
function encryption
so when we talk about randomized
functionalities
we mean that any attempts at decrypting
can use a fresh random string this is
different from previous notions of
randomness in functional encryption
where we'd have randomness come from a
new functional key
and then when we say stateful we mean
that each of our decryptors
can hold some kind of state for each of
the functions they want to compute
such that any decryption can update this
private state
in practice the f the class of functions
that we can
implement that we can compute in a
function encryption scheme
takes in as additional input a state
string and a random string
and return an additional state string
our steel protocol as i mentioned is
based on trusted execution environments
which are extensions on cpu
architectures to guarantee
additional properties like
confidentiality and integrity
in particular our work is based off iron
by faciadal
which already implements public key
functional encryption
using intel sgx within our protocol
we have the detractor and the key
management authority
as sgx secret machines the encryption
phase
is simply a plain public key encryption
you can join with a plain text proof of
knowledge and the key material for
public key encryption is kept within
the two enclaves confidentially and it's
only a change if the two enclaves can
convince each other
that you're running the genuine steel
code the functional keys
are simply signatures over our
presentation of the function
which the decryption enclave will verify
to be authentic before
authorizing decryption
our proof is in the uc with global
subroutine setting
where we are where we can add a global
functionality to
any uc protocol oops sorry
and in particular we formalize
in particular we use the global
attestation functionality from passethel
to uh to other um
hardware based functionality um some
data from the proof one particular
challenge that we have is that we need
to synchronize
the state of the a real functionality
without a simulator
uh so as we mentioned whenever we run a
decryption
the state the inner state to the
decryptor gets updated
uh so so whenever the environment picks
a challenge ciphertext
because it encrypts it using the public
key encryption the dr functionality has
no notion
of this encryption phase so we need to
extract somehow
the message and this is why we add a
plaintext proof of knowledge which the
simulator can use instructor to
obtain back the original message x and
pass it on to the deal functionality
just like it would have happened in the
real world where the enclave
would decrypt the ciphertext using its
key
finally we model an additional
relaxation over the psd functionality
to allow two different kinds of attacks
so in the normal
in the honest setting uh any update to
the state would proceed
in such a linear fashion like in the
figure however we model an additional
battery that can conduct a rollback
attack where after some
states it can rewind it to a previous
state
as well as an adversary we can conduct a
forking attack
where you can hold different branches of
the enclave at the same time
we show that steel is vulnerable to both
this kind of attacks
and discuss some potential mitigations
from the literature
thank you these are the main takeaways
over picker
and i'll take questions then
thank you lorenzo so i had a question or
comments
maybe a quick one then on my side so uh
if you find a new extension so you may
call it
silver or gold so depending on the
result
yes that's the next paper
no no questions
um so maybe then we can recap for all
the the talks and so if you have any
questions for any of the the previous
tools
feel free to to ask
you can also check on zoodeep so i don't
read our question there
yeah miguel maybe a question for you
regarding the
generic negation sort of follow up to
the previous questions
for most of the predicates the uh
the uh encoding that you get from
generic negation do they match the uh
previous encoding for the negated uh
[Music]
predicate
all right sorry i missed the first half
of the question because i was
refreshing my browser oh actually no
that's fine um
sort of like uh you know is it the case
that for most predicates
if i take the uh if i take the
uh if i apply a generic negation um
the encoding i get is the same as the
existing encoding for the negation of
the predicate
ah okay so um i don't think so
but maybe after simplification it is the
same so i remember that
for the the predicate encoding negation
that i also developed
four years ago that was actually the
case for many encodings so if you first
negate
and then simplify you were getting the
the actually negated encoding that some
human had developed independently
i see and it was by human some human i
mean you
basically because you you develop most
of uh pretty the predicate and
colleagues
um but uh
yeah so something interesting that i
want to point out is that sometimes this
after negating you are getting something
even simpler
so for example that was the case of
monotone spam programs
so you were getting something that was
even smaller than the original encoding
but you have to simplify negation is
generically
bigger it will be it'll be it'll grow
but maybe you can simplify you can
you know find some linear combinations
that simplify and you get something
smaller than the original and i have not
observed this
phenomenon in the new one but in
parenthesis but maybe
it happens that's an interesting
question whether it will happen or not
i see but can you apply the
simplifications even before
applying the negation or the
simplifications uh
the simplification technology is
inherent to
having applied the negation
transformation
right so um so first of all
i don't really know how to
systematically simplify brain coding
so there was there were some ideas in
the in the predicate encoding framework
in brain coding i have
no not really a good idea how to do it
but um i don't think
those simplifications were not working
on the on the original encoding
i see so it's when you introduce the
redundancy after negating it turns out
that
you can simplify even farther but
those simplifications were not giving
you anything on the original
and this is some weird phenomenon that i
couldn't find explanation for even
even after a few years maybe someone can
can
give a new
so size sounds like a great open
question um yeah
yeah do you have any questions for maybe
for either mcgill or the other speakers
um maybe one of the shouldn't you any of
your co-authors can try to answer my
course question from earlier
about motivations for kdm
uh you're calling me uh yeah maybe can
you answer
my course question earlier about uh
multiplication
yeah yeah so so so for the for the ktm
so
uh the the main difference or what they
enhance the security is that you can
encrypt something related to key
so so the triple k said that uh you can
encrypt
a key so for the for the standard cpa or
cca you cannot do this
so so so for this point uh we we can
have
several applications or some scenarios
we need it
from a theoretic part or maybe real
world application
so for the for the theoretical part so
so maybe you all know that for the
for the uh for the homomorphic
encryption we need for striping
you need to encrypt some key
uh for the for the next round
uh for the application when we saw uh we
saw a scenario that described in
uh previous papers that's you know if
you have an ib system
some something like this so you want to
uh do some revocation
you have some time period then you can
encrypt
the secret key for the next round
for the next time slot using the
the encryption system for the current
time slot so so in this case you need to
encrypt
key using the same encryption system so
uh this is what we know for this uh for
the applications
uh for our work actually we follow the
line that
extend the expressiveness from pke to
ibe to av that is somewhat uh
somewhat unnatural uh a natural
desirable things we want to have
uh but for this we also give an
application so
for the for the extension from pke to
ibe we can do something like uh
pke with cca security and also kdm
security because we need ibu to do this
i mean we need a kdm secure ibe
to to work with the transformation so
the classical one
so for our work we uh we use the
same paradigm to to show that
an ab scheme with kdm is also useful
because we can get
cc secure and kdm for ib scheme
so that's what we all know for the for
the application and also it's it's
really a
interesting uh question to find more
application i mean uh in the theory
part i mean how to use uh a b with
such kind of expressiveness because we
can do uh
uh kdmav for uh from the pretty encoding
that means we can do uh
um very expressive abe so
yeah it i think it's an interesting uh
direction to find more application
yeah i i hope this answer the questions
yeah no very very detailed answer thanks
a lot
i have another question maybe an
application so i was wondering whether
the
functional encryption community sees
value in
and for instance using hardware to
implement things that at the moment are
too too inefficient but that can later
on could be used with
cryptographic solutions for general
functions so kind of better this is a
way of exploring kind of the
potential of using functional encryption
in applications
you know but maybe maybe henrik wants to
say something on that i don't know
but i don't want to pick anyone now but
just curious but for the other speakers
of the talk so about that
for me i don't know so so much about the
the hot heart way of implementation but
i
i think some wonderful sgx
or something like this but i didn't
check the paper i guess
so so if anybody know the no more i
would like to hear about it
yes it's uh it is true that for this
it's a good point
yeah so so so yeah the the same for ib
so the very first implementation of ib
basically was using a smart so that was
a long time ago by the smeting kiscarter
so
i don't remember when but uh and then
came those pairings and then
just a few you know i mean that's
natural to look at the solution i mean
there is
nothing else available
do you know who did this smart card
implementation of function encryption
yes it was this method scatter i forgot
the year so i i i wanted to say
something wrong but uh yeah
it's good that it's good that even this
map is not here he would have shouted at
us
yes okay that's very good
yeah you're missing that too
[Laughter]
okay very good late 80s
late 80s thank you mati
yeah but there's also been recent work
looking into research
looking into using hardware
secure hardware to accelerate fully
homomorphic encryption
so i think it's a matter of time that we
will also start
looking into using hardware to
accelerate our functional encryption
yeah but there's a difference between
using hardware and tamper-proof hardware
which the user itself
doesn't see the inner working
like the public key that has actually
based on a secret key there
that does symmetric encryption and claim
to be
publicly it was done by uh this medkit
scatter it was part of
an ibm old architecture in the 80s too
it's all tricks they always come back in
a new format
when there are more new primitives
yeah i think this works on using minimal
hardware tokens to implement
function encryption so there's also more
theoretical work in that direction
yeah yeah all we say is that there are
now new new dimensions to the old work
it's not exactly the old one new
primitives
so actually building on that uh coming
back to lorenzo and the last work
um you know when you use your hardware
and your enclaves you stay a sense of
this
you know how simple can you make the uh
functionality
you require from the trusted hardware
components
um so sorry can you say it again uh by
by simple do you mean like
uh so you require some trusted hardware
right
uh yes and then you need to trust that
where to do some computation for you
um how simple can we can this uh
computation be
uh i think that's a great question i
think uh it's somewhat a trade-off
between
efficiency and uh you know security
because obviously we know trusted
hardware has some problems
like side channel attacks uh so right
now in our construction we
basically rely exclusively on the
trusted order to
to do the entire competition uh which
us and trade-offs but uh so we've been
thinking about trying to add
in more more crypto outside of the
anklet itself
to to to to to strengthen it uh but
obviously that would mean a decrease
because
just running the code in the enclave has
basically no
performance impact but any further
crypto we have to do
would affect that yeah i hope they
answered the questions
yeah um so we have the test of times
or what ceremony coming up so we should
try to end on time
well one more minute any other final
comments or remarks or questions for the
speakers
if not maybe we can take further
questions to tulip and
let's thank all the speakers again for
the session
all right thank you oh wait we still
have one minute so
questions after the applause
uh maybe we can finish a little bit
early
thank you everyone