and you're ready to go have a good
session
thank you so uh welcome to today's first
session of pkc
2021 uh this is the second session
of pkc focusing on cryptographic
primitives
i'm christian and i'm co-chairing this
session together with lisa cole
so as in previous days please respect
the code of conduct which in particular
includes
displaying your full names here in zoom
in this session we look forward to seven
important contributions uh to the space
of cryptographic primitives
where each speaker gets roughly five
minutes to present the result
which is then followed by one or two
questions from the audience
and please ask your questions by uh
and we will then read them out
and if time allows we will have more
time for questions to all offers at the
end of the session
so without much further ado let's
proceed to the first talk of this
session
uh it's the paper with the title a
geometric approach to homomorphic secret
sharing
it's joint work by evolution
and julio malavolta russell is giving
the talk
uh please go ahead thanks thanks for the
introduction
so i yeah i'm russell i'm going to talk
about a geometric approach to
homomorphic secret sharing
and as uh said in this introduction is
the joint work
between yuvai shai and julio malavota
so what is a homomorphic secret sharing
scheme in our definition an
nmt hss scheme is first of all a t out
of m square sharing scheme
where n input clients secret share
inputs to m servers
out of them t can be corrupt but
additionally these m servers can
evaluate
evaluate some function on the shares
and produce some output shares and send
them to another client called the input
client
and to capture even more schemes we
allow the share algorithm to produce
some extra recovery information which
are also sent to the output client
so this deviates from existing
definitions slightly
and we will focus on evaluate the
evaluation
of n variate degree d polynomials f
and in general we can think of
a high supported degree d being
correlated to a high communication cost
so we can we are incentivized to
maximize the supported degree d
while minimizing the communication cost
so in this context we present three
results the first is a generic compiler
based on degree k homomorphic encryption
these are more encryptions which are
able to evaluate
degree k polynomials and this compiler
turns a family of
hss scheme where the recovery algorithm
is a degree l polynomial in the recovery
information
and and they could have high
communication cost such as
in order of n to the power l and after
the compilation we get
some xss scheme for the same kind of
polynomials for the same degree
but with much lower communication cost
in the order of
n to the power l minus k
so from another perspective we can
interpret this result as follows
if we assume that we have
so we insist to pay only order n
communication then this compiler can
boost
the supported degree from 2m over t all
the way to k plus 2 over m
k plus 2 times m over t where k is the k
of the homomorph encryption and the idea
of the compiler is that we can push
the k degrees of the recovery
computation to the servers using khe
and let the output layer let the output
client complete the remaining l minus k
degrees
and for the second result we will
extract some compatible
information periodic hss schemes from
the private information retrieval
literature
and specifically we are looking at the
beautiful pir scheme of woodruff and
japanese
extracted scheme will be parameterized
by an integer l
a natural number l and they will support
a degree d
equal to l plus one times m over t
and note that when l equals zero we we
will recover
the well-known xiaomi secret sharing
scheme
so the w yl scheme is uh
shares many components with the xiaomi
square sharing scheme but on top of that
the sharing and the evaluation algorithm
will compute a bunch of high order
derivatives
up to order l and correspondingly in the
recovery algorithm
instead of using the lagrange
interpolation like in the xiaomi scheme
we will use a generalization of it
called the emit interpolation scheme to
interpolation
to take advantage of the derivatives
and finally as our third result we
construct pre-processing mpc protocols
from pre-processing hss
to recall a pre-processing mpc protocol
is one that has two phases offline an
offline phase and an online phase
the offline phase is potentially
expensive but it only depends on the
function f
but not the online inputs it can be done
by just the party or
by another mpc protocol and
all this is uh the goal is that with all
these pre-processing
we hopefully achieve a online
communication cost
which is much smaller than the
description side description size of f
which could be as high as n to the power
d and to do this we will use something
called p preprocessing hss
in which p out of the m shares are
independent of the online inputs x1 to
xn
and for our schemes we have p equals to
the floor of t
over l plus one and the idea behind this
transformation
is that since the p out of m shares of
the xss are independent of the inputs
we can generate them in advance and push
the computation of
ps hss servers to the offline phase of
the mpc
and again assuming order of n
communication
and if some conditions are met namely l
plus 1 divides t
then we can hope to get one more
supported degree so in conclusion these
are the
results presented in this paper and for
some concrete feeling of
how the supported degree b looks like
here are some examples
and finally feel free to check out the
eprint version for more details
thanks
thanks a lot for this desktop
so i haven't seen any questions in
philip chat but it's also feel free to
unmute now and and ask directly
in zoom if there is a pressing question
from the audience
otherwise we have uh you've got a
question so um
can you can you give like you you talked
a lot about this uh
pre-processing application so did you
think about a concrete example where
you know where you expect is
pre-processing mpc
protocol to improve over other
approaches
um so i don't remember the food details
right now but in the paper we
we have a special paragraph talking
about this saying that you can use this
pre-processing mpc protocol as a
building block for
a bigger mpc protocol so and this bigger
npc protocol is used to compute the
arithmetic circuits
with with degree d gates so each gate
computes the degree t polynomial and you
can
change these protocols to and then yeah
high degree polynomials are i guess in
general useful for a lot of
purposes like machine learning computing
statistics and then so on
and this brings me actually to an uh
follow-up so this so what other
functions could be of interest to you
i mean you you said it low degree
volumes are interesting
machine learning but uh so what other
functions are there in the
literature that might be you know
verified to look at
um i don't fully understand the question
but people have
looked at other computation model so in
instead of polynomials they look at
if i remember correctly branching
programs
so yeah other computation model and
try to build hss for them or even
arbitrary
boolean circuits something like that
we thanks a lot so any other questions
from the audience we would have
time for some at least one more question
otherwise we proceed
doesn't seem to be the case so thanks to
the speaker again and let's move to the
next stop
uh so then i will take over
uh you can already start sharing your
spring
so a screen so the next talk will be um
revisiting rcca security and replay
protection
uh this is joint work by christian
ulimara christopher portman and julian
rito and
william will give the talk so stage is
yours
thank you okay so hi yes i'm yam and
welcome to my presentation on revisiting
rcc security and regular protection this
is joint work with christian
really and christopher so security
notions are usually designed with
concrete applications in mind however
they often do not
match the exact security requirements of
their intended applications
what is their purpose then for example
what is the purpose of cc2 security for
pk schemes
we know on one hand that cc2 security is
sufficient to achieve confidential
communication
however there are also non-cc2 secure
schemes
that also offer this type of
communication
the same happens with rcca security so
rcc security is just a relaxation of cc2
security
relaxation in the sense that cca2
implies rcc security
but rcc security does not imply cc2
security
so it is known that confidential
communication
requires indar cca security however
in general industry security is not
sufficient to achieve confidential
communication
so in his work we identify technical
inconsistencies with
existing game-based notions and we
showed that
they are not implied by cc2 for the case
of probabilistic decryption
this actually contradicts a claim made
in earlier work
furthermore they also have no
non-operational meaning
so we showed that cc2 does not imply pd
rcc security
and as it turns out it does not even
imply the weaker
in sd rcc security
so we clean up the space of
game-by-security notions for pke schemes
for capturing confidential communication
and we do so by following a systematic
approach
for characterizing security using a
composable framework
which essentially consists of defining
different applications of pke schemes
as benchmarks which are composable
security notions
and we consider three different
benchmarks
the first one is one i was just
referring to before
and this one is taken from earlier work
and then we consider a variant
of confidential communication where this
time the receiver is responsible for
detecting and filtering out ciphertext
replays
and finally there is yet another variant
of confidential communication
where this time it is a third party who
is responsible for detecting and
filtering out ciphertext replays
so we consider these three applications
or benchmarks and for each one of them
we propose a gameplay security notion
capturing the intended application
so for the first benchmark we introduced
ncl rcca security for the
second we introduced in srp rcca
security
and for the third we introduced in prp
rcc security
so we showed that these notions captured
intended
benchmark so clrcca captures benchmark
one srprca captures benchmark 2
and prp rcga security captures benchmark
3.
finally we give a full characterization
of our game-based security
notions we show that they are correctly
placed between
cc2 and rcc security and we also give
all possible relations between them
for instance we show that cc2 implies
prp rcc security
which implies srp rcc security cl rcc
security
and finally nclrcca security implies in
rcc security and you also give
the converse non-implications so indar
cca does not prove cl or cca which does
not
imply srp prp and finally prp rca
security
does not imply cc to security
so for more details please have a look
at the full version of this talk
and thank you for your attention
thank you very much for the nice talk
are there any questions
in the audience either speak up or
write it in tulip or in the chat
yeah maybe maybe i can ask your view
about like what is the practical impact
of having all these different notions
so um the main thing is
uh i mean domain there could be an issue
with
schemes which are just proven rcc secure
in particular if their
message space size is small um i mean if
it is large then they are fine
but if the message space size is small
then
there might actually be like molding
attacks that you can mount on them
so even though they are in rcc secure
and
one would expect that they could be used
because for large message spaces they
can for a small message species there
might actually be attacks
on the malleability
does this answer your question yes thank
you yeah i mean i think one conclusion
i would voice that even for simple
things like
security of encryption there are many
subtle notions and
differences and that we should not
expect it to be
less complicated for more complicated
notions it's just that we haven't looked
in
as much detail that is that a fair
uh conjecture sorry
could you repeat sorry so so i my
i said that even for things as simple as
public key encryption and
cca security there are so many different
notions depending on
what exactly we want to construct so
we should be kind of we should expect
for more complicated cryptographic
primitives or particles
there will be just as many complications
and this is kind of like a
a good good thing to be aware of
yes yes i mean it's i mean at least i
found it a bit surprising but
like something as fundamental as like bk
has like some issues and if this is the
case for
very simple uh primitives like pke
then yes for more complicated ones i
mean one can certainly
expect i mean more
other issues to arise
well i hope not but it might happen
are there any other questions so i don't
see a question
on sulip currently anyone also wants to
ask a question we still have time
ah so we have a question on shulip so
i'm
just going to read it out um the
question is by daniel avon
is there a natural example of a pke
scheme that is more efficient or simpler
to describe in
a design to hit rcca security or another
relaxed variant rather than designing to
hit cca security
and in brackets i don't think this
overlaps with the small message space
example
so the question is if there is like some
big gain scheme which is
more efficient if we only restrict
rcc security rather than cc2 security
yes yes exactly or simpler to construct
generally i mean there are some that
simply cannot be achieved by cc2
security
um so i mean in one hand on one hand
they're
easier to construct because otherwise
it's impossible for example for
a re-randomizable encryption for which
cc2 is just too strong
i hope this answers the question
regarding efficiency i'm not sure
okay thanks so i guess if there is a
follow-up question
please write in the in the chat any any
more questions
um so maybe um you you already mentioned
that there is a problem with the rcca
security
uh with the that you have with uh with
small
like when the message space is small
because you don't get actually
uh confidential communication like your
benchmark
mark one can you say uh why like
why this is the case or or kind of what
goes wrong
uh so why benchmark one is not achieved
for us
yes yes exactly so the issue is that
there might be pk schemes which are
malleable
uh and still all are in darcy secure for
example
if you consider the binary message space
then
when you submit two challenges to the
game you just get well
presumably one encryption of zero and
one encryption of one
and then you simply are in the
decryption oracle is very useless
because
it you it just tells you whether the the
ciphertext like it's a valid ciphertext
in which case it outputs test
or if it is some some bad ciphertext and
it replies with blood but
otherwise it just does not help so even
mulling attacks cannot be translated
into something that
allowed to win the rcc security game
yes thanks that makes sense thanks very
much thanks
okay so i think we can move on to the
next session thanks again very much for
your time thank you
okay so the next talk is on group
encryption so please uh good
speaker yeah perfect
so this is talk this talk is about the
paper
group encryption full dynamicity message
filtering co-paste instantiation
it's a joint work by uh
probably have to unmute
okay perfect introduction
yeah and i'm going to talk about fully
dynamical encryption uh message
filtering and the code based
instantiation
and so first i will start with group
encryption
then briefly state our three results in
retirement group
encryption message filtering and the
purpose instantiation
so first group encryption was
introduced by chiani janis and young in
and it is the encryption analog of group
signature
and there are four parties involved the
center
the receiver the group manager who
manages a group of receiver
and also there is an opening authority
who is capable of identifying
the recipient of ciphertext
group encryption allows the sender
verifiably encrypts message
to a certified group members while
keeping the anonymity of the
receiver and more formally
group encryption allows encrypting while
the following holds
the ciphertext is well-formed and can be
decrypted by some registered group
members
second the opening authority can
identify the intended receiver
and sir the prem tags satisfy certain
requirements
such as being a witness for some public
relation
and group encryption skin have many
appealing privacy preserving
applications
such as in encrypted email filtering
anonymous chess asset party applications
and secure obvious retrieval storage
and so far group encryption has been
much
less well-studied and we aim to
contribute to the development
of group encryption given its compiling
features and mass application
and now i will identify several
limitations of existing group encryption
schemes
and the first limitation exists in use
certification
and the kty model allows dynamic
enrollment of new users
to the group it does not provide any
mechanism to prevent revoked users from
decrypting new ciphertext intended for
them
even though this revoked user
will expel from some misbehaviors
or they are retired from the
organizations
so a formal treatment of free dynamic
group encryption
is highly desirable the second
limitation is about the usefulness of
existing group encryption skin scheme in
the context of email
filtering so in all no instantiation of
group encryption
the relations for messages are defined
according to the computationally hard
problems and for example the discrete
log relation is employed
in the kty model for message filtering
and this treatment fit the definition of
good encryption
but in our real life it is hard to
sample a witness
to satisfy the relation so
can we design a group encryption with
some
expressive policies and
third regarding the diversity of
concrete computational
assumptions used in building group
encryption
among all existing schemes the only one
that is known
to be content resistant is the
lattice-based construction
and this reads the question of realizing
group encryption based on alternative
quantum resistance assumption
such as can we can share code-based
group encryption
so we have three contributions the first
is the formization of free dynamic
encryption and we realize message
filtering
with two expressive policies and we can
check the first code based group
encryption
scheme follow our this model and these
two suggested
policies so i will go to the first
contribution
uh briefly uh introduce the model of
free dynamical encryption
then in this the opening authority and
the group manager can
run the setup algorithm to produce their
public or secret keep here
in this joint and the issue this is an
interactive practical security run
between a user and the good manager
and the user obtains our own copy on
secret key and groupmanager updates
the good information and our model
enables
the group manager to remove some users
from the group
through a group updating algorithm so in
this aggregation
the group manager advance the input and
update the group information
and this is an encryption algorithm and
the
sender can encrypt weakness for its
chosen user
so in the proof and the verification the
proof acquisition is run by
the sender and who act as approver
and demonstrate the honest computation
of the
cipher text and this verification reason
can by
any verifier to check if the proof is
valid
and also there is a decryption agreement
aggregation for
the user to decrypt the ciphertext and
the opening authority can
anonymize the sample text
next is the message filtering
so our goal is to equip our
group encryption scheme with some basic
yet commonly used policies for filtering
and more precisely we consider a public
list
s with s1 to sk of k binary keywords
and each of them has a bit less t
and we want to test against less t
substring
of the encrypted message w
and by the way the list can be regularly
updated by the group manager
depending on the interest and the needs
of the organization
all these keywords as i could be some
either
it could be some good keywords or some
bad keywords
so we can define two policies in the
permissive policies
you will accept the message if it
contains some good keywords
and informally w uh is a
legitimate message even only if there
exists
a si keywords which is the substring of
the message w
and all messages do not contain any of
these keywords are
rejected and in the prohibitive policy
you will accept the message if it is far
from some bad keywords
and the bad keywords can maybe
corresponding to some topics that are
illegal or simply out of groups
or interest so we will accept the
message if it is far from some bad cures
and here we want to make sure even the
adversary
changes minor parts the bacteria are
still
recognizable and how we model this
so we will make sure the distance
between the bacterius and the message
and is at least d so in formal words
the for every less t substring y
of the message and every keywords is i
their harming distance is at least d
and following the model of the free
dynamical encryption and the policies we
just mentioned
so we can have our code-based
instantiation
and the idea of our code-based fully
dynamic
encryption so at first when a user
requests to join the group
it genera generates its own public and
secret key
then he sends the public and the zero
hash value d to the
manager and second to
achieve dynamicity you will following
the updating algorithm
and third when sending the message
satisfying
uh list either of the two policies
to the user the sender will use the
private key to encrypt the message
and use the public open authorities
fabric key to
encrypts the identity
also the sender proves in zero knowledge
that the message satisfies the given
policy
and the cipher text of the open society
is an
honest computer cipher text of the
identity and
also the this one is a correct
ciphertext of the
message and computing undersigned hidden
public key
and we satisfy this constraint
so we construct the first code based
fully dynamical encryption
so compared to uh the only known group
encryption from
lattice-based construction and us is
more efficient
since we use a macro tree can see as a
weak form of signature but
our construction is still not practical
due to the improvement of
heavy zero knowledge agreement so we
have a open question
is can we construct practically usable
free dynamic group encryption skin from
post-content assumptions
so thank you for listening and any
questions
thank you for the great talk so are
there any questions from the audience
we have time for maybe one quick
question
i don't see anything on suli but also
please
feel free to unmute maybe you mentioned
that it has privacy applications so i
was i was wondering whether
it's whether this is like not doesn't
need to be balanced a bit more because
isn't that essentially
as a form of keyscroll or at least
identity escrow so
it can be seen kind of as not
necessarily being good for privacy to
use group encryption
so i was wondering whether you discussed
that in the paper
uh pattern i'm not very
so can you repeat again for the question
so the
i think as i see the goal of group
encryption is to also allow
kind of the identity to be leaked so
it's less private than just anonymous
or key private encryption
uh you mean compared to the key privacy
encryption
yeah this one is uh
allow the sender verifiably uh encrypts
message to
certified group members but this one
keep the anonymity of the receiver
yeah but for the
key privacy
okay but this one
a key privacy but this one the public
key
is hidden in this when we encrypting
the messages
okay so does this answer the question
i think the public key is also hidden in
in key private encryption so maybe this
is true for both schemes
i'm not very familiar with key privacy
encryption yes sorry
i mean if there is time we can discuss
this at the end of the session because i
i feel we have to move to the next talk
okay thank you
it's quite time constrained but we would
definitely get back
to this if if there is enough time at
the end
so yes and with this uh please lisa go
ahead and the next speak can
already sell off
yes so the next talk will be okay thanks
thanks for sharing the screen so the
next talk will be bootstrapping fully
homomorphic encryption over the integers
in less than
one second um this is a word by
either vito lima pereira and the paper
is invited to the journal of
propoligy and uh there will
well give the talk so please go ahead
hi hello everybody so
um okay so for the fully homomorphic
encryption schemes
nowadays we have basically two main
families okay we have the
schemes based on the lwe problem which i
guess you already know
and we have the schemes based on the
approximate
greatest commodivizer problem so we
call this simply agcd and in this
problem the secret is simply an integer
okay and then we simple uniform elements
like
here we sample noise elements and then
we have the agcd samples which are
of this form so p times q plus uh
some noise so a multiple of p of p plus
some noise okay and the problem is given
these approximate multiples of
p uh we have to recover p
itself so the fhe schemes based on this
problem
are what we call fhe over the integers
okay now for the schemes based on the lw
problem we have fee and tfhe
which implement about strapping that
runs in less than one second
but for his schemes uh of this family
fhe over the integers we have no such
bootstrapping
so the goal of this paper is
closing this gap between these two
families of schemes okay
so i will now briefly present
what i did in this paper to try to close
this gap so the first thing was
proposing a gsw
like a scheme that's based on this
problem
so first we
defined a new problem which we call a g
c d
and in this problem we still have the
secret p which is an integer
but now q and r are simply uh
polynomials they are polynomials that
are just uh
composed by the old q and rs that we
have
for the agcd problem and then we
randomize this polynomial with a secret
polynomial k
in some cycloatomic ring r
now using this problem we we can
construct a gsw
scheme that can encrypt polynomials
m in two formats so we can encrypt the
polynomial m into
another polynomial or we can encrypt a
polynomial m
into a vector of polynomials and then
we define the mixed homomorphic
multiplication
that can multiply this ciphertext of
these two formats okay so this is
more or less like the tfhe external
product
and it's more efficient than simply
using the gsw
homomorphic multiplication
now the second contribution of the paper
is what we called
hidden approximate modulo switching so
we have the base scheme ciphertext
which is an integer c and
here we have r which is the noise and
the noise is large so what we want to do
is to use the jswe scheme
to compute the decryption function of
this basis scheme homomorphically
but this means that that we have to
reduce c
module p homomorphically and this is a
problem because
p is secret and also in the
a gcd problem p is exponentially large
in the security parameter lambda
so the gsw scheme cannot handle this
okay so what we do is we encrypt the
values that are close
to these fractions and over p
in the bootstrapping keys and then we
can use the bootstrapping keys to
switch to replace this b here by this
value
n which is public so it's no more no
longer secret and it's
small enough for the gsw scheme to
handle it
so at the end of this step what we get
is a gsw encryption
of a power of y that depends on m okay
y is simply x square in this case
now what we have to do to finish the
bootstrap is to
get this to transform this gsw
encryption
that depends on m into a base scheme
of this format again so here we have an
encryption that is actually a polynomial
and here we have an integer
so to do so we propose a functional key
switching procedure so we
we with this procedure we can take a
cipher text that belongs
to a ring r1 and encrypts a message me
when there's some
key and we can output the ciphertext in
another ring encrypting a function of
the message
under a second key okay
so in particular you see that if we set
n2 here to one
then this ring r2 is is just the
integers
and also because we know some bounds to
r into
delta here we can choose m
such that m of this power of y is
sorry f of this power of y is m
okay so this means that we can use this
um general procedure to
switch from a gsw encryption of a power
of y that depends on m to a base scheme
ciphertext
of m
so when we put all this together what we
have is
this bootstrapping we start with an agcd
encryption with them with large noise
we use the mixed homomorphic product of
the gsw scheme
and then we produce a jsw encryption of
a power
of y that depends on m and this is the
step that
reduces the noise and then we use the
functional
key switching to change the format and
set back an encryption of m under the
agcd
uh problem okay so
in this paper we have adapted the
bootstrapping from
fiu and tf80 to fhe over the integers
and there is also a proof of concept
implementation in c plus and you can
find the source code on github
and well if you think this is
interesting you can check the paper
and of course you can send me messages
emails and i will be
glad to discuss thank you
thank you very much uh for the nice talk
this sounds uh very cool uh so it are
there
any questions in the audience or on
yes russell yeah so i have two questions
so first
what are the advantages of schemes based
on hcd than those based on lwe
and the second question is that as i
understand you
in this short talk that you constructed
a new scheme based on agct so but
does this mean that the existing agcd
based schemes
still don't have fast bootstrapping
okay so the first one is about the
advantage of agcd over other schemes
right
well this is actually a trick question
so
the first papers that proposed uh
schemes based on the agcd problem
argued that you have advantages because
all the primitives that you use are
simpler
so for instance you don't have discrete
gaussian distributions you see
you just have integers uh maybe
it's uh maybe it's easier to
to do a constant time implementation for
instance
yeah but yeah i would say that simply
[Music]
having schemes based on another
hardness assumption is already
interesting enough
for us to work with them okay and
um yeah the second question is
why why i construct another scheme right
so actually construct actually i
construct a gsw scheme
based on the agcd problem because the
gsw schemes that exist they are not
efficient enough to work with
polynomials you see that i had to
encrypt and multiply
polynomials yeah but um
yeah of course there are already fully
homomorphic encryption based on the
gcd so you have these schemes that can
be bootstrapped
but not in this framing work that allows
us to bootstrap
uh in less than one second you see with
uh in which you have
fastboot strapping okay so those games
do don't have
fast bootstrap no no there's a scheme
the existing schemes are more like the
gsw
so it's very hard to bootstrap
or let's say they are like uh
bgv but not really but you can see it's
also hard to bootstrap
but which step takes a lot of time
thanks
any other questions
[Music]
here's the question so the question is
does the security of your scheme reduce
to this new
ragcd assumption can we have confidence
in the hardness of that assumption
um well yeah this problem cannot be
easier than the
original gcd problem the catch here
so this is for sure but the catch here
is that actually i used
uh this problem to select this uh
parameters that are
smaller than what i would select
uh if i simply had used the agcd
huh so this is the catch but
you can also prove the security under
the
agcd itself but then you
yeah but i mean we have the sketch with
the parameters that's that's true
so if you just if you simply select the
parameters
take into account the attacks against
the
acd the agcd problem
then you basically have to increase the
parameters by a factor
of n
okay thank you very much i hope this
answers the question and i think we
should move on to the
next talk for timing so thank you again
very nice
thanks a lot so the next talk is about
the paper
rate one key dependent message security
via reusable homomorphic extractor
against correlated source attacks
it's a joint work um by gg ly
feng hang liu and jalon wang and she
should give the talk
please go ahead thanks thank you for
introduction
uh hello everyone i'm chili my paper is
a real
wine kdm security very usable morphing
structure
this is a joint work with heart and
jordan
when considering security for inclusion
schemes
we always assume that the the messages
are independent of the
uh the strict key however in some
special
sorry in some in some situations
the message depends on the secret key
in order to solve the security issue in
this special case
the notion of kdm security has been
proposed
and the relationship between message and
the sixth key
can be generally described by a function
class
in this case the queries from adversary
is modded
as a function f and the answer is the
corresponding subtitle more formally
the kdm security can be described by a
security
game between the challenger and the
adversary at the beginning
the challenger first choose a run bid
and understand
the most public key to the adversary
then otherwise we can conduct
a key extraction and the kdm queries
finally the reverse will respond a bit b
prime we see that
adversary wins again if b equals b prime
in this formal definition the class of
function f
is an important parameter which is
called the kdm challenge function class
there is also another important
parameter um
the number of number of different public
keys in the security
industry game in a modular case we call
this ktm umbra security
there uses many pku-ib schemes that are
ktm circuit with respect to different
ktm challenge function class and
the number uh umbra however
all the schemes have a common drawback
their information
their information rates are quite small
my question in this paper is how to
construct a ktm circuit pke
with optimal information rate and
the my result of this paper consists of
ktm1 circuit pke with optimal
information rate
kdm umbra circle pke with optimal
general measure rate for unbounded
polynomial number
ktm and browse cycle ibe with optimal
information rate
for unbounded polynomial umbra
innovation about pku or ib schemes
is also leakage resilient with the
optimal liquid rate against the blood
leakage from
blood like function here i just focus on
the first result
and others can be viewed as each
extensions
in order to introduce our technique more
clearly
i adopted the following framework view
first
this paper tells us that homomorphic wps
implies ktm1 security
second broker's key at all the people
tells us that
batch encryption plus xo operation
implies ktm1 security
and leakage resilience inspired by these
two papers
we consider whether we can get much
better ktm circuit constructions
from wgps with additional structure
and homogeneous charter of course of
course
due to of course due to time limit the
detailed
introductions of building blocks are
different to a paper
in particular with two building blocks
or basic constructions can be described
can be described in the following way
first location algorithm is that runs
the center of algorithm
of wps
oh sorry and
the encryption algorithm is that run the
valid income solution algorithm of wps
and compute the advertising in this way
um next through using the properties of
the used dual hps and the extructor
we can prove the security of a basic
construction for just
one ktm surface test furthermore with
the leveraging
the correlated source security of
extractor we can achieve
the normal ktm1 security we also notice
that
batch encryption here is already implies
the required the required wps
next we focus on each parameter clearly
for physical for basic construction with
this form of a test
each information rate is one over lambda
and
the ktm function class is a function is
a is a fine function
so is still far away from or desired
target
optimal information rate so
next we try to improve information rate
through
uh using reusable property and
blog so setting in particular our first
step
is to replace the instructor with a
reusable version
in this case and in this case the
information rate is one over constant
our second step is to oscillate step
is to replace oscillator
is to replace the original source with
the
y in the block so setting
in this case the information rate is
optimal and the ktm challenge function
is a power source for a fine function so
next we need to try to amplify
the profile and function class for
audience security
in order to do this we can encode
the labels of a coupled circuit into the
massive space
uh besides moreover
we can adjust the parameters of a
message space
sorry message space to achieve
optimal information rate so far
and many more details can be found in
all paper
so after putting all about things
together
we can get ktm one circuit pke for any
bonus size circuit
with optimal information rate and all
the building blocks can be extensioned
from tdhrwe
next for kdm umbra circle pke
we roughly adopted the following three
steps
finally for ibe starting we roughly
adapted the following four steps
details for detailed construction placer
paper
thank you for your attention
thank you very much are there any
questions from the audience
we would have time for a quick question
please feel free to unmute ask the
question
otherwise i have i have a question so
you have this
okay two main results so one for public
encryption one for
ibe right yeah and there
and the kdm security always involves
some function class
right so and and they're different for
those two cases
yeah right right right is there an easy
explanation
what is exactly different and maybe why
even
here for i for pke
for p for pku or
function class is a can be said to be
any bounded size circuit
uh and besides we can achieve optimal
information rate
and in the case of ibe
in order to achieve optimal information
rate
we need to start a particular
function class for optimal rate and
it's a little complicated
and it can be fun forever
okay yeah i think in interest of time
you already have to
to move on uh yes so please go to the
next speaker
i already set up the slides
so thanks again for this very nice talk
and let's move on for
uh to the next stop
so uh yes i say that thanks to you for
sharing your screen uh the next talk
will be
impossibility on temporary auxiliary and
cryptography with uniqueness properties
this is joint work uh by yu yuvang
takahiro matsuda
hanaoka and uh
tanaka and uh you will give the talk so
please
okay thanks for the introduction i'm
yuang
uh today i will talk about the
impossibility on tampa brazilian
cryptography with uniqueness properties
let's join work with takahiro matsukoi
and
quesada
uh usually uh when proving the security
we assume that the keys are perfectly
protected
but in the real world the adversary may
execute some temporary attacks such as
heating up the devices and
injecting ports to tamper with the keys
and then the anniversary may observe the
signatures
or the ciphertext generated by the top
marquee
so it can get some extra advantage
from this to break the security
uh by now there have been several
positive results
in the crs model in this model the
adversary
can tamper with both the public and
secret keys in any way it wants
but it's assumed that there are temporal
proof
camera reference strings but it's still
unclear
whether we can have secure schemes in
the plain model where we assume
no tamper-proof crs in this work we show
that
it's impossible to derive the temporal
resilience of a broad class of
primitives
from any internal assumption by black
box reductions
here by a broad class of primitives we
mean
several types of primitives including a
unique signature signature with unique
signing key
randomizable signatures and also pku
with unique message
injective one-way functions and vrf
here by pke with unique message we don't
mean the deterministic
pke we mean that in such a scheme for
each ciphertext
all the value secret keys with respect
to a same pk will lead to the same
decryption result
also we showed how it captures the
chromaship encryption and pku with
unique
secret keys in our paper and
now i will briefly introduce our
intuition we will use the unique
signature as the
example here is our temporal resilience
model
in our model the anniversary consists of
three components
temper brick one and group two notice
that
the three components are indeed
independent with each other
and they cannot communicate with each
other
temper can be treated as selectively
a selective tempering function which
take a
text size into the public key and the
secret key and
outputs a timbre secret key which is sk
prime
week one takes size into the public key
and makes the signing query which is m
and greek two uh texas include the
public key
the signature generated by the time
party which is
sk prime and tries to forge a message
and signature
notice that this temporal resilience is
quite weak since we just allowed the
adversary to make
only one tampering query and one sending
query
but since we consider the negative
result the weaker the security is
the stronger our results are
to show the impossibility of the
reduction from tamper resilience for any
common assumption we just
have to show that the reductions do not
benefit from having access to the
adversary so we consider two cases
in the first case the reduction gives
the onus keys to the first component
which is temper
in this case the reduction has already
known the secret key by himself
so he can sign the uh message in the
forgery which is same style by himself
and due to uniqueness the signature
generated by
the reduction will be the same as the
one generated by break two
which means that the communication with
the adversary is
meaningless for the reduction
in the second case the reduction gives
invalid keys to the
first component and since
the temper doesn't receive the owner's
keys
it doesn't have to give the tamper keys
which is sk-prime to reduction so in
this case the reduction
learns no information on sk prime
which means that he cannot answer the
sending query since it doesn't know the
secret key
so the the reduction cannot simulate the
view of the adversary
and the adversary does not have to give
a valid forgery
to reduction so the reduction cannot get
any useful information from the
adversary in this case
as well which means that the
this reduction should not exist
otherwise it can break the assumption by
himself in polynomial time
we show in the strict proof we have to
take care of several points
such as that the reduction can make
adaptive queries to the three components
in any order
and we have to find a way for timer
which is the first component
to check the validity of the keys
and we showed the street proof
under the framework of simulator well
attacks
defined by wix so this is
my talk thank you
thank you very much for the great talk
um are there any questions
if yes then please just
unmute yourself and ask or post it on
sule
okay then maybe i i will ask a question
in the meanwhile um okay
can you say something like what happens
uh if for example you
you allow random oracles as you have in
brf constructions do your impossibility
results
still hold or do like are there known
uh like positive examples if you know
this or
what can you say okay i mean
uh for example if the hash function
which is the random oracle
is part of the crs
and the crs is temper proof then our
result doesn't capture it
but if the we if we treat the hash
function as part of the public key
then and it's not temper proof then our
result
captures it so i mean
we are not sure if there is any positive
result if there is time per proof
for example a random oracle hash
function in the public key but
if we allow it to be a time per
then the negative results hold
okay okay thank you very much
um uh anyone else
yeah maybe you can elaborate a little
bit on
when when your kind of result breaks
down so
like when you don't have uniqueness why
does
like where does your where does it break
down why
why are there why does the impossibility
not vote for other schemes
okay so
[Music]
um
uniqueness uh appears here here we will
use the uniqueness to
show that the signature generated by the
reduction will be the same as the one
generated by the adversary which means
that uh
what what the reduction receives from
the adversary
can be generated by himself uh if
uh the uniqueness doesn't hold then
maybe the the signature uh returned by
the uh adversary will be different from
the one
by the reduction then the reduction may
make use of the two different
signatures to do something uh
that's why the unique uh the unique uh
the
uniqueness is uh necessary
okay thank you yeah would be interesting
whether it could be replaced by some
some other property
maybe weaker yeah um maybe i mean
as explained before we can use the
randomizable
randomizability as explained before
if we have the randomizable signature
then
the negative result also holds since we
can randomize the signatures
so the we can randomize the signature
generated by the reduction and the one
generated by the adversary
and they will be the the
distribution of the signature will be
the same
which also uh gives the negative result
since the the one given by the
adversary can be simulated by the
reduction
but i'm not sure if we can have other
probabilities
that will be a good direction i think
okay thank you very much for the
nice talk and and also for your answers
and i think we should move on
to the last talk thank you
yes um so could the next speaker uh
already pretend start presenting the
slides
please yeah
thank you so uh the last
talk in this session is the title
adventures in crypto dark
matter attacks and fixes for weeks of
random functions
uh it's a joint work by uh chung
[Music]
please go ahead thank you for
introduction
in our paper we introduced a new direct
statistical attack on recovery candidate
presented by
bonnie adele using conditional
probability with exponentially many
samples
bona adel proposed two week prf
candidates and
we break uh break both suggested
parameters
with special case and also we propose
fix to prevent our attack
their weak pr candidates have many con
many contributions
they are very simple construction they
just mix linear computation
over different moduli and they have low
depth circuit complexity
uh they are first proposed depth two
week prior candidates
and also they are assumed to have
exponential security but these are
constructed based on the
newly proposed problems so it is
necessary to prove
insecurity through various attacks
in this presentation we present only
alternative weak piano candidate
case so other cases explain
the on loaded video so if you want to
know
please watch the video the alternative
weak periodic candidate
is defined did as follows
the secret key is a ambit vector
which is chosen by is children
uniformly and lambda and also the input
input x is n bit so
they compute the inner product inner
product
input and secret key for different
modulus and
and then finally the sum of them in
modulo 2.
this is very simple construction and
also they suggest the
dimension n is 384 from
the 84 which comes from vkw
attack our attack is also simpler
let h be the number of ones in the
secret key
then compute the conditional probability
the jc element element
j of vector input x is zero
when the output of prf is zero
uh we prove that if the
secret key j's element is one then the
difference of conditional probability
and half
half and one half is
uh one out of two to the power 0.21 h
and also the secret key k is drawn
uniformly and random so
we can assume that h is half program
so therefore if the number of samples
is larger than 2 to the power of
0.21 n then we can distinguish the
wikipedia samples and random samples
so if we can get exponentially many
samples then
we can uh then dimension end must
must grow from 384 to
610 to be robust against our attack for
128 bit security
and also uh we our attack is just
to average the sample so we do not have
store
or center so we need only one bit memory
for precision
uh unlike pkw
then how to prevent our attack uh our
attack only depends on the number of
ones in secret key case so to prevent
our attack
change the distribution of securities uh
from uniform distribution to
the distribution of the secret k
whose number of one is three three
hundred
five so it also withstand the brute
force attack
finally our open question is how to
attack
uh wikipedia candidate when when
polynomially many samples are given
and also we use the circular
circular matrix a to attack other
other wikipedia categories so it
still remains the open problem when
the matrix a is full random thank you
for
listening my presentation
thanks a lot um so we have time for
some questions for you so please feel
free to
ask them in sule or just right away here
in the meantime uh let me ask a question
so
your your attack needs uh samples
right and it needs a lot of them
uh do you suspect you can also do
you know perform your attack with
polynomial numbers an efficient number
of samples
[Music]
i think what's your like what's your
feeling about that
i i think it it can
cannot protect the pulling with
polynomial many samples
i have i have a lot of experiments about
this
pr episode but it cannot work
okay so this brings me actually to a
follow-up question so is it so you
presented a text but these are also good
news
in that like that so so do you think
the scheme is like stays at that level
of security you
figured or do you think this was just
one step towards better attacks
in the future so what's your
oh
i don't know about that yeah it would be
speculation but maybe maybe you know
might be that you you see some uh nice
nice uh
follow-up or you know some further ideas
how to
you know to to improve this attack even
more
um yes so any other question
from the audience yeah maybe um can you
go to the previous slide the
future work slide
one is one was the question that
christian asked about polynomially many
samples yeah um what
so what can you can i was curious about
the second point
i wasn't quite sure what what the goal
there is it's a it's a new scheme right
or yeah
so this is uh another
candidate i don't uh i don't explain
in this presentation but i i explained
this
this uh our attack for this
candidate is unloaded video in
downloading video
so do you have an attack on that scheme
as well or that's that's an open
question no you don't right
yeah yeah i guess one question would be
what kind of mattresses allow for an
attack
rather than a fully random one
in in documentary paper there is no
attack for full random case they they
are just
uh some rationers for security
they uh i think that
they they said that uh it is hard to
hard to convert the rational polynomial
so they they are
they they uh argue that
n n is just 200 by 56
is secure so
there is no attack for full random
metrics
thanks great so we are already
uh time-wise at least at the end of this
session but i'm
i'm sure there are more questions around
for all speakers
uh so let's thank all speakers of this
session again
you did a great job and so this ends
this this formal part
of the session um
but in case you have questions i mean
now it's the break until the invited
talk
of anchor kills so feel free also to
stay and then ask
questions