now you can welcome everybody
thanks so welcome again everybody to
um our second invited talk
by a speaker who had made
who has made many fundamental
contributions to uh
design and analysis of cryptosystems
he's a professor at rural university at
bochum
did a postdoc in san diego and then
cwi i think that's what i met him
uh he has published over 100
publications in conference and journals
received the sophia kovalevsky
award for developing quantum system
crypto
resistant crypto he got an
erc consolidator grant for building fast
cryptography on small devices
and currently is the spokesperson for
the cluster of excellence cyber security
in the age of large-scale adversaries
of the dfg which stands for german
national foundation no german
research foundation all right
so we're happy to have here ike
like kelts and ike welcome and the floor
is yours
okay yeah thanks juan
for this introduction and uh well thanks
for the
program committee to to inviting me uh
to give this talk
um so when i thought about the topic uh
well i looked at
leo duca gave a we'll give a talk on
something more well
some some modern cryptography so i
thought i'd give a talk on some
old-fashioned cryptography
so that's why my title is how provable
secure
are ec dsa signatures
um okay all right let's start
um okay so let me start by giving you a
little bit of a history uh
over a digital digital signature
algorithm so dsa
uh well this started in 1982.
some of the audience will remember so
1982 the u.s government
solicited proposals for a public key
signature standard
and uh well meanwhile in 1984
taher al gamal invented a proposed
agamal signatures it's the same
uh algamal that you know from public
encryption so he also invented
or he also gave fundamental
contributions to
signature schemes a couple of years
later there's
a schnorr signatures proposed
essentially there are a couple of
improvements over algamal signatures
but unfortunately and that might be a
lesson
for for today he filed a patent
that was granted and well with insight
we would probably it's
probably safe to say that's probably the
reason why they were not used in the
last
20 or 30 years um in 1991
the nist so that's the uh
national institute of standardization
and technology
proposed the dss which is uh synonymous
with dsa so dss is digital signature
standard and dsa's
digital signature algorithm the have
also filed a patent
which is uh attributed to david uh
kravitz
who at that time was an employee of the
nsa
uh but they gave it uh the algorithm to
public domain so it was free cheats
uh interestingly so there was uh since
there was an involvement by the
nsa there was a 1992 panel discussion at
the
eurocrypt if there's possibly a trapdoor
in the dss at the dsa and i read out the
the panelists because some of them are
in the audience today it's interesting
so
it's never destined landrock leinster
kevin mccurley
andy lisco ripple and and smith it was a
lively uh
panel discussion i mean there is no
video of that but there is some
something like formal statements of each
of the panelists
in in the proceedings of youtube 1992.
um in in the same year there were some
public comments
most notably by rivest and
and hellman and let me read out some of
the comments
so these are comments about the nist
proposal
so rivest says it is my belief that the
nist proposal represents an attack an
attempt to install v cryptography as a
national incentive
and that nist is doing so in order to
please the nsa and federal law
enforcement agency
uh a u.s standard even if weak and
flawed may be widely used
overseas making nsa's job easier
uh another nowadays famous uh
comment from that from that position
paper is that uh
runways also said the poor user is given
enough rope
with which to hang himself about dss
interesting and
well some more some more technical
objections so obviously that
dsa was limited to 512-bit modelly
which means it's obviously breakable
into to the 60 time
uh it was criticized dsa prove
performance is a
honest necessarity to a computation of
an inverse
each time a message is to be signed
these a is a requirement of a
cryptographically strong random number
for each signature
and in 1992 the list itself publishes a
paper which was called response to
comments and then this proposed digital
signatures on that
um it's interesting because that at that
time there was actually crypto paper
right so like a couple of years ago you
got with
such a response you could make a crypto
paper i don't think this works anymore
let me again read out from this answer
so it's an interesting quote i want to
say
so while government agencies tend to
support
the proposed standard the number of
negative comments was significant
larger than normally received for such a
proposal
so there was a lot of objections but
nevertheless in 1994
the uh standard was fired into the fips
one 86 than that and well one thing that
they
they amended is that they included a
124-bit
modulus interestingly it was also the
first digital signature
uh recognized by any government uh
two years earlier right so this is not
linear so two years earlier actually
winston proposed in the
curve variant of dsa and in 1995 the
ieee p1363 working group
uh proposed the current form of ccsa and
then a couple of uh standards were
involved in iso on c
and then finally in u3000 the ieee
standard um also in the year 2000
the fips updated its standard in 186.2
it included also ecdsa
in particular included 15 elliptic
curves that were chosen by
jerry salinas at that time at the nsa
including the sort of the most used uh
nistp2556 curve
so the most recent thing that happens at
a couple of updates in the years on the
standard so fips
186 three and four happened and then
finally in 2019 fips 1865
which is currently a draft standard
interestingly it forbids signing with
dsa
right but verification is still looking
but also
interestingly includes adverts dsa which
is
a snore variant of what it's a snore
signature essentially
okay so now the question now we're in
the year 2 2021
and who is actually using ecdsa or dsa
signatures
well first answer is i did use it so i
used my laptop and you know said open
ssl client connect wikipedia and there
it actually says
uh yeah
did you have different encryption and
ecdsa so
in this used uh cdsa for signatures
um you can also uh look at sources
and uh well i'm thankful for for a
number of people for providing these
sources
so there's a web page called the notary
ic
at berkeley uh has data from july 2018
and it says
by over ssl connections we have more or
less
twenty percent of ecdsa signatures and
uh
the other part is eighty percent is rsa
the picture is a bit it's similar in tls
which is twenty five percent of
bcdsa but now we have a bit more uh
recent data from from this month from
mozilla interestingly almost 100 support
ecdsa
of a certain type no but of course this
is always a negotiation
and not always this algorithm is used
it's just that the
the servers depart this in terms of
certificates
you can lose look at the census io
and uh well the the computation that i
did
and again this month is that like seven
percent of the uh
certificates are based on ecdsa
so car 2x communication um i ask a
couple of people and
they tell me it's mostly ecdsa
interestingly so in cars that's actually
used it's also a campaign
in a in the in the standard ieee 1609
too uh mainstream cryptocurrencies there
are mostly ecdsas like let's
say bitcoin and and others
and that's also the reason why there's a
more recent interest in ecdsa signatures
people constructed threshold signature
schemes multi-party
signing protocols adapter signature
schemes
i think we also seen a couple of works
here at a pkc
and i was not able to find any usage of
dsa at this moment so
if someone from the audience knows where
dsa is still being used uh
please let me know or write it in the
chat i was not aware i asked a couple of
people but also that's not my expertise
anyway so the summary is that the ecdsa
in still in 2021
like 20 25 percent of users is still
high
and the other half is rsis inches
okay um so what is dsa and then what i
will do here is i will present you
an abstraction of dsa it's called
generic dsa
gen dsa and is using a group
of prime order p and lg is a generator
of the group
it's using a hash function that hashes
bit strings to zp
so p is the order of the group it's the
prime but also hashes that use
also uses so something which is called a
conversion function
a conversion function uh we'll see that
later is
some abstract function that uh well
takes group elements and outputs element
again elements from zp
okay so we need the these two uh tools
in order to build a
generic dsa signature by the way this
abstraction is due to brown
the examples that i want to mention
are first of all in dsa ge
the group is a subgroup of finite field
and uh wait
and
suck technical problems
all right and uh the conversion function
is actually taking
an element from the group right which is
the sub group of f fq so this is an
element modulo q
and just take this element which is an
element between zero and q minus one
just take it model u p right that's the
conversion function for
dsa and for ecdsa
the g is actually an elliptic curve over
f q
in wire star's form so
um an element from the curve no an r
from the curve has actually an x
coordinate in the y coordinate
each of them it's a little curve over f
q so each of them is an element of fq
and the conversion function is
essentially just take the x-coordinate
right so from the group to
take the x-coordinate and a modulo key
i think this should be a final video fp
i think i'm i was mistaken so just
taking the x coordinate and then we are
done
okay so these are the two examples of uh
generic dsa
um building blocks how does dsa
look like so key generation so the um
the secret key is a deluxe so the public
key is the g2 dx and that's all
plus the prescription in order to sign a
message
a message is again an arbitrary big
thing what do you do so you first
pick a uniformly random exponent
from zp star little r and compute
capital r is due to the r
and next you compute you apply this
conversion function
to r and compute the little t so um this
is now an element in
zp you also hash the message here
right so hash of m is a little h and
then sort of
so that's this is sort of the signing
equation so the s is h plus t times
x divided by r the whole thing but so
what do you return you return a
signature which is
s and t in zp times zp
so that's a signature and verification
inputs the public key and the message of
the signature and essentially what it
does i want to go through it but
essentially recovers the the capital r
here
right so that so the commitment to speak
no
and checks if the t in the signature
right that one that is output here
equals the conversion function applied
to the
recovered r so the r prime and outputs
one
if and only this is the case all right
so that's that's
the stage so what i forgot here of
course because i just overly simplified
we need to
make some containment checks for a
little s
uh to gt and r prime and signing and
verification but i don't wanna
go into details here so they cannot be
zero or something like that so
that's clear um these a signatures are
actually a special case of elgamal
signatures
um there's a deterministic variant
called ecdsa
it's specified in rfc 696979
and instead of choosing a random r e
times a signature is being signed
it deterministically derives the
randomness and the signature process
by applying it to a hash function and
the c
key right this is like a common a common
way in
in order to de-randomize signatures um
remember this was one of the criticism
like each time a
signing process it's randomized that you
have to choose
a perfect random generator here oh and
this is also where
things went around a couple of times
also in the difficult
version this doesn't really work this
attacks
there's also a couple of
country-specific variants
so there's the russian version you see
ghost there's the chinese version which
is called
sem2 and there's the german version
which is called ec
stands for germany i suppose uh
i mean they're mostly the same they i
mean there's
there's um the only thing the only way
that is
where they're different is that the s is
sometimes computed in a slightly
different way
but i'm not really sure why they which
country needed their own version
all right so that's the definition of uh
dsa
um all right so i want to talk about the
security of
the approval security of dsa signatures
um let's uh say what i want let's define
what i'm going to say about the security
so
standard security notions unforgeability
against chosen message attack or
simply security you have cma security
where the game is the following so the
challenger
generates a public unicycle he sends the
public key to the
bursary that well that can specify a
couple of messages
and one until mq and which he gets
signed and then has to specify a message
and
a signature m star and sigma star sort
of in wins
if the sigma star of the signature is
valid and the message was not varied
before right
i mean this of course captures the
scenario that
the adversary have seen a couple of
signatures on message of his
choice and then still is not able to
forge a
signature on a fresh message there's
also a stronger variant called strong
enforceability
essentially the adversary um
has to as the adversity um
even breaks the experiment if he can
forge
a signature on a message that he has
seen before a signature on
so m star sigma star as a tuple has to
be non
equal m i and sigma i right that's a
strong unforge ability in some scenarios
you actually want to have strong
unforgeability
let me also define two more variants of
this so
unforgeability against one per message
chosen message attack so that's a bit of
an artificial notion
notion that essentially means that all
of the signing queries
mi they have to be distinct
of course this only makes sense that the
signing process is probabilistic because
otherwise the signatures would look the
same so if i asked
twice on the same message then the
signature would look the same if the
if the signing process was deterministic
but in dsa and ecdsa the signing process
is probabilistic so here it actually
makes a different
uh difference and of course this is
equivalent to
standard ufc main ufcma security for
domestic sign
one more um attack goal i want to give
you so this is uniford unforgeability
against
no message attack also known as key only
attack
which is a weaker form again an
artificial form
but i will use it later in my security
setting of the security results
here the adversary does not get any
signatures he is not allowed to make
signing queries
to the experiment right so three notions
unforgeability against chosen message
attack and forged agility against one
per message shows a message attack and
then forge ability against no message
attack
um so maybe one thing about approval
security
just to to define what i mean by that
um brewer security means that security
of a implies a security of b so we
do statements of this firm which is
usually it means
we do that by uh in terms of reduction
so suppose there's an adversary
this orange elephant against uh
a b um against uh primitive
b um then we'd build a reduction that
uses this orange elephant to attack a
and then hopefully this production is
smaller successful whenever b is
successful so that means
that if the existing errors are at
breaks b they also exist and first here
that
breaks a so that means that a implies b
so these kind of statements is what we
prove and prove the security
um well then i wanted to make a standard
disclaimer so
of course crypto can be secure in
practice without like having the label
of google security
no things can be secure in practice
that's that's no problem we don't need
to prove it
but of course a proof gives us a fuzzy
warm feeling that i mean we haven't
really
overlooked something and well but
when students ask me why do you do this
approval security
why i mean i mean engineers are smart
people and they know what they're doing
and they always uh tell the story of uh
of pierre de femme
and i mean you know fema's last theory
you know from um
so i'm looking at the numbers from 1637
so that's the the famous uh
uh theorem that there's no the integers
abc such that
a to the n plus b to the n equals c to
the n for any n
uh greater than two right and that was
proved only in 1994 by
the famous libra and ryers but not
everybody knows that female also made a
conjecture
and he conjectures that the female
numbers female numbers are
numbers of the form two to the two to
the n plus one
right that those numbers are prime um
and it took almost one century so this
conjecture was made in 1650 it took
almost one century
for euler to disprove it in 1732.
so we actually showed that for n equals
five
this number the fifth phenol number is
actually not prime
[Music]
and these are two conjectures that i
think at the time being both looked
reasonable
for for one now we have a proof and for
the other one uh i mean
it was uh clearly wrong right so that
should give you
some idea why a proof is actually
important and gives you this
warm fuzzy feeling i'm talking about and
even in crypto i think it's even more
important now because we're talking
about the security of things so that if
there is actually an attack right
account example an attack
um then things are broken and then this
i mean if it's used in practice this
stuff usually translates to the loss of
money
on the other hand crypto can be insecure
in practice
even being proven secure and that's
sometimes that uh
mathematicians they don't really
understand because improvement is secure
if you write a theorem then things
should be secure but i mean in practice
this is not the case and one of the
famous examples is of course knowing
not talking about uh flaws improves
right but uh
it's a side channel attacks right so
which is like the adversary goes outside
of the model
and this isn't particularly important
for ecdsa because it's very very prone
to side channel attacks
and i'm i'm quoting then bernstein and
he says
every natural implementation of ecsa
makes heavy use of secret branches and
secret area in this case which i mean in
a couple of
timing observations natural observation
natural implementation of ccdsa you can
easily break it
and i will also not did my talk will
also not cover about randomness
which famously uh was the playstation 3
hack from 2010 which also relied on
ecdsa signatures
their bad randomness was used uh
to extract actually the secret key of
ccdsa
well having said that let's look at what
kind of
security research was done on ecdsa
and dsa well these are eprint papers and
what i did i looked i i searched through
the
papers in a very very simple way and
probably it's not very accurate but i
think it gives you a nice picture
so you probably see three waves well i
mean the
covet crisis we all know how these waves
work so this was the first wave
and these first wave of uh security of
results and
dsa and ecds very mostly theory papers
on on the prover security
then there was another peak and then
people sort of invented
well not invented but looked at site
channel security
of uh dsa and then like in 2014
cryptocurrencies uh uh peaked again and
then there was like now it's sort of
it goes up you know i mean i think the
third wave is not over yet
um but overall there's little on
approval security of
ac dsa and dcsa and why is that actually
well my intuition is that this
conversion function of ecdsa
so this f of r is fr moduluq
and or f r
is the x coordinate of the elliptic
curve this is actually
algebraically this is quite ugly oh to
be honest and this
sort of makes any proof very difficult
and this is
i guess by many theoreticians that i
don't want to deal with that i
i don't know what to prove with that and
that's what but many people didn't
really
look at the security of of dsi
signatures
so the question is still like the 2021
how approval secure are
you csa signatures and that's by
coincidence that's the title of this
this talk okay so
how brutal secure is uh do you say cdsa
or
this talk do you say so i will give you
four results here i want to present you
four results
um and i found out that out of these
four security results that there are in
in
the literature only one is well known
um and the one that is well known and
decided all the times
i think it has well some problems at
least
i will come to that later so the first
result that i mentioned is that
so remember that dsa had a hash function
h and this conversion function as the
sphere
conversion function f the first result
considered modeling
both h and f as venom oracles that's as
early as
uh brickell in 96 and many fallout works
the second result was modeling the
group ge the underlying group as a
generic group and that's due to brown in
the third result was modeling age as a
random oracle
so that is an f is arbitrary actually
and that is due to brown and
together with uh manuel farsch
and bertrand petering in 2017 i did some
work and some recent work with the
dometic hartmann unpublished stuff and
the fourth result is that modeling this
conversion function
well using something which we called in
this work again with
manual fashion bedroom puttering
using something which called bijective
random oracle well these are the four
results that i want to give you
um
before i go into details uh i would like
to say there's
other results on the security of ecdsa
that i will not talk about
um there has been several results
of several observations by by brown
who's been really the
the driving force behind the analysis of
dsa signatures
um very interesting reads all of them um
sashford in a uh did some on i think
sufficient conditions for security
and there's other people uh that did
a lot of work in particular uh on the
insecurity
like breaking side channel attacks and
uh breaking the security of dc
um okay so now i want to give you
the result of modeling h and f as a
random oracle
by raquel all right so let's uh recall
what our
gen dsa signatures so this is again
designing routine
just for your reference and the first
theorem was that if
f the conversion function is a
programmable random article the hash
function is also a programmer when a
marker
the group the underlying group is hard
has a hard d-lot so it's
hard with a hot dog problem then this
theorem shows that the generic dsa
incented with gf and h is secure ufc in
a
cm well us cma secure they should be ufc
and my secure
um the proof is based i'm not going to
give the details of the proof it's proof
is based on the forking lemma uh by
ponchov and stern the famous one
um but the observation is of course that
f this conversion function no that was
like the x coordinate of the elliptic
curve this is actually not a random
oracle
right this makes sense to to model this
as a random oracle
in particular in the ecdsa case now it's
the x coordinate of the elliptic curve
this is invertible
random oracle is not invertible and
that's also the reason why
uh by uh why brickell and all the other
authors they don't call this a security
result on
dsa or vcdsa or 10dsa they say
it's a you such a security result on a
variant of dsa which they call dsa-1
when we take dsa and replace this time
96 there was only dsa
so if you take dsa and replace f
by hash function then our security
results apply so it's like
an observation that on a variant of
of dsa another variant was also
considered in these early works
by um
i think in 96 which is dsa2
so instead of it uses the standard
conversion function but instead of just
hashing
um the message it hashes message
and the t that comes up out of the
conversion function
and then again you can apply the forking
lemma and then you can again prove
security
right this was exactly the difference
between
elgamar signatures no which uh
the dsa is a special case of and
a schwa signature so as they mentioned
by schnorr to also hash sort of the
the random nuns or parts of the random
nouns no this was not done by an ipsa
and that
actually has perhaps the proof of schwa
signatures
all right so so much about the security
of modeling fnh as a random oracle but
again as we've seen
this is not really about dsa this is
about a variant of tsa so that shouldn't
matter so much about the security of tsa
so the next is next result is on
modeling the group
as a generic group and this now becomes
a bit
subtle no but it's not too technical so
again here is the
as a reminder that's the dsa function
signing process and the theorem of brown
in the
year 2002 says as follows suppose
f the conversion function is almost
invertible
and almost objective i don't want to
give formal definition of these two
things
but uh these are um
information these are properties of the
function f i mean there's like
they're almost invertible and always
explains itself they're almost
adjective it almost explains itself
these are
um two properties that ecc ecdsa
definitely has
uh so that's the first thing that is
almost invertible and
almost objective uh the hash function is
like these are three security properties
has to be one way
it has to be second pre-match resistance
and it has to be zero finder resistance
i think again i don't want to go into
details here but these are three
reasonable i mean the first two
definitely the third one is also
you cannot you cannot find a a you
cannot find a premature
zero so that's also a reasonable
property of a hash function
the third thing is that g is a generic
group
then a generic dsa is strongly ufcma
secure
that's the theorem of brown
brown also knows this is only applicable
to ecdsa no the
conversion function in dsa is actually
not almost invertible
it's not invertible at all um
but and that was uh an observation made
by sternidol at crypto 2002
ecdsa is actually it's malleable boom
which in particular means it's not
strongly ufc made secure
so why is that the case so ge and ecdsa
is indeed the curve
right so um uh so a
point in elliptic verb has the x and y
coordinates no if if we fix a point
elliptic curve
then it's inverse right so remember now
we're using weird notation
we use multiplicative notation for the
group so usually we use additive
notation for the curve so
inverse is r to the minus one and
multiplicative notation
is r x and minus r y knows that maps on
the y-axis
the point so that means if if f of r is
rx
it's the x-coordinate of the elliptic
curve then f of r is the same as
f of r to the minus one
okay because it forgets the y-coordinate
so that means if you look at the signing
equation that if
s and t is a signature on a message
right and then uh the minus s
essentially well corresponds to the r to
the minus one which has the same t
value which also means it's easy to
verify that minus
s and t is a six also signature on them
so that's what it's called malleability
and that's why it's not strongly
ufcma secure but
um but the proof actually shows that
strongly ufc may secure
and so something is going wrong actually
the proof of brown itself
actually does this bounce the theory of
brown himself actually does not so
bronzer doesn't show that it's strongly
used he may secure
but the truth technique like one to one
like almost riveting
as shown by stern at all is that the
same proof techniques also shows that
strongly ufc masque so that's why i
credited the strong ucma security to
brown
and uh what
so all right so i have to change my
setup otherwise i cannot see what it's
written there
um what sternite i'll actually say about
this
is what goes wrong here is the adequacy
of the model the proof is correct
right but the underlying model is flawed
since it disallows production of
malleable signatures and here in this
talk i think i want to explain a bit
what's
what's really going on here i think
there's a there's a
much deeper reason why why things uh
go wrong here and uh the problem is that
it's exactly
it's not really clear what this means
like um
if you model dsa or generic dsa
in a generic group what does this
actually mean what does this model
how do you model this actually let's try
that in
a let's go through this and let's go
uh let's maybe uh let me start with
giving shupes generic
model from shoepin97 so suppose we have
a cryptographic experiment
defined over some group you might think
of uh just
the discrete logarithm logarithm problem
so g to the x
given due to the x and g uh compute x
okay and the general group model idea is
that adversely can only exploit the
group structure to solve this problem
and the implementation of this idea is
that the access
access to the group is restricted to
random encodings
this is actually in the following way so
the first the
experiment chooses a random injective
encoding pi
from g to some a so a is some subtype of
zero one two
so some bit string is some set that has
to be as these as large as g
sufficiently large and uh
well in when then pi of g says
experiment is executed where each
appearance of a group element is
substituted by its encoding
pi of a and the adversary
only has access to the group with
oracles
um let's go through them to the full
example so this is the
the famous dispute locked example in the
general group model so first of all the
experiment picks a random encoding from
g to a
and then experiment displeatlock picks a
random exponent x
and then sends an encoding of
the generator and an encoding of g to
the x
okay and the adversary wins if he
outputs the x in the end and doing so he
can make
um maximum of q queries
the queries are of the form he sends two
encodings like
editing in a and what is being done is
like here the experiment
inverts these encodings so this is a
group element here
this is a group element here and then
um combines these two group elements
like using the secret
group law and then applies now this is a
group element here what's inside of this
big bracket here
and then and can encodes it again and
this encoding is being outputted
right this is the way the adversary can
access the group this makes sure that
the adversary can
only exploit the group properties and
nothing else and then there's the
shoot bound that the probability and the
probability is over the adversary and
over the encoding that reduces solves
the discrete log in the
jail group model is upper bounded by the
number of fair square divided by the
kubota
which means it's impossible and that
actually matches the lower bound
now um now if we want to mix
the general group model with algebraic
functions
so suppose the experiment no not no not
don't think anymore of the discrete log
now think of more of dsa
involves some non-algebraic function in
the non-algebraic function
it's some function in this case that
like takes elements
from g and outputs some element in set p
like in dsa and think of maybe after the
ecdsa example g is a group and it'll be
curve
group and the um the conversion function
is just taking the x coordinate of the
elliptic curve representation
so here's the group and here is the zp
element
now we live in the soviet genetic group
model
so the adversary can only has access to
encoding so he doesn't see ge but he
sees pi f
elements in g so how do we actually now
model um
so what is fgg so how do you model the
conversion function in the generic group
model
so this so the the conversion function
of ecdsa it's only defined
if r is actually a point on the elliptic
curve
um so it's undefined for like an r which
is
an encoding right so how do you define
this function
i don't know let's try so the first
approach which turns out to be stupid
but i want to give it to you anyway
um nobody has done that so far but just
to make sure that uh
this is not a triple way so which is we
just use
right okay so instead of we just use uh
so we have to define this function so we
just use all right so the
inverse of pi right so we from the
encoding
we go back to the group element and then
we apply the original conversion
function
right that could be an idea at least
this is well-defined okay
but of course then during the experiment
you would output
uh uh the um um
um ftg of r which but really information
about the inverse of encoding which
would uh
which would output some information
about the group element possibly no if f
is
invertible then you would this would
legal elements uh some information about
the group
right so this doesn't make any sense no
that's in the general group model
because it leaks information about the
group and this is what the general model
wants to avoid
right so that doesn't make any sense all
right next try and this is what
so far everybody did so assume actually
now we make the assumption that the
group
so that things actually is the things
are well defined that the group is
actually
well most cases the same as this
encoding set
and then just in fine define the uh
this function here now the the
conversion function for the encoding as
the same as the conversion function here
right so assume that this is a subset
base so it's just to make it well
defined
um well now the problem is that
this implicitly so now what have
we done so we fixed this thing here so
this is
actually fg here right this is fixed
right so let's look what is this
function here
and this function here is actually now
now this function here is actually
f g um connected composed with
pi right so i mean we go from from here
to here
right this is how this function is
defined so this implicitly
modeling it like this implicitly
considers the
uh the initial experiment with
um the conversion function the original
converged function the one we actually
wanted to model
composed with this um
this encoding function which is the
uniformly random encoding function
so this actually means that we modeled
things
with as an model that um conversion
function at an idealized object
which has entropy in it and the bad
thing is that now the
ggm proof can and in some cases did
exploit the entropy
of this of this encoding function um
well this is exactly what happened uh in
in this
sort of the flaw and the security proof
why is
uh ecdsa signatures it's not strongly
secured even though one can prove it
strongly secure
right because there's entropy in it and
so that in the j
group model fgg of r is not fgg of
r to the minus one even though in the
real world it is
like even worse one can even show that
if you define f of r using this way in
the g
group model uh take just cut off half of
the bits
right and like the remaining bits is the
output so half bits of
r f of r is half bits of r this acts
like a random oracle
like this is as good as a random oracle
in the jankwoop model
so this is not very useful
okay so this i hope this was not too
technical i just wanted to show you that
um when you try to model non-algebraic
functions in the jaguar model you have
to take extremely care
um and this was exactly what was done
by brown so the the modeling was was
done like this that
this was the the fgg was uh defined as
fg of r right so that
this modeling was done and that was why
the
proof gives er security result that this
strongly ufcm is secure but i think it's
even
that's even worse and that's like my my
opinion is that don't mix g
and general coup model with nonjab
algebraic operations
um that makes a formal
that the proof is informally correct but
again the
what's the interpretation no so if you
had entropy to it
um then you probably can prove anything
and then as i said this this half bits
uh
example this even is as good as a random
oracle so you're probably
able to prove a lot with this um
unfortunately this the same problems
were
repeated over and over again so for
example in threshold ecdsa
uh the the proof was repeated again um
in in in other crypto that was done
myself
and uh that was done as well and uh even
had my paper uh
more than 10 years ago that sort of did
the same it's not a mistake but it's
like a
it's a it's a sort of a meaningless
result i think
so there are very model things in j
group model with the non-algebraic
function and then sort of concluded that
this is secure but i
with insight i don't think this uh this
this is uh
this is secure it's just an artifact of
the model
my advice here if you want to be strict
and you want to be precise
use not do not use shupes general group
model no because this has always entropy
use maura's genetic group model which is
much more precise because it doesn't
generate any entropy it has just unique
handles and that makes things easier
because there is no
non-algebraic primitives in there you
have to somehow define them and you have
to make that explicit
so such yeah and
such unclear security results will be
much more difficult to state
um and one thing i wanted to say is that
you might argue that well this is the
jackhoop model this is an
this is the engineering model i mean
somehow similar the rom probably has
similar problems but the rom doesn't
have similar problems
because the hash function the random
oracle models the hash function as
as perfect and ideal
but uh the hash function is still has
the same domain in range
so the random argument does not have any
similar problems
right because it's not it's not algebic
because it's not about
algebra it's just about hash function
and making
modeling hash functions perfectly random
i think is useful
a group in this setting might not
uh okay so that's the result on the uh
security in the jail group model so the
next
result i want to give is that modeling
age as a random article that was brown
and
and then later a bit formalized into
more papers
so in the random oracle model um
the model h the hash function as a
random article
and the model f as something arbitrary
so can we whatever you want for the
moment
okay let's see what you would like to
prove is that the discrete log
implies ufc may security but of course
we cannot prove that we can prove
only that the semi d log implies ufc
male security so what is the simi
dialogue that was
that is again was proposed by brown
so the cme d log essentially given a
public key
you want to forge a gsa a signature on a
message
that attaches to one what does it mean
it's like input g and x compute and s
prime and t such that t
equals f of g times x to the t the whole
to the s prime
so that's the cmd log
what we can prove is the first theorem
that if f is arbitrary
h is a programmer random oracle and g is
a group with heart
simi d log the first result is that then
these a is uf anime secure so no message
secure
so it means that these two things are
actually equivalent
okay the second result that there is
that
um but the same with the same so f is
again arbitrary h is a programmable
random oracle
then and the third thing is that the dsa
is nma secure so we start from here then
it's also uf one cma secure and remember
that one cma security was
um only one
so each message can only be queried once
okay and of course for digitalistic
fertilistic schemes these two things are
equivalent the third result that there
is is that
from you might ask yourself if you can
go from non-message security to cma
security
a full cma security not one cma is a
full cma security
the third theorem actually says that
this is impossible
with some restrictions of restrictions
of course
all right um all right so uh
let's uh try at least to prove something
or to give you an idea how to prove
something like that
so let's prove that no message security
implies one scene execute the third
the second tier so suppose on that side
we have an adversary against
one message uh one cma security
um we want to build in diversity b
against
no message security okay all right this
is the experiment this experiment sends
a public key that
the green experiment the reduction sends
over
um the one cma adversary will ask
some signatures on messages they have to
be distinct
might do some random oracle queries um
and then in the end i'll put the forgery
m star on the
forgery sigma star on the message star
um okay and then the
reduction also outputs the same fortune
all right and then the idea is that here
we they cannot ask for signing queries
so some of you have to simulate all the
signatures
without knowing the secret key so that's
going to be the tough part
the other tough part is going to be
sometimes you're going to program the
random article
and h is the random oracle that is uh
by this one c made vsp and h prime is
the random oracle just to make them
distinct by the anime
experiment okay so sometimes you want to
program and sometimes you want to
you know you want to query and hand over
the result
right so how do you simulate these
signatures here
so this is again the real signing of uh
of dsa signatures and how do you
simulate things right
so um you pick a random am and a bm for
each m
m is not fixed and instead of defining
r as d to the r you do define r as
d to the b i'm going to leave at the
subscripts g to the b times x to the a
which means the r
little r is implicit explicitly defined
as b
plus a times x okay that's the pick
and while you compute your t the way
it's done in the real signing
and now what you do that's that's that's
the
main trick so you program the random
article as b times t
divided by a right and note that
this is still uniformly random because
the b and the
a you only know one linear equation
about this so this is still uniformly
random
and now we can look at the the the s
value which is
which is h of m plus t times x divided
by r so you can plug things in
blah blah blah and you will see the x
cancels out so you can actually define
the s
as t divided by a and which is
independent of x so you can simulate
things
right so sigma is s smt as defined here
is actually a valid signature on m and
it has actually the right distinction
okay and that's essentially the whole
trick here and the only thing where you
have to take care
is that um well sometimes you want to
program the renault here
right and sometimes you want to carry
the the function here why
because if the adversary outputs a
forgery on m star
right so only if we
vary the random market so we hand over
this if the the random oracle values
they are they agree on m star
only then a forgery here will also be a
forgery up here
and here you have to apply something
which is usually called a coron trick
some some guessing is involved which
means that the reduction
loses a number of signing queries
in in tightness okay
so that's this proof and note that sort
of the proof
makes use of the fact that this is a one
seaman adversary
because if the adversary had asked for
two twice the same
message here we could only so this this
technique only allows
us to simulate one of the signing varies
because so that we committed
here in the age of n be committed to b
times t divided by a and that only
allows us to
um to establish one signing query not
button not another signing query with
distinct randomness okay
um
[Music]
okay so um one can also show that
there is no algebraic reduction from
that shows that
ufc nma implies full ufcma
so this is sort of optimal but i don't
wanna an interest of time and i wanna go
give you details here so let me skip
that
um and let me go to the conclusions so
what we showed in the random oracle
model so if f is arbitrary
h is a random oracle then we showed
actually the semi-dispute logarithm
problems equivalent to one
you've one cma security that for
deterministic
uh dsa this is equivalent to ufc my
security
but you're not able to prove um you've
an mma secure you've seen my full ufc my
security
all right that's forbidden by a theorem
figure that i didn't show the proof of
and interesting so we can boil it down
to see me discrete log
but we cannot go to this the discrete
log and of course this is not possible
because
all these results that i gave here are
for arbitrary f
i mean here at some point you have to
exploit some
some properties of f to show that this
implies this no and this would be
would be here but here we don't know if
the discrete log and c minus g log are
equivalent
what we know is that by um
from 2005 that there is no algebraic
reduction that proved
discrete block implies youth in a new
anime security but in the
in the standard model right no random
orders involved
right what are the takeaway messages uh
for this
the first use deterministic ecdsa if you
can
right because then you get full uc may
security
but of course in some applications this
is not possible like
threshold signing might be difficult to
deterministically agree on on randomness
and of course if you want to try to
break the dsa or ecdsa
then try to exploit that no so ask
so we gathered two signatures on the
same message
and somehow try to exploit special
properties of s
f to break it that's the only way
that there is okay
so let's also extend to ergamal
signatures and
and to sm2 ghost and eg gtsa
okay um so the fourth thing i wanted to
say
is the model f using a bijective random
oracle
and i think i only have five more
minutes so i'll try to go through that
quickly skipping all the proofs um
all right so um in the bijective random
oracle model the model f
not as a random oracle as it's been done
before but a bijective
random oracle what does it mean so the
problem with modeling the conversion
function f as a random article as done
in dsa-1
is that f is invertible now the idea is
to model f
to be invertible and at the same time to
destroy
all algebraic structure right and we do
that
by um decomposing f into
phi times pi times psi
so phi maps g into
its strings zero into the l and then we
apply
a permutation here pi that
outputs an integer same format and then
implies
psi to get an element in zp for example
in ecdsa
the five function would be take
an ep curve element and then compute the
field to string
right it's a field and then computer
string out of it
of the x coordinate the pi
function is the bijective random oracle
which is well what is a budget random
oracle it's like a
random oracle but it's objective you can
query it on x it will give you pi
of x uh and you query it on y and it
gives you pi of minus one of i so you
can
create both directions pi and pi to the
minus one but otherwise
it acts as a perfectly random object and
the psi
is well just inputs a t and outputs an
integer
which is essentially the same as the
string just converts it to an integer
um what we can show with this modeling
and that was
again a paper from uh 2016
that the first of all the discrete log
assumption or the discrete problem is is
equivalent to uf
mma security in the random oracle model
in the projector freedom oracle model
and the ufma security is equivalent to
ucma security again in the budget of
random oracle model
and so that shows that the street lock
implies ucma security
and we only need division cycle division
resistance for the hash function h
which is defined here so that is a bit
unusual definition but it's
true for example if h is a random arca
um for random beta and beta prime
that are given to the adversary as
defined in m and m prime
such that hash of m times size beta is
hash of m prime times
psi theta prime whole thing model of p
right that's unusual but uh
anyway so that's what we found out and
the theorem says that
if f is decomposed is semi-injective
it's again some information with the
property
it's a pi is a programmable objective
random oracle
the aegis has this property of being psi
division resistant the group is
hard discrete log group then the generic
dsa is
european anime security and in
that assumption we can also prove that
genetically is a if you've seen a
security
okay psi being semi-injective is that
it's either two to one or it's injective
okay um all right
so i will skip the proof
um it essentially it's using the
fork lemma and rewinding um to
extract the discrete log um
well maybe the the
breaker the takeaway messages i want to
give is that
what we did is we saw in this in this
work we modeled this uh
conversion function where pi is a
bijective random oracle um i think it's
a bit more realistic than just modeling
f as a random oracle but it's possibly a
bit
too strong abstraction of f so it's not
really
i'm not entirely sure what it means in
practice but at least it's a step
towards
proving something about east dsa and
that's
so far as i as i know it's the best
known pool security guarantee for
full ufc my security of vcdsa
remember if just um just having
a h2 random article only gives you
you've one cma security of cdsa
okay so these are my conclusions my
summary so to speak
um so i showed you four security results
and here's sort of
some rating in terms of how good is the
modeling how how well does it
represent reality and what is the
quality of the security result
so first of all was the h and f are
random oracles no then we have full uc
mail security from discrete log
the modeling is pretty bad because f is
not a random oracle no so that doesn't
get any star for modeling
security is great because we have ufcma
security from the d-lock
but anyway the modeling is is not useful
again if g was a generic group
then we have full uc-ma security no
information therapy general group model
again i hope i convinced you that i
don't really like the modeling no
because of this non-algebraic properties
of f
but the security still would be a great
result but some other modeling is not
really not really right the third result
is that
h is a random oracle f can be arbitrary
then you have one cma security
is implied by the semi d log
problem again the the modeling is great
because the only thing that we do is the
model h is the random article right
that's pretty realistic and there's no
almost there's no um property if we have
to assume
of f so bonding is great but the
security is not as great
right because we only prove it from a
non-standard assumption and we only have
one cma security
the fourth result where i didn't give
you too much details is that if you
model
if you could decompose f um and the pi
like the inside thing is a bijective
random oracle that destroys all
algebraic structure
then we get ufc may security from the d
street lock assumption
again the modeling is not as good but
it's better than nothing i would say
um and the security is good because it
again shows full ufc mail security from
the g speed clock assumption
okay so a couple of open problems
um so the the second result talks about
generic group
model with non-algebraic operations and
i gave you my opinion that i don't
really like the
the current proofs at least not the
interpretations but i think
more people should think about that and
verify maybe
maybe i'm wrong no but uh let's see what
is what is the exact meaning of these
proofs
in the gen group model that involve
non-algebraic objects
um like talking about the third result
um
so this bootstrap security from the
hardness of the cme d-lock
problem um it's not really well
understood this problem nobody studied
it so far but i think it's as
as far as we can go and this should
deserve some more
some more uh analysis not cryptanalysis
but maybe we can
sort of prove it doesn't uh it's it's
not implied but this could block or
i don't know some more realistic
modeling of f would be
it would be great and so there are
several issues in terms of tightness
all those reductions that i gave some of
them are not really tight
and uh okay so that's the state of the
art of
generic gsa's signatures
um that's my last slide so i'm gonna
give you my conclusions
and my personal conclusion is that ecdsa
signatures are nice
but we don't really understand their
security yet there's some preliminary
results but
we don't really know if their approval
is secure or not so what i would
actually recommend
is use adverts dsa
um the csa is not
ecdsa instantiate with a adverse curve
is actually a schnoor signature together
with a specific adwords curse
plus statistic signing plus some more
tricks to make it more efficiency
make it more efficient it is actually
superior to ecgsa and all
measurable metrics so it's more simple
it's easier to implement it's more
efficient it has
proven security it's more versatile it's
like
it's more like really more everything um
schnoor was not used because it was
patented in the in the 90s but 20 years
later no uh
the pattern expired a long time ago so
that's why it's not used
and surprisingly like it's good to see
that adverse gsa is used in gls
ssh signal tor and a couple of
major major projects
alternatively fleet you could also use
bls it's full domain hash signatures of
verbal linear maps
and that's used in the version 2 of the
blockchain ethereum
of igrund and also it's used in in gea
and it has the advantages even more
versatile than adverse gsa so there are
some more so all these protocols
threshold and
aggregation these are much more natural
with bls signatures now of course
and i want to conclude with that also if
you want to have post quantum security
so we talked about the discrete log
i just use uh the lithium or any other
of the
round through pre uh post quantum
candidates so far they're secure and
they're efficient and they offer
post-quantum security
okay um i think that concludes my talk
and i want to say thank you for your
attention
all right thanks very much okay we'll
owe you the round of applause
uh very impressive uh nice uh overview
so unfortunately we are already
uh five six minutes into the break and
we have to start in a few more minutes
but i think you have access to there are
a few interesting questions in
both uh both uh zulip and the chad
it'd be helpful if you just look at them
and questions about
the a the algebraic the agm
and some more questions on zolip
so if you have a chance just you know
take a look and answer them all right
and again thanks a lot
for giving this talk and we are going
into the break