okay you're good to go have a good
session
uh okay thanks k and kevin uh hi
everyone uh welcome to the
pkc 2021 thursday session and um i'm
going to co-chair in the session with
akshay
um this session is about the
crypto crypto protocols and i
probably as most of you know the each
talk will have
about 10 minutes if we have uh some
short short time we have a short
questions without further ado let's
start the session the first talk is a
flexible and efficient verifiable
computational encrypted data
those are alexandra ignacio dario and
dongwoo
i think dongwoo will be giving a talk
so if you are around could you start
sharing your slides
and don't go i o around
yes let me start okay okay
okay
can you see this
uh yes yeah okay sorry for the
slow okay hi everyone hi
i'm donkey i will talk about flexible
and fg verify computational encrypted
data
this is a joint work with alexander boyd
ignacio cascado and dario fury
okay let me start with the motivation of
our work
we will think about the outsourced
computation where a client our sources
data and computation to
a possibly untrusted server in this case
we can think of two security concerns of
the client
the first one is a data privacy that the
client doesn't want to expose its data
the second one is in computational
integrity that the client wants to be
guaranteed that the result given by the
server is correct or not
for the data privacy we can see that
fully on
encryption can be a solution since it
enables the computation over
the site text and the client can protect
his data
in case of computational integrity we
can use
verifiable computation where a server
provides approval with
its computation result to the client
that the client can verify the result
and here the natural question is if
there is a solution for
this both privacy and integrity which
also provides an efficiency
and in fact there are only a few work
which provides the solution to this
both privacy and integrity among them it
will focus on the theory
gentry and past pastors work which uses
fully-owned encryptions to delegate
computation
then use verified computation on this
site of text computation to guarantee
the integrity
this is quite a simple solution but the
main question here
is that we should design an efficient
paper computation
for this science text computation
and there are a few work provide the
solution to this
problem and our work also provides a
and you can summarize the result of our
work as this at this slide and
we can compare the result of ours with
our other previous
the main point is that we can work with
any prime
any fully on fingerprint modules with
any module skew
while the previous work can work only
with
the prime modulus which is about
256 bits for 128 bit security
for this our we introduced the new
homework cache
which is just a ring home vision from
this two variate ring
with questions from prime power modulus
to the gallery ring
then we apply this gkr particle over
this string
which can verify the computation over
i can give the overview of our solution
the verifier first our sources is data
in encrypted form with some of
encryption
this life text can be seen as two
variate polynomial with coefficient from
this
prime power module string then the
prover gives back the result
then instead of verifying this
computation the verifier samples the
whole cache which is just a ring more
feasible from the side text space
to the gallery then the proverb gives
back
the profound the skyrowing space
then the verifier can verify this
computation instead of
the subtext competition here the point
is that
these verified computation on this ring
is much smaller
cost in than the computation
or vapor computation on this large ring
we can see the efficiency of our
solution by seeing some example
parameters
here uh we can see that the cipher
string
has degree like this 2 to the 11 or even
15 while the coloring which is the
target of our verification
is has degree much less than the
ciphertext ring
so we can also gain efficiency in this
verified computation
and we can also compare the previous
work with ours
in the previous work the bb scheme the
whole encryption scheme
should must also use the parameter with
low cube
bigger than 250 which also gives that
the degree of cipher space should be
bigger than 2
to the 14 or more while we can use these
small parameters
in our scheme and yeah this
is the end of our talk and thank you
very much for your attention
very nice talk thanks donal is that
if you have any questions feel free to
unmute yourself and ask here
seems any question
um since we have one one minute i have a
very good question so
it looks like the the nice technical
tool of a new
homomorphic hash right yeah do you find
it like
any other broader applications of this
uh new primitive
the primitive yeah yes
maybe we can use this technique to
verify some same operations
so if we want to verify many other
bigger polynomial
operations on bigger polynomials then we
can reduce this with our hash
so we can verify that yeah i think we
can
use this technique in others verify
computation over
other things then this one
inclusions okay okay great thanks
uh if is there any other question
if there's no more question let's move
to the second
talk our second talk will be
transferable ecash
a cleaner model and the first practical
instantiation
from bausa gurg and chen
i think balzaza will be giving the talk
yes i'm here do you hear me
yeah yeah can you share your skirt yeah
do you see is it enough good
yes
okay so
[Music]
hello everyone i'm balthazar boyer and
i'm happy to present you a
transferable ecash a cleaner model and
the first practical instantiation a
joint work with
georg foxbower and chen can
so first i would like to speak quickly
about the history of ecash
so ecash is a basic payment system with
three types of entities a bank
which is authorized to issue a coin to a
user
yeah alice who is allowed to spend this
coin
at the shop which can thus deposit this
at the bank it is very easy
to make such a system with basic
cryptographic functionalities
such as signatures but the goal here
is also to protect the privacy of the
users and
the merchants against a curious bank
and to be more precise about what does a
transaction anonymity mean
in the model of charm the inventor of
the cash
with his definitions we have the
guarantee that
the bank can't identify the kind issued
as the kind received it means that the
bank
cannot link alice and the merchant
as it is written here chum has not only
defined the main oceans
but has also built a first instantiation
in the 80s
the main drawback of
such a system in the offline context is
a non-transferability
indeed the merchant cannot directly
spend the coin received
to another merchant
that's why more recently researchers
have developed more powerful schemes
which merge the user merchant statuses
by authorizing an arbitrary number of
transfers without any communication with
the bank
and of course we would like to still
have anonymity guarantees
i will not details all the numerous
publications
about transferable cash but the
important thing to know is that in
2015 baldimet chs foxboro and coldweiss
proposed the first polynomial time
scheme
which verifies satisfying anonymity
properties
now i would like to speak about our
contributions
by comparing it to the work of 2015.
first we have rewritten the anonymity
definitions
then we have added missing economical
properties
and finally we have built a more
efficient construction
about the anonymity definition i would
like to introduce
a notion which is specific to
transferable cache
contrary to the standard model of cache
in
transferable cache a user can receive a
coin he has previously owned
then we have to define a feature which
protects
us against such a curious user for
example here
we do not want to authorize a list to
link
the current transfer to charlie and the
coin received
from the store we call this property
coin transparency
now let's explain briefly how our scheme
work
so suppose alice wants to withdraw coins
and
she would generate a serial number
and ask the bank for a signature on it
and if bob wants to receive
this coin he should also generate
a serial number sn1 which will become a
part of the coin
and a list to confirm the transfer will
create
a tag related to both serial numbers
and which encodes identity and will be
required
to address so-called double spendings
and bob will do the same with charlie
for the next transaction
now let's consider alice once double
span her coin
to bobet then bobet will generate a new
serial number
sn1prime and alice has to create
another tag t1 prime that links
her already used serial number sn4 with
a new
one of bobet sn1 prime
and if we consider that both coins
are deposited at the bank
then by noticing twice the same initial
three and
serial number the bank will detect the
fraud
and by the property of the tags
two tags for the same initial serial
number
leak the identity of the double standard
here alice so now a good question is
how to make such a system anonymous
first by using a blind signature
we guarantee that the bank can't
organize an issued kind
then we have to modify the scheme
to achieve the previously defined coin
transparency nation
indeed since the coin contains the
serial numbers
alice could easily recognize account
when she received
it again so we will hide the serial
number by using
commitments to do it and give zero
knowledge proofs
that the committed values are correct
for alice not to be able to recognize
the commitments we will randomize the
commitments and proofs
which can be done for grocery proofs
however now the bank cannot check for
double spendings
we will therefore include encryptions
of serial numbers and tags
which the bank can decrypt
uh of course this cypher text
must also be randomizable so we will
reconstruct a new complexity
[Music]
cca encryption scheme
and yeah and and
yeah and now i would like to thank you
for your attention
and if you have questions i would be
happy
to answer them thanks for the nice talk
uh any questions from an audience
just feel free to unmute yourself
yeah so you mentioned that you model
some economic considerations so
what what what are those
okay so
the in previous model
if someone spend a coin
honestly received we
we can imagine he can break the coin
then he didn't
create new money but he breaks the coin
and he transfer it to someone
and the receiver
has no guarantee he can detect the fact
the coin is broken
so this we it's this type of attack
was not considered in the previous
scheme
so but it's an important
property because it guarantees to a
receiver that a
transferred coin can be transferred to
another honest user
and has not been broken
i don't know if it answers to me
what is what does it mean to be broken
exactly
uh no there is no double spending
because in this case the
the the adversary
does not create money it just break
money
but it's
theoretically it's theoretically
possible
that he that he
convinced you to
the coin is valid but after you accept
you have accepted the coin
you cannot transfer it again
but it may be as yeah it could seem
very weird because he has not created
money but if
he's heavily he can just wants to
destroy
your money you have accepted
and yeah thank
uh you also one quick one question in
zulip
uh where do the serial numbers come from
uh you mean as a primitive
you mean the history of
the syrian yeah that's just a very
simple question
in the zulu or maybe if the answer is
pretty longer than you you may
answer directly at zulip but guarantees
their uniqueness
so so the serial numbers are created
with a
secret key of owner of users
and yeah he
two different users can't have the same
serial numbers
that's a very good answer but maybe you
can chat more in the loop
okay i i will check
thanks again and let's move to the next
talk
next one is a beta biometric enabled
threshold authentication
from zhonjang uh say christina
payman and uh
zika i think sakura sheena will be given
the talk
about maybe you should stop sharing your
screen
uh i'm just trying to share my screen
sure
uh do you see my screen uh yes can i do
the presentation mode
yeah yeah good enough
um so thanks for the introduction and uh
yeah uh my name is sai krishna i'm going
to be talking about a paper
titled beta which is an acronym for
biometric enabled threshold
authentication
um this is a joint work with shashank
payment pratiyan sugar
so first let's
let's look at how traditionally
biometric authentication
works you have an enrollment phase
where the user stores and draws their
biometric template and stores it on a
server
and then in an online phase when the
user wants to authenticate themselves
they enter the new biometric measurement
onto their mobile phone
um for example and then the phone
transfers this measurement over to the
server that stores
all the um biometric templates in the
enrollment phase
the server privately checks whether the
entered biometric measurement
matches the user's original template or
not and if so it authenticates the user
as as we all know biometrics provide
better usability than passwords
but unfortunately a server-side breach
of biometrics is much more damaging
than in the case of passwords because
you cannot really change them that
easily
the fido alliance is a recently uh
popular industry-wide standard
for replacing this traditional solution
to biometric authentication
and the way it works is as follows now
in the enrollment phase
when the user enters the biometric
template it's no longer sent over to a
server
but instead the biometric template is
stored locally on the user's device
the device then generates a secret a
signing key and a verification key
and only sends over this verification
key to the server
storing the secret key locally and then
in an online phase
when the user wants to authenticate
themselves they enter the biometric
measurement
the phone locally checks whether the
entered measurement matches the template
or not
and if the match is successful the phone
is able to unlock the signing key
and generates a signature on a
server-generated challenge
to prove to the server that the user was
able to correctly authenticate
themselves
okay while this solves the problem that
uh the server doesn't need to store
every user's biometric template
there are still a couple of concerns
here the first is that now naturally
once again the phone is a single point
of failure
and anybody who's able to break into the
phone can steal the users by metric
and then in order for the user to
authenticate themselves they need to
take
care on the same device every time along
with themselves
in this work our idea is to propose a
new notion to
distribute fido and we introduce a new
primitive called a fuzzy threshold
tokenizer which works as follows in the
enrollment phase when the user enters
their biometric template
instead of storing it entirely on this
single device
the idea is we want to secret share this
biometric template and also the signing
key
amongst a set of devices that the user
owns
so the phone now generates different
shares and sends across each share to
one device that the user owns
and then of course sends the public the
verification key to the server
you could also imagine a setting where
each of these different devices
are not necessarily the user owned
devices but it could also be some
multiple servers that are not controlled
by the user
depending on the application scenario
and then what happens in the online
phase is that now when the user enters
the biometric measurement
instead of the phone locally checking
the measurement
with the template the phone now runs an
mpc protocol
interacting with various different other
devices that
that whole secret shares and this
protocol checks whether the entered
measurement
matches the original template or not and
if indeed there was a match
the protocol also generates a signature
on the server generated challenge
before sending it along to the server
and um
and how do we leverage the threshold
structure
and what is the communication pattern in
such a primitive
the idea is that now in any
authentication session in the online
phase we want the user to be able to
involve only some threshold number of
devices and not necessarily all the
devices that store
that hold one share of the key and the
template
we don't want we don't want to require
all these devices to
be able to talk to each other in
particular we want
we want a communication pattern where
all the communication is routed only
through the initiating device
in this case in this diagram the phone
out here
and finally we don't want the user to be
required
to every time login or authenticate
themselves only using the same device in
particular
any of these devices that hold one share
of the template and the signing key
could be treated as the initiator onto
which the new measurement is in
is and turn into this way
we saw one concern that we had earlier
where the same device needs to be used
every time
in the authentication phase
so this is briefly the description of
the perimeter
and let's look at what are the goals or
the security goals we would want out of
such a primitive
suppose we consider the malicious
adversary that corrupts a set of devices
maybe less than t
the first requirement is that we want
privacy of the biometric template
that was entered in the enrollment phase
and then naturally we also want privacy
of the biometric measurement that was
entered in the authentication phase
so no single device should be able to
learn any information about
either of these values and then we want
unforgivability
in this context that means that an
adversity should not be able to generate
a valid signature
without actually running the protocol on
a valid measurement
what do i mean by a valid measurement it
means that the measurement
that that is used in the online phase
should match the template that was
stored in the enrollment phase
moreover we also require that in any run
of the session
no more than a single signature should
be generated by the adversary
so if you want to generate two
signatures you should necessarily run
two sessions using two valid
measurements maybe the same one also
and briefly the results we obtain is
that we we have a new primitive
for threshold biometric authentication
we provide a formal security model with
uc security
and we give three protocols with various
trade-offs
the first protocol works for any number
of parties with any
corruption threshold it's a feasibility
result based on tour on npc
the second protocol is also a
feasibility result and this one is based
on threshold fxe
both of these protocols work for any
distance metric uh by distance metric i
mean that the biometric matching
mechanism is not tied to any single uh
way of matching to biometrics the third
protocol works for the notions
called cosine similarity or euclidean
distance both of which are popular
metrics for fingerprint and face shield
recognition
uh this protocol is uh is a concretely
efficient one
it's based on prior encryption uh but
unlike the first two protocols this
works for the most specific setting
where
the number of the threshold is only
three and the adversary can corrupt at
most one of the three devices
um and i'd like to end here thank you
for listening
thanks for the presentation uh do you
have any
quick question we have like one minute i
have one quick question
sure if i have as i do three devices
and two of them are turned off so that
there's only one party involved does it
reduce to the original problem
um if you have only one device in uh
involved in our solution
unfortunately you wouldn't be able to
authenticate yourselves um
the reason being that we don't want any
single device to be
able to hold the entire
signing key or the biometric template
but if you wanted such a feature to be
enabled then you're right that
it would just reduce to the original
setting because each device should now
be locally able to
do the matching and and the second thing
is
if all three devices are capable of
biometric
verification do i have to enroll all
three of the devices
so that they're they're sharing shares
with each other
uh any one device can be the one running
the enrollment phase and
that device could then generate the
shares and send it across to the
other devices with the way we modulate
is by assuming that there is a
trusted phase a trusted setup phase that
happens at that point so that no single
device
stores the shares um locally even after
the enrollment phase
that's very interesting so that if i
enroll on one device i'm basically
enrolling
all on all 10 devices yeah that's
connect
okay thanks for the question and thanks
for the talk again
uh our next talk will be
private set operations from oblivious
switching
it's from uh gaia three ir3 payment mike
saeed and jasper thank you so much for
the introduction
i'm gayathri and i'll be presenting
private set operations from oblivious
switching
this is joint work with payment mohassel
mike rosilick says
jaspal singh so let's get started
in psi alice has a set x bob has a set y
and we want alice to learn the
intersection
in recent years there has been much work
to make psi practically very efficient
both in the semi honest and malicious
setting
but many real world applications lead us
to ask the question
what if alice only wants to learn some
partial or
aggregate information about the
intersection for instance just the
cardinality
consider this example proposed in this
paper by authors from google and
columbia university
their goal was to measure the
effectiveness of their online
advertising
so they wanted to know the number of
people who both viewed an
ad online on their platform and then
went on to buy a related item offline
and they also wanted to know the total
transaction amount generated by such
people
in the most general terms what we're
looking for
is that alice and bob are able to learn
some function
f over the intersection for any function
of their choice
so we call this private computation on
set intersection
there have been some works that have uh
in this direction
and the state-of-the-art protocol was
given by pinkish schneider kachenko and
yani in 2019
and i'll call this the psty protocol
so let's start by identifying a
performance gap between psi and pcsi
for a million items in the semi-honest
setting computing the intersection takes
well under a minute
but for the fastest pcsi protocol even
computing something like the cardinality
takes around 9 minutes
so concretely this is 20 times slower
and needs 30 times more communication
so let's see why this is and how we can
bridge this gap
so the psty protocol starts with a
pre-processing phase
at the end of this step we are in we end
up with the following situation
alice has a fixed ordering of her items
and alice and bob learn vectors s and t
such that s i and t i are an additive
sharing of 0
if x is in the intersection otherwise s
i and t i are a narrative sharing of a
pseudo-random value
so if alice learns that s1 is equal to
t1 then she can conclude that x1 is in
the intersection
so clearly it's not safe for alice or
bob to learn the outcome of
any individual comparison because that
would leak something about the contents
of the intersection
and that's not allowed in pcsl so what's
done
is the comparisons are made inside some
general purpose mpc protocol
and the results are fed into another
circuit into a circuit f
which will compute f on the intersection
so comparing two l-bit strings in a
general purpose
mpc requires order l times kappa
communication
in the psty protocol the comparison
circuit accounts for 96 percent of the
communication cost
in concrete terms in contrast if you
look at psi
comparing two l bit strings just takes
four point five times kabab it's a
communication
notice that it's independent of the
length of the strings
but the caveat still remains that alice
or bob learn the outcome of each
individual comparison
so our goal is that we have these
special purpose equality tests which are
really efficient
and we want to somehow make them
compatible with this pre-processing step
so our main idea is that we shuffle the
equality tests
according to some permutation that's
known to alice
then it becomes safe for bob to learn
the output of the equality tests
so basically he only ends up learning
the number of strings that match
but the oblivious shuffling network
breaks the correlation between the
strings that match and the items that
they correspond to
so we call these three steps our
protocol core
and asymptotically we go from order nl
times kappa
down to order n log n times kappa for
the shuffling cost followed by order n
times kappa for the equality tests
in almost all cases log n is much much
smaller than the length of strings
so we give both an asymptotic and
concrete improvement
so we can summarize our contributions as
follows
we give a new protocol for pcsi provided
it's always safe to leak the cardinality
of the intersection
this gives us 2.5 to 3 times lower
communication
as a result of which we have faster
running time on slower networks
our main construction is what we call
our protocol core
and once we have this we're able to get
secret shares of the intersection
which can then be fed which can then be
fed into any circuit which will compute
f over the intersection
we also show that protocol core can be
used directly
to realize some interesting
functionalities like
cardinality we also get a protocol for
cardinality sum
without having to compute the secret
shares of the intersection
we also get a faster protocol to compute
the union's
union of the sets although it doesn't
strictly fit into the pcsi framework
and this union protocol can be used to
realize a functionality called private
id
which was proposed in this paper and
ours is the first ot extension based
construction for
realizing this functionality
finally i'll leave you with some
takeaways from our performance numbers
and these are the links to our code and
our paper thank you so much for
listening
thanks a lot for the presentation a very
nice talk
any question from the audience we'll
have about 30 minutes
where is the core functionality
instantiated who is doing the
computations so this is a two-party
protocol so it it will be instantiated
by alice and bob together
the first step of the core will be the
psty pre-processing
then alice and bob will do the oblivious
switching which is another two-party
protocol and then
alice and bob will do equality testing
which is another two-party protocol
and where does the shuffling take place
uh so yeah so it's an interactive
interactive protocol between alice and
bob so alice has the power to choose the
permutation
and bob will have like and both of them
can feed an additive shares of some
vector
and then they'll get a re-randomized
additive sharing of the permuted vector
uh is that clear or should i try to
explain it in a different way
uh no but i'm i'm just thinking that
somewhere along the way the lists have
to be sorted in order to perform the
comparison
is that correct uh so we're not doing a
comparison based switching so
we will have like a switching network a
universal switching network like a
banished network or a
walksman network and the guarantee of
that like
such a network would be that like if you
feed in
a vector x then you can realize any
permutation of your choice by
programming it so you have like
programming bits
so you'll have order n log n switches
and if you can program those switches
then you can realize any permutation of
your choice
thank you yeah
okay uh thanks thanks again for the nice
talk thank you i will hand the session
to akshay
uh thanks so the next talk is titled
mass
triples amortizing multiplication
triples across conditionals
uh it's by david vladimir and stennis
law and sten's law will
give the talk
thank you for the introduction let me
share my screen
can you see my screen
yeah uh okay so my name is tim passeni
and this is a joint work with david
heath
and vlad kolesnikov and i will be
presenting
mass triples amortizing multiplication
triples
across conditionals
so in this work i'll be discussing a
classic
npc protocol and this protocol uses
pre-processed multiplication triples to
evaluate arbitrary functions represented
as boolean circuit
and a boolean circuit consists of and
and xor gates and
while evaluating the linear xor gate is
essentially
free the non-linear and gates are
evaluated with
beaver multiplication triples and those
are
expensive to generate
in our work we reduce the cost
associated with generating
these multiplication triples our
improvement
results in significant reduction to both
communication and runtime of this
triple bass protocol
we improved the protocol by carefully
reusing the multiplication triples
in conditional statements of the source
program
traditionally it has been assumed that
we need multiplication triples for all
branches in a conditional
and this is because for security
each multiplication triple can mask
at most one and gate
in this work we show that this is not
necessary and the number of triples we
need
is proportional only to the size
of the single longest branch
prior work looked into conditional
branching improvements under other
protocols
star garbling looked into the problem in
yao scarborough circuit so into bc
and motif which was presented at asia
creek 2020
was the first work that achieved
significant conditional branching
improvement in the multi-party setting
motif worked with the gmw protocol which
is
also related to the triple bass protocol
so
our approach works in a similar setting
to multi but our solution is distinct
and yields a significant concrete
improvement over motif
so i want to very briefly show motifs
limitations
so the key cost in the gmw protocol is
pre-computing random oblivious transfers
which are used to evaluate the and gates
of the circuit
and oblivious transfers or shortly ots
are expensive
public key primitives and motives
improvement stems from amortizing
these ots across conditional branches
motives limitation is
that the improvement is dependent on the
alignment of the and gates
across branches meaning the branches
need to have a similar number of n-gage
and gates in each circuit layer for
optimal performance
in the sample conditional i show
there are two unaligned branches and in
this case
motif would pay for four n gates but the
longest branch has only three n gates
our new work is mass triples and
similarly to motif we
reduce the number of these expensive
random ots
in the triple base protocol random ots
are one way to generate multiplication
triples
and unlike in motif the number of random
ot's we need to generate
is proportional to the size of the
longest conditional branch
so i have introduced the key idea for
improvement
i will now get into more technical
aspects of our improvement
so recall that the xor gates are
virtually free
the triple base protocol cost really
comes from generating triples for the
end gates
hence we would like to reuse a single
triple across
all conditional branches if we are able
to do that
and securely then we have effectively
made all untaken branches free
i will now show how to do that and for
simplicity let's just consider two
branches where the top branches the
taken branch
we would like to use the same triple on
both end gates and the two branches
the key idea behind reusing triple
securely is that we can carefully
apply secret shared masks to the triples
for the inactive branch the priority
sponsor triples with uniform xo shares
of
uniform masks rns thus randomizing the
triples and
preventing us from breaking the security
of
one time pad and by randomizing the
triples we
violate the correctness of the and gate
on the inactive branch but
this is of no concern because the output
of these inactive end gates
are ultimately discarded
for the active branch that is the taken
branch the parties use the triples
as is meaning the active branch is
evaluated normally
of course the party should not know
which branch is inactive so
from the perspective of the parties it
should appear plausible that either
branch could have used randomized
triples
and to achieve this for the active
branch the parties also exhaust masks
onto the triples
but in this case each mask is a uniform
sharing of zero
hence the exuring is a no up
i stress that masking only the a and b
bits of the triple is
necessary and sufficient and uh
to see why please see the full
presentation
or our paper
importantly our approach of significant
concrete improvement because
generating these masks is much cheaper
than
generating additional triples and
unfortunately due to the time
constraints i cannot go into
how the masks are generated but the
details are in the full presentation as
well as
in our paper so i have introduced the
mass triplets protocol
again the key contribution of mass
triples is that we introduce a protocol
that has communication proportional to a
program's
longest execution path in the
multi-party setting
and unlike state-of-the-art motif our
improvement is
independent of the circuit topology so
thanks for listening
and i'm happy to take any questions
so thanks spencer for this nice talk so
any questions to the speaker
that i have no questions uh i have a
quick question so
how do you hide which branch is active
and which is the invalid function
so basically when you're evaluating
conditionals
in in this triple-based protocol you're
evaluating some circuit and then at some
point uh
you branch into one or another branch
and
you have you you have this branch
condition
bit you hold the share of this bit
determines
which branch is actually taken
and since this condition bit
is secret shared you do not know which
which branch will actually be taken
uh any other questions
so let's uh thank uh stanislav again
thank you uh so the next talk is
uh titled two server distributed oram
with sublinear
computation and constant rounds by ariel
uh and mayank and ariel will be giving
the problem
all right um thank you let me just share
my screen
all right um thank you for the
introduction
uh first off i want to apologize if
there are any background noises
there's construction happening in the
apartment below me so
bear with me in this regard
today i will be talking about two server
distributed oram with sublinear
computation and
constant rounds this is a joint work
with mayank
uh varia from boston university
to first describe distributed oram it
was introduced by ostrovsky and shupe
in 1997 and formally defined by lew
nostrovsky in 2013.
it exists apart from the original
oram setting in that it
basically allows for multiple
non-including servers
um to interact with the client and this
distributed nature was first
employed as a way to get around the
lower bounds within oram
particularly today i will be talking
about
the distributed oram in the secure
computation variant
meaning things like mpc for ram
um often we'll use this where the two
servers
not only act as the oram
servers but also uh emulate the
oram client in a distributed way
so there are quite a few works in
this model i've highlighted two of the
more recent ones
that sort of perform the best gordon
cats and wang
are able to get polylog bandwidth
and constant rounds but
they do require local server computation
on each server in order to answer a
particular query
uh directy and wei in 2018 have sort of
the best asymptotics across the board
but they require non-constant rounds in
cases where
bandwidth is
not so much an issue but latency between
rounds are
a non-constant number of rounds is
really not ideal
so in this talk i introduce the first
two constructions
in the secure computation for do-ram
model
that achieve a sub-linear local
computation
and constant rounds the first of which
is a sublinear doram that obtains
square root log n where n is database
size
local computation and bandwidth and
constant rounds
this is based on an adaptation of square
root oram
and second we'll briefly go over the
construction
for our unlimited reads doram
where we leak the difference between
reads and writes
and assume that reeds are much more
common than writes
and this allows us to get better
asthmatic performance
so for the rest of the talk i briefly
want to go over our sublinear doram
construction
and how we managed to do that in
constant rounds
as i said before it is based on square
root o ram and there are two main
problems
in adapting this to the secure
computation setting
rather than just sort of applying a
generic mpc
compiler to a square root orm client
which would result not necessarily in
sub-linear local computation our two
main problems
are reshuffling the um
stash back into the store in constant
rounds at the end of an epoch
and the second is representing the
permutation
over the data in the store in a way that
is
conducive to the secure computation uh
sort of environment so i'm gonna go over
how we solve those two problems
um at a high level our two servers
store um as their store
a permuted additively secret shared
database
so both servers have the same
permutation um and uh
sort of also store um the permeated
secret shared database is a read-only
data structure
in addition to that they also store a
stash
which is going to be a read and write
um where updates can be sort of
cataloged
until the end of an epoch where they're
shuffled back into this permuted secret
shared database
so when an operation is submitted
to a doram in the secure computation
model the operation
itself and the index to be read are also
additively secret shared
so the server does not know what
operation or which index
it is sort of emulating the client on
a read operation basically takes three
steps
um as very much like square root o ram
we simply scan the stash
um to see if the record is already there
depending on that outcome we either read
a dummy or the actual index
from our store and this is where
we first come across how do we represent
this permutation over our secret shared
database
the way we do this is to leverage
oblivious pseudorandom functions or
oprfs
at a high level oprfs allow you to have
the key and the point to be evaluated
for the prf
secret shared amongst two parties and
during the evaluation
they didn't learn anything about the
other person's input but they both
do in fact learn the output so that is
exactly what we do
each server has their own prf key um
the read index is uh secret shared
amongst the two
um and we output and get essentially the
prf
evaluation on this point um we then
are able to look up in the permuted
secret shared database
that is sort of sorted according to
these tax
recover the shares of that as part of
this step
then finally we write this back to the
stash at the current index and increment
that index
so rights are fairly similar um
they only differ in one regard which is
in this third step
where we go to write something back to
the stash
um and in this instead of writing at the
current index
um we are if we sort of
during the initial scan find the place
where that element is stored
when we write back to the stash we write
it back to that specific location if
it's already there
and this is important to maintain sort
of our constant round shuffling
so in particular the invariant that if
an element has been read or written to
already
it is in the stash and each element only
occurs in the stash
once this allows us to essentially
reshuffle in constant rounds in a fairly
straightforward way
essentially what we do is we note that
the unread elements
are public information essentially to
each server
so since we're only reading each element
in the stash
once we simply take those unread
elements at the end of an epoch
and know that the rest of them are going
to be in the stash
and so all we have to do is concatenate
the two of them together
uh permute them obliviously between the
two servers
and then apply a new prf key for a new
permutation
so shuffling becomes constant rounds and
fairly straightforward
um so yay new prf key
um we also provide a doram with
unlimited reads namely we leak the
difference between reads and writes and
assume reads are much more common
we assume we essentially add a second
store to each database using a
appear that has sub-linear server
computation so a secret key deep here by
canadian all and boyle at all
that has an encoding of the database
shares reads happen only from this
database and rights will happen as usual
secret key deep here is
kind of highly amenable to this and
provides a modular extension for pretty
much
any dorm in the setting in order to
approve improve asthmatics
when we assume sort of this
differentiation between reads and writes
as i just said secret kdpir is mostly
local linear ultra computations
so this easily allows us to perform
constant rounds
um and of independent interest we do
provide
a fast fourier transform a secure
computation protocol
that is able to sort of run in
quasi-linear time
with only local computations and we use
this
in our secret pdp here for polynomial
interpolation and evaluations
so in summary we're able to get two
protocols the first of which that have
sublinear local computation and constant
rounds in the secure computation
uh do-ram setting and we're able to get
better performances
when we sort of leak the difference
between reads and rights
um thank you for listening to my talk
please feel free to reach out to me if
you have any questions i will note i
have not been able to get on the zulu
chat so please feel free to reach out to
me via email
they both should be on the eprint
so thank you yeah thanks ariel for the
interesting talk
we have time for a quick question
ah so i have a question so how does this
oprf
assumption compare with the prior
non-constant on
protocol uh so do they also need
oprf or can they do it from better
essentials
so um our opr can the particular
instantiation is based on elgamal
encryption um the strongest assumption
is actually hiding in our
unlimited reads doe ram um which is
a new coding assumption based on noisy
uh permuted read muller coats but in our
sublinear doram
um our our assumptions are are
relatively minimal
based on um sort of the underlying
assumptions
of the dorm that we use for our to
implement our stash
which relies on functional secret
sharing
and then our own construction really
only relies on
um uh additively homomorphic encryption
and algomal for
our opr
or any other questions
so let's thank ariel again
uh so so the next uh is a
joint talk of two papers
so the first is multi-party cardinality
testing for
threshold private set intersection by
petro branco nico dotling and srihanku
and the
next is multi-party threshold private
sector intersection with sublinear
communication by say krishna payhan
srinivasan
and peter
so yeah payhan will be
uh thanks actually for the introduction
this is a soft merge of two papers
and i will go first and sahan will
present the other one
uh so our work is multi-party threshold
private set intersection with sub linear
communication
it's joined to work with sai krishna
srinivasan and peter from visa research
um we start with the problem of private
sector intersection or psi
for short or there are two parties alice
and bob
each of them has a private set x and y
and i want to jointly compute the
intersection of the two sets
but nothing more and more generally we
can consider multi-party psi
where there are multiple parties each
having a private set
and they want to jointly compute the
introduction of all the sets but nothing
more
but in certain scenarios psi as a
functionality is not
enough we need something stronger for
example threshold psi
where the parties are only supposed to
learn the introduction
if the intersection is sufficiently
large
more generally in the multi-party
scenario they're only supposed to learn
the intersection if the intersection of
all the sets
is sufficiently large for example in
privacy preserving right sharing
the parties might only want to share
right if their common trajectory is
sufficiently long
the next question is how to achieve
threshold psi
a natural approach is to first compute
the psi cardinality
which is the size of the intersection
and then check if it is sufficiently
large
following that approach the best
communication complexity
is of order m where m is the size of the
smallest
set and this is tight so
does that mean this is the best
communication complexity we can hope for
for threshold psi surprisingly the
answer is no
in a recent work by gauss and simkin in
they developed a new approach for
two-party threshold psi
to get a round of this communication
lower bound
by doing cardinality testing so they can
reduce the communication complexity
to only grow with the size of the set
difference
in particular the two parties can only
learn the intersection
if the total size of the set difference
is less than or equal to t or t the
threshold
in particular they construct two
protocols
one based on fully homomorphic
encryption with communication complexity
of order t
and another based on additively
homomorphic encryption with
communication complexity roughly t
squared further they show a
communication lower bound
for such kind of cardinality testing
let's order t
and in this work we ask the following
two questions
first can we extend the two-party
threshold psi to the multi-party case
and second can we bridge the gap between
upper bound and lower bound
from assumptions weaker than fhe and
before we talk about our results
i want to take a step back and think
about the formal definition for
multiparty threshold psi in particular
what does
what does sufficiently large mean how to
define it
and actually there are different ways to
define it at a very high level
the first option considers more on
whether the setting transaction is
sufficiently large
and the second option considers if the
entire set difference
is sufficiently small they seem to be
defining the same thing from two
different perspectives
and in fact they are equivalent in the
two-party scenario
but they're not in a multi-party case
and for that reason we consider both
functionalities
and we study both the communication
lower bond and communication upper bound
for both functionalities with the
complexities
showing the table where n is the number
of parties
and t is the threshold for upper bound
we construct three different protocols
from an outer band threshold for the
homomorphic encryption
or threshold actively homomorphic
encryption and all the protocols are
secure against
semi-honest adversaries corrupting them
up to n minus one parties
i want to point out here when n equals
two
then this protocol gives a new two-party
threshold psi
from additively homomorphic encryption
with communication complexity
better than the prior work as i
mentioned earlier
and the very very high level idea is
that the prior work gs19
reduces the problem of cardinality
testing to the problem of testing
singularity
of a handhold matrix and then they stop
there
to do a two pc for this task but we
take a further step to reduce this
problem to another problem
called half gcd which can be solved in
time
t log square t so we can reduce both the
communication complexity and
computational complexity
to summarize we study both
functionalities for multiparty threshold
psi
and we show various lower bound and
upper bound
in a concurrent work bronco dotary and
pool
complement our work by showing a
protocol for
the first functionality from threshold
activity homophilic encryption
with this much communication complexity
and so how is going to present their
work
uh
so since for introduction uh can you see
my screen
okay um okay uh thanks for the
introduction uh ms hung
uh i represent our work about uh my
particular multitasking for
structural psi uh which is joining work
with a pedophile
so we mainly focus on the functionality
uh as uh mentioned we only focus on the
function the fc test means uh
they only check their criminality if the
intersection is large enough
let's first see what happens uh when we
directly extend just 19 approach to
multi-party setting so um
for each m stat set uh encoded as a
n term polynomial then we can show the
difference
among n parts polynomials
assuming the intersection cardinality is
m minus t
m is a each step size so this is a
binomial the regarding polynomial with
degree n times t
so um the problem is uh if we want to
check
if this is a sparse polynomial but
location codes for each party will
depend
on the number of parties n which is a
highly desired
in our case our approach avoids this
blow up for
for each party let's first consider the
insecure way to do a cardinality test
so for uh each for each encoding we use
a
catalytic characteristic polynomial
being called each set
before uh um m such set we encoded as a
m degree polynomial and for all of
encoded polynomials
we can choose a rational function as
follows
so after cancelling all the common
factors
the resulting rational function i have
degree p
at most is uh intersection size is
larger than m
minus t m is a set size as i
mentioned before so uh
uh so other clinic tests can boils down
to
the foreign degree class problem so
given a
rational function f of x can we decide
if the degree
of this um both polynomials um
it's smaller than t with only all of the
evaluation points
of this uh rational function f of x
our answer is uh our main observation is
it will interpolate this ratio function
on two different support sets v and w to
get f v
and f w respectively where f of x
is some unknown reduced rational
function
which means p1 and p2 are grouped one
polynomials
then we have fv equals to w if the
degree is smaller than t
otherwise they are not equal except with
a
negligible probability
so also note that interpolating a
rational function
can be reduced to solving linear system
equations
by extending secure linear algebra tools
to multiply the case
we can securely perform the test above
and we prove our security in
externalized uc framework
we conclude we present a multi-party
called analytic test for structural psi
whose communication capacity only
depends on the strategy for each party
that's all that's for our internship
thanks uh for the interesting talk so
we have time for one quick question to
either one of them
so uh if there are no further questions
uh
so let's thank the speakers
again and uh let's thank all the
speakers for this session
uh so yeah so this brings
close to the session on cryptographic
protocols and secure computation part
two
so we'll convene once again in