hello everyone i'm david from paderborn
university in germany
and today i will speak about the optimal
tightness of verifiable random functions
intuitively we can think of very very
random functions
or short vrf as a combination of
pseudorandom functions
and digital signatures that is a very
vibrant function just like a prf a
subsidiary an impede function
however in contrast to a prf vrf when
evaluated additionally produces a
non-interactive proof
that allows to publicly verify the
correctness of the vrf output
with respect to the input and the public
key
due to these properties vfs have found
several applications
the most prominent one probably being in
the consensus mechanisms
of several proof-of-stake blockchains
like algorand dfinity or cardano
other applications include ensuring
privacy in key transparency systems and
in preventing zone enumeration attacks
in the nsx
in the proposed nzec5 protocol
during this talk i will first quickly
recall the syntax and the concrete
properties of vrfs
then i will discuss the tightness of
security reductions for vrfs why it is
difficult to construct optimally tight
reductions for vrfs
and finally how we can address these
difficulties
and actually construct an optimally
tight
reduction for vrf
so let us start with recalling the
syntax and properties of vrfs
so technically a vrf consists of three
algorithms
first a generation algorithm that
produces a pair of secret key and public
verification key
then an evaluation algorithm that
produces a brf output y for an input x
just like for a prf the algorithm
requires a secret key sk
and the output y is supposed to be to
the random
however the evaluation algorithm also
produces a non-interactive proof of
correctness pi
this proof can then be used with the
verification algorithm
to verify the correctness of y with
respect to the input x
and the public verification key we
require from
vrf that is correct meaning all
endlessly generated vrf outputs are
accepted by the verification algorithm
we furthermore require unique
probability
from a react meaning that for every
input x and every verification key vk
there is a unique output y for which a
valid proof pi
exists note that we also require this
for maliciously generated verification
keys
not only for only generated ones
naturally we also require
pseudorandomness from a vrf which we
model using the following security
experiment
between a challenger and an adversary
the challenger first computes a keypair
and gives the public verification
key to the adversary which can then make
evaluation queries to the challenger
at some point the adversary has to state
a challenge input x-star for which it
has not created an evaluation before
the challenger answers the adversary's
challenge input
with either the honest evaluation or
with the uniformly random element from
the vf's range
however the proof of correctness is not
given to the adversary for the challenge
input
the adversary then may make further
evaluation queries for arbitrary inputs
of course
except for the challenge input
at some point the adversary has to
submit a guess on whether it was given
the honest evaluation of the vrf or a
random element from the zvf's range for
the challenge
it's common with such security
experiments we say that the vrf is
pseudorandim
if every polynomial time adverse we only
has a negligible advantage in
distinguishing an anonymous evaluation
of the vrf
from a uniformly random element from the
rear app's range
in terms of contribution this paper
revisits the lower bounds on the loss of
public key cryptography from eurocup 16
by badat isle
and accents them to also apply to vrfs
furthermore it also introduces the first
construction of a vrf that can be proven
secure with this optimal security loss
the construction is based on the vrf by
yamada from crypto
17. next we will look at
the tightness of security reductions for
rfs and first of all
what tightness actually means and why we
should care about it
when we speak about tightness we usually
do that in the context of complete
security
that is we want to choose theoretically
sound key sizes
such that it takes at least a certain
amount of time to break a scheme
using a reduction from some established
hardness assumption
we can choose the key sizes such that
any adversary that is faster than what
we aimed for
would imply an algorithm for the
underlying hardness assumption
that is faster than the conjecture
fastest possible algorithm for the
assumption
and in particular faster than the most
efficient noun algorithm
however some reductions incur in
significant computational overhead
or only carry over a small fraction of
the adversary's advantage
this means that the reduction can be of
a better or worse quality
we quantify this quality with a loss of
a reduction
this loss of a reduction is a factor l
by which the run time of the algorithm
for the hardness assumption that is
implied by the reduction
over the algorithm's success probability
is larger than the respective
refraction for the original adversary
thus the loss captures how much less
efficient the reduction
is in breaking the hardness assumption
compared to the efficiency of the
adversary
in breaking the security of the
considered scheme
for the key sizes that we decided on
in this way this means that they can be
significantly larger
or smaller depending on the quality of
the reduction
thus a tight reduction allows us to use
theoretically sound small key sizes
and by that improves the efficiency of
our scheme
before we look into the loss of brfs let
us
first look into the loss of a closely
related primitive
unique signatures that is signatures
where there only exists a unique
valid signature for each message
these are close related to vrfs in the
sense
that if only not only the vrf output y
but also the proof pi of a vrf
is unique then the vrf is also a unique
signature scheme
process transformation intensifies us to
just consider the pair of
vf output and proof as a signature
indeed most vfs in the standard model
have this property
thus let us look into lower bounds for
the tightness of reductions
for unique signatures for unique
signature scheme schemes we know that
informally every reduction from a
non-interactive hardness assumption
to the unforgetability of the signature
scheme has a loss of at least the number
of signature queries
of sephora which we will denote as q
furthermore this bound is typed since
are
there are unique signature schemes that
can be proven secure with such a loss
under non-interactive assumptions the
unique signature scheme by lucianskaia
from crypto 2002
is such an example
the question now is is the situation for
vf similar or different and if it's
different
how different is it
and indeed what we find is surprising
namely
we find that the current bounds only
apply to vrfs
with re-randomizer proofs pi and not to
all vrfs
more precisely it only applies to vrfs
that have a unique
or re-randomizer proof pi
however we are able to address this in
the context of brefs
that is to extend the proof by badadar
from eurocrypt 2016
to also apply to vrfs we won't be able
to go into the details of the proof
but i'd like to give the quick overview
of the technique and give an intuition
on why the extension works the lower
bound is indeed slightly more general
than just for realfs namely it is
for verifiable unpredictable functions
or short vrefs
these are syntactically identical to
vrfs but for security we require the
adversary
to forge an output instead of
distinguishing ramp from randomness
note that this forgery does not contain
the proof of correctness but
only the vrf output thus every secure
vrf
is also secure vuf but not the other way
around
if we now consider a security reduction
this usually looks as follows we have a
reduction that receives an instance of
the hardness assumption
simulates security experiment for the
adversary and in the end
uses the adversary solution to solve the
instance of the hardness assumption
when we want to prove lower bounds on
the tightness of a reduction
we we usually do that with the meter
reduction
technique by ground that is we build a
meter reduction
around the reduction that also solves
the same hardness assumption
however instead of using an adversary
the meter reduction
simulates an adversary for the reduction
therefore in this proof it is actually
the reduction
that solves the instance of the hardness
assumption not some adversary
this way we can show that any polynomial
time reduction
that has a loss of a less than q would
be able to break the hardness assumption
without the help of an adversary
in the meter reduction by badat eye the
re-randomizability
or uniqueness of the signature scheme is
used by the meter reduction
when it produces when it produces the
forged signature of the simulated
adversary
for the reduction however for vuf
this forgery only contains the voip
output and
not the proof of correctness thus the
proof goes through
even if the proof of correctness is not
re-randomizable
because the meta reduction never needs
to give it
to the reduction
now that we have established the lower
bound on the loss of vrfs
let us consider the loss of previous
brfs
this table shows the loss of most
previous brfs in the standard model
in some cases for reasonable
parametrizations
unfortunately the loss in the last
column of all these constructions
is significantly worse than what is
indicated by our bound
next let us look into why there is such
significant difference between the
tightness of reductions for vrfs and for
unique signatures
for this purpose let us recall the
uniqueness property of vrfs
that requires that there is a unique brf
output
y for each combination of input and
verification key
for which an executive proof exists
for the reduction this means that it
implicitly has to commit to all vrf
outputs
the moment it gives the verification key
to the adversary
it could also not generate something
like a lossy verification key
that would that would allow it to
indistinguishably
forge vf outputs because the uniqueness
property also has to hold
for maliciously generated verification
keys hence there is no room
for the reduction to lie to the
adversary without being caught
in consequence this limits us to doing
a so-called partitioning proof in order
to prove substituted randomness of a vrf
in such a proof the reduction randomly
partitions the input space of the vrf in
two
disjoint sets a so-called controlled set
and an uncontrolled set
for inputs in the controlled set the
reduction can simulate answers to the
adversary's evaluation queries
but it cannot extract the solution to
the underlying hardness assumption if
the adversary chooses the challenge
input in it for the uncontrolled set
it is exactly the other way around this
means that for the reduction to be
successful
we need the adversary to choose all
evaluation queries from the controlled
set
but a challenge query from the
uncontrolled set
if this is not the case the reduction
can only abort and output a random bit
indeed this strategy suffices to prove
optimal titans for unique signatures
the analysis of such a reduction in the
computational setting
like for signatures is straightforward
we only need to show
that the probability for the reduction
to not about and for the adversary to be
successful
is non-negligibly large here depicted as
the green part of the picture
the decisional setting however like for
example for vreps
this becomes more difficult
let us thus consider this visualization
on the left side we have the probability
that the adversary wins which we assume
to be one half plus
its non-negligible advantage now we
again have the event
that the reduction does not abort and
obviously if the adversary wins
and the reduction does not abort then
the reduction is successful
however this fraction is much too small
to reduce to a decision assumption like
for example ddh
we thus also have to consider that the
reduction
is also correct in half of the cases
where it aborts and just outputs a
random bit
unfortunately we are still not there
because the reduction wins in less than
half of the cases
where it doesn't abort and what we need
is more like this
where the case where in the no abort
case
the reduction wins with much more
showing that this holds has been rather
cumbersome for most of the partitioning
strategies
with whole papers on optimizing this
part of the proof like the run by the
land risen part at eurocrypt 2009
however we actually can achieve this
optimal tightness
and that is what we look into next for
the intuition behind our
technique let us slightly move the goal
post and assume that the adverse
reversal nice
to choose all its queries and its
challenge uniformly at random from the
domain of the vrf
if this were the case we could just
guess the first log q plus 1 bits of the
challenge input
meaning the reduction would abort if the
first log q plus 1 bits of the challenge
do not match the guess
or if the log q plus one bits of any
evaluation where we do match the guess
then proving that this strategy yields a
loss of only eight q
is rather straightforward and we refer
to the paper for the prominent proof
however it only holds in this very
simplified scenario
and the adversary usually won't be that
nice
so in order to use this strategy we have
to use some further trick
this trick is to pass all inputs through
appear first
before comparing them to the guest
prefix
then even if they are adversely chosen
they will be distributed computationally
indistinguishable from independent
uniformly random values
however this evaluation has to happen
outside of the viewers of the adversary
and has to be incorporated into proof of
correctness
fortunately one of yamada's vrfs from
crypto 2017 allows us to do exactly that
more specifically it allows us to embed
an arbitrary nand circuit in the vrf
such that the reduction can simulate an
evaluation of the vrf
if and only if the circuit evaluates to
zero and that it can extract a solution
to the underlying hardness assumption
if and only if the circuit evaluates to
one on the challenge input x star
this embedding hides some chosen input
bits and also the internal state
and the output bit of the circuit from
the adversary
thus we can embed the evaluation of the
prf
and the comparison of the guess by
setting the prf key and the guess as the
secret input bits
then the partitioning proof we discussed
before works out without any flaws
yamada's vrf is based on the qdb.hi
assumption
where the queue is exponential in
circuit depth meaning we may only use
logarithmic depth circuits
and even then this assumption obeyed
being non-interactive
is still relatively strong however proof
and key sizes
are modest but certainly not as good as
constructions designed for
for efficiency nonetheless
this construction allows us to achieve a
loss that is at most
8q and thus attain in up to a constant
factor
optimally tied reduction however there
are still some interesting research
questions remaining
first of all it would be interesting to
apply these techniques
to prove more constructions optimally
tightly secure
but also whether we can strengthen the
lower bound
to also apply to interactive assumptions
and larger classes of reductions
a good starting point for this would be
the meter reduction technique by morgan
and pass
for you for unique signatures from tcc
finally achieving optimally tight
reductions
from weaker or maybe even standard
assumptions would also be nice
since our current reconstruction only
works
from the qdbhi assumption
but there exists vrf constructions from
standard assumptions like the one from
wufensenjaga
from tcc 2016 also runs by rosia
or cool from 2018 and 2019.
in conclusion we first showed that the
lower bound on the loss of many public
key primitives verbati from eurocrypt
also applies to all vrfs in the standard
model thus every reduction from a
non-interactive complexity assumption to
the security of the vrf
necessarily has a loss of at least q
we then showed that this bound is tied
by presenting vrf with an accompanying
partitioning proof that achieves this
optimal loss up to a small constant
vector
the technique builds on homomorphically
evaluating a prf
and might also be applicable to more
scenarios where this is possible
and partitioning proofs are a suitable
technique
finally if you have any questions feel
free to send me mail or contact me
during the conference
thank you all for your attention and
have a nice day