good afternoon everyone and thanks for
staying for his last talked this is the
end of the conference and we really
appreciate that you that you stayed with
us and you are interested in or Porto
even so that there is another talking
downstairs in Dubuque which is also
looks very interesting given by my
colleague so seems that the last two
talks are two slots were given to the
crisis so my name is lamentable Jan my
colleagues on the icy and if you give
this store together also presents on
introductory slides and then we get to
the technical details and there is a
certain person who was also involved in
this very short selling and they are all
from the University of Technology and
economics detour from the peace love and
joy from the Department of Motor
mobilize and very cool manufacturing and
you talk about hacking cars and
yesterday someone asked me whether we
will bring the car on stage and I i
taught him that no unfortunately not
maybe this is disappointing for you to
but hopefully this is the only
disappointing so why we don't bring the
car to the stage because we are talking
to both checking cars but in fact as you
will see most of the verity did was
mainly on hacking and application on a
PC PC which had some bad effect on the
car itself
as well but actually debacle but it was
really very taking the application on
the PC and that's what I mean
infected stocks this dialectic but I
explain this later so as you know more
than cars are full of embedded
controllers which are basically small
computers inside a car which caused
royal different things in the car like
the air bag which was mentioned but also
the engine of the car or the break and
so on and all these electronic control
units use are connected by internal
networks communication networks for
example the CAN bus in addition the cars
have different external interfaces like
most of the modern cars might have
Bluetooth stack interface which you can
connect your hands free said some cars
have a wifi hotspot some cars have some
GPS receiver or a GSM module or some
cars have some so-called by unless tire
pressure monitoring systems so if you
put all these computers connect external
interfaces so there might be a tax and
cyberattacks against these more than
cars actually a plausible threat so
people started to consider that
and researchers started to work on that
early as early backing 2010 2011 and
some of the 11 of the landmark papers
which have been published by a very well
known conference on USENIX security in
2011 it was written by us- based
researchers from universities and
basically in their paper they show that
cars can be compromised remotely
very very nice paper that goes through
systematically over you
the attack surface of the modern car
they identified three types of possible
surface
physical access to the car basically
value that will be the interface
short-range wireless access such as
Bluetooth interface or by fight and long
range wireless access for example sailor
or
overview these interfaces and they
develop practical a tax proof of concept
attacks against each of these interfaces
so for instance one of them today
developed was exploiting a vulnerability
in the media player there is a software
there which parses the mediafire which
is played and there was a bargain that
sort so they were able to construct a
specially crafted music song tried they
put the CD in the media player and then
immediately replace the CD basically the
block the bug was exploited her and they
took over control over the media they
demonstrated exploitable vulnerabilities
in the Bluetooth stack of the car that
they investigated or 11 over the the
attacks that they constructed was
basically it was exploiting bugging the
GSM will do so they were able to call
the car remote location calling the
telephone number of the car and they
played a specially crafted video again
which exploited the bug and additional
software modules on the on the on that
GSM module and it was compromised and
wants these views are compromised and
you are already inside a car and on the
canvas days basically no more protection
usually so far and after that there were
some follow up there
very very own researchers will work on
that very soon that Charlie Miller with
his colleague Chris Wallace second they
basically their idea was to repeat the
research that was done by these us-
based researchers I just mention because
these guys these academic guys they did
not publish order details for good
reasons but Charlie Miller and his
friend had the idea of repeating all the
and publish everything so basically they
come up with a report that contains a
very detailed description of what they
did and all the tools that they used and
in fact some of you might remember that
Charlie Miller gave a talk he wrote
activated two years ago about this third
so we had already occurred hacking
presentation two years ago
activity which is actually on youtube so
you can you can watch it and they
continued and a very decent trees are
you might have heard about death in June
or July this year there was some news
anchors remotely illegal regime on the
highway and this was also the vehicle
Charlie Miller and his friend very
recent physical ed exploited some
vulnerability in a wifi hotspot on this
modern Jeep so they could remotely
connect via the internet because the
Jeep public IP address the remotely
connected and exploited someone that
will be taken to hospital software and
promoted to cooperative control and
there are other examples so if you look
at the richard is example of infecting
the car veered FM radio broadcast or
violated tired or dimension violence
tire pressure monitoring system or some
addicts on really communication between
the key the viola scheme of the car and
and so on and all those are removed
ethics so basically do they mean that
you compromised of car remotely not
being physically present or close to the
car were you in the car
and they are in fact very intriguing and
scary bewbs you that and they can
attract of course a lot of media
attention because it's always a good you
know the news that you took over a
five-year remotely but the real risk is
in order opinion is quite unclear what
what we mean by this is that it is not
so easy to do those kind of remote
attacks so they need first of all an
exploitable vulnerabilities in some of
the interfaces and there might be such a
vulnerability but it's not so easy to
find such a vulnerability source finding
those vulnerabilities which I really
exploitable this this is far from
trivial it needs reverse engineering
embedded software which is difficult
there is left very little information
available about these embedded was
because the car manufacturers typically
don't share too much so very limited
information from his you can start and
there is a risk of bricking relatively
expensive equipment so then you
experiment try to exploit buffer
overflow you might actually ran their
device unusable and you have to throw a
billion buy a new one and this kind can
be expensive so it's not easy and it may
not skilled very well because of an
ability of the interfaces in one of the
carbons might not lead there in another
card ending in the same interface around
so basically just one vulnerability you
can maybe compromise one type of car and
not the others so that's why I mean
that's what do you mean by not scalable
and the question is there may be some
crew is a hanging lawyer
easier to do than these kind of remote
addicts and that's what we mean by this
Stuxnet style at Soho Stuxnet
basically most of you should probably
know about this and yesterday we had a
wonderful talk one attacking chemical
plans and the speaker there he explained
in fact what we show the video in fact
about how stocks that are so you
probably know but the idea just to
repeat the main point is that Stuxnet
was warm attacking pieces first of all
and then modified the POC that other
unions centrifuges but but if you look
at what started it is really basically
of warm against windows-based pieces so
the idea was that your first infected PC
and took over the communication between
that PC and the PSC and then once you
have that you control the communication
then you can modify the PRC some
parameters or even over right some of
the programs and then that has some
effect on the under control system and
as I said the exploited weakness indoors
and faded to go over the communication
was basically just replacing the deal
which was responsible for the
communication between a SCADA software
used to manage the POC and the BSE so
this horse stuff actually it's kind of a
blueprint for similar attacks against
similar type of systems so if you have
embedded systems typically they are
managed from PCs and so basically debt
or idea to repeat exactly the same kind
of logic in four cars so you have some
PC which is a diagnostic PC used
encourages repair shops running some
sort of her some whole community is the
car for instance via deorbit interface
and then infected PC that PC might
change values or other rights scenes
hidden between the car and that causes
problems to the car so that's that's the
logical 44
why is this worrisome because PCs in
repair shops and carriages are probably
vulnerable probably Dr connected to the
Internet very likely the law also
connecting USB devices and mechanics
probably connect all kinds of USB and
they are probably poorly maintained and
administered because that's not their
main job they're the guys there to to to
maintain their PC and probably they are
also used for other purposes not just
running the diagnosis so if you put all
this together it's relatively easy they
believed to infect them with known or
unknown mother and was the commander
infected the PC then tomorrow can
compromise the diagnostic application
running on the PC and then implements to
us for example for you can implement
many in the middle between the
diagnostic software and a car and then
they have almost direct access to the
car by the GOP interface and this not
only needs standard standard poor's
reverse engineering of pc-based not not
very special and we also believe this is
better than remote attacks because the
same software is usually used to do
diagnostic on multiple types of cars
multiple brands and everybody stick into
the carriage regularly so any any car
could be affected in this way so for
proof of concept we decided to
demonstrate that it is indeed easy to do
in practice so in order test environment
we had access to an OGTT because that's
a test card at the University of
Technology
and economics is using for teaching the
Eagle engineers and we have had had
access to that car for some time and so
we have chosen a vital used search party
diagnostic software which basically is
compatible with this car or all the cars
we differ in the fourth group and he
tried to make modifications in this
diagnostic application too low for men
in the middle attacks between the
application and the car which allows us
eavesdropping or modifying messages on
the flight we make the assumption that
the PC is already infected by malware so
we did not write in my hair for this
work but actually the parallel
presentation in the room downstairs
about them are very type of sample that
he wrote for for bypassing different
security protection mechanism but this
work was not about writing them are
where we are seeing the monastery
infected the PC and they momma can carry
out all the equations and applications
that we do because they basically two
very basic modifications ok so the
outline the rest of the talk will be
that we will present you with a little
bit more detail about the system which
we investigated some of the protection
mechanisms that we discovered that the
application developer putting the
application but as you will see it or
not so effective two day did not prevent
us to understand and reverse engineer
the application and the protocols and
then we can go into the details of the
techniques so show you how we replaced
one of the dealers of these applications
we do a very similar kind of attack that
Stuxnet did DL which is responsible for
the communication between the
application and the car diagnostic cable
TV did this replacement then we explain
the whole
reverse engineer the protocol because
there is a proprietary protocol between
the application and diagnostic cable and
we had to understand the message for
months there's also a checksum
computation they had to figure out how
it works because many modify messages
and there is some encryption scheme
involved as well so messages are
encrypted you know certain way and we
had to figure out what holy books and
once we did all these damn can then
implemented many in the middle attack
and explain how we did
logging and replaying modify messages on
the flight and then do you mentioned
some of the experiments including this
ok so let's start with the system so we
have a diagnostic PCV have a nickel and
they are connected via special so
so-called diagnostic cable on the PCB
have a softer stack we have these
diagnostic application running the
diagnostic application in fact is there
the component which was necessary keys
and the protocol implementations for for
communicating with the cable and the car
and it implements certain diagnostic
functions which basically means that it
reads and set a value was inside a car
in India in the selected easy and
communication or so so so sorry was is a
number of dealers and one of those
dealers is a DLL which is responsible
for the communication between the car
and of course at the lower level there
are drivers which implement
communication functions we have this
cable which is in fact not a simple
connect or but inside a cable that is a
microcontroller so there is a small
PCB the microcontroller and other
components in this microcontroller is
basically functions as a gate soil the
application in fact the application and
Andy's get V Day the micro controlling
the cable then translates to messages
and sends them really to do so head to
this communication between the
application and these get to modify and
and we have been on the cardio video be
the stands for on-board diagnostic and
most modern cars has this interface that
manufacturers put in the car for
diagnostic purposes to do diagnostic
work on the car and behind the OBD then
there is the CAN bus which is connecting
the ECU was essentially OBD is not equal
to can but essentially then you have
access to do you have almost direct
access to the cannon you can send
messages to do you see you saw the
application developers try to put some
protection mechanisms in the India
application to prevent reverse
engineering and and hacking the
application so one of one of those is
signing the dealers that the use or
dealers lauded by the application
digitally signed but for some reason
they did not really check those
signatures so in fact this looks like an
effective protection or maybe the check
but did not find their digi-key they
might get some very silently we don't
know but but one of the dealers there is
some program application to the usual
stuff they try to hide the function of
the program program by my office keating
the code with some common methods
however vendor application is started
it deal so if you attach to the applica-
running application
debugger to attach a debugger to already
running application then you and you can
infect investigator memory and
understand how the application of course
you only see the binary but that's why
we have you know who who can read the
binary and and he understands how the
application and then you some License
Verification so you cannot use any any
kind of cable the application checks did
the cable is genuine but there are fake
copies that you can buy and that's
actually that's what did so on Amazon
for $15 Chinese General Cable and so the
Chinese somehow managed or so to get the
license information and put in so we did
not have to be very very few seconds and
then if you wanted to do this man in the
middle so well was to really develop
some component which can do is repeating
can replay messages or inject pic
messages and and one natural idea was to
somehow modified a DLL which is
responsible for the communication
between the application and the car so
he could for instance you know david a
binary because the source code is not
available of course and and some hope is
to binary but all the functions that we
need one infected lose even simpler to
introduce another fake a DLL load that
he'd yell and then that video below the
origin of on energy use just the
functions of the origin of the allow for
communication but since your video is
loading before you get all the course
before and we can do all sorts of
modification before he passed to the
original so that's exactly the idea that
and no idea I give the floor to crash
with you then give you all the details
about the technical part of the moment
but I am Andrew you may know that
usually mean those low there goes an
application to the memory and after work
so it's important and gather the
necessary shared libraries etc and loads
them to the memory too so in this case
windows loader Lothar Thiele named as
the original after it loans to dealers
cause they are their enterprise entry
point before passing the control to the
original application so are the kids and
extracts the origin of the hard drive
and then reload back so that you can see
the chain
application calls read or write function
then we could simply make many in the
military and the redirect the call to
the original function of the original
ideas and then the core interests beyond
the control again and we can return back
to the original application how can we
improve there are some tips firstly you
have to check you have to take care of
yourself party components to not just
for your own competence to check every
the ideal windows the areas maybe and
they two fires that are pleased it's in
your program that your program notes so
you have to perform dictatorship UDD
digital signature checks and CSE checks
before loading and finger and after
learning anything and you should do the
periodically during the program runs and
should integrate some or all of these
checks to York many of your calculations
like when you are sending the request to
disable their usual place empty holes in
the message that will be replaced by
after the calculations of the protection
of them
CNC or digital signature checks and of
course you should use proper
cryptography other reasons not just
simple XOR as you see to reverse
engineer application we used these days
contains exporters name like in the
origin of the idea some of some of them
we redirect some of them but some of
them be modified to make
to end their functionality for example
after you read and I feel right to
modify them and there we can capture or
modify the communication then the
application causes of course we use
favorite 2013 various diagnostic
application cheat engine parameters
scanning and three very rejects the
exact order to capture data and some
handy tools for filtering that they can
see your usual message either consists
of three bites the first light mean the
message direction know this means to the
the message goes to the cables so
sending by the original application goes
to the cable and of course for demeans
the application gets the message and
cable Oscars after that you can see
signs look size by the size the size of
this message including checks on
Wednesday after down the type of the
message in this case its request message
and of course being seven as you can see
his response
know what their debts you can see the
beta-blocker the force some of the force
by force
first of its kind of target identifiers
after that there is data linked identify
your thoughts by singlet that saying bye
comes from the original application
who's the developers leave it in the
application as a simple CString so we
named like this because they named after
and you can see the actual data block
that wheel
the identify your target we discover and
these checks to complete this chick suns
isn't too hard so you can just simply
acts or all of the bites of the message
and you will get the chance can see a
simple acknowledgement message this user
accounts comes from the cable and cable
has done such as truly an operation for
example of course is a type I and III
that this is an acknowledgement message
here is he messaged you still in israel
needs realize the encryption session
this thing in b2 b6 me is this type of
message the key message consists of buds
these boys are in the existing static
table that diagnostic application and
the cable both have this table aesthetic
table consists of randomly generated by
and and you and you also exercised to
perform the encryption you can see in
this example you get the SMS from the
table with the help of the key and you
just simply excellent excellent with the
original message and you will get the
end result and of course you then after
and you have to recompile the Jackson
here is the table as I said this is
static table and of course they are key
value and you can gather these are
indexes and you can get the real
excellent divides from the table as the
following ok
when the application cause or FB right
function we of course need a backup of
the buffer contained in this function
and then we can redirect the call to the
original deal so that's how we love the
logging and of course when the
application is the reason function that
we are in the reeds and then we can save
the bus and can return to the
application before any kind of cable
needs to be realized or tested the cable
during the initialization the cable
examines the capabilities of the car and
the cable to the software examines the
capabilities of the car and the cable
speed limits license etc and store in
temporary files its source in temporary
place usually these tests before any
bigger operation books
okay and you can see here so far checked
the license if you want to perform
license check you have to conduct the
the obd2 connector to the car but you
can bypass this protection with
collecting
will teach to the beach to collect all
16 four-plus and pin for or minus and
that we will use the same here is an
example of locally made the request and
the responses here you can see the
leaders
yes and of course looking be made off I
said the initialization it's it's called
in dinosaur three four tests we we
perform poor test of those cans so far
and of course the cable scans all of the
ECU's in the car and of course the
Arabic consumer and ABS brakes ABS
brakes and the last year because of the
application less functionality or the
cable as function we don't we didn't
know that
and example for replacing session
these are messages all the right so we
have every player to be replaced these
messages messages here you can see these
riots that you have to send out before
any kind of operation this is a kind of
cable in the series in cooperation with
its related is a separate so it is
invisible for the diagnostic application
and if if we want to perform testing
right Steve rights of course by using
STD idea because they too will also uses
the origin of the ideal 02 performed
write and read operations you have to
call these functions with the correct
parameters before any kind of writing or
reading operation and there are some
here instead you have to wait after any
sent out message so you have to try to
be late too late to the cable and of
course the Joker bites that you have to
send me for anything and
yes we could easily replace the future
internal messages because there is no
need to change anything including or
data structure anything you just replay
that we recorded it so let her a simple
process and as I said this really is a
separate application so it is invisible
to the diagnostic application and yes we
can also modify the communication as you
can see here the application sends the
messages in bite after by style so
performers St right on each bite of the
message yes and here is an example of
this it is simple we want too much and
that we want to replace for reaching a
decision that we can find the match and
from the last bite of the match we can
modify the data and copy the others and
of course we calculate the checks and I
think you saw these were the technical
details of how we can local and I
recessions whole weekend replay messages
from a separate application to the to
the diagnostic application and very
importantly hope we can modify messages
on the fly it was running in the in the
faded yellow and can change anything you
know message was sent out by the
application or received from the cable
and utilities tools then the team made
some experiments and this is just too
sure you were some of the
the pictures and some of these things
that he did so so here is this btw in
the gauge of the university and this is
on the receipt in here and having fun
with these experiments were carried out
during spring 2015 and so this slide
shows you that the diagnostic
application itself produces some log
files simple text size and we just
wanted to check if you make and so here
is the original log here here is some
parts of the of the logs that he made
and certain things you see these values
show up or logs so this was just a check
of your skin and the replay of the
airbag anybody simple message
explained it was just very easy
previously recorded messages so these
messages of infected defer all in this
to bite the scene by the source for
different but not really don't really
know what it is what's the purpose of
that scene by its so this replay ver
perfectly earlier recorded message that
could have been experimenting read very
successful conclusion so as we try to
explain cyberattacks on modern threat
but research has started to focus more
on remote attacks and we argued that
there are easier ways and that's what we
mean by the Stuxnet style attack where
you don't really need to have very
special knowledge about cars and
internal components of the cars that you
basically
applications on normal PCs and we
believe it has a much higher risk
because it's easier to do when maybe
more scalable and so on and the proof of
concept that we that we made is is just
simply replacing an Arabic enabled
disabled message which doesn't look like
very sore why why why is it interesting
but this is just a proof of concepts as
as we said we have a man in the middle
tool which means that you can modify
anything you want including may be firm
and interesting thing is that you can
also modify responses from the cable so
you can hide from the diagnostic
application if we set because vendor
that value is read from the from the car
then you modify the response from the
cable showing a different value so in
this case we just deeply back
message now the mechanics convey that
I've an assist softer and tries to read
this setting out from the car and we can
modify the settings that it still shows
that it's gone so they don't the airbag
remains switched off and the diagnostic
application get speaking formation
because of the many in the middle at
that he that he performed and that can
be of course hideous right because if
you can switch off the air bags of
thousands of cars and it's not visible
to anyone than any time in any of those
cars have some accident and it might
have some serious consequences of course
and as I said you can also very small
would look to the future we are you know
this is a new buzzword and Internet of
Things Remembered basically embedded
devices connected wireless internet and
and if you connect these devices way the
internet then of course create so but
the point is dead that body shirt is
valued also for these embedded devices
of the future so basically you manage
those devices from PCs when you connect
your PC to PC or venue later in in the
future you configure your refrigerator
or whatever you probably will not have
pretty user interface to configure but
you will use a PC and you will connect
to the refrigerator and and configured
that the PC so this Hologic what we are
advocating here with so one could in
fact a PC and from the PC or those
embedded devices and what is maybe more
scurrying at least to me and I would
like to just bring this up as a kind of
a discussion topic there what if then
Alastair some point the infection
disappears from the PC demand their deal
itself for instance
detect that would was embedded devices
are in fact affected already and you
know i i dont have it was solution for
that so i as I said just bring it up as
a question what can you really do about
this whole weekend really security
Internet of Things then you have to
steal by multiple PCs which are used to
to modify or manage those devices thank
you for your attention