I
okay we're going to get started just a
few things first of all they found a
white 16 gig iphone it's headed to ebay
in about 15 minutes if someone doesn't
claim it there's a store around the
corner that can do that yeah so first of
all thanks very much to the social
sponsors from last night course site and
I'm greatly appreciate that it's it's
great for those of you who are newcomers
hopefully that that helped you find the
15 people that you need to meet that so
we spoke about yesterday and the
newcomers breakfast as speaking of
breakfast thanks to mr v for sponsoring
this delicious breakfast that we had
this morning and and a huge thank you to
the speakers from yesterday I think the
content we had is fantastic we closed it
out with the peering track you know
thanks very much everyone who
participated both here in the plenary
and split out in the tracks today the
track we have is DNS after the close of
the plenary one thing I just want to
call out again on the mics we have the
discussion guidelines as a little hairy
there for a little while yesterday
people could just recognize that the
speakers that come up here doing this on
their own time and in some cases on
their own dime and just remember to
respect them and respect the people in
the audience it's just greatly
appreciated it causes less friction
overall i would like to invite up vijay
gil and david schmidt they in the room
there we go
there's Vijay they can talk to us about
automated configuration validation of a
large-scale network DJ is ambling up now
you need four minutes to talk four
minutes early your calendar does not
scale hello does this work let me try
this out and the reason I want to try
this out is a I'm four minutes early and
be last time I gave a presentation with
somebody else's laser pointer was at nay
not 20 in DC and I shot myself in the
eye in front of like 200 of my best
friends so vaguely embarrassing so let
me try this out pointer works how do you
go for here we go next back excellent so
hi I'm Vijay kill I work for Microsoft
and we are going to talk about automated
configuration management today this is a
very large topic and this involves a
cast of hundreds although the primary
author of the work is actually mr.
Schmidt on my right so what is the
motivation everybody knows sorry for the
eye chart it looked a lot better on the
84-inch windows tablet I do my work on
my bad so what is the need for
configuration management there's a
fairly widespread audience here how many
people here run or operate networks or
other large automated systems for
network operators these are not as many
hands as as I would prefer to see so
what do the rest of you guys do
drink lovely let me try this again how
many people here don't run either
networks or other automated or other
systems at scale like this like do hands
up so there's a discrepancy here
somewhere either you guys are still
asleep or you're not paying attention
anyway so for the problem I'm having is
I'm having a hard time reading what's on
the on the monitors here good thing I've
memorized entire thing one of the things
everybody knows is there's a network
skills you have to make sure that the
supporting systems scale sub linearly
right I mean on average in the g8 and
you are looking at a loaded FD cost of
about five to four per million dollars
of GNA right so as you increase your
network size and having your
organization scale linearly your your
cogs Also Rises everybody here knows
what cogs is Right see OGS cogs is cost
of goods sold it's a large metric it
determines gross margin and a net profit
and we're all here to somehow make a
profit except for some were non profit
but point being you don't want cogs to
grow linearly with your service you want
cogs to ideally or portions of cogs to
track sub linearly with your scale units
and as a result putting more people to
do more work is a losing proposition
many many reasons for configuration
management one of them is scaling the
second one is that it makes it makes it
easier to reason about what it is you
are doing and i'll go into stats on the
next slide and the second thing is it
enforces standards and it reduces
complexity and one of the things it does
which is very important for us as a
service provider is that it allows us to
standardize the network and stand with
standardized
you can get to scale and one of the
things here is how many people keep
documentation in a wiki or a SharePoint
of course SharePoint or some sort of
other documentation management tool I
see 35 about oh wow because you know
what my next question is how many people
here don't keep their documentation
around and nobody raises their hand
shame on you the point is as soon as you
put any documentation or any
configuration management or any process
in a document management system like a
wiki or a SharePoint or JIRA or whatever
it is it is obsolete it is obsolete as
soon as you hit enter and click on
submit or save or save to SharePoint
it's done it's obsolete so one of the
things configuration management allows
us to do is it keeps your documentation
as code code is documentation and this
is applicable for process it is
applicable for configuration it is
applicable for standards so therefore if
you change a standard and you change the
code it pushes it out there's no lag
between what you are doing and what your
documentation looks like how many people
here love to document stuff they do
alright at least this time we are being
honest here exactly well played sir well
played well played Patrick well played
the point here is that if documentation
is code then there is no discrepancy
between updating your documentation and
updating a code because there are two
things people hate updating
documentation for the most part as you
all are tested and second is any time
you type stuff in twice there is a entry
point for errors for configuration miss
for typos for configuration creep so and
humans make mistakes even engineers
and of course since we are better humans
we that's why I actually this entire
talk is a reason for me to show this
picture because I mean one does think
like civil engineers constructing
bridges are very rigorous because
people's lives are at stake here they
tend to have very large amounts of
program management budgets and of course
all the ancillary equipment that goes
around with building a large seabridge
you would figure that they of all people
would get this right but obviously not
so much so moving on so here are some of
the stats this is why I said it is
easier for for me to show you and then
we can talk about how to reason or think
about how do we operate on this entity
the key part here is there about 77 280
device rolls we don't know for sure
because they keep changing around and
not all of them are documented in our
share points this tens of thousands of
networked devices number is very large I
see a bunch of Microsoft people here you
know how how big that is and how chaotic
but I should have said that inside voice
there are 30 million lines of config
approximately so now if you look at the
reasoning about 30 million lines of
config that's one config line it's about
57 config lines a minute so what
approximately 1 config line is second so
trying to reason about something that
large is is just completely not viable
by manual or human processing or
scanning right on the other hand if we
have a generating function and that
encapsulate sand generates 30 million
lines of config that generating function
could be 10,000 lines of code or five
thousand lines of code and we can reason
and think and analyze and check for
correctness ten to fifteen two hundred
thousand lines of code which is multiple
orders of magnitude less than the output
that core generates so therefore from a
inspection validation and testing
purposes having automation that can
generate 30 line 30 million lines of
config is much easier to get right to
reason about and think than to look at
the actual raw information that it is
generated through that generating
function so that's all good and well but
in the net-net people don't care whether
what my cogs looks like as long as they
get their service at a cheap or
acceptable price so in the net all we
are trying to do here is make sure that
what we are doing is actually resulting
in good service management because
customers care about reliability data
loss and so reasoning about how to give
them that using in a large system and we
are working on large systems now there's
no longer like networks or computers or
data centers it's all one integrated
system it requires very rigorous service
management it allows us to reduce costs
already talked about cogs on an SG&A
perspective it's great for users it
gives them reliable service without
manually triggered outages although if
you've been reading the press lately we
are not quite I think as an industry
where we need to be and in the proofs
time-to-market you can't reason about 70
million lines of code or 30 million
lines of code and then make changes
operational transforms to get you from
one service offering to another service
offering but you can reason about code
that takes that operationally transforms
this service offering with that 30
million lines of code to this service
offering with that 30 million line of
code because here you're operating on
10,000 lines of code I can understand
10,000 lines of code I can understand 30
million lines of config at least I can't
most people here I guess can but that's
why you're smarter than I am so how did
we do this well when I say we I mean
David did this I'm only the mouthpiece
work and credit should be given to David
and one of the people here who are
writing plug-in scripts and David
how that's implemented so one of the
things we did was I set a principle out
that in two years there should be no
human touch on the network except for
very urgent break fix and having that as
an operating principle or an overriding
goal then allows us to work back and
like reason about how do we get from
where we are today to where we want to
be and so Microsoft like like our
friends is Edward here Edward Edward
crab here he is much like our as Edward
gave in his talk yesterday and there are
two networks one is the internet
backbone and then there is the data
center to data center backbone and one
of the goals we set up for the data
center backbone was that it should be
entirely hundred percent automated and
and David will go into more examples
there and it's inspired by other
programs on Microsoft if you bring for
an auto pilot Microsoft the first hit is
a paper by microsoft research that talks
about out of the autopilot fabric
configurator and the second one is the
azure fabric controller so if you bring
for that that you also see the right up
for that which is pretty open I guess in
the industry so we are trying to move
the industry forward by publishing some
of the work that Microsoft Research and
some of our business groups have done
and the thing that was trying to point a
point out here is that we are now at a
scale where we humanly can't do do this
it's not possible on a manual inspection
or manual work to actually get to where
we need to be there are services here at
Microsoft that don't don't boot up short
of like twenty thirty thousand servers
at a time that's like the minimum
footprint for the service to come up and
I can't at least I don't know anybody
else who can manually configure any
element that takes care of like 30 40 50
thousand hundred thousand hosts at a
time it's just too large to do by by
hand
and of course one of the problems is
that at that scale you are constantly
broken failure is rampant at all points
just by the law of large numbers and so
therefore as you at that scale there's
so much failure that if you have to
manually remediate that failure you
would have like 10,000 people just
sitting there like 10 people per door to
figure out what's going wrong I see
Dylan is here he's like I do that we
just stop lying but you see where I'm
going with this just just think about
the numbers and of course it follows the
light rod management principle which is
to reduce SGA so here are some of the
stats we've seen so the first set is
about a year ago it took us about two to
three days to roll out the router after
the the automation was in place it's
about 30 seconds and most of that is
getting your credentials in it took
about two to three engineers to do peer
reviews jacks and all the other
associated process to turn something up
for Network acceptance now it's one
engineer and that's mostly typing's to
your credentials in and of course even
our engineers were making ten to fifteen
percent error rate compared to base
config these stats are derived from
checking what was bounced back through
peer review and after their 0% the Bill
of wrongs is a is a system that we keep
that notes exceptions and every router
would have like we would discover in the
network 426 items that would go into the
Bill of wrongs after automation there
are 0 because well you either code it in
the documentation and so you don't need
a bill of wrongs or it doesn't make the
mistake so you don't need a bit of wrong
so either way bill of wrongs is now
being rapidly cut down and change
velocity just from the sheer amount of
process and human inspection we could
push about 50 changes on a certain
segment of the network a month now we
are pushing I think it's 1,300 now how
much oh it's out of date we are not
pushing 2,000 changes a month into the
configuration and there are some issues
with that
I'll get to it in a second here but
basically this kind of shows the amount
of goodness that we managed to leverage
and to do that there are certain
principles that we adhere to when
designing the system and the first
principle is deployment is declarative
you declare what the state that the
desired state is and then the
operational transforms looks at desired
state current state and does a minimally
invasive set of procedures that takes it
from current state to desired state so
it's decorative deployment I already
said we had a principle that said no
human changes on the network and by
decorative in programming we can we can
make sure that that happens and there
should be never any end-user downtime
during deployments that is more of a
platonic ideal because everybody knows
our friendly bug filled routers even
with the most rigorous testing some
still escape in the field so we would
like to be there but in some cases we
are not but we are minimizing those and
we are a lot less than when we were
doing it by hand one of the things here
is that we can now repair automatically
I talked about it a little bit at the
scale we are operating under when I say
we I mean the generic industry is moving
to you can't repair things by hand you
have no time to inspect test validate
and then issue a pair order it has to be
done automatically kicking the RMA off
bringing the stuff in and of course keep
repair simple an ideal world if you have
large enough scale systems you can turn
the network or the managed elements off
and this applications will be able to
deal with it so if you have enlarged
like assume like let us work this mental
exercise let's take a cluster with
hundred thousand systems out of that
system over a month hundreds of disk
drives will die there will be tens of
tour failures there will be hundreds of
link failures if your application is
designed to run on that system
it can deal with network failure which
is the purpose of this particular
automation the same way as it deals with
the host failure because from the
application perspective if you are
running across a bunch of servers and
the far side server goes down or an
element goes down in the middle that
allows this server to communicate with
that server it is indistinguishable from
a host failure a network failure is
indistinguishable from a host failure
because the unreachable hosted an
unreachable host regardless of whether a
disk drive failed you had a CPU hard
error or an element that connected you
to that hosts the network in between you
and the host failed so at that point the
application itself is designed to deal
with host failures and for free you get
network failures in the fabric and now
that's not a hundred percent true for
grey failures where from a network
perspective sometimes you do it's hard
to distinguish between hard down and
soft corruption so on and so forth but
for the vast majority of cases an
application looks at a network failure
as a host failure and that allows it to
mitigate the service away by moving it
to a different set of hosts and then you
can kick off your repair process at
leisure so this allows you for example
to move away from a four-hour
replacement window which is very
expensive to maybe one week replacement
window which is significantly cheaper
from a MN our perspective nmn are of
course is directly flowing through two
cogs alarming if you can detect a
problem and you can alarm a problem you
know something is wrong and since we are
in a declarative policy system if you
know what is wrong you know what what
you need to do to fix it so repair
becomes the same as alarming or alarming
becomes the same as repair or vice versa
again there are some nuances here that I
because of time I'm not going to go into
follow me up outside follow up with me
outside but for the high level you can
think of alarming and repair as two
sides of the same coin in a declarative
system
and of course software development
lifecycle Microsoft is a software
development company and applying the
same sdlc principles to network as we do
to Windows our office or to other
products actually Maps very well in the
net net and I've told my guys this I'm
not looking to hire network engineers
anymore I'm looking to hire software
engineers because this is now in all
ways and forms a software system it is
you I don't need quote unquote router
jockeys I need people who understand can
reason about systems and programs and
code and unit tests and we'll get to
that in the next slide this is an area
where there is still a lot of room we
have to do work on so again like I said
it is easy for us to reason about 10,000
lines of code versus 30 million lines of
config right you can think about it but
still people make mistakes errors come
in data quality issues transposition of
IP addresses so one of the things that
we are working on now is we can test and
validate the program the generating
functions that generator config but
there's also another software test
system and David will go into that a
little bit in his portion of the talk
where we are looking at how do we unit
test two things unit test the output of
the programs and then you unit test the
program's themselves so an example we
have a router which needs a loopback
address so you run a unit test on the on
the module that generates the loopback
config but one of the things that you
can do is that we know that the loopback
address should have two properties first
property is that it should come from a
assigned block of Lubeck addresses so
you run a / 32 or a / 128 match against
the reserved block of Lubeck addresses
and see if it fits into that the second
property is that it should not be
assigned elsewhere on the network right
and of course that is again easy to test
for you run a grep or you run some sort
of other check against what's already in
the network and see if both those
properties hold true if those both those
properties hold true it is much safer to
push out that config and know at least
that we are not going to bollix
something majorly up because the worst
case is that we assign a loopback
address that is on the far side or on
the near side when it shouldn't be but
we know that it's not going to conflict
and cause is is week Alex and we know
that it's not going to blow up an ACL
because in the ACLS we know that lubeck
addresses should be denied or whatever
it is the policy is for they say also we
feel that within the guard rails of the
of the unit tests that the output of
this program is now valid for deployment
into the network and that's an area we
are still working on we know what the
end state looks like an undescribed it
we are not fully there yet in interest
of full disclosure but again just
reducing the entire configuration to
generating functions that are several
thousand lines in code allows us to be
much more manually rigorous in
inspection and with the output we've so
far haven't managed to blow up anything
major why automation and of course one
of the last principles is
standardization by definition if you're
coding out and we are splitting a small
generating function that explodes out to
hundreds of thousands of lines of code
you have to have standardized and
standardization because you need a very
few elements because you can reason and
think about those three elements and
then replicated Lee apply them it's like
a fractals most people here are familiar
with fractals the generating function
for fractals are like in some cases a
couple of lines of code the equation is
like single line of code one of the
simplest fraction is a square is equal
to C minus Z square plus a constant but
if you look at a fractal there's a lot
of information there's a lot of density
in the output you can reason about the
generator
function refracted fractal easily
because it's literally like five or six
bytes of information versus the output
which is which by definition essentially
infinite same way from our purposes the
minimum amount of generating functions
we have the simpler and easier it is to
reason but correctness in the network
and which forces standardization and
with that I hand it over to mr. Schmidt
twice forward there we go hi my name is
david schmidt i work with the core
network danger engineering team with
microsoft and the system that we
developed was designed to do a number of
things minimizing croft identifying and
removing any bits of leftover code that
was unnecessary to the operation of the
network any time a design update is
needed to push it out the the core for
example is made up of approximately 180
design elements and on occasion those
elements need to be updated as we do
maintenance verifying the output
verifying the conclusion of the
maintenance is critical are we sure that
standards have been met are we sure that
the network is going to run as designed
after we can after we conclude a
maintenance the less variation there is
in the network the easier it is to
support this adds to operational
simplicity if the router is predictable
and its function is predictable and how
its configured it is very easy to
support and troubleshoot when there is a
problem at Microsoft we have many hands
in the network it's very easy for those
many hands to come up with many ways of
doing things and when that happens
accuracy goes downhill so we needed a
single way of deploying changes to the
network and that adds to the efficiency
when there's many ways of doing things
efficiency also declined
the approach we took was to break down
the configuration and standards into
little elements when you have little
pieces of code it's easy to verify that
those pieces of code match to the
standard it's also very easy to come up
with a remediation action when they do
not match for example we have a snippet
there's six different elements
identified here as for the individual
scripts themselves logically they're
broken down into sections the scripts
are templated in such a way that non
scripters can easily modify these
elements the libraries for example are
separated off so that keeps the
individual scripts very lightweight the
scope identifies what routers or devices
this script applies to this can be done
via database mechanism pattern match on
the name or whatever other mechanism
would identify a specific router that
this script applies to dependencies I
will talk about later the expected state
is the standard you're comparing your
network against this can be hard-coded
into the script it can be pulled from an
external source it can be dynamically
generated by the script itself the
conditions are the flexibility in by
which the the script will pattern match
the expected to the actual state of the
config this is an important component of
the overall system and I'll talk about
this later the user options define what
the action is that the script is
required to take whether to generate a
change and push it out to the network or
to just simply report on here is a
failure and what you need to do to fix
it the actual configuration is more or
less at pattern match against the
configuration of the device that we're
looking at finally the
script will compare the actual to the
expected if it doesn't match then it
moves on to the output which is generate
a report or push a remediation action as
I mentioned earlier the libraries are
very important to keep the scripts
lightweight a typical script is only
about 60 lines long this again allows
non scripters to be able to go in there
and tweak them when a change is
necessary this is an example workflow so
for example we have a device
configuration the various components are
monitored by individual scripts for
example the interfaces there is a
problem and based on the user option
there's a report or repair action and
the repair goes back and fixes the
incorrect item conditions and then as I
mentioned earlier this is very important
we have various pattern matching
auditing tools today they unfortunately
generate a lot of false positives due to
the inflexibility of the pattern match
there's oftentimes many ways of doing
something and a pattern match can be
very rigid at times so the example here
we have to prefix lists at first glance
they do not match however under the
loose match rules everything is
accounted for and this particular
configuration would pass however under
strict rules there's one line in
particular that does not belong and
should be removed and then finally we
have strict order which requires the
expected configuration to exactly match
line by line in order to the actual
configuration and the remediation would
be to remove the prefix list entirely
and readd it in the expected order
dependencies since we broke down the
configs into very small pieces
oftentimes there's one script that
monitors one part of the config while
there's another piece of config
somewhere else that is perhaps broken
and one script is unaware of the other
so we built in a way for scripts to
recursively check other scripts to see
that other components are also passing
so the example I gave a peer group has
dependencies on EGP policies BGP
policies have dependencies on prefix
lists and AAS paths so if there was an
issue in the ass path for example the
peer group when I ran it would run it
would fail and would identify the
dependency as the failure the initial
deployment we wrote approximately 230
scripts across four device roles in our
core and edge routers as I mentioned
earlier advert on an average script ran
about 60 lines we found across those 230
scripts about 4,000 different variations
that we needed to remediate some of
these variations were very simple
description issues extra croft not a big
deal a few of them we looked at and
wondered why we weren't bit by them
earlier challenges so one of the biggest
challenges is different vendors and how
their configurations are formatted how
the behavior of the router is when you
make a change you can move from with one
vendor loading a config and saving it
and you're okay whereas another vendor
removing a prefix list for example might
be a problem and we adding it may have a
brief period where there's there's
issues on the router we're looking into
netcom to solve some of these issues but
we're not quite there
at during the initial cleanup we found
we had to do a lot of research into why
things are simply going from the current
running state to the standard state was
not always the best choice doing so
could lead to outages so the cleanup
process was was time consuming and and
difficult scripts can conflict with each
other so for example if you have two
scripts that are both looking at the
same portion of code and they want to do
something different they can both or one
or the other fail so you need to be
careful to limit how the scripts are
monitoring your configurations and then
finally strip coverage is really
important to achieve maximum benefit for
example if you only are monitoring half
of your configuration how do you know if
there's croft lingering in your other
half of your configuration so by
covering the entire code you can quickly
identify what doesn't belong and what is
left out of the framework as far as
other use cases we use it for a config
generator with just a few variable
inputs we can generate a baseline
template for a new router as Vijay
mentioned it takes just seconds to do
and has greatly diminished the number of
errors in new router deployments we also
using the framework the same libraries
to do incremental changes for example
new peering sessions new interface
turnips are tailored so that they take
user input and the user input creates an
expected config compares it against the
router fails generates the the
remediation and we push it out to the
routers thank you are there any
questions
how do so obviously you know these are
networks sorry name it really Hydra crab
Google these are networks these devices
interact and you're going to have
changes that encompass multiple devices
do some transactional semantics to take
care of partial config changes across
the network that are actually related to
each other do you just roll back all of
them and then how do you deal with the
different levels of push that you may
have forgiven transaction across
multiple devices I can't get it so one
example was updating a md5 password on
our ldp sessions obviously you have to
have the same password on both sides so
if you have one router updated the
session will be down until the other
side is updated we have the ability to
push out all the configs within a few
seconds by doing parallel streams with
these scripts most of the time that's
not necessary we just push out one at a
time as necessary I don't really tell
you much speed of delivery though I'm
talking about when one is the pushes
fails right so you have to you have to
keep track of state on on multiple
devices to determine whether descriptive
completed for the complete set of places
we run into the complete configuration
if the network is clean and you know not
mark dirty anymore rather than an
individual device or or script
partitioned config portion of a device
okay so after the scripts are run all
the changes of push we can rerun the
same script with a different option to
report out what is still failing and if
it comes back everything passes then
we're done if you're looking for or
Thomas City transaction or tomasetti no
we don't have transaction or dama city
yet I'm looking at you though we'll fix
it
a tot under in Google I think this is a
question for Vijay because it's not
about the structure of the configuration
management system but it's about the
cultural issue you said you're looking
to hire software engineers not network
engineers and I assume that's because
one of the biggest problems that network
engineering shops have with automating
network engineering is that it puts
network engineers out of business and
it's a very different job that needs to
be done how do you deal with that like
there's a core of people I mean they're
people here have been ranting about this
for you know a couple decades now about
monkeys on keyboards but like in reality
there's still a lot of monkeys on
keyboards and lots of us feel better
when we type things in it just feel like
we're doing something and even though we
know that's wrong like that's the wrong
way to do something but we feel like
we're doing something how do you deal
with that okay so did everybody get the
question the question was in defect and
summarize it was basically that a lot of
people feel that automation will take
number of a job and some of us just feel
better when we type stuff in so how do
you reconcile all of those so I if you
want to pull back a little bit and think
about the stem production of of
Engineers right the stem production in
the u.s. is much more heavily tailored
towards CS as opposed to network
engineering specialities in fact most
places don't have network engineering
specialities so if you if i just look
back five ten years going forward into
where the networks and systems like i
mentioned earlier evolving to by
definition I need to go where the the
engineers are right it's like why do you
rob banks I rob banks because that's
where the money is and so now i'm going
to tailor my systems to go to where the
money is and in this case the money is
in engineering and engineering the vast
majority of people that are relevant to
this industry are coming out of software
engineering CS degrees sorry sorry i
think this is exactly the right thing to
do one good olympic ahsha's how do you
sell i'm damned getting there right so
the first part is that by definition i
have to go to software engineering
anyway right so the second part is then
how do you transition our existing base
while keeping the system
running into a software center culture
so there there are two things that work
here the first principle is that as you
are well aware and so is Edward these
systems are too large to reason think or
even type stuff in by hand anymore so
there are no other option did I
say that so that's one by definition not
just you can't just do it the second
part is that this is not really a role
removal I am I'm hiring my team
essentially by I'm doubling the size of
my team this fiscal year which starts
now in three weeks I'm doubling the team
because what I don't need highly paid hi
GNA folks to type stuff into router it's
not a good use of their time v I need
them to start thinking and reasoning
about design goals about operating
principles so they can feed back stuff
two coders even within the coding
community it's not like one giant
amorphous blob of quarters right there
are people that want to do testing their
people that want to do new features
there are people that are very good at
doing maintenance right so even within
the network engineering field it's not a
blob of network engineers that type
stuff in in two routers those are the
people that are spending time typing
stuff in where I would rather have them
spend time thinking about other things
like how do I do it design how do i do a
regional routing system as I expand to
emerging markets how do I think about
that how do I operationalize and
implement scripting how do i make my RMA
process more efficient I want them to
think more high-level design not type
stuff in and most people who are good
and the ones that you want to keep
anyway are bored and don't want type in
two routers for the most part so that
actually dovetails very well in and
there's always going to be people and
this always going to be need from a
break fix and an operational perspective
of of turnips or bass configs who want
to do stuff on routers unfortunately
that is a requirement in some ways and
will contain
would be but that's it in my thinking
that's a career limited role thanks Aunt
acapella I've known as no one else in
Warren welter to warn you please okay
thank you what what do you think is the
future of this area that you're working
on in respects to sdn networking that's
salt call it non-traditional I'm
assuming right now the target is pushing
things into existing disparate boxes may
vs changing is this something you're
thinking about in terms of a completely
broad sense generic abstract of American
configuration or is a specific
specifically working on right now things
that we would think with traditional
routers with consoles and the problem
with that so in general this is a
context or a cultural shift what it
operates on is in some ways completely
orthogonal to the problem what what we
are doing here is semantic development
what it operates on is syntactic sugar
whether operates on a Juniper or a Cisco
or alcatel-lucent or whatever cool is is
syntactic sugar and is irrelevant to the
larger principles at work here so
whether operates on a SD n-type network
is is almost in one I would argue is not
really relevant except to the point
where Edward was talking about because
that is more closely coupled than what
we have today this is what they were
saying that some of the syntax input or
CLI exposure lends itself to some
problems for example we consistency with
the facts what Edward was talking about
yesterday is actually a very good system
where you can think about the entire
unit as it as a single entity and
operate on it in different fashion but
the principles are still the same it's
the implementation that that's a little
different and there some deltas with
with transactional consistency which are
easier to deal with in what the SDN type
workflow is versus our current piecemeal
unit at a time current state of the
rotting art and that's that