you sitting there here freezin I'm okay
yeah i'll just keep standing you're just
missing there's missing boy we're just
waiting yeah okay we're just missing one
panelist who is who's on her way but
I'll get started good afternoon my name
is paul stewart and i'm from nex accom
as1 one triple six we're a service
provider and regional transit provider
based in ontario my role within nexa
calm is that of a global appearing
coordinator and i'm also a senior
network architect in our operations
group in the spirit of full disclosure i
am also the secretary for the board of
directors for the toronto internet
exchange a significant part of my role
in our small organization is building
evaluating and maintaining peering
relationships at public exchange points
we currently belong to three canadian
peering exchanges eight US exchanges in
one european peering exchange we
averaged approximately seventy-four
percent of all of our traffic is done
through some form of peering we are
constantly evaluating traffic levels
between networks looking for better ways
to push the bits this of course includes
additional peering locations where value
proposition and possible performance
gains are the two largest considerations
taken into account Canada is the second
largest country in the world and as a
population of approximately 34 million
people of those 34 million it's
important to note where Canadians live
75% of Canadians live within 160
kilometers or 100 miles of the US border
according to most public estimates so
it's no surprise that the largest metro
regions are toronto montreal and
vancouver with just those three regions
having a combined population of a
point seven million people in Canada the
largest Internet traffic levels come
from the dominant providers the
incumbent telephone companies in the
cable companies this is nothing overly
unique to Canada examples of these large
providers include Telus Shaw bell canada
bell aliant Eastlink cogeco videotron
and rogers there are over 350 internet
providers in Canada according to
Canadian I SPCA which is a website that
allows consumers to search for a
potential service provider in their area
when these 350 or so internet service
providers want to exchange traffic with
other providers where and how do they do
this today I find this to be an
interesting question with typically
three answers internet exchange points
using public peering private peering of
course or upstream via their transit
providers in a lot of areas of Canada
your options for upstream transit
providers are limited to one or
sometimes two options it is only in the
heavily populated cities where many
transit providers start to emerge as
options the most common of these cities
that come to my mind again are toronto
montreal and vancouver there are many
other cities that have options but those
three have the most options if you're
not near one of these major cities in
canada you have the option to transport
your traffic to those locations at a
considerable cost or to purchase local
transit options but what about peering
where do canadian service providers do
settlement free public peering what
about us and international networks that
want to come to Canada and exchange
their traffic as well when I take a look
at data in peering DB and search for
Canadian exchange points a list of 12
possible IXPs came up if I filter those
results down a little further by
removing the possibly dormant exchange
points
or those that sometimes only have one or
two peers on them I really end up with
four or possibly six IX piece I'll
explain the Toronto internet exchange
known as Toric's is definitely the
largest ixp with approximate 156
participants and peak traffic levels of
over 70 gigabits per second currently
it's also canada's oldest ixp having
been established since around 1998
equinix has one peering exchange in
canada located in toronto as well
Equinix toronto has approximately 11
participants greater toronto
international internet exchange gtii x
is relatively new and launched around
March 2011 it has approximately seven
participants Ottawa internet exchange
known as audax has approximately seven
participants and peak levels of around
200 megabits per second it was
established back in two thousand and one
that's the four exchange points that I'm
able to confirm remember I said possibly
six the other two exchange points are
kicks in van tix if you will kicks or
Quebec internet exchange has
approximately 12 participants in
Montreal information about this exchange
point is a little bit vague however I
understand they're still pushing traffic
if anyone has any information on Kix
please come up to the microphone later
and share your your details Van Van TX
is the be seen at Vancouver transit
exchange up until recently I'll admit I
had never heard of this exchange
appearing DB shows 0 participants
however I did exchange some brief emails
with their staff and was told that while
there are primarily a research and
education network they do operate public
peering exchange points with active
participants their website is quite
informative on their offerings and their
staff are very fast to respond to the
inquiries I do believe that some of
their staff are here in attendance as
well the purpose of my lengthy
introduction
was to hopefully share a few key
elements about Canada the geography is
quite large and diverse the state of
California has more population than all
of Canada and we have a limited number
of active peering points today and we
make the best beer in the world had dad
that in there now got me thinking about
beer it's only noon now it's pleasure my
pleasure to introduce our panelists
today Patrick Gilmore is chief network
architect at akamai technologies where
he has worked for over eight years he
currently oversees the network
architecture department Patrick is also
vice chair at links vice chair at of
peering DB on the board of six and on
the board of nanog Sylvie hi Sylvia
laperriere serves as the chair of the
board of directors for nanog at Google
Sylvia is on the program management team
building out the internet connectivity
and content distribution reach required
to deliver Google services worldwide
John mr. has been the president of the
Toronto internet exchange for the past
two years it has been assisting Toric's
and various capacities for over the last
ten years bill read sorry is one of the
founders of the Manitoba internet
exchange the organization of em bi x
started in the fall of 2011 and the plan
is to be up and running this summer mbi
x will be the first IX that will receive
support as part of Sierra's project to
increase the number of I X's in Canada
Sarah is the Canadian internet
registration authority and oversees all
the dot CA domain names Victor cursing
is the network architect sorry for
Rogers Communications leading the
introduction of new technologies along
with steering the wireline wireless and
business networks in his role he also
contributes to the IETF in CableLabs
helping bring operator focus to those
bodies I'd like to extend a big thank
you
for these folks agreeing to participate
the main focus of this peering panel
today is to explore the current state of
public peering options in Canada I've
seven specific questions to ask these
panelists and then I would like to open
it up to the audience for any feedback
these questions are those that I get
asked on a regular basis by other
providers and in some cases consumers
themselves so it seemed prudent ask our
panel of experts their opinions on these
questions my first question for the
panelists some Canadians share a concern
excuse me some Canadian share a concern
around the amount of Canadian destined
to traffic the loops into the US and
back I did a really brief survey of the
big five a name commonly associated with
the five largest banks in Canada from my
home in erkan interconnexion in Ontario
I did a traceroute out to these five
banks of course this isn't a hundred
percent conclusive and only one
viewpoint but I found it interesting
that my potential banking traffic went
out to Chicago and came back to various
points in Canada for three out of five
of those banks my questions for the
panelists is do you believe that this
concern is valid if your personal
banking traffic or other sensitive
information goes to another country or
through another country do you find this
concerning and do you believe that
potentially more appearing options in
Canada would alleviate the concerns that
these folks have or is it just a lack of
peering in Canada who's that first
ladies ladies first okay yes okay so
when I thought about this question I
can't answer it in many ways first off
as a citizen of Canada I was thinking
while it seemed wrong why is my data
going somewhere else then I thought as a
networker I should have asked myself
that question maybe I should have done
some freestyle
myself but it never occurred to me and I
wondered why is that I do trust my bank
to do what's best so I do trust that
they have a networking team that is
protecting my data we do have a lot of
laws protecting confidential information
especially financial information so it
didn't seem to be a big problem for me
as a networker though I think we're
always better served as consumers when
the data does not travel long distances
so i would encourage my banks to look at
alternatives thank you so be John so
Sylvie's first mistake is trusting a
bank but to her concern a you know as a
resident as well why would my traffic
have to leave even the Toronto area but
then it just dawned on me well he's an
example TD Bank it's very popular in the
Boston area so the sort of begs the
question do Americans now have to come
up to Canada to do their banking so it
is quite interesting it is a valid
concern you know if I were to ask my
mother the same question she would
probably would have no idea would she
care she would definitely question why
it has to happen to the second point do
you believe that there's potentially
sorry was there more peering options
within Canada to alleviate the issue I
would say it would it would alleviate
part of the problem but then ends up
stirring up other problems Victor
so I mean I guess is a citizen that kind
of care of my banking traffic those who
the US or not probably prefer that it
didn't but I see it you know from an
operator perspective I see it as more
just efficiency I mean the banking
traffic's problem some you know some
amount of traffic i might care about it
but when we start talking about other
types of traffic which might become more
indicative of the future i start to get
more concerned about how efficiently
over moving beds across and can i be
more efficient by having more local
pairing that can offload things in
canada is that pose it shipping it all
the way down to the u.s. bill well i
don't have much to add but but my point
is basically the efficiency you know
obviously that silly said it exactly
yeah you don't want your data traveling
all over the place just to get next door
but the networks are very dynamic so
even if you did check and see you know
whether it was very difficult to even
check with content deliveries and
everything else you've a CDN metrics
it's very hard to determine exactly
where your data is flowing so and the
things that are important like financial
data are encrypted so theoretically it's
there's no security issue as such and
patrick maybe from a opposite
perspective here the u.s. traffic come
in the canada so there's two things to
worry about here the first one is as a
consumer I look at my banking data and I
want to know if it should travel across
a geopolitical boundary and what that
means to the laws the whatever I mean
I'm sure Canadians are worried about the
Patriot Act or the Americans are worried
about you know some guy on a horse
trying to run down our data but
whether that whether that happens or not
whether it's encrypted or not that's a
little beyond the scope of what I can
think about the efficiency that Sylvia
and many others brought up is very
important to me as a networker
unfortunately I don't necessarily think
that it is the most efficient thing to
always peer at the closest place right
if we have two banks in two towns that
are 100 miles from each other inside of
Canada and it takes 200 miles to get to
the US and back but the amount of
traffic between the two cities is five
percent of the total it could very
easily be more efficient total to go
through the United States remember we're
all for-profit businesses I mean to a
first approximation I'm sure there's
some educational institutions and
whatnot out there but in general is PS
or for-profit businesses and we want to
make money and to make money that means
sometimes doing things that may look in
a small scope as suboptimal but in the
larger scope will increase the bottom
line so going through the US if there's
lots of fiber that's cheap in it going
in that direction may be more efficient
than going across you know the frozen
tundra when it's expensive and you have
to dig or something thank you so earlier
I mentioned eight of the larger
providers in Canada just using examples
and using publicly available looking
glasses I took a look at these eight
providers to get a feel for how many of
them appear with one another or if they
purchase transit from one another my
interests here light and how the traffic
flows between these eight large
providers roughly speaking and
definitely not conclusive by any means
about fifty percent of them communicate
directly with one another the number is
actually higher than what I anticipated
the remaining fifty percent of these
eight large providers go through a
transit provider to communicate with
others a bit of a political question and
one that gets asked sometimes is do you
feel that governments should look at
imposing requirements for large telecoms
cable companies to connect to IXPs
locally in their region and if so those
larger companies should provide
reasonable peering guidelines for
interconnection it's a bit of a loaded
question John
okay um should the government get
involved probably not a brief discussion
earlier today sort of regarding this
whole thing there's any time the
government is involved with stuff it
seems to either drag on for an extremely
long time or doesn't get sorted out the
way that's maybe in the best interest of
how people want to see it in the case of
I X's here to have the government
regulate telecoms or other providers to
connect to I X's they may start doing
other tricks to avoid putting traffic
there so again to the day you could end
up with less traffic than initially
started Sylvia I really don't think
government should impose peering peering
as a mandatory thing I've said many many
times and many years ago and haven't
changed my mind about this I think
peering is a commercial decision it's
very easy technically to peer what
prevents people from peering is their
commercial and their business plan and
like Patrick was saying everybody has a
business plan and every ISP every
content provider has a business plan and
you have to trust them to do the right
decision for their network so and we do
also have examples in the world where
governments have imposed IXPs and
presence and mandatory peering and
they're not successful so what we want
is the peering point to be alive and
well and to be alive and well you have
to let the ISPs and the content provider
and whomever joins the exchange to do
exactly the commercial arrangement that
they want to do Thank You Victor
so off to probably concur the last few
folks here I don't personally think that
you would probably get the right outcome
if the government was to try to craft a
way of doing this I find that the you
know notion that you know if it's
there's commercial benefit of doing it
if it serves a customer base you know
people's overall experience is improved
by do having more pairing that that
should be the driver to doing it
unfortunately like mentioned as well
there are various commercial processes
and various companies that kind of limit
the ability to do this and hopefully we
can get past that because you know I
think there's a lot of benefits to be
able to have better establish parent
cross the Canadian operators excellent
Patrick I should point out that i speak
for myself not from my employer who is
apparently CBC now but anyway sorry aqua
speaking for myself only the idea that
the government imposed peering is a
really bad idea all that will do is make
a lot of networks exit Canada so I
encourage everyone to not do that and
built well I agree that it's probably a
good idea the in Canada with the CRTC
and the telcos a lot of the orders were
for cooperation and love and all that
successful because a company if it
doesn't want to cooperate and always
think of ways to make life difficult I
be more interested in the government
themselves in Manitoba I'd be very happy
for that government in Manitoba to
appear with our IX itself you know I'd
be happy that would be a good step
forward
and if there's a business case for for
isps to to appear well then fair enough
thank you given the large geography of
Canada which I've talked about and
taking into consideration the limited
number of IXPs I'd like to ask each of
the panelists if they believe that this
affects content delivery networks in
their ability to effectively deliver the
content Patrick no I was told to keep my
answers short sorry many content
delivery networks are happy to put on
net nodes inside of networks so the lack
of a strong pairing base in many places
is not a complete and utter inability
for us to deliver content locally there
are obviously lower limits you can't put
nodes in every single ISP no matter how
small they are so I X's that can
aggregate many small ISPs into something
that is large enough to you know require
a note a dedicated node for that I X is
useful but the lack of those I X's
either means there's not enough small
ISPs because otherwise one would grow
organically or that there are enough
large ISPs in which case you can just
put notes on them is that a better more
complete answer Thank You Sylvie I will
draw a parallel here to the u.s. in the
u.s. we have nine large peering metros
in Canada there's three large peering
metros and nine large peering metros for
ten times the population in the u.s.
seems to have done the trick yes but
those three large peering metros are
Seattle Chicago and
New York so I think that content content
delivery networks have other means than
just peering so by deploying caches in a
network you're effectively going much
deeper than appearing point and that is
what drives benefits to end users
because you're much more closer to them
than if you just leave your traffic at
the door of the peering point so it
won't it won't prevent cdns from
deploying the lack of IXPs or the lack
of peering point won't be an impediment
to deploy CDN networks thank you Bill
well Patrick and and silly answer the
question but what has said we're just
starting an IX in Manitoba and we are
we'll be installing back on my server
and a google cache server of course the
transit are not being supported by a
comma or or Google but these cast
servers will be very beneficial to the
local community into the peers so I
think that's the the approach you can
you can do and also the cache servers
are still useful just that the CDN are
not actually appearing at the the I axel
Victor
I mean I think the CDN provider is going
to be able to I mean whether they brute
force or not they're going to be able to
provide to their customer base you know
whether or not there's more or less
exchanges I mean I don't over use the
word efficiency but that you know maybe
there's better ways of doing it i don't
know i can't speak on behalf of you know
third party sedans or sedans that I
don't want to control so I bet if I look
at it you know in the future from our
own contents perspective and how I like
that the flow to customer bases I mean I
would say there's my personal opinion
that I think there's some benefits
behind there the one thing I try to do
supposed to be new technology guy is I
try not to use my old way of thinking to
define what's the best way of doing
something moving forward so I do agree
there's a lot of established ways and
practices to do things and you know
we've gotten pretty good at how we do
things in the past but I don't want to
limit our ability now kind of putting a
future hat on on you know moving this
thing there's beast forward by
consistently trying to figure out well
if it's worked in the past that
obviously means old work in the future
so I'm always open to trying to figure
out these are better ways more efficient
ways of doing it one last little example
there is you know there's the whole idol
I figured maybe people don't care about
this the green thing I mean it'd be nice
to be able to just use less electricity
no less resources to be able to
effectively deliver the same amount of
service to the same amount of people
jointly so one thing to touch on is that
at least from only some torx examples
over the past little while we've had a
lot of peers come in from very remote
areas in Canada through layer 2 circuits
to be able to pick up some of these
content providers so one way or another
those bits are going to get there
whether it's through these layer 2
circuits that come through or they end
up picking up transit through somebody
else so I don't think it'll answer
essentially is no
so world ipv6 day is coming up very
shortly as we know this is a major
milestone for content providers and
eyeball networks in my opinion there
have been some transit providers that
will provide free ipv6 transit if you're
at a common ixp with them and there are
also some large peers that have
restrictive policies on ipv4 appearing
but for ipv6 are very open to peering
even with small networks so my question
is in your opinion do I XPS contribute
towards ipv6 awareness and adoption and
i'll start with bill please yeah I
assume they will in in our case though
an IXP actually goes a long way to
encouraging acquiring an asn and then
bgp knowledge and just the whole process
of hearing a lot of the big big
organizations in when they don't have a
don't have any ascends so you know so i
think it that an i extent goes towards
improving in the small areas improving
the knowledge of networking entirely
ipv6 of course Victor it's actually a
loaded question I probably no way off
topic on this one whether IX peas help I
mean I guess some of these practices
have helped although I think at this
point and I could be wrong neither you
know is it on the operator side on you
know the folks in this room I think the
ISP I've sorry the ipv6 issues well
understood and the need to move towards
it i mean there's a very impedance there
and but you know I think ipv6 adoption
has some had some other barriers
hopefully in the next couple days some
of those will be lifted and excuses are
removed and we can kind of move forward
but like i said it's had some
contribution did did in the earlier days
it did have some people asking the right
was I just found it took a long time to
get the whole operator community to
finally realize you know you gotta got
to kind of figure this one out and and
on the enterprise side but I guess
that's not directly related to the IX
piece excellent it's a kind of
non-answer John I think I acts as a
whole I now this is obviously from my
viewpoint but from a permit or expect of
at least we try to encourage our peers
to reach out to other peers to get their
v6 connectivity flowing in a lot of
cases there's many people that don't
know how to where to start necessarily
or how to get it set up so we generally
tell them you know fired up we'll send
them a couple sites to at least get
started with it or get a better
understanding of it and suggests them
who they can reach out to locally to be
able to start doing some testing amongst
each other and whatever else like even
all of our welcome package stuff that
goes out to peers always includes v6
information because we try to push our
peers to once they connect do their v4
and either v6 at the same time so they
don't have to worry about it later on so
Sylvie I'm not sure that it would spur
the adoption of v6 or not I think people
well first off I hope you're all
deploying ipv6 I mean really this is the
second or third ipv6 day so if you're
not on with the program get started it's
going to implode in your face otherwise
so I don't know that an IXP would be a
motivator I think the motivation has to
come from your own network and that you
do believe that this is the best path so
i'm not sure an IXP has a role to play
there but it certainly doesn't hurt I
mean it's a good way to test it out and
test your peering policies and test your
maps so why not but I don't think it'd
be like yay we can push v6
is Patrick so I get this question
actually I quite a few times because I'm
you know involved with a few internet
exchanges I think that the answer is
that internet exchange has a nice role
to play because participants you know
talk to each other and so you can lob
the idea out there the reality is that
everybody who's got enough clue to
attach to an internet exchange better i
already have enough clue to do v6 and
they better have enough glue to have
already done v6 we all know that's not
the truth and unfortunately I don't
think that the people at the internet
exchange are going to change that much
it's not like torques or links or Jay
picks is going to say Oh what you should
do v6 in the isps going to go oh well
what was I thinking I'll do v6 now um it
also as Sylvie says how to has a nice
role because you can you know enable it
on appearing router not the rest of your
backbone our setups and sessions get
some idea about it so there is some
small use utility there but reality is
that you guys have to do it and the
exchange is not going to either help you
or be able to push you to do it it's got
to be down into your own networks if
it's your own business cases for your
own customers for your own reasons good
answers thank you when we look at the
known active peering points in Canada
there's no I XP in let's say Calgary
Alberta just as an example there are
several internet providers in the
Calgary area so you could conclude that
those providers might benefit from
having an IXP so my question is is why
do you believe cities such as Calgary do
not have an IXP today is it for lack of
interest from those providers funding
knowledge why isn't there one there
today sylvie please so if we look at a
model of opening up an IXP what makes
enough what what are the conditions that
you need to have a successful is V first
off I think you need a critical mass so
there are there needs to be sufficient
networks in the area that do want to
enter can
secondly you need to have fiber
diversity you need to make sure that
there's there's more than one provider
going to a location every network has
their favorite providers and when you
give them the choice to extend their
backbone to a location and they can do
so using their providers you will
generally find a business case to do so
so when there is critical mass of
providers of networks and where there's
also more than two fiber providers and
think you start getting the conditions I
would also say that what you need to
have a very strong I XP is you you need
people like you you need members you
need people that will make it work I
think the IXPs have had an amazing role
in expanding the internet i can think of
the seattle exchange in the Toronto
exchange that are all member based and
volunteers are powering the IXPs and
that makes a nugget of collaboration in
a city and I think that's important so
if the value of an IXP is to make us all
work together I think it has a lot of
value so I would add that and and it's
also a way to collaborate to to make
sure that we we get closer to users and
so those would be the conditions to open
up so the reason is why Calgary not I
don't know but I would go back again and
say do I have a business case to join an
IX in Calgary or not and to make my
business case I need to make sure that i
will connect to a sufficient number of
peers and that I can do so Kasich
cost-effective
using by extending my network to that
area Patrick so as I was just saying a
little while ago whenever somebody says
why does something happen or does
something not happen the answers money
we're all for-profit businesses if
you're sitting in Calgary you clearly
have to have a line to somewhere else
whether it's Vancouver Toronto Chicago
Seattle somewhere to get to the Internet
in general you may not need a line to
the building next door where your
competitor is and even if you buy that
line even if it's very very cheap even
if you could pair with your competitor
which is not at all guaranteed because
you know some people don't like to pair
with their competitors if only one
megabit of traffic is going between the
two of them there's no business
incentive so summary is really just what
Sylvia was trying to say and more
importantly just does it make business
sense if it makes business sense if
there is a compelling business raising
you know if it's just break even if it's
closed somebody might overlook it but if
there were a strong incentive if
somebody could make a lot more money
increase their bottom line there would
be an exchange since there isn't that
strong evidence not proved but strong
evidence that there is no business case
there maybe we can change that business
case by having somebody like Google or
Akamai or somebody show up and say hey
will pair with everybody well everybody
now come because it changes the business
case but at the moment there's clearly
not one for the ISPs in Calgary to do it
themselves thank you John
Calgary okay Calgary could have up to 50
ISPs first question that comes to mind
is what central location is there in
Calgary to put something like an IXP at
a lot of people may have some
reservations regarding connecting to a
nice p that isn't in a neutral location
the other thing that comes to mind one
of my previous statements with layer 2
circuits it is cheaper to get a layer to
certain to Toronto than it is in some
cases to go across the street in Calgary
so in a lot of cases people may just run
connections elsewhere do I think there's
a lack of knowledge not necessarily you
can always turn around and ask somebody
for some assistance or reach out to the
other I axes and see how they're doing
stuff in terms of a funding model if
their word maybe a neutral location now
pork started off with the switch in the
back of a beat-up honda so i mean i
don't think that's necessarily a concern
I remember the Honda yeah we're going to
open the bikes up in just a few minutes
just so I don't keep you standing there
too long okay thanks Victor yeah I mean
I think everyone's kind of beating the
calorie horse down but yeah I don't
think the lack of interest I think
there's a lot of operators are probably
well if they can make it come if is
commercially viable they might try to do
it again I think based on how some of
the Contra visors have spoken to me
there might be some challenges figure
out what the what the viability of
having an IXP out there might be you
know like John mentioned me right now a
lot of people make because the business
case is really about cost of circuits
and building with fibers maybe hopefully
in the future the business case will
include other factors that are currently
not taken into account which include you
know maybe operators making or content
you know people put content on the
content providers see DNZ make it part
of that the deal you know if you're
going to have my content I want you to
have the certain types of assurance
quality quality of assurance
so hopefully that might be factored in
the future yep excellent and bill well
Calgary Alberta has has a network called
super nap which is mostly research but
education but it also has sofa doing to
businesses as well that may satisfy a
lot of the needs for fur and IX I don't
know why we don't don't know in Manitoba
which is somewhat smaller than algorithm
is difficult to start an IX because of
the equipment of the points that Sylvia
and Patrick of have said it it's very
hard to get that you know that critical
mass it's really really hard
particularly when the dominant ISPs the
cable companies and the telcos are don't
seem to be all that interested in
joining and IX so I think it's really
difficult it's a tough slog thank you so
taking the Calgary example a little bit
further of course this can be applied to
several locations in Canada the Canadian
internet Registration Authority known as
sarah has announced on their website
that they've engaged an organization
called nor DISA T the purpose of
engaging or dicit is to have them build
a business case for potential
development of Canadian IXPs in
different regional areas well the study
is still ongoing this raises several key
questions in my opinion you know the
ever going question is do we need more
Canadian I XP points and if so what city
or cities are appealing given in that
some of these identified cities there's
no why XP today it's safe to assume that
there was no business case previously or
do we feel that nobody has built a good
business case to date John it would be
beneficial to have more in terms of
locations
I would probably say Montreal in
Vancouver out of the two and the reason
I say that is there's likely more pull
from other international companies
whether it's in the US or overseas to
land in those locations simply from a
variety standpoint in terms of a
business case maybe there is a business
case kicking around but maybe there
aren't actually any people available in
those cities to start running one of
these exchanges now that's not to say
that you couldn't do it remotely but
sometimes you need a couple local people
to kick it off another Victor again I'm
probably in line with with mr. there
John mr. sorry I call them mr. JH is
that I think Vancouver Montreal are
probably pretty good locations they're
big metropolitan areas it's probably
likely easier to build a business case
around that there's a lot of local
talent in those areas to help work the
exchanges and help out with that so I
think those are probably good places to
have and you know expression the
Vancouver side to things it really helps
us because you know we talked about the
whole 10 to 1 ratio of population but we
have slightly different drivers in
Canada and in the US this is not just
about density of population it's about
dispersion of population so it would be
nice to be able to set you know satisfy
the needs of for example those in the
West you know west coast or the west
side of Canada you know I'm looking at
some other factors of it because of
distance so we still have a distance
challenge in Canada so I think that
plays a bit of why Vancouver might be a
good selection as well excellent thank
you Sophia please
I definitely want appearing exchange in
Montreal because that's my backyard I
think it would be great I also think
that as a as Network planners you can
look you can you can consider Canada as
a diverse dirt diver spat for your
traffic if you look at City pairs you
can easily take Montreal New York
Toronto Chicago and Vancouver Seattle as
pairs and you can deploy a redundant
paths for your network when you do when
you do the the Northern Corridor the
former network that employed me Tata
Communications have that plan and it was
really really useful when there was an
event a networking event or I can think
of a brownout in midwest at one time so
it you can take I would look beyond the
boundary and say this is North America
and look at your network and you could
look at your fiber routes and make that
determination in terms of having a
sustainable exchange yeah I think
Montreal does have a lot it's really
close to New York and it's also well
served by European networks so it would
be a good a good location and Vancouver
as well considering Asian networks and
also diversity I think diversity as we
grow the internet is really important we
should all think of losing a metro what
happens if we lose a metro where does
that traffic go Patrick well my
geography sucks to begin with us on
sitting up here looking at a map of
Canada I'm going hmm edmonton they have
a we have a hockey team in
pretty sure about that so that must be a
big city right I think it's at it and
then how it works I mean we do NFL
cities in the US you guys do pal ki
cities I'm just but back in reality land
choose the matter is I don't care how
many people are in a city I don't care
how many people you know how many fiber
paths or whatever what we're looking for
is a hit bang on this drum again but I'm
looking for money right I'm looking for
a way to making you rich i'm looking for
a way to increase the bottom line in
Ruby PS whatever else you want to call
it and that is loosely but not / not
perfectly related to bits so we look at
places like Toronto Toronto is well
served by the torques and okay I don't
even there montréal is well served by
New York and his appearing point and
there's not a lot of advantage I don't
get performance I don't increase my you
know I get new customers I can't lower
my transit bills there's you know the
long lines are not that cheap or
something like that then I don't really
care about that and I look at the
edmonton which is a much smaller city
than montreal but perhaps the network
costs are much higher to reach there
those are the kind of things that i look
at and everybody in this room should
understand exactly how peering works or
you know most of you should understand
how pairing works and the rest of you
hopefully are trying to you know get
there it's a business decision I want to
make money so while it's fun to look at
where the hockey teams are and it's
entertaining it doesn't help me increase
my eps and that's really what i'm trying
to do so look at performance look at
long-haul costs look at you know what
will get more customers more dollars in
savings revenue etc and then do that and
unfortunately i don't know enough about
canada to answer that question so maybe
it's manitoba maybe it's newfoundland
although they have a half hour time zone
so i don't like to talk about them and
maybe it's edmonton I don't know thank
you and bill yeah it's it is hard in
Manitoba
being written the centre of Canada when
we do Trace routes of various traffic
often that the traffic's will that the
packets will go to Calgary Toronto and
then to Winnipeg or sometimes they end
up calling the states and then Toronto
whatever and so most traffic in in
Manitoba when they go between ISPs
travel quite a long distance and it's
not as not necessarily that they're even
paired together it seems so there was
quite a bit of interest in creating an
IX in in Manitoba but was mostly among
the smaller ISPs and and so we had back
in the fall we we had three or four ISPs
that were interested and we have about
half a dozen that are interested clearly
we don't have enough traffic to
encourage akima or Google or anybody
else content delivery to actually come
into Manitoba or only a million people
and of that only a few hundred thousand
perhaps our are actually would be
eyeballs would be in on the i-x but the
you know to set up Nyack's is not that
much money and so we were going ahead
with it very fortunately what a
coincidence Sarah had decided for their
own reasons that they would like to see
if it was possible to increase the
number of my exes in Canada and you know
we got talking and very fortunately as I
say we were ready to the point of
implementing it and sarah said well how
politically use the Manitoba internet
exchange as a test case we're seeing if
we can develop an IX in an area which is
too small to really warrant an obvious
business case so Sarah we're very happy
to be working with sara sara is like a
brand so it gives some credibility to
the IX and might encourage companies to
join it Sarah what Sarah has done is
there going to be putting at the I
accident putting a dot CA a root server
and an owl root dots are alert and ntp
server and they also are going to be
paying the transit for an Akuma cash and
I think Google cash as well so right
away you have some reasons for isp
smaller eyes peas to to join the join
the i-x so we'll see if that's enough to
get us a critical mass annual time will
tell but so far we're very very pleased
with Sierra's involvement okay thank you
no no I've got a seventh question here
and I'm just going to pick up the pace a
little bit because I know some people
want to come up and ask questions I'm
just going to ask one of the panelists
this question if that's okay content
providers naive all networks are always
looking at connecting a new IXPs it
realize that's a very blanket statement
but let's a true let's assume that
that's true for a moment so when
evaluating potential IXPs what are the
common challenges you see in DC any
challenges in Canada that are unique to
other locations in the world Sylvia I
think that'd be a great question for you
you're welcome I was distracted by the
colorful map can you repeat ribbon
thinking this is great for Patrick I was
going to give him a test after and ask
him where Nunavut was
can you repeat the question yeah so no
I'm not listening it will be ok so when
evaluating IXPs what are the common
challenges you see and or any of those
challenges in Canada unique compared to
other parts of the world hmm that's good
question I what's unique it's cold I
guess I guess I cooling down the gear
will be a problem and that's not even
true you know collocations power
spaceland finding places to put you know
the IXPs or where you know attractive
things that your neutrality for sure so
neutral location neutral providers of
fiber those are really important to set
up a successful ISP nobody likes to feel
captive of one network so you do you do
need to pick your building carefully
when you set up an IX also i would say
cheap power is becoming the order of the
day we all know that transit costs are
declining bandwidth costs are declining
but one thing that is steadily
increasing is energy costs so energy
costs in canada is actually very low so
it would be a differentiator and it
would be helpful to set up a business
case thank you you go back to the map
now yeah so we'd like to open it up to
the microphones here looks like we are
just under ten minutes so the audience
can ask a question I just have one quick
question for the group as people are
coming up to the microphones
and it's kind of a bit of a loaded
question but please put up your hand if
you actively peer in Canada it's quite a
number and out of that number how many
are you are not on torex for peering hmm
okay thank you we'll be talking soon
let's start over here please hi my name
is John Francois and I happen to be from
Calgary so I'm with cyber on the
research Network for the province and
I'm actively looking at starting up an
IXP we're at early phase right now
looking at where we could actually
locate it so I'll be I'd like to have a
chat with Bill and a bit later and see
if we can exchange ideas thank you
accept thank you sir Bloomberg I could
probably use the most appropriate
affiliation which is tor Exim on the
board a bunch of other companies very
early on you discussed government
regulation in regards to IXPs and you
know what I thought of was what's going
on and go back because there is some
form of regulation in Quebec but I'd
actually like to flip it around and ask
sometimes regulation is bad but
incentivization is good we have all of
these funds in Canada in regards to
deferral accounts towards you know
putting internet putting telephone and
communications on North etc would
incentivization be a better way of doing
it rather than regulation or is that
just you know the the same dog that the
lipstick know if you're going to pay me
I'll do lots of things I wouldn't do if
you didn't pay me and everybody stopped
the jokes that are in your head right
now
in me buddy else just picking up on your
question i would say that
incentivization should be definitely to
provide internet connectivity to rural
areas or remote area it is a very large
country and as you as you leave the band
of a hundred miles or 160 kilometers it
becomes increasingly difficult to
provide internet services so you rely a
lot on satellite or wireless and those
are typically networks that are a little
more expensive to build so I would if I
if I had like a government had I would
save my money program for that type of
access I think when you think of an
exchange it's easy for people to make a
business case to join in exchange and
and that should be it should stand on
its own and if otherwise if you
incentivize and you create an exchange
and it doesn't stand on its own other
than by government grant or funding it
will die because people won't join it
you'll have an initial uptake and then
it will just dwindle into oblivion
that's my personal opinion it doesn't
reflect that of my employer or anybody
else thank you so just to quickly touch
on that I think from an incentive
perspective if there's any type of
government hand and the thing you're
going to want some type of say in some
of it um I do a lot of work in Northern
Ontario and they still have party lines
up there so I'm not really sure that
getting internet to some of them would
even matter because
just don't you know they're fine without
it they also have a comment or a bit
with him not yes sir just introduce
myself Paul is a guy that tagged me I'm
with nerdy Citigroup and we're doing
this study of the Canaan acts fees so we
also on others if you are interested in
saying Canadian tax fees I'd love to
hear from you just a quick question do
commercial grade standards make a
difference in terms of attracting people
or not and should those be written into
some sort of s ellos or anything else or
are they really a discouragement in
terms of bringing in new peers
commercial grade standards are always
nice you don't want to fly by night
place but realize that the most the
largest internet exchanges in the world
are typically have no SLA you know
they're typically member base they don't
give any money back if they go down and
things like that so the members wanted
to be professionally run they wanted to
be stable but we're not looking for a
telco style SLA in general I think the
Internet is built on what we we called
best effort but we have to be realistic
and best effort is pretty much golden I
don't know of any ISPs that don't have
five nines or really bad uptime or
packet loss everybody is vying for the
same customers and best effort is really
golden so I don't think s la's would
make any difference I think everybody in
the room here wants to build good
networks and they won't they won't
settle for a lesser quality so we just
that's the way we build it thank you
yeah yes sir 10 Bloomberg again so in
the one thing i saw that is different
about canada is that in the u.s. a
mom-and-pop isp probably starts at 50
million dollars of revenue and that's
considered mom and pop in canada we have
because of the regulatory framework etc
we have a number of smaller ISPs half a
million 1 million five million dollars
in revenue lots of pockets of ISPs where
you might only have five or three is BS
in the town in the u.s. you might have
fifty or a hundred like in Montreal they
are probably over a hundred is BS in
Montreal that don't connect to an IXP
today because the cost to get Toronto as
an example is too much but if there was
one in Montreal or Vancouver you'd have
all these smaller players suddenly
connecting is that an accurate
difference between the US and canada in
terms of the network makeups that there
are lots lot more smaller providers
compared to the u.s. well obviously if
there are more providers and it's
clearly a difference right I mean this I
think the question is a little Tut
illogical hi we have more providers is
that different than the US where you
have fewer providers the answer is kind
of yes would it matter does that mean
that you should have exchanges that's up
to the smaller providers you know it's
it peering is not free as we've said for
years and years so if you have somebody
with half a million dollars with the
revenue and it costs him five grand to
you know go to the building bring up a
quarter rack by the equipment in set of
peering is that worth it to him or it
will he only save five megabits of
transit which costs him you know ten
bucks a month I I can't answer the
question whether it's useful or not
because I don't know enough about the
smaller providers it's up to them and if
they do or if they think that it would
be useful to have somebody like Google
or meijer you know anybody else out
there to come and peer with them all
they have to do is email us we are more
than happy to discuss it with them but I
can tell you right now one guy got
emails us and says hi we'd like to set
up an exchange and it's one small
provider with one small amount of
peering traffic the answer is going to
be no you got to get them together so
talk to each other you have ISP
associations you can do it a
I've been so careful not to say that the
whole time of that up here yes sir hi
Ron Berta skywave s here in Vancouver
and because no one from pure one is
standing up to correct them is
conception I have to point out that
there is a internet exchange point in
Vancouver called pics and there's what
15 members and of which we are one
there's an act Amaya limelight
connection to it and lots of big
providers there and it does very well so
you know you can join us technically
there's a pics in Toronto and Montreal
as well but we have not seen any type of
update at all from sort of the pier one
side of the house but you know so does
anybody from pier 1 it definitely would
be nice to hear more about it and I do
believe that so first of all I know that
aqua doesn't have a router in Vancouver
but apparently that exchange is
connected to the Seattle internet
exchange is that correct Mike yeah so
i'm i'm ninety-nine percent certain you
know having being in charge of akamai
hearing stuff that we don't have a
router in vancouver but if it is
attached to the Seattle internet
exchange that's great and you know you
appear with lots a lot more than fifteen
people there so sorry I should've
mentioned we also have a and the same
you know on the same route is the six
that connection is in our connection
that harper center so yes there is a and
I standish into the six in Vancouver as
well thank you we're just running out of
time so just one more quick question
your please yeah it's going to be quite
godly Cosby from CBC how successful our
Canadian internet exchange is compared
to the rest of the world
the the rest of the world is vastly
different right so you have things like
am-6 and links and d cakes which have
terabits traffic i was i was looking at
stuff like all Equinix exchanges around
the world are less than a single track
these less than the total traffic of
am-6 by itself literally so would you
consider equinix not successful yes or
no I mean it's it's hard to say what is
the metric of success number of peers
number of routes number of megabits
whatever the Toronto internet exchange
is smaller than almost every you know
major exchange in the US but I would not
consider it I wouldn't even begin to
consider it unsuccessful it's very
successful I die but the rest of Canada
i would i would consider toronto to be
honestly the only quote unquote
successful exchange I think the there's
a somewhat an evolution for your network
as well when you start peering on an IX
at one point in time you do make a
determination that it could be too much
traffic on the public fabric and you
prefer to pry to privately pier with
another network and again that's why the
neutrality of the site and the abundance
of fiber providers to help you do those
private connections by Iran is important
great thanks next week we're kind of
running really out of time they're going
to throw something at me soon but you
have a quick question very quick just a
point of clarification when you guys are
talking about the terabits per second of
peering traffic that's very often the
public traffic that you can see so when
Patrick says you know these guys are
these big terabit per second exchanges
as public hearing fabrics other
facilities like in equinix for example
would have an enormous amount of traffic
going privately between parties that you
cannot see so it's very difficult to
compare the two um the private peering
is by definition not exchange traffic
you know one 11-8 has a lot of
privateering if you take you know the
exchanges out of it
the point is yes there's lots of
buildings with lots of private
connectivity the question was are the
exchange is successful and I would say
the internet exchange generally consists
of both public and private peering that
goes on and I woodsy I would disagree
with that because if you take Equinix
and packs out of the loop if you look at
you know links as a private private
peering product but m6d cakes tour x 6 j
pics etc do not they don't own the
buildings they don't own the facility's
they are not in any way related to the
private peering so no the exchanges
exchange and private peering is private
peering now it's perfectly valid to say
that one is useful and the other is also
useful but they are separate I was just
close by saying I disagree I think the
public and private period collectively
is what makes the exchange valuable
whether you use one or both or a hybrid
anyway that's cool thank you heard I
think we're out of we're out of time
here folks sorry to cut cheese off I
just like to thank the panelists first
and foremost for participating and thank
the audience for their feedback and
participation as always thanks again
ok so just on the programming notes we
reconvene at two-thirty after lunch
there is a meeting and open meeting that
for feedback with some of the folks from
the board and the program committee
that's going to take place just on the
other side of the back wall in the open
seating area if you're interested in
giving feedback on the things that were
discussed at the community meeting
yesterday thanks