great thanks Chris next step we have a
Vince fuller and Glenn Wiley talking
about lists DDT
you're safe trust you we gonna my sign
these twin Darrell so I'm uh I'm Glenn
Wiley I'm a systems architect at
Verisign I spend most of my time with
ComNet and the anj roots we've got Vince
fuller from Cisco and Darryl Lewis from
Cisco and these guys are the some of the
original authors of the list of drafts
of DDT draft it's kind of interesting I
was glad Vince put some dates in his bio
on the abstract 1983 his first people
weren't even born in 1983 so yeah I was
getting paid in 87 to do stuff with
computers but it was nice to see that he
he beat me there so we're gonna do a
little bit of tag-team here now we'll
talk about what's going on we'll give
you some reminders about what Lisp is if
you don't know what it is it's not the
thing you use to automate Emacs how many
of you guys have done development and
Lisp actually for production
well come on so I've been paid to code
and list back in the 80s I they're like
two people then we're gonna talk about
DDT and this isn't the pesticide that
you used to see in TV in the 50s and
then finally we'll go over some some of
the stuff that's going on at Verisign
with respect to Lisp and DDT so Vince
okay I'm gonna handle this part we're
gonna do it we're gonna do a review of
Lisp you know how it works things of
that sort and before I start that I'd
actually be curious to know how many
people here have seen one of these lists
you know intro presentations before
that's not bad it's what about 20% maybe
I've because it's been a while since we
did a road show at one of the one of the
regional registries before and so it's
gonna be a little bit expired I guess
they passed our sell-by date and I'm my
eyes are good enough to read these
slides
but anyway first question to ask is you
know why are we doing this why did we
start doing this well initially this was
this was work that was kind of spurred
by a workshop in 2006 looking at growth
of the global routing state in the
internet and there was some concern and
we decided to look at solutions and one
of the solutions that came out of that
was was list that was the I be writing
address workshop in October of 2006 the
concept of ID and locator were something
that were it was first developed back in
the 60s there's a Jerry Saltz er paper
that is cited by a guy named Noel
Chiappa who was one of the early
developers of Internet routers in the
80s and it's a concept that was kind of
foreign to people because the Internet
Protocol suite combines both the
identifiers you know what the end point
is with how to get there that with
routing information for it and one of
the revelations of this this paper and
this study that was again back in the
60s was that by commingling those things
it makes it kind of hard to scale the
routing system and to give some things
like mobility ability to change
providers things like that by separating
those two concepts by introducing two
new dress spaces effectively we you know
we give the ability to do those things
turns out that not only is this a good
thing for solving the global routing
system growth issue but you can also do
some other things I mean obviously you
get some mobility advantages you get you
get mobile multihoming with ingress
traffic engineering which is really hard
to do today in a destination based
routing system the only tools you really
have our you know pre pad you know
prepending and doing other community
hacks with you bgp edit vertiginous you
can also build large-scale VPNs and it
turns out you can also do some
encapsulation tricks to make it easier
to transition to new to new protocols I
hesitate to say which new protocol since
I'm not a big fan yeah some people know
what I mean by that pictures worth a
thousand words this picture is kind of
the reason why when we started looking
this is a who here here has seen this
picture before some variation of it
you're kidding that's all I thought this
picture was like in every single IETF or
Nanog or ripe or anything presentation
about routing since no one since people
haven't seen it I'm going to indulge
myself with a minute to explain some of
the spots on this this skirt No okay
well the thing is I love this picture
because each of the different inflection
points on a tell a story if you look at
the beginning you have kind of a super
linear growth curve then there's a
little uptick when we started deploying
site or addressing but we couldn't
aggregate the routes yet then there's a
down short downward period it's the only
time the global writing system is ever
shrunk
that's when cider was deployed then nice
linear growth as cider was working and
then things started to to go super
linear again when you had the internet
bubble achieving it's it's super growth
and also you started seeing the
aggregation for things like traffic
engineering then that flat spot in the
curve who knows what that is exactly
that would basically routing system
growth stopped for a year during the
collapse of the internet bubble which is
you know it's profound that you can see
that here then you start seeing growth
again and then you see start seeing very
sharp growth as we started seeing the
post post bomb explosion the little tick
mark off to the right of the graph there
that's actually an artifact of the data
it's not really a decrease in their
growth rate so that's why I mean we want
to try to reduce the kerbs thing length
there quick review of some terminology
again we're talking about separation of
endpoint ID and locators endpoint IDs
are the things that hosts use they
terminate your TCP connections or your
HTTP sessions there are things that you
want to be able to take with you if you
pick up and move your site from one
provider to another they they are
generally more amenable to aggregation
within an organization rather than
within the topology in lists in the list
world the separate one of the things we
do when we separate this function out is
we don't propagate endpoint ID
information through the routings
on the other hand there's routing
locators those are topologically
assigned I think of that as being
provider assigned address space
they are aggregated opportunistically
wherever the topology allows it and
they're subject to change when there's a
change in the thing where you are in the
network if you change providers you get
new locators if you have a mobile
handset that moves from you know from
Tokyo to Vancouver it gets a new locator
even though it keeps the same end point
ID user data is all a list encapsulated
because since a IDs are not propagating
through the routing system you can't get
directly to them just using internet
routing so you need some encapsulation
mechanism mechanism and a translation at
the edge between the endpoint ID and the
locator the network elements that make
up the list encapsulation decapsulation
and database systems are the ingress
tunnel router that's the thing that you
send but generally it's in your default
path for traffic exiting your Lisp site
it will encapsulate the packet it will
take the e IDs lookup destination the
IDS look up the located destination
locator and then it will encapsulate the
traffic so that it can be routed through
the global internet to get to the Lisp
end point at the other end the egress
tunnel router provides the opposite
function it receives it receives the
tunneled traffic the Lisp encapsulated
traffic it unwraps it takes off the the
locator header and then delivers it to
the end host which uses the endpoint ID
addressing typically those two functions
are co-located in the same box which we
term in xtr since it's an ITR and ETR at
the same time there are two other types
of devices that perform this
encapsulation and decapsulation on
behalf of non Lisp speaking devices the
proxy ingress tunnel router is basically
sits on your provider network and
accepts traffic does the encapsulation
for it the egress tunnel router is
actually something that you can use for
transition and to hop over parts of the
network that don't speak Lisp also to
get around things like ingress traffic
filtering that get in the way of doing
Lisp like things
this is the diagram that shows how the
basic Lisp encapsulation decapsulation
and then and transport through the
intermediate network works on the
left-hand side we have a source that is
sending to a destination the right-hand
side we have a pair of
ITRs ingress tunnel routers that it's
going to use to get to encapsulate so
they can forward through the intervening
internet and then there are a pair of
ETRS on the right side that will DQ
capsulate that traffic and deliver to
the end destination the first step this
is actually common to pretty much any
internet a transaction is you look up
the host name in the dns you get back an
IP address in the list for all that IP
address is an eID you then take that you
know we can take your data packet it's
got the Eid source it's then going to
forward it to the ITR because it well I
won't tell I won't explain why it knows
that it should go to the ITR that's for
later in the presentation but it will
send that to the ITR the ITR will
determine through magic that will be
explained later how to get to the
destination address which again is a
destination a ID it will look in its map
cache it will say you know I have this
source going to this destination the
destination locator for this destination
is this I can't read address because my
eyes aren't good enough but you can
probably better than I can
it will then encapsulate put an outer
header using those locator addresses on
it and then send it into the internet
the internet you know goes to the 1st
provider while the provider knows how to
get to the destination that's on another
provider network it forwards it along to
the destination locator which is
associated with the ETR at the other end
of that the path the ETR will strip off
that header find the inner address which
is the endpoint ID for the destination
and then it will deliver it to the
destination right there any questions
pretty standard map and encap the magic
that makes it possible to figure out you
know
what a ID translates to what locator is
the mapping database the the mappings
themselves are actually stored in a what
we call it would consider a distributed
database where each mapping is actually
stored by one of these ETRS and that is
propagated through a mapping system
which is really a way to index all the
mappings they to get the appropriate
appropriate locator for a particular
destination the ID an ITR will send a
map request to an e TR which then will
respond with that locator information
how it finds the e TR is where the
mapping database where the index comes
into play there were some fairly
ambitious constraints placed on how we
would build this database it has to be
able to support millions of sites and
subscription time changes in mappings
we're not talking set seconds but we're
talking you know hours to days the
actual transitions a greater rate than
that or have handled by no other
mobility mechanisms that originally when
we prototype this we looked out at you
know what could we take advantage of
that was already available on the
Internet well there are two large
database systems on the internet there's
BGP for routing information and then
there's DNS for name to address
translation initially we took we decided
to go with the you know BGP plus GRE
plus v RF approach because we could use
existing router technology with only
minor changes conceptually it's very
simple in practice it turns out to be
kind of painful to operate the
infrastructure that uses the database
and manages this database is made up of
a number of other devices map server
that takes information from the etrs and
publishes it in the database there's a
registration mechanism where the ETRS
can give that information to the
database and yes it does have a security
authentication mechanism then then the
map resolver which acts on behalf of the
ITR to find the right ET are going
through the map server infrastructure
these in case it isn't obvious these
these terms were chosen for deliberately
to be similar to the DNS terms resolver
and server because they perform
relatively analogous functions list ball
then was the original database indexing
technology is an overlay network of
tunnels generally GRE tunnels with vgp
sessions running across them where the
actual iid prefixes are advertised among
the participants in the database
remember how I said I IDs are not
advertised on the Internet well they're
not they're only advertised on this
private all overlay Network again all
was a simple concept turned out to be
really painful to work with
operationally and it took you know quite
a bit of time took like an hour to add a
new site because you had to go through a
fairly painful process of adding GRE
tunnels and and Moulton figuring
multiple brf's I don't know how many
people deal with TRS but I find them
hopelessly confusing so that's when we
came up with the need for to do
something better and that's when DDT was
born this is a diagram that shows how
the old Lisp control playing with all
was you know works it's the reason that
we show it here is because there are
some things that are similar in
particular the use of the map-resolver
and the map server but all that alt
stuff is actually replaced by DDT which
Glenn will go over in a few minutes
again we have a destination IP address
ITR needs to figure out what ETR to send
it to and so they can get send a map
request and get back the appropriate
locator the way it does this is it
basically it has a connection to the alt
it takes the destination a ID and it
just forwards it across the overlay
Network - a map resolver well actually
know that excuse me I'm getting ahead of
myself
the map-resolver is actually statically
configured on the ITR so that the ITR
doesn't have to know the details of the
database it says here I have this
destination I want to send the map
request I'll send it to my configured
map-resolver same thing you would do
with a caching dns server that acts as a
resolver for your site
the the all the map-resolver intern has
a connection to this overlay Network it
takes that destination Eid and it just
sends it into the overlay Network which
is routing the eid-prefixes it goes
across the BGP overlay Network ends up
at the ETR ends up at the destination
map server which knows the ETR sends it
to the ECR DTR then sends a response
back with the needed the needing mapping
entry the map the ITR then can go back
to the previous slide and put that in
its cache and then forward traffic
between the to that destination Eid
using the locator address so that brings
us to you know what is Det and how does
it work and I'm going to turn it back
over to Glenn for that so so DDT is
creates a hierarchy very similar to DNS
it's statically configured to begin with
you can think of the ideas of you know
say transferring its own files that kind
of thing
and there's this idea of delegations
that you can hand responsibility for
some of the prefixes prefixes within a
prefix you're responsible for down to
other servers now originally they they
did try and work with DNS actually with
the protocol and ran into some problems
in encoding the prefixes was awkward
they had issues with there's this idea
that we need to be able to offer
negative replies so just it became
painful the other thing is dns does a
lot of work with labels you know it's a
lot of what we do on those servers is
has to do with compression and handling
all the stuff that goes with a label
with with Lisp you don't need to worry
about that it's it's all numbers so a DD
T node will have an authoritative prefix
a set of V IDs that it's responsible for
but it doesn't actually keep the IDS
it's just say like a net block those e
IDs the the extended Eid is tupple
comprised of instance ID that you
the prefix of length and there are a
couple of other little bits in there
that you'd seen the standards the idea
of the instanceid that actually lets us
create multiple instances of an eID
prefix say again right for vin said for
VPNs so the the DBT nodes will accept
map requests they return map referrals
and that will either tell the requester
whether it needs to go to another d/dt
node or whether it's going to a map
server to actually get the final piece
of data now if you think of this as DNS
you can think of this as exclusively
name server entries and the a records
would end up ultimately just on the map
servers so you wouldn't have any a
records in the sense that you're trying
to get to that final endpoint actually
configured on the d/dt nodes so the DBT
node can also be a map server and and it
there's really a lot of this is
implementation detail but but you could
overlap the functionality everything
that that Vince talked about with the
map servers could land on a DDT node
there's the idea that would return the
same messages ultimately it ends up
returning an acknowledgment that tells
the query err when the query is done we
don't have to iterate through anymore
DDT nodes so the the resolver this is
this is more like a recursive resolver
in DNS land it would do the work of
actually hitting each of the nodes we'll
go through a diagram that shows this
makes it a little more clear some of the
jobs a resolver our caches requests from
ITRs remember those are the the routers
sitting on the at the site that's trying
to make the queries out trying to find
where to send traffic though it'll query
the resolver queries the DDT hierarchy
iteratively there isn't the idea that
the ITRs routers need to do this I hand
it over to the map-resolver and it takes
care of going out and hitting each of
the nodes you can do things like detect
loops and delegation errors within the
map resolver and there's also the idea
that you're maintaining a cache
and that helps us get around potential
latency if you had to do this every time
you're setting up a session that could
create some work so there's the idea
that we have referral caches and request
caches so positive referrals like I said
they're pointers to DDT nodes it can be
an odor for which means go get the next
more specific prefix from this node it
could be a referral to a map server
which says go get your final PID from
this the R log for this AI e ID from the
map server and it would say that it's
answering with the the finally ID in
that type - so the the negatives are if
you have a map server that has a list of
prefixes for which you know ETRS are
registered you'd get a type 3 message
the idea is that a map server can be
aware of the set of prefixes but might
not have anywhere to send them until any
TR registers for them there's an idea of
a delegation hole there could be part of
the prefix that hasn't been successfully
delegated out to another d/dt node so we
don't have anything more specific to say
about it or not authoritative that's
that's the idea that somebody has made a
mistake
they've asked for prefix that this node
isn't authoritative for so walk through
how you set how you set the the system
up now this is the static configuration
you think of the idea of root hints on a
name server resolver that's what we do
here we have to identify where the root
nodes are for DDT so it knows where to
send its first message and then each of
those DDT nodes would be configured with
the delegations that would take you to
node 2 3 and finally down to the the map
server the ETR actually does the
registration dynamically so as an e TR
comes online it would let a DD T node
know that it's there then we have our
our packet flow now this is actually
happening in
real time so the ITR would send a map
request to the first DDT note it says
Amar's I think that should be DVT node1
and the DDT no dancers tells it that it
needs to go to DDT no.2 and this
iteration proceeds until you get to the
final point where you have a map server
to go to now this only happens once when
you first start the session or when TTLs
expire after that you end up in a steady
state will see that on the next slide
but it's the idea that the EMR can now
carry conversation directly with a map
server ultimately getting the
information back to the ITR so that
there during a query that we just went
through doesn't have to continue to
happen
okay just report on where we are now we
actually have implementations on two of
the Cisco operating systems iOS and
nx-os we're also working on one floor
that for iOS XR which runs on the CRS
and the SR 9000 we have abated network
that we've built out of this that we are
using DDT on today with a bunch of sites
who are participating with this open
list which is a open BSD based
implementation of Lisp is also
implementing okay also implementing Det
at this point and then Barisan is going
to deploy a prototype deployment using
the existing implementations which is
also working on their own implementation
so now the open Lisp is implemented in
the BSD kernel it's you know so they've
tried to keep that fairly efficient in
the verasun implementation we'll talk a
little bit more about in a second but
deployment and interoperability are
going on on our beta network today we
have what Daryl we have one hundred and
something
beta sites and in a bunch of different
locations around the world and then we
have probably a half a dozen different
sites that are where the DDT the
regional delegations are maybe I'll have
a slide on that and
nice thing about this is the
configuration and the operation is much
simpler than all it was we don't have to
deal with any BGP filters a s number
assignments you know GRE tunnels or vrf
management and we also have more
flexibility as gland said we have the
concept of instanceid that's part of the
the Eid that allows you to have parallel
infrastructure for things like VPNs war
for you know private address deployments
where you need to do some sort of
encapsulation to get them dinner operate
the current implementation does not
include they propose security extensions
that will have a mechanism for doing
authentication and signature validation
of the actual map requests to prevent
certain spoofing techniques organization
and operational status as I said we have
abated network going on right now
there's a collaboration among Cisco
Verisign and a company in Amsterdam
called in touch that is collaborating
and working to manage the root zone on
the DDT world and operate the
infrastructure boxes
common route you could go to DT route
org it'll actually show you what the
boxes are give you some more information
about what's going on now as I said
earlier this is all running on the list
pilot network the we did a transition
from list vault back in March and we
removed the last messages thank goodness
of the alt configuration back in April
and all of us Darryl and I in particular
read the great sigh of relief when that
was done we're looking at a number of
different options for how to operate
this you know how to operationalize this
in the future should the route be
operated and run by a non-profit you
know kind of analogously to the way that
they route you know the route DNS
servers are operated or what sort of
model makes sense we need to focus on
transparency you know we want this to
all be open and people to understand
what's going on and definitely
scalability that's probably the most
important issue and then of course
efficiency and simplicity because we
want this to be able to be operated
without a PhD in uh in routing science
this diagram is just
I don't expect anyone to read it because
it's kind of an eye chart but it
basically is there just to show that the
you know the D the existing pilot DDT
deployment is distributed we have a set
of root servers up at the top those can
be operationalized at some point in the
future they're a prototype for that then
we have you know they delegate a chunk
of the address space the prefix 153 dot
16/16
to the list pilot network which then
just for proof of concept has further
split that into regions so that we can
get an idea of how easy that is to do
and how easy it is to sustain that's all
running today again we have 100 and
something sites that are all
participating all using this
infrastructure Glenn's going to talk for
a few minutes about the list development
at Baris awning what's going on there
I'm going to have to talk fast so we're
right now Verisign we have we have some
gear set up we're trying to support the
open list of development and part of the
motivation there is you know obviously
Cisco isn't going to be shipping source
code for an X OS out to everybody to
show you how they've built Lisp and
Verisign can't release the code that
we're working on internally that runs on
our infrastructure so we need somewhere
to do this work that's visible as we
continue to produce standards and
contribute internet drafts we need
reference code and an open list seems
like a good place to put that now
Verisign we have a pilot program in
place that's running a mapping service
now we're testing a customer portal to
use for provisioning and onboarding
folks very similar to what we do with
the registrar's now and this in-house
service that I mentioned will be coming
online in q4 of this year and that'll be
deployed on the same infrastructure we
used to support the ComNet dns
resolution platforms and so Vince
mentioned a second ago how important
scalability is our a and J roots in the
comm net resolution platforms are have
proven skateable scalability list seems
like a good fit for those platforms in
our pilot network we have redundant
servers and resolvers at a couple of
different data centers with redundant
transit
native v4 v6 should make some of the
folks happy here I think Martin and my
people please do that
we're running everything on our 710 s
using nx-os right now the open list BDT
capable code is due out in the very next
release that they make it should be in
June of this year we're talking next few
weeks and then like I said our map
servers and resolvers will be online in
q4 running the native Verisign code now
the bottom layer we've got some details
about the root servers like been said
that's available from the DD t-- root
service dot org and this is just a quick
map to remind you guys about what we've
got going on in the Verisign network you
know if you're if you're concerned about
where the list nodes are going to land
we have gear in over 70 places around
the globe
most of our most of our installations
have pretty fat pipes and plenty of
equipment to handle high query loads so
far we've got a hundred percent network
uptime for more than a decade for ComNet
and that number 105 million domain names
I think it's up 220 million now the
point is it's big Vince I'm just gonna
got one slide here just to talk about
where where Lisp is going I mean this is
one of the things I want to emphasize is
this is not a Cisco project yes people
that have design Lisp and working on it
from the beginning after mostly Ben
Francisco but we have other people and
it's all being done in an open forum
it's in there's a list working group in
the IETF d/dt actually all of the list
documents the core list documents are
already submitted for RFC publication
we're just waiting on some dependencies
to be cleared on for some non list
document doctrine on those documents
that they reference DDT is a draft in
the IETF this working group the version
1 is out there version 2 is in progress
it's going to clarify a bunch of things
and and actually give some more detailed
information in the form of a finite
state machine or event you know decision
tree for to help implement or is
actually implemented future work I'm not
gonna go over that now but we've kind of
covered that already the eCos
refers to how the organizational
structure will evolve an interstate
internet scale deployment well I think
we have a pretty good idea how to do how
to do that given the model of Vera signs
a DNS server deployment these are the
resources you can look at these later
some web pages where the first one is
general information about Lisp the
second one is you know the Cisco
implementation information how to get it
and then the list but IETF dot org is
the IETF lists working group open
working group and again DTU org that's
the list boot operators and the status
of what we got going there questions and
comments
here are some contact information for
further information listed for at cisco
comm list but verasun comm and there's
actually a mistake in the last one
that's actually list interest at PUC
nether net some reason I had a brain
freeze when I type that in is because
there's an internal Cisco list with the
same name definitely welcome input we
definitely welcome more participation so
please contact us if this looks
interesting there's going to be a list
presentation tomorrow morning that talks
about how Lisp is being deployed today
and how it may affect your network so
that's 9:30 tomorrow morning and you
might that might actually make this a
little more real for people do we have
time for any comments or my way over
schedule being take up maybe one or two
and then move on but we should partly
make it pretty fast so a couple any
questions quick ones Mandy rate abortion
IJ yeah your presentations not up on the
web so I couldn't grab it oh the word
security oh yeah that was something we
got I knew someone was gonna ask that
question there actually are a couple
mentions in the presentation that I
glossed over and because we were going
too fast the the delegation process
actually does have a signature mechanism
where every delegation from a parent to
a child is signed and that information
is propagated through the map referrals
so those that information can be
verified when you get the delegations
and you follow when you push an update
when when you that's actually there's a
separate site security mechanism for the
ETR to map server registration and
that's actually documented in the map
server specification but that is there
we are we
but we're not crazy so so in a sense
okay thank you in the sense alt was
sticking to be in BGP yes and this is
kind of a warped version of stick it in
the DNS it's well it's it uses the DNS
model of a statically delegated
hierarchy but it uses a total at first I
thought it was like a DHT no but it's it
is DNS delegated but there is I mean if
you look at the DDT specification there
is a whole section that talks about the
security model
and we actually have a I was off the
security okay just trying to understand
your structuring and you are choosing a
delegation model as opposed to a hash
model yes and because we understand how
to make that scale okay thanks sure
anyone else I think it's about it for
questions so okay thanks anything any
other questions comments feel free to
contact us on those man this Thanks