Thank You Jessie that was scary but now
it's time for the lightning talks and
first up here is Tony who's going to
talk about the DNS changer and yes I'll
just leave him thank you all right so as
you can see for those of you know Mary
Kay I'm not her and she was unable to
attend to the last minute because she
hurt her back and can't drive the
distance it takes to get here so i
offered to present the slides on her
behalf because i have some familiarity
with the subject matter to could you
reset the clock work all right and it's
also a timely topic that's important so
I didn't want it to get missed this time
so we just talked briefly about what
students change or what the takedown
would happen during the takedown and
replacement of the seas servers customer
infection remediation statistics efforts
and what happens on July ninth which is
only a little more than month away so
for those who don't know Dina's changer
is a malware that changes the dns
settings on on victimized machines and
also tries to reconfigure the home
gateway to point at DNS servers that
were operated by a criminal enterprise
of folks that were mostly located over
in Europe and there was a coordinated
law enforcement effort to take down
these to arrest these individuals take
their assets and prosecute them and what
basically what it was was to make money
off of illegitimate ad insertion traffic
here's the net blocks involved
the what happened during the takedown
was that the seized servers which were
actually physically located in the US
were replaced by ones that that operated
normally and and and generally gave
correct answers and so the they were put
in the place of the existing servers on
the same existing address space in the
same ISPs were continued to advertise
that address space so that there was an
interruption of service a blackout for
all the people using the bad DNS servers
for them just because of them just going
away that was back in November and this
is kind of just a quick cartoon about
how how it happened they took the
servers on the Left away and inserted
the the ones on the right to pick up the
traffic so what happened after that is
also they took the information from the
logs of the servers about who's hitting
them to give a sense of the affected
machines so that then the people who own
those machines were the people who were
upstream of them could notify the users
to that their stuff was broken that they
could get well and this ad hoc DC WG
which is dns change a working group was
formed to do this work and generally
promote the the remediation of the
infection under a an existing thing that
is C does call the security information
exchange s IE the informations published
if you're interested to to receive the
the detailed information about who's
hitting the servers and who among your
user base might be infected you can do
that there's information on the DC WG
org website
there's also information there about how
to detect whether you're infected in
local languages their websites you can
hit that give different visual responses
based on whether or not you're hitting
the replacement servers for DNS
resolution or not and there are some
cases where it will return a false
negative because there are some ISPs
that have chosen to redirect to
basically in cary internal routes for
that address space and pointed at their
own internal dns servers that's all done
with a positive outcome in mind which is
to keep their users running and also to
be able to internally detect whether
their which of their users are affected
so that they can notify them and help
them remediate there are tools that have
been work to try and help clean it up
unfortunately this malware is really
nasty it affects the boot Master Boot
Record and and often actually
reformatting the disk is is that the
only thing that will really fix it but
there's also cases where it's updating
the home router let's see I think that's
in the next slide there's a number of
ones that since obviously probably
everyone here knows that the many home
routers ship with the default config and
user login credentials it'll try and
exploit those to reset the the configure
the router not actually install malware
on the router but that's one nasty
aspect of it so this is a little cartoon
that was supposed to show essentially
what what happens how how an affected
home router can make it appear that
device is behind it that are not even
affected with malware like a smartphone
or a printer or what have you it will
also may show up so if you if you try
and get to the website
that shows the different green or red
based on your infection you may see it
on device that's not infected but
affected because its downstream of a
device that's using compromised DNS
configuration here's some statistics
about the overall trend of the
remediation of all of the of the
detected affected machines over time and
there were some spurious spikes in the
beginning but it all started on november
eighth when the when the replacement
servers were put in and it's been
trending generally downward but there's
it's been about forty percent remediated
by this metric and there's still well
over three hundred thousand apparently
affected people although that may be
something where there's a number of
devices behind a NAT even a an
enterprise firewall that that that's
masking some larger number of infections
but this is the course coarse-grained
view here's a little bit more detail
that was provided by some folks in in
germany about different events in the
remediation effort including public
publicity campaigns and roll out of
their specific native language detection
site to show that you know how this
helped but still basically lots of
infections so part of this is all it to
thinking back to jesse's doc you know
it's a bottom-up community organization
involvement and trying to figure out you
know what went well and what didn't is a
little bit of the the exercise people
have probably seen discussion on the on
the nanog list about well i've got this
notice from the FBI or my isp and it
didn't make sense or i didn't care or
what have you so that's all part of the
learning experience and more feedback is
appreciated constructive feedback
so what's going to happen is in less
than a month's time no sorry slightly
more than a month's time those the court
order will expire that provides these
replacement servers so people who are
still pointing at them will we believe
go offline because they won't be able to
resolve DNS there's possible it's
possible that some operating systems
will fall back to dynamically learned
DNS servers so it's not completely known
what what will happen with all of them
but there may be a wave of extra support
calls if you have relatives who you'd
like to check out their configs you
might that would be helpful because
better that you do it proactively while
they're still online before they just
call you and say you know what happened
in the internet this is a cat picture
that record put in okay
so any questions I do have some
familiarity with the topic but I can't
necessarily answer everything that she
may have put in here questions comments
all right no oh very sorry next up is
sorry gosh yep well done that's Shane
amante from level 3 there you are thank
you and Shane is going to talk about
resource certification using DNS and I
are us Thank You Shane this is to the
force yeah cool hello everyone I'm Chan
amante from level 3 i'm here to talk
about resource certification using dns
and IRRs some things that i've been
working on with some collaborators my
colleagues at level 3 and also era
castor oil from verisign so the broadly
I think there's a probably agreement
that the three Horsemen of the Internet
is three things the IRS the Internet
routing registry specifically is what is
encoding routing policy information what
is the intent of what is an AS wants to
originate or effectuate from a routing
perspective you have the output or the
results of the policy information
carried inside bgp that's routing that's
reach ability information and then last
but not least you have dns which is
naming right naming is obviously very
important because that's what gets
everyone to their destinations without
having to memorize IP addresses so these
are very three very critical systems
that are already deployed scaled being
used and they have been for well over
a decade if not longer so the question
came up as to why not just use the IRS
for resource certification and usually
the first answer you get back is the IRR
sucks period and then you ask ok well
why you know what does that really mean
because there's aspects to the IRRs
there's the data portion of the IRS and
then there's the routing policy
specification language or our psl the
latter of which is a very rich syntax
which allows which is very expressive
and allows one to express many things
from a routing policy perspective and
usually the concerns are not around the
RP SL but around the data or the quality
of the data and that's really what the
the fundamental issue is is I don't
really know what data within the IRS to
trust so the question I asked back is
can we actually improve I are our data
quality and I believe the answer is yes
with the light assist from DNS so the
question is will why DNS well why not
obviously I'm not sure how many folks
are aware but DNS SEC is deployed for
reverse dns we've in fact signed several
/ sixteens through Aaron already it's a
very quick painless process to actually
set up and works just fine I'll talk
about that in a couple of slides the the
other important points worth mentioning
is that in DNS in particular there's a
single route obviously and there's a
single trust anchor that is deployed for
DNS SEC that's operational today which
is all good obviously given the
operational experience we have in
deploying DNS for the last couple of
decades there's obviously substantial
resiliency and scalability to DNS and by
that you can easily think of
a couple different scenarios one is
anycast DNS is a mechanism that's widely
deployed on the internet for
high-availability reasons as well as the
capability to deploy multiple name
servers and obviously you should deploy
multiple name servers across multiple
networks of course for maximum
resiliency if you don't know how to do
these things than perhaps you should be
looking at a provider that does do these
types of things and entrust them with
your DNS and then last but not least of
course there's obviously a massive
amount of monitoring documentation
training tools etc that have been built
around DNS for the last several decades
as well so it'd be very nice to leverage
that same already deployed
infrastructure if possible to provide
research for Internet numbers so how
could such a system work what we would
propose is that one takes in builds
first and foremost you actually go in
build in your reverse DNS using the
nomenclature provided in that draft
gersh DNS op reverse DNS cider the IP
prefixes and origin a esas in what are
called secure route origin resource
records inside DNS i'll show you a
little example of that and in fact
there's a talk that's on tuesday that's
also showing some examples of that but i
encourage you to go read the draft and
you can see more details about it
obviously once you've encoded that
information inside dns you've signed the
zone with DNS SEC obviously to ensure
that it's secure the next step would be
how do you validate against that step 2
would be back czyli using the existing
mechanisms that we already have today
you actually build a candidate IRR
origin list using your favorite irr
toolset flavor whether it's homegrown or
one
is open source and you effectively are
coming up with a set of IP prefix origin
a.s pairs next step would be after that
you actually go through and you verify
each one of those IP prefix origin es
pairs that you pulled out of the IRR
against DNS SEC so you're looking up an
IP prefix and you're looking to find and
make sure that the AAS or origin is
actually matches in the DNS reply that
what you is what you pulled out from the
IRR and then last but not least
obviously if it matches then you're you
have a sect of Li a secure route origin
if it doesn't well obviously something's
broken so here's a little bit more
details of what the DNS lookup process
would actually be obviously you know
there's only three steps here it's
hopefully pretty simple obviously if the
DNS SEC SRO resource records set matches
what you pulled out of the IRR for an IP
prefix in origin a yes it's valid you
have a signed authenticated response
following the DNS hierarchy that that's
a valid origin obviously if that's the
case you can include it in either IP
prefix lists with origin a s matches
inside routing filters that you're going
to apply two routers inside your network
or you could just use it for offline
manual verification if you want it to do
that and and and using information as
you want to we already talked a little
bit about the second step was if that's
invalid if the DNS SRO resource records
set does not match what you pulled out
of the IRR then it's considered invalid
you should not include that in your IP
prefix list step 3 obviously a little
bit more tricky what if you get a not
found coming back from DNS what if you
don't know what to do with it well if
it's a more specific that you have
already validated a covering aggregate
because you've basically pulled a less
specific covering aggregate out of the
IRS and you validated that against DNS
and this is most likely a Miss
configuration case where someone forgot
to go in code the more specific inside a
DNS so I say go ahead and trust it
because you have a covering aggregate
with the same origin as4 it on the other
hand if you consider that the prefix in
origin is does not match a valid
aggregate then it's invalid and you drop
it so give you a couple of examples of
the encoding inside of DNS SEC this is
an example of a couple of prefixes that
we've encoded various prefix lengths you
can see there a / 20 s / 22 / 24 in fact
you can go and run these same dig
queries yourself at your leisure and
verify that they actually do match and
then last but not least as far as
conclusions go hopefully everyone agrees
that using DNS SEC for resource
certification is actually a pretty
straightforward process actually using
DNS SEC and I are ours is also a very
good thing because it's leveraging
deployed systems that we have decades of
operational and experience and tool
chains and training already built and
available so with that there's about a
minute for questions
hi Doug Montgomery news why would you
bother putting prefix origin information
in the DNS to validate prefix origin
information in the IR IR why not just
take something else in the DNS if you
like it's trust hierarchy and digitally
sign the route objects in the irr I'm
not really sure what you're alluding to
but this is a very lightweight and
coding scheme that's using the existing
inadar address that are patrie that is
signed is just a naming convention of
what you use inside of DNS so you're
already there and it's your duplicating
prefix origin information in the DNS to
validate prefix origin information and
the irr correct because there is no
deployed security authentication
mechanism in the irr itself
unfortunately that's it's it's not
widely available so what can I actually
use and DNS SEC is basically an answer
that has a single signed route that
allows me to do that but it only
validates one piece of the route object
if I was going down that path i would
just digitally sign the route object so
maybe the piece that you're not
understanding is that when I build
prefix lists and origin es filters that
I applied towards my customers I already
have a tool chain that's built around
pulling information from the IRS which
gives me a fully enumerated list of IP
prefixes in origin a esas which then I
can very simply walk through one at a
time and validate and if I get an
authentic signature back I can then say
with assurance that that is a valid
origin is tied with that particular IP
prefix so it gives me an enumeration
capability as perhaps the key thing that
is what I'm trying to say here ok guys
please remember one question per person
and we need to wrap this up rather
quickly thanks Radhika your first
rüdiger
okay okay sandy Murphy Sparta there's
been suggestions Ruettiger was one of
the ones who first put it forth to do
something to use the row as in the rpki
system to produce something like route
objects that can be used with the
existing tools to build filtered lists
there's also a draft before the site or
working group in the ITF right now to
use rpki certificates to do
authentication of information that's in
the RP SL it's the RPS l sing stuff and
what was I going to go there's a subtle
difference in the semantics of the SRO
and the robot object in the RP ki and
the route object have you looked at the
way the RPS s the defined security
system for irrs defines the authority
for route objects so again I'm not here
to talk about the rpki i'm here to talk
about existing tool sets that are
already in use in the internet i'm
talking about the things like the IRR
power tool set like the PE of l and all
those sorts of things you can use the
yet you've not using the rpki currently
i know you aren't and so I think I don't
have any early to extract information
from the rpki and stick it into and
quite frankly I want to stick with the
existing systems that I've already got
deployed and leverage those as my path
going forward okay is there you're
talking about ways to improve the route
object on data that's in the IRR with
the data that you're doing in DNS SEC
correct do you think you will take a
look at what is being proposed to use
rpki data to provide authentication for
irr data so I'm familiar with that work
but I'm not here to comment on it I'm
asking you whether you would know
thank you for your refusal semi or
Sparta so you're talking about how the
reverse tree is very well signed catches
the reverse tree doesn't currently have
a naming convention for net blocks are
in this new one that gursha mothers are
proposing and when I've looked at that
naming scheme it looks like is not quite
a parallel tree but sort of an overlaid
tree or it's actually not fully deployed
so you talked about using this in some /
16 switch I can believe but I think that
using a / 15 would actually be very
challenging right now is that accurate
so that's accurate in so much as you
need to we would need to get cooperation
from the rars that would hold that
reverse tree to do this naming scheme
I'm not necessarily a DNS expert here so
i would actually defer you to Eric who's
actually at the mic that can probably
give you a better answer could I could I
I have to cut you out I'm sorry Eric but
I have to make a commercial for the DNS
track in the afternoon and I think that
would be a great place to continue this
discussion I just say one thing like 30
see 20 seconds 20 I'll do a 15 I think
unchanged second or third slide he
pointed out that the IRS are giving them
policy semantics that don't exist in a
lot of the other systems you guys are
talking about i think that's why he
threw those in there ya know Rudy good
know what what policy definitions has
shane actually fun we're gonna have a
discussion about tomorrow as well
because we have more presentations in
this subject you will get more and
welcome to edward from google everybody
i think at this point i have like
negative five minutes so i try to keep
it brief and get you out of here so you
can get to whatever you're doing so you
know Google likes to talk about open
flow a lot open flow in general has the
hype machine running on it pretty hard
right now
there haven't been a lot of real
deployments as far as I know we have the
world's largest open flow deployment
currently in terms of total
state-managed total number of nodes
deployed total pops pretty much you name
it so I'm going to talk a little bit
about that and I'm also going to talk
about how we did it if there's time so
Google has a big network you probably
knew this already if you believe Craig
labovitz which I do sometimes in 2010 we
were the world's second largest network
this is before the agglomeration of
global crossing and level 3 Thank You
Shane so this was only our front-end
network though our back in network is
actually much larger than our front-end
network and you know this is the
standard boilerplate for why I think
some of these numbers are inaccurate at
this point I think we have 72 hours of
video every minute which is like one
point one point two hours per second so
anyway yeah it's big and we push a lot
of content over it we actually have two
different backbones we have internet
scale backbone which is what the Atlas
metrics were on and we have a Google
scale backbone that orgy scale which
runs between the data centers and this
only runs between the data centers that
it only carries kind of bulk data
traffic for us index pushes etc etc as a
result of this we have pretty widely
varying constraints with regard to the
lost sensitivity of the traffic classes
that we're talking about and with regard
to how the topology is deployed the
overall availability of the network etc
etc in other words we get to be a little
bit more experimental with the back end
network and we get to do some exciting
stuff and that is the open flow network
for google in addition the widely
varying traffic characteristics between
the network's lends itself pretty well
to a lot of operations research e-type
techniques for doing optimization of
crap
engineering on the front end in general
you can do pretty standard traffic
engineering because we have a fairly
smooth diurnal cycle there's a few
exceptions to that obviously on the back
end though we have extremely bursty
traffic when index push starts it's
basically a square wave and since we
have some idea about what the schedules
for these things are we can take
advantage of this in traffic engineering
so why do a software-defined Wayne in
the first place what's not sufficient
about existing protocols well a lot of
it has to do with the hardware honestly
so in doing this we get to separate the
hardware from the control plane software
and that means we get to take advantage
of a very cheap fairly high powered
commodity compute and that is a good
thing as i'm sure you all know the
controllers that you're putting in your
routers are you know four or five years
out of date and you're paying a great
deal for them so it's very nice that we
had to make use of our bulk compute
infrastructure for doing a lot of the
stuff that we want to do with regard to
optimization in addition the fact that
is logically centralized gives us a more
complete view of total network state
which makes for a lot of pretty
interesting opportunities in
optimization and I'm going to talk about
that a little bit later it also gives us
the ability to automate fairly simply
part of the problem with running a very
large heterogeneous environment
obviously is that you have a lot of
northbound API is in the form of
different config systems or XML or etc
etc and so having to deal with this
stuff in a non-uniform way is kind of a
pain as we all know and I think Vijay is
going to talk about some of that and in
that too distant future and we also get
to control both the horizontal and
vertical on this network so having fine
gain control state like this let's just
do some pretty interesting things and as
I said I'm going to talk a little bit
about that so in general the theory is
that this results in a higher
performance land that's more efficient
more fault tolerant and cheaper
basically we get better ROI so where is
this deployed pretty much everywhere
this is public information
Greenpeace actually did a really great
article on data center locations
recently and modulo you know the wattage
they got a lot of stuff right so he's
never underestimate the power of two
hippies and paisley with a pair of
binoculars but yeah it's deployed
globally at this point and you can see
it's very difficult to see for me at
least I'm sorry but you can see we've
been working on it for about the last
two years and that we're starting to
we're starting to taper off as the
complete set of back-end traffic has
been migrated onto the open flow Network
so this is sample utilization across the
set of links in the network yeah so run
stuff pretty hot in general this this
would obviously be problematic if we
were worried about you know if we were
doing like standard mm1 modeling for
queuing delay or any of this stuff and
we're actually concerned about that this
would not really be all that tenable
moreover we were worried about standard
kind of TCP transport protocol semantics
with regard to having some sort of
sawtooth going on we that would be a
problem fortunately because of the fact
that we run this network and we run all
the systems that are on it we get to use
non-standard transport protocols we also
get to do a lot of fairly interesting
stuff with regard to scheduling so so
what are the implications for network
operators well the pros are that we've
seen it reduce the cost of the total
land deployment in terms of dollars per
bit per second in capex it's less true
for op ex currently actually I think
that I think that you know we're going
through some growing pains but there's a
lot of potential here in terms of
automation that were would be difficult
to get in other areas we get to do less
over-provisioning for SLA is this is
because the protocols that we run our
entirely deterministic modulo the demand
being non deterministic now because of
the fact that we actually have some idea
of what we're transferring between
systems and we can schedule these things
they're a little bit less
non-deterministic than you might think
but there is a certain amount of
uncertainty there however given a demand
profile we can tell exactly what the
network
is going to do so we've managed to
deploy it incrementally and we've
leveraged known techniques for
delivering this functionality the cons
are that with regard to open flow it's
not really a good package solutions
currently for on the land side at least
the protocols are in their infancy
anyone who looks at the OpenFlow spec
currently is and who's done protocol
designed before it's going to be pretty
disgusted and and rightfully so the
software in order to in order to do the
sort of stuff that we're talking about
here obviously a lot of software
engineers spent a lot of time on this we
did a lot of protocol design work we did
a lot of algorithm design work and we're
fortunate enough to have a really great
operations research team doing
optimization on this stuff and so if you
don't have those things your mileage may
vary as I said there aren't really any
good package solutions right now but
hopefully someone will fix that it will
also vary based on your demand
characteristics as I said you know the
more square wave of your demand is and
the better you know the schedules the
more you're going to get out of this so
what this google Software Defined Wayne
actually look like well this is built
from our own hardware that we've been
working on for a little while in general
it's entirely built out of merchant
silicon and it features open flow
support which was something that we
weren't able to get from any of the
vendors at the time in general we would
have liked to have purchased this stuff
because developing your own hardware and
is a pain in the ass pardon my french
but we couldn't at the time so we also
used open source routing stacks in
particular quagga to do BGP and is is
for the sake of the initial integrations
likely the BGP portion will obviously
stay around for a while because we're
going to have to interface with a lot of
other networks it doesn't have the
complete feature set doesn't have your
Apple talk I don't care sorry it's very
cut down and so the sort of embedded
software that we write is extremely
minimal and it can be considered a
little bit user unfriendly at times but
it's also cheap and functional so
obviously you deploy multiple chassis
for site blah blah blah so what does it
actually look like well we have what is
effectively out-of-band controller array
these are a bunch of machines that are
just pushing flow mods down to
individual devices and these are
deployed on a per data center basis in
addition there are quagga machines that
are associated with the controller
arrays that runs through what's
effectively a large rib manager which
Trant does translation from routes to
flow mods there's also a traffic
engineering server and these two things
run in parallel and basically I'm sorry
basically the traffic engineering server
just pushes out stuff and that
represents the overlay topology on the
existing is is topology so in order to
do this we have a global broker which is
effectively a global scheduler I'm not
really going to talk about that all that
much we also have a path allocation
algorithm which is you can see some of
this work and the more recent infocom
we've been publishing some good research
on upward maxman fair throughput
optimization and some other things that
we've been looking at most of you
probably don't care about maximum fair
but when you're trying to schedule
really big data center pushes it can be
important so and of course the topology
manager that has to collect state now
this is something of a point of
contention when people talk about
centralization or even a modicum of
centralization because of the fact that
people think that the control loop is
going to be pretty flabby because it
takes a while to gather the state from
the network and have any sort of
accurate representation where you're
unable to check point it you may end up
either out of sync or you're going to
end up with an extremely loose and
flabby control loop I guess my answer to
that would be obviously these are all
concerns and these are things that we
have to look at but if you look at how
fast the TE control loop is right now
it's actually pretty easy to get better
than it we also have a controller
obviously the controller basically just
as I saying has a Quogue associated with
it and a tunneling app running off to
the side
mods separately one with the
encapsulation that we use for the
tunnels to just direct hop-by-hop flow
state and then the other being you know
complete is is and bgp these push things
down to agents that are on the switches
which then interface with a bunch of
hardware tables and obviously there's a
whole bunch of work if you're going to
write your own user agent for how you're
actually going to interface with
whatever Hardware you have there's an
additional layer of hierarchy on top of
this because obviously if you have te
then you have some coordinated mechanism
this is actually kind of a sticking
point with a lot of these architectures
right now in that how are you going to
distribute state between decentralized
te servers if you're not making a
complete decision on a single server I
will say it's quite difficult and if you
would like to talk about it later then
we should I yeah because I think that
I'm at a time if you have any questions
please step up to the mic hi gender
confusion do is do you share any state
between the I scale control plane and a
G scale control plan at all or is it
just done through standard it's just
like it just edged state so standard
protocol great thank you it would
and now it's time for coffee after the
coffee break we have the DNS track here
in this room hearing oh my god sorry the
peering track not in this room somewhere
else