[Music]
how's it going i hope everyone's doing
well
um my name is jbo
and today i want to talk to you about
mac os security features uh and how we
learn about them by bypassing them in
microsoft
we have to have one who in my slide
my name is jbo yo yo jbo on twitter
i'm a security researcher in microsoft
focusing on offensive security
i'm the microsoft defender for endpoint
uh research architect for cross platform
it's a huge huge uh line it basically
means that i'm responsible of paving the
way for
uh microsoft defender on everything that
does not run windows and that
specifically includes linux android mac
os and ios
we do some windows stuff here and there
but that's basically our our focus uh i
also try to come up with funny
vulnerability names and you'll see two
of them in this talk right here
i want to talk about mac os security in
general
mac os is really interesting in terms of
history and how it's it's intertwined
with posix and bsd and and some apple
stuff
but basically when you look at mac os
security you look at three different
classes if you will
one of them is like posix traditional
one the ones that you usually see in
linux let's say
there is a bsd layer which is very
interesting
macports for instance is is an important
one in bsd and it's not just found on on
mac os you can find that for instance on
new herd or whatnot
and there is an apple proprietary layer
and today we'll be focusing on the apple
proprietary layer although the other
ones are still very very interesting
apple proprietor when we talk about the
apple propriety
proprietary layer
we basically talk about apple entitled
binaries what are really entitled
binaries even
entitled binaries are
are
certain binaries uh that can do certain
things that other binaries cannot the
entitlements are basically a set of
capabilities that are signed as a part
of the digital signature
the digital signature on the binary
itself
uh and that's pretty interesting and
basically that means that that's kind of
like a security capability they're
interesting because they're just
interesting they're undocumented some of
them at least and if you reverse
engineer them they have tons of
assumptions and this is not my quote i
don't remember who said that but
basically it took years to secure linux
suite binaries and we still get some
interesting sweet binary vulnerabilities
even this year um but we got two really
and how much scrutiny did apple really
get on the entitled binaries and and the
answer is that
less than the sweet binary is probably
um so i'll talk about my first
vulnerability uh it's a sip bypass
called truthless
what is sip
sip is uh system integrity protection as
the name suggests it kind of protects
the integrity of the system uh even from
root uh also it's called ruthless for
for obvious reasons uh it's what it was
introduced in yosemite
it leverages the apple sandbox which i
won't be talking too much about today
on the entire platform again even from
root i see that and that's just my
personal interpretation uh as the
equivalent of sl linux but on mac
and the interesting thing about sip
obviously it has to protect itself
against root so you can't really turn it
off unless you're in recovery mode
internally sip is is is co is configured
at least by two nvram variables one of
them is called csr activeconfig which is
a bitmask of enabled protections and the
other one is csr data that they won't be
talking about at all uh so forget about
it uh you can't legitimately again
modify those two nvram variables without
booting it to recover recovery mode
otherwise sip is is useless right
and there is a tool called csr util it
controls zip
and in non-recovery mode it can only do
very basic things and here you can see
that i'm doing csr util status and it
says enabled just like get enforced on
linux
and if you try to disable it basically
it will uh like
under the hood it will try to change the
nv ram variables but on a live system
you won't be able to do that so you just
get like no
um so that's sip
um
the nvrm variable is as i said bitmask
it controls all the protections that you
see here and basically compromising any
of these is considered a c bypass
some of them like you can read the names
here i'll i just want to talk about some
interesting ones the first one
basically
allows you to load untrusted kernel
extensions so that's pretty good
the second one is bypassing file system
checks by sip and we'll be talking a lot
about that the third one for instance is
uh allowing task for pid which the is
the equivalent of open process but on on
mac
uh kernel debugger upper internal is
pretty interesting but i won't talk
about that too much unrestricted nvram
is also interesting for obvious reasons
and so on
so
tons of interesting things to do here if
you're able to bypass zip
if you didn't know anything about zip
but you did some
but you did some work on on mac os
the first thing that you'd notice is is
probably the fastest run
file system restrictions
the reason for that is because it it's
really noisy and very really powerful
and you'll discover that you can't
modify restricted files
um and a file is restricted if it falls
under one of these categories either it
has an extended attribute called com
apple rootless or if it's it's under
some uh directory mentioned in that
config file right here and it's not
white listed by two other files so
basically either it's configured in some
config to be uh protected or if it has
the extended attribute
and obviously you can't manually turn
off like any of these and you can't even
turn on
uh sound like that because if you could
then zip would protect you
and
you will be undeletable so if for
instance you're able to create a file
and um and basically make yourself see
protected no one will be able to put to
the delete you obviously very good from
for malware um
and um basically like you can always try
to look for these these things manually
if you want to ask yourself whether a
file is protected or not but apple made
it easy with uh the extension to the ls
command with capital o that's a capital
o right here and in here you can see an
example of me doing ls on slash user and
you can see that some some of them says
restricted these are basically c
protected files and you won't be able to
override them you won't be able to write
them and so on
so that's like a very strong security
feature and it really allows you to stop
malware in this uh in this screenshot
right here it's always interesting by
the way to look at the log because the
log can tell you a lot in this
screenshot right here i'm trying to copy
a plist file which is kind of like a
configuration file on mac uh two system
library launch demons that's a
persistence mechanism in mac and that
directory is protected c protected so
even though i'm running as root i won't
be able to do it it says operation not
permitted and if i look at the log it
will say localhost kernel sandbox if you
see the magic words together kernel and
sandbox that's basically sip
so that kind of brings an interesting
question
an interesting question because
apple needs to override these files once
in a while let's say you do an os
upgrade or something
so how do they do that so you have like
a very powerful wall and what apple did
is to puncture a little hole in that
wall so they can do their upgrades and
what not and this is exactly what we're
going to basically abuse here
um in in this talk
how does apple really handle those
upgrade situations what they did is to
have again
apple uh a set of apple entitlements uh
to completely bypass zip checks and all
of these entitlements begin with the
prefix com apple rootless so if you have
a binary that has com apple root list
whatever it will probably it will
probably skip some uh sip checks
uh there are two important ones for the
file system checks one of them is com
apple rootless install which basically
bypasses all the file system checks and
the other one is com apple rootless
install inheritable that's even more
powerful because not on it it means that
the of the child processes will
basically inherit that
rootless install capability basically
meaning that all of the child processes
of that process uh will be able to
bypass sip checks so that's basically
kind of the the attack surface if you
will the obvious attack surface
um that's an example of me showing you
uh in
an entitled uh process
uh or an entitled apple and title binary
in this case it's system shove
uh i don't think it's
i think it's no longer entitled to do
that but whatever and uh in here you can
see as part of the entitlements it has
com apple rootless install so it's able
to uh bypass the sip
checks for file system and if you were
able to let's say inject inject some
code there or make it do whatever then
you bypass zip great
um
so that's the obvious uh attack surface
for for sip bypasses and you know when i
started looking at seed bypasses i've
seen like really funny stuff like this
thing right here which is like a
tweetable exploit uh for this is from
and um in this case it was a c bypass
not like uh i call it winning by points
and not by by knockout but the idea is
that um i won't go over like the entire
details but you have this binary called
uh
uh fsc fsdk underscore cs that's
supposed to fix like a file system and
uh basically this thing will trash a c
protected file just rush it with data
that the attacker does not control but
just because just because the attacker
trashes the file it basically
invalidates some other protection
specifically the kernel ext
the kernel extensions that are
excluded from mac os so that's like a
tweetable exploit from 2016 and i wanted
to do something like that again as my
learning process into mac os
i started hunting for c bypasses
obviously looking for
sip and title binaries on my box and
look for operations that could be
exploited by an attacker
interestingly enough i used j's
entitlement entitlement database it's an
online thing that you can use if you're
unfamiliar with entitlements you just
click there and it will ask you let's
say
give me all of the com apple uh rootless
inheritable uh entitled binaries in
yosemite and it'll just give you a set
of processes of binaries it's pretty
cool to use
uh and after i found like a set of
interesting uh um
a set of interesting apple and title
binaries i actually used microsoft own
edr because we collect a lot of
telemetry for our customers to look for
interesting child processes because i
was looking at the inheritable thing
uh and i did see these things and as you
can see like well efw cache update is
not that interesting i started
understanding what it does not very
interesting but what about zsh
um
i found that zsh was a child process of
system install d and system installed is
a very interesting just like any other
process that ends with a d it's a daemon
it does something on behalf of the
system uh and in this case uh this
binary also has com apple rootless
install inheritable so very powerful all
of its child processes will by
definition by definition we'll be able
to bypass zip checks on the file system
that demon gets invoked when you install
is an apple signed package a pkg file so
uh pkg files are also interesting very
much but i won't talk too much about
them
but i did start playing a bit with
system install d and uh system installed
they will do various tasks like updating
caches moving fast to temporary pass and
and so on and interestingly if the pkg
file has a post install scripts and some
of them some of them do then it will
invoke the post install script
and
that kind of explains why zsh is a child
process it's basically like a shell
script that runs after the pkg was
installed in the temporary directory
so that's pretty interesting because
that means that zsh now has control over
over the file system without sip
restrictions um so what does zsh i mean
what can zsh do obviously just like bash
rc you have zs hrc uh
the zshrc files only run when when in
interactive mode obviously we're not but
i did find zsh and uh
like dot zsh and von your
home directory and etc zsh and and if
you read the zsh source code that's
always fun because they call like any
person that uses the zsh and the swine
or something and i really wanted to be
that swine so um so basically i i abused
just that
and that's my trivial very trivial
exploit i have to say uh almost
tweetable
you what you do is is this the following
thing you download an apple sign package
that legitimately invokes dsh because it
has a post-install script that invokes
zsh
and you plant an easy etc csh and that
does the following three liner if my
parent process is system installed then
do whatever seep free and basically you
trigger the installer and bam you've got
a vulnerability with a funny name as i
as i promised um in this in this
screenshot right here you can see that
i'm showing you that csr uh with csr
tool i'm showing you that the uh
uh the sip is enabled i uh show you the
first line of uh that particular file
that was protected and abused in 2016 by
the way
and you can see that it looks like an
xml i try to write echo to it from root
again it won't let me but then i run my
schruteless exploit and i show you that
basically i'm able to write whatever
content that i want to that file and
it's also it stays like a c protected
file so that's pretty insane because if
i'm a malware author i can create like
malware that way and no one will be able
to delete me like ever right and that's
pretty bad because we're a microsoft
defender for endpoint and we're trying
to delete files when when they're bad
so um that's my first exploit uh for
that i'm going to show you today the c
bypass
and there is a bonus round here i
discovered that uh when you run sudo s
specifically on mac os zsh uh saves
uh saves the home directory as is from
the admin it doesn't change to like
slash root like you're used to in linux
and that's kind of like an admin to root
eop if you will basically doing the same
thing with uh the home directory dot csh
and
saying sound like if um
if my uh effective user id is zero then
do whatever
um
it's this time it wasn't easy for me to
trigger a root csh uh but it's cool to
just lurk and wait to be rooted if that
that makes sense uh this thing is still
unfixed but i let apple and the zsh
community know uh at this point again it
doesn't look like a vulnerability per se
because it's not easy to trigger that
root csh but you can consider it to be
like a red teamer
tactic if you will
so um
an honorable shout out by the way after
we released uh schruteless and the blog
post and everything uh
we we saw that there was a similar
discovery i think a few months after
uh by his perception point uh they did
something uh very cool instead of uh
they also abused a system installed but
instead of um
instead of doing what we did which was
already patched by apple they abuse the
fact that
system installed it drops files to slash
temp
but then slash temp is a sim link on mac
os to private temp so by remounting
slash temp and winning a race you're
able basically able to make system d in
run whatever you want so that was a
pretty cool exploit again this is also
uh also patched now so don't worry
um my second um my second part of
my second part of the talk is a tcc
bypass that i call power there
and um
here we go
tcc is a transparency consent and
control
that's a mac os technology that was
first introduced in mojave and if if
someone asked me what tcc is i say that
it's the usc equivalent of mac os so
whatever wants to control whatever and
in here you can see microsoft teams want
to access your microphone or access your
camera or access your desktop or rss or
whatever so you'll get one of these like
nice little uh pop-ups and you can also
configure this thing in like the
security and privacy pane
on your mac
and
interestingly unlike usc if you if you
remember the vista days when uh usc came
out uh you had to like always always do
like okay okay okay let me do that let
me do this and so on and apple did
something differently usc is stateless
but
tcc is stateful so if i click ok here on
microsoft teams would like to access
your microphone
mac os will remember that and the next
time that teams wants to access my
microphone
it will just use my response so if i
deny that
it will stay denied and if i allow that
it will stay allowed unless i change
something in this pane right here that
you see on the right side
internally tcc uh is maintained by a
sqlite database or databases in plural
uh because there are two of them at
least two uh one of them is like a
global system-wide one uh saved in that
directory right here and the second one
is a per user one saved under the user's
home directory and then
like a big subdirectory right there
both of them are called tcc.db
um because of that you have two tccd
instances again a process that ends with
a d is a daemon
and tccd enforces the policy the tcc
policy
uh so you have two tccd instances one
for the user and one for the system
in terms of protection what protects
those databases files
the system tcc database is c protected
so in order to write to it you have to
have a c bypass or zip disabled in some
way but it's also tcc protected so tcc
it's kind of interesting tcc protects
its own databases from being overwritten
and also from being read actually so if
you don't have specific tcc capabilities
you will not be able to read the
database itself the user tcc database is
not c protected but it's still tcc
protected
and again you can't even read the
database without a capability called
full disk access which is managed by the
global sea protected tccd
so
so it's it's pretty well protected in
order to know whether you're
tcc protected or not you can just try to
list directories this is my home
directory and then the the director the
directory where the tccdb uh sits and
you can see here again i'm running even
as root i won't be able to even list
files under that directory uh
interestingly by the way if you try to
list the specific file under that
directory it will just show it to you
and that kind of gives you a hint on how
tcc really enforces things
uh in the second line right here in the
second
snippet right here you can see me again
looking at uh entitlements in this case
the entitlement belongs to tccd that's
again the demon that enforces tcc and
you can see that it's quite powerful it
has tons of entitlements but
specifically i want to talk about the
com apple private tcc allow one the one
with the string underneath it just keep
in your mind that tccd is able to uh it
has this com apple private tcc allow
um
a naive tcc bypass and i'm saying bypass
here
i'm saying bypass here like in quotes
because it's not really a bypass per se
if terminal itself let's say your
terminal has full desk access and a lot
of
mac os users do set full disk access to
terminal then basically you can modify
the user's tcc database without root
even
so that's pretty pretty cool to see
checking if terminal has full disk
access i mean without doing a lot of
work you can just conclude that from
either logs or by trying to do the list
listing of the files that i mentioned
earlier
um
and uh so you can basically conclude
that like automatically
uh if you're a defender what you
probably want to do is to watch out for
file rights
and file reads of the tcc database
anything that happens not from tccd is
is basically suspicious
uh so be aware of that
and interestingly it was abused by
dropbox originally again this is not a
bypass per se uh dropbox assumed that
there is going to be full disk access
and once you have full disk access you
can enable all of the users uh uh tcc uh
permissions so that's pretty cool to see
okay
and uh this this uh screenshot right
here shows you how the tcc database
looks like again it's a sqlite database
uh once of course you have full disk
access otherwise you're not supposed to
do that thing
and as you can see here there is a table
called access and it has a bunch of uh
uh basically entries i won't go
i won't go over all of the entries all
of the different columns here but i will
say that uh the first two ones are
interesting first two ones first one is
uh ktcc service whatever which kind of
indicates the kind of tcc capability
that you have and the second one is the
name of the app so
if your teams has microphone access
you'll see ktcc service microphone and
then
com.microsoft.teams for instance
and in terms of tcc capabilities tcc has
really fine-grained access this is not a
complete list by any means but
this is the name of the access versus
the description next to uh where it's
saved so for instance liverpool is like
location services so if your app wants
to access location it will have to have
ktcc service liverpool uh same thing
goes for calendar or reminder or whatnot
microphone camera are also obviously
interesting and note that the two last
entries are saved in the system tcc
database and one of them is the full
disk access
keep that in mind
if you remember from two slides ago by
the way tccd had um
had this com tcc apple uh
com com apple uh private tcc allow
entitlement with full disk access and
that kind of explains why tccd is able
to even access the tcc database
there is one more minor thing that i
won't talk too much about but basically
for some tcc services there is a blob
called cs rec that's being compared
in the table versus the calling app um i
won't talk about it too much but it
encodes like the code signing
requirements for the app and it wasn't
uh in my opinion at least it wasn't
created in order to mitigate against tcc
bypasses so basically you can just forge
your own if you have your malicious app
you can just create your own cs rack so
that's not like that's a tiny hurdle
really in a tcc uh bypass coding
and again
when we talk about uh about the attack
surface the obvious thing is
it is uh
apple entitled binaries and specifically
com apple private tcc allow is the name
of the uh the name of the entitlement uh
that apple has
private apple binaries made may have
entitlements that allow them to bypass
tcc checks we've seen that with tccd
and there are others of course
uh that's the obvious attack surface and
the obvious technique would be finding a
binary with com apple private tcc allow
tamper with it in some way to affect its
code flow including
injections extensions whatever and get a
fine-grained tcc access so if you
piggyback ride on on an apple uh on an
apple uh entitled binary that's allowed
to do tcc stuff you're able to do the
exact same thing without any pop-ups
um
apple takes tcc very seriously if you
guys
never looked at tcc and you want to
start this should be like a good uh
a good
motivation for you for those who are
driven by money i mean for even for the
like minor tcc bypass you're supposed to
get like 25 grand for a complete tcc
bypass you're supposed to get like 1
100 000 grand so 100 grand sorry so
pretty good money i guess if you're able
to do something like that
um and i want to talk a bit about
history of tcc bypasses this is not a
complete list by any chance but um
it kind of shows you the different
mindsets or attack classes if you will
for tcc bypasses so this was done in
2020 and it was done by uh
by basically mounting backups
there is a utility in mac os called time
machine and time machine basically is a
backup and restore kind of a system
and the backups apparently could be
mounted with apfs mount apfs is the uh
file system native file system on mac
and you could mount it with the no owner
flag the no owner flag specifically
makes makes it
makes it
available to read certain files and
write to certain files and because
backup contains the tcc database the
file could just be read without any
restrictions by anyone it's also again a
tweetable exploit
so the idea was pretty simple and even
that just be just reading the tcc
database file is enough to be called a
tcc bypass so that's like a trivial cool
uh tcc bypass from 2020.
uh another one from 2020 this is this
wins by knockout and not by points uh
this was pretty interesting when tccd
starts the user tccd not the system one
it needs to access the tcc database in
the home
under the user the relevant user how
does it how does it know where the tcc
database lives well it's easy it lives
under the home directory and then
whatever but what is the home directory
apparently what tccd did is to expand
the home environment variable so
basically if you poison the home
environment variable and reboot tccd
you're able to even plant your own
malicious tcc db file for instance my
home directory is now the temp directory
uh so that was basically the exploit
um
it's pretty easy to do uh so this was a
really really awesome exploit and uh
and again from 2020 and if you think
that only uh only like researchers do
those things malware authors also do
this thing this was found by jamf in
2021 it's a it's a malware that
basically piggyback rides on on existing
uh apps with known tcc capabilities like
zoom for instance
uh and because of a bug in the way that
apple attributes certain operations to
apps it it thought that uh uh the uh
malicious the the sorry the microphone
access for instance didn't come from the
app it's like the internal app right
here it came from zoom and basically
attribute that to zoom uh so uh that was
like an interesting uh bug that was uh
used by uh by malware uh just to bypass
tcc
um
so when i started looking i looked at
all of those things and asked myself
well
how did apple really fix those things
and apple speaks specifically to the
home directory issue
was basically changing uh from expanding
the home directory environment variable
to use getpwuid as they should
getpwuid
that's like a standard code even
there is there is a linux version for
that as well you get basically a
structure with all sorts of interesting
information including the home directory
of the user and that's basically what
they do
interestingly enough
in apple specifically apple works with
something called open directory which is
like the ldap implementation for mac os
and there then you can change like your
picture picture and and name and whatnot
and also your home directory and the way
to talk to uh this uh directory services
is by a tool called dscl directory
services
something and the idea is is to change a
property in your entry called nfs home
directory if you're able to change nfs
home directory entry you're basically
able to
basically
revive that bug from the grave and do
exactly the same idea planting your own
malicious tcc database
apparently you can't simply use dscl
create the command line that i just
showed you because apple foresaw this
and saw that nfs home directory is kind
of dangerous so it's now hardened and
you need a spec a specific tcc
capability again the chicken in the egg
problem you need a specific tcc
capability to actually change the nfs
home directory and uh that thing is
saved in the user's local tcc database
and this is the equivalent pop-up
interestingly the pop-up doesn't say
do you allow terminal to take over the
world it just says sound like do you
allow terminal to administer your
computer if you say yes then basically
uh you might get screwed because of that
thing
but still again this is not a tcc bypass
because it does require some user
interaction
um so after some research i discovered
two other commands that are very cool
one of them is ds import and the other
one's ds export and the idea is that you
can export your uh
directory services entry to a file edit
it and then use ds import and
interestingly ds import does not require
that tcc capability it wasn't hardened
so that was basically my exploit i i
couldn't find a way to run ds import uh
without running this route but still i
mean if you're able to do a tcc bypass
from root it's still tcc bypass
um
and then so i basically submitted the
bug to apple with a full exploit and
they were like yeah yeah we're fixing it
and then they fix it by accident and if
you if you want to be snarky it that's
not the right time because it's it's a
really hard bug to fix without breaking
anything
and um that was kind of a happy accident
and in monterrey i noticed that my
exploit doesn't work anymore and the
reason for that is because they removed
some
entitlement from ds import
so
basically when i talked to apple they
said that the issue was not fixed but
the question is how can i bypass their
happy accident right because now i can't
rely on this import anymore how can i
still uh uh
change my home directory and if you
remember my the theme of this talk
uh apple entitled binaries if you
remember that i basically went on hunt
again and went to try to find an apple
entitled binary and i did find one
config d
config d again is a demon because it
ends with a d
it's responsible for configuration
changes to be honest i have no idea what
configuration changes mean but it's a
pretty good like binary for me because
it's very attractive it has the com
apple private tcc allow with the same
tcc capability to change the home
directory
it has no hardened runtime basically a
hardened runtime is a way for apple to
prevent you from injecting code into it
and injection is not something very easy
on mac it's not like linux or or linux
linux or windows sorry
but in this case config d is extensible
by definition this also explains why why
you didn't have hardened runtime it
basically allows you to load a
configuration agent which is basically a
bundle which basically will do a daily
bloat die labs are basically like the
dll or so equivalent in mac so and
basically using config dash t in a
bundle path it will load that bundle it
will load my own daily and that was my
renewed exploit and this is the video
that i'm going to show you
uh you can see here that i'm opening the
privacy pane and you can see that
microsoft teams that's the app that i
wanted to exploit doesn't have camera or
microphone access i open my terminal
run this route because i still have to
i show you the os version for fun i
reset all of the tcc information in the
database there is a utility called tcc
util to do that
for all of my terminals just to show you
that i'm not cheating obviously
and now i'm going to run my exploit and
my exploit again called power deer uh is
uh is going to give in this case a
microphone and camera access to
microsoft teams silently with no uh no
user interaction it will inject a dire
lib to config d and do all the things
that we just discussed and here we go
important shout out
a very similar approach was discovered
by watching regular there is no way i
pronounced that correctly uh uh and uh
basically what he did is was injecting
uh to the app that controls directory
services it had the same kind of
capabilities and again reviving that
awesome home directory uh poisoning of
vulnerability from the grave uh
washington sabah uh presented other
interesting ways of tcc bypasses some of
them win by knockout some of them win by
points but they're really awesome and
you should definitely check them out if
you're interested
um bonus round i noticed when i started
reversing tccd the daemon that controls
tcc uh and i saw a lot of interesting
sql strings obviously because it has to
interact with a sql database and if you
can see here right there in the corner
it looks like it's injectable so i'm
still like i wasn't able to really
inject because of the code path uh that
the code flow that flows to this thing
but basically i'm still looking for
interesting sql injections on on not
just on tcc by the way there are other
mechanisms in mac os that use uh use sql
databases for instance gatekeeper right
so uh
basically the challenge would be doing a
sql injection on the os itself
um
and basically we're continuing uh we're
doing uh kind of like challenging every
mac os security mechanism one time one
at a time we already reported the
sandbox escape to apple but we can't
disclose it because we don't drop zero
days here
uh it's going to be called open sesame
because i decide on the vulnerability
names
um
we are looking for a gatekeeper bypass
there are two awesome ones in recent
memory and we have a lead on a third one
that we're going to basically implement
um i'm pretty sure we'll be able to find
one kernel bugs are pretty awesome i o
mfb seems to be a gold mine in in in
apple in the apple um landscape and
there are you know we're starting to
look
at the app specific ones i heard that
imessage is turing complete so we want
to do something similar perhaps
perhaps less sophisticated though
a summary mac os is a unique os with
proprietary security mechanisms that in
our opinion does not get enough scrutiny
from security researchers
and and especially ones that are
overpowered again apple can sign their
own stuff you won't be able to do the
same thing so they have a lot of power
in their hands and we want to make sure
that attackers don't abuse it by
disclosing responsibly uh stay tuned and
thank you so so much thank you
[Music]