[Music]
hello blue adail
how are you doing blew it let's get some
energy
very excited to be here very excited to
introduce my
research on aws this late august 2021
this is when i i researched aws
and the research is called breaking
information from an error message to aws
infrastructure now i can't skip the
classic who am i right this is the cloud
edition
my name is tsak bakima as you've heard
is my twitter account you can follow me
there for further research i'm a
security researcher at orca security a
little bit about my background
i was at idf for five years at the
intelligence unit then i had exactly two
days off and went straight to orca
security no cloud experience whatsoever
i run a little bit on the side i also
freestyle rap as you've heard
if you want to see a demonstration of
that that's off stage i can show it
afterwards so come get me now this
research i'm going to talk about
was taking place in the first two weeks
i have an orca really not a lot of cloud
experience that i had
the first thing we do need to talk about
though is why am i doing what am i doing
why am i researching the cloud and why
am i researching aws specifically what
is my purpose
so
two purposes one is my team purpose i'm
in the thought leadership team at oregon
security basically we want to generate
high quality research and advance the
cloud security in the world
and the second thing is my specific
uh interest or my purpose which is
gaining more cloud expertise again i had
no experience whatsoever in the cloud
maybe ran one or two aws commands in my
life
and recent cloud is a great way
to get to know the cloud but ywas
specifically so two reasons one it has
the largest market share a third of the
market is owned by aws so when you find
a vulnerability or a finding in aws it's
more relevant it's more interesting
and the second thing is and it's the
most important thing is a challenge
there were not a lot of attacks on aws
infrastructure
so this might be the public first
okay
one thing we do need to get out of the
way is this major buzzword called
cloud
what is the cloud so some of you may
have ran
a lot of commands on aws azure gcp
whatever and some of you may have only
heard the word cloud in articles
what does it mean let me introduce you
to the world of the problem say i want
to set up a server specifically
a database
okay
now what do i need to do i need to go to
the hardware store buy the hardware plug
it into the electricity pay my
electricity bill and everything
and then i need to install an operating
system i need to make sure i have
backups i need to make sure that i
install the latest software i don't have
any vulnerabilities but what happens if
my database server suddenly is on fire
right
it's a problem
i need to make sure it's always online i
need to make sure it always has backups
and i need to make sure it's secure
encrypted whatever i need
aws azure gcp whomever whatever vendor
does this for you and it's only it's not
only databases
it can be a file storage
it can be a web server a virtual machine
whatever you pay them they do it for you
you don't need to take care of anything
and just so you understand how scalable
this might be netflix their entire
infrastructure is on aws everything you
use every server you communicate is on
the cloud not no physical server that
they're taking care of
now aws we need to talk about because
this is the target of my research so
short introduction would be
this
aws is an acronym for amazon web
services it's the largest cloud provider
to this date and it has over 200
services just to name a few
and you choose which service you need to
use for your purposes right so ec2 is a
virtual machine service
lambda is a service where you can deploy
your own code s3 you can store files you
have database solutions such as dynamodb
and rds
and a lot of other services cloudwatch
for example can show you metrics
cloudformation can help you deploy
resources in your account we'll talk
about some of them later but just
understand whatever you use the cloud
for you choose the services you're going
to use now aside from services another
keyword in aws is regions basically
geographical regions each service if i
store files for example i want my file
storage to be close to my customers
right if i serve the east coast i'll
choose
a region near the east the east coast if
i serve israel i choose a region that's
near israel
uh basically each region divides into
availability zones that's not so
important but their data centers that's
all there is to it and because we're
going to talk about the vulnerability in
the cloud we need to understand a little
bit about cloud security so two key
concepts about cloud security one is
tenant isolation
and that's the important premise of the
cloud i'm a tenant me and my
organization if your organization uses
the cloud you are also a different
tenant and even though we share the same
resources for example we both have two
virtual machines on the same physical
machine
the cloud should promise that i can't
access your virtual machine you can't
access mine
same example
if i have for example s3 storage we said
it's a file storage if i store my files
on a hard drive and you store your files
on the same physical hard drive
still i shouldn't access your files and
you shouldn't access mine that's tenant
isolation different tenants
can't access each other and the second
thing is a model that aws relies on
which is the shared responsibility model
this means who's responsible for what
side of security
if we take ec2 which is a virtual
machine service as we said so everything
that goes operating system and up is me
if i install unpatched software if i
don't make sure the permissions are
correct my fault
but anything below that say the hardware
the networking
if there are hardware vulnerabilities
that's on aws size i can control it so
whatever i can control
my responsibility
whatever aws can control and i can't
their responsibility
most researchers done aws are focusing
on the upper side what can the customer
misconfigure
unknowingly and is somehow not secure
not a lot of people focus on this side
what can aws do wrong and this is what i
wanted to focus on
now
every good story
has a villain right and we need to get
to know our villain the villain is a
service called cloud formation so cloud
information is 10 years old actually
turned 10 like a week ago so happy
birthday to cloudformation and it's an
infrastructure as code service we'll see
what that means but two key concepts or
keywords in cloud formation are
templates and stacks it accepts a
template as an input and the output is a
stack
that's all we need to know about the
concept of confirmation now 10 years old
is pretty good for us because some of
the code might be deprecated
you can target the code it might be more
prone to vulnerabilities and also 10
years old is enough
or is old enough to manage his own
twitter account so at aws cloud former
you can follow cloudformation remember
it's evil it's an evil service so you
can twitter bullying dmm
do whatever you need to know there
so we talked about stacks and templates
stacks are the output template are the
input
what are stacks in cloud formation
just a collection of resources
everything in aws is a resource a
virtual machine a file storage whatever
everything is a resource
a stack is a collection of resources
managed there's a single unit if you
delete them you delete them all if you
duplicate them you duplicate them all
this is the way you do it this can also
be a part of a stack set and what are
templates remember that's the input
templates are just the recipe to how you
make a stack
the types of the resources their data
you can also have parameters rules
conditions for example if you have a
production environment in a development
environment you might want to deploy
different resources in each one
and the templates are either yaml or
json2 formats this one is a yaml
template it has two resources one is an
ec2 instance remember ec2 virtual
machine so this is a virtual machine
that one of the data that is mentioned
here is a shell script that initializes
a web server and the other resource is a
security group basically a firewall rule
and this firewall rule says i allow any
transportation tcp port 80. like an http
server should
now why should anyone research cloud
information specifically why is it so
interesting three reasons so first of
all it has plenty of features because
you input a template you can mention
every resource you want so there's a lot
of
play here
and it has a parser actually two one
json parser one yama parser for the
templates and they may contain sensitive
customer data we saw a template with
shell script earlier
it might contain passwords database
passwords whatever that is super
interesting and it's a high risk service
it does not only store files it does not
only operate virtual machines
it deploys the resources
to my account
so maybe i can give it a template and it
can deploy resources to your account
could be very very interesting but it's
nice to say the cloud formation is a
villain you know it was always bullying
me but that's not the case actually mean
confirmation we used to get along pretty
well
actually there was a time remember i
have only two weeks of experience at
this time with aws i didn't even really
know cloudformation so how did i get to
cloudformation
i had different research idea
not close the research idea was
bypassing logging in aws there are two
services that are responsible for
logging in aws one is cloud trail and
one is cloud watch
and i wanted to make
api calls in aws for example try to
download a file from you try to upload a
file to your storage but not show up in
the logs that was my purpose
what are cloud trailing cloud watch
cloud rail tracks user activity and api
usage and one thing we do need to
remember is that everything in aws and i
mean everything is an api call
if you
reboot your machine that's an api call
if you give it credentials that's an api
call if you create bucket a bucket
is a storage of files in s3 it's an api
call
if you change its permissions if you
update a table in your database whatever
it is it's an api call specifically
console login is an event but everything
else
and for our sake everything is an api
call
and when you create a cloudtrail
logging group you could say it's called
a trail
and you choose what events to log so in
this case i won't talk about the
different types too much management
events or events happening in my account
data events or events happening to my
data if i have a file storage and you
try to access it it's a data event if i
change something in my account it's a
management event
now how does the log look
and remember i'm trying to bypass it to
make api calls without getting logged
how does a log look it's simple it's
simply a json
three interesting points of data one is
who made a specific action
in this case cloudrail the service
itself made an action in my account
did it do
put the object in s3 meaning it uploaded
the file to my storage
and how did it do it like the parameters
the circumstances so
in the request parameters you can see
the bucket name where did it upload the
file to makes sense
how did i get from my research
of
you know bypassing the login mechanisms
to cloud formation
there was this feature introduced to me
by you avalon
my team leader and orca cto and he said
to me you know you're researching
cloudtrail and cloudwatch and all these
services cloudtrail we said responsible
for logging cloudwatch
shows logs and metrics
these kind of things
and he said you know there's this
feature aws published it's a new feature
in cloud watch
you have a lot of dashboards where you
can see metrics and there's a way to
kind of program your own custom widgets
might be interesting i said okay let's
click on the link let's get to the
samples
of this feature and i went to sample
widgets and literally clicked on the
first one called echo it's a basic echo
we're testing html
and
it led me to this page cloud formation
stacks quick create stack receives a
template url
aml file again confirmation accepts
templates
and if you press next next next you get
to this page again echoer you input echo
it gets echo echo echo seems like it's
working but something was a bit after me
and i was only again two weeks into aws
but something did feel a bit after me it
was this
there's this link template url it's an
https link to s3 it's not that weird
because if you browse to this link
you'll get the yaml template as you
should s3 is accessible by web
but usually when we're talking about s3
links in the api of aws you either give
a bucket name
in the api or you give an s3 link not
https as a scheme but s3 is the scheme
and when i say usually i mean usually
you get s3 links not https
now truth be told this page
that shows the actual feature that i set
out to research is a page i've never
seen in my entire life up to making this
presentation
because even though i set out to
research this feature the https link so
much bothered me that i said i have to
focus on this thing
and why are https so links so
interesting unlike s3 links this one
concept called ssrf
what are srfs it's an acronym server
side request forgery basically if the
server accepts a url and it doesn't
filter it
you can give the server url
and when it requests the resource from
the url
it might lead to localhost or it might
lead to the internal network or to an
attacker server
this is why https links are kind of
dangerous
that's pretty good but in the cloud it's
even more dangerous because you have a
thing called imds it's a server with a
static
ip169254 and so forth
which is used for vm configuration
so you can see the host name the public
ip address all this you have there so
you have interesting metadata about the
vm
but also you can give vm credentials
because of my vm for example maybe wants
to write to my storage in s3 so i can
give it credentials
to access my s3 bucket
again a bucket where you store files
so if you can access this and you can
gain credentials this can be super
interesting some of you may have also
heard about capital one
uh
an attacker added an srf there they
could have read the answer they accessed
the imds got credentials
then leaked a lot a lot of data
revolving credit cards
okay so accessing data is interesting if
i can access the imds would be very cool
but first i need to understand where
that template url is coming from so i
looked at the url
and i focused on it and i got the url
equals whatever i put
and this is the page right
so i said okay let's take this and put
in valid url just for just for a sake of
it let's try
and i got this error
template url must be a supported url so
it's not that easy
now
where does this error come from i turned
on my purpose proxy
and i got to this page
there's a request to cloud formation
service template summary template url
invalid url and you get an error
template url must be a supported url
when you use it normally you just get
json which kind of summarizes that
template makes sense cloudformation
service template summary
now remember everything is an api call
everything in aws is an api call even
this so what api call is this i just
googled cloudform agent service template
summary enter
i got to this page aws documentation get
template summary its cloudformation api
call returns information about a new or
existing template
and how do we know this this is the api
call i'm looking for
it has an argument called tempe url
which says it's the location of file
containing the template body located in
an amazon s3 bucket this is
documentation
so what i did right now i said okay i'm
trying to get the imds right i have
maybe an srf i don't know if i have an
srf i want to find an srf let's play
with that template url
we know we have this input the normal
input the cloud watch s3 amazon aws.com
to that yaml file that's the valid one
and when i put it as input obviously i
get the normal output i get that summary
of the json so this one works it
bypasses that url filter that we're
handling with
then i said okay let's try to change the
scheme instead of https try http
tried it
it worked i said okay i can play here
but i i said okay let's try setting
check
to see if i can really
influence the scheme let's try a scheme
called blabla this one should fail right
there's no such scheme called blah blah
it did work
so at this point i was like okay i don't
really understand what's happening i
think it's ignoring the scheme
completely
let's try to cut straight to the chase
go to the imds and see if it works
didn't work
template url must be a supported url
makes sense it's not an amazon s3 bucket
remember documentation it should be a
file in an amazon s3 bucket
so i'll say let's try a different port
the same cloud watch s3 amazon aws.com
with a different port 13337 shouldn't
work right this port is not open this is
not the https port
it did work
so it's ignoring the scheme it's
ignoring the port it's probably only
using the host name and the path i said
let's write the ad symbol because the ad
symbol you might know it from ssh you do
user at a certain domain that's how you
give a username or credentials to your
url so i said let's try s3 amazon
aws.com like a valid s3 bucket
at evaldomain.com see what happens
didn't work so it can really parse the
url it knows how to parse it
so at this point i said
okay i'm having a certain problem
i need to understand what it can do with
s3 buckets i created my own bucket
called blue test bucket and i
told it the template url is blue test
bucket slash existent it's an existing
file it's empty
and i got a different error template
format error unsupported structure
makes sense it is a supported url so i
don't get that error unsupported
structure basically meaning because it's
an empty file it's not a yaml template
it's not a yaml template does not
contain any resources cloud formation
can't do anything with it not
interesting
and then i tried
a non-existent file just for the sake of
it and i got this s3 error x is denied
that's kind of interesting because if
you take that same url and you browse to
it with your browser you also get
access denied inside of an s3 error
okay
now this point
i
said to myself you know what this starts
to be a little bit harder than i
imagined i tried to play with the inputs
a little bit more
didn't really need lead to nowhere but
frustration
so i said let's get back to my
original research
bypassing the logging mechanisms so i
went back to cloudtrail
i only concluded that blackbox is hard
nothing makes sense and i need to get
back to cloudframe
and i went to cloudtrail and it logs api
calls and i saw this api call
it's a get object to s3
to that blue test bucket slash existed
initiated by cloud formation makes sense
right i told the cloudformation access
this
and it was logged
seems like this is how it works
and then i search for the other log this
is existent remember i tried
non-existent and it gave me an error
i went to the logs and instead of one
log line
i found two log lines
one
makes sense it's called formation same
thing but non-existent
and the other one
was this
same get object non-existent blue test
bucket but an internal ip address and
the user agent was not cloud formation
the user it was apache http client slash
unavailable with the java version
i was like
what is happening here
how does http client know about my
non-existent uh
template that i led cloud formation to
doesn't really make sense so i play with
it more and try to understand the
behavior because again this shouldn't
happen only this log should occur but
both occur
so i understood it's a fallback
and apache http client is
a client written by apache in java
uh pretty basic
and the server-side logic that i
understood goes like this i go to
confirmation pass the url to my template
transformation validates the url and
after it validates it it goes to the s3
bucket
when it fails because it's a
non-existent file
then it goes to apache http client then
apache http client tries to access that
bucket
now if it works cool if it doesn't work
it spits out s3 error
access denied
now i've searched hp client online found
the cve said hooray i can execute code
on http client no this vulnerability
basically says to http client hey parse
this url you'll think you're going to
blue test bucket s3 amazon aws.com
a legit s3 bucket
but you'll actually go to
sockseverdomain.com sounds perfect let's
try if it works i tried it wasn't
working sad face
what else can htp clients do what is my
input
i only give it a url i tried the s
symbol right i tried a vulnerability
with the ad symbol doesn't work what
else the urls have
you know the scheme it
doesn't use it the port doesn't use it
we have url parameters
and aws has common parameters one of
them is xam's security token used to
pass credentials
to aws services to authenticate yourself
you need to use three parameters then
you can incendicate yourself
and i said let's try combining this
parameter inside
of the url url i passed to
cloudformation so i did it
this is the request the api call
blew a test bucket slash non-existent
remember because it only happens
on non-existent i get two logs not one
and i gave it x am z security token
equals a a invalid input now when i
browse to that blue test bucket with
that parameter myself i get xs denied no
aws access key was
presented when i use it in cloud
formation
i got that same thing
s3 error no aws access key was presented
there's some error parsing here that's
what i understood
now this was on the thursday and in
israel most of you know we don't work
friday and saturday me specifically i
might not look the part but i'm an
observant orthodox jew so basically from
friday night to saturday night i don't
write anything i don't type anything
nothing
shabbat shalom
so all i could think of through shabbat
was this error extracted how does it
happen how does it extract errors from
s3 what does http client do
and i was about to take my nap
after saturday lunch i get one hour nap
my beauty sleep and
i only could think of three things one
is sap client parses the error from s3
the other is url parameters do work it's
an actual http client
and this flow is only a fallback right
slash existence doesn't work slash
non-existent http client accesses it so
parsing
parameters fallback parsing parameters
fallback i was just about to go to sleep
and
it hit me
when you start napping but you then come
up with a vulnerability the problem was
again it's about i can't write anything
i can't type anything
i can't go to sleep because i'll forget
it
so i just stayed awake lost sleep stared
at the ceiling and said i need to
remember this vulnerability and i
couldn't say anything to my family you
know remember this about http client
they'll be like who what are you talking
about who's cloud formation who are you
playing with
okay
so what was the idea that there was a
race a race condition
how does the race apply here is cloud
formation normal flow with a tip with
the url right it validates the url goes
to the s3 bucket and fails
now we should access apache
apart you should access the bucket but
say right now
i upload the template to s3 before about
http client access it and then about
http indexes in the bucket
and instead of filing a non-existent
file there is an existing file there and
what does this template or what format
will it be
it'll be the format of an s3 error xs
deny
now two things can happen
either s3
passing to http client and http client
will say okay this is not a cloud
formation template it's not a yaml or
json you're fooling me
unsupported structure remember
or it will say
my error and i tried my own error
document called this is literally my
error and if it spits it out
then this race works right there's
something
to look for here
there's more game
i said let's implement it two things one
is burp intruder every half a second or
so
goes to blue test bucket non-existence
through that api get template summary
and the other thing is the shell script
what does it do instead of uploading an
object because this takes time and we
want to win the race
so i uploaded the object called
non-existent
even though it is existing now and i set
the permissions i set it private
then half a second then public private
public this is the iteration
and i did it
i tried
this is the
shell script saying private public when
it iterates this is the burb
intruder and this is how it went
private public iterates the api
keeps iterating and i should have two
responses one is unsupported structure
when it's public http client reads it
says this is an xml this is not a ammo
or json
on support structure
the other thing is when it is private
and http client reads it what i should
get is a nexus deny because it's private
http client can't read it these are the
two errors i should receive
if the race doesn't work
but if it does work
and it did work
s3 error this is literally
my error
this point
i was like wow this is literally working
i came up with something i lost sleep
over it but it was worth it or was it
i mean
i only give it an input and i can
control the output a little bit but what
does http kind of parse right it passes
the s3 response looking like this
and what format is that can someone tell
me
it's an xml
and why are xml parsers so interesting
so there's this thing called xxc some of
you may know it
now a normal xml document has a root
element as a children element and can
have attributes doesn't matter we can
have text
when this is rendered it's just aaa
right the text inside of it
now there's a thing called xml entities
if for example i want to use lower than
symbol or greater than symbol they mean
things in xml so i need to encode them
how do i encode them for example
ampersand lt semicolon lt lower then i
get the lower than symbol a lower than b
good
now i can define my own xml entities for
example
if i wanted to use my name in an article
or whatever i can define the entity in
me called pagima if i want to be a
rapper i can define this entity called
mc
containing obviously the most renowned
world in the rep
in the rap culture which is chika chika
and then i can render this to be hi my
name is chikachika
nice
why is this so interesting for a
vulnerability there's this thing called
external entities you can borrow a file
for defining your own
externality so this is why it's called
xml external entity xxe in this case
nothing to see here not malicious it's
an entity i added the word system and
instead of this being a string it's a
url it goes to that url fetches the
string
puts it
in my
xml document
now
we know the http client does parse xml
we know that some xml parsers are
vulnerable to x60 it's not always you
can configure it
i wanted to give it a shot and i gave it
a shot and i ran verb intruder right web
intruder with my script
and this is what i got
s3 error roots etc you can understand
you can get the hang of it and this is
censored because there were a lot of
users here
and when we searched them on linkedin
and google they were they were aws
employees so uh we had to censor it
at this point i was filled with joy i
was jumping in my place and i was like
this is amazing but one thing i did not
say i need to say
i'm not racist
i mean i love races but they're not that
practical right 25 to 30 requests for
one leak racist race conditions are not
that practical
so i said
what can i do
to maybe create
one shot one kill one request
read a file not 28 requests not 30
requests not whatever one request one
file and long story short you can do it
it's a feature called bucket policies in
s3 you can create and configure bucket
policies to grant permissions to your
amazon s3 resources
put this
policy in your bucket basically denying
all access for from people not having
the user the words http client in their
user agent or rather if we go the
negative way then only people with http
client in their user agent can access my
bucket
and then what happens here is same flow
but instead of arrays i start with
contacting the s3 bucket i give it my
file called non-existent looking like an
s3 error payload with an xxc and i give
it a policy the policy sort of puts a
lock on the bucket ix is confirmation
with url it accesses the bucket fails
the bucket is locked right
then it accesses apache http client
which
coincidentally has the key unknowingly
right because it doesn't know about this
concept but his user agent contains http
client the lock is removed everyone's
happy and in action
it looks something like this i create a
bucket
i upload the policy right to it one
request the api and boom
now this is
all good
but what can we really do so we know we
can read files this is what we did right
now
when you try to read a directory
i tried i think i did it accidentally
uk directory listing so this is good
thanks to apache exercises 2 which is
the xml parser they're using in java
so we have directory listing we have
file read and we have an srf why
remember this is url right now it's url
to a file
but it can also be an http or https url
and why is that interesting in the cloud
again
imds we talked about it remember capital
one
now one thing i did not
tell you about imds there's this thing
called ids v2
aws saw the capital one incident and
they said okay you know what maybe
something here is
not very good
one ssrf can the credentials can do all
that things
how could prevent prevent it they
created v2
most of the serifs are just a get
request one request you get a response
now they said imds you can't just pull
off a get request you need to make a put
request with a certain header then get
the response then
only then you need to use that token and
do a get request basically 99.9 of srs
are unusable
and to enable this or rather it's always
enabled to disable ids v1 because
they're both enabled
you need to just click this right
they say that you want disabled
obviously aws will do it because they
have an article called that use idsd2
and they also
strongly recommend adopting v2 and
restricting access to v2 only for added
security makes sense i said
i can try this let's see what happens
nothing to lose this shouldn't work
shouldn't return any response because
i'm this v2 should be enabled
but
it does return a response
so okay uh aws recommends ibs v2 they
are using it but they're also using
idsv1 basically
doesn't do anything
happy hanukkah
now this is only data about the ac2
instance that we were using
um we also found credentials identifying
that instance you can enjoy the word
code success because we had to censor it
and we took these credentials used them
to access mys3 bucket to see in the logs
who accessed my s3 bucket i did it
and it was aws service
invoked by aws internal
pretty good
now this is not cloud formation but
still
in aws service it was kind of
kind of
weird weird to us we saw this and we're
really excited and wanted to explore
further
but
we stopped here because we need to have
responsible disclosure we need close to
aws and props to them because in 25
hours they deployed the first patch 25
hours since we sent our email
and it was fully patched in all of the
regions in six days so props to aws
and if we want to talk about maybe
further elevation what we could have
done with this so again i want to
emphasize these were not cloud
formations credentials they were
identifying a machine as a part of the
service of
cloudformation
and we didn't explore much further what
we did find were internal configuration
files evidence for internal services
internal credentials
basically
this and superglue which is the research
done by yanir tsurimi from my team at
orca which is a service takeover highly
recommend reading about that uh we do
believe that an escalation of this to an
rc if we would have continued
could have led or rather would have led
to severe cross-tenant violation
okay
we also validate the fix i won't get
much to it we don't have much time but
you can find in our technical blog it's
not tomorrow sorry it'll be probably
next week
and some takeaways i'd say so we have
three takeaways maybe a bonus one one is
black boxes hard
i think you concluded that a lot of
speculating you don't know what
happening what's happening behind the
scenes the other is logical
vulnerabilities
are a thing right even though you don't
have any source code
it's only you versus an api you can
still find logical vulnerabilities which
is pretty cool
and no platform is infallible but i
would say the cloud is more secure
nowhere in the software world for
example look at the block for j
vulnerability you can never close it
within six days in every instance here
one deploy
one patch six days everything is closed
everything's good now we published this
on twitter we had fighter jets in our
logo
breaking formation right like a
structure
and
twitter sensors that's us basically
this is what we got
for the for the first week of the first
few days twitter doesn't like fighter
jets that's the next takeaway
now
i promise i talk about research avenues
in the cloud so
two things i'd say one is services trust
one another cloud formation didn't
expect s3 to give it an xml external
entity inside of the document write a
malicious xml document doesn't make
sense so if you have communication
between two services in the cloud
generally if you can trick one of them
this is probably more prone to
vulnerabilities second thing is fallback
mechanisms are
a nice avenue again http client was only
a fallback happening when it's not
existent so i would say
you can look at these things
and
more researchers in the cloud would be
much appreciated because i think more
manpower generally researching the cloud
we can find even more exciting things
and good things are coming soon real
real nice vulnerabilities in other
platforms even i would say
you can look forward to them this is my
twitter account at saga follow me for
more information about the next
vulnerabilities coming out was a
pleasure to be here thank you so much
[Music]
you