okay okay well thanks thanks for the
opportunity to speak so I'm gonna post
august the University of Luxembourg and
I'm going to talk to you about an
interesting well what I would expect to
be an interesting crypto primitive for
an audience like this which is a
password authenticated key exchange and
more specifically the modeling of this
primitive in the crypt a world tour in
the provable security world so it's
basically a two-part talk where I start
by explaining what password
authenticated key exchanges and maybe
giving you I i've been asked to give a
maybe a small definitely not exhaustive
list of some of the protocols that
exists and then I'll talk to you about
security model definitions and
specifically some little differences
between models that bother me and I'll
tell you why they bother me and how I've
tried to maybe not correct them because
that's a bit that's that's a bit 22
would be a bit too too exaggerated but
I'm trying to understand them and I'm
trying to interpret them or over or make
adjustments to to to help out so it's
the Alice and Bob setting of the crypto
world of course where you have Alice and
Bob who are trying to run some
cryptographic service over a network and
to do so they need to share some session
key for that only they don't know what
the quality of that networkers in the
sense that there might be some attacker
in the middle so the best way to do that
is to run a key exchange algorithm that
has authentication attached to or
incorporated into it and password
authenticated key exchange uses as a
trusted set up passwords so Alice and
Bob each hold the password and the basic
basic correctness requirement or
function basic correctness requirement
of this primitive is that if the two
entities are running this protocol then
they're going to end up with the same
session key if and only if they had the
same password now this can be a little
bit modified one user can have a hash of
the password on the other one can hold
the actual password but those are small
differences that don't change the
functionality very much
something I didn't write on the slide is
the session key they obtained as high
entropy whereas the password of courses
is low entropy so it's a way to kind of
bootstrap high entropy security from
from the low entropy secret which is
quite unique in the crypt of course as
you all know this is a fundamentally
different from usual key exchange
protocols which rely on public
infrastructure or shared secret keys
that are a yes keys or things like that
passwords being well entropy they can be
brute forced so you can have a kind of a
kind of a a secret key that is the
password and to have a public key that
corresponds to that passwords just not
going to work of course the brute
forcing of pastors as possible only
assuming that they can be verified so
it's the verification of guesses that's
crucial to pay attention to in these
protocols and there are two types of we
usually classified the attacks on takes
between offline dictionary attacks first
where what happens is you have all this
data flying around on the network
between honest users so these are these
arrows represent either protocol runs of
the protocol itself or they can
represent you
session keys that are used in higher
level applications all this data
ends in one way or another on the
password or input to the protocol of
course an offline attack the adversary
who is the network gets to see all of
that and tries to correlate the
information that it sees with pass from
guesses of its own and this is only
useful for him if he can do this in with
efficiently computable functions and
some some dictionary attacks are
essentially eavesdroppers that are
trying to correlate pass from data with
with what is what's what's flying around
on the net
an example of a bad pic protocol that
would do this as something like this
where you just you want to authenticate
a diffie-hellman key exchange by just
buying the password to the
diffie-hellman key exchange itself using
a hash this is obviously a vector for an
offline dictionary attack on the
password
unpaid protocols when they're trying to
prove things we want to eliminate
offline attacks completely and we can do
this it's possible to do this I say it's
possible to prove it at least because
then it depends on what you consider
proven depending on what what kind of
idealization you make an approval
security frameworks also few words about
that later an online dictionary attacks
you have something a little bit
different you have an honest user which
is expecting to talk to somebody to
somebody else that's honest and engages
in a protocol run but is actually
talking to a malicious adversary who is
trying to infer information on the
password like that that's an online
attack the online attack me there's
interaction basically and testing is
done directly through this interaction
and the the the prototype of such an
attack is a simple log-in what's what's
particular about online dictionary
attacks that in the paid service when
you're trying to model it it's something
that we can avoid something that's
inherent to the service and the crypto
can't do anything about at least not at
this level so we had to factor that
somehow into the security model what we
can do is eliminate them but we can try
to do is make sure
that login attempts are the only
possible ways of attacking the system so
here's a slight a DUI last night which
which which kind of recaps a few some
protocols that exists out there
basically paying research started as
early as 1992 with encrypted key
exchange which you may have heard of
that was invented by Bulova and merit
and it basically entails a symmetric
encryption of addition Helmand key
exchange with the symmetric key itself
being the the encryption key so it has
been analyzed in what's called the ideal
site for model crypto but it's very
difficult to implement to avoid offline
dictionary tax it's tricky to implement
another example is speak with you may
have also heard of these two are kind of
the most known because they're also the
ones that have caused the most trouble
if from a patent point of view
I've heard I've heard that people tried
to deploy peaks but it's hard to do so
because they keep getting they keep
getting patent roadblocks and it seems
to be essentially due to these 20 lot of
protocols are kind of variations on
these two especially on one example of
this is the pack and PPK protocols that
came out and 2000 pack provides explicit
mutual authentication PPK prize implicit
authentication so they're different
security properties you can look at
there is a protocol from 2001 which was
kind of an important one at least from
the theory community will from castro
skin you know where the idea here is
they were able to prove secure their
protocol and the specific the sports
specific about this protocol is that it
doesn't require any random oracles are
ideal ciphers to get approved to go
through so it's a standard model
protocol but it comes with a different
caveat that that's I don't want to get
into right now it's also much less it's
also less practical a lot of protocol
spun off of this last one
in the sense that there are secure
without idealized assumptions are still
there security using standard number
theoretical assumptions but they also
cost more to implement I mean there they
they they have a lot more than a lot
more group multiplication and
exponentiation these than the ones that
rely on random oracles so they tend to
be much less practical theoretically
efficient but they're much less
practical and I don't think they've been
implemented so much and there are other
there so there's the JPEG protocol by
how and Ryan from 2008 which is secure
in the random oracle model but is a
structure the structure is sufficiently
different from the previous protocols
that this one isn't bothered by
Pattinson I think it seems somodevilla
for instance use this in some of their
own and some of their features I don't
think they use it anymore I can't recall
why there's also a protocol by a
dragonfly by drunk by Dan Harkins from
2008 which kind of looks like the speak
protocol from jablon but is sufficiently
different that maybe it it it it's not
bothered by patents and there's a whole
bunch of other protocols that theory
people have have come up with with over
time so it's not like there isn't a lack
of protocols but maybe we're out so good
at communicating that and I'll talk a
little bit about security models and the
problems that I kind of have with them
so first there are many models in the
literature starting with the blog a
rogue wave and flashing LED model which
I'll just called BPR that was a
so-called in distinguishing bility based
model and there's a model by Boyko
McKenzie and Patel which is one of the
simulation based models Kennedy and is
listed for other authors don't recall
came up with a model for pay cuts
universally composable and yet another
one goal duration
Lyndell came up with a model just so
that they could have a framework to show
that take as possible under standard
complexity theoretic assumptions so that
that's already a lot of models so it's
hard to describe it's hard to see which
one is the good one if there is a good
one which is already kind of something
that bothered me but it gets a little
bit worse than that so within within
though the pool models that exists the
most successful ones have been the blog
points about rogue away one which all
described as soon as an important role
play at al from 2005 so we're going to
focus on these and already in this kind
of some class of models their little
technical differences between models
that make it kind of difficult to assess
security somehow so it's it's I find it
difficult as someone who looks at this
alot I can't imagine what it's like for
someone who's a practitioner who wants
to get some assurance that our protocol
is is correct or is secure so I'll get
into the descriptive description of the
BPR model and how it works but we start
with as a fixed collection of users
which is usually do
separated between a bunch of clients and
servers that's not very strict and our
adversaries in polynomial time adversary
which just represents the network and
it's the one that communicates with
these users now before your for your
security game begins each client is
given as a signed a password for
simplicity is like that uniformly at
random from my password from a password
set any server is assigned a vector of
passwords from all of the clients so
these things can change also from from
paper paper more specifically the the
attackers and going to talk to users
it's going to talk to user instances and
you can think of a user instance as you
want to run of the protocol being
attempted by that user
so we just indexed these instances with
them with integers
how an instance functions as it gets
instructions from the adversary and
reacts to those it reacts according to
protocol specification eventually it
might compute some kind of my computer
session key or it might reject messages
but if it computes a session key and
then it thinks it should it should it
thinks it shares the ski with what it
believes to be at parker and the way the
adversary communicates and model of
these instances vaya queries various
queries so for instance use the send
enquiry which delivers messages of the
adversaries choice to these instances
and see what happens if a response is
generated the adversary gets it
the execute query just runs the protocol
honestly between two instances and gives
the adversary access to a whole pool of
honest protocol runs to eavesdrop on and
the reveal prairie basically what we do
is we don't know which one calling the
algorithms are our session kids are
going to be run and are there is also a
pessimistic we assume that the adversary
can just obtain any session Kia wants by
looking at serving the network the idea
being that if a session has disclosed
that shouldn't damage the security of
other protocols and we have the special
test query which is used only to measure
the adversary success and a model like
this so the test Cory works is it gets
in it it it it once it's invoked by the
adversary you flip a bit and what you
get with the anderson gets in return is
either a random key if this bit was no
or the actual session key that was
computed if the bit is set to 1 and the
adversaries goal in the whole game the
way we measure of the adversary security
is to check for us whether it can still
check can output correct guess on this
bit her she wins the game if the bits
are equal and it loses otherwise
so what we want to hear so we're trying
to measure the Sandman what we call the
Symantec Security of the session key
advantage in winning is typically what
is typically this for ordinary
authenticated key exchange the advantage
is defined as being twice the
probability that it wins 2-1 and when
you're looking at high entropy high
entropy based protocols we require this
to be negligible we can we can do that
because the because of the the other
long-term key material is its high
entropy but for patrons a bit
differently can't do that because we
have to factor in the fact that there
are online dictionary attacks that are
possible and these will succeed
depending on the size the password space
surrendering those negligible as an
option anymore so if the change your
requirement for a little bit the
requirement on the bound we want now is
this we want to make sure that the
advantage of smaller than a constant
times the number of sand quarry is
divided by the size of the passwords
base plus some negligible chance so here
she is just some constant it represents
into an early should represent the
number of passwords that can be ruled
out but in one login attempt but so
ideally would want this to be one the
number of sankara's basically measures
the number of interactions with intense
with instances and you don't use the
bathroom space just taking longer than I
thought so the definition is only
meaningful after we've had a restriction
however because we don't want to be
testing aqui that's already been
revealed to the adversary so where we
need to what we need to add as a
restriction has that the user instance
can be tested if its partner or if
itself has been has already been
revealed and that's where a lot of
problems begin at least for me so maybe
I'll skip skip a few things here to get
to the point the point is that we don't
really know what a partner is anyway
this is the thing that changes from
paper to paper intuitively instances and
want to be part of her
heard if they had a correct exchange but
we don't know how to form we can't seem
to formalize this very well or
consistently across papers assessing
secure least from my point of view it
seems to make assessing security
difficult I don't see how you would how
you can trust the security in one model
of a protocol that securing one model
but that doesn't carry over to another
mall so what I guess one take away from
the stock is that there are a lot of
technical variables that that are used
to keep track of what instances key
moments in instances life during the
during the execution would be one that's
willing to use a session key when it
stops 12 instances are partnered and
these are things that change all the
time so it in the paper what I tried to
do is come up with a consistent way to
to put all these to put all these
together which kind of sounds like I've
added so I'm gonna skip all this because
these are details that are not going to
take too far but it kinda sounds like
I'm just proposed another model but I
don't see it that way I just see it as
an adjustment to the ones that kind of
exist and I couldn't see myself
complaining about certain things without
trying to suggest something not to
replace but at least to try to explain
the others
one thing that I found particularly
annoying as in the partnering definition
there are two different kinds of
philosophies some of them are going to
have a partnering definition of this
formula list of technical conditions and
on two instances and these instances are
unique in satisfying these conditions or
sometimes this condition has dropped and
I found that this causes a bug at least
in it causes a bug in certain models
definitional II and I wanted to try to
fix this bug so that
so at least it made more sense to me and
maybe it'll make more sense to other
people as well
this unique Mustang has also bugged me
and another way so in the paper I show
that if I ignore it I keep in the
partnering definition and it causes
trouble definition it causes a bug in in
in in one of the models which bothers me
but ignoring it completely is ill
advised as well so I'm going to I won't
go it would not go over the bug because
it's again it's technical and I'm
running out of time but ok so the thing
so now I'll talk about what happens if
you try to eliminate uniqueness
completely from the definition so you
need to some of the partners something
you would require an authenticated key
exchange protocols and natural
requirement I want if two instances are
partnered they should be they should be
uniquely partner there shouldn't be a
third one hanging around but this
requirement on land off as vanished from
authenticated key exchange papers not
just past four runs and that that's a
little strange because one of the first
the very first paper on authenticated
key exchange have this as a property
that was proven so I found a weird one
reason I guess for this is that some
people it seems to be assumed that maybe
session key security implies uniqueness
of partners but by reason of this for
multiple partners would imply violating
the partnering so I have to put
partnering because if you have
uniqueness or not then partner is
formally invalidated this would imply a
legal way to distinguish session keys
from random and therefore would be
captured by the definition but first can
get the store maybe somebody has been I
could not any straightforward way and
secondly even if it did or password
based key exchange this wouldn't even
help us because the security bound thats
optimal intakes isn't even enough
double bound so we can guarantee unique
partners with negligible problem with
overwhelming probability even if we just
rely on session he Securi now it's in
the literature the pics that you find a
security proves don't suffer from this
because of the way the partners are
partnering function is defined it takes
as it takes it's a function of the
randomness of both partners so there's
always gonna be the randomness of the
partner included in the way the
partnering functions computed in the
paper
protocol which is kind of convoluted but
that shows that you can create a pic
kind of cake that allows multiple
partners with a non negligible
probability but at the same time has a
security proof in a model where you
don't pay attention to this uniqueness
stuff so so I really think that
uniqueness of partners among other
things ought to be an explicitly proven
property even if it's easy to do it's
very it's it's it's almost the first
thing you prove when you're going
through the pics security proof I find
it would make a more complete and a
clear model and that it wouldn't be
making more sense
mathematically because if you have i
mean I say make more sense
mathematically because the definitions
if they have bugs on them then it's kind
of I find it pointless to try to do
something mathematically with
definitions that are bugs in them if
you're not precise at it it's just not
as not real mathematics somehow so if we
want to do this in a provably secure way
we need to make it as mathematically
credible as possible so i think i think
im young done so I'll just stop there
and I'm happy to take questions