I'm Jeffrey Goldberg from a job it's
you'll also see listed here Julie how
and Jesse are waiting to actually
sitting right there though they actually
haven't really had a chance to actually
see what I'm going to say and I should
point out that I security team really
like arguing with each other so in a
good way but it seems to have some very
much part of the process and so do I am
I would not be surprised if they
disagree with lots of stuff here
ok so who we are a job it truly make no
that's not right
ok we make a password manager one
password and internal recently we're
said we actually we until recently was
we do not host your data in any way
whatsoever we have absolutely zero
knowledge of what people do with one
password and we like this design
but there's also a need to be able to
get convenient to useful sharing data
among members of teams and so for quite
a while now we've been working on I'm
one Password four teams the beta was
introduced last month and so that
changes a lot of the stuff that we've
had to do while we still try to keep
this principle of we just don't want to
know anything so so my job title is
chief defender Against the Dark Arts
which was something that was decided on
after they decide after we decided that
what I was called internally which was
wearing one in chief was a little too
negative so so curious things that we
can worry about customers lose access to
their data data is the latest tampered
with and secrets and private information
is revealed to unauthorized entities and
of course by unauthorized we not
authorized by the customer we do not
have the power to authorize you should
not have the power to authorize who
data's release too so we work to deny
ourselves any power we shouldn't have so
we can treat better if we keep hard if
if all data is encrypted we do not have
the keys to decrypt that data and we
aren't in a position to acquire those
keys and that third point is what I'm
going to be focusing on now
so roughly speaking there are two ways
that we could acquire keys when somebody
just doesn't normal password login to
the site
they're sending their password and so
any fighter service temporarily acquires
a using secret that way they had shit
but they are in a position to directly
acquiring is a secret another way to
acquire a using secret is to have
something like a password hash they can
be used for making guesses against that
can be used for tracking so we want to
avoid not only never seeing the secret
secret directly we do not want to see a
hash that can be used so this is just
another way of saying that if Y is a
hash of P then even though you can't
even though the hash function may be
great
cryptographically her shaped all of the
things that you expect from a hash
function it does not stop you from using
why as a way to test whether you have
guessed the right P and if he is low
entropy then this can actually be useful
thing everyone who does after tracking
mostess
ok so now I'm going to just talk about
the things that we would want in an
authentication protocol and because
until now we've never done
authentication everything was just local
creeks encryption there was no
interaction with our services services
we actually started having to worry
about indication so the first thing you
want is that the client proves its
identity to the safe that's what
everyone does
we also would like this server to prove
its identity to the client this is
typically but you rely on TLS for but we
would also like to have that we don't
want to leak any secrets to an
eavesdropper we don't want anything that
can be replayed we don't want to reveal
any secrets to the server and we like to
negotiate a key that can be used to
encrypt the session and finally this
thing that I keep I'm getting around to
is we don't want this server to obtain
information that could be used for
tracking so we're trying to do we're
we're trying to make it so that if
somebody get our hashes they can't do
anything with it
password login that's the wrong the
wrong comment only one ignore ignore the
bad numbers for their vanilla password
login only does my client whose identity
to the server
that was supposed to be a different
flight a password authenticated key
exchange protocol does all of those
things that we were looking for
except for the last one it does provide
some it does have something stored on
the server that can be used for lunch
get crackin attack and that's where that
number forest run
multi-factor typical you know I mean
there of course different instances of
these things but that typical way of
doing multi-factor authentication so
you've got a password login and then
you're using something like TOTP for
something else it reinforces it beefs up
the number one the client proving itself
to the server because it's proving
itself in multiple ways and typically
the second factor is a one-time password
so it helps resist replace ok now if you
can't see that their sign on that Gates
has noticed keep gate closed and locked
now as exceed the game actually isn't
locked so we've got a real problem here
and you know so we need to have some
kind of authentication system to secure
this so and let's say a combination like
to the game
and the combination is something you
know and we can improve that by adding
to lock that has a key with something
you have and if we really want to go to
really the top notch best security for
this system possible we can added yet
another factor is something you are we
could have a fingerprint scanner that ok
that was my rant about multi-factor
authentication point is that it is not
addressing the problem we want to solve
it may be addressing some useful
problems in some circumstances but
multi-factor authentication does not
solve does not protect a customer
against us over breach at all and so
it's a lot of extra work we heard
earlier today about the burden she put
on users by adding yet more work for
them to do so
about some of the things to consider
when different security problem anyway
john we'll be talking about that later
today
it's generated by the station and stored
locally by the clock using is not
expected to to know this day and so so
this is a high ankle
combining things like and the email
address and we get by without that and
then we run this week we're about to end
but you know we had the talk yesterday
about the pain of these this to happen
while you're doing all of this file
inside and so it is easy to implement in
awhile so so fortunately the path of
help you competition haven't thought
they did stuff that isn't that except
for make while but all of that about
memory hardness are really kind of
killing that it's hard to get into
trying anything we go
together he get and then we export those
things together that lending you the
mastic pass where he or five people to
call if you know the actual people call
the protocol don't worry about it but
that's the key
used that line in secret used for
authentication we also use this method
were just different fault and it uses a
different in those hands so to dip in
salsa complete even in the worst case we
wouldn't want anything to be use to
actually
gonna say ok we're done we saw this is
actually the hard stuff so that may
actually all that hard
typical problem and we actually seen in
the beta period how these things are
working out and I'm some kind of a death
would allow the county to be stolen
any word has to be but it's much easier
to reach a person's machine and snow
back to factory and neither is the
combination
so how so
and I have to actually