and that's a very brief opening talk and
often this
the subject now I'm done with what I
wanted to talk about that
20 slides also I still cannot do the
things slightly differently I do hope
wherever the organizational hidden going
forward as it turns out on the only
person to get along with this my friends
are now I did not write I've never seen
them write about
change
getting pictures
I think this may be a subtle dig at my
age
allegedly an interesting point where I
read recently needs that are looking to
tariffs microbes in life and see if I
can I change the nature of habitable
which raises interesting questions
ethical debates and get those articles
like found on asteroids and I love a
real fan of conspiracy theories just
because they make me
people's views on the Illuminati did
this and technology 3d printing one-way
trips to double world millions of miles
away when we sign up from a trip to mars
people's names
thank you very much
just mentioned in the post in secret
Illuminati 911 was a lie it is currently
there are no actual time
every three years
there is one of the things I do
children and say thank you very much for
sharing with me there's anybody does
have any questions at all about anything
I've said as long as in operating the
flight got a couple of minutes but why
did you do that Campbell do you agree
that this to be honest I think yeah I
would
I would fight again however I think I
would choose my crowdsourcing flight
created a little bit more careful next
time don't use your friends to this day
will be revenge but first of all
qualities that I secondly thank you very
much