hello
good morning I did originally was going
to bring to talks so I submitted through
the CFP to do talk on started testing
and they're getting scarcer environments
up and running and was in a smooth ass
on Oct 2 2010 actually that's one in the
same israeli everybody me so what I've
had today strong combined 22 in 2012
trying hits and keynote but also to
provide you with some information and
scarred her so I started see a thread
forming a little talk to you about
however there's also a third element in
this mixture and i'm looking at the
organizers of silicon for this bill
cannon known for wanting to do things a
little bit differently this is going to
be quite a difference talk they will do
normal things will go sideways shortly
commence Camry I'm technical director
encryption limited I was originally
founded the Tigers game certification
scheme back in 2007 I also who founded
the cycle scheme in 2013
hanging around in the information
security industry for over 17 years I
think eighteen years this year I think
about the offensive roles throughout all
of those seen a number of changes in the
developments in what we do what we
perceived to be information security and
how we go about helping our customers in
our role during during that time again
that houses talks is gonna be a few
minutes of some common sense normal talk
about common sense
followed by something which has been
dubbed blind slight not sure I think it
was John Carroll who came up with this
was basically gonna happen and I'm going
to track my flight out as long as
possible
yes I am like to turn the conference
talk on its head there are a number of
slides which have been crowdsourced
which will be sucked into this machine
at some point during this tour i think
im terrified apparently I'll be fine I
have been told the information given
isn't there are an equal number of
slides which contain Disney characters
to slides which contain images of
pregnant man
happens anyway so fine waiver testing
out something in this industry a long
time and I've seen trends come and go
over the years particularly driven by
the clients in particular
Manchester first and foremost and I
started out saying the government area
back in the mid to late 19th i've seen
contrasting what we dubbed fantastic
time going from an average of a
six-month engagement where we literally
given in town told nothing about it is
that right in between January and July
you'll find out everything he possibly
can you will get a job at a company you
will get in that you will find extract
all of their information in any way
possible
catalog document every single
exploration route that this organization
or company presently that was when there
were a lot of us in the industry around
industry specialists stuff we don't
really have a pair of NCAA with
interesting because I wasn't really
thinking what we found people like
myself moved out of that year in which
we work and consultancy became more
commercial we started attracting the
interest of all kinds of other companies
big and small thats the benefits of what
we did but they do have some kind of
budgets and drivers the introduction of
compliance sticking around government I
T health checks for the public services
network to all public bodies have to be
connected then including now from this
year the police sources to gain piercing
connection you have to kind of
protection thing that you've done that
and thanks in part to help end
regulated and mandated what we do now
and the way we based on price not own a
good you are
satisfactory regulatory compliance
around the people that are employing
these people at least have passed a test
within the industry people who got the
qualifications will have slightly
different approaches and pen testing
community has been largely constructed a
constrained and being dictated how we
actually doing things I got down to the
point where a pen test back in 30 2010
we were winning tests and work on the
basis that yet we continue our health
checking today's
how much value that I actually have
quickly realized that in having a
network that supports four thousand
employees being contested in two days to
pay for it cuz I have to have it done
now going on up there some way to
realizing that we need to spend more
time you need to let these people use
their imaginations let them explore get
that box standards mechanical pencils
down the way they're going through your
mind around what would you do if it was
an employee and company and I worked
there for years and I got to really know
systems IV expiration date or in
different ways that just simply wouldn't
be found on it but what are not so happy
about being street cred teeming with the
red thing now paralyzed whatever team
exercise is now is a fantastic and what
from what I've seen of the industry of
its social engineering team red teaming
is taking thermite through the door
hinges on the Rhino steel door burning
the damn thing down that hitting it
repeatedly with a sledgehammer to look
forward over that's right time I'm not a
big fan of the time being used in the
context that it is now but it does show
an upsurge in the sine wave of the
client's demands and clients
expectations of what we do and that
we're going back to Long reagents are
going back to open up the scope and
saying blankets go you find out what you
want to know about it we'll see if we
can detect your active
30 and work out what you got and that's
a healthy thing for the industry but its
maturing in a way and by that we are
really looking at is the requirement for
the number of princess when I started in
the industry as a people to really say
what they did nobody really knew you
were aware of pockets of people doing
stuff here and there but now it's a
career path you can go to university
degree in penetration testing and
ethical happy there are loads of course
is a qualified we've reached a level of
maturity now where the pen test is
having produced and push down into the
industry being created in very formulaic
way being given a very prescriptive
methodology and tool set to use whereas
the appetite for the industry is going
up for three more inventive as I'm gonna
hit by some very near future
skills gap in its own right now we have
people with the tail with the job title
Penn testers and difficult to prove that
they are without homes meet the
requirements getting into Penn testing
in the in the mid to late nineties
nobody knew about it you just kind of
ended up in that role as a typical grip
are now it's a conscious choice that
people have decided when going to
university or when picking their
employers but that is something I want
to do that's why wouldn't that be
something completely different mindset
people into the industry that has
matured but there are always
opportunities to learn not just from
happens to think I'm Pentastar
I can do the job if you think that then
we need to look at your job title is
absolutely fantastic fantastic have
imagination creativity that's the
defining role from each other and from
every engagement which we undertake we
should be learned something you should
be seeing something that benefits
before I think I've been doing this a
long time going still learn something
new every week since he would like to
see people is notion that we had an
encryption particularly hard to do with
the tsongas King station program to
start a Cyber Academy now that these
plans are well progressed on the way to
recovery is intended to work with
government apprenticeship scheme to
provide an alternative routes to working
information security industry now most
of certification schemes that are
available to focus on penetration
testing forensics however information
security when we talk about the skills
gap we're really ignoring areas we have
to ask ourselves why are they gonna
bilities and systems number ones there
are very very few good quality courses
and education part that people can
become developers creating robust coach
is really as far as I'm aware and
correct me if I'm wrong
a university course we can go and learn
to count see shop
securing the role of the developers to
produce CO on deadline on budget ship it
to deal with the bugs later and that's
something that really needs to change
with nobody out there addressing that
policies and documentation I'm not a fan
of paperwork but there is that wrong
people need to be defining policies
applying and running standards like I
think we have until I want another or
cause you can do to become a lead
auditor
verifying somebody else has done it
right where the court is to put people
in positions in corporate organizations
where they can start to manage and
maintain the 27th of July 1 I think that
completely absent the Cyber Academy is
intended to take people from the age of
16 and a two-year course working with
industry sponsorship to provide key
skills such as secure coding
CCNA CCNP deciding the STM industry
placements during those two years
pay them a wage while they do that and
spit them out the end well-rounded well
experienced and ahead of the curve in
terms of their skills and I can bring to
the industry and those people coming
through the Academy will have the
opportunity to specialise in defensive
policy that I'm pen testing being
forensics and choose the path from one
of the skills options of any doubt that
the marketplace with level of maturity
which at the moment I believed to be
absent that's something that would like
to watch the press this we should be
making some announcements later in the
year at the moment we still do numbers
and juggling government grants and
contracts and finding venues and the
first year we should be putting 25 26
people three in the first year but
wanted to spread the Academy's to be
available in different cities around the
UK as well as a very firm and very
definite alternative to taking
University 390 20 universities they work
for some people for everyone but the
option for many people who want to enter
deeply technical field going forward in
their career is to go to university and
leave with frankly crippling debt
whereas the alternative is there you can
sure this process and to earlier if you
want to sustain yourself on a living
wage throughout and leave with him very
very good job prospects having already
made contacts in the industry having
shadow professionals having spent time
in placements in information security
and industry companies finds out I have
high hopes for it it will be a lot of
talk about the Garda
and that was the one you promised a
highly technical talk
well we're not gonna get too technical
but thinking about this over the last
few days it did throw up an interesting
rounds what we do in the industry have
different approaches and different
attitudes people have little pen testing
tools technology in general is its Garza
sada and the reason I bring this up is
really funny conversation will never
forget this conversation in many years
ago when into a financial means to do
for a prepayment SKP exercise had a chat
with the tech guys find out what they've
got with her about what do they want to
get out of the activity and one of the
most with a question about the platform
the CEO's what kind of technology are
gonna be bringing in on your laptop to
say well we are the government job it
might be mandated school windows 7 beta
blocker but by and large we like to use
a Linux operating system and more tools
you can lock up strips quickly if we see
something we want to test now I'm sorry
its operating system that has a slightly
different architecture to win over you
mean line and this is something I find
quite often is the numbering around
round our technical approaches about our
little fortress of knowledge we like how
we do things in a particular way and
that is the only way should be done
everybody else is wrong and that's
something that is crippling our industry
many many ways and skills people are
coming out into the industry and I am I
alone people I can save you a lot of
people who fortunately gradually turn up
made it through which are made it
through commercials somehow managed to
sit in front of me for for face-to-face
interview we get that you go through and
the people who are you human and quickly
as possible never speak again are the
ones who I say this is you look into
that gateway what do you do if they
flatten answer first look at a map of
the normal run this is like that of the
being a musical comfortable zone of
understanding what it is you want to do
and how you want to do it in every given
situation is not dependent on the
reasons to class Garda is because carter
also because the gaza testing industry
exactly that they have almost built a
fortress around what they will today
they put out the message that now we
know about this nobody should touch it
really shouldn't matter experts always
trying to build a fortress is around
themselves and treat everything has been
very very precious so I'm going to spell
for you today is one of those with room
for Garda technologies technology I
spoke about methodologies along one of
things I will firmly laid the challenge
to anybody who's bringing me something
I will paint tested regardless of what
we've looked at whether we seen it
before it could be a car system we can
sometimes lead pencil heating systems
for it really doesn't matter you don't
need to be a heating engineer to be able
to reverse-engineer heating system and
look for vulnerabilities so she started
on the counter and reflect light on this
one of the reasons I wanted this to be
brief reprieve actually how simple it is
what I think you might hear that
industrial control system not like magic
its industrial control system controls
industrial systems is probably
windows-based it's probably an awful lot
more familiar to you than you might
imagine but just because it's outside of
your fear of knowledge and outside of
your comfort zone doesn't mean that you
should be afraid of me at all feel that
you require mister industry experience
or stipulation system troops to
industrial control systems affecting the
nation from it you can't rule out
industrial control systems and scarred
the S&P standard office network is
basically doing the same thing you have
a national P trap which is not very
different systems
looking for information about the
intestines Carter infrastructure does
differ little bit different to different
to below-normal are you fired up
nice n Easy Street although he may not
have just hangin are still get around
this kind of stuff everything else is
pretty standard believe the slide to be
available so don't worry about these two
not a lot of the solution fairly
familiar to most people know my secret
databases which housing data this is
just a sample of technology there's
nothing really just a blip language on
the front end for replicating and I see
a system
tengo working as these are typically
repose I mean if everybody was talking
about with ICF daniel is just being
proposed we did you try the case either
positively and install the time that
providing the 22
follow these steps you have a completely
customizable portable ICS system there's
no black magic about this it is simply
technology its system employs
information and you are looking at ways
of communication with a system as I know
once you find out your card controller
will do everything I just said in the
last 20 minutes or so but there is no
next step is whatever you want to do
this is where you can test it by
examining following a rigid methodology
but following a scientific methodology
to observe collect that information
hypothesize what could happen if you
press that button their proper count on
that and then test the hypotheses
observe the result for those just
reading cycle over and over again to
some of the tools you can use tanks and
if you were probably gonna system
fingerprinting program for services to
get some information you can refer you
look manly looking vulnerable see
configurations look probably just
connections and systems as passwords if
they're in place
there is no how to do now that there is
no real how to do a penetration test and
surety the industry now is such that
that is what we're telling people I'm
pushing people out into the industry and
this is how fantastic is very good thing
I can tell you how I like to test that
theory how concerned should be done
anything is take the precious away from
ivory towers which people are building
the mint with if we're going to satisfy
client needs and the ongoing requirement
for information security skills in the
industry globally going forwards we
can't remain containerized we can't
believe that the skills that we learn in
one set of courses is going to have a
cool enough to push us toward an
actually replicate the activity of the
malicious attacker in the driver of
having security testing done
availability that could be found by
militias which are plentiful UK is under
attack every country under attack on
iraq press like to make
lot of figures out how much money we
lose to cybercrime and cyber attacks
every year we're different 21 industry
criminals
legal constraints will they do I was
thinking legal constraints and they have
the time they can spend six months 12
months however long it takes to examine
systems 22 probity different plans to
take as many imaginative routes to
getting that data that they want to
actually play and we as an industry
leader without a thought it was thinking
when I love box
disrespectful people particularly scar
experts are not so good experience and I
mess around 120 tests there are people
in a moonlighting and that's fine but
trying to keep all my way we should be
doing is in my mind's not the right
track community taking we do need to be
respectful respect of which we need to
learn from everybody and I said no right
or wrong way and that's a very brief
talk