so high I'm Phoenix
I'm going to talk about gonna talk about
the similarities between the manhattan
project in the global surveillance news
that came out reason why she recently
about two years ago I'm going to talk
about the Manhattan Project hands up if
you know the manhattan project is okay
I'll not do the German join the
surprisingly a lot I live in Germany now
if you're wondering where all this job
stuff comes from and we talked about
manhattan project I'm gonna talk about
the global surveillance project you know
prism of above all of the stuff that
stopped the Guardian from going bankrupt
people have got to eat right way not
let's not get back so the first striking
similarity between both the Manhattan
Project and the global surveillance
project is surprise surprise that both
top secret projects as I said this
earlier on in the highlight the
manhattan project employed a hundred and
ten thousand people a thousand knew what
they were doing so they can give you a
rough idea about what you can really get
away with without people noticing so the
first striking similarity between the
Manhattan Project and the global
surveillance stuff is that both both
instant both bands have suffered from
whistleblowers few people realize this
this guy called clubs fuchs you guys
know who he is if you're a break you
should be ashamed of yourself right now
this is the reason that we have a
nuclear project in the UK comes fruits
was a German Jew who suddenly found
their homes a little bit hostile towards
the beginning of World War Two became a
came to Britain seek asylum we gave it
and the he became part of our equipment
the manhattan project he's also a
trained to the Great Britain as well
was convicted for treason and sentenced
to 14 years he's also the reason that
the Soviet Union had a nuclear weapon to
but we'll talk about this later on when
you think about the damage that can be
done this nameless all that no one
really knows it far much more than this
one that we all know all roads lead to
Russia as well right which is a little
bit strange so people that wondering why
the the manhattan project was about the
manhattan project was about building a
nuclear weapon so just before world war
two starts they managed to split the
atom in Berlin and everyone with a grade
school and high school grade education
in physics understands very very quickly
holy shit we can make a bomb and we just
wore it might be really handy but to be
fair what was really hard for people to
get their head around was trying to
explain the nuclear weapon to people
don't have experience to of conventional
weapons is about explaining bigger bands
right i mean it's a problem that we have
insecurities I mean it's we've got we're
gonna have a bank but we've got bangs
now it's going to be really big how big
ten thousand times because you had just
doesn't comprehend it so how did the
Manhattan Project star the manhattan
project started like all great projects
star by fear uncertainty and doubt right
so who knows who this guy is Einstein
Einstein have a choice of come to
Britain had a choice going to America
where do you think you when you went to
America
so you might see you write the letter
goes to Cbus president and explains to
the you s president the germans Hitler
hasn't newt right he's going to nuke you
need to start building a nuclear weapon
they have weapons of mass destruction
and if we don't start now we're done is
over we need to start doing now he was
famous then is the is now right so if
you're talking the one of the world's
most famous scientist killing an
American president in building new what
do you think happened the manhattan
project started ok today is still one of
the most expensive projects that the
us-led military
this do you guys know what this is
know this is a nuclear reactor this is
actually the first nuclear reactor this
is where it all goes batshit insane
right they built this in Chicago under a
sports field not know any nuclear
reactors while the first nuclear reactor
they had no idea he said control rods
pulled them out to to start the nuclear
reaction ok I can guarantee you if you
build a nuclear reactor in your basement
you're probably gonna go to write it's
not a challenge for you to accept by
always friendly advice not something I
would get into the actually had health
and safety offices there with buckets of
distilled water you know your schedule
is distilled war had no idea what was
going on in about this and what they
were able to prove is that they could
they can start a reaction process and
then the project begins
so what we find with varies it's really
easy to think about you really hard to
put it into practice so they could split
data and produce a nuclear reaction they
just won't you sure about the best way
to go about it and what they knew was
the materials that they had were not
sufficient for the job basically they
needed uranium 238 which they'd only
ever produced in in lab quantities which
is you know couple of grains of SAT what
they needed was some pounds and pounds
of this material and no idea how to do
it so this was the first problem and
they had to solve a problem for him
because these different theories of how
you could enrich uranium so it was
wartime just to save the war it was to
save civilization to stop it from being
so bad blah blah blah blah blah so they
had their backs and went for every way
that they knew to enrich uranium they'll
have a go and they they built a number
of plants two billion dollars in and you
ask wartime billion dollars in nineteen
forty four or forty well early forties
they they spent two billion equivalent
26 billion dollars today so pretty cheap
if we think about the the the what we
spend now in more interesting story for
you they the Los Alamos plant consumed
per cent of wartime America's
electricity put that in context with you
they use more electricity than Chicago
and Boston put together right no one
noticed so anyway they built the
building number of plants here are the
heroes some of them five of them
Los Alamos is probably the most famous
this is a gaseous diffusion plant this
is very interesting you see these these
legs here this you shape of the building
these are half a mile long ok op til
1980 1983 I think the USA government
disclosed what this building was up
until then they did which is quite
interesting because this was the largest
military building a bill and still no
one noticed rate they had no when we
built it they had no idea what they were
going to build they just knew it was
going to be big right that's that's all
they knew so when they laid the
foundations for this thing they didn't
know they didn't know what they were
going to put on the roof right there
hadn't thought that far as they still
managed to get out is also slightly
radioactive to go this is a general
groves is an interesting character he's
the guy who built the pentagon he's also
the guy the military arm that supported
all of these physicist talk a little bit
about him in a little while he's a
famous story I feel that his assistant
and happy as we have a little bit in
common at the moment right so you have
this military guy goatees military
leaders and say I can't work with these
physicists and they're all prima donnas
I just cannot get a straight answer out
of him every time I speak to them they
just speak to me in a different language
sounds a little bit familiar right I
hear this all the time so
physicists about building some of their
plants
the physicist said because they didn't
know this was a research project right
they they gave their estimates to a
factor of time
doesn't sound that sounds like
conservative with the union of this
military guy who builds military
buildings like the pentagon he isn't
really used to this gray area you need
to tell me in black and white what you
want and I will build it that's kind of
how this works he was explaining to
eisenhower it's like me arranging a
wedding party for 4,000 people but maybe
thirty or turn up or maybe three
thousand alternate you know you know you
can't expect me to build these things
and basically what they said was shut up
build these things so the scientists one
in this in this story right now
interesting thing about los alamos is
that it's an interesting plants so I
could oppenheimer pretty sure you've
heard of he he was asked to head up a
project a little bit of a controversial
choice to say the least
you spoke to grows and grows wanted to
do was split all the scientists put them
in different parts of the country
because of security right departmental
eyes of resources so that if someone
compromises a site they don't have the
whole picture just very typical in a
military way of doing things not so
typical for theoretical physicists who
were building the world's first nuclear
weapon they might need to be around each
other so they came up with a solution
where they were going to build it campus
specifically for building a nuclear
weapon they were going to bring in all
the brightest and we're going to put
them in the comp the problem with us
you don't take lessons from Chicago
right so in Chicago you build a nuclear
reactor and felt the same they sat down
and thought about it when you know let's
let's put it in the middle of
nowhere right just just in case
something goes wrong let's let's not put
it in a dense popular area so they won't
the middle of the desert 200 miles away
from adding another interesting security
talk right aspect
be careful about what knowledge you know
where you disclose it an example to this
is so they build Los Alamos to start
shipping all of these physicists waiter
and there is this little train station
nobody is ever used to go to Chicago
cash the training to this place you get
picked up in an army jeep taken off the
Los Alamos so the train clerk has
started noticing that station in the
whole twenty-odd years that I've been
working here no one is ever taking the
train to all of a sudden we're starting
selling tickets and there's nothing
there to compound the problem may not
even get in return to his to just
getting single tickets what is going on
needless to say he was relocated from
his position and we shall never talk of
this gentleman again right but yeah
upset you know it's not just a dream
right
so mister said manhattan project
employed about a hundred and ten
thousand people is pretty big brown is a
huge deployment numerous of these people
have no idea what they were doing
they're doing just general day-to-day
operations so some of the plants had a
whole city culture attached to them I
think so I think the one in Tennessee
had two football teams had baseball
teams you know mars shops the big hole
amount of people working there doing
things there's an interesting story
about this manhattan project comes
flames everyone is a bit like when you
speak to him an American right
speech in american they always know
someone who was on the Mayflower it's a
bit like this with the Manhattan Project
to the time whenever they everyone has a
story about working from manhattan
project we was a woman who did have a
story she had a very strange job working
in the launch and waving this magic
stick over the laundry and when the
stick start making noises she was to go
in that in general will stick turned out
to be a Geiger counter and when she was
contamination so basically click click
click all we've had a leak I'm gonna get
the general but this was her job for you
she had no idea that she was frontline
decontamination give you a rough idea
about how need to know actually was
always find stories amazing right I
don't know we have a date here at
Eclipse right I'm getting knocked around
tell us that will still talk story so
1945 happens and who knows what happens
in 1945 the German surrender for a long
time they've been building weapons to
specifically talk to German threat ok
that the Germans are going to new cures
and all of a sudden Germany it's not all
of a sudden is not an unknown this is
this was on the cards for our journey
surrenders what do you think happens to
the Manhattan Project it just carries
ongoing like Jeremy still in war
remember jimmy had weapons of mass
destruction right and they were going to
nuke America and oh my god if we don't
do something now we're never going to be
able to do anything this is the German
reactor the non functional German
reactor turns out they were slightly
preoccupied with occupation and didn't
find too much time to do
R&D for news so they had very very very
little in the way of
any program whatsoever at all although I
will tell you whether their their
research stands up quite interesting so
this is this is the inspection of their
reaction as I say absolutely no nukes
strange isn't it like I remember an
incident in a couple of years ago where
we invaded a country because they had
weapons of mass destruction and I'm like
home would you mean that there is no
nothing here you know what's interesting
about that story is one of the huge
positive evidence that was given to me
by a guy called hans blix does anyone
know about his big sis the nuclear
weapons inspector who told them they can
make you when you make make a bomb
they've got the infrastructure they
could have the new right
the same story that was used very very
interesting so I was Brett's germans we
work this all out right you know
surrender happens however the us- is
still at war with Japan so ww2 is still
kicking off its just not in our backyard
anymore right so this is the interesting
story
U-boat 234 ok amazing story hugely
interesting but let's I only find this
story interesting because the context of
the implications to contact the store
pretty harrowing so who knows why we
were able to hammer the German Navy so
hot again and I we broke enigma so we
pretty much broke the back of the
germans naval systems and you to 34 was
the biggest you vote that they had a
problem is they don't have too many
sailors left good way of sinking them
pretty much stopped them from being
useful right so rikki Compton they give
to this is U-boat 234 so
towards the end of the world as we
discussed the indictment was a huge
player so the only way that Germany and
Japan were able to communicate securely
used to send to secure such a relative
term right but the only way that they
can communicate was to send U-boats to
each other right so that's how they work
that's how they were communicating they
were putting like offices on boats and
sending them and then we were trying to
bomb them on the way so you 2342
Japanese ambassador's make it to germany
and Germany's Germany's history is
written in the books already raised its
coming here knows it's here and Japan
Lika argument that if the worst succeed
it needs to be the flag-bearer right
whatever Germany can assist Japan it
needs to do it now and Japan will
continue on fighting it's a very
desperate from Japan Japan where we're
in no winning streak at this point
either bizarrely agrees with them and
what he does is he takes you to 34 which
is a battle + you vote under the sea
boat they like to call them they strip
it and they turn into a cargo vessel and
then what they do is they put basically
hitler's treasure trove of evil ship in
the submarine is caused by planes new
weapons and all of the germans nuclear
project which with some you to 35 which
still needed to be enriched but it was a
good starting point it was the plans
their ideas I mean you know it's not
going to give you a bomb but it's a
bloody good stuff because up to this
point
Japan didn't have anything so off they
send what is interesting videos of the
germans sailors that were on the decks
saying how weird this whole thing was to
Japanese guys came up in speaker word
German and they started walking around
in writing you to 35 on the boxes the
gems sailors had no idea what the cargo
where they just thought these were
stupid Japanese guys right you 235 w 22
free fall
right seriously this is what they
thought no other japanese were writing
you to 35 something else so anyway they
set off on off they go and we break the
break the code being sent out and we
don't know what's on the boat but we
should know that it's important enough
noise going on was so very very
interested in it so we basically start
bombing its its path this boat should to
about 300 feet the bombing was so severe
that they took the boat to 600 ok far
far beyond what it was supposed to do i
mean a depth charge anywhere near could
have easily sank them and their reports
that this is not the only shipments of
Iranian that was supposed to be sent to
Japan you know there is believed that
some uranium is still in broken U-boats
at the bottom of certain sees but so
right away you know the germans survived
an onslaught like you wouldn't believe
they finally outrun the allies they
surface so they got reception two gether
signals to get their commands and they
hear that hilary is now that the Third
Reich has surrendered unconditionally
you are crazy black flag upon your mast
and you are to sail to your nearest
Allied fleet and surrender and of course
the commander of the u-boat doesn't
really have a choice right he ignores
those commands he's a pirate and he will
be the first such which is really
interesting problem because they happen
to have two Japanese guys on their boat
who haven't surrounded who are still at
war with America and the only in vessels
in the area or a Canadian bustle an
American vessel the Germans have decided
that they want to for some reason
surrender to the Americans not the
Canadiens no idea why they give bad
signal intelligence to the canadians and
head out to meet the Americans the
problem is you have these two guys on
board that went on to ship full of
allies when they started and became
prisoners straight afterwards right
where tens of these two buses also
happen to know a little bit about
submarines so the U-boat commander was a
little bit concerned about this and he
locked in their rooms relieve them of
their weapons blah blah blah blah blah
they didn't hear from them for a couple
of hours went in to check special price
they've committed suicide notes probable
that L and the wife of one of the
ambassador's that she believes the
husband could have sunk the ship but
decided to save everyone's life
basically night he would just take it on
because he was not going to be taken by
the Americans so anyway the boat comes
along they surrender themselves to Aus
smaller ship that put on the guns they
bring into the USS talk only when it
pulls into you realize that it's the
equivalent of like a two-hour shouting
down a rock viola it's a tiny little
boat big bow and it's like any day of
the week and twice on Sunday the Germans
were always gonna win this argument
apart from this day
ISO 200 over and this is when they start
to look through the tenori-on workout
that actually is about this both
slightly interesting uranium is quite a
rare property was enough to build a bomb
that had enough uranium in that was
pretty cool so the manhattan project
turned up and took the uranium and then
threw it into their reactor turned into
uranium 238 and that made parts of the
bomb dropped on Hiroshima so history
he should have a cruel sense of irony
yes it got in Richton delivered by the
American history has a very crude sense
of irony right it's not enough to make a
bomb but it's it's a sizable amount you
have no idea with what care they true to
the treated this uranium they got the
uranium and certain the power with the
rest of uranium it wasn't like and the
little bit of the ball here is the
German part so yeah they they they took
something like four hundred pounds and
turned into 50 grams that's the kind of
attrition rate you looking at this is
little boy this is one of the weapons is
a bit strange the call a little boy
right doesn't look so fucking loan
that's why they call it this is fat man
not the five and Tayside metropolitan
area network for anyone from Janet this
is this bad boy right you don't wanna
mess around with this is this is
basically the gadget this is the test
piece is quite funny in this story as
well
five years they took them together and
finally they've made enough plutonium
and uranium they can they've got enough
to spare right to blow up a test piece
so they're pretty sure that the pretty
sure that little boys going to work as a
piston system is inefficient but it will
work but they're not too sure how this
which is an implosion method work so
there goes the day as well
problems along the way right so they
bring out this great big bomb four days
the constructing the training ground
that Alma Gordo which is called Death
Valley by the way apparently if you in
the New Mexico desert if you call on
this path without any water
died they thought it was a great place
to stop project Trinity which is Alma
good over the bill they got it so they
start building it take the plutonium
call
they they go to put it in the gadget and
it doesn't fit right after six years of
plutonium call does not fit in the bomb
scares me pretty cool all the way
through it but he's at this point where
he's like well for years we've been
building this for this long and you're
telling me it doesn't science right what
they forgot was the case been out in the
Sun for four days and that the heat in
the Sun and expect expanded the metal
components of the device will they
needed to do was leave the plutonium
core out for a couple of hours to get up
to similar temperature dropped by but
just just for a couple of minutes
boy did they think they felt so you can
imagine how nervous she would be like
two billion dollars later told him it
doesn't fit I didn't allow not only did
not go via web application so the most
infamous picture we probably see
throughout history there's been a cool
moment that changes changes everything
they had no idea I say to you that had
no idea of what would happen they took
backs right so you know the sweepstakes
if someone's pregnant in the office you
bet on the baby's weight that's exactly
what they did here like hey when it goes
off how many kilotons well I'm gonna
take 2 I'm gonna take twenty I'm gonna
take thirteen I'm gonna take 11 seasons
sanctions that building the ship had no
idea right they just knew is gone be a
big right ok they were a little bit
right so the spectators like
twenty-month 200 miles away right this
how far you can see this thing and their
advice was when the detonation goes off
lay on your back with your feet towards
the explosion
right and you'll be ok thanks for that
like I really need to do to what that
show so anyway and we talked about a
little bit to do any of you know where
Tyler is he's really the harbinger of
death so he'd managed to scare the shit
he was one of the the Greek went to
America fantastic physicist very very
egocentric though he managed to sell but
he managed to basically scare the whole
entire account that there was a
possibility that a nuclear weapon was
going to ignite the atmosphere right
which you can imagine if you're a
military person that's probably slightly
worrying to hear i mean for any other
person is a little bit concerning as
well so general rose walks into the
office space oppenheimer shots
oppenheimer and I'm so no we've we've
crunched the numbers and words got it
wrong ok it's only a one in three
million right that suggest that dole 24
there's a one-in-three million chance
that the we could ignite the atmosphere
you can imagine is a general it's not
one that kind of how to punish trying to
convince the whole office that will blow
this up the atmosphere we're glad to
report that metallic was wrong right you
know they did they still fuckin turned
on right well you know we don't turn 3
million of them on this ok right so this
is probably one of the most infamous
quote that you'll ever find from
oppenheimer oppenheimer is a complex
character passionately believed the
atomic weapon adamantly against I
imagine that once you once you build a
war war stop her
you probably don't want to be involved
in building too many more we have a an
equivalent of oppenheimer
members name in the UK who once we built
our weapon project icon ops all his
papers he didn't keep his papers his
journals everything he didn't want to be
remembered in life somebody built a
nuclear weapon so it's a bit of a tough
cookie to carry out margin but as a safe
America still at war with Japan who
quite clearly doesn't have a new project
because you just enriched uranium right
to you you kind of ahead of the game you
know it's not gonna have so few logistic
problems in dropping a nuclear weapon
right like you can't just turn up you
you can't send it via DHL wrote you know
the Royal Mail was not going to deliver
this you will need a signature for that
ok so they had to have to practice
flying planes these guys have no idea
what they were doing until later on this
is the most amazing story ever see this
guy here right he said he was gonna do
the first bomb run nuclear weapons and
he thought this plane is going to be the
most famous plane in history right so we
named after his mother enola gay so
history now records that gave bombed
Hiroshima but you know interestingly
enough so they practice this run they
going to do it you know when we speak
speak about snowed in we talk about why
didn't he use official channels to
suggest a little segue feel why didn't
why didn't he gon speak to people about
what he discovered you know he's an
example of people involved in the
Manhattan Project writing saying we've
seen the demonstration of the web you
cannot drop this on japan ranks they
have no nuclear project you cannot do
this you need to set up a demonstration
and show them
you cannot drop this on people this is
the petition and they set up in Chicago
this is the petition and his staff las
alamos the oppenheimer himself stopped
from being distributed throughout the
rest of the camp this is the official
channels and their answer was is too
quiet all of these prima donna
physicists as they like to call them
where they were going to have a debate
where they were going to have debate
basically with the president's man but
dropping the weapon and don't let
history confuse the selection of the
bombing targets they specifically shows
civilian areas to drop their bombs if
you look at where both bombs were
dropped there were military targets that
they completely missed and in the choice
to bomb down the center of town another
interesting fact for you
Hiroshima and Nagasaki both were not
bombed by conventional weapons for a
good 11 days prior to them being bombed
because what they needed was a city in
top so that they could gauge the damage
so you were sitting there if you were in
hiroshima thinking while everyone else
had been bombed with a blast
yeah maybe not but like I said this is
the official channels that quite clearly
didn't want the people who built it
saying we can't do it
Hiroshima Nagasaki this is the case by
the way of the black box where anything
anything we should just build stuff
whatever they build those artists out
right now that's the ship they send they
send a lot of the manhattan scientists a
way to look at hiroshima none of them
are pretty much the same afterwards
right it's quite hard to get their head
around when we sit there and laugh about
nuclear weapons but it doesn't have any
more eyes right there's still a huge
amount of damage done in this Japan
didn't have nuclear project power pretty
close to surrender
it's a lot of debate that this weapon
was dropped a lot more to scare the
soviets than it was to be the judge
needs and you can still see this later
on russian intelligence we haven't
spoken about the russians is not
security and cyber without the russians
right to the russians bear so the
Americans gap a game-changer weapon the
Americans drop it on a country that
doesn't have any weapons and another
country without any weapons looks
diego's holy shit they're going to do
that to us right so startling decides we
might want to get involved in this
nuclear research project right now that
we've tried no no we're going to do it
now we tried know if you don't do it I'm
gonna kill you trust me he killed a lot
of people this is this by the way
IP theft IP that plus plus plus a
suprise suprise russians are pretty
known as a lot and they like to March
and take over ship I don't like to fly
in we just walk away with doing it so
the russians had plans but they didn't
have any bombers little bit it's pretty
much the same again we can be a
challenge so what we gonna do when we
gonna meet Obama so we've got to build a
bomb and bomber ya know the americans
build it in Mexico right yeah ok send an
engine with a suitcase full of cash to
the factory bribe someone to give you
the plans and that's exactly what
happened so this is the to pull off and
this is the Flying Fortress which is an
exact carbon copy Coast outsourcing they
paid the Mexican and they got the money
like dating give a shit sure this is the
best I don't think I've ever heard about
anecdote than this one right now so the
reverse engineer looks at the American
Boeing plan
ends and sides make this but we can make
some improvements here here and here
says no I want an exact copy this
sometimes in life people say stuff
without thinking right and get to get to
tell the consequences and this is one of
them to starting system engineer no I
want you to build an exact copy to
reverse engineer says he wants to paint
the stars on to the guy lives to tell
the tale which is surprising because
there's a lot of people who died for a
lot less than 80 they were all like he's
like a legend in my book i mean this is
this is how we get into trouble anyway
basically the Tupolev is a carbon copy
of the the the the Americans so the
Manhattan Project the russians the home
Russian weapons system basically their
first job is literally a photocopy
plants fruits gave the russians the
plans from the manhattan project so talk
a little bit about classrooms what he
was part of our project when we got
involved in the nuclear game before the
Americans when the americans decided to
get involved they said well why don't we
absorb your your team where turns out
that our guy was an ardent communist
regime in giving information to the
russians for quite a while but how about
this for a clusterfuck they blew the
russians top nuclear agent and dropped
him right in the middle of the manhattan
project right literally they flew their
assets and the russians lost contact
with him like where's that guy going and
he finally makes contact with them in LA
where you are
so they didn't bomb everything you say
so everyone's part about blah blah blah
blah
let's go back home Americans soon as
we're out the door the Americans Elect
Sharon Papo with you go right so when he
gets fuck we're like hey can you tell us
what you did and basically klaus fuchs
stealing Intel of the Americans to get
to the Brits to get our project back up
and start but at the same time
supplying it the russians as well so
closely examine his handler in London
he's got the plans to to Fatboy
basically stuff down his trousers and
little tube some metal thing right now
is this
rushing rushing case officer basically
just spoke in London right not commit no
specialist knowledge just the listening
station bomb means club suites gives in
the plants gives in this mount stuff
says he could care of that they're gonna
need it dude traps bounced off to the
side of his chest
sticks the the plans in a suitcase flies
out from moscow has over the plans gives
over the mount stuff and i'm for the
rest of his life as radiation burns
decided his ballyhooed throw eat flown
uranium 235 235 struck the side of his
body on a commercial flight had no idea
whatsoever right so if you look at the
data loss you know didn't give a lot of
data right you know some reports and
some files but the implications of
massive if you look at the the day at
the start of the leaked yet as a lot of
it right needs adjustment estimates US
ambassador because even general
alexander hasn't got a clue what this
guy to have been out there for a while
yeah you can imagine there's a lot of
David flying about reason so what does
it all come from so when the russians
drop their set off their first nuclear
weapons so the Americans the Americans
thought they would have 10 years
monopoly right that's what they thought
we have this game-changing weapon we've
got ten years to cement our Monopoly
within four years Russia sets off their
first nuclear weapon right and it kind
of scares the shit out of the american's
begins the mccarthyism trials and stuff
like this but when that happens what
stocks is the cold war right this is
what becomes which shapes our lives
today quite predominantly right mean we
like to believe that we don't we're not
in a cold war but I didn't feel much
different than it did twenty years ago i
mean is there still a lot of bullshit
going on
mccarthyism if we knew history batter
will call this Hoover -ism that that's
you know coffee -ism ripped America
apart right so anyone who is suspected
of being un-american aka communist was
basically black ball which is a problem
from oppenheimer because basically
oppenheimer on inspection would look
like a communist right his wife was a
communist his brother was a communist
his friends were communists the FBI
maintaining him from 1933 when they
reviewed his case with any any police
officer reviews your case you can hope
for this moment right with a wheel in a
big trolley stop to file and the person
book saying goes
gonna take awhile they say is the other
four you want to worry about
that's how big his fire wars spoke to a
friend recently was telling me all the
good old days prewar least had some
minor focus with tapping the
oppenheimers lawyers office oppenheimer
case review for security clearance and
the quote-unquote prosecution were given
tapes by the FBI of the whole legal
defense prior to me going in you know
let's let's just not talk about the
Constitution anymore right i mean you
don't need that right communism
mccarthyism times my interest from this
comes from article I wrote about how
hackers we experienced version of
mccarthyism
if you want to silence someone who
accuse him of being a happy right i mean
you put them in a jail cell five years
without telephone calls you know just
ask mitnick have now got bail hearing
right you know you can let you know I'm
not a big fan of we look at what was
done that that the whole list goes on in
these instances and the late great great
our stores lost his life for checking
out too many library books so you know
mccarthyism still here still remnants we
still have a figure of its still there
so if you're wondering where I came from
I spent some time looking at mccarthyism
and following without way that's where I
got this is oppenheimer who even today
would never get fucking security
clearance right this guy put it into a
modern context this guy you were given
security clearance the guy that used to
hang out bin Laden that's basically what
you would be doing right i mean this guy
had so many red flags it was
unbelievable I mean and the reasoning of
a security clearance was literally a
train ride with general growth
lives in general growth asking communist
no ok but that was it
bank this space and so does cowboy
wasn't having any of this left the
communist look OVR you communist ok it
wasn't before this is Edward Teller so
you talkin atomic weapon is a nasty
piece of equipment right is tackled over
its weapons you can use practically what
they worked out is that they could use
an atomic reactions self the
thermonuclear reaction which is a pretty
shit right it's like a thousand times
more powerful than the most powerful
atomic weapon you can think of
there's absolutely no top to call back
to using a thermonuclear weapon
basically built bomb chicken new moscow
that's right it's there is nothing out
when they demonstrated the bikini but
they have operated the island they
tested right let's just get out of
context they blew an island away
gone no more not know landmass gone
that's how powerful this thing is right
lots more far more deadly oppenheimer's
very much against the thermonuclear
weapon basically what you said was and
it's a price price right way said was
the only reason the russians have a
nuclear weapons because we have a
nuclear weapon and if we build a nuclear
weapon guess what the russians will have
a thermonuclear weapon right they built
one because of us if we do this they
build one because of us and needs
weapons from North tactical advantage
they will just and the world and it was
his opposition against the thermonuclear
weapon which inspired his hearing that
got him to lose his security clears the
guy that gave america its nuclear
project was deemed unsafe to know about
the new project that shit
you know it's kind of strange because we
have this insecurity all the time the
shit they said they were going to do
they did you guess what when the
russians got the thermo knew when
america made this number new
russian-made is not so long after its
all here we go with the security should
write so all the shit they said they
won't do it totally doing and why we're
doing it
cyberwar right if you wander in these
people in uniforms have a question I've
asked everyone why is it a drone
operators wear flight suits right
there's something in that logic that
just doesn't work for me you're not
supposed to be in the play is inflict
ok but cyber war and we said this for a
long time right
like here is something that happened in
1952 we playing out in 2014 the BMD
which is the German equivalent of the
NSA went back to the pond stock which is
the German equivalent of the government
and said we need 300 million euros to
compete against the NSA in the exploit
purchasing business they literally like
we need more money to buy my side
weapons because the americans have got
it and they start a cottage industry
firstly I think they need another 0 but
this is the beginning right well now you
know you don't have to worry about
bugai's by 20 days right gonna be out
price the market by the the industrial
military complex when it goes down or so
yeah this is already starting to happen
when this this is just a country that
went on record with God knows who elses
start another game at some point you
have to have a snow dome comment I'm
kind of gratefulness known because it
means I have to stop doing some new
comment to let us know in comments now
show all is good right
but basically he said you know we have
computer scientists have their atomic
bomb known and we do we pay by piece do
things his researches the scene with
outweigh them seem so important when
they connected into bigger things start
to become more important let's get this
clear metadata kills right that's the
simplest are right when they launch
their attacks on bin Laden it was purely
metadata that they went on there were
right this time as a lot of people in
weddings in Pakistan where they were
wrong you know so when we say the Mac
sedate we know we're not collecting
content pager we're collecting metadata
people died on that share right this is
not just their i mean we teach as a
community we teach security but we have
very little concept of the implications
of where we go so it's like bill
mountain you know that's the security
industry that broke SIM cards yay for us
you know we we screwed the
telecommunications industry over when
you know if we look if we look at the
companies that were targeted each were
american companies targeted by an
american agency will show you what do
what look do you think the welcomed when
Google when PayPal targeted by the
nation give you some worries right is a
really shitty for you to see so sucks to
be you right so this is the budget from
2013 USA National Intelligence reached
its fifty two point six billion dollars
in 2013
this is what they're spending on spooks
Saibaba you know people where this money
would have trickled down to buy
HP quote just to show you that I do have
some corporate blueblood somewhere right
record 2013 the global spending on
defense products globally that's the
planet was forty billion dollars right
one country spent more on offensive
operations lot massively then we spent
globally on defense forced to tell you
something right that we are where we are
in a very very particular situation and
it's a lot like the military industrial
complex I feel kinda glad that managed
to go all these late lefty liberal runs
out of the way right but the problem is
is that the situation and when can you
imagine the NSA saying hey there's no
more threats it's all good we can go
wrong we don't need any of that 53.6
billion dollars anymore rain is a bit
like polar bears voting for blacks
controls and carbon emissions right i
mean the military-industrial complex you
know and and Boeing and all these other
countries companies that make money from
war you have to turn around and get
these people say no is not going to
happen it doesn't happen right it's
never going to be the case you know what
we find is the government's will turn
for these companies to give expert
opinion on the situation so you're going
to speak to write about how safe the
world is and what do you expect nothin
to say probably gonna need some more
bombs right how many of you know what it
is quotes from war is peace is it's a
little bit screwed up with the reference
worst pieces is 1984 reference if you
haven't read 1984 don't mistake it for
an operational manual
if you have read it read it again today
with today's context right really today
again with what's happening and it's a
very scary read i read it just forwarded
this talk a few months ago
ready before but it was a little bit
more hard-hitting when I'm like a lot
worse if we did it right so much stuff
in 1984 as a little bit less horrible
than alright so war is peace mean we
have a system that is continually
designing to the European Way right
European Way is war war war that's all
we've done is a general alexander this
general alexander lying to his bosses
and its general alexander lying to us a
black right so yeah you can get away
with not telling the truth as long as
you have stripes and stars right this is
growing if you're wondering
he's the the military guy build the
pentagon is pretty cool can be a bit of
an ass but no general alexander on so
many different conclusions a lot of this
is about the problem is we seem to have
speaking to engineers security minded
about it and your freedom is it
something as simple as knowing the two
plus two equals four support freedom
actually ultimately is right and a lot
of what we're going on now is trying to
have like asymmetric information where
people take control of Dayton I will too
when are able to share I've said this a
number of times about the whole and I
say leaks its people ban on as those
snowden you know it snowed in spied on
people's emails you know it's not you
know if light if the truth
Scrushy operations up maybe your
operations were a little bit to start
off with freedom is to know the two plus
two equals four and it's a freedom that
we're losing massively censorship so on
and so forth
and I wonder if a lot of the way how
many of you read brave new world
you know all I can say is net neutrality
right i mean if you want to look at what
damage you can do if you tend to PSN PSN
off on the PlayStation Network offer on
Christmas day right you could probably
start right well as if we turn on the
Netflix often well don't laugh and joke
but the very means that we used for
communication is is greatly being
affected with you know we are a lot like
physicists if we're not care but the
thing is people are not going to ask us
how to use our research very much longer
you know to build nuclear weapons
doesn't require nuclear physicists
anymore right
it requires a factory and we will get to
this point in security offensive
security where does not require security
consultants talking about ethics and
morals to launch an attack against
anyone of us I'm gonna leave you with
her friends with this quote those who
can make you believe it can make you
commit atrocities I feel that this is
pretty rather than where we are all in
all so that being said I am a little bit
over time but your game a little bit
later if you want to get a hold of me is
less hopeful says feel free to email me
and I'll feel free to ignore it right
but I would like to thank you for coming
and I would like to thank you guys
the volunteers and you guys to thank you