lakme presents an overview of the
Lifetime Achievement Awards the Lifetime
Achievement Award is like Nick
initiative the names that honoring
individuals who have made significant
contributions to the development of the
internet and the information society in
Latin America and the Caribbean since
2009 these awards have been presented to
since 1987 and for 27 years the house
was the head of the central computer
service of the Republic of your way in
the early 1970s if the house was part of
the first generation to graduate from
the University of the Republic with a
university degree in Computer
Engineering EDA has always been a
pioneer playing a key role not only in
your white but also at regional level
she played a leading role in the
construction of latnok the Latin
American network forum the organization
of latin america and caribbean country
code top-level domains lack TLD and the
Latin American cooperation of advanced
networks plaid during the past 20 years
in the house has permanently contributed
to the development of icts in Latin
America the relevance of her work is
commendable not only for the concrete
results she has achieved but also for
the example it sets for the entire
community in 2013 EDA was inducted to
the Internet hall of fame as a global
connector being the first person from
Latin America and the Caribbean region
in receiving such recognition carlos
Afonso executive director of new path
new Clio the best kisses estudos for
Mossad brassy Carlos Afonso has
contributed to the creation and growth
of the region's Internet community where
he has played a key role in several
pioneering experiences during the early
nineties he contributed to the creation
of the Latin American network firm and
has actively participated in the
creation of the first Brazilian internet
steering committee in 2004 the United
Nations accredited general appointed him
to be a part of the internet governance
working group and later choose him to be
a part of a multi stakeholder advisory
group for the Internet Governance forum
Lawrence Ignacio trade-ideas executive
director of Clara Latin American
advanced networks cooperation Chile
florencio traders has been the executive
director of Clara since 2004 Lorenzo has
been involved in internet development
and academic networks for more than 20
years and has received several awards
for his contribution to the
dissemination of Internet technology and
research networks among many other
activities in various organizations and
institutions that promote internet
development florencia participated in
the organization of 98 96 and 98 97 he
was also president of the local
organization committee for the icon
meeting held in Santiago Chile in August
1999 where the original community
presented the application for the
creation Atlantic in the year of its
10th anniversary latnok decided to
present a 10th anniversary edition of
the Lifetime Achievement Awards which
recognized 10 personalities from all
around the region
the 10th anniversary honorees were
marcos debating a canteen private sector
founder and CEO of mercadolibre mercado
livre has changed the lives of many
people and the way business is done in
the region godparents initiative has had
a huge impact in Latin America Luis
foolin what a mal Academy poulan
introduced the internet to his country
and is regarded by watermelon media as
the father of the Internet in Guatemala
he's the director of Guatemala's dad GT
at the Universidad de hua shi de
Guatemala he has been a professor of
computer science since 1970 and has been
working as the director of the
university's management of GT since 1992
heaters the university's computer
science department and serves as a
rector for its centre of interactive
technologies he is also a member of is 0
z i ii ii ii and lack TLD
Jose saw Diana pero Technical Community
a Peruvian internet pioneer Jose was a
strong promoter of the Peruvian
scientific network which made the
internet available to the masses in his
country Jose served as general manager
of dot PE the Peruvian country code
top-level domain for 10 years and was
also very active in building the
regional community among other things he
has worked as a national coordinator of
the Mercosur digital project and
provided consultancy services for the
argentinian national office of
information technology the UN PD the
inter-american Development Bank UNESCO
like Nick and flee been pet rats in
Argentina academia and international
organization from his position at the
eye dr see ben has promoted many ICT and
internet development initiatives in
Latin America and the Caribbean he has
supported projects in many different
fields such as the creation of
communities education access research
and indicators he has also taught at the
business school of the Hong Kong
University of Science and Technology
served us advisor to Argentina's
national congress and taught at the
National University of Buenos itís
Laurette the same Grinnell government
Loretta Simon is the ICT director for
the government of Granada with a
specific Monday to lead Granada into
becoming a full knowledge society as
Granada first computer science lecturer
he has been responsible for training in
nitey at the secondary and tertiary
level she now serves on the Caribbean
examinations council span alone
information technology she is also a
regional each other and regional court
coordinator with a University of the
West Indies open campus initiative and
has served as an OAS consultant on the
integration of ICT in the secondary
schools curriculum Bernard Lewis synodal
and tobago international organization
Bernard Lewis is the Secretary General
of the Caribbean telecommunications
union since august 2003 she has
accomplished her mission for the
organization which is to ensure that the
citizens of the region have affordable
access to and are able to derive
tangible benefit from the effective user
information and communication technology
Anthony Harris Argentina private sector
Anthony has been executive director of
the Argentine internet chamber kawase
since 1998 a year that had great impact
on the future of Internet organizations
in 1899 this process also led the
creation of econ black an organization
in which anthony has served as executive
director in his double role he was also
active in the process of icons
recognition of latnok Anthony is
currently a member of the icon standing
panel of experts vice chair of the
Internet service providers and
connectivity providers constituency and
a member of the executive committee of
the commercial stakeholders group baladi
of a tank or Ecuador civil society
baladi is a sociologist and political
science and activist in the field of
icds for development and social justice
for the last seven years she has worked
on supporting civil society organization
in the strategic views of iced teas and
facilitating their involvement in ICT
policy processes at national regional
and global level she participated in the
first and second phases of the boozes
brothers facilitating the relationships
and articulation of civil society
organizations in Latin America and
loving for the inclusion of their points
of view and priority issues in the same
its documents and official results she
has been project coordinator for the
Latin American ICT police monitor at the
Association for progressive
communications and she is currently
serving as director of a PCS global
policy program demi get Brazil
Technical Community demagogic o is
director president of the Brazilian
network information center Nick that BR
in 1991 he was part of the team
responsible for the first Brazilian
tcp/ip connection for which reason he is
considered to be one of the fathers of
the Brazilian Internet among many other
roles and positions in various companies
and organizations until night 2009 Demi
served as a member of the Internet
Corporation for Assigned Names and
numbers board representing the country
code name supporting organization amumu
italic Venezuela technical community
among many other rows
responsibilities for various Venezuela
and initiatives and mundo Batali has
served as education manager at the
Venezuelan National Center for
information technologies coordinator of
the Rana project the national network of
contents for schools and coordinator of
the national education portal project
mundo was one of the founding members of
isla rail and general coordinator of the
internet workshop for latin america and
the caribbean walk he was also a member
of and rail the network forum for latin
america and the caribbean member of the
project of illusion committee for the
Frida program latnok since 2006 and
coordinator of the unesco cisco computer
networks professorship at universidad de
los andes during 15 years in mundo was a
regional manager of the cisco networking
academy the network technology education
program for Central America the Andean
countries and the Caribbean can sec the
2013 lifetime achievement awards will be
presented soon so we invite the
community to submit their candidates by
writing to trajectory ax at like Nick
dotnet for more information on the rules
for participation please visit www net /
web / trajectory thank you very much and
congratulations to winners