hi we're here with David olive vice
president of policy development for I
can and we've asked him to give us a
little preview of what's going to happen
this week at ICANN 48 we're very excited
to be here in Buenos Aires Argentina for
our I can 48 meeting the other important
element is this is our 15th year
anniversary and so we're pleased to be
in this part of the world of Latin
America to be able to celebrate that
with our stakeholders we're expecting
over two thousand registered people
coming to the meetings so it should be a
really action-packed event with many
topics and we're excited for that
possibility so David what's going to
happen on Monday well before we get to
the Monday session the representatives
of our community are already coming to
do some pre meeting activities many of
the stakeholder and consistency groups
have new members coming to join their
councils or executive committee's so
they've had a series of orientations for
them so they can meet I can officials
and community members so what do you
what do you think the high interest
topics are going to be this week the
high intro sessions on Monday will be a
focus on internet governance some
background on meetings of the Internet
Governance forum that just took place in
Bali Indonesia as well as a domain name
security forum for the Latin American
region focusing on our ability to get
representatives from this region to talk
about their issues so that'll be a big
big day on Monday the formal day if you
will then other highlights of the
meeting our Tuesday meeting is really
the big stakeholder gatherings with our
Board of Directors and so we have
representatives from our registries or
registrar's civil society academics
technical community business community
non commercial users all getting
together to talk to the board of
directors about activities that involve
our I can work in addition to that we
will have a public forum and a
meeting on Thursday this gives our
community a chance to talk directly to
our board raise issues comment on topics
of interest to them and then the board
does some of its own work approving
various resolutions and recommendations
that have come through our bottom-up
process to present to them for final
approval in addition there will be a
focus on our new top-level domain
program new gTLDs briefing sessions for
some of the applicants and those
interested in how that new program is
developing and being implemented finally
of course as I mentioned the 50th
anniversary of I can we're going to have
some celebrations of that to look back
at the last 15 years but more
appropriately look forward what will be
the next 15 years with all our community
here obviously with the focus in Latin
America we will have a workshop on ipv6
this is an internet protocol version 6
adaption in the region an update on our
Latin American strategy and of course
our at large community will have its
lack Rallo showcase again gathering
representatives from all the Latin
American countries that are here to talk
about their interest and support for I
can work David is there anything else
you want to add just want to thank the
people of Buenos Aires in Argentina for
their wonderful hospitality the food is
wonderful the people are tremendous and
that'll be part of our successful
meeting here I'm sure thank you very
much David