we look forward to the success of our
partnership and to produce results and
many of us in this room look forward to
see you in Busan next year at a very
very important meeting for all of us
okay this is the part where I'm supposed
to take off my jacket and tell you
what's going on are you ready okay it's
getting a little harder to take off my
jacket because I'm collecting a lot of
airport and airline food here around my
waist but that will keep me in sentence
to keep my weight down this is a very
special time in icons history 15 you all
remember when you were 15 got your first
shaver here a boy somebody told you that
you're now going to be an adult and in a
way I think we're going through this
transformation as well that I can
together as a community we are taking
all the learnings from the last 15 years
and preparing ourselves for an important
future and so I'll find my clicker here
if you recall when we started we said we
have a new season and indeed it's been a
year a year ago I met many of you in
Toronto and you had asked me to start
this journey with you and it's been
quite a journey I'm an immigrant twice
first because my parents moved from our
native country to Lebanon where I ended
up having to learn to live in a new land
and then second time when I had to leave
as an adult to come to the United States
and learn again to integrate into a
community but now I'm an immigrant a
third time because when I arrived to
this community I did not know how strong
and deep this community is and I was
definitely an immigrant in your
community a year ago I didn't know what
to expect but I had the experience of
having been through an integration
activity before and I must tell you a
year on I'm feeling at home now thanks
to many of you
and it's a testament to you to the
beautiful empathy as Steve called it the
beautiful relationships many of you have
and there are so many in this room I
can't even start counting as I meet many
of you I find out how all interconnected
we are thank you for welcoming me to
this great community and I hope I'll be
able to serve it well in the years ahead
it's been a year and when we started I
told you that we need to get the ground
ready I think we're done with that face
we're starting our year two of the new
season and in the second year we're
starting to see these buds coming we're
starting to see the fruit that we will
hopefully reap in the years ahead start
sprouting and what does that really mean
so I'm going to take us a little bit on
a journey over the last year so we see
how far we've come together if you
recall we laid out in Toronto these four
objectives and the 16 goals under them
this was the roadmap we've set up so we
can go on this journey together in each
of these objectives we found projects
and we found initiatives together that
are needed to advance our program let me
walk you through these first affirmation
of purpose today core to our purpose is
getting our core activities of the
ground when I met a group of you that is
actually right here in front of me when
I started I asked if you remember vent
over that dinner and John I asked what
would be catastrophic a year from today
what would be a terrible thing for I can
a year from today and that at that
moment all the people that that dinner
told me make sure that this new detail
deprogram
gets off the ground if it doesn't not
only is it a problem for the gTLD
program it's a problem for the
credibility of I can today we can
celebrate the success the gTLD program
is off the ground in fact we have added
more new gTLDs to the route today then
all the gTLDs in the history of I can as
of today 24 new gTLDs and I love
watching them on the left of your screen
there in Arabic in Cyrillic and in
English and that's something to
celebrate all of us so congratulations
we have focused on the NSF not just
because my boss tells me that every time
I meet him dr. Crocker but because it's
important the NSA is central to the
stability and resiliency of our internet
and I'm very happy to let you know that
the biggest new TLD that was just sign
is China we just got confirmation so
congratulations to all of us and to
China our teams have been busy around
the world in trainings lots of capacity
building on DNS SEC and this is
important and we will continue this work
our policy work which is central to i
can has been progressing very well and
today i'd like to invite all of us to
change our posture about our
policymaking process and this and
jonathan robinson from the dns oh didn't
pay me to say this it is important that
we stop badgering our own PDP process it
works it produces results and the amount
of effort that our community puts in
making these pdps produce policy is
incredible multi-stakeholder bottom a
policy is not easy top-down policy is
hard this is much harder and yet we are
producing policy so let's stop being
defensive and instead celebrate our
policy machine it works it works
and our community the advice we've been
getting from the a lack thanks to the
energized a lack and the leadership of
olivier tremendous work and the
seriousness with which this work is
affecting our activities at the ward
thank you a lie thank you s sack thank
you as sack as well because s sack has
been very diligent in giving us valuable
advice we should celebrate all these
things i want to point out from this
slide also the important public interest
commitments if you recall this is now
like ancient history during the last 12
months we completed working with the
registries and the registrar's to
important agreements the ra and the Raa
are tremendous progress for i can and
for this community and within the
registry agreement we introduced the
concept of voluntary public interest
commitments which many registries made
477 registry agreements with public
interest commitments this is the new i
can the i can that knows that our
ultimate responsibility is to the
registrant to the user and that the
registries and registrar's are our
partners to deliver value to that user
this is the right posture and this is
the right approach and finally i'll
point out to you I can learn visit learn
doc I can org this is a new canvas we
created for any of us to actually learn
or to teach it's a beautiful new
platform and I want to frankly
congratulate a lack for being the first
part of our community to leverage the
new learning platform of icon and they
have used it this last week to actually
invite
anyone who wants to take leadership
training and to learn how we grow
together at I can we need to share our
knowledge share our experience anyone
can add the course anyone can take a
course all free or welcomed into the new
learn that I cannot work at the bottom
of the slide you see some of our work to
affirm our purpose together with our
partners you heard Steve Crocker invite
my colleagues who are steeped in the
commitment to the multi-stakeholder
internet governance and activities they
do and every time I meet to them I learn
more about the great work that goes on
in i sock in the regional registries in
w3c in the IETF and I had the pleasure
of going to my second IETF meeting in
Vancouver what a tremendous community
together we are and so I thank them for
welcoming me because I am the newbie and
learning all the time from them thank
you for welcoming me to the your
community we've done quite a bit
together in the last 12 months and i
look forward to do a lot more together
with you and finally on the IG ecosystem
the Internet Governance ecosystem is
important many of you have seen our
activities in the last few months and
said why is I can busy with this because
I can is not an island I can as part of
an ecosystem and the environment around
us affects us we have to be engaged it
doesn't mean we leave behind our
responsibilities it doesn't mean we
increase our responsibilities we have a
clear remit we have to stick to our
knitting and do it well but we have to
also be active participants in the
ecosystem and therefore we support the
IGF we will continue to support the IGF
this is central to the multi-stakeholder
success on a global level and we will do
everything we can to work with our
community
in one net the new platform the new
initiative the new dialogue that we
should all have in the months and years
ahead about the importance of the
multi-stakeholder model I go to our
operational excellence I remember
meeting some of the alumni's of the
board for a breakfast in Prague when I
was brought in to meet the community and
boy did they take me to task on
operational excellence Hagen is here he
was the leader of that pack telling me
focus on operational excellence I can is
not just reflected in its policy and its
commitment to its core principles but
also in its ability to deliver its
capabilities and its services so we did
and that was the part that was frankly
natural to me because that's our
background and therefore we created a
new division the global domains division
is a very important step forward in how
we deliver our capabilities and by the
way this was I didn't come to I can
thinking oh we need to create a division
some of our community members were
criticizing me one of you here in this
room wrote a tough blog about I can call
this Janice faced I called him and I
said let's sit down and talk why are we
Janice fast he said because it's hard
you have on one side this global domains
division and on one side you have to do
all these things purely bottom-up and
sometimes these things get mixed fix it
so I said would you help me he said yes
and the CC community immediately called
the meeting and invited us to help us
fix icons operations and we went for it
and we listen and we learn and we
created the GDD so thank you I know
you're here my to thank you very much
for helping me get through that
many in the registries were telling us
we need to get these delegations to go
fast we cannot wait months so working
with ayanna working operationally to
improve our processes we are now down to
a week instead of months to make these
delegations work it below very important
as the number of registries grows our
commitment to our communities to make
sure that as registries grow and sprout
around the world we have proper
emergency mechanisms to deal with
failures we have to e bros up and
running today contractual compliance
this was the third area many of you
caught me early on fadi contractual
compliance must report to you within a
month of me starting maggie reported to
me we tripled the size of that
department we gave them all the
resources they need and most importantly
we told them that they're not policemen
what they are are stewards of the public
interest they are responsible to make
sure registrant's are well served so
they can be tough through their work but
they also have to work with our
community to make sure all of us are
partners in serving the same end user
and I thank the steam for the great work
they've done in the last year many
people told us oh my are you ready to
contract hundreds of contracts the
numbers speak for themselves we have a
superb process systems and people now to
deal with contracting 960 applicants in
the last few weeks have been invited to
start contracting and we already signed
144 register agreements in weeks weeks
not months very big focus in this area I
want to congratulate iono for being the
first department that I can to pass the
he F qm commitment to excellence test
this took a whole year
of hard work to pass that test and we
did and we now are planning to take the
same level of excellence across all of
the other I can operations departments
the l root the L roof is now one of the
mo it is the most present truth on the
planet 146 instances in 71 countries
this is the I can one of the routes that
I can is managing though one route that
I can as managing and then on the
left-hand side I want to show the
system's we've implemented many of you
said operational excellence as you know
is process systems and people we needed
systems that I can all these systems on
the Left have now been deployed that i
can successfully and I've deployed CRM
systems before and some companies take
years to get a CRM system out we have
all these systems now deployed and
operational at I can i want to point to
cost management many of you have said I
can as a runaway budget well as we grow
as we fulfill our mission we need to
start implementing cost management
procedures and cost management systems
this is normal we don't want ICANN's
money to be spent ever unnecessarily so
we are adding number one a full
procurement department which we didn't
have so we can start managing our
spending in a structured way we're
adding cost management systems already
just using these systems and these
procedures we've reduced the expected
increase of our health costs
significantly from 12 to one point six
percent and we are doing the same in
translation through good planning and
revamped teams and streaming just at
this meeting we without losing any
quality as some of you can attest to our
translation we have reduced our
translation costs at this meeting
by two hundred twenty-one thousand
dollars this is cost management without
quality reduction and we will continue
to do that because that's our
responsibility to you the third of our
objectives was internationalization and
if you recall we came up with this idea
that we shouldn't have one headquarters
I can is global we should have three
headquarters so we do now since we
talked to you we have established legal
entities offices and teams in Istanbul
Singapore and of course in Los Angeles
we have moved the posture of I can from
being a us-centric frankly Los Angeles
centric organization to a global
organization in Asia we had one person
we will have 12 people by the end of
march in Africa we had one person in
Egypt looking mostly north now we have a
team led by Pierre and we're growing
across Africa and the same needs to
happen across all regions and we're
opening engagement centers Montevideo
Beijing geneve next this next month and
dr. Tareq Emma will be moving to Geneva
and leading our new team in the
engagement office in Geneva this is the
I can we want and I can that also builds
its planned bottom up I am extremely
happy to report to you that from the
first day we started we told our
engagement teams we're not sending you
to these places to talk we're sending
you to listen so that you can learn what
regions need and so we started six
regional bottom-up strategy meetings
these took hundreds of people that got
engaged in order for us to build our
strategies bottom up this is very hard
stuff I used to work for IBM where we
made a strategy at the top and then told
everybody how to do it here we had to
get everyone from the bottom up to tell
us not just I can
but also our partners everyone was
involved I saw the rirs everyone was
invited to tell us how to perform in
these regions the country partnerships
you heard today about kisa but a month
ago I was in New Delhi and we announced
the first DNS security research center
in the world in partnership with India's
largest research laboratory and we're
very glad to do that with the government
and the researchers in India one of the
programs that is very dear to me is the
fellowship program many of you here are
fellows right fellows can you stand up
welcome welcome and many of the fellows
from the last year our leaders this year
my count is five fellows have become
community leaders we grew the fellowship
program from 90 to 120 and I challenged
my team to get it to 200 as soon as
possible and make sure it serves all
communities across the world and all
stakeholders our meeting attendance and
the last year compared to the year
before went up by twenty eight percent
so we are seeing a growth also in the
people attending these meetings we
establish the speaker's bureau and we
this Bureau has been fielding not just
myself and our team but also our board
members and our community members across
the world we have reached 33,000 people
through our speaker activities in the
last 12 months and you can see the
breakdown by country one of the projects
i'm very proud of is the glossary
project some of you in the communities
came and told us i can has good
translation but the terms you use don't
fit for us what you use to describe the
internet or multi-stakeholder ism in
spanish is not exactly how we see it
locally so we listen and we immediately
started a bottom up groceries project
and the glossary is up and running and
it'll be on the icon website this week
in six languages glossary is built
bottom up in the regions so we all use
your language not the way we see it that
the way you say it my I can if you
remember was something we did because
many of you told us that the website is
very difficult to navigate I still think
it's difficult to navigate but what we
did in the meantime is created my I can
today my I can is the most successful
most used online tool of I can and its
history nine thousand registered users
are on my I can't today getting daily or
weekly briefs automatically generated
based on your interest
and the things you are phone and who is
that I can't org our newest website the
first time we start a new website at
launch in all six un languages so we
continue internationalization because
internationalization is not just about
numbers and facts internationalization
is about all of us understanding the
other person first and making an effort
to go to the other people to go to the
other regions and be part of their
culture be part of their understanding
and yes I'm someone mentioned that i'm
doing a lot of miles but that's the only
way we can be together and we can
understand each other and advance our
internationalization not by sitting in
my office in LA the last of the four
objectives was to evolve our
multi-stakeholder model and this is an
area that is much more delicate because
we love our multi-stakeholder model and
it is probably maybe the most
sophisticated multi stick governance
model that man has created it's the most
complex one as well the fear we have is
for that model to end up being not fully
inclusive we need to bring more people
to it so it doesn't become a model that
is comfortable for a few the legitimacy
of ICANN is in the ability of everyone
to participate in that model we lose
that we lose our legitimacy and so we
started a project called I can labs
hundreds of you participated this is the
first time in my 30 years software
development career where we're
developing software with hundreds of
people telling us how they want it in
real time literally in real time those
of you who have been on a can labs you
would go up you tell us what you want
we'd have coders coded put it up and
then you tell us
we don't like it and we killed some of
the experiments we enabled others and I
can labs has been producing some great
ideas why because these are the ideas
that the community wants in order to be
more inclusive and enable more people to
participate engage and make policy I
want to thank you for what you did to
help us and I can labs will continue but
here's the good news out of I can labs
we have developed now a number of
excellent applications based on your
specifications and they will be part of
the new I can website which we will
unveil in Singapore I had to preview and
it's fantastic because it's a website
built around you not around us it's
built around the needs of the community
and it has some very powerful engagement
and new applications to enable all of us
to participate so you will see it in
Singapore you've also heard that the ATR
t2 and here also during our meeting they
will be sharing a lot of their work has
produced their recommendations 12 very
important recommendations I must tell
you when i arrived at i can i had very
little understanding of this a TR t
think i knew there's a lot of activity
going and then i got a couple of calls
from many from people here in this room
and they said you have to pay attention
to this this is what gives you also
legitimacy you have to understand what's
behind this and then when we looked at
it we were rushed to start paying more
resources and attention to the core of
the ATR t1 recommendations and i'm happy
to tell you that during my first summer
at I can this was my number one focus
and we got all the ATR t1
recommendations completed as we promised
by the end of the year then we started
the ATR t2 effort and now we have their
12 recommendations
I want to assure you that no one needs
to explain to me the importance of this
anymore I know what it is and it's on
the top of my priority and these 12
recommendations which I think by the way
pack some incredibly important evolution
recommendations for us i will pay
attention to them my team will pay
attention to them but more importantly
all of us should pay attention to them
because if we implement them i can will
be a better and more legitimate
organization for the world of course the
growth numbers you can see for yourself
but I want to focus on our panels and
the ewg this is important many of you
and I'm not going to ask you to stand
we're not happy with the creation of the
ewg the expert working group that was
focusing on our directory services you
are not happy because you said that's
not bottom up why are you who are these
experts we're the experts why do you
bring another team and you say they will
come up with a solution but let me tell
you the idea here was not to replace in
any way shape or form our policy
processes was not to replace the work
that the community still needs to do but
it was a way for us to create some
knowledge that allows us to work
together and build solutions and the
same applies to the strategy panels many
people are asking why do we need these
strategy panels they're just new fresh
thought that comes together and produces
hopefully some input not output they
produce input to the community so we can
take it absorb it learn from it and
advance our work and I want to publicly
commend the expert working group because
they presented their progress yesterday
jean-francois Burrell who is sitting
here a friend of mine who I pulled into
our community as well and I asked for
him to leave this and the results of the
work as many of you have seen yes they
are stellar and they will help us
finally
move the directory services debate to a
new level of dialogue through our
processes not outside of our processes
same with the strategy panels and I want
to thank the heads of our for strategy
panels here today with us dr. vint cerf
from google all of you know him niqua
know who's leading our public
responsibility panel and professor Beth
Novak who's leading our
multi-stakeholder panel and Paul mocha
Petrus where are you momoka Peters the
inventor of the dns and the leader of
our fourth panel he's back there he
stood up happy birthday Paul birthday
today you may have seen yesterday we
announced the fifth panel the fifth
panel will be chaired by president
toomas Ilves the president of Estonia
and this is the panel that will look at
the Internet Governance side this panel
took a little more time to assemble but
it's a panel that will help us prepare
for the year ahead and give us some
solutions and some ideas that will shape
the Internet Governance debate in the
coming year I want to thank president
toomas yields who's an eloquent speaker
on multi stakeholders in fact some of
his speeches are quasi manifestos on why
multi-stakeholder ISM is the way forward
and I want to thank Vint Cerf for
agreeing in addition to his panel here
to also serve as the vice chairman on
the internet governance panel with
president toomas eels thank you vent and
also with us here are some of the
panelists on that there is Olaf cokeman
who's the past IAB chair he's probably
here somewhere in the room thank you
Olaf and we also have al in Santa more
the CEO of I sock Thank You Lynn for
agreeing to serve with us on this panel
and I will serve on this panel as well
which is the only panel of the five that
will be in partnership
with an educational institution and with
an international organization so the USC
University of Southern California
Annenberg Foundation as well as the
World Economic Forum the web have
partnered with us so we ensure that this
panel has some level of independency n
is functioning on a broader scale
globally so we welcome all five panels
they do not usurp who we are they
enhance who we are they inform us they
give us more input and we thank them for
the great work they're putting so this
is our model that all of you know and
this model will survive with us in the
next year and the year after that
there's a lot of work still to be done
so i'm going to share with you now what
I think we could have done better on
this in the last year I have not
achieved my goal in the area of
measurements I wanted a deeper set of
measurements on our success many of you
who come from an operational background
know how important metrics are we're not
done we have more work to do but by the
time we meet next year we would have had
a living set of metrics that allow us to
track every area of this model across I
can we have the beginnings of the model
but it didn't advance as far as I wished
so once it's ready and I hope sooner
than later i will share it with you and
it will be our scorecard it will allow
us to see how we're managing in a very
precise way another area we didn't do
very well I think last year is cost
controls and this is why I'm putting a
lot more emphasis on cost control this
here this doesn't mean we plan to reduce
our services and the quality of what we
do but this means when we grow from 125
people by next June to probably 300
people and our expenditures grow it
means we need to put in place cost
controls
this is very important this is an area
where I promise you next year we will do
better the third area where I don't
think we did as well as we hoped is the
website itself notwithstanding my I can
we did some few things to make the
website better but our team is very hard
at work to completely change the
experience of ICANN org and we are doing
it in consultation with the community
we're getting a lot of feedback through
I can labs and I promise you that by
Singapore we will have a whole new
experience at icon org lastly the fourth
area we didn't do very well at is the
area I promised to break the silos when
I arrived at I can it was very quickly
obvious to me we have a lot of silos
there were silos within my team within
the staff people were not coordinated
were not integrated there were silos
between the staff and the board this we
have addressed today within the I
canteen staff there are no Silas and we
did that not just by telling them talk
to each other but by creating for the
first time a cross-departmental project
management tool that allowed projects to
be worked at horizontally not vertically
across all of I can and this tool is
working and driving our activities with
the board we broke all the walls between
the staff and the board and there were
many when I first started the board had
a meeting in LA and I asked the board if
we could have our first lunch with the
whole staff and we started mingling and
staff members were asking me can we talk
to the board members yes you can talk to
the board members can can we exchange
ideas with them yes of course you can
exchange ideas with them this is how
difficult it was today we are completely
open and that's the only way to go
transparency and openness to break the
silos is
how we need to move forward some of you
may have seen that at some of the input
that I got from the community I moved my
own office at this I can meeting to the
hall it's completely open you can come
and visit me anytime but if I'm Anna
meeting allow me to just finish the
meeting but my office is outside
complete transparency this is something
I need to learn and continue to learn
because that's the only way in the icon
community in this multi-stakeholder
community I must tell you that as I look
forward to the next year I have two
things I want to tell you about next
year the first is that I understand that
the marrow of ICANN is our
multi-stakeholder nature that's our
marrow and if I don't live in that
narrow with you then we don't get there
you have my commitment sometimes it
appears that I'm not as committed to
that model but believe me the energy the
enthusiasm that I have is because of you
it's because of that model it's not
because of what I want to achieve it is
because of what you have invited us all
of us to do together that's my
commitment to you that's the marrow I
will not forget and I learn as I go I
learn and sometimes I speak my mind as I
learn and those of you who don't know me
well think that he's changing his mind I
just speak my mind as I go forward
that's my style and forgive me for it
but it's the only way for me to be
completely transparent and to show you
what I know and what I don't know one of
you sitting here in the front hit me
with a mallet to understand something
they are the day in Vancouver thank you
for that dress it was very helpful but I
learned something from that by listening
I learn and I my commitment to you is to
that is to that marrow we need to keep
it and the second commitment I make to
you is as we get busy next
here with internet governance that I
will not forget that what's most
important is to make i can continue to
perform on the things you've wanted us
to be work on together our i will not
get off the ball yes we will look at
internet governance and the environment
but our home first and that commitment
you have from the moving for i also want
to tell you that i've just added two
email addresses that i can for me
because many of you know that I get so
much email that somebody has to read it
and sift it and tell me something these
two new addresses come to me directly
you can use them starting tomorrow
morning the first one is learn from year
one things I can learn from my first
year things you've seen that I can do
better learn here one at I can or this
is yours to use and I will read them and
the second one is do year two things
you'd like me to do in the air too
please write me I do read and it's very
important for me to be one with you
because if we lose this unity we're not
going to do well united we have a tough
here ahead and that's the elephant in
the room that I haven't talked about yet
many of you are arriving here too when
Osiris to talk about what's happened in
the last three months what's been going
on we will talk about this no worries we
have plenty of sessions in the next day
a few days to talk about these are the
sessions where I will be there our team
will be there our partners from the I
start community will be there we're all
attending we're all participating we're
all listening together we should figure
out the year ahead so that elephant
should go away and instead it should be
our cause today I wish to tell you that
why we moved on this area in the last
few months is to protect I can
I can was under pressure to increase
what it does to make its remit larger
icons model of multi stakeholders was
under pressure and the Snowden
revelations didn't help because they
pushed more people to say we need
governments to govern the internet we
need to stand up for our model and
therefore what we did together with you
I star leaders was to energize the
process we didn't invent anything new
you've been working on this for years
all we did was to energize the process
and the energizing of the process is
going to lead us all to work together so
let's mobilize this is our moment in the
next 12 months and 24 months the world
wants to see us as one and how do we do
that so we propose to you one net what
is one net one net is a canvas it's an
empty canvas there's nothing on it bring
your pens and pencils and come draw on
it tell your stories you've had these
stories you've lived them they're not
our stories that they're your stories
one net is a place where all of us can
tell the world what we believe in we
believe in a multi-stakeholder model to
govern the internet we do not want large
centralized organizations we want a
network of nimble agile bottom-up
institutions write these stories let's
work together and let's make one net the
canvas on which we all tell our stories
I hope you have a wonderful week welcome
to I can't 48