so firstly I would like to introduce
lady Allen a Villanova she's my good
friend she is now in the u.s. can you
tell us where exactly where are you in
the middle of in the middle of the
desert next to Joshua Tree Park okay so
it's like it's Joshua it's California is
if I'm correct yeah or she doesn't want
to disclose because that was a very bad
okay so al anam she's a really respected
figure in encrypted community she was
the CEO of Satoshi Labs few years which
is a proc company responsible for a
building bit confessor now she is like
private consultant involved in many
different crypto project and she's also
adviser for many ICO project and she
cooperates with a lot of crypto people
and many different cryptic communities
unfortunately she couldn't come so this
is the reason why we just having like
this cat call and and then I would like
to introduce I'm not sure if I
pronounced your name properly Giacomo
Duke Oh perfect station and and Giacomo
Giacomo is Bitcoin maximalist at this
Congress you maybe maybe you have
noticed we have a lot of beautiful
maximalism sometimes think that is like
like mythical Maximus conference by the
way okay so and also libertarian he is
like a power guy as I know yeah
originally you finished physic physics
as I know electrical physics so and you
and Ilana created presentation and have
a high time just to leave
word so welcome here oh thank you thank
you very much so I will leave in turn
the voice to Elena to introduce the
first lights thank you by the way I'm
super sad that I can be there this year
with you guys I curse Congress is by far
my most favorite conference in the space
so saying hi to all my friends and hope
you enjoying so what we what we're
trying to convey the message that we're
trying to open and discussing with these
slides with Giacomo is that what is the
actual state of the market and
originally when we presented this in
Vega I was talking about how different
participants in the market see Bitcoin
are the needs and what we can do to to
you know improve the situation I was
mainly focused on the people outside of
Whitman because I believe we when we
join forces we can help bring in more
people from beyond Bitcoin to Bitcoin if
we you know improve on the messaging or
the user experience and so on but
because we opened the discussion and we
had a lot of different interesting
reactions I could also see that there's
a lot of different expectations inside
the community so let's let me dive like
just really quickly into the different
categories participants let's say by the
way these two slides that are following
or three slides are I was inspired to
structure it this way by melting the
mirrors and her previous you know
attempt to do something very similar
anyway developers so development in
Bitcoin I feel like it really sped up
especially after the sacred debate was
concluded and now we have a lot of
tremendous developments happening but
you know everyone who understands the
space
seize that there's still a lot to do and
getting more coders for Bitcoin I think
it's absolutely crucial especially you
know these are the big box in in the
code I think we need more code reviewers
I think we need more application
builders and eventually made even more
core developers so this is something
that I see that you know outside Bitcoin
developers are drifting towards some
permission block chains and I SEOs and
we are kind of losing out on a lot of
great power there investors is very
important you know participants in the
space tend to be and I'm trying to
figure out his like these tactical
investors that most we are after tokens
and quick returns that's fine then there
are hard type of visas that don't really
have the perfect understanding of
Bitcoin as technology and what it can
bring and there's they're following some
hives and then their strategic type of
investors that are natural Bitcoin alike
is because they tend to think making
long-term toddlers very important to
have them to kind of support to the
prize and support the entire ecosystem
there's gonna huddle but also they are
eager to see the moon and the you know
to to to support the price there has to
be more substance to it than just you
know riding the waves of trumpeting
bouncing and eventually even hard lers
want to get to a point where we don't
just hold on to the bitcoins but we kind
of use them traders they create volumes
that's fine but the real economic value
is quite to be inside
being Jack oh yeah please click next
thank you
I spent since I left my position as CEO
of treasurer last year I spent a very
decent amount of time traveling around
the world and going through all possible
blockchain and Bitcoin conferences and I
was I was quite sad to see that a lot of
companies are in the lead or they're
considering to for example issue
something and that in my opinion is
basically what I call a dump token right
which is just some smart assets and
representation of some sum of values
some of some value and they neglect be
why because they do not hear about the
capacities of Bitcoin they see er c20
they want to ideally built their own
block chains and I think that's that's
again a little bit waste of energy
and so there's a need in my opinion to
be more present and and communicate
clearly on what's possible to do today
on top of Bitcoin and then merchants and
small companies small medium sized
enterprise they believe that you know
mostly or not to believe they don't know
really why to the Bitcoin mean it's
either too nerdy or too volatile for
their business and they are not sure how
to do accounting there's a lot of
question marks about taxation in each
country of course this trend and then
the ultimate claim is why would we start
accepting Bitcoin if nobody wants
suspended yeah
and then influenced by influence suicide
me you know pop stars people who have a
lot of worship
and for me as a Bitcoin er I kind of
said to see them hyping things like
stable coins and other types of blogs
names and policy makers they're trying
to rule Bitcoin they are trying to
impose kyc and AML and all this kind of
blanket surveillance that for me you
know I'm very very opposed to to this
kind of approach because it just assumes
everyone to be a criminal by default
kyc is has been invented to kind of
patch the legacy banking system and to
prevent to prevent money laundering or
whatnot which is I think a failing
project but I don't think that is this
is absolutely necessary for Bitcoin and
I think the police may because she get a
real understanding of capacities of
Bitcoin and that KYC is not needed in a
transparent ledger like Bitcoin and this
is the most important target audience
for me your mom or my mom as I said you
know I was traveling a lot to us last
two years and every time I'm sitting on
a plane I'm trying to brain or someone
with Bitcoin but before I jump on that I
learned to ask what do you think about
Bitcoin and you know we understand to
live in a kind of bubble thinking like
everyone has to understand it's so clear
right it's so obvious
but then the media in the guarantee that
that has been pushed pushed for many
many years showing Bitcoin as the money
for criminals
is something that's important and
consumers too much energy all these all
these misconceptions are deeply engraved
in people's minds and we should we would
be foolish to close our eyes and expect
my mom to just go into her research so
yeah next slide please
so I was thinking what can I do about
that next slide thank you and I was
trying to define like what what can be
done what is needed to be done and found
certain important areas or defined these
yellow areas that I think we can focus
on but also the other ones that can be
definitely improved development of
Bitcoin is traditionally quite under
financed and even if there are private
investments and sure we can do a better
job on getting more developers
interested in Bitcoin I think we can do
a better job in having investors
understanding the capabilities and and
why they should support people with
their money of course there's never
enough security and and privacy around
Bitcoin we are working on that but we
can definitely into things like
usability of security I'll touch on that
a bit later
for merchants we have tools but we
expect businesses to to go and do quite
a lengthy and deep research in how to
get started with Bitcoin I think it
should be as easy as one-click you know
we need to we need to really focus on
early
emanating the friction that's there we
shall give some reasons to shield
Bitcoin to all these influencers and
make these policy makers understand that
bitcoin is not theirs to take they
Bitcoin it does not fit into any
specific brackets and cannot be you know
taking hostage by any legal framework
and most importantly my mom should
experience Bitcoin if experienced in a
lightweight fashion we may try to talk
us on a digestible messaging skipping
the technology is keeping the weirdness
and just having big homework no showing
like implementing the benefits or having
my mom in enjoying the benefits instead
of having to go to technicalities yeah
so this is where my story connects with
with Elena's consideration Elena was
already thinking about these these needs
these market needs and the best ways to
fulfill them my experience was basically
in the last three years concentrated in
the first two rows that that you see
there basically developers and investors
and corporation basically I was the
witnessing to a huge asymmetry in the
market you have smart Bitcoin developers
they are mostly underfunded they they
can go on to develop stuff not just a
the consensus a Bitcoin node layer which
is something that hopefully will go to
stabilize more and more over time so I
say something very provocative here I
think we will not need Bitcoin core
developers I hope we will not need
Bitcoin core developers in not more than
a few years but we need a lot of
developers for the stuff on top and
there was a serious problem of
underfunding why because the well
Bitcoin is is
open is so open-source peer-to-peer free
is so different from traditional
software stuff even in the free open
source sector that is very difficult to
find monetization hornist monetization
model in order to pay for the developers
let's imagine just a good Bitcoin wallet
so there is a good Bitcoin wallet you
cannot use intellectual property to
monetize because it's open source of
course you cannot use a login or a fee
extraction because since it's
open-source you can just copy it and do
another version without any kind of fee
or without any kind of advertising you
cannot sell the people's data like
Google Google does for a full Google
application because if you are creating
a good become wallet you are not getting
any of the data of the important data of
your of your customers so if there is a
problem to find it good models to find
to fund Bitcoin developer sure you can
scam some VC into investing in your
startup telling them that there will be
some kind of monetization later but that
usually never come and you can scam
retail investors in to buy your token
but that's not very nice and not very
honest and on the other side I was
seeing a lot of corporations a lot of
big banks institutions with these
innovation managers they were told by
their boss to do blockchain stuff or
crypto stuff but they after after a few
days have a few months they realized
that all these crypto high panels this
blockchain hype is basically just a coil
and so now they need something serious
to do and my attempt during these years
was to connect to try to to play some
arbitrage trick be in this market
asymmetry
what if guy I can take money from
institutional corporation and investor
use this money to donate to free
open-source development and use the
knowledge I get from these free
open-source development in order to
extract these corporations about how to
adopt serious technology a few example
you have to do something about
certification of documents scam solution
put your documents on your own
blockchain doesn't make any sense
reasonable solution keep your document
in your cloud system but use open test
stamps to time stamp for free every
document every every day that's
completely feasible or you are a Swiss
bank let's say broke let's use the
blockchain to manage the Swiss franc
accounts that doesn't make any sense
work
just use your centralized the legacy
accounting software to manage Bitcoin
accounts in behalf of your customers
that want to invest in Bitcoin this is
something that you can do so I try to to
use different approaches to this kind of
arbitrage first of all another question
that I want to be clear about I try to
be clear in Riga about this but I think
I was not very effective so let me try
to stress this a little bit more does
Bitcoin need any kind of effort we are
talking about my opinion is absolutely
not Bitcoin does not need this kind of
effort especially in the long term what
I think and what also Alain agree agrees
with me about is that other people is
not Bitcoin that needs these people
these people that needs to understand
Bitcoin sooner in an easy way if they
don't want to understand it later in a
more painful way
so does Bitcoin need a JavaScript
developer no does the JavaScript
developer need to understand what is
doing in order to not not waste three
years of his life learning solidity to
do depth and years and reputation and
instead maybe learn how to connect a
node.js application with a lightning
payment or with an open 10 stamps or
whatever that makes some sense other way
around does a Bitcoin need is which
investor to retain investor to be able
to invest one on one percent of his
portfolio location in Bitcoin no Bitcoin
doesn't care does a Swiss retail
investor need to allocate one percent in
Bitcoin
if things go in a certain direction yes
they do actually at least as an edge
they do so yeah it's not important for
chances of success in the long run I put
a question mark here he
but my clear answer is not we can you
can think about a scenario in which
Bitcoin success may depend of our
ability to market it like if we market
it hard enough but can we succeed if we
don't Bitcoin will fail but if this is
the scenario then Bitcoin has already
failed because there is no way that good
responsible tech aware form of realistic
form of marketing can ever keep up with
scamming are realistic snake-oil
promising
I mean bitcoiners can never be as good
as marketing as all corners all no
corners by definition of incentives also
because if you have to promote your scam
token your your your benefits from
promoting it will be very very large we
will never have the same kind of benefit
to promote Bitcoin because of the market
debt so we will not earn money by by
shilling Bitcoin so we will never be as
good as marketing so my point is that in
the long run Bitcoin has to succeed on
his own merit or it will just not
succeed and I think it will but in the
short run we can reduce a lot of losses
especially we can reduce losses of time
and money and brainpower there are in
there are millions of dollars spent by
big corporation in to do blockchain
research that those that money can be
used in to improve Bitcoin development
there is there are a lot of investors
try to to escape inflation of their
currency they are now driven to invest
in any kind of crazy psycho
the financial instrument they can
allocate something Bitcoin and get maybe
saved by the fallout of an IP
mechanization so we are not doing that
this because bitcoin is it but becoming
mostly Bitcoin because people outside
bitcoin right now need to be taught
about bitcoin in the good way in the
soft way in the gentle way before the
hard way arrives on its own so there are
different models to try to do the
arbitrage oh we're talking about so try
to take money from the big industry and
to put this money on open source
development these ways are basically the
model called hold and build order and
build this model as some pros like is
very decentralized you cannot that the
model goes like this by Bitcoin how to
Bitcoin make become better Bitcoin goes
up you profit this is working right now
many many people in this ecosystem they
are they are they are paying themselves
like this they they earned or mind or
both Bitcoin in 2011 now they are
working full-time Bitcoin because they
believe in it and because they know that
if they do a better Bitcoin I mean we
are still in the phase where one single
developer can make Bitcoin more useful
to people like think about the work of
Nicola Doria which participate one
single developer pista that bitpay
on Twitter can actually make bit-bit pay
obsolete and change the market now any
merchant can easily accept light in
transaction with BTC pay so you can buy
Bitcoin whole Bitcoin make Bitcoin
better is decentralized
nobody can heavily corrupt this kind of
effort is also a very aligned from an
incentive point of view is very nice as
incentives as far as status go but there
are some cons the first course is the
free writing basically yeah if you buy
and hold then you biddle then you profit
but if you buy and hold and then you
stay on your couch to watch Netflix for
3 years you still profit so there is a
lot of free running right here and the
second problem is long-term stability
are we assuming the
Bitcoin development especially
application on top is going to be
obsolete and useless in five years but
maybe five years from in ten years we
will be well above the iPad
mechanization curve and so the rise of
price cannot be cannot go on forever it
can go on for a long time but at least
let's say at least in some model the
price of Bitcoin cannot grow forever and
it will eventually reach a plateau even
a very high plateau so this model is not
very sustainable in the long run also
this is not working in the beer markets
like during the 2014 beer market if this
beer market is going to to last for for
some months this model doesn't work in
in those in those in those moments
redhot model so let's build a business
this business will sponsor Bitcoin
research and development open-source
everything will be released open source
upstream so we will contribute for the
community for free but in doing so we
are becoming the experts so my engineers
that are working on this open source
protocol they are becoming the best
engineers because they're working on it
they're building it so when I when
companies they want B to be to be
consulting or a customization or a
seminaries worship education any kind of
stuff that needs or reviews that needs a
lot of highly high skills and very
specialized skill you can sell that so
basically you sell B to B education and
B to B consultancy B to B customization
right like red hat basically does red
people they work on Linux they work for
free on Linux they release that they
maintain basically great part of the
Linux codebase and then they get a lot
of skills and knowledge and they sell
these skills and knowledge on the market
this is sustainable so I've done this
for three years we paid our rent and
food so this can work I I was taking
money giving money to free open-source
development getting information in
exchange and consulting companies with
this information it can work but it
doesn't scale the first conscious
you cannot do Syria there are a lot of
occasion in which my client where we're
actually available to donate an
important amount of money in order to
sponsor some kind of beacon development
but this kind of model is not it's not
enough to sustain this this arbitrage
also there are conflicts of interest
when you are a company and you are a
for-profit when you create something new
something fine something cool there is
always an interest to keep it keep it
secret
I mean if Red Hat employees discover a
very very cool kind of feature they
start to build some kind of code base
yeah they will release it upstream
because that's their ethics but there is
a conflict of interest there you you
have some it may be you do not succumb
to your conflict of interest but you
have it then there is the cognitive
dissonance I was personally very very
hit by this by this cognitive dissonance
basically you have a company you have
people working for you and a company is
supposed to make profit and instead you
take your profit and you give it away
for free to people doing other stuff
these people like developers you found
they are not really I mean they are not
really committed to your company your
company is completely disposable you
take money you have a lot of money you
give this money away you don't
understand if you are a non-profit or if
you have a for-profit when you face the
client you have to behave like a
for-profit so big bank I will not tell
you another word if you don't pay me
when you when you face developers your
your you're behaving like a like a dawn
or like like some kind of of
philanthropic entity and that's that's
very difficult to coordinate especially
from accounting point of view this model
I don't want to say that this model
doesn't work if you think about this
this is basically the model of many very
important Bitcoin startups basically
every startup in Bitcoin that doesn't do
exchange fees or hardware and any other
form of profit is this way so I always
lighten Network so far making revenue
always blocks for him so far making
revenue so maybe they will
I'm the product like liquid etc right
now this is the model of the best and
most legit Bitcoin companies so I don't
want to I use this model for three years
but is really not scalable that it has
some kind of complexities so there is a
third model the thermal is the Linux
Foundation model so you have a
foundation instead of having having
these conflicts of interest you don't
have the company directly managing the
sponsorship of the free open source
development you have the company taking
the money for profit keep it the morning
for profit giving away the money to the
stakeholders so behaving like a
for-profit company but for convenience
when it convenient this company and
other company they will all donate to
the Linux Foundation and the Daily News
Foundation will manage the governance
and the evolution and the maintenance on
the open source protocol so the goals
are clear there is no cognitive
dissonance it's very clear there is no
conflict of interest because you're
removing the conflict of interest
insert inserting a new intermediary but
there are some cons the first is the
centralization especially political
centralization there is just one Linux
Foundation this one Linux foundation can
be used in order to month to attack
Linux basically in order to insert
malicious codes in Linux is I'm not
saying that happening but it could
happen recently some very strange stuff
is happening basically right now the the
Linux Foundation managed to basically
fire leanest or Wald about some kind of
social justice water conduct code
something that's probably not very
dangerous right now but as a tendency
can be used as a vector of attack so a
foundation is centralized and fragile
you can easily compromise it you can
easily buy it or or blackmail it or sub
P Knight
you could lose the transparency there is
a there are a lot of cases of nonprofit
foundation where money comes in when you
are a business you are accountable to
your stakeholders so every penny that
enters or every Satoshi that enters you
have to account it for a accounted for
what are you doing to improve the
that basically the value of the company
with a non-profit that's not the case
and so that creates a lot of lack of
transparency and basically the
Lamborghinis are multiplying every very
very often in very very short time and
they lose focus if you don't have a
market to aggress by you're just donate
receiving money and donating you tend to
lose focus and to the and to really lose
your focus in the long term and also
there is a huge terrible legal overhead
you are you have to prove that your
nonprofit that you are not giving away
dividends so there is a lot of legal
overhead here so none of this model is
it's perfect but basically what we try
to do is to try to create a model which
is not known on the above it's a little
bit new we are trying to avoid the
centralization of the Linux Foundation
by not explicitly not having anything
which is directly connected with the
development of the of the Bitcoin
protocol itself but mostly connecting
with education and user experience or
stuff on top that cannot be easily used
to influence the underlying code it will
it will be based on a get up style okay
so this is the model basically so clear
focus so we try to avoid the focus the
focus loss in the in the long run the
idea is to fall to fund stuff about
Bitcoin and and lighting Network which
for me is still Bitcoin just just
another layer ization of Bitcoin the
idea is to have a very simple website
then we'll match donors and projects
with a hierarchical tree so this is in
order to avoid the transparency loss
over time instead of having an approach
give us all your money and we will take
care of it which can work very well at
the beginning but it tends to
deteriorate over the years or even the
months we will try to match some need
from the market to some need from the
developers more directly we will build
or we will we will accept requests to
build of course we decentralize the comb
this is not a decentralized effort so in
order to cleric clarify this this this
effort is not decentralized it will be
very centralized because anything that
has to work on small-scale and fast has
to be centralized centralization is
fragile but is efficient so we will
create of course listening to a lot of
external feedback a tree a article tree
or project and we will expose this real
project in order to investors to be able
to donors to be able to donate to their
projects the advisory board that will
include a lot of people from the Bitcoin
community not really a lot of developers
not really a lot of businessmen but
mostly people in a little bit in between
who was watching the presentation in
Riga they know some of the names some of
the faces the idea is a class of people
which is some someone has a mine between
the the business approach the
consultancy approach and the technology
that they can at least the vet
technology in order to to to filter
projects the idea was would be to to use
this board in order to keep the tree
clean so everybody will be free to
propose a new project to sponsor so you
have your project you can go on the
website and propose your project to
sponsor but it will not be immediately
listed on the website the board will try
to put heat in the right ordering a
merging redundancies avoiding spam so
there will be some kind of cover of hard
governance in order to not let this tree
to become chaotic an entropic and all
the discussion about which project to
accept which project to not accept which
project to where to divert funds like if
you donate to let's say open ten stamps
but there are three tasks under opened
an stamps and we have the we advisors
the reviewers of that branch they will
have the privilege to select where the
money are going inside opens and stems
development so every discussion of this
kind will stay on get on get up
basically in order to be able to to be
transparent as long as possible this is
an example but I'm running late so I
will not I will not focus on this
example so I will I will leave this
light too
to Elena and in order to represent you
the legal structure and then in the last
minute I will talk it a bit about who
are the people involved here and what
what has been the reaction so far by the
community which I think it was very very
interesting so let's go well you know
with this Thank You indeed so we chose
Liechtenstein as the place to to create
the the structure just because the
government is extremely Bitcoin savvy
and Bitcoin friendly and supportive and
also their their legal environment and
allows us to create a mixed type of
foundation which is charitable and
commercial and I'll touch a little bit
on that the governance of the foundation
is very quite simple and quite almost
linear I would say there is a legally
required Council that you know is
responsible for doing the accounting and
keeping everything keeping us away from
jail and then some executive team
director and maybe some assistant to
make everything happen but basically the
majority of the participants in the
governance of this structure will be a
non-paid Board of Advisors for in terms
of donorship or donors that we accept I
said every money is good money except
for the state stolen money or the tax
money I believe and I'm happy that that
Giacomo and others basically basically
agree that we don't want to support
violence and violently taking money so
this is basically the only hard-coded
rule and we will accept any other types
of funds and I'm circling back to the
charitable and commercial structure I
personally don't believe in purely
taking and giving so that that's very
short and it
Circle and so I think we need to make
every effort and this is not just around
the P but every single effort in Bitcoin
should try to be sustainable unless it
has a short-term purpose and so this
this type of mixed foundation allows us
to not just distribute funds to the
projects that need to be funded but also
to invest to own parts of commercial
activities that in the mid term and long
term will feed back the monster as I say
with new funds and you can imagine that
for example the beef will finance
development of a game that will be sold
or a merchandise that will be it's all
these kind of activities that will help
get more funds into the into the basket
and I don't know why it's like okay
nevermind so we can we can skip that and
basically talk about priorities for
decent next year and then touch on the
reactions and the communication that has
been a very life since our announcement
for this year we would we want to focus
basically on just like the boring
establishment stuff being fully
operational setting up implementing the
donation workflow and raise funds so
next year in 2019 we can move forward to
start to financing actual RMP could you
please Giacomo click through to the next
slide so I can see thank you and these
are these are goals that that I wanted
to give you as example so you can see
what we want to do what one of the first
things I want to focus on is getting
more developers allow
the first touch with Bitcoin with some
ideally some scalable solution because
we have people that are training their
developers such as you know Jimmy Sun
who does an incredibly great job but
it's not scalable he can only train as
many developers as he can so what I
would like to do is find partnerships
and create maybe some online workshop
just to allow people to get the first
touch and then just let them loose and
trust individually Chris they will know
what to do next right I feel that we
could do a good work in the banking
summits for for the media developing
some very light when it may be even fun
ways to interact with Bitcoin for people
that are outside of Bitcoin so as you
see a lot of the focus is not towards
current current ecosystem that the focus
is really to to attract and to speak to
people who haven't had the chance yet or
didn't think it's worthy to actually
look into Bitcoin we want to donate at
least 1 million dollars towards research
and development that supports privacy
smart functionality on top for Bitcoin
ok before the before the last slide
there was a we we had changed this
presentation actually but probably we
have the the old version here and the
presentation was changed in a way that
he didn't have the famous faces anymore
so what happened is that when a mean
Elena started to discuss this stuff we
were also in discussion with a lot of
people with the same kind of problem
people that wanted to somehow help the
industry to adopt a Bitcoin good
practices and use some kind of these
financial flow in order to support the
free open source development and these
people were all very interested in these
and so they decided to help to manage
this donation the idea is that if this
donation will be
and coming with a good rate we will not
have the time to assess the project to
decide which project was there and so
the idea was to involve all the
important players of the ecosystem that
are also trying to to take money from
the industry and put the money in these
kind of priorities the effect was to
have a lot of famous Bitcoin people in
the same place and this effect are
basically triggered a lot of reaction
from the community I decided to play on
that situation too showing a slide which
was very similar to an ICO advisory
panel it was of course a play but it
didn't it didn't go very well so
basically what what we witnessed in the
last week since Riga is in my opinion
something we shoulder discuss in just
five minutes because it's extremely
interesting for the ecosystem basically
we said bit corners we are game we are
going to take a lot of money and
donating it no profit to Bitcoin
developer development and we have been
basically best as the number one danger
to Bitcoin and that wonderful I think
that's beautiful the slide I wanted to
replace to replace that visor a board
slide with one of the reason I'd want to
show the faces anymore is of course
because I we didn't want to really give
the effect that we need to show
important faces in order to to to I mean
to be attention seekers we did that was
not the effect that we wanted to have
just the we wanted to let you know that
there are people in the industry that
has the same set of problems and the
kinda fun interesting the same set of of
solutions also the the reason I don't
want to use the slide anymore is that it
doesn't express very well the way that
these advisors will interact with the
project the way in which these famous
advisors will interact with the project
is purely technical you can go on get we
will never show them face again in our
presentation you go on get up you see
what kind of workflow is for various
project and you will probably see the
github account or some someone very
who's deciding helping hard to decide
where some money will flow or where it
would not flow so you go there you see
the famous names we were not going to do
to to brag about the names anymore but
those today I want to put there a a
beautiful picture that unfortunately we
don't have in this version of the
presentation with the new hat by Rodolfo
Novick
the no foundation hat donate by Hodel as
a representative of the reiation by the
community the rationale has been great
in my opinion
first of all Bitcoin has to be bit
corners have to be adversarial they have
to use adversarial thinking if something
can look as a threat you should look and
you should call it a threat bitcoin is
not run on kindness and beacon it's a
serious adversarial system we will have
bad actors trying to attack Bitcoin
using centralized companies and
Association and foundation that apparent
in the past that will happen in the
future maybe they will it will happen
with new very good faith experiments
that they will be hijacked by external
interests in order to damage Bitcoin so
centralization is dangerous I don't
think it's dangerous for Bitcoin if you
remember what happening with the 2x
attack is that basically 90% of the
aschen power and almost all the Silicon
Valley companies try to attack Bitcoin
together and they failed Bitcoin one and
they failed and lost their reputation
hopefully for a very long time so right
now I mean if you have Jeff guarding
attacking Bitcoin you you are not going
to see Bitcoin bleeding but Jeff
bleeding so that's good and that's also
guarantee for us but I'm also happy
because this is a it is also our
insurance policy basically if we will
ever be pushed about doing something
that is not very good some compromise if
we are pushing a good Bitcoin wallet
open source become wallet with some kind
of privacy feature in and somebody is
pushing us to take the privacy feature
out
is very good to have a plausible
deniability some along the line of I
mean look I cannot
we are always under attack at these
crazy bit corners they are always
thinking about something bad I really we
are our hands are tied the community can
keep the community of Bitcoin fanatics
can keep every kind of effort in place
also I would like to praise the
aesthetic and and the trollish value of
the reaction of the community after few
minutes an account called the Debbie SS
or the was created promoting
the foundation and then there
was like that no foundation offered all
fund and there was the a foundation
mocking our effort with etherium kind of
of language so it was very very funny I
think the best quality of trolling that
you can find around the market you can
find it in the Bitcoin community I'm
super pleased about the trolling we
suffered and and I look forward for a
lot of other trolling so finally and
then we closed okay I can go directly
you can follow the the B foundation on
Twitter we discussed it about after the
reaction of the community we discussed
so this is a this is an internal news
that I'm spreading right now for
transparency we debated internally for
two weeks basically about changing the
name because this one was too much
triggering and then we decided to follow
the internal democracy and we took three
days to decide how to vote and two days
to Doctore vote and then the B
foundation won so basically we're back
to where we started so that that's the
Twitter handle and right now Elena until
the elixir stein foundation is not
incorporated Elena will act for as a
proxy of the very first good fate small
please donations small because if you
donate two million Elena's going to have
a lot of legal troubles so you can you
can ask us directly if you want to make
a bigger donation or you can send money
here and
and I mean just follow Elena on social
network to to see if she changes her car
or not so you understand what happens
with the funds yeah I publicly pledged
it anything that arises that QR code
that address of course forward to the
Foundation's wallet I have I must say I
was happy about the response and the
willingness of a lot of people to
support this not not just philosophical
ad and not just by doing you know
creating scholarships and creating like
educational programs in marketing but
also really by money I just was crypto
Springs conference where some big
supporter came to me and handed over his
donation on an open time which I think
Rodolfo would be super happy about so
please keep the potential donations if
you want to donate now and small terms
like really under under $1,000 and if
you want to donate a million write to us
to these emails and we'll take care of
that okay I think we have time for a few
questions or no sure that we don't have
any time for questions girls thank you
very much for the talk and if you want
to discuss this stuff with Jacomo you
can catch them okay Jim today or
tomorrow during the conference you saw
the email addresses of of both Alanna
and Giacomo so write them an email in
ten minutes the gold coin auction starts
in Slavonia
in la fábrica so if you are interested
in buying this gold coin with Ross
Ulbricht
come to Savannah and after the gold coin
auction we have a party in la fábrica
with live music live music performance
and tomorrow we start the same way as
today I think we open at 9:00 and the
first talks should be at 1:00 p.m. so
see you at the party see you at the
auction see you tomorrow
enjoy the evening enjoy guys I'm jealous