so we're going to be talking about the
title of my talk is smashing Bitcoin for
pain and losses basically what we're
gonna be going through is some pretty
fun stuff so we're gonna talk about what
what threat modeling is and why we
should do it we're gonna talk about why
Bitcoin matters and that's related to
the human threat model so just to give
you guys a little bit of background
about a year ago I got interested in
Bitcoin for the first time I had a
pretty extensive background in software
security and then Austrian economics so
it didn't it didn't take much once I
actually focused on it to realize it
wasn't pretty incredible but the way
that I did that is I produced the threat
model for Bitcoin and then I immediately
produced the threat for what I'm calling
the human threat model that shows a lot
of the implications of Bitcoin if it
actually works
so it will reference that a little
throughout the talk we're going to talk
about the skeleton Bitcoin threat model
the threat model is it too extensive to
cover in 45 minutes so I'm gonna give
you basically the bones of it the
structure which is the most important
really then from there go and we're
going to talk about some of the fun
attacks Bitcoin has suffered to date
over the last few years also a couple
recent attacks and then some attacks
that I see coming on the horizon so it
should be should be pretty entertaining
you can hang with me for the first part
that will be a little bit more
entertaining towards then okay
so threat model everybody is a security
design analyst unfortunately very few
people are systemic so there's a lot of
people that are very active on Twitter
and if you if you ask them about
anything they'll they'll basically
create a rough draft of the threat model
right but bitcoins first real systematic
and formal threat model was only
completed a year ago and we're actually
nearing the tenth anniversary so it's
kind of this weird
it's this weird dichotomy every single
conversation about bitcoin is basically
a threat model brainy brainstorming
session
but what it lacks is the follow-up
discipline it lacks the systematic
documentation and organization and I
think that part of the reason for that
is that it's not even fashionable and
academia anymore or pop culture it used
to be if you were an expert in any field
you would write a treatise and then
people would recognize that you had the
ability to systematize everything in a
in a given field that's really not even
that common anymore so systemic thinking
as a whole is kind of out of fashion but
throught modeling is still a really
critical thing to do
it really got popular in the 1950s but
really every large software company
today that has anything that they really
care about securing does a threat model
so we really should do that more in the
open source software community and
something like Bitcoin specifically
especially given its complexity really
deserves that so what is threat modeling
or what are the advantages of threat
modeling well one is that and this is
really the most important slide so if
you can if you can hang with me through
this it'll like I said I'll get more
entertaining and more of a narrative and
more specific but this is really the the
most important stuff it's probably the
least titillating but it's the most
important so one of the great things
about any kind of systematic analysis
and especially with threat modeling is
that it traps our mind in the truth
for example if bitcoin is a mission to
create a global money then it follows
that all altcoins are an attack that
might seem like a leap but it's really
not if you know what money is and you
know what's going on so so even if you
know even if we would have a tendency to
think a certain way
threat modeling basically constrains us
and forces us to see things that we
would rather not see it also exposes our
oversights so for example if Bitcoin
cash is an attack then how do you end up
categorizing things that you like like
Manero
grin or even litecoin to escape that
categorization the structure itself and
when you document specific criteria
categorizing things makes it much more
difficult to just be swayed by you know
a popular guy or somebody that's likable
um and that's it that's a huge advantage
especially in something like you know
digital cash and it also along those
same lines corrects our prejudices and
it reveals a lot of surprising and
profound truth so for example and this
is a reference to the human threat model
if people are enslaved because it's
profitable and Bitcoin makes it less
profitable to steal from people then it
could potentially you know logically
bring about the end of human slavery now
that's that's certainly not something I
expected to find when I started working
on the threat model but that's not
totally uncommon for systemic thinking
systemic thinking often has really
strange outcomes so for example systemic
thinking about the speed of light it
created a lot of shocking like truth
traps right where the conclusions that
you had to come to to systematize the
topic that you were thinking about
we're very disturbing and weird but but
that's the value of it right that's
that's the benefit we we don't really
want as much freedom when we're trying
to think clearly and then it also
accelerates learning quite a bit so I
have been around Bitcoin for a year and
but people have accused me of you know I
must have been around before that
because because I couldn't have either
written the threat model or come up to
speed so quickly and in all fairness
like I said some of that is because I
had a background in software security
before I got interested but really in a
way it's more extreme because I pretty
much learned everything that I know
about Bitcoin within the first six weeks
I mean everything else has been
and a lot of that is because I went
about it in a very logical and
systematic way and the last thing that I
want to sort of convince you guys or
sell to you guys about threat modeling
is that it encourages logic when you're
trying to put something together that's
structured and systematic you can't like
I said you don't have as much freedom
but it really emphasizes the logical
connections to things and you'll see
that as we go through a little bit more
and the reason that's important is that
logic is it's just a better way to find
truth than anything that we have
available and and I think the easiest
way to convince you of that is just to
explain that or just to point out I
guess that logic is required for all
thinking so if you were doing historical
analysis
you still have to use logic but on top
of that you have to analyze a bunch of
historical data and hopefully you're
getting the right documents and you're
putting them together in the right order
but if if all you're doing is pure logic
right then then your your your
conclusion is self-evident so for
example two plus two equals four that's
true by definition just by the
definition of two and by the definition
of four there and there's no external
data required so there's a lot of
reasons that logic is our our best
friend when we're trying to find truth
but well one of the easiest to get at is
just to say you always have to have
logic and there's room for errors there
certainly but once you once you move
away from the more you move away from
logic and the more you go to something
like historical analysis or psychology
or really any other area of human
thought you you have all the potential
to make the errors in logic but you also
have another set of potential errors so
when you can stick with logic you're
you're better off and when you can
emphasize logic in your thinking you're
better off
but it's it's kind of painful I mean
it's it's laborious in a sense and I
think in a way the reason that I've
structured this talk by showing you guys
the bones of it and then going and
looking at specific tax part of the
reason for that is it's a little bit
more exciting and a little bit more
interesting it's a little bit more
it's it's got a little bit more of a
narrative to it right like you don't
want to sit down and read a novel that
has a super structured table of context
you want to you want to read something
that's fun and interesting and
unexpected and so I've kind of
compromised a little bit in the talk but
you can't do that in something like a
threat model it forced your very logical
and systematic and start with sort of
first principles but it's worth it and
the reason that it's worth it is that
that Bitcoin is pretty profound I didn't
expect I didn't expect it to be
something that was anything other than
maybe an interesting investment I
started Lowell but say I can tell you
that it has really incredible potential
a modern slavery and I know a lot of
people hate when I use the term slavery
because they think of racial slavery or
chattel slavery but slavery in and of
itself is just recurring theft and we
have a lot of different forms of human
slavery today that are on the board if
you want a systematic analysis of that
seem a human threat model but Bitcoin
really does have the potential to end
all of it by itself now it's possible
that it will only eliminate like legal
tender slavery but that's more than
enough to justify a very careful and
systematic analysis of it and I actually
think it's going to do more than that I
think that it's you know the modern
forms of slavery are really a house of
cards and Bitcoin and of itself could
could be the you know the the Achilles
heel of the whole thing but either way
even if you're just considering
investing in Bitcoin you know it's worth
the systematic look so a quick overview
of the of the bones or the structure of
the Bitcoin threat model so when you're
doing a threat model one of the things
that's challenging is right off the bat
in the beginning you have to decide what
it is you're trying to secure and when
it comes to companies it's pretty easy
because you have shareholders and they
want to they want to you know have a
profit and you have products
and so what you're really trying to do
is you're trying to secure a product but
only because you're trying to secure the
future revenue of shareholders but when
you're doing something like open source
software development or an open source
project and you're trying to threat
model that it's it's a challenge because
you can't say that you can't say this
open source software project is a is a
repo or a set of code because it's
changing all the time it's not it's not
a set of contributors right because it's
very porous people are moving in and out
all the time so really I think open
source software projects are missions
and if you look at something like my
sequel my sequel is a mission to create
a good sequel database and no matter how
much they change that over time or
replace elements or you know completely
re architected possibly it's still it's
still a mission to create a decent
sequel database and Bitcoin is the same
way except it's a mission to create a
secure money and what I mean by a secure
money is money that can't easily be
stolen through inflation or through
extortion
so then the question becomes and the
reason that I'm going into this is that
if you if you accept any of these
premises the conclusions are really
broad and profound but the premises
themselves are really really
straightforward right
so if you if you don't agree that
bitcoin is a mission to create secure
money you're not gonna agree with
anything that I say throughout the
entire threat model but if you do then
then your universe of truth just shrank
drastically right the number of things
that are good ideas are much smaller and
that's not a bad thing because it allows
you to it allows you to avoid a lot of
frauds and facts and scams and things
that would distract you from being
productive which is our goal in learning
right figure out how the universe works
so that we don't we don't hit the
buttons that smack us in the face so so
if you agree that that's the mission of
Bitcoin then the question becomes what
is money if it's a mission to create a
secure money and this is this is another
sort of huge leap that will depending on
whether you go right or left on this
will put you into a very different camp
when it comes to Bitcoin so money is an
item that's used by a group of people
that trade together to make trade easier
I don't have time to really support that
argument or justify it but what I will
say is check out the book human action
by Ludwig von Mises or really any
Austrian economics book it's going to
it's going to cover this at in some
length because it's very very
fundamental to economic science is to
understand what money is and that has
implications because if it's one thing
then and it is one thing it's a it's a
thing that a group with people that
trade use to lubricate trade and make
things easier then attempts to create
multiple of those things is not it's not
helpful to the mission at the very least
so those were those were two big sort of
decisions going into the threat model
that affected the direction of it quite
a bit from there it was really just
another threat model and when you do a
threat model one of the things that you
have to do is
take the system that you're looking at
in this case Bitcoin and and basically
break it up and look at it look at it in
sort of its its major elements so with
Bitcoin you can pretty cleanly Blake
break it into software in humans because
humans are required to be note operators
miners investors they they they have to
accept Bitcoin as merchants they're
developers and then they manufacture
hardware so if you look at if you look
at Bitcoin as as the human component
that's required to support the software
and then the software itself it's a
pretty logical way to break it in half
and then on the software side you know
the software is doing a few different
things it's it's creating transactions
it's broadcasting them it's confirming
them and then observing them and then
what you do is you for each one of those
major components you just think of the
different ways that you could break it
so what are what are the things that we
could do to humans that are operating
nodes that would prevent them from doing
the function that they have to do in
order to keep things running if you want
to see the full threat model please do
even if you just look at the table of
contents it'll give you a pretty good
sense of of kind of the universe of
attacks that are that bitcoins facing
but like I said I can't cover it in this
talk but I definitely encourage you guys
to take a look at that but that said we
can cover some fun groups of attacks so
you guys you guys have sat through the
hard part of the talk now we're gonna
get to kind of look at some fun things
that have happened and yeah I think
this'll this'll this will be interesting
so although I am looking for your
questions on the first part because this
is really this is really the heart of it
the whole operation making those logical
connections and coming to coming to some
pretty profound conclusions but some
noteworthy attacks and to some degrees
the the fools that attempt them so one
of those sets of attacks that bitcoin is
based over the last
has been block size increases
everybody's probably to some degree sick
of hearing about it
but but it is interesting because it
goes back a lot further than I thought I
did when I when I started getting
interested in Bitcoin and heard about
segue to X there was Bitcoin unlimited
there was Bitcoin XT so there have been
a lot of people that have been trying to
introduce basically UNH's you know in
securely large or unsafe blocks that are
dangerously large let's say and
fortunately all of these guys have
invested considerable time and money and
reputation and and they all failed
another set of attacks the bitcoins
dealt with is spam attacks and empty
blocks so from about 2017 or 2015
through 17 and this was probably to
justify block size increases from what I
can tell based on the rhetoric that was
used when I'm looking back and trying to
kind of analyze these things
historically a little bit it looks like
based on the timing and the rhetoric
that it probably was to justify a larger
blocks but the great thing about bit
model or Bitcoin is that all of the or
the security model of Bitcoin is that
attackers are not prevented from
performing attacks it's not the it's not
the way that Bitcoin tries to secure it
stuff there just simply impoverished to
the to the degree that they they attack
Bitcoin and they're financially rewarded
to the degree that they you know do good
things to keep it up and running and in
functioning so as a result of these
attacks the block rewards were or the
attackers were the attackers were
impoverished right the block rewards
were smaller to the degree that it
reduced the Bitcoin price so the miners
get rewarded when they find a block if
the miners are doing things that attack
Bitcoin it probably didn't help the
Bitcoin price and so it probably didn't
help their mining rewards or at least
our block rewards and then the mining
fee is the other thing that rewards
these guys were also lost because the
attackers mind empty blocks or they
mined loafie transactions or No Fee
transactions and a lot of these the
times it looks like it was actually
their own transactions that they were
mining so they were paying their own fee
which is not which is not very rewarding
and and at the same time they were
ignoring higher fee transactions so they
definitely left money on the table in
that regard
also mining Hardware was less valuable
at least in the degree that the Bitcoin
price was reduced there was less demand
for people to buy mining hardware in
mine and in hindsight were pretty sure
that the bit main played a pretty big
role in this they're a manufacturer and
also a miner and if they were spamming
or mining empty blocks it certainly
didn't help their hardware sales and
then there's a couple other things that
are interesting out of this one is that
it encouraged premature optimization
like lightning and patching had they not
done this attack it wouldn't it all
surprise me if Bitcoin fees would be
around 25 or 50 cents maybe even $1.00
per transaction right now but because
they pushed it to such an absurd
situation where all the businesses were
really damaged if they weren't ready to
do things to really reduce the the size
of transactions it encouraged premature
optimization so that has not been good
for them and it opened the door pretty
wide for the crap coin narratives all of
the scaling coins came out of this or at
least were were significantly bolstered
by a and and that's not gonna be good
for Bitcoin miners as well
because again it's gonna affect the
Bitcoin price so in hindsight you know
this may have been a reasonable risk if
they thought they could completely get
control of Bitcoin and they were gonna
own you know the have a monopoly moving
forward on global money but they didn't
and they couldn't have so it was a
pretty pretty foolhardy effort
this next attack is a little bit more
interesting the asic boost attack so
basically what this allowed was
attackers were able to fake the amount
of work that they are performing but if
this attack did suppress the market
price like knowledge of the attack maybe
insider knowledge and there was when we
had the recent bug that was disclosed
people were very shocked that the price
of Bitcoin actually went up
it could be uncorrelated it could be
unrelated but a lot of times when you
see a price go up after bad news it's
because there were a lot of people that
knew about it or there was some insider
knowledge of it and that was affecting
the price I'm not saying it was in that
case but was something like ASIC boost
if there were no hundreds or thousands
of people that knew about it and
considered it a possible problem and
they were invited vies unveils on what
was going on with Bitcoin it's very
possible that that it negatively
affected the the price of Bitcoin and
actually since it seems that protection
of this ASIC boost security flaw was the
big motivation the big driver for
creating Bitcoin cash even if this
particular attack was profitable at
least for a bit main it looks like all
of those profits were consumed in the
next failed attack
which was Bitcoin cash so from what I
want it was clear that with 2x was going
to fail be cash was sort of the fallback
attack and be cash was a combination of
three different security flaws
introduced into a copy of Bitcoin so the
first two the dangerously large blocks
and the transaction malleability bugs
these were bugs that the second one was
actually just introduced into Bitcoin
innocently in early days of development
and the first one the dangerously large
blocks is that flawed that that
attackers had been trying to get into
Bitcoin for a long time so those two
were part of past efforts in a sense to
protect the second one and to introduce
the first one the the crazy insecure
difficulty adjustment thing that seems
like it was kind of a last minute bonus
but the result was that miners were sort
of in a similar way to ASIC boost they
were able to get rewarded
disproportionately to how much they were
actually securing the network and that
was because they were able to just not
mine wait for the difficulty to go way
way down then mine rapidly and get a ton
of Bitcoin cash and then rinse and
repeat and that went on for quite a
while the end results is that a lot more
Bitcoin cash was issued than would have
been otherwise to miners and in general
I think this this attack was at least in
the United States it seems to be
primarily targeted the tech illiterate
libertarian community I've been really
surprised over the last few months at
how many how many radio stations and
libertarian folks media outlets are
accepting Bitcoin cash and that's
because there was a campaign to go out
and attract these people to make deals
with them to offer matching donations
whatever it took to get them to be
excited about Bitcoin cash so that's
that that seems to be the group that's
been hit the hardest by this attack or
buying this fraud in the United States
and from what I can tell I mean I it's
hard to say because I'm an English
speaker but it seems like investors and
knowning
speaking countries also might have been
a focus which makes sense if you're a
scammer and you're trying to push a
fraud on people you don't you don't want
to go after the people that are least
likely or most likely to have access to
data that would make that harder for you
but the end result of this is
interesting you know bit main the main
guys that back this it seems they lost
really really big there according to
their own documents at the time of
trying to file an IPO they're holding
six hundred million dollars worth of
Bitcoin cash and the way that they got
that is that they traded actual Bitcoin
real valuable non flawed non in secured
Bitcoin for Bitcoin cash and it's so bad
I mean this you know they say they have
six hundred million dollars worth of
Bitcoin cash but the the real sad part
is that if they tried to sell it it
would tank right I mean this is the this
is a Ponzi scheme where the guys that
funded the Ponzi scheme are still
holding most of the most of the scam so
they're not gonna be able to liquidate
that they're not gonna be able to sell
it and it's actually so bad that they
lied on their IPO balance sheet and they
inflated the unrealistically high price
of $500 right like the current market
price maybe five hundred bucks but again
if they tried to sell hundreds of
millions of dollars worth they're not
going to be able to get hundreds of
millions of dollars out of the market
because the price would would go below
five hundred immediately but even that
price they inflated by four hundred
percent as they're trying to sell bit
main to investors so pretty interesting
outcome and extreme extremely making it
for the attackers sorry let's see yeah I
think I think the only thing I wanted to
say the only other thing I wanted to say
about this is that yes bit-bit main may
end up being sold to other investors
through an IPO sort of new money may
come in to buy up the company but even
if that happens it's it's really a new
company in the sense that they're not
currently sitting on a lot of
that's there they're basically an empty
shell of a company at this point and so
if a lot of new money comes in maybe
there will be a new company with the
same name a bit mean but but in a sense
they're dead they've killed themselves
through this attack so that is the
that's that's very interesting because
they were the largest most successful
Bitcoin company up to this point and
they they flew little too close to the
Sun I guess so the next next group of
attacks is the altcoin attacks so we've
got light coin ripple Manero aetherium
so the reason that these are attacks is
that again if mony is a single asset
that's used a facilitate trade then
competitors and these are competitors
incidentally that have no chance of
replacing Bitcoin if they actually were
better than Bitcoin then in a sense they
would be the new Bitcoin right they
would be the new the new best effort to
create a global money and if Bitcoin is
a mission to create a global secure
money then in a sense they would be
Bitcoin but all of the guys on this list
will tell you even their own sort of
advocates most of the time when they're
there they're talking about this they're
they're gonna try to avoid the fact that
they have to compete with Bitcoin
because they don't ever want to say that
they have a chance of replacing Bitcoin
because that's just it's pretty
laughable so what they try to do is they
try to say that money doesn't have to be
one thing right just they take an
economic fallacy to open up the door for
themselves to sell to scale or to sell
to their victims but out of everything
on the list on this list the ones that
really pissed me off the most are
probably mineiro and grin and the reason
for that is that these are the most sort
of viable the other ones are relatively
laughable I mean ripple you have to be
pretty stupid to think that that's a
good idea but but mineiro and grin there
you don't have to be so stupid and what
that means is that they're going after
people that that really should have a
bigger influence on the future of the
economy then they're gonna end up with
if they if they fall for these sort of
things and basically they take
advantage of people not understanding
that that money is a it's a
winner-take-all project and that if it's
a winner-take-all project to be money
you can't have like a privacy money
because it's either money or it's not
money so for example grin you know
they've got this really terrible in
addition to some other problems they've
got a really crazy inflation schedule so
that's that's not gonna work out but
it's a little bit more subtle than just
something like Ripple all right it looks
like I have to do the Q&A soon so I'm
just going to burn through these last
ones really quick so recent attacks and
near misses proof-of-work change attack
this one is really interesting so Luke -
jr. and CRO Cobra in mid 2018 put on a
pretty good campaign to try to get the
Bitcoin proof-of-work changed and the
reason that I'm very comfortable calling
this out as an attack and these guys out
as scammers is that they were very very
dishonest and greasy about how they went
about sort of the debate I interacted
with both of these guys directly and it
was it was not it was not an honest
search for truth by any means and if
they had pulled it off it would have
destroyed Bitcoin security who prom
probably irreparable so it's worth
noting this and I think it's very likely
that we'll see more of this next year
the inflation bug that was found last
week so this in and of itself isn't that
big of a deal in the sense that some
people could end up with counterfeit
Bitcoin but I think that it does open up
the possibility of a bug like this being
exploited a lot of people getting
counterfeit Bitcoin and then potentially
a follow-on campaign to honor those
those issued Bitcoin if that was the
case we would end up losing our 21
million supply cap and I think that
would be really really damaging in the
long run it doesn't seem like this is
super likely and in fact all of these
attacks I would say are not very likely
to be able to be pulled off the
historical ones failed miserably they
had a lot of resources and and bitcoins
actually a very well designed system so
that's that's the overarching narrative
but these are still interesting to to
keep an eye out for and future attacks
so insecure side chains I'm actually I'm
gonna run till 35 and we'll just do a
10-minute Q&A just so you guys know so
insecure side chains so so side chains
are basically broken down into two
categories right now you have federated
side chains which are basically just a
group of exchanges let's say or a group
of custodians working together and then
you also have a we'll call it a drive
chain just in honor of the the scammer
that is pushing that the problem with
the drive chains model is that 51
percent of the miners can just drain all
of the funds now 51 percent of the
miners in Bitcoin can do double spins or
some little little stupid annoying
things but they can't just take all of
the Bitcoin they can't wake up tomorrow
with 130 billion dollars a Bitcoin if
51% of want to but that is exactly
what's possible with with that
sidechains model so the the attack there
would be probably a combination of
taking the funds and shorting Bitcoin at
the same time it's going to be very hard
to explain to the average investor that
this is not a flan Bitcoin we can't even
explain to the average investor that
Mount GOx wasn't enough on Bitcoin so
good luck with that
and then and so a couple examples are SK
is a combination of both they've got a
federated model but with the federated
model it's like an exchange right or a
group of exchanges so the the Federation
partners are really really critical they
have been really cagey about that
reality and they have kind of obfuscated
that by saying that they're also going
to do the drive chains thing so in a way
it's a combination of two insecure
solutions to store funds and it makes a
little less obvious but it's still a
really really bad idea and then drive
chains is just purely one bad idea
liquids interesting so it's a federated
model so it is still custodial but at
the same time depending on how much
money and how big and how much
reputation the Federation partners have
it could be okay it could certainly it
will definitely not be as secure as
Bitcoin so I would be very concerned if
there was a hundred billion dollars
worth of Bitcoin in liquid tomorrow but
as long as the people are managed that
are running it manage it really
carefully make sure that there's
essentially a lot more reputation on the
line than there is money so the
incentives are balanced right it could
be just fine
and the other thing that we'll probably
see as bugs in the Lightning Network so
the design does appear to be really
sound but it's new and new stuff is
gonna have bugs the Lightning developers
have been really vocal about don't put
too much money in this and part of the
reason is that if the pot gets big
enough and there's enough there's enough
reward some of the bugs that are sure to
be in there will be will be exploited
but lightning is it's not like
sidechains in the sense that there isn't
one huge pot of money so it's a it's
probably going to be minor exploitation
Bitcoin org this is something that I
expect to happen given that Cobra has
been such a such a greasy character and
he is the one that that owns the domain
to Bitcoin org I think we're gonna end
up seeing something similar to Bitcoin
com happen at some point if there's if
there's a good viable attack that's
worth kind of using that asset putting
that putting that in play that said I
think the solution there is is for us
all to be prepared just to switch to
another domain switch all the links and
kill them from from a Google search
perspective and finally I think we're
gonna see some large-scale theft of
private keys you know hacked hacks are
gonna happen constantly there's
basically something that happens where
if the exchange gets enough money
the reward for attacking it either an
inside person or an outside person gets
big enough to where it's inevitable so I
think we're gonna constantly just like
what happened with gold I think we're
gonna constantly see an oscillation
between too much money being held
custodial II and then being stolen and
then it will drop down because people
will be afraid of it my hope is that as
it oscillates and people get burned they
learn to hold their own private keys but
I don't think that this this pattern is
gonna end anytime soon
so yeah thanks for thanks for listening
and if you guys have any questions now's
the time
[Applause]
do we have a questions
we do
do you consider Manero and green a good
and a flounder is despite of them being
cursed games in terms of store of value
proposition I'm sorry can somebody can
somebody repeat the question it's a
little too much echo for me to hear that
I know it was a question about Marilyn
yeah - oh do I consider their mixing
good enough like is there is do they
provide privacy and transactions is that
the question yes yeah so so Manero is
interesting because in theory it has
some you know stuff like confidential
transactions and ring signatures that
makes it better I wouldn't use it though
and the reason that I wouldn't use it is
that there's not very many transactions
so the anonymity set that you have is
pretty small there's also other ways to
attack it for example most people that
buy Manero buy it on a on an official
exchange that has their identity so if
you do that that's pretty pointless that
that eliminates the the security value
pretty quickly Green isn't released yet
but it's based on the middle Wimble
concept and that's very cool I mean the
the part of the thing that sucks about
Green is that they're taking something
in the same way that Manero took
confidential transactions they're taking
something that's legitimately
interesting in the context of something
that has the ability to become money and
then they're applying it to something
that doesn't have the ability to become
money to scam potential investors so I
think you know it's it'll be interesting
to see what happens there I can't say
that they don't have enough transactions
because they haven't launched yet but
yeah I mean from my perspective I would
probably not mess with any of that stuff
because there's there's gonna be little
numbers of people that use it for a long
time and if I was sort of a corrupt
government that was trained to watch
what was happening it would be pretty
easy for me to focus some efforts on the
small number of people that are gonna be
trying to use those things to hide their
transactions
so my my question is about what do you
think about what what the motivations
are for Roger ver so I have like two
suggestions like either is illiterate
when it comes to tech and economics or
he could be like a epic Machiavellian
superhero so in order to increase that
fragility of Bitcoin is there going to
be its worst enemy before the states
really start to attack unitard yeah no
that's a really interesting question I
have struggled with this a lot over the
last year to try to categorize different
actors in the space and Roger ver is one
of the easier ones I think fluffy ponies
a challenge I think Charlie Lee is a
little bit more of a challenge not not
really but I mean I definitely think
there are dirty bastards but you know it
took me a little bit longer to come to
that conclusion
so with Roger ver he's an interesting
character because he knows enough about
Austrian economics to find the parts of
it that would be confusing and he's very
very good at having his set of bullet
points that that harp on things that
that have been effective so I basically
with him I think he's too he's too good
at what he does for it to be accidental
I don't know how he I'd love how he fair
old Bitcoin cash thing was he you know
was he profiting off of Jihan stupidity
or did he actually lose that as well
it's hard to tell what was going on
there but what I what I can say for sure
is that the the lies that he uses are
extremely well crafted and extremely
effective for his target market of
technical illiterate libertarians that
you know they've like they've read the
synopsis of human action but they
haven't actually read the book I mean
it's it's very very well executed so I
do think that because of that he's got
to be malicious yeah you mentioned
briefly about custodial exchanges you've
mentioned briefly about custodial
exchanges and their risks have you
analyzed the risk
of non-custodial exchanges or is that
something you're looking at I think the
question was the risks of exchanges were
talked about but what about non
custodian yes yes are you are you asking
about the theft of private keys that are
held by individuals individual owners
yeah and also government monitoring
potentially of custodial exchanges the
way that the government so I mean if
you're using exchange then there's you
know there's no question that everything
you're doing is monitored and fed as far
as individual ownership of private keys
that's the way to go I think I've
written some stuff on how I would store
between $2,000 and $5,000 worth of
Bitcoin overall I think it's hard to say
whether Bitcoin is more or less private
than than cash right now I'd have a
tendency if you're in a country that's
using cash a lot I'd have a tendency to
think that cash is going to be more
private the other another big thing in
play though is just the phase of
adoption that we're at with Bitcoin it
really doesn't make sense to to sell
Bitcoin or to trade Bitcoin at all and
the reason for that is that we're in the
we're in the exponential adoption phase
of a new money and so the value you
should expect the value to go up
considerably probably well over a
million dollars per Bitcoin because
there's only so more so much Bitcoin to
go around and if it actually is the
technology that humans have got their
hands on that works best is money you
believe it's going to be adopted as
money then then everybody's going to be
using it on something right because
that's how that's how money works and
the assumption there is that humans
adopt the thing that works best that
that's been you know pretty reasonable
throughout history so I think that we're
in the phase where people should buy a
Bitcoin and put it in cold storage and
not spend it at all and I don't think
it's a great idea to - trying to use it
for private transactions though you know
if you're trying to do business with
somebody overseas I'm sure there's a lot
of niche cases in circumstances where
it's the way to go and you know I use it
too for convenience but I definitely
wouldn't try to use it for anything you
don't want a government
nova we have time for one last very
short question if there is any there is
hey so um Bitcoin miners could
technically still all the bid concern
themselves but the way they why they
don't do it is because it would be
immediately obvious and price would
plummet so how is this different to a
drive chain so Bitcoin miners that's
that's a great question and again I mean
I I'm not just trying to get you guys to
read my document but I am pretty much
just trying to get you guys to read my
document so Bitcoin miners there are
some things that they could do but
stealing the Bitcoin is not one of them
what they could do is they could create
an invalid transaction but anybody can
create an invalid transaction the miners
would normally ignore it invalid
transaction and not spend tens of
thousands of dollars on electricity to
produce a block that has garbage in it
because it's not going to be it's not
going to be considered valid and they're
going to be poor but you can you can
create invalid transactions all day long
if you want to and so can they but it
doesn't make it a valid transaction
the problem with drive chains is that
you can have a valid Bitcoin transaction
that's honored by all the Bitcoin nodes
and that should be honored by all the
Bitcoin nodes because it's legitimate in
every way that refers to Bitcoin but but
has a payout to to anybody that they
want so you can think of the money and
drive chains is basically a big pile of
money that and it's actually designed
this way that anybody can pull the money
out of so it's it's far far worse
there's no there's no I mean drive
chains in particular from what I can
tell was actually an idea that Matt
Corallo came up with and he abandoned it
because it was a really stupid idea
unfortunately Paul stork has picked this
up and run with it he also works for or
has worked for I think Jeff Garza
so it's interesting how few shady
characters are in this space
you know there's probably
a couple dozen really greasy folks and
they seem to be behind all of the
attacks so you know RSK you're looking
at guys that were that were a big part
of the Segway 2x attack drive chains you
know you're looking at guys that are
that are employed buying closely
associated with people think cars it
goes all the way back to like Bitcoin XT
and Bitcoin unlimited so so it's pretty
easy to kind of follow the money and
follow the bad actors here as well so
just help but but no drive chains is a
really really bad design JW thank you
very much for your lecture
[Applause]
super
you