okay
sir good afternoon ladies and gentlemen
I hope you had a good lunch so it is my
pleasure to introduce the next speaker
Todd Weaver from the US so the question
is that why we why did we decide to
invite him to discomfort the thing is
that as you can see there are a lot of
privacy extremists here people with a
mask you know this crappy mask and all
these people are almost all these people
there are the happy lucky customers of
purist company because they bought very
unique piece of hardware which is called
purist Libre even even me I bought this
hard world like maybe one year ago and I
was so surprised that it's still
possible to build like really super
secure hardware like for example this
hardware is a physical switch so we can
easily switch off Bluetooth Wi-Fi
microphone camera and also it it comes
is of multiple open hardware components
instead of BIOS it uses coreboot so it
has a lot of great features and I think
that will tell you much more about the
school project and cool hardware your
counter thank you
[Applause]
sadly I'm actually not going to be
shilling product I don't actually think
that's that ethical so I'm actually
gonna be talking to you about the future
of computing and why you should care
so first a little bit about me I'd like
to show you with you six statements and
you get to decide which ones are true
and which ones are false and then I'll
answer those at the end of the talk so
the first one I want you to think about
is I was born in the u.s. capital of
Washington DC on Independence Day in
1970 for making my birthday seven four
seven four number two I've been at
digital civil rights activist since 1995
number three I played bass guitar for a
decade or so in a punk rock band I
joined in 2003 number four I built wrote
and deployed over a quarter million
canoe based Hardware media players in
2005 number five I started the first
online cable company in 2007 and was
sued for 30 billion dollars by 34 big
media companies for copyright
infringement number six I founded the
first social purpose technology company
called purism in 2014 there's a clue to
that one I'll be curious which ones you
think are true and which ones are false
now I'm gonna inject some quotes into
this talk for no other reason than
people like quotes such as this one it
took me more than three weeks to prepare
for this impromptu speech in this talk I
would like to discuss the future of
computing and why you should care
if you came to hear me talk about our
product software services I usually
don't do that
but since they gave me an abundance of
time and I can't fill all that time you
can grill me afterwards with questions
or and you can find me afterwards and
I'd be happy to show you what we're up
to
so this talk is about the future of
computing and why you should care and
let me begin by saying something is
wrong with our digital world something
basic something is rotten to the core I
want to talk to you about what that is
how it came to be and why we must change
it here's another great quote a person
who won't care has no advantage over one
who doesn't care this talk comes in
three parts part one is history part two
is the present and part three is the
future for the cynics in the audience
which are probably most of you those
parts translate to part one history and
this boring
are to the present that's totally lame
and part three the future and I already
knew it here's a great quote there are
two types of people in the world those
that understand binary and those that
don't
part-1 history the history of the
mistreatment of our digital civil rights
big tech companies that abused people
like Apple Google Facebook Microsoft to
name a few are based in the US therefore
I will describe to you the history from
that legal framework it's the one that
brought you the exploitation of humanity
so I'm going to talk about it from that
perspective some things you need to
understand the first is that governments
like them or not right the rules of the
game that society plays the second there
are always rules and right now
government's influenced by big tech are
writing those rules third if you are
somebody who wants no rules whatsoever
you will quickly realize that rules will
be written that govern you without your
involvement so my sage advice to you is
write the rules let's write the rules
that we want to see in an ethical
society that respects freedoms and
liberties
what do you call the dumbest person who
passes the bar exam a lawyer nearly
everybody discussing the vacuous big
tech you know Apple Facebook Google
Microsoft and all tech corpse abuse our
digital civil rights but everybody is
missing the larger and more menacing
issue it's because it's at the core of
their business it's backed by
governmental laws it will not get better
unless one of three things happen one
government regulation that is ethical
for society business models change to
something ethical for society or people
switch to something ethical for society
that is not then regulated out of
existence I recommend not trying to
avoid government by scurrying from one
dark corner to the other because in many
countries we have an opportunity to come
out of the dark corners and write the
rules big tech Apple Facebook Google
Microsoft's right are just a few of the
litany of tech corporations whose
business model exploits humanity for
their profit they all suffer from a
systemic toxin that discourages personal
freedoms and removes any digital civil
rights we as society demand the
marketing efforts from big tech will
continue to push the agenda of privacy
protection because they all fear the day
they will be found to be just as guilty
as the Facebook Cambridge analytical
debacle it is only a matter of time
before it happens and these big tech
corporations are already starting the
marketing to try to differentiate
themselves from it but marketing alone
will not remove the poison within their
business model that is the mistreatment
of society
now a minor disclaimer and this minor
plug because you may be asking but
you're a company actually no we're a
social purpose corporation and that's
just not a series of buzzwords that's
actually a legal registration of a
business that carries with its
significant importance it's the reason
we have a strong depth to credibility
it's the reason we can influence change
for the better with solid legal footing
it's the reason we can't ever exploit
people for profit it's the reason we are
unlike all big tech who are formed to
strip your digital civil rights in the
name of maximizing shareholder value
there was a recent article in ink
magazine about us and it's a pure ISM is
what is called a social purpose
corporation which allows a business to
prioritize social objectives over
fiduciary duties so I'm sure can
elaborate on that point all corporations
like Apple Facebook Microsoft Google and
all tech giant's have a single goal
maximize shareholder value that's it
that's the only goal but it's actually
not just a goal under eBay vs. Newman a
lawsuit setting legal precedent stating
the law makes it literally malfeasance
for a corporation not to do everything
it legally can to maximize its profits
so you can imagine given the choice of
making $1.00 by exploiting people or
opting to treat people ethically the
corporation must exploit people for the
dollar or the board of directors and the
executives could face a lawsuit from any
shareholder that claims they did not
maximize the value of their shares
the regulations at the foundation of big
tech are forcing the exploitation of our
digital civil rights quoting from Jan
Chancellor William B Chandler the third
who sums up the problem perfectly in his
Delaware Court opinion when eBay sued
Craigslist for not maximizing its shares
he said having chosen a for-profit
corporate forum the directors are bound
by the fiduciary duties to promote the
value of the corporation for the benefit
of its stockholders
we have centuries of legal precedent in
the physical world advanced by science
and society guiding our moral compass
trespassing laws freedom of speech
privacy rights protection against
personal harm and abuse we have no
digital civil rights big tech trespasses
on your data big tech restrict speech
big tech obliterates privacy entirely
big tech exploits people causes harm and
inflicts abuse on our society if
somebody approached your bedroom window
from outside put a camera up and started
recording you would immediately call the
authorities report the numerous laws
broken the case would be opened arrests
could be made charges could be pressed
trials could ensue criminals could go to
jail or depending on where you live you
may have just brought out a shotgun in
the beginning but in the digital world
none of that exists you are forced to
leak far more details than a camera in
your bedroom window would share and you
are forced to leak that personal data
from your phone all the time like the
wake of a ship right to be scooped up by
big tech or many governments that have
influence over them big tech exploits
you every millisecond of every day
all future government regulation will be
influenced funded and lobbied by big
tech imagine if this future government
regulation lobbied by big tech made
anonymous crypto currencies illegal
could you imagine a future of regulation
where big tech was to cryptographically
sign everything with their keys under
their control on their products what a
nightmare scenario I mean could you
imagine your mobile phone under the
complete control of Apple or Google oh
wait that's reality
I wish there was a social purpose
company building a convenient ethical
phone to compete against big tech you
know one that wasn't Android or iOS you
know a phone that used secure hardware
combined with freedom respecting
software including services that
defended our liberties I'm trying to
think of what social purpose company
that could be this is where I insert a
subliminal message
now listen we need to write the rules
based on values we want in society AI
algorithms from big tech have one input
variable maximize shareholder value and
that translates directly into gather
everything on all of society keep people
digitally captive maximize exposure time
polarize opinion to elicit more profit
that is not what AI should be taught due
to data manipulation no two people in
society are getting the same information
it is impossible to have a same debate
about any polarizing topic because we
aren't starting with a foundation of
shared knowledge get your facts first
and then you can distort them as much as
you please what if the input requests to
AI algorithms was build an ethical
society that respects digital civil
rights what would society look like then
let's take a quick poll who here would
like an unethical Society okay that was
easy to count who would like an ethical
Society all right now let's do a quick
calculation factoring in some deviation
from this audience Oh awesome okay good
we all want to think maximizing
shareholder value in a society that has
no digital Civil Rights guarantees
exploitation of that society now who
wrote that oh wait that was me why did
we let this happen how did we let this
happen
I know why because it's convenient to
give up control it is convenient for you
to download a proprietary application
that exploits you agree to the legally
binding Terms of Service that you didn't
read and blissfully believed big tech is
helping you in the digital world it's
inconvenient to stand up for your
digital civil rights so it seems it's
all about convenience versus control I
believe we can have both convenience and
control we can build technology that
benefits society faster when they are
based on principles we deem ethical
society's technology genius is not
lagging behind our moral genius is
I wish there was a social purpose
company building convenient ethical
products that compete against big tech
insert subliminal message here
Big Tex Trust is eroding rapidly and
while they may mark it heavily claiming
things like we protect your privacy or
we use encryption or we are secure or
you can trust us but no big tech company
has core values that help our digital
civil rights when they say we protect
your privacy it's actually know you
exploit my private data when they say we
use encryption no it's inside
proprietary app that you control
we are secures no you hold the master
keys controlling me you can trust us
that's my favorite one
no you won't let me verify anything
I did not attend the funeral of Facebook
but I sent a nice letter saying I
approve of it part 2 of the present
you'll be happy to know these other
parts are not as long as that first part
currently big tech is maximizing
shareholder value without values the
product software and services offered by
big tech will continue to mistreat
people unless we can establish what
digital civil rights are and change
society for the better then we advocate
regulate and build products that adhere
to those digital civil rights it is
curious that physical courage should be
so common in the world and moral courage
so rare
I believe there are five fundamental
digital civil rights the right to change
providers the right to protect personal
data the right to verify the right to be
forgotten and the right to access this
is what I call the purest principles
number one the right to change providers
if a person wants to change a service
provider they can easily move to another
right it's just basically decentralized
services number two the right to protect
personal data a person owns and controls
their own master keys to encrypt all
data and communication nobody else
that's user controlled encryption the
right to verify Society has the freedom
to inspect the source code of all
software used and can run it as they
wish for any purpose that's free
software foundation's software freedom
the right to be forgotten a service
provider only stores the minimal
personal data necessary to provide the
service once the data is no longer
required it is deleted it's what I call
the minimal data retention a right to
access a person must not be
discriminated against nor forced to
agree to any terms and conditions before
accessing a service so what I call
personal liberty if we can do these
things we can change the future of
computing for the better
part three the future as technology gets
closer and closer to our brain the moral
issues of digital civil rights become
clearer and clearer
it started with computers then it moved
on to phones that you always have on you
or near you with millisecond leakage of
personal data that's beyond human
comprehension but those are just the
beginnings of the tsunami wave coming
we have wearables that are already here
and tracking very private details IOT
devices are everywhere and I have to
stop and let everybody remind everybody
that the s in IOT is for security and
finally there's surgically implanted so
a question for you what big tech company
would you purchase your future brain
implant from this is coming so just a
quick poll who would like a big tech
controlled brain this one to confirm ok
and what about you control your own
brain
it lets do a quick calculation yeah
that's everybody knowing the severity of
your technical decisions and your
understanding of this importance of
ethical technology it's a wonder why
unethical big tech is still big let's
all advocate regulate and release
product software and services that
ensure digital civil rights that are
ethical for society if we do that we can
advance technology that is rooted in
ethical values and rather than fear what
may be coming from big tech we will
welcome our own advancements with open
arms and open minds from our ethical
socially responsible Technology
organizations I believe we can change
the future of computing for the better
oh and to answer those six statements
from the beginning as either true or
false number one I was born in the US
Capitol Washington DC on Independence
Day in 1970 for making my birthday seven
four seven four that is true which also
tells you how old I am I have been a
digital civil rights activist since 1995
it's true I played bass guitar for a
decade in a punk rock band I joined in
2003 it's also true
I built wrote and deployed over a
quarter-million canoe based Hardware
media players in 2005 mr. I started the
first online cable company in 2007 it
was sued for 30 billion dollars by 34
big media companies for copyright
infringement it's true number 6 I
founded the first socially purpose
technology company and peers them in
well that one's true but before I turn
over to questions from you I have a few
questions for you
will you buy Apple products that lock
you in with their keys so you have no
control will you use Google products
that control and exploit you for profit
will you use Facebook Twitter Instagram
whatsapp WeChat or whatever the next
unethical service is that control you
and exploit you and your friends will
you use products and services from big
tech when you know they are rotten to
the core I suggest you take a chapter
from history and answer those oppressing
choices with nope like Rosa Parks did
unethical or ethical what future will
you choose now I can't leave you here
without giving a quote from a punk rock
band what's your plan for tomorrow are
you a leader or will you follow are you
a fighter or will you cower it's our
time to take back the power thank you
[Applause]
thanks thanks a lot for a presentation I
think there were a lot of questions so
raise your hand and ask ok the first
time
own to the process or architecture your
company is suffering have you ever
thought about using for example some
exotic CPU architecture which is maybe
not open-source but you don't get hacked
by NSA but it's that other Russians like
L Bruce L Bruce processors which are
pretty capable but they are not far in
common so yes so the question is well
basically or what are the CPU choices
that are there and what are we looking
to do so in our laptops we use Intel but
it has a management engine what we do is
we disable the management engine and
make sure that it's not running so we
get very very very far farther than
anybody else with regard to freedoms
about laptops on the phone that we're
coming out with the Libre v that's
running an IM x8m CPU and that means it
has no binaries in at all in no software
updates that are anything other than
free software so it's a completely
ethical Hardware choice we also are
gonna be releasing the schematics so you
can actually compare the schematics
against the hardware to verify that the
hardware has nothing in it that is not
expected and then but you're probably
bringing up things like risk v and the
future CPU architectures and they're
just not yet primetime they can be for
smaller IOT devices or things that are
like routers but as far as a device that
has interaction with a person it's not
there yet and so we're gonna continue to
follow that and we'll evaluate risk v
when it is mainstream or available for
us I have a question you spoke a lot
about freedom and just just giving the
people the power but it seems to me it
seems very similar to problems of like
going to a store which buys a coffee
from like Africa where they would I buy
it from from people who take money from
it's like similar to food due to organic
food to more expensive so do you have
any plan like like how should we or how
should you or how is it going to be
pushed to all the people because the
phone is $600 the
Computers $3,100 and you can get a phone
from one euro here and you will most of
the 95% of people will just just go and
get their phone anywhere and so do you
have any idea how to push this okay
let's not say in five years 10 maybe 20
years how they should be done to to
deploy to more than then hackers and
those people who can have money to buy
these phones yes so it's all about
leverage so one of the things that has
always historically been the case is in
the supply chain nobody has ever pushed
for freedoms or liberties
so as purism grows our social purpose
can be advanced and we already are
influencing the supply chain as a matter
of fact when I have supply chain
conversation I advance to say you must
release all the source code before I'm
gonna purchase your product and you can
imagine money talks with suppliers so I
can actually influence change and then I
can influence change beyond things that
are just freedom with hardware or
freedom with software we can actually
say where would like to manufacture our
phone is there an area that we'd like to
manufacture it over another area because
of human rights and so those are all
things that we can influence change
because we are have leverage and that
leverage is going to be used for good
purpose because that's part of our
Articles of Incorporation so it's going
to be in some cases very rapid right as
an example when our phone comes out it
will be a qualify for a respects your
freedom certification from the Free
Software Foundation that's a gigantic
bar if you've ever read the
specification of that and then your next
point of your question was about price
price is also based off of leverage now
there's some aspects is that we will not
be be able to sell a product for $0 or
for a 1 euro because at the end the end
the game of that is of course your the
product and you're just giving up your
data over time but it doesn't mean that
economies of scale don't come into play
when we are purchasing product so right
now it's very expensive for me
to manufacture a laptop or a phone that
respects your freedoms but as more and
more people and it's clear from how many
people are interested in our phone even
before it's out is going to make it
where we can lower those prices but
that's probably going to be a couple
years out has to be you know different
revisions or hardware as you can imagine
that takes time but but it is certainly
something that's addressable by gaining
by having leverage how it's it's more a
philosophical like how do we push people
to even think about their security even
care for the data because and when I'm
looking at people my mother my friends
my wife they don't care they just why
would I don't care if anybody spies I
don't care I mean I'm telling like like
you send me these photos do you want any
better did you see them and she's like
oh and you send like your bankers data
and then they go like like how do we do
this if I understand the question
and again it's convenience in control so
what happens is the reason that society
just is like well I'm gonna use this
product is because it's convenient
however there's an overwhelming pendulum
swing back to the center of awareness
that big tech is exploiting people but
what they will usually do is try and
rationalize that because they need to
have a convenient product so what we're
doing and what I recommend to anybody is
make convenient products that are
ethical and then we can actually just
simply hand somebody a phone right it
doesn't have to be a long diatribe about
digital civil rights and why those are
so important they can just simply use a
product and support that product that
are advancing the technology and the
ethical thing beliefs that we have in
society so it's about convenience and
control I like to add that for example a
good marketing strategy in case of food
is a fur trade you know somebody maybe
you should think about like for privacy
for computers yes sir
smartphones you know like something like
that because I think it will really
promote the real value oh yeah
absolutely of your stuff okay anyway I
have a question like technical question
many people from hardware Elmen many
people from hackers community they have
problems using phones just because they
have proprietary GSM baseband mm-hmm you
know so many people many people from
hackers community they think the
government they have some zero-day
exploits against gsm baseband of the
most phones and it doesn't matter if you
use iOS or Android or anything you know
because it's like low-level things so
yes and so maybe the question is from
the hackers community whatever your far
how do you use like open open source
just as best answer your question so so
first of all all phones are completely
exploitable okay the baseband and the
CPU are combined in everybody's phone
right so when the baseband and the CPU
are combined which is the cellular modem
as the baseband and the CPU then that
means anybody who has control of the CPU
or has control of the baseband has
complete control of the entire device at
the hardware level so that means that
any secrets that you think you have on
your device you don't so what that means
is what are we doing to solve that issue
well first of all we have this really
cool thing is called the hardware kill
switch that actually severs the circuit
of the baseband that's pretty awesome
but we also take it one step deeper than
that because we separate the baseband
the cellular modem from the CPU and it's
actually a module you can actually open
up the phone remove the module that is
the baseband and put it in a different
one if you wanted to so by having proper
separation which means we can have
proper isolation and then you can have
your rights respected the other piece
that's really important about that
because you brought up you know who can
infiltrate into a device well of course
all ISPs can infiltrate into a device on
current phones on our phone they're a
dumb pipe and they are used over the
dumb pipe connection to the CPU which
means they're providing you data or
audio service for your phone
they have no additional access the
software update is actually if you want
to do a software update then you are
pulling in the software it's not being
forced upon you so that's where CPU and
baseband separation is really important
from a rights perspective now it wasn't
some malicious intent originally it's
actually just economies of scale it
costs less to fabricate a single tin can
that has a CPU and baseband in it so it
costs us more to separate them but
that's the ethical approach to make it
where service providers are only dumb
pipes and that's exactly what they
should be okay and another question many
private server people they use like
black phone you know project black phone
so so if you if you can summarize the
competitive advantage advantage of
purist phone compared to black phone
what are these advantages okay these
ones you have just mentioned probably
one I think I just mentioned almost all
of them so the fact that we release a
schematic the fact that all the hardware
is available to evaluate the fact that
all of the software is free software so
the source code is available we utilize
reproducible builds so you can actually
confirm that the source code is actually
the proper source code we have Hardware
kill switches we separate the baseband
from the CPU we use a CPU that doesn't
require any firmware blobs we have
everything that we have the software
updatable is free software so the source
code is available I mean it could go on
but that's plenty okay we gotta kill off
thank you a lot thank Allah for a
comprehensive answer questions
sure the the future that you're
proposing somehow implies that
individuals have greater control over
their cryptographic keys absolutely so
can you just talk a little bit around
you know how you see that coming into
play where they're generated where
they're stored how we actually engage
with them across multiple devices yeah
so there's a number of areas to address
but I'll try and hit on a few of them so
the first thing is if users control
their own identity which means the
devices that they have which you're
going to then carry that forward to a
brain implant right is that you need to
control the keys and how where that
stored needs to be something that you
also control meaning a hardware secure
token right so if you want to generate a
key and load it into a hardware secure
token that you control then you can also
make backups of it on devices you
control which can actually just simply
be a USB Drive you put in a safe and so
making sure that you have Hardware
tokens that are completely the hardware
itself is released under free hardware
licenses and then the software itself is
also released under free software
licenses which means then third parties
can verify that that device is not
compromised by anybody else
so hardware secure tokens are great but
they have to be done with the full stack
right if you're just buying a hardware
secure token and trusting the entity
who's shipping it to you and they don't
adhere to those values then you just
really didn't solve anything
now you just sort of naively believed
you were being protected so where things
need to be stored there are a lot of
effort to be put into sharding which is
just an awesome word so to separate out
your private key and backup across
different ways but then you know there's
a number of options that are coming out
in the end result is that you need to
have a hardware that's secured where
it's also available for verification and
the software that's secured and is
available for verification yeah my
question is about the artwork so let's
say that
here let's say that I'm worried about
our door back doors so I buy your phone
mmm
when I get your phone how do I verify
that that word is doing what is supposed
to do yeah excellent excellent question
so a few things right now we actually
have what's called anti interdiction
support which actually means we will
take a high-resolution photo of the
device the motherboard of the device and
then ship you actually have what's
called a Libra McKee which is a hardware
secure token and we can actually
generate on the delete secure key
signature and we can insert in the
device laptop or phone and then
cryptographically sign onto that key the
state of that device and then we ship
you the key and then we ship you the
device separately and you actually get
it you plug it in and if the little
green light blinks you know that it has
not been tampered with and this is
actually something you can carry with
you forward into other things meaning
you can take your laptop and if you left
it over here next to the sketchy sound
guy he may tamper with it and what you
can do then is you can bring it back you
can plug in your Libra McKee and you can
see does it blink green then you know it
has not been tampered with any single
bit and you want to measure as deep as
you can so there's ways in which to
remove of what would be interdiction by
cryptographic signatures confirming the
hardware and that means that any
modification to the hardware would
actually be triggered as a tamper okay
thank you we have another question
I am can you say a little bit more about
your hardware choice for the Librium key
and your opinion on the smart card
hardware landscape in general yeah so
anything we do with hardware we advance
toward schematic release and then having
it where you can confirm that with the
hardware that's actually produced
we also are controlling the fabrication
lines so if we fabricate at a dongdong
china then we are there on-premise to
confirm that the run is exactly as we
designed and then we ship it to
currently either South San Francisco or
Carlsbad California and we verify all of
those the other thing is on the phone we
actually like our dev kits that are
shipping well like in a few weeks
those were completely fabricated in
Carlsbad California so the same with the
Nitro key-based Libre McKee so what we
did is we partnered with nitro key and
then you and then modified their
firmware that's of course also free
software so it's released and then also
modified the hardware to have a little
blinking LED if it's green or red since
people like convenience and those are
great colors so then by that we end up
releasing all the hardware releasing all
of the software and then through
reproducible builds you can download and
confirm that everything on that device
is designed to be have you retained
control thank you any questions okay so
thank you a lot yes thank you for coming
here and having a very interesting
presentation and thank you all for
having also just in question and from
coming here oh thank you excellent thank
you
[Applause]