it's a good home
to go
good afternoon ladies and gentlemen I'd
like to introduce you our regular
speaker who is creator founder of
Freeland probably the only free land in
the world
liberland vd8 Logica welcome thank you
very much Powell and I would say it is
this this Congress is somehow special
because unlike years before when I hear
all these lectures and regime for
example that was a great speech
I'm always or smuggler I always almost
hear like they're talking about what
we're doing in a way and they're giving
us the kind of a preparation or a logic
ideological background and of course
liberal and if you were here for the
previous lecture is a working working
progress on alternative legal system
liberal and we were basically portrayed
as the the best tax haven in the world
by the by the mainstream media and they
constantly portrayed us as such but idea
of liberal and is it's much broader we
really want to make a a heaven rather
than Haven if you can distinguish the
difference between these two words
I don't want people to hide in liberal
and neither criminals or or black money
or any kind of share of economy I would
really like people to come there and
enjoy as much freedom as possible when
we found it liberal and we knew that the
voluntarism
is something that has to be introduced
into the relation between the citizen
and the state a completely open relation
in which you can again obtain an opt-out
out of the relation and that we need
more competition between existing states
in order to build a freer planet that
nothing actually a part of competition
works if there was not a monarch on the
borders of France you would see the axis
probably a couple percent higher if
there was no like Tinch time in
Switzerland we might see a
a taxes in Switzerland much higher and
of course if there was no Switzerland in
the U we would probably see much bigger
tax hell in the EU itself so we were
reasoning like that and we were thinking
why don't we have more freer places like
these small small Republic's or small
monarchies that are making possible for
you to enjoy a rather free environment
and why don't we go to the extreme that
we really turned the relation from a
obligatory relation from the social
contract into a completely voluntary
interaction between a citizen and the
state so we found it labor line on 13th
of April 2015 and that was a special day
because it was 272nd birthday of Thomas
Jefferson and we wanted to pay tribute
to the founders of the United States
that they did a great job in defining
what the government should do and let me
just read this quote the vice man and
frugal government which shall restrain
men from injuring one another which
shall leave them otherwise free to
regulate their own pursuits of Industry
and improvement and shall not take from
mouth of labour the bread it has earned
of course the government should be
minimal as possible we decided to limit
a liberal and government to take care
only of justice security and diplomacy
and I think nothing a part of that we
have decided to take the best elements
out of the US Constitution and
incorporate them in our Constitution and
the work is still in progress you can
read the last draft of liberal and
constitution now there is a nice new
addition to it which was actually done
in cooperation with some people here
close to Peroni police I've got a couple
copies here and if you would like to be
part of that inner team it's going to be
soon on get up as well and we are trying
to base a system on property rights in
which the property rights art are the
key key element from which all other
logics in into the in the Constitution
are stemming from
so we've got a system of Republic's
that's something that was proven for for
now let's say 250 years as a very good
system of of running the state but we
know that it decays over the time we've
got elements of democracy in which
basically half of citizen can veto any
kind of decision and we are putting into
the elements of the meritocracy so
meaning that live liberal lenders are
also the shareholders of the state that
they're living in meaning the more taxes
you pay in Liberal and the bigger is
your say and we are putting it on top of
the centralised autonomous organization
which means we are partnering with the
best companies out there that are
working on this right now with Dow stock
to put the whole governance model on
blockchain if you want of course to read
more about this labor line publishing
has recently published a an open source
government book one the end the fall of
the political class it's a trilogy and
it gives what we are doing a deeper
psyche deeper inside but what do you
need to have a country and I bet many of
you guys actually we're thinking about
starting a country and when we started
liberland we were looking into what are
those elements that are necessary to
start it you need a population you need
a defined territory you need a
government and a capacity to enter into
relations with other states let me show
you how much liberland is fulfilling
this criteria by now and by the way if
you want to read more about it you can
read the Chi cago Journal of
international law there is a 35-page
study completely natural study that done
by this very prestigious institution now
we've got half million and 50,000 people
that registered on our website we
consider these people a residence of
liberland and we will soon issue them
the e-residency cards we've got two
hundred and five thousand eligible
applications and that is growing quite
fast these days I think it's like three
to five hundred people a day we've got
one thousand and seventeen people that
indicated that they want to start a
business in liberland and that would
already make us a nice powerhouse
in terms of business incorporation we've
got defined territory that the piece of
land was unclaimed for more than 26
years when we claimed it by any foreign
government and we are still the only
entity that claimed it
despite Croatia now telling us you know
we are not completely happy with your
existence we're still not having a
direct dispute with any sovereign state
and Serbia on the other hand was very
nice to us they told us we don't mind
creation of labour land it was not form
on our territory and and that aspect was
kind of indirect recognition we've got
an amazing amount of professionals that
apply for citizenship if you look into
the database the amount of lawyers and
and experts in different fields is great
but I think the strongest community that
was developed so far our architects and
they got together when liberland started
and they said we're gonna make a
competition and how liberal and should
look like and zaha hadid
I think many of you might know them is
one of the most famous architectural
studios in the world organized that
competition and we hit some 70
architectural studios that applied to be
part of that competition we had very
nice results how liberal and could be
developed that was a proposal by team
from Harvard University for example
which really took in consideration the
local ecosystem and how the place could
be there I think it's a little bit
overpopulated but if you consider that
we've got half a million people that
would like to live there this is
probably only hundred twenty thousand
this is a similar density like Monaco so
it would be quite hard to fit fitted
there if everybody would like to live
that applied for citizenship so far
would would be living in there we would
be 3 times more overpopulated and the
most overpopulated place on plant which
is Macau by the way this is how it would
look in our cadastre maps and by the way
liberland is still the only country that
has cadastre maps for this territory and
we've got some very nice futuristic
proposals as well interestingly enough
this this concept was based on on these
capsules and right after I found this or
I saw this I I found out that there is a
company in Slovakia that actually
produces them and funnily enough our our
former representative to Slovakia became
the marketing manager of that company
and apparently we're more and more going
into that kind of eco-friendly direction
we've got government that's the picture
from this summer when we all met in
liberland we've got Minister of Finance
a poor graphic Thomas walls bogie
Wozniak vice president and we've got
some really strong supporters in Croatia
which i think is of course most
important for us what liberland started
there was this party called gvz headed
by Evan Turner and at the time they had
four or five percent in the Parliament
but right now they've got almost 15 and
it's great that they're with us that
they are fully supportive what we are
doing and without them of course our
struggle for full sovereignty and for
for recognition by rest of the world
would be much more dim but I'm happy
that he's not just supporter he is also
liberal and diplomat in Eurasia
Parliament that he has struggled to
explain to the rest of Croatia in
Parliament already couple of times and
explained them all the benefits that
liberland could have and of course
liberland because of the nature of this
border dispute between Serbia and
Croatia is the best solution for Croatia
as well liberal alliance creation is
actually in line with Croatia's claims
for the territory and we also are
looking forward and claryce is one of
our key partners for decentralized
justice system it's basically system in
which first three randomly selected
jurors make some decision if you
appealed and six randomly selected
jurors if you are building 12 and
everything is running on blockchain on
etherium
and I'm happy that they're willing to
partner with us to build it we've got a
workgroup now and we've got a meeting
with them and I think three weeks from
now and I hope we will push the
cooperation forward and there will be a
first pilot Italy Italy next year we've
got another key partner and you might
have heard about das stack those are the
guys that are I would say on the top of
creation of dowels liberland itself will
be running as a dau when this technology
matures a bit our first pilot should
start in one month and half and it is a
I would say the key cornerstone of
building a trust between liberal and
citizens and the government so everybody
will be able to vote using our platform
and there will be basically two things
your citizen plus you are a shareholder
and these two things will combine the
weight of your boat and we have this
merit system and that was there from
very beginning and everybody talks here
when you speak these experts that there
is some need for collateral and how
merit system will work it is not just
your share in labour land but it's also
your collateral in the justice system
that you are in so if you manage to do
something wrong in labour land and you
according to the law you reject to
compensate for the damage that you have
created your merits are at stake you
stake your merits to to become citizen
and to to vote in labour land but also
it is your collateral in the justice
system that we are creating but of
course you know those are some of the
important aspects of liberland but you
can have a real country unless you have
an a beer and airline and that's
something which was created in an
extraordinary way right from the
beginning of labor line and let me just
give you a little bit of update
liberland brewery has now expanded into
serbia it's it's brewed also as labour
beer by the dogma so it's kind of a
flying brewery and when I was two weeks
ago in Novi Sad for this Hecker's
Congress I again and they we found it in
the first pub that we went to so it is
well distributed in Serbia you can also
buy it here in brac in number of places
and of course
it is available in liberland we've got a
liberal land which is growing and I'm a
kind of excited about their idea to
offer a search engine for both
commercial flights and private flights
and that we've got every growing number
of liberal lenders that of course become
quite rich in many cases by investing in
early days into Krypton out there buying
their private jets and it's nice that
they formed association and they are
helping labour land to grow by helping
us to travel around
we've got Pavel carpi Sheikh here who is
the CEO of liberland jobs it's one of
the companies that is pushing for usage
of crypto for payments for for work so
it is one of the portal where you're
expected to find somebody who will work
for crypto there and it was recently
lunch and I think there it's already
quite nicely used so if you're looking
for a job or you would like to advertise
some job of course come to come to
liberal and liberal and jobs you can
incorporate your company now easily it
just takes couple of days now probably
two or three we are doing a proper check
on the background of people that are
incorporating liberal and company so
that's why it takes a little bit longer
we're going to have a nice set of ear
acidic cards and I can tell you that in
January we will open an office also here
in Prak where it will take just couple
of minutes to get your ear azide and C
card and and to get your background
check and it will be right in the centre
of Prague but liberland of course is
about this piece of land but not just
about it it is a wider idea it has
attracted so many thousands of people
it's unbelievable and they are spread
all around the world
so right now we've got representative
offices in more than hundred countries
around the globe and we've got also
villages and the diaspora villages and
it started at the beginning of this year
they're popping up one after another and
you can see that we've got two places in
Indonesia
one place in Somaliland one small
settlement starting in Russia a bigger
village in Norway in Portugal in Belize
in Panama in Mexico and I'm kind of
excited about it because it is a a nice
sign that liberal lenders are actually a
living nation which is getting together
no matter where they are on the planet
and they're building something great
we're working hard on diplomatic
relations with other countries I just
came back from United States from US
Congress I was invited to speak at the
Alec conference which is actually one of
the biggest meeting of legislative state
legislators congressmen and Senators I
met a lot of congressmen a lot of
Senators of course many of them are
rights a Liberty leaning but also couple
Democratic senators that are very
favorable to what we are doing so I'm
kind of excited that I think we we have
now actually eight US congressman
supporting liberland and we hold a very
nice reception I think it was just a
week ago interim hotel for these
legislators I think we had like seven of
them actually coming there and some very
very nice guys that are helping us to
get liberland recognized in the United
States I was already on official state
visit to Palestine and just for a short
meeting as you can see we changed the
flags with the minister it was very
interesting they actually received the
first ether Palestinian government got
one as a sign of goodwill and we got
recognized by Somaliland last year which
is I think extraordinary achievement for
us in this early stage we signed a
bilateral agreement about about
cooperation in different fields we are
going to bring them the latest
technology for registration of Lantern
blockchain like that is a great
technology for registration of
identities on blockchain and we are also
building a small village there and I'm
actually heading there directly from
here on Monday I am flying to Dubai and
Dube I am flying to Somaliland to
continue that cooperation and if some of
you didn't know where Somaliland is
which I think at some point of the time
there was much more publicity for
liberland and for Somaliland it is it is
this is Somalia or Puntland and this is
Somaliland and unlike Somalia actually
this is very safe place to live in it is
unlike Somalia it was colonized by
British not by Italians but somehow the
rest of the world still rejects to fully
recognize it as a state which is
interesting because they've got all
elements of statehood for more than 26
years as long as liberal end is
unclaimed these guys actually are
running their country in a very nice way
let's our embassy there if somebody
wanted to join us for the trip it's
gonna be exciting we've got some eight a
big bigger names to help them in
different spheres but also some
investors so I'm hoping that we will
open open this on next Saturday this is
our village in Panama it's called a
charisma I think it's one of the
greatest place to live in actually with
super climate and of course let's say
Panama is a great competitor to
liberland so no wonder that liberal and
village was created there it I think
it's it will be a vibrant community now
they just started to sell plots and it's
affordable I think two hundred fifty
thousand dollars including a house there
there is a libre stat which of course is
a completely different jurisdiction not
that nice one as in Panama but it's in
the middle of Norway also a very nice
intentional community done by labor
lenders and it was only lunch like two
months after liberland itself was
lunched and I'm more than happy that
these guys are supporting liberland and
that most of them are of course liberal
lenders and then there are projects
around liberland and
I think you're the first guys to hear
that we are gonna have a lot of fun in
liberal and next year there will be a
festival in August in the middle of
August our work name for it is floating
man but I think it's gonna be a lot of a
lot of interesting events because what
is happening right now
this is when you come to liberal and we
basically take you as close as we can to
liberal and without inflicting conflict
with with Croatia sometimes people get
to visit liberal and write down
sometimes not but we already have a nice
boat there that can host like 60 people
for events we are improving it now to
Bitcoin freedom that's gonna be parked
right in front of liberland it should be
650 meters of space kind of alternative
space for you know for really people to
come and enjoy and then bring their
friends maybe make some weddings in
liberland but also that all the groups
that are connected liberland like
liberal and lawyers liberal and
architects liberal and volleyball
players or circle players they will
finally have a place to go and visit
liberal and and socialized and their
main tasks actually beginning 13th of
April this year will be to organize a
major festival in labour land in summer
so I hope I will be able to see some of
you there it's actually it's going to be
able to host some 30 people for to stay
permanently there is a restaurant here
upper terrace and upper deck also you
know this is not a stage fully state-run
project it's a private public
partnership in which I would really like
to remove the the public part at all to
get rid of it and just make it a private
business one of the physical first
private businesses to be located in
liberland and also we've got a nice
project for houseboats so you know
settlement is of course one of the key
elements where we have still some things
to do so right now I think there are
five investors into these houseboats so
there'll be another place for 50 people
during the summer where they can stay
and enjoy enjoy
I'm on Danube that's the important part
about settlement but of course the IT
part is one of the most important that's
why we are organizing or Co organizing a
hackathon on 8th of November which
should be a major event where all the IT
guys and all the programmers should get
together and and finalize the the IT
solution for liberland so I hope that
the the pilot for the Dow will be
working that the first decentralized
resolution mechanism will be in place
and if you have a time of course you're
welcome to join us on 8th of November in
Israel so as I told you 13th of April a
liberal and anniversary 13th of August
liberal and festival and hope to see you
there thank you very much
[Applause]
okay thanks a lot wait for your
interesting presentation questions thank
you for your presentation I would like
to ask what's your ideas about if some
other countries start to claim the land
or by force I mean do you have some
strategies or what might happen and what
can you do about it
well we're kind of lucky because Korea
puts a lot of resources to get there
anybody from coming there right now and
I mean when I say a lot of resources I'm
talking maybe like quarter million
dollars a year extra which would be
really a burden to liberal and budget
budget at this stage so we sometimes
semi jokingly but in reality it is also
you know they simply when you come to
Croatia from and you want to go to
liberal and you will be arrested for
illegal border-crossing so please don't
go to liberal and through Croatia always
you know talk to us we will update you
on the security situation but just go
with the boat through Daniel so right
now we don't have a problem because
anybody that doesn't know the situation
and comes there basically gets arrested
by Croatia just for coming too liberal
and so we don't have any problem with
anybody else coming there and claiming
this piece of land
okay and a question
hi thanks for a really nice idea and a
really nice state I just want to ask if
a business wants to come into liberland
how is it how its own corporation is
being then perceived in European Union
I mean business starts making money in
liberland base monetary taxes will be
additionally taxed in you or will it be
considered to be a non-registered
whatever business conduct how do you
have an experience with that is really
only country and every country is a
little bit different legal setup for
example Czech Republic and Slovakia are
very specific about a third country they
don't mention if the country is
recognized or not in their legal system
so basically since they don't mention it
you can assume that this is kind we are
third country apparently and of course
if the if the essence of your business
is not based in Czech Republic and for
example is done online there is no
reason why that activity should be taxed
in Czech Republic you know this is this
is really something interesting you know
we are kind of tried like these verses
to the plastic chairs in a way we are
thinking about these things but of
course all these company incorporation
Seychelles Panama those are just
concepts right it's not a not something
tangible and those are man-made rules so
what we are doing right now we of course
want to be a place for the first dolls
to be incorporated directly in some
jurisdiction let's our second goal with
the Dow stack but if you have a physical
business we've got a great opportunity
for you there is this free trade zone
right opposite to to liberland in Serbia
and by the way that's kind of special
right because you is kind of putting
down all these special economic zones
but Serbia is still not part of you so
we can come to liberland
you can visit lip line and then you can
come and see the free trade zone only
ten kilometers
from liberal and there is no vhe and no
import-export tax I think that's it's a
really great place to make business
whatever you are producing physically
can be actually done out of that free
trade zone and right now we are in
process when liberland libera lenders
are trying to buy a whole piece of that
free trade zone which is a separate one
which includes shipyard so if you were
interested in that I think that's a
great opportunity an investment
opportunity because I think once it gets
to be branded as a liberal and free
trade zone in Serbia its gonna apply
attract a lot of a lot of capital hi I
would like to ask a similar question
let's say that there is a company in
liberland and it provides some service
or product to another company based in
Europe let's say sake or Czech Republic
so would the company in in Europe be
able to deduct their taxes based on the
fact that they go to service from
liberal and you know like - I'm telling
you for example Czech and Slovakia a
legal system only talks about third
country we know that in Malta the
Abkhazian companies couldn't really push
their invoices through them out the no
Cyprus through deciphers tax Bureau so
it depends country to country and the
whole thing is a process right some
company some states recognize some
companies and some states don't
recognize some companies from foreign
foreign states we are at the beginning
but apparently you know there there were
cases now where liberal and invoice was
accepted by state authorities in Poland
without any problem so we've got these
first precedents which are happening
right now we haven't really been
promoting the incorporation you cannot
go and incorporate directly from the
website where it's still in testing mode
and we are pushing the boundaries
further and further but what I'm really
excited about that the whole system is
growing now that we've got the first
insurance company that is really
interested in launching in Libra line
that the banks are willing to cooperate
with liberland because they see a large
potential
in terms of e residents actually
becoming their level and D residents
becoming their customers so as long as
we've got a good kyc which is backed by
regular documents that actually don't
have problem with with opening accounts
for liberal and individual so the whole
thing is in process and I think we're
just about to launch many of these
things at the beginning of next year
thank you so I personally appreciate the
diversity cooperation with Dallas tech
because for me like the centralized
autumn's organization in the future
I had a presentation out there so this
is probably I think this is a really
good move and other questions don't
hesitate and ask by the way this is
Jeremy misha kievsky he was there on the
day one of foundation of liberland he's
the crazy guy but crazy enough to start
with me such a state especially what I
personally like about liberal and is
that people start thinking that like the
international law an existent of state
or even virtual states everything like
like it's very fungible very flexible
you know like there are knows some
specific strict borders you know so well
Dublin is kind of cool because we have
all the all the options to explore how
much can be done in the virtual space
but we also have a nice claim to piece
of land which qualifies us to fulfil all
the Montevideo criteria right so it is
kind of difficult to to do a start-up
country but maybe no longer you know and
I think we will see in more and more
countries erupting in the crypto space
right now I was saying I think we're a
little bit slow in attracting icos into
liberal line but we also have two bigger
icos coming up next year one of them is
actually energy company that will trade
any energy tokens on the European
exchange so I'm really excited about
couple of these projects and of course
the ICO for the insurance company I
think will be a big one
but I will see more and more
jurisdictions but it will be fully
defined by the doors that they are
incorporated in and it's something where
we would like to push the boundaries as
well okay maybe a question so if some
people wants to be liberal and citizen
just now can you describe shortly what
he or she should do well of course if
you stake 5,000 merits that's a
fast-track to citizenship but if you
help us for a couple of months with
anything you know we get involved in on
one particular aspect of labour land I
mean be it the legal system be it how
the dial should work or or just come to
liberal and in summer for a couple of
months and help it's also a very good
way and fast way to get citizenship but
the residency will be there for
everybody it is something where you just
register on the website it days couple
of minutes the citizenship will be a
little bit prestigious thing we're
actually thinking that since there will
be only 700 million tokens the marriage
that since you need to take five
thousand merits oh there will be maximum
hundred forty thousand citizens on the
planet ever limited by the divider
technology so it is a a citizenship
basically must have a value there must
this it's not that easy to acquire
citizenship in any other country by the
way there is a new company that just
launched yesterday liberland citizenship
calm I think but also not doesn't only
offer liberal and citizenship it also
offers subjects and kids and navies and
Dominica so I'm happy that you know the
ecosystem of these companies is really
growing and that we are getting actually
on the catalogues of other citizenship
advisory film that's that's pretty
that's pretty cool that we've got now
two companies that already took us among
those other countries that have
investments investments or programs for
citizenship by investment for example
anyway I heard I saw some question here
okay question hello I would like to ask
you what are adults let's say three
biggest challenges you
objectively have all you have to do well
I think there couple right and I think
the biggest one is to get the systems
right because if we incorporate the Dow
there is not too many ways to change it
later on now we'll be able to alter it
so encode that's one of the basic things
but it still will be quite difficult to
get things right if we get them wrong at
the beginning so defining the rules
finalizing the Constitution and and set
of basically go codes that's also
important and of course the relations
with Croatia I think that has the
priority over everything else to make as
much friends with them as possible and
basically to let to make them let us
live which is an important important
part ok another question yeah
Thanks another more kind of a tabloid
question how do you provide security and
law enforcement there well the idea is
that liberland should be really focused
on security justice and diplomacy that
that we would we would not like to put
our nose in any other area and you know
tourism being one of them for example I
hate that we are kind of starting these
things I just wish there were more
private investors that would go into it
and I think after we launch it there
will be a much more much more private
initiative so security is number one
right so we've got already couple we
actually had a couple full-time security
guys right now since the winter started
they are a kind of on a vocation and
they've got what waterskiing
they can make sure that nobody gets
drowned in liberland and what we are
planning to do in terms of international
security is offer a Croatia a decent
amount of money as a protection fee
basically to leave us alone so that's
part of the strategy but internally
we're just planning to basically have a
security agency internal security agency
that will take care of making sure that
people don't hurt each other there
another question okay oh there was a
question
yep there is this liberland residency
app which basically is a kind of a pilot
for uber rising police in liberland so
if you want to check it out it's on
android and i think it will be like a
2.0 by the end of the year so you can
see all other labor lenders around you
and you can also kind of declare
emergency and ask them for help but I
was thinking that we can actually run
the the security in a much more
efficient way than a traditional state
through uber izing it okay I have
question related to the finances so how
do you finance it all I mean like from
like everything like flying to Dubai and
then to Somaliland and or whatever or
just of course there is enough liberal
lenders six hundred thousand and if
every single liberal enter paid a
voluntary tax of one dollar a month
which is not the case by far you can
check all the financial statements we
would not have any problems with
financing a flight over to Dubai but
luckily enough we don't have a financial
issues I'm happy that we are able to
pursue all the projects that that we
need at this stage we will need to put
together as a nation some decent amount
of money on the table for Croatia so
they can consider accepting the
protection fee I don't think we will be
able to move without that forward at
some stage Oh a lot of to questions I
just your question is Mary token
publicly traded somewhere not yet and
the whole thing actually depends on
launching the Dow itself I I don't want
to language the token because it will be
connected with with the voting rights
and with the legal system so I want to
launch the token before these rules are
actually defined and we are at least
very close to the final definition of
them I think we are now now some 90%
done we still need another month to
launch the pilot and after we launch the
pilot and we will see that it
successfully works we will also make the
token tradable luckily enough you know
there is a lot of liberal lenders that
have crypto exchanges in the community
so I don't think there will be any
problem with trade ability I think the
last one is
from China it's a decent-size already
krypter krypter exchange and I've almost
forgot one thing
there is another exchange being lunch
out of actually our embassy in
Somaliland so there will be a first
crypto exchange that will be run from a
sovereign soil of liberland and I think
that will be a lot of a lot of fun
they've got that some decent technology
it's not a decentralized exchange it's a
centralized one and the key server will
be placed on a recognized Embassy of
liberland in Somaliland it's kind of a
symbolic thing but I think it's an
important one
thanks Thank You bit good for in
interesting speech I would like to ask
about karate strip because you had to
talk last year in here and shared some
information so if there is some actual
thing about this thank you yeah the
whole the whole thing is now process of
the in process for an update in in terms
of our IT so there will be this simple
IT system where you'll be able to manage
all the registries at once if it's a
boat or if it's a car or if it's a
property everything will be kind of in
one one system and the carriage is tree
we've got a couple cars still driving
around with liberal end plates and
amazingly enough they didn't have a
major issue it's it's funnily enough we
had I I had personally big trouble now
for putting the liberland sticker on the
check license plate but the guy that
drives around with liberal and license
plate didn't have any any issue right
it's kind of ridiculous but this is the
situation now in Czech Republic so so
far you know you can also get a liberal
and license plate which i think is
pretty cool you can actually get a
insurance for it that has been not fully
solved so that's I think the major
obstacle for mass adoption is that we
don't still don't have a insurance
company that would work with us for
longer than half of the year so then you
have to basically register it back but
as long as your car is insured
and has a green card there is no problem
with driving it on liberal and license
plate okay another question okay so it
seems and I'm happy about it that the
Berlin project is moving forward
sorry I wish you a lot of luck
thank you very much Pamela okay so thank
you a lot for coming here I thank you a
lot
also the audience for your questions
I've got some souvenirs if you guys want
it from liberland
what is it
[Music]