yeah so so this is the last session by
tone race analyst trader and content
creator you might know tone ways from
last year's conference because he's
slowly becoming a regular here and he
has a huge experience from Wall Street
and now he is applying it in the
cryptocurrency space so I think it's
gonna be very interesting talk
so last people are getting seated and I
think that I will give the floor to down
enjoy the talk thank you
[Applause]
everyone thank you for coming out and
thank you for hanging in there
I know it's the last session of the day
I'm standing between you and alcohol so
I will do my best to make it quick and
it is gonna be fun so how many of you
watched me here last year oh wow good so
last year I went through the history of
Bitcoin all of its ups and downs
economically and I talked about more of
a Bitcoin price economic perspective and
soon after that presentation I stirred a
new presentation called the inevitable
ICO bubble it's actually still called
the inevitable ICO bubble in the slides
I totally forgot to edit that because on
all the papers it now says has the ICO
bubble popped now the presentation
hasn't changed the environment has and
the presentation talks about the
similarities and very few differences
between what happens in the ICO bubble
and what happened during the dot-com
bubble so what happened
going into most of last year and going
into this year as you know with all of
these icy OS I don't know how many of
you were getting these emails but I know
Jimmy song is sitting in the front row
I'm sure he got him everybody wanted me
to be an advisor for their ICO or their
decentralized project and that actually
forced me to change my LinkedIn summary
and my LinkedIn summary has been saying
the following for six months I am NOT
interested in your ICO token sale or
token sale please send all requests to
victaulic pewter n' instead who is
responsible for this nonsense to know
why your ICO or token sale is probably a
scam my Consulting rate is so-and-so and
I'll be happy to explain it to you
actually this has been around for over a
year
time really flies quickly so I want to
go through a couple of things so one of
the things that people don't realize is
that the price valuations are tend to be
very separate from the actual underlying
fundamental reality now we all know the
internet was an amazing technology but
if you look at the price
history of the Nasdaq which is the
technology stocks built on top of the
Internet we had a peak in March of 2000
look what happened during the crash of
2008 we were not even 50% back we were
at about 50% dropped back then the
Nasdaq the value of the companies
utilizing the Internet did not reach all
time highs until 2015
it took till 2015 took 15 years for the
valuation to go back to the bubble top
but what happened to the Internet during
that time the Internet usage was going
up exponentially smartphones came out in
2007 or eight and even that did not
bring the Nasdaq back to its new
all-time highs so what happens
how do prices get so far out of control
so let's go and take a look let's dive
in to the reality of the Nasdaq bubble
the first company the first major
company to really go IPO was Yahoo in
1996 and that was shortly before alan
greenspan coined the term irrational
exuberance and clearly he was you know
way early to realizing how irrational
people are going to get but yahoo IPO
had an amazing first day it had a 50%
increase in the price of the opening
price and it closed that day at $33 if
you are just up for splits it's about a
dollar 38 in today's prices of Yahoo
stock the next really big notable IPO
was Amazon Amazon want IPO and gained
31% on opening day look there it is when
IPO gained 31 percent of opening day
closed @ 23:50
which is approximately 1.5 dollars in
today's split adjusted price we'll get
to pets.com later that's a really
interesting example but around early
1999 is when things really started to
get out of control and the first notable
company to take those things out of
control was the globe calm the goal calm
was almost like all the things
here today you need to have your own
money the globe calm was you need to be
your own internet you need to have like
your own internet environment you're
gonna be the internet and that company
was that company went up it broke a
record it was up six hundred percent on
the first day of trading that it was
supposed to open at about nine dollars a
share or something like that it closed
the day at sixty three dollars a share
and on opening day traded as high as
ninety seven dollars a share everyone in
that company became multimillionaires
the founders were worth hundreds of
millions and even their web developers
were worth tens of millions of dollars
by 2001 of course this company no longer
existed and it ended in a lot of
lawsuits and it did not end very very
well that was the globe calm now their
record of a 600 percent increase an IPO
day was beaten by VA Linux via Linux
what went public and they were going to
custom-make your Linux machine that
stock opened to a bunch of fanfare the
opening price was at $299 and that was
700 percent above the anticipated ICO
price there is the stock chart of VA
Linux it opened at 300 and in one year
the price was down to about seven
dollars and they got delisted the
following year when the price fell to
under $1 that was VA Linux anyone here
remember cyber rebate because I do and
I'm not I guess I'm old these days is
that so did you use it I used it though
so cyber rebate had an amazing business
model was going to be the future of the
internet so here's their business model
right so this is back in like 1999 we
were in college I think it was even
before mp3 players they were just coming
out so let's talk about a discman right
so a discman would be like I don't know
25 bucks or something for an average
this man they would sell it to you at
250 dollars instead of 25 dollars
but if you fill out this rebate and mail
it to them they will send you the full
rebate of what you paid within six
months so their business model was that
half the people will never turn in their
rebates and they would get to keep the
difference of course that did not happen
and there were over ten people who they
owed over a hundred thousand dollars to
the company went bankrupt and people got
paid about nine cents on the dollar
these were some of the ideas that were
coming out at the height of the real
estate bubble real sorry at the height
of the Nasdaq bubble now of course when
you have the money you start to make
crazy deals a Oh L bought Time Warner
Cable for 156 billion dollars it's
bigger than the entire crypto space
combined and I think neither company
exists today or Time Warner Cable only
has a few days left
thanks to Netflix so I a bubble is one
thing right but some people can get out
at the top it's all about finding a way
to get out at the top and sometimes you
need to be more lucky than good here is
one of those examples broadcast calm and
before broadcast a common was audio net
before audio net I think I already
forgot the name of it but what year was
and I think 1995 was it around 1995 Mark
Cuban invested $10,000 into a company
for the sole purpose of being able to
listen to his Indiana college basketball
games on the internet and their goal was
to put radio on the internet with his
ten thousand dollar investment he
initially only owned like maybe ten
percent of the company or something but
he was the better businessman he
convinced the CEO that he should be the
CEO in order to take the company to
another level and they agreed the
founder of the founders of the company
took a much smaller role Mark Cuban took
over Mark Cuban took the company public
in 1998 they rebranded from audio net to
broadcast com took the company public
the moment they took the company public
was worth 1 billion dollars and Mark
Cuban was worth 300 million nine months
after taking the company public Yahoo
bought them out for I believe six
billion dollars
am I making Mark Cuban a billionaire who
in Yahoo stock which he immediately sold
and cashed out within two years Yahoo
delisted broadcast.com and it was gone
so that's the story of Mark Cuban
becoming a billionaire basically through
creating audio net so if you can get out
at the top you do well now that's that
corrected about 80% and Wikipedia has an
amazing list of all of the other success
stories or people thought they were
success stories but here's an
interesting thing because there's a lot
of similarities to what happened back
then to what's happening today let's
take a look at a digital it digital
changed its name from Norris
communications to e digital in January
of 1999 when the stock was at a whopping
six cents by changing the name later
that day the stock price was at two
dollars and 91 cents and or by December
within a month it was two dollars and 91
cents and then early of the and then
within a month after that it reached the
price of $24.50 so by changing your name
from Norris corporations to e digital
within two months your stock goes from
six cents to $24.50 okay
of course the SEC took notice and didn't
like it and we already had a few similar
stories right here is a penny stock it
was trading at about five cents they
announced that they were gonna do an IC
o---- and the stock pops to 40 cents
the SEC gets involved a little bit later
here's a better one the Long Island iced
tea company soars in its price on the
exchange because they have changed their
name to the Long Island blockchain again
everything you've seen that's happening
it's all happened before there is
nothing new here
and what not happened there was a good
quote from the Bloomberg article where
someone says it's so reminiscent of what
happened in the late 1990s sets
carnations or for author of the book the
history of the United States and five
crashes
a company would simply change its name
to something to do with the internet and
their stock would absolutely soar so
what happened the stock was worth it
looks like it was worth under $2 the
moment they announced that it says it
right there in the print the stock went
up to six dollars and 91 cents but there
takes about an hour from the story that
gets written to the story that gets
published you can clearly see in the
graphic that the stock went all the way
up to $16 so from $2 to $16 for the Long
Island iced tea company by changing
changing it from iced tea to blockchain
so that was pretty amazing I'm not sure
if the SEC got involved or not now let's
talk about pets.com I actually do not
make fun of pets.com
because if we go if we go and take a
look when pets.com went public it was
only about nine months after Amazon went
public and here's the thing pets.com is
Amazon right they didn't do anything
different Amazon was selling books
pets.com was selling pet supplies both
had the same business model and no one
knew which company was actually going to
succeed do you know why I'm confident
and saying that anyone want to take a
guess who the biggest investor in
pets.com was before the IPO Amazon
Amazon was the biggest investor of
pets.com
before they went public so even they
didn't know right and this gets into
this whole topic of does the average
person why doesn't the average person
have the ability to invest in these
speculative pre-ipo companies in a
speculative pre ICO companies because
you missed out on all those gains of
Facebook the rich people prevented you
from profiting from Facebook here's what
they don't tell you none of you would
have been invested in
book my money would have been in my
space I like my space I hated Facebook
coming in I had to redo everything I
spent so much time learning HTML setting
up my MySpace page I don't know how many
of you were there back then and so many
other social medias so social networking
companies were there before Facebook
friend ster was there women was there
hi-5 was there there were so many of
them it didn't end and no one knew
Facebook was gonna win and they won and
the average person unless they have the
ability to invest in all of them would
have never done it the time to invest in
Facebook was after the IPO the IPO was
grossly overhyped that fell over 50%
within the first few months of the IPO
but what about after that Facebook IPO
at $40 it fell to 20 bounce to 25 fell
to 17 and then went to 200 okay even if
you invested it for at 40 you still made
about five or six times your money if
you waited a few months and boarded at
20 you made ten times your money with
almost no risk almost no risk of
speculation are they gonna get wiped out
by the next Facebook okay so this
concept that the average people should
be investing in speculative companies
completely crazy because the majority of
VCS they don't beat the S&P 500 they
actually lose people money but the
difference is they're losing money for
people that can afford to lose it which
is not the kind of people that have been
buying up all of these icos
which we'll get to in a little bit so so
what else that we think we're seeing for
the first time that was actually
attempted back then well how about
currency for the internet let's play
this video and check it out
gotta get a gift for a kid you don't
know what they want cause you're all old
honey give them flows online gift cards
it's just like when you send it by email
they spent it at some of the web's
coolest stores and you come out hip and
smoke it's graduation day da that was
actually a Super Bowl commercial at one
point and so that was Whoopi Goldberg
I'm advertising flues and lost
thank you and flues was attempting to
put currency unique to the internet but
here's the problem just like everything
else other than Bitcoin they were
centralized so how did flues end in 2001
flues comm was notified by the FBI that
a Russian organized crime syndicate was
using flus and stolen credit card
numbers as part of their
money-laundering scheme in which stolen
credit cards were used to purchase
currency that word then redeemed at
stores so that did not end very well for
flues and they blew through about 35 to
15 million dollars of capital and that's
how flus ended Oh can I get control of
the go thank you I am okay cool thank
you so one more story of how again
similarities when you start googling for
interesting stories of the current
environment and then you're like hey has
this happened before
and here's one so sometime in 1999 in
San Francisco some guy had a really cool
idea so what did he do with that idea he
wrote up what is now called the white
paper he created a nice website and he
purchased a really awesome billboard and
put it in a high-traffic area in San
Francisco with the funding that he
raised now what did that lead to a
company bought him out for a hundred
million dollars however they wanted to
make sure they integrate his idea so
they gave him a contract you have to
stay with us for three years to
integrate your idea into our company and
then you get to keep your hundred
million after about three weeks they
realized that the guy was kind of
useless so they said why don't you leave
take the hundred million we will
integrate your idea on our own so as
he's leaving he realized he never really
had an idea and he was able to short
that company and
himself another hundred million dollars
and it all started with a billboard and
oh no maybe the battery died
nope that's unfortunate because I have a
lot of slides and and that all started
with the Billboard and that really and I
was I found this story at the same time
as consensus yeah this is not gonna be
convenient though I found that story the
same time as I was at the last consensus
and there it is I look out the window
and what do I see in Times Square a
giant billboard of us before they raised
the four billion dollars for iOS ok
looks like so how do a lot of these
things end well
that's like oh it's not a clicker
awesome thank you so much cool so how do
a lot of these things n how many of you
saw the movie wolf of wallstreet hope
every hand goes up there it is alright
so but does anyone know what did Jordan
Belfort actually go to prison for it
wasn't for his extracurricular
activities it was actually for financial
fraud but what kind of financial fraud
was it it was very briefly explained in
the movie for only 15 seconds have a
listen and then think about what a pre
ICO is let's go ahead and play it
an IPO is an initial public offering
it's the first time a stock is off the
for sale to the general population
now as the firm taking the company
public we set the initial sales priced
and sold those shares right back to our
friends yeah no you're not following
what I'm saying anyway right that's
that's okay that doesn't matter the real
question is this was all this legal
absolutely not but we will make
more money than we know what to do with
you guys catch that because that was it
right so basically by being able to set
the initial sales price because they
were taking the company public what
happens is you know what the actual
valuation is and you know what it's
gonna open up and you know who to sell
those early shares to and you know when
those people will be able to get out on
a profit and you know they kind of kick
back you're going to get with that Plus
you have shares yourself so that is the
reason why today very few companies are
allowed to take the company public
because they're able to keep their
mouths shut and they're not going to be
dishing out preferential treatment to
the pre IPO companies and this is why so
many people are complaining how come I
have to pay Goldman Sachs and JP Morgan
or Deutsche Bank in order to take my
company public and it costs billions of
dollars and that's pretty much why
because a lot of very notable people got
in trouble for this
so this is a courtroom you know
pronounce his name Frank Quattrone and
he was sentenced and he was involved in
in IPOs of Amazon and Netflix and he was
involved in several of the other
high-profile IPOs and he also got in
trouble I think he appealed and was able
to get out of a prison sentence but hey
that's connections pretty much so so
that's pretty much so some of the
similarities that we had during the.com
and I'm gonna wrap it up with another
little thing that you know I realized
that during the ico bubble I was always
fascinated because I was still in my
University
the dot-com bubble I didn't graduate
till like 2002 2003 so it was already
over but while I was there a couple of
my friends were finance majors I wasn't
that was a science major at the time and
I remember one of my dorm mates he was
also like 18 19 he borrowed a thousand
dollars from his brother and he would
like run into the common area talk about
the latest penny stocks that he bought
and he's like trading penny stocks
because all he has is a thousand dollars
and I didn't understand any of that at
the time and then when I learned trading
in like 2003 2004 from the people that
survived the trading environment of the
dot-com bubble you know it always
fascinated me how things got so out of
control how does a company trade on the
Nasdaq for $100 a share and then two
years later it's gone because there was
anything it wasn't anything underneath
how do people get into that how does
that happen and then you hear all these
stories hey when your taxi driver starts
telling you about the latest IPO when
your barber starts telling you about the
latest IPO and my barber they come to me
to buy a Bitcoin at 16,000 that was
great uh-huh
and how does that happen well that to me
I thought that that happened because of
things like etrade and scotch right who
remembers the e-trade baby commercials
right so the one difference between
trading in the 80s and trading in the
late 90s is that now you can trade from
your own living room all of a sudden
there weren't these boiler rooms that
had to call high net worth individuals
all there was was you you can open an
account but it still wasn't as easy
right
not everyone can trade almost anyone can
trade you still needed to be 18 there
was an age restriction there was a
geographical restriction right if you're
somewhere in India you can't trade the
Nasdaq US companies and there was you
know you needed a bank account you need
to have some money and if you want it to
be a day trader or a speculator you need
a $25,000 the three day rule or you got
to hold your positions for
three days if you don't have $25,000 so
there were some restrictions and all of
those restrictions are now gone so I
would not have been surprised if this or
if the bubble is not even over because
this bubble could go global because
there's no restrictions at all there's
no financial restriction there's no
geographical restriction you only have
$100 to your name no bank account please
go and trade go use the no kyc exchanges
no one is stopping you the funniest one
however is no age restriction because
here it is from my email box do mr. vase
I am 15 and a half years old and in high
school I am interested in Bitcoin and I
read and I've been reading your Twitter
posts
I have fifteen hundred dollars in
savings and is asking for trading advice
but at least he's asking about Bitcoin
oops I shouldn't submit on the other one
here's a better one I'm gonna
conversation on slack and here goes I
got a few of some Tolkien I can't really
see it the xcp I think no it's not like
CP something else and asking me if I've
heard of it and I say no I have not
heard of it not really interested is and
the person replies well it's a game and
Tolkien I'm like oh I'm not interested
well I'm 13 so I am kind of interested
in a gaming token so these are your
traders guys these are the people that
are buying those pre I SEOs that are the
insiders get first and then they sell
them to these people those are your
second-level buyers I really like these
tweets by Alex Markos he says here's one
big difference between traditional
startup funding and icos
founders of failed startups shouldn't
come away financially enriched risk
capital to explore ideas is great but
incentives aren't aligned if founders
make money at expense of investors
regardless of outcomes I followed up on
that I just to clarify the difference
between icos
and everything else because I had to
reply to someone that just didn't get
the fact that I SEOs are just
centralized schemes what are their
securities what are their you know
printing
their own money doesn't really matter
they're basically there to separate
unqualified investors from their
hard-earned dollars or Bitcoin bitcoin
is actually a new decentralized asset
class bitcoin is the asset class not
crypto just Bitcoin you don't
decentralize Bitcoin by buying into like
you don't decentralize Google by buying
into Google's competitors who are worth
$1 a share and Bitcoin can be used as a
currency and you know and it has its
properties on confiscate about
censorship resistant and hard monetary
policy that's pretty much it I do want
to close out this presentation with a
short video well maybe not that short
it's a ten minute video it was a recent
documentary that I watched and it really
and the documentary was made in 2012 he
just paused that for one second just
look at her and the documentary is me in
2012 the research was done started in
2002 so this was all done before the
world of crypto there was one part in
there about maybe five minutes in pay
attention to it it's called distance
from money the documentary is dishonesty
that shoot about lies and it really
resonated with me and the current ICO
environment so let's have a listen and
we'll do Q&A right after
[Music]
my baby Stella really and I'm interested
in human behavior I'm interested in
rationality and irrationality I'm
interested in the cases in which we make
good decisions and the cases in which we
make bad decisions and in the last few
years we've been focusing on dishonesty
we watch corporate scandals everyone
Enron
WorldCom the financial crisis of 2008 we
saw an increase in cheating in
professional sports witness political
deception and it's huge repercussions as
the NSA collect any type of data at all
on millions or hundreds of millions of
Americans no sir but one thing we want
to look at the mirror and think that
we're good honest wonderful people on
the other hand we want to benefit
selfishly from being dishonest as long
as we choose just a little bit we don't
have to pay any price in terms of the
image and the way we view ourselves and
we call this the fudge factor so this is
the ability to misbehave and think of
ourselves as good people and you can
think about all kinds of ways in which
in your own life you have a fudge factor
the speed limit maybe it says 55 but are
you okay in driving 60 what about
cheating a little bit on taxes what
about exaggerating their online dating
profile across many studies we find that
everything that changes the fudge factor
also changes people's ability to be
dishonest there are dozens of elements
that can change the magnitude of the
fudge and we've been able to observe
many of them in the lab for example if
you can say to yourself everybody's
doing it it's easier for you to
rationalize to yourself that this is
actually an OK thing to do and cheat to
a higher degree
dishonesty we need to be able to measure
hopefully precisely the extent to which
people are dishonest so we have all
kinds of methods I'll describe one of
them you can just haven't seen anywhere
with a packet and a band in front of it
we gave people 20 simple math problems
find the two numbers that add up to 10
these are problems if everybody could
solve if they had enough time but we
don't give people enough time we are
going to give you five minutes to solve
as many as possible at the end of the
five minutes please stop put your pencil
down and count how many questions you
got correctly and now that you know how
many questions you got correctly take
the sheet of paper go to the front of
the room and shred it people do that
they come to the front they say they
sold six problems pay them six dollars
they go home what the people in the
experiment don't know is that we played
with the shredder
the shredders for the size of the page
but the body of the page remains intact
and what do we find on average it will
solve four problems and report to be
solving six so six no this is
embarrassing a lot but I got six I
believe I got seven right we've ran
these experiments on 40,000 people and
so far we found about 20 big cheaters
those are people who cheated all the way
said they solved 20 problems and they
stole $400 from us
we also found about 20-some thousand
little cheaters and they stole about
$50,000 from us I think this is not a
bad reflection of reality yes there's
some big cheaters out there but they are
very rare and because of that their
overall economic impact is relatively
low on the other hand we have a ton of
real cheaters and because there are so
many of us the economic impact of small
cheating is actually incredibly
incredibly high in one project then and
I decided to look at what's the
influence of others unethical behavior
on our own decisions to cheat so we
designed an experiment with different
type of conditions so imagine the same
experiment I described to you before but
with one main difference we hired an
acting student and thirty second into
the experiment he raised his head yeah
and they say I solved everything what do
I do next
I should come up here so this is 30
seconds into the experiment you are
still on question number one
there is no question in your mind that
that purse is cheating and the
experiment has said you finished
everything you're free to go and you see
that person taking all the amount of
money and going home what would happen
to your own morality
well lots more people cheat but it could
be two explanations here one explanation
is we just proved to people that in this
experiment there is no downside for
cheating the second possibility is that
it's not about the fact that they
wouldn't catch you it's about the fact
that it's actually socially okay and so
we decided to study this by looking at
whether the person cheating is somebody
like us somebody we feel similar to or
somebody who's very different from us we
run this experiment at Carnegie Mellon
everybody was a Carnegie Mellon student
the acting student was a Carnegie Mellon
student we dressed the acting student in
the University of Pittsburgh switcher
now what happens if your University of
Carnegie Mellon student and the
Pittsburgh student cheats you still know
that you can get away with it here's the
proof that somebody goes home with all
the money but you don't think that
people like you are doing it and what
happens now cheating goes down so it's
not about the probability of being
caught it's about the question of what
is socially acceptable in our circle
so imagine the same experiment I
described earlier you fill in your
sheets you solve these little problems
you shred the piece of paper and you
come to the experimenter you tell them
how much money you deserve
you tell it in tokens I solved X
problems I deserve X tokens so now you
pay them in pieces of plastic they take
this piece of plastic walk 12 feet to
the side and change it $4 so when
somebody looked you in the eyes and they
lied is all right for my denied for
something else but that thing becomes
money very quickly what happened in our
experiment people double-dutch it this
by the way is the most troubling result
I think we got think about the society
we're moving away from money credit
cards stop stock options derivatives
delivered people over great distances
could it be that as these distances and
all of their versions are increasing
people find it easier to misbehave and
still think of themselves off ourselves
as good people I think the answer is
absolutely absolutely yes
took all the elements that we studied
and we combined them into one
environment we would get an environment
that is very similar the one that's
operated in the financial crisis of 2008
generations is Wall Street absorb the
number of body blows it took today three
of the five biggest investment banks are
gone the country's biggest mortgage
lender is gone we had politicians banker
regulators and even investors all
influenced by many factors
self-deception social norms distance
from money lying for the benefits of
other and of course conflicts of
interest and this is what I think
corruption is all about it's about that
when you get into a system and something
in the system tells you that things are
wrong there all of a sudden you abandon
your own moral fiber and because of that
we need to figure out what can we do
about it how can we get people to behave
better because if we don't we're just
going to get more and more disasters
like the one we've just experienced many
of the experiments that we have
conducted are about trying to find ways
to curb dishonesty we went to UCLA and
we asked about 500 undergrads to try and
recall the Ten Commandments
how many of them do you think recalled
all 10 commandments zero that's right
by the way they invented lots of
interesting ones what happened after
people tried to recall the Ten
Commandment even if they weren't
successful nobody cheated
it wasn't the 60 people who remembered
more Commandments the people who are
presumably more religious cheated less
and the people who remembered almost
none of them cheated more nobody cheated
it didn't matter what religion the
participants had you know what the Ten
Commandments are about they are about
the moral code they are about proper
behavior and just knowing that and being
reminded of that decreases dishonesty in
fact even when we take self declared
atheist ask them to swirl the Bible they
stop cheating it is not about heaven and
hell and being caught it's about
reminding ourselves about our own moral
fiber
we found this result to be very
promising but we wanted to test it in a
non-religious context so we went to MIT
and we did a similar experiment with
Oracle's so he got students at MIT to
sign the honor code I understand that
this short study falls under the MIT
honor code they did it shredded a piece
of paper what happened no cheating
whatsoever and no cheating whatsoever
despite the fact that MIT doesn't happen
on account then we replicated the
experiment at Princeton Princeton has a
very strong honor in fact the freshmen
get the whole week of crash course on
morality lectures discussion so we took
the Princeton students signing the honor
code and not signing the honor code the
MIT students signing the honor code or
not was there any difference no when
they did not sign the honor code they
both give it to the same level when they
sign the honor code none of them cheated
nothing this is kind of a mixture of
good news and bad news the bad news is
the crash course on morality
particularly the Princeton version
doesn't seem to have any effect two
weeks down the road the good news is
that even without a crash
reminding people about the road moral
fiber
does change how people behave
alright guys hope you enjoyed that video
and that's it for the presentation and
I'm open to Q&A
[Applause]
let me ask first question because I
think it's it would be interesting if
you can like tie this to your
presentation do you think that what is
happening in the crypto space is related
right it was the the thing that really
ties this to the presentation was the
Tolkien part right and like we even call
them tokens when I the distance from
money and tokens because you're just
selling tokens you're selling or what
they've called them software licenses
they've called you know utility tokens
you know you call it whatever you like
and then oh look at all of this distance
from money well now you gotta you need
aetherium to get it and then you have to
turn a theorem into Bitcoin and then
eventually you turn Bitcoin into money
so the further you are from the actual
money the more you feel okay in doing
what you're doing but at the end of the
day well if the ico bubble has popped it
actually wasn't that bad but if we were
to reach you know Nasdaq level
proportions and potentially we could
have gone higher because it's no age
restrictions less restrictions more
global the world as a whole is Richard
today than it was back in 2000 because
you know again the world is generally
gets richer over time so we could have
been a lot worse so I kind of hoped the
ico bubble popped because otherwise it
would have been a lot worse so I think
that part really should resonate with a
lot of people and what these tokens
sellers are doing Thanks
do you think like just like after the
internet bubble pop there were a few
legitimate companies that came up you
know 15 to 20 years later the same thing
will happen with icos sure but you said
it in your question you said the word
companies they're companies right of
course there could be companies if they
manage you know to somehow convince the
SEC that you know not to arrest them or
whatever because they can't arrest
everyone right so sure companies can
come out of this right can a lot of
these I SEOs be converted to traditional
stocks maybe right because they have no
utility as a currency they'd have no
utility as a utility token either right
like where would Amazon be today if you
have to buy everything from Amazon with
Amazon stock or Netflix stock right I
mean this is the the recurrence right
well you have to use our token to use
our product and our token has this
financial component where it changes in
value every second of every day so it's
literally like eBay only charging eBay
stock that fluctuates in value for their
products how do you acquire eBay stock
well you got to go to each trade or you
got to go to you know Ameritrade you got
to go to each trade and by eBay stock
okay how do I go to each trade and by
eBay stock well each trade only accepts
the currency of each trade stock in
order to buy anything from each trade
right so so you see the problem here
right it's like every person speaking
their own language and you gotta somehow
communicate so none of these things work
they just make stuff up so could there
be companies that come out of this sure
but I wouldn't be looking at those
companies again I see Bitcoin as like
the fundamental layer we have one
Internet one Internet today we're gonna
have one public blockchain of any use
everything else is gonna be just private
centralized stuff so whichever companies
are utilizing the Bitcoin blockchain
those companies can succeed and they are
already succeeding several mining
companies are succeeding very well I
mean bit Maine is a little bit debatable
but they could have a you know their
value only themselves
billion-dollar IPO bitfury successful
Avalon is actually gonna go probably go
public before a bit name because they're
cleaner company
I mean coinbase is a pretty big company
I personally think they were a disaster
but you know is it possible for a crypto
exchange lie like who owns the New York
Stock Exchange well New York Stock
Exchange is owned by I see I see it was
also an exchange it was a futures
exchange it's actually not as old as the
rest but they did very well they did
great they made a lot of money and they
bought the New York Stock Exchange so
it's owned by I see could it be possible
that a crypto exchange has created such
efficiency in the world in the concept
of being an exchange and they got so
rich and made so much money that they
will then buy the New York Stock
Exchange
they will then buy the Nasdaq right so
companies that utilize Bitcoin well
those companies can certainly succeed
well any of these ICO companies succeed
I doubt it maybe one or two of them will
but even if they will there's 3,000 of
them out there I'm not gonna pick the
winners and losers I'm gonna wait
because picking the winners and losers
is a horrible gamble and it's not worth
it you're already seeing so many people
that got rich a year ago are more broke
today than than they were before thanks
a lot
hi what's your general opinion about
tokenization of securities and good
Bitcoin bubble could be indirectly
driven by security Jesus say the
beginning again yeah what's your general
opinion about security tokens and good
next big going bubble being directly
driven by security tokens I'm not
exactly sure what security tokens are
right I mean if you were security you
were security so if you're a security
token right I mean if you're a security
you are trading on a centralized
exchange like the Nasdaq or New York
Stock Exchange if you were security
token you're trading on top of an
insecure technologically and all over
the place layer right whether it's a
theory em whether it's aetherium classic
iOS who knows right so by going with the
security token model you are basically
putting every one of your investors at
technological risk and regulatory risk
because what happens if the regulator's
want to come down on your underlying
layer right like what happens if you are
a security token and people own your
token and aetherium you know has another
hard fork or which is probably will
between proof of stake and proof of work
right like how do you explain that
like like by creating a security token
on top of a a layer you don't understand
you may have a problem down the road and
saying well I didn't know a theorem was
gonna collapse maybe an excuse it may
not be an excuse but I think you're
taking an unnecessary risk if you're
gonna be a security just be a security
so the security token part that doesn't
really make sense to me because of the
layer that you're on look I I have found
you know two or three legitimate icos
out there built the CRC 20 on top of
etherium and by legitimate I don't mean
good investments I mean that they're
honest about what they actually created
it they weren't printing money for
themselves and they actually had a use
case now they still have the technology
problem because they're building on top
of something that is just not
sustainable and not scalable but at
least now I can't mention these things
because I don't want people speculating
on them because I think they're terrible
speculative instruments they're not
designed for that but people will
speculate them on anyway so there are a
few honest ones and they can just
migrate they're not tied to that system
but if you're tied to your underlying
system you gotta trust it I mean I mean
I trust a Bitcoin blockchain that's why
I I know I have value on the Bitcoin
blockchain but I don't trust any other
blockchain to put my life savings on god
forbid my company on to it where
employees are now dependent on it yeah
but but security Cana tokens can be
based on blockchain Bitcoin blockchain
yeah well I mean when they are sure if
that the Denisova then it's probably
okay but I would I think it's too early
I mean
Bitcoin may not be here in a year right
it needs more time
it needs more confidence how many people
were quitting their jobs and starting a
business on the Internet in the you know
early to mid 90s it took a while it took
people the confidence to say hey the
internet isn't going anywhere I'm gonna
wake up in the morning and the internet
will be working when more people you
know have the confidence that they're
gonna wake up in the morning and Bitcoin
is working and it has been Bitcoin has
like 99.99% uptime if that can continue
for another five to seven years that we
could see something like that security
tokens built on top of Bitcoin because
that's a strong layer that will be
functioning every single day at 99.99
percent hopefully better up time but
etherium doesn't have that kind of
uptime and but it may now because
etherium has competitors now so now you
can create your IC o---- on everything
and i've been saying for a while i cos
they don't need a decentralized platform
their centralized entities every IC
o---- is a centralized entity it's part
of a company the last thing they need is
an unsecured decentralized most
inefficient blockchain to move on they
want efficiency Bitcoin layer is not the
most efficient database is probably the
most inefficient database right so you
would need a sidechain maybe a rootstock
will do something maybe you can build
something with lightning you need
efficiency you don't need the
centralization there you just need the
ability to quickly move something and
the centralized database can do it
better
now the current centralized databases
are kind of old so maybe they're not
doing it better but the future
centralized databases will do it much
better they can call it a blockchain but
we all know that you know if it's not
proof of work it's not really a
blockchain that's the invention of
Satoshi Thanks more questions Oh while
we were for this question
um so I'm sure everybody knows Jimi song
as well we are doing our traditional
corn every dinner Sunday night so if you
google our corn every dinner or go to
Jimmy's Twitter or I'll tweet it out as
well so
there's an event pray so you can sign up
if you want and that's gonna happen
Sunday night at Brazilian barbecue here
in town so just Google car never eat
dinner Prague and they'll show up at an
event bright
oh right their question was hoping that
you could reiterate possibly your
confidence you stated previously that we
have one Internet I think the the
reality of the structure of the Internet
is quite a bit more complicated than
that in terms of where packets can
originate where they can go where
information can flow I was hoping that
you could perhaps reiterate your
confidence that Bitcoin will be the
ultimate Victor amongst all of the
different coins out there some of which
addressed serious flaws in Bitcoin which
enhance certain features such as
fungibility or allow for different use
cases that Bitcoin simply isn't intended
to address so if you could perhaps
reiterate why you think that Bitcoin
will be this this one public join and
other other coins will show so you're
right the internet is pretty complicated
under the hood too complicated for me to
even comment on it because I don't
really understand it but what I do know
is that I only have to build my website
on one place I'm not building my website
on five different internet so that's
convenient I know China kind of has
their own thing and I think that's been
holding them back a little bit I think
China could have done much better by
being more technologically open as far
as Bitcoin being the final winner well
Bitcoin had several things going for it
that not nothing else did a Bitcoin is
by far the most decentralized a coin we
have the reason for that is Satoshi was
invisible Bitcoin doesn't have a leader
any other coin has a leader a lot of the
other coins I don't hear
so much anymore because I guess the
trend has died talking about we have
better governance well if you have
better governance then you are simply
more centralized no one controls Bitcoin
between the nodes we have nodes we have
miners we have core developers it's by
far the most decentralized core
developer team it's by far the most
decentralized mining operation and it's
by far the most distributed token we
have so while some coins temporarily
might have better privacy they might be
faster but they're the reason why
they're faster is because usually
nobody's using them Bitcoin does have
the brightest minds and I in any like
miles away from any other project and
it's not the fact that it was first it's
the fact that it grew in the wild
nothing else grew in the wild everything
else has central leaders and people that
have a disproportional say in what
happens next with that token they are
much more coerced and those other tokens
are a lot easier to infiltrate and
they're a lot easier to you know create
future bugs so you just can't replicate
what Bitcoin did it was worthless for a
year and a half people were working on
it the amount of money and effort that
got put that was and still is being
putting being put into mining is just
not replicatable any other token is at
risk of being attacked because you have
a higher level token like Bitcoin to
move that money into and still profit
Bitcoin is the only one where this
current bug that was found like only 7%
of the nodes are upgraded to fix that
bug so while no one is going to execute
that bug because all you will do is
destroy all the block chains right and
external people can't execute it because
you need a giant mining operation that
is already functioning and executing
that kind of a bug on Bitcoin would just
ruin confidence in all
blockchains and everything goes to zero
Bitcoin is has the highest store of
value property right so here's the thing
myself included and I'm sure many of you
in the audience and a lot of people with
a lot more Bitcoin than me have been
trusting Bitcoin with their store of
value imagine if all of that goes to
zero why would I ever trust any other
blockchain with a store of value like
there's only one shot to get the store
of value right and if it's not like
switching from MySpace to Facebook there
was no store of value property so if the
store of value has to transfer to
another coin why would anyone trust that
coin with future store of value you can
just be replaced by another blockchain
so the store of value property is gone
and when a store of value property is
gone what you have is the Venezuelan
peso right you just want to get rid of
it as fast as you can I mean sure I mean
bitcoin is the only currency that I
except for my workshops and stuff but I
keep most of it in Bitcoin for as long
as I can if the store of value property
of Bitcoin is gone I'll accept by an
arrow I'll accept the coins I'll
accept anything it doesn't matter
because the moment I get it
the first thing I'm going to do with it
is I'm gonna sell it for the US dollar
and then the next thing I'm going to do
what is it I'm moving into the S&P 500
because that your best store of value is
the stock market which has gone up what
10,000 percent since the creation of the
Fed you're your gold coin still buys you
a suit like it did in 1930s but if you
sold that coin in you know in the 1920s
instead of you know holding on to that
gold coin you sold it in 1920 you put it
in the stock market probably by I don't
know 100,000 suits today so your store
of value needs to adjust for inflation
and increase in technology which the
stock indices do I think bitcoin is a
great store of value for now hopefully
it will continue but yeah the store of
all your property is huge and people
underestimate that people think that you
can just move store of value somewhere
else you can't
all right so we're back for one more
yeah yeah yes oh yeah last question okay
so you mentioned the stock market is the
best investment but if Bitcoin becomes
the global currency having Bitcoin
savings will be the same as having it in
a global index fund do you agree um it's
a different type of investment I mean
Bitcoin is still going up in value very
very quickly because it's so young and
you know the world isn't using it you
know if Bitcoin is still with us 50
years from now 100 years from now it may
not increase in value any more at that
point because population isn't always
increasing right I mean we look at Japan
look at Europe I think America's birth
rate is still higher so all of these
fears that the world is gonna get
overpopulated they're not exactly true
most modern countries the birth rate
starts to decline like Japan has a huge
problem with this so eventually for now
sure I mean as long as Bitcoin is
becoming as long as Bitcoin is rising
you can look at oil the same way right
like in what eighteen eighty you bought
a bunch of land in Texas you stuck a
shovel in the ground and a bunch of
black goo came out you just got you know
scammed for buying land 20 years later
it's the greatest thing that ever
happened to you right and the price of
oil like skyrocketed during you know
during the 20s the 30s the 40s but the
price of oil has pretty much stabilized
right I mean no one sees oil these days
as that speculation and increase in
value so that can happen to Bitcoin but
that's a long time away and then once
again we're back to capitalism were back
to doing something productive you know a
bad companies disappear Kodak was the
number one company in the 80s now it's
gone
you know blockbuster was doing well now
it's gone
no now we have you know Amazon and
Netflix and Google and Apple and in 20
years there could be different companies
replacing them because companies come
and go so eventually when Bitcoin no
longer has that early stage growth it
will be it will just be the currency of
the world and you're back to having you
know companies as your investments
you just have to diversify can you know
put everything into a single company
because they come and go all right thank
you so much stone for this talk
thank you thanks guys this was the last
session of today but you don't have to
go home we have a party starting in
front of studio one we will have a live
music performance tonight and tomorrow
we open at 9:00 a.m. and the first talks
start at 1:00 p.m.
enjoy tonight don't get drunk too much
but also not too late oh and enjoy the
evening and sooo tomorrow