[Music]
[Applause]
you
hi everyone welcome to the stream from
para una pelea streaming zone about
heckles Congress Peron police 2018 this
is too much c'mon the main coordinator
of Equis Congress today the production
stage and I think it will be a bit of
freestyle right so it took us a while
until we set it up all these devices
here so because we have new streaming
studio it's still there are a few things
that are still settling down whenever
I'm witnessing this kind of setup issues
I'm kind of like worried like what the
bigger come much more complex system
might be exposed to potential failures
aren't you scared some sometimes like
speaking of power plants or frameworks
because you're and absolutely really big
apologies to those who have been waiting
for our live streaming and we're not
that and dropped out again it's recorded
session so anyone can access it
afterwards before we move to hackers
Congress another so because I have not
been there but if you look at Def Con
and you've been there for a couple of
days now so and the question would be
how different is to the Congress we have
had in October so is it brutal
commercial driven event
I guess surprising kind of surprising
it's like but it's no problem for them
to come and pay for a coffee or
something so if you would if you should
pick one thing that is inspiring that we
can take into our concept what would
that be that's like hard to say
I guess because there is so so much
staff at the conference everything runs
runs smoothly you could say the
registrations there was plenty of stuff
to do the registrations but I came a bit
a bit later so maybe it was different in
the beginning but also the catering and
everything there is like lots of
information now you can see that that
the conference is professionally
organized like obviously at every
conference you have some organizational
issues maybe you talk about some during
this stream but it all looks really
professional but one thing that's very
different from us is that the conference
starts at 10 a.m. and ends at about 5
p.m. or or half past 5:00 p.m. so it
starts rather early for us and it ends
very early but in the evening there is
like party everyday like someone is
organizing the DEF CON parties side
events and so on right now we have the
prague blockchain week running some of
the events are here in parallel police
so like the the side program is very
rich and the schedule is accommodating
to this to these events
I must definitely agree that these side
events is something that maybe we could
work on for coming years
speaking of not failures but some
challenges as you remember we discussed
like we could organize some kind of
crypto Expo or some parallel event that
would be open not only to the Congress
goers but also to draw the audience we
we were discussing to organize it in
space which is quite near to our window
to our know yes and that and torn a
space is perfectly great fit I mean for
such kind of even but I'm coming back to
where we started like when you're making
things a bit more complicated so it's
your complexity increases the
exponential way right so and my role as
a lead coordinator I was always trying
to be focused in terms of keeping things
simple so we are very good and inventive
when it comes to like crazy new ideas
which needs to be managed right because
sometimes there are so many ideas and
things you can organize and go for but
in the end it has to be delivered right
so do if you have too much only on your
plate the bigger the risk for failures
so and after some discussions with this
Expo into Varna we simply arrive to
conclusion that maybe it's not worth
risking de railing from our core focus
which is the event itself I think that
actually people appreciate it that the
whole event is concentrated in this mmm
relatively small venue compared to
DEFCON s and they actually I appreciate
that there is very little commerce at
hackers Congress if you come to echoes
Congress you barely see any any like
brands and and company logos basically
the only space where you see that is on
this stage but more or less nowhere else
like there are there very few stands of
the main sponsors but nothing else so
that's something that that sets hackers
Congress apart from the other
conferences because there is so little
commerce compared to them you mentioned
two aspects right so first is the the
size of the event
and speaking of size we are fairly
limited right because we are having this
building which accommodates only small
portion
of the attending goers but and this is
also it sometimes you need to have luck
right so the the attached building the
la fábrica the new space is perfect I
would say enlargement of our existing
space but there are some physical
limitations and I've had like rounds of
discussions like hey guys you're doing
great job let's expand let's go for
bigger event let's maybe change location
and arrange much bigger Congress that
you would definitely sell out right but
it's not about selling more tickets or
filling in more people right because the
key driver for us is the quality of
speakers the content the spirit and
we've had a number of feedback responses
and people were basically saying hey
guys great even but please do not expand
we don't want to end up in some like
arena kind of commercial site right so
this is definitely something which we
are taking extremely seriously and this
is our differentiator right because
there are a lot of events now nowadays
out there and we want to preserve this
unique spirit this intimacy this
opportunity for networking for basically
no commercial kind of
discussions and this is what people
really appreciate and definitely it's on
our priority list very high if there are
basically two approaches that you can
take if you have popular conference and
you cannot accommodate all the people
the people in into the venue well either
you find a new venue which we don't want
to do because of the atmosphere and we
want to like have it as our home home
based confirms and the other approach is
increasing the price and lots of people
said hey
if you sold out in 17 17 days was it
this year if you sold out in 17 days he
should like increase the price
accordingly but that's also something
that we don't want to want to do because
we still want to keep it accessible to
the general public and we had some
discussions about how how to change the
concept and we were talking about maybe
spreading out like tokens which would
allow people to buy the vouchers and
these tokens would be distributed into
into the community into hackerspaces
into friendly organizations into the
maybe attendees of the previous
congresses and so on and it would be
something like what what the cows
communications conference does so maybe
if you could like dive into this and
tell us a bit about it do you want to do
it next year or we're definitely we've
been thinking about it right so the my
key focus is how to improve the Congress
right so how to make it even more better
next year and it's sometime sometimes
it's brew it brings interesting new
situations like for us I remember last
year we spent a lot of effort into
promoting the event we had for the first
time I mean last year the entire venue
in la fábrica and we wanted to sell it
out ideally right but it was kind of
like new territory for us so therefore
we spent a lot of time and effort and
communication for promotion and in the
end we were successful because last year
we sold out the event one month prior to
the event this year we sold out the
event as you mentioned rightly in 17
days at the end of April which moved us
into totally different positions so I
recall my discussion with our PR
and she said guys there's forget about
media presents because no one wants to
write articles about Congress where no
one can go because it sold out so I said
uh-huh it's okay wow I didn't think
about it right and also you mentioned
the price it's definitely a sensitive
topic and I've seen a to like extreme
opinions right one is saying you guys
are way too cheap because there are so
many other much like I mean conferences
where the quality is not that good and
your conference is like top and you
should increase the price because it
deserves you you would bring more money
for which you can translate into better
experience bring more speakers etc right
the other other extreme is like all your
increase the price from last year and
you're getting a bit more expensive now
we need to balance it somehow right and
there will never be price that'd be
perfect for everyone so what my role is
to drive and facilitate this discussion
to make sure that we are not overpriced
but we don't want to be really really
cheap because simply the cheap means low
quality and low possibility to bring
top-notch speakers although the heck US
Congress is still much cheaper than lots
of one day long conferences and we have
like three days packed with 40 speakers
or something like that so I don't think
that we are like at the expensive level
yet and if you keep the price too low it
brings you like new kind of problems for
example people buying lots of tickets
then reselling them to other people at
much higher price and we already saw
that this year some
people bought the tickets in the
earlybird stage where it was just 2500
Czech crowns and then once we sold out
they were selling the tickets for like
10000 Czech crowns or something like
that so they they made some some like
big profit obviously there is problem
with trust because if you buy a
secondhand ticket then you cannot be
like sure that that the person will not
use the ticket before you so it's
obviously risky but because it was sold
out there was still demand for this so
keeping the price too low it's like also
problematic so settings it is it's very
sensitive topic I agree and I recall
some meetings where we were discussing
the the price and they were like I was
pushing and challenging the discussions
of one discussion as you may recall was
that we would issue some small batch of
tickets like student very discounted
tickets for people who cannot afford the
regular price etc right so and then we
end up in some discussion how we would
evaluate the validity of direct quest
doors and etc so and in the end we just
put it off the table the solution we
came up with for this year was basically
live streaming right because we said
okay last year all the videos that we
could record I mean talks we were
post-production
needed to go through post-production
which took us time and basically the
content gets obsolete very quickly so
this year we said okay we would go for
totally new think we will go for live
streaming and again the question was
okay if it's live streaming do we want
to make people to pay for these live
streams right which if you would be
normal typical commercial entity you
would say okay I'll just expand our
revenue streams and come up with another
revenue channel which we said okay but
maybe it's not what should drive our
focus or activities well obviously we
are not-for-profit organization and we
need to consider our mission and vision
and our mission is to provide the people
with education and tools they need to
increase their personal freedom and if
we would charge money for for these
streams it would significantly decrease
the amount of people that would be able
to watch these streams and recordings so
in line with our mission we decided to
make it make it free so anyone could
access the same quality content
immediately and they wouldn't have to
equate for post-production or pay
anything and so on and you mentioned
like an important point not everyone was
was not every speaker was recorded and
and streamed why is that those who have
known or have been in to our Congress
they already know that the the privacy
is the name of the game right so they
there are like House Rules
which we all stick to and treating
personal identities for people who are
who prefers their real identities to be
not not exposed it's what we are also
tweeting very carefully and that's why
we had all these signs like
recordings or taking photos is not
allowed on the premises at all and same
goes with speakers so every speaker
actually we have few like guidelines so
whoever wants to apply to be a speaker
except for passing the first gate like
that he has something to talk about
there are other things but so we do not
pay speakers fee right so we and that's
another uniqueness of this event so we
are trying to build the trust in the
speaker's community that this is a
professional event and it has its
reputation and we are able to manage
such a demanding professional event and
make it happen right so everybody's
happy and so no speakers fee also we are
asking every speaker if he or she is
willing to be recorded and there are
speakers who are basically giving their
talks not disclosing their real
identities and we respect that and that
we've had few that are not recorded or
have not been recorded and we're not
their talks were not made public and
this is how it goes and on the other
hand it's surprising that some guys who
are like real privacy extremists in the
end gave us their concerns and
permission to be recorded and that's
amazing right so that's why I'm so happy
that guys like smuggler for example gave
us his yes and that's a matter of like
long-term relationship and Trust we have
managed to build over the years with
these guys exactly I wanted to say that
that smuggler always didn't want to have
his talk record it because smuggler and
Frank Brown they are like regulars that
echoes Congress they've been here since
the beginning and in the past smuggler
never
gave consent to to have his talk
recorded or streamed and this year he
gave the consent so he was live streamed
the recording is online and his talk was
actually very interesting he was talking
about crypto Anarchy about its relation
ship with other kinds of anarchists and
what are the differences and so on so it
was like a really important talk with
respect to the theme of this year's
Congress which by the way was was the
new order you are discussing like new
order of society which which is brought
by technologies it's not like we know
what the new order would be but we
strived to invite the interesting
speakers who have something to say in
this regard and it's up to the
participants and and people who watch
the recordings to decide what what the
future might be right so you mentioned
new order right that was the theme of
this year's Congress do you remember the
discussion how this where does does it
came from like the origins of new order
because I came into this discussion with
slight delay so that's who's the
originator of this idea I guess I guess
it was bubble loop talk one of the
speakers at the hackers Congress and he
is one of the founders of Peroni polis
and he's basically the the mastermind
behind the selection of speakers and
because he attends lots of conferences
he gets in touch with interesting people
and in vines invites them to the ecers
Congress so I guess it was him who came
up with this with this team of hackers
Congress being new order and it's a bit
of a twist on the New World Order like
Illuminati conspiracy III remember two
remarks like first why you're mixing
messing with the Illuminati's and New
World Order what
doesn't mean second remark was the
there's famous British band and entitled
with this with these two words so and
and also I remember interesting
discussion that new war new order was
maybe not the exact messaging we want to
put in place and send out to the world
we were discussing the big question mark
at the end right so the question that
nobody is sure what what's gonna happen
and maybe what's missing there is the
question mark at the end yeah exactly
that's that's what I was saying that we
are not like giving a description what
the world will look like we are just
discussing the possibilities and it's up
to the people to to think about it and
maybe work towards the future that they
want and yeah we as an organization want
to provide them with the tools to build
better freer fairer future and then we
have right now
so yeah we discussed putting a question
mark there but in the end we decided not
to do it but still like the content is
the same it doesn't matter if there was
or wasn't question mark in the title
right there were a few things do you
treat or perceive hackers Congress is
pure crypto event depends on how you
define crypto even do you mean like
crypto a crypto currency event or crypto
as people technology okay good point
okay the crypto currency event yeah lots
of people mistakenly think that the
hackers Congress and parity policies and
organization is about crypto currencies
but if you come to our building or to
the hackers Congress you find out that
crypto currency is just like one albeit
prominent but one of the of the tools
that we use here
that we talked about cryptocurrency
itself without the the other crypto
technology tools doesn't make any sense
so the whole organization and the event
is about all the crypto technologies
about cryptocurrency about encryption
about anonymous ation techniques these
are the tools that allow us to to build
like crypto anarchy on the Internet to
to colonize this Terra Nova that we have
in the in the cyber world but the
hackers Congress is not only about
crypto technology
it's definitely visible that lots of the
talks are related to crypto technology
because still it's a conference where
hackers and visionaries around the world
come to to present their ideas how these
technologies will shape the world but
hackers Congress stands on like multiple
pillars the same way as Peroni polish
stands on multiple tours and these
pillars are technology social sciences
and heart so not everyone at attackers
Congress was talking about technology
there are talks about other stuff yeah
and that's my point because I think
sometimes maybe we're not sending out
the right messaging right or positioning
ourselves
the fact that when you look at our
website right so there are a lot of like
big names right so we have peter told we
have a long browser and jimmy song and
other guys who are basically the part of
the bitcoin core developers group right
so at first side it may look like oh
it's another like Bitcoin conference
right sometimes people are coming at us
like you guys dude through the one of
very few through a Bitcoin maximalists
events right and that's not just right
okay so and
I think we've at least foreign like next
years we would like to dedicate more
space to other pillars or other themes
right like arts and social science I
remember we've tried to bring few people
that and those would fill these gaps
unfortunately we're too late on this so
I think one of those priorities for next
years is to go for more balanced mix of
what we represent and what we would like
to represent right and this is our core
focus and again I'm relating back to
this like space you guys why why don't
we want to grow right no we we still
want to be here but we would like to
bring more balanced mix of really
groundbreaking innovative opinion
leaders and teams into those three days
but still we we had some arts and social
sciences present the echoes Congress
this year we didn't have any any movie
premiere am i right we didn't have last
year we also it was one of our fails as
well
because I think it was 2016 right we
were screening down the deep dark web
including the discussion and Q&A panel
with the producer and movie crew we want
it basically to replicate the same
concept and bring another interesting
movie for some reasons were not that
good in opening doors to those producer
groups or studios because you may have
contact to producer or movie creator or
actor right so we were looking at
the new radical movie were a mere tacky
and codedes featured we said that'll be
amazing right because both were
scheduled to be here and to bring also
the film crew and go for some panel
discussion that would be awesome and mix
it with the live screening of this movie
which on the other side increases the
complexity for me as a organizer because
first thing we learned was that you guys
forget about like some regular video
format right
it comes in digital cinema format which
requires totally different devices
yeah like extremely expensive I could
man set it up and so on yeah so we are
still not giving up I am still hoping
I'm professional optimist that the next
year we'll manage to bring some
interesting movie document or other like
medium or long format there is like a
documentary movie which is being
produced right now about about like
movement for freedom about crypto and
our case about Peroni police here in
Czech Republic and in Slovakia and so on
so I hope that we will be able to screen
it next year if it will be ready it it's
still not sure whether they will make it
on time but it would be like really good
addition yeah but for me this is
low-hanging fruit we've been always very
ambitious so I like for example the new
order theme came out and was made public
and after few like weeks or months Keanu
Reeves Wright came up with his article
entitled basically with the same topic
right so we've been always I've been
also trying to somehow and hoping but no
I'm just trying to say that we are
really keen on bringing top events or
speakers themed
opinion leaders and so far we have
managed because if you look at the
lineup for this year Nassim Nicholas
Taleb there is the legend so I'm still
like I have I'm blind how we could have
managed to get him here right it's
almost like mission impossible if you
imagine that you have your own Congress
and you would like to have Speaker like
nothing yeah I I think it's it's proved
that the reputation of a curse Congress
is increasing every year so it gets
easier for us to convince like big big
names to to come to a curse Congress or
at least give a remote talk so dalip was
like one of one of the superstars of the
Congress but there were so many
important names that like is one of one
of the few important ones there all of
the speakers are important but he is
like very famous and he is one of the
people who brought a bit of the Social
Sciences to the ecers Congress since he
was talking about the structure of
society and how how its influenced by
people not having their skin in the game
by by not having to pay for their
mistakes they never learn and the
society never improves like bureaucrats
in the government's never never get the
the heart market feedback by having to
pay for their mistakes so he was like
reiterating this this point of quite a
few examples and he wasn't talking much
about technology he was talking about
like the way that people behave and how
it could be changed by having the skin
in the game
yeah and what about the story with Cody
yeah that's that's what I actually
wanted wanted to ask you because you are
mentioning the the movie new new radical
which features America and Cody Rosen
and both of them should have been here
this year but in the end it didn't
happen so with Cody Wilson it's it's
like quite well known already what
happened that he was accused of some
personal stuff with being involved if I
think 17 year-old girl which was illegal
and in the u.s. currently he's out on
bail I think it's not sure what what
will happen but for these reasons he
wasn't able to come but what was the
story with Amir Turkey the story again
there are no like secrets or behind the
scenes kind of speculation so basically
we had Amir last year and he brought us
a lot of attention he was also present
on the press release when we were
opening the Congress last year and he
really helped us a lot in terms of move
the reputation or aspect of this
Congress to higher levels right this
year we were trying to go for some
slightly different speakers to bring
another angles and varieties of opinion
so and we don't want to build the kind
of same and repeat the same little list
of speakers every year so it's boring to
repeat the same opinions every year so
this year we were in a mirror of somehow
discussing his potential speaking
opportunities which in the end he just
gave us his
announcement or notification or some
kind of message that he's not coming
right so and maybe I'm definitely sure
he had his own reasons which we respect
we didn't want to do any big theme out
of his withdrawal from the lineup
released it can happen to anyone
but by the way emetic is at the DEFCON
conference so we actually met two days
ago he was holding a session about about
society about politics about power and
it was a very interesting session where
ever we were discussing like the
philosophic background of of these teams
unfortunately I wasn't able to stay
there unto the end because I had to run
to our stand and they take care of other
stuff but he he had quite a few people
in the room and he was there and trying
to push the freedom movement agenda I
would say yeah he's definitely
inspirational leader and he has done a
lot of great things who may inspire and
provokes the conventional way of
thinking right so it's definitely part
of the speakers which we would like to
have him have here with Cody it was
really the unfortunate consequence of
events that happened in the really bad
time for us so we had confirm we have
Cody confirmed from early this year and
we've we've been in touch with Cody
regularly because every time we're
talking to speakers we just need to
confirm like give us these photos or
give us your profile and abstract and
there's so many communication that we
need to manage before we open the
discussion until he or she appears here
then like three weeks before we started
that it happened what happened and we
said okay it was just let's wait we
don't want to just take him of this
lineup because picture was there until
the like very last moments before the
Congress we we were trying at least two
maybe arrange for some quick remote
session and we were very pragmatic
because we don't want to judge anyone we
just want to connect people and he's one
of those speakers who have something to
say and the funny thing is that one of
our sponsor or partner was Purusha
research right so that's the very
successful company that produces and
manufactures the 3d printers so that
would be awesome opportunity for some
panel discussion yeah I was I was
looking forward to a panel discussion
with Cody Rosen and use of Purusha but
unfortunately it couldn't happen in the
end I think that this is like a really
good point because since you mentioned
how much work it was to communicate with
the speakers this is like good good time
to say a huge thank you to floor who was
one of one of the members of the huge
team who made the raucous Congress
happen and she did a tremendous work
with like taking care of the speakers
he's behind the great and huge success
of this year and the way she handled all
that communication really big glory goes
to her because she has done as you
saying tremendous job and and and she
didn't do it last year right so for her
it was like first time and basically she
jumped in the in the arena and the
expectation was these are some contacts
we connected with some people but you
just go and figure it out and she
managed that really well I think she has
some experience with conferences from
paralysis but but still the like US
Congress is like
completely new concept for rolls of
people because the way it's organized it
stands on on the work of plenty of
volunteers and for you
it's it's the second time that you
coordinated the echols Congress did you
find it easier this year or I think yes
it definitely so last year it was a bit
more rough there were few okay every
Congress has few memories in my head
which are taught like micro details but
for me I it was pain in the in the neck
last year it was the situation of the
partners logos right so 2016 we had
these traditional roll-ups and LA and
last year we said doesn't work roll up
is not perfectly fit for displaying
partners logos so we we spent like three
months brainstorming how how to put it
the error so it's not disturbing but it
still represents the brand and it's
serious and etc so in the end we managed
to figure it out I think I have not I
haven't seen this kind of concept
anywhere yet and works perfectly well so
this year we had another challenges so
one of those was the the badge right so
for those who were at our Congress so
and and back to what you said early so
where there are so many ideas and this
idea came from Carroll kievsky from
general bytes because he was connected
to Michael from Munich Germany and he's
this Michael is producing these
wonderful gadgets and it was like July
or maybe early August he said Wow last
year we have these NFC carts let's have
this gadget right and again we
completely
gated put another complexity factor in
our organization prep work and we were
brainstorming like what we can afford
like so it costs some money but we were
also looking for some functionality that
we could put in it and in the end it was
a bit tough because everybody knows we
have like this triangle right so but all
the traditional badges are manufactured
in square kind of shapes so and
therefore we had to test the NFC antenna
so it works and we had to do the special
visual for that so the manufacturing
process was really troublesome
but in the end and again your brother
did amazing job with helping to make it
happen and last in the end we were just
discussing how to get it here right so
it was I literally had to drive to
Munich and to pick those up because like
one almost two weeks before the Congress
and it was Oktoberfest there so for me
it was painful
to drink so I had to sneak between the
beer lovers and in the end we made it
which I'm very happy that we could have
launched or initiates something like
that because we were discussing some
let's put some like display right so
it's configurable device so it's not
only fancy nice thing you can have on
your neck but it has some functionality
so in the end we were basically forced
to put only a bitcoin and litecoin
wallet but we we were discussing the
configurable chip and the display that
we could play with and let people to
maybe configure the content or display
messages by themselves etc again we were
running out of time but this is what it
is and in the end Peter Todd said this
is the worst Hardware wallet he has ever
seen it's because it's not a hardware
role it it's like replacement for a
paper bullet but I think that it's like
one of the small touches at the Wreckers
congress that show how how we combine
art with technology because it's
visually it's very interesting badge
it's unlike most of the badges that you
see in at other conferences so it's it
shows how how we approach stuff
differently so so you said that this is
your your memoir if Rebecca is not the
owner
yeah obviously another memory was the
looking for the the regular table of
specific size for our live performance
for like yeah well since we are
discussing the hackers Congress here it
seems like there is like lots of issues
and troubles and so on but
from the outside if you look at it it
all looks very smooth and very
professional and high-quality content
and I would say that compared to the
previous years even from the inside it
it gets much better a much smoother this
year even the neighbors didn't complain
about noise and so on so and that's a
huge achievement yeah I was really
shocked by the the message she posted
like they called me the day after
Congress to tell me that they
congratulate us on organizing the event
in such a professional way that we
didn't disturb them as passed and so on
so I would say that this year was pretty
smooth even even though you you have
this memory of like having to go to
Munich on such such tight deadlines and
so on yes the fact that there are always
issues right there's always things that
break up that they don't work properly
something simply doesn't work and you
need to detect it as fast as possible
and then get it fixed right so ideally
without anyone noticing I think the the
success of this even or the fact that it
looks that smooth a bit smoother than
last year it was we enlarged the
volunteers crew so we had almost like 30
3-0 volunteers so on top of the course
organizational team we had a great deal
of people and you can see under non the
closing ceremony there are all these
people who are lining up and there are a
lot of people some of them were missing
from like every year there is a few
people who who have to be somewhere else
during the closing ceremony and and also
the fact that we had the experience from
last year so last year the one of my
nightmares was how to get the
connectivity for our ATMs machines right
and how to
logos on stage on time and this year
specifically who we were like panicking
about every minute and we started with
these things right so give us the moment
we could enter la fábrica we started to
work on these things that didn't work
last year and I think this is something
that's important in general right so if
something breaks it's really great if
you can have a like moment understanding
why it didn't work out and lessons
learned do it differently next year next
time right so but sometimes we fail on
keeping the habit running these lessons
learned and then we're basically falling
into the same traps I think this is good
good time to say a huge thank you to all
the volunteers who took part in echos
Congress parent police because without
their help it wouldn't be the event that
it is and the atmosphere would be very
different if you would like pay
professional people to prepare the
conference it would it would have to
feel that you get when you go to any
generic conference which is organized by
some event even agency and it wouldn't
be the same so a huge thank you to all
all the volunteers who took part and
some of them take part every year so
they are like part of the family here
and becoming our regulars it regarding
the the problem speakers I think we had
another speaker who had some issues I
think sayfudine a mousse he had his
laptop stolen or something like that
because he wasn't supposed to have a
remote talk but he had a remote talk in
the end I don't recall these details I
recall again yes I heard this story
somehow but I didn't have like really
so I'm not able to command good thing to
know that he knows and he was still able
to give his talk albeit remotely yeah
but I think he was supposed to be here
like physically with us yeah we've had
few change requests from speakers and in
terms of checking the possibility to
give remote talk instead of physical
presentation we've been always very
sensitive not to have too much or too
many remote talks so every year we have
like I don't know three four remote
talks which i think is a good number and
there is always a reason because if you
have like almost 50 speakers sometimes
someone is sick someone cannot travel
due to personal issues etc there is
remote talk arrangement always welcome
if there is some reason behind and we
respect that but we don't want to
organise the remote Congress so the
physical presence it's not only about
having this top guy here on in our house
but also to give people opportunity to
meet this or because there are so many
networking activities going on during
the entire Congress right and this is
another I would say great thing about
this Congress that we do not have like
second-class citizenship and VIP zones
where nobody can internalize these some
gold badge whatever so there is one
community one space opportunity for
networking open discussion with deep
respect to privacy and this is the
foundation based on which the entire
event is build on
yeah well the talk is just like very
small part actually of the presence of
the speaker at the Congress and I was
actually the moderator for sayfudine
Alice's talk and it it was a really a
real interesting talk since he's the
author of the Bitcoin standard book so
he gave his view on why bitcoin is the
hardest money ever and how how it can
change society based on being the
hardest money and because we had some
technical difficulties that's always
happening if you have streamed talks and
it's very difficult to do it right so at
one point I had to tell people in the in
the audience to turn off their Wi-Fi
because they were blocking the
interconnection for for the talk but it
worked out in the end so so he was able
to give the talk but unfortunately
because of the delay there wasn't much
space for discussion so well I think
there was there wasn't any space for
discussion actually so we didn't we
didn't ask him any questions but he gave
his email address so people could could
ask him afterwards but it was one of the
examples for where you could see that it
was like a really missing that he wasn't
here physically present to be able to
discuss with with people because his
talk was like really inspiring
yeah I agree and again if you have so
many speakers there is like close to
100% chance that something will go wrong
like either technical issues or some
delays in in starting of the
presentation etc I'm still like very
happy that we have had not almost no
major disruption into our schedule and
last year it was same so I'm just hoping
it will stay with us for coming years
because what really is a nightmare for
organizer is when
speakers are not able to stick to time
slots they've been dedicated and then
the domino effect comes and the entire
event falls apart and that's why we had
this role of moderators and stage
managers who were carefully watching the
clock and then just making a really hard
stop call like sorry guys no more minute
left we need to start with something
else and amazing thing was we we were
running into some challenging situation
with one of our speakers and she was
announcing the delay and we ran into
tone base right and he said yeah I
wanted to talk about that because I was
actually the one who was running to tone
race I was discussing with this with
Fleur that like we need to shuffle the
stalks a bit because one speaker is
going to be light so I went to tone race
I discussed it whether he is okay with
like having his talk at a different time
and so on so we like did all this
shuffling and then the speaker like
called us and said that she's going to
make it on time
so I had to go to tone ways and scratch
the plan of shuffling the talks and so
in the end the schedule remained the
same as it was supposed to be and it's a
good thing because when you when you
shuffle talks it always creates a mess
and people are angry that they wanted to
see this dog and that talk and so on
it's me and and and tone is great
because I also recall the moments he
said like you guys somebody drops out
let me let me know I immediately will
step in because I have another field
presentation I could just give and on
the spot right so and some speakers were
introducing other speakers so this is
like amazing that there's like sense of
community and respect and again it's not
typical commercial event where
everything is driven by some rules or
some budget or some
interest etc right so and this is why
and this is my view this even has become
so popular and recognized by the
community not only here but surprisingly
elsewhere and today I've had discussion
with I just because of DEFCON there are
so many people here in Prague these days
and he's and I met a girl and she's from
San Francisco and she said mazing place
like and the Congress so said I miss
that and same with some speakers like
Pamela Morgan for example she was almost
crying emails like sorry guys I'm not
able to make it but at least I'm sending
you like view of my new books that it
was just go public and this is my gift
to you and you just do whatever you
think its best with this gift yeah I
think that you made a good point here
that some of the speakers introduce
other speakers and they are really like
becoming one huge crypto anarchist
family here it's it's a sign of the
regularity of the events that we do
because we've been doing the hackers
Congress since 2014 this was the fifth
iteration of echoes Congress and some of
the speakers have been here multiple
times I think we have a few speakers who
have been we've been here every single
time so they they came to know each
other quite well over the years yeah
that's that's true and again it's it's
really helping us to bring
another interesting speakers for next
year etc because the moment you can say
look we are organizing this event this
other this is the website by the way you
can go through the number of speakers
who have been here already you feel free
talk to them right so
this is the only like solid foundation
based on which you can attract more
interesting speakers and opinion leaders
otherwise if and that's the most
pressure to keep this spirit of this
Congress not only within the speaker's
community but also the the people the
the visitors who come to our event
partners Network media right we've had
like almost 30 accredited journalists so
the event attracts a lot of attention
and this is what basically what we do in
terms of improvements for next year
I think because the improvement between
last year and this year was we
introduced new streaming studio right
though there was totally new concept so
one day and this is the studio we're
broadcasting from here right now one day
before they even started it was like
still concrete's foundation of something
to be in but we had a wonderful group
from the states the world crypto Network
community
the guys who basically hijacked our
streaming studio and it basically the
parallel stream of interviews and live
coverage which had I would say amazing
like side effect right because the
speaker's after they gave the talk they
could be interviewed here in the studio
and the discussion could continue we
introduced workshops so we had five
workshops on various topics like not
behind Bitcoin and lightning Network the
game theory
and we had a group from Serbia crypto
party and the guys came here to give and
educate people on how to use modern
technology to save their digital privacy
and be more careful in the digital world
we had this live streaming and for next
year we will also start thinking about
how to improve it for next year so maybe
well have you had a chance to because
you mentioned you were introducing some
speakers right yeah did you see any
presentation like in a sitting watching
kind of relaxing mode good question I
don't think I had time to like be at any
other talk than then the ones that I
moderated but thankfully we have the
recordings so although all the
variegated that the team puts into
making this conference happen
it's like saved in those recordings so
we can look at the content but like it's
still it's like great pleasure to make
this happen to see the happy people
coming to the Wreckers congress and when
the people go to you and tell you like
hey this is so cool and thank you so
much for making it happen it's it's
always like it makes it well was the
energy that that we put into it so I'm
like I don't have any problem if not not
seeing any other talks than the ones
that the time moderated because it's
still the content that that comes out of
it is amazing it's so for next year we
need to figure it out how to organize
that even and enjoy it from the like
that's why people pay agencies but I
also one-and-a-half talks which is
one and a half talks more than last year
and you know how it works so we're still
a bit like sensitive to what what can
break or stop working
so maybe what is the black best moment
from this year you have what what is the
thing that stay the top
I guess the moment when it all ends when
you can just stand people clap and you
can enjoy the moment and just go to
party and and so on but it's like it's
like the emotional part but I don't know
it's it still didn't end for me yet
because still there is plenty of
administrative tasks that are still
coming in like we get invoices I had to
do the payments and all this stuff so so
for me the records Congress is still
still going a bit and I will I will need
some time to process so all the stuff
that happened and and enjoy it bit more
so it's hard for me to to decide this
right now but I I remember one funny
moment regarding the production work and
what everything was going smoothly and
so on I remember when I went to the
production room during the hackers
Congress and you are sitting there
behind your laptop and you were like so
what's happening what's the problem and
I was like there is no problem both
confused and how is that possible that
everything was running and there were no
issues at that point so that was a good
feeling a little bit scary because it
might mean that there is something bad
happening it is because my favorite
saying is that if everything goes
perfectly well you have obviously
overlooked something yeah
but yes so that the best and it was
interesting when we had the discussion
with volunteers because it takes some
time and before they accommodate it into
our team and we explain what's gonna
happen so and their fear was that last
year we've had complaints that they had
nothing to do right so there were
situations like I was I felt like
unutilized like I'm not contributing
right and I said like that's the best
situation you can have right because if
there are so many things to work on
something is not running smoothly so for
us every moments when we can basically
be bored while the Congress is happening
that is the best spot you can be usually
doing like US Congress I run around the
place and so try to like put out the
fires that happened but this year I had
a moment when when I actually played
table tennis at the chill-out room
so yeah this year it was fine because we
had we had moments where there was like
nothing urgent to solve
yeah I'm just running through my notes
because I wanted to mention we were
supposed to do this dreaming until four
o'clock but we started like 90 minutes
late so it's okay if we take it longer
I think what's more you were mentioning
something cues definitely like big
thanks to Martin Fisher for the all
visuals because sometimes people say
like you're so weird in terms of like
design and image and the visual
perception right because it is not
traditional commercial look and feel
right and maybe sometimes it's too much
black and too much drag girls but really
Martin is doing great job in terms of
basically visualizing what we all spin
around and try to say out loud and it's
difficult for us to articulate so and
and what amazes me is that this can go
to really extreme right so every single
thing on every single merchandise is
being on the radar on radar and I've
learned how to cope with Martine because
I basically understand now that he is
the I have the truth here right so I
remember a few things that nobody knows
or maybe very few people know we've had
two versions of congress official
branded t-shirts right so and that's
because one night I wake up and say I
may be too late so someone has version
one and someone has the the later
version and but it amazes me like how
we're taking this visual look to the
extreme yeah we we didn't want to change
the t-shirts for the people who already
ordered them so that's why we decided to
make the the original version in the
amount that was already paid for and
then we we did the second newer version
for for the rest who wanted to buy the
t-shirt that the Hecker's Congress I
actually personally like the original
version that's why I why I got it for
myself but I also have the new new
design that the crew t-shirt which every
volunteer gets so I have both stuff best
of both worlds sleep Edition which which
brings me
do you think we've had the gold coin
auction this year yes we did
so were you there I was there I was
actually bidding on the clock okay
because like the the starting price was
really low it was just the costs of
making the coin but the purpose of of
auctioning this coin wasn't to sell it
for the costs but it also wasn't to make
as much money as possible the purpose
was that we wanted to point out the the
issues that that other people in the
world face regarding the relationship
with governments and so on so last year
we were already like we already had this
this edition of coins with Russell bit
and this year we were auctioning the the
golden coin like limited edition there
is only three of these in the world so
one of them was auctioned that at the
ecers Congress and by this auction we
wanted to like raise awareness of the
case of Russell it was supposedly was
the the operator of Silk Road and is
currently in prison for life and so we
wanted to raise awareness for his case
and we also wanted to raise money for
him because like half of the of the net
profit from from the gold coin auction
was sent to to his mother I think or
order like movement 2 to 3 aerosol baked
so we wanted to support him medially and
also financially in his case and this
year's edition of coin featured Julian
Assange who is currently well he's not
in prison but he he might as well be
because he is stuck in
in eco Ecuadorian Embassy in London so
it's it's similar case and I think that
next year there should be a gold coin
auction with Julian Assange with with
the same purpose of like raising
awareness for him and supporting him
financially
hopefully Julian Assange would be able
to give a talk remotely maybe at next
year's across Congress we will see and I
guess we will have this discussion
definitely been entertaining the idea to
have the speaker remote which leads me
to the like realization that we are
somehow able to attract the top most
influential people definitely in crypto
community or crip or cryptocurrency or
Bitcoin space in cryptography space and
cyberpunk
community because time flies right and
we realized that some people are already
maybe a bit older than we assumed right
so most of our let's say quote unquote
heroes because the either they
co-founded the Electronic Frontier
Foundation or are behind the signal
protocol or other things or
cryptographic technology that we are now
trying to teach people how to use it
right and that's something where I think
it's good to mix to build our content on
the traditions of where it all came from
and also augment it with new potential
opinion leaders and disruptors right and
then you have something someone in the
middle
people like hunter Andres Anton applause
whoo whoo again we tried to get him here
again but then the mix is very important
to nail them correctly right and I think
this is the biggest challenge for next
year to have like vetting board or
Authority through which we will be
selecting the confirmed speakers because
so far we have not paid that much
attention to the selection process
sometimes it was too spontaneous or to
prompt or quick I would say like maybe
we didn't pay that much attention as as
the whole team behind the Hyksos
Congress but we still have power loop
tack as the mastermind behind behind the
seal selection and he was like
dedicating a lot of time into selecting
the speakers so it's not like we would
just randomly select and really great
thanks because Pavel and his connection
and credibility in this community helps
us a lot to bring these people right
well what I'm talking is how to expand
to other domains which are maybe more
social science kind of oriented or new
technology or / artistic kind of things
so for this to be able to evaluate these
proposals whether those propose speakers
are so significant opinion leaders this
would require bigger discussion and this
is I think that the much bigger focus
for us then
like those quote-unquote done silly
things how to expand to bigger space
yeah definitely definitely all right as
we already discussed this year we didn't
have as much social sciences and arts
that as you would like to have at the
conference but still I am like I would
say quite happy with the content that we
had because we had quite a few talks
about social sciences and not all of
them were about technology you are
discussing things like financial privacy
the Panama papers was interesting panel
discussion as we already discussed we
have assembly costs talib talking about
society and there were quite a few talks
about this we are discussing the
pharmaceutical industry and how how the
patents are like making making medicine
very expensive poor people unnecessarily
so I think it it can be improved for the
next year but it wasn't a disaster at
all this year
I'm not saying but I'm more like looking
for some opportunity so I how to push
the barriers how to okay we've done it
this year how we can make it better next
next years and these are all discussions
which we all need to have I I liked how
you mentioned that some of some of the
some of our heroes are getting older and
we should like built on these traditions
it it reminded me of demo team a who
gave a talk last year I think and he was
talking about 30 years of crypto anarchy
and it was it was really interesting to
listen
someone with such a long history in this
movement and fortunately the recording
is online so anyone can can look at it
and demoting make sure doesn't give that
that many talks so it was like very very
special to have him at hackers Congress
and give a talk it was a remote talk but
still it was like very very interesting
moment from last year I'm cautious about
time so maybe let's run to so I think
that we should like definitely say thank
you to to all our partners because we
mentioned some of them during this
stream but still we should like say it
properly for all of them because they
are like definitely one of the important
elements of echos conga lessons they are
the ones that help us make it happen
absolutely and it's on my list
don't worry I would never end up this
streaming session without explicitly
saying big thanks to our main partners
this year general by its simple coin
crucial research and going mate Cohen my
yes so big thank you and it also relates
to what you said about differences
between hackers Congress and DEF CON we
are not commercial event right we are
known for profit kind of event and it's
a bit tricky to go into some
relationship with partners and it
doesn't really matter if we say like
partners sponsors etc so there's always
some logos that are married to our event
and I am really so happy that we have
companies who are willing to contribute
some money
to our Congress with and with these
companies were able to find the right
balance between how to help their brands
to be visible but not cross the line
where the pure commercial product
placement starts and I'm so happy that
we've been able to manage this
relationship and also like the more the
sponsor give you the more requires from
you in return right so we have always
had these partners not for the filling
the cost gaps but for building the
relationship and I'm happy that all of
these companies are from Czech Republic
and we've known these guys and they do
not support this event only because for
their pure commercial benefits so again
big thanks to our partners and some
other black brands like we've had
catering partners right or like Club
mutt guys there are a lot of
interactions we had TVs from Philips oh
yes Philips and it's very tricky because
it's very tricky path right and I think
so far we've been able to manage the
expectations and still keep the Congress
that it's not treated as a pure
commercial event and it builds on the
community regulation
so closing closing remarks okay so
that's all in case you would have any
questions comments we've been not able
to see whether there are any questions
or comments posted streaming channel so
you know how to reach us or meet us in
person so you know where to find us
and definitely follow up on the social
networks Facebook YouTube and Twitter we
are posting major updates with very
significantly and repeatedly so it's
hard to miss and next year stay tuned
and definitely follow our Facebook page
where we have the events that we do and
also on our website if you come to
Prague any time during the year stop by
at Peroni place you can grab a cup of
excellent coffee or a cake or something
and maybe visit an event some of them
are in English so it's always good to
check the program and maybe stop by talk
to us and so on on our website you can
find the email addresses you can just
shoot us an email and we will be happy
to answer thank you for your support and
for tuning in tonight or today stone of
night it seems like night in here since
we have the lights
yeah so yeah thank you thank you all
Thanks
[Music]