so hello my name is Travis Ormandy this
is Julie antennas where where
information security engineers on the
Google security team and yeah talk is
called there's a party at ring 0 and
you're invited so all systems make
assumptions about Colonel security and
in fact in the entire scheme bottle of
some systems can be based on the
security banjee provided by the colonel
things like Sam boxing in google chrome
and and an android make make Google in
particular in particular dependent on
Colonel security and of course this is
true for lots of other applications on
other platforms so we've been involved
in finding fixing and mitigating some
really interesting killer bugs over the
last year and I'm looking to share some
of our work today so we can discuss them
the ways that that you can protect the
colonel from malicious user line code
and mitigate unknown clever burner
abilities that in in the kernel itself
so the first section of our talk is
called the colonel is a target so
imagine you have arbitrary code
execution on a machine and if you want
to escalate or just merely switch your
privileges because it's not necessarily
an escalation you might want to get the
privileges of just another user what can
you target you can target in general
processes with more or different
privileges so for instance running
demons situat binaries you can execute
on unix and you can also target the
corner and the colonel has a lot of nice
properties for you as an attacker for
instance it has a huge code code base it
performs a lot of complex and
error-prone tasks and it's responsible
for the whole security model of the
system so it's really a primary target
for you the Linux kernel has
has been a local target for over a
decade we've seen we've seen many
different kinds of bug we've seen memory
and memory management corruption type of
bug which is the first type of bug
versus logic bugs and the complexity of
a kernel makes for more diverse and
interesting logic bugs than then in New
Zealand usually we've we've listed here
a few logic bug that we really liked in
particular the first one I think is a is
a really good example of things going
wrong so if you want if you want to take
a look at this they are really
interesting and we've seen within also
memory management corruption bugs and
they also tend to be more interesting
and diverse than their usual encounter
part where it's almost always the same
this is due to first the complexity of
the memory management because of course
the the colonel is handling the whole
memory management and it's also due to
an interesting different wording where
the attacker actually finally controls a
full address space so this this this
allows an attacker to make way more
complex attacks because he had the
controller whole address face 22 finally
finally exploit any any bugs he might
find on the other hand in user none
usually if you're trying to exploit a
bug remotely trying trying to get
control over the other dress space by by
by itself is already something some
something quite hard and that's why you
see things such as heap spraying and all
this thing there are they are just
giving you some control over the address
space in this prodding you have full
control so we've also listed a few bug
that we won't detail today that you can
at which you can look if you're
interested we will just mention today
no or two to use a long pointy our
differences we will mention two of those
today's and give them as example so
escapes for the colonel and exploiting
the calendar is often the easiest way
out of basically all kind of San boxing
techniques so all school ones such as CH
food gels which have been used forever
mandatory access control which is which
has been gaining traction in Linux for
the last ten years but it still not
really widely used continuous tight
segregation such as V server and I'm
only talking about linux right now but
on Windows you see you see the same the
same thing happening using this for
segregation you still mostly export the
full colonel at extra phase which is
also why virtualization is a popular
alternative because it gives you a very
very different security because you have
a sanotica you will have to attack the
virtualization layer instead of just
having to attack a kernel to to get out
of state for jail or any traditional
sandbox and things such as mandatory
access control for instance selinux they
make more sense if you have a full fully
featured security patch such as gr
security that also tries to protect the
colonel in Windows the situation has
been different but it's getting more and
more the same traditionally local kernel
bugs were not considered really relevant
and important on Windows it has changed
somewhat recently especially since the
introduction of Windows Vista and we can
see an increased reliance on domain
control the use of network services and
features such as protected mode and
integrity levels have been introduced
with Windows Vista so this has changed
in the last few years and no windows is
roughly in the same situation as Linux
now and people care more and more about
a local private education on this
platform so it's still it's a bit of the
same that I've seen no real big complex
min direct access control system on
Windows but that's yeah that because the
difference now in terms of remotely
exploitable bug bugs on linux they have
been quite rare we have seen a few
notable exceptions around 2004-2005 when
when Wi-Fi was was getting more and more
used and was getting into the linux
kernel's we've seen a few remote
exploits by different people but
otherwise there's this rare exception SG
rock you sctp exploit which has been
released I think two years ago he has
written a reinter esting article in fact
if you want to check this out with
twists and a few others but it's it's
not very common on Windows it they have
been quite popular for yeah at least six
seven years I think actually Barnaby
Jack who gave a talk yesterday gave a
talk in 2005 on on on some remote canal
bugs on Windows and usually the the
target was not Microsoft code itself but
mostly third-party naive code in
antivirus and personal firewall you've
seen also a few a few GDI related bug a
very few tcp/ip stack rated ones our
colleague nina mehta and others have fun
one quite recently also you may be
noticed this SMB v to exploit by
immunity last year which generated some
some buzz and was quite impressive so
those were nice remote colonel bugs but
the web browser are really you what are
changing the game now because
surprisingly they do expose colonel
attacks for face remotely for instance
through GDI and
it's it's something that we've also seen
on Linux for instance there has been a
remotely exploitable bug in nvidia
drivers that you could actually exploit
through web browser and and the reason
for that and Tavis will talk a little
bit more about it later that we have we
have tons of new features coming to the
broader set of such as web font WebGL
and so this expose a lot of canada
texture face remotely so we will now
present some of the bugs we found this
past year so we were working on Colonel
security for about a year and over that
time we published lots of bugs me we
still got some dough and patched we're
still waiting for fixes for some of
these but yeah we found quite a few over
the course this over the course of this
year so there were many entry points for
an attacker to reach Colonel attack
surface the obvious ones are system
calls but there's also things like a
lock tools anything that the colonel
passes file systems weren't
traditionally considered part of you
colonel attack surface but within recent
in recent years or things like water
mounter it's a legitimate way to attack
the colonel obviously those things like
network protocols which are extremely
attractive two attackers and apparently
on Windows you have things like fonts
another formats that are handled in
kernel of course there's been lots of
issues with the executable formats which
are quite complex object object formats
on Windows and Linux there's in famous
bugs in in cough elf ADA outs and so on
but when underappreciated entry point
that we reconsidered word DPLA interrupt
handlers so we decided that that we
should take a look at the stuff so we
found one interesting issue on windows
2003 so Microsoft introduced a new DPL 3
IDT entry DPL free just means successful
to win 3 code so in the public symbols
Microsoft called this ki raise assertion
it if you this basically makes if you if
you ax you in to see it makes it makes
roughly equivalent to just raise
exception state
unveiled so this is kind of odd I've
looked a lots of Microsoft curtain I've
never seen me use this feature and in
fact looking at the the implementation
in the kernel it turns out that they
made an interesting ever they dispatch
the interrupt before enabling they just
passed the the exception before enabling
interrupt so this bug while not
particularly high impact I had had two
interesting characteristics the exploit
you simply just invalidate ESP and then
call in to see so you could exploit it
in just four bytes and and the patch was
interesting as well simply because it
just that you had to just me enable the
interrupt flag so that's just one byte
instruction STI so I it's not ticking
hind back but we thought it was fun
because this and I asked you have a
video with this happening
okay oh okay so i'm just using CDV to
open a an extra bill so that i can have
some code into it
so yeah I just choose anyone demise
beatable so that i can use the the
assemble function from the windows
debuggers so yeah Justin valet DSP call
in to see to raise the exception
detached from the process and yet you
see soft paste is x-default and begged
you to facial if I turn off faults and
then letter continued you get a bug jack
so it's it's kind of a funny bug it's a
but this one wasn't particularly high
impact but it was just interesting then
shows that really there isn't much
exploration whom researchers in this
area see okay so on the subject of
exceptions and interrupt handlers every
cup of how page faults work so as I'm
sure every when I was a page fault
occurs when when there's some attempt to
access a non present page but it's also
if you have insufficient access to to
touch a present page and this various
other low-level paging related errors so
when a page fault occurs the the page
fault the handle of a page fault is
passed an exception code which has a
number of flags that describe what
happened when the page what occurred so
the flags are ID which is which explains
whether is was the page full was caused
by instruction or data fetch us which
means the page while occurred when
during the user or supervisor mode WR
which has where there is a read or write
and p or ND which means presently not
present so so supervisor mode which is
what sets the u.s. bit is is that when
the patriotic ered during some
privileged operation so if the
supervised a bit is set it can mean
various things it could mean the bug
Colonel bug was encountered and then
you'd expect to see an oops or a budget
on Linux or bug check on Windows or some
of the kind of panic but it can also
mean some other unusual low-level event
happened in and you'd expect it would be
normal for that to occur in sudden like
a copy from user operation in most other
circumstances it would mean something
unusual happened
so by looking at this code we realized
that if the processor can be tricked
into setting these flags incorrectly
then you can confuse a lot of really
privileged core operating system code
and so we were thinking about this for a
while and we came up with a way to do
this so what we did was study the
machine state of while executing a
virtual 8086 mode task in vmware in a
vmware guest and we actually found a way
to make vmware set the supervised a bit
for an unprivileged paid fault so the
problem was if you do a far call in
virtual 8086 mode the p it was emulated
incorrectly so obviously when you get a
far call you'd expect that the the cs
and I prepare to be pushed onto the
stack and this is actually done with
supervisor access it's it's it's it's
reasonable to understand why VMware did
this they were probably trying to reuse
the real mode emulation code for if you
want to Doss guests or something like
that and it's a it's obviously pretty
reasonable to to use supervisor access
for that because it makes no difference
but in virtual 8086 mode intel actually
guarantees that you're always running
his wing free it's a as a CPL 3 it's
it's very clear and all of the manuals
that this is guaranteed so this was an
error and surprisingly we were able to
exploit this get ring 0 code execution
enter VMware guest the the reason we
were able to do this was because the
links kernel has a magic check has a
check for a magic CS value to look for
an unusual unusual event caused by pnp
bio support but because this magic value
is something that you wouldn't normally
be able to set in virtual 86 mode you
must be allowed to set it because this
is how real mode addressing works in ode
the obviously address is a 16 bits in in
real mode but the address space is 20
bits so you do this by shifting around
CS and adding it to IP so in order to
access the full 20-bit address space you
need you need to be able to set any CS
value
obviously this has that this has a
special meaning in protected mode but in
in real mode yeah it doesn't mean
anything is just part of the address
calculation to form a physical address
from a from a from an address so believe
it or not we can actually exploit this
error it might be surprising but we
worked on this Emily we actually got it
to work so all we have to do is mi pie
shell code and no and then we've enter
vm age of 6 mode so as we when we were
working on this there was a new feature
of image that was beginning to gain
popularity called nmap me nadra at the
moment it's it's it's quite well known
and well used but at the time we were
concerned that maybe we would say this
was this wasn't real and this issue
wasn't really realistic because of their
mark may not have just been introduced
so we find a way to bypass that as well
begin to talk about later so all we had
to do was set up a far call to a non
present page at SS with a non-person
page with the SSSP address a PF is
delivered which is as expected but
because we can set these magic values in
in CS and then which is recognized as a
PMP BIOS fault then because the colonel
wasn't expecting as fault and there was
no handler set up the fault isn't the
fault handler isn't installed it's a BSS
object so it's set to know and the
colonel just jumps to know and then you
basically you've got you routed the
machine so this is how we triggered it
we basically you put set some nonsense
in the SP and SS so that you'll call it
cause a page fault because the please
obviously this page is going to be
present then we set CS to 90 which is
the magic value for PMP BIOS faults and
then we did this Park all and that was
that was it basically the kennel we just
jumped to our code has rings ero so this
was when the first issues we found with
page faults but we formed we found some
more as well on Windows so obviously
it's it's well known that if the colonel
ever trusts any data from user space and
there's going to be a security issue
somewhere but it's not just a presence
of data that users control it's also the
presence or absence of data so you can
set up some nonsense and set at Ella
Colonel this is like some data
structures expecting
you can say there was date there's more
data here than was expected or less data
than expected and the and and the same
things can happen so by claiming we have
more data available than we really do
and we can reach lots of unusual abba
parts and this is this is mainly to on
windows because the system like the main
system types are large interdependence
structures that often have multiple
components and they sometimes have
version numbers we have to read the
first version number first to see how
big the structure is going to be and
then they can have valuable sized arrays
this is a millionth case on linux we're
at best you have like you have one
structure that's they could be read in a
single operation or at most two
operations for things like sized for a
for something like and white v
structures i 0 vectors but on Windows
yeah reading data from user space can be
a complex operation and we found an
example of this that they could result
in a privilege escalation on every
version of Windows NT the bug wasn't
particularly exciting because you had to
win a race condition to win it to get
code execution so it wasn't particularly
exciting for attackers because simply
because nine times out of ten you're
going to get a bug check whether than
code execution but it was it was a
legitimate issue and it was a double
three in NT filter token so aunty filter
token is the backend system surface that
makes the win32 API create restricted
token work how ND filter token works
would be that you'd pass it it would
pass a pointer to a pointer to a helper
routine that was try to capture all this
complex SI d data that it would they
need it a pass but we can post this to
fails but we can we can bigger a check
past that says the date was present
because by putting that by starting the
the structure on a on a pleasant page
and then saying it spans across a page
boundary to a no access page so we can
cause some unusual ever conditions like
this and by making this structure he has
trouble page boundary so on our this
helper routine they were supposed to
capture this user data would release
this buffer they was going to save the
data into and then we turn 20 filter
token
ND filter token didn't handle this
correctly and it would try to flee the
bathroom again so if because there's
only a short period between these two
events the colonel took that detects a
double free and bug checks so you only
get one attempt to exploit this and you
need to get that buffer reallocated
somewhere else within this very short
period so we know this is exploitable on
MP systems because using a debugger we
can force us we can let ourselves win
the race condition every time but Emmy a
Latino buddy is going to be no real
attackers going to be interested in this
burg simply because they'd only win one
in 100 times it was possible and it was
a fun bug and that there's a URL for
some from example code so you can check
if you're interested how I did this okay
so this is another vulnerability in
Windows NT so this is a quote from from
recent of H in Windows internal fourth
edition he explains the moving GDI from
user mode to kernel mode has provided
improved performance without any
significant decrease in system stability
or reliability I think you might regret
this regret this quote it's maybe it's
true but there's no question the GDI
represents a significant criminal attack
surface now and that it's possibly the
most easily accessible remotely so it's
it's obvious to us that the fun passing
was going to be one of the weak point
simply because it's series so easy to
access via Internet Explorer's app font
face support for CSS which allows a
arbitrary web fonts to be downloaded for
your web pages this is probably our most
critical discovery over the year that we
were working on this simply because just
by visiting a website you could you
could actually arbitrary wing zero code
this is interesting because it doesn't
matter whether your sandbox tour your
unprivileged or using protective mode it
makes a difference we can make an
exploit that and become the most
privileged users on the system it
doesn't matter if you don't have
administrative access anything about it
was easy to use easy to escape so the
way this work was that the font format
supported by Internet Explorer is called
eot which is embedded open type it's
essentially just a trivial drm layer
added on top of TTF format forms the it
defines some interesting data
compression sub formats called CTF and
MTX
we actually also pwned these as well
with some bring three vulnerabilities
these were you can see ms1000 one but
there's a couple of others that I don't
know the numbers but eot is basically
just added confession and reduced
redundancy CDF and MTX are actually
quite clever data compression formats
and they're quite interesting to read it
isn't they do some cool tricks to make
fonts as small as possible I believe the
Microsoft license this technology from
agfa and they published in documents on
it they're actually pretty cool if
interested in data compression sorry so
yeah eot had had some pretty silly
extensions things like support for x or
encryption and some other drm techniques
the the XO encryption is really silly
basically just if the flag is set that
says this is encrypted it basically just
exles the entire data stream with this
fixed x 0 x 50 so yeah that's not it's
not particularly challenging to to a
decrypter there's also some other some
another drm technique called root
strings I think the idea is that if you
want you have a form that you've
licensed and you only want it to be
accessible on your website your you'd
get your you put your website into the
old you put all the URLs that you want
this pond to be accessible for into the
eot file and then sign it but the
signature is ridiculous especially just
add all the character the character
values and then accelerate with a fixed
32-bit keyword so yeah it's not taking a
challenging to the Venus so so yeah this
is all handled by a new library called T
to embed but basically it just takes the
eot file handle the XOR decryption and
so on and then passes it to GDI and then
everything from that point on happens
with being 0 so this is pretty scary and
it turns out we were able to find lots
of integer hours when GDI passes the ttf
directories so the directories are
basically at the at the start of a ttf
file and the explain why each table is
in the rest of the file this was we this
code was all exited a ring 0 and the
code was really old it was unchanged
since at least NT 4 and in fact if you
got a ftp don microsoft com you can
still download
t three point three point one service
packs and you can see curls as old as
like 94 95 and and there's that the code
is very similar it's barely changed and
so Mike's wasn't alone there were lots
of other implications that work that we
tested that were vulnerable to pretty
much the same bug but it was it was
mainly serious on on Microsoft platform
simply because they run this code at
such a high privilege level so we had a
we had a this was obviously explodable
remotely but we only worked on a local
exploit just for demonstration purposes
it was a very reliable and nice nice to
exploit bug yeah so it's this one was
pretty fun we'll talk a bit about null
pointer to references so in in general
what we call null pointer references
aren't necessarily not pointed
references it just in general to user
long pointed references just when the
colonel dereference is a pointer that
goes to user none so and of course if at
any time the colonel trust data in user
space there is a likely privilege
escalation so of course the the reason
why most people call this null pointer
references because null is the very
common value because since it's a common
initialization value for pointer it's
also a common error code returned as a
pointer and it's a special value in C
and so some people just expect it to be
special to the underlying hardware but
it's absolutely not the case on x86 and
very interestingly they used to not be
exploitable so if you were familiar with
linux to the zero and the versions
before that actually segmentation was
used in the the colonel had its its code
its code base and its data segment base
both above page offset so basically
above all user column oh all use our own
data in code so a different pointer
without a segment override would never
reach you turn on which what was quite
convenient
because I mean you explicitly had to
write a segment override when you want
it to reach you turn on so so you
couldn't unexpectedly rich ozone on
which was a cool feature so Ron pointer
Francis didn't become two years alone
point early references automatically and
so their destination would be harder to
control of course you can argue that you
still have some you still have some
control over the Connors address space
from New Zealand so first because there
are this usually this hyper space inside
the kind of space that map's the
physical memory and also because of
course indirectly you control some
kernel structures but still it would be
way harder to control in to exploit
those bugs in the situation and instead
interestingly I remember that in
2004-2005 we had some interesting
strides with linux kernel developers who
did not understand the security
consequences of them and it was not very
clear if if they just expected not to be
special to the the underlying hardware
or if if they still remember the more
early days of Linux when this was not
exploitable but it was expected on
another platform so I don't know what
happened but for some reason a lot of
people didn't think this this was an
issue and it was very surprising because
it wasn't the most trivial and easy to
understand issues but many people didn't
didn't get it and so even even recently
a few of you even seen your kernel
developers in Linux didn't didn't
understand that we will talk about a map
minute or later because now no this this
problem I think is very widely
understood and there is even a feature
and the linux kernel to prefer to try
and prevent you to exploit this so we
found we found of course a couple of
those types of bugs one of one of those
what the linux kernel sucks n page but
we found last august and it's quite well
known and actually it was nominated for
a pony award yesterday because it
affected our Linux kernels from to dot
for revisions and to that six revisions
to
so it was 10 years worth of Linux
cannons and every major distribution
ship venerable cannons it was an odd
function pointer dereference which makes
it even easier to to exploit it was very
very very easy to exploit and we've seen
public exploits for a lot of
architectures every every saw so the way
it works is that the reason for this is
every circuit in the linux kernel every
type of circuit has a set of functions
pointers associated with it called proto
ops which stands for protocol operations
and those protocol operations they
implement the various operations that
can be performed on the circuit so it
can be except buying shut down etc and
and thanks to this the general circuit
management code doesn't have to know
about the underlying transport or
protocol because everything is
abstracted away so that that's quite
convenient and you can see you can see
here the proto of definition as
available in include / news / net dot H
so you see a struct photo ops with
different operation release bind except
and so some basically what drivers do it
they implement the operation they
support and they point to opera and they
implement the operation they support and
they point to operation they don't
support to predefined Colonel Stubbs so
in this illustration you see for
instance release points to my release
which is an implementation bind to mind
bind but accept appoints to sock know
except which basically means this is
unknown implemented operation so this
model is really fragile if you if you
think about it because anytime you add a
new operations on sockets what do you
need to do you need to update all
drivers and point the new operation to a
stab or implement it and it's actually a
lot of code to update because it means
all drivers right and on Linux it's it's
it's a lot of of drivers and also since
macros are used for initializations you
also need to update
all those macros so of course it went
wrong and when a 16-page was was added
so 16-page is quite all I think it was
odd in Linux to the two actually well
anyway so when 16-page was added it
assumed the corresponding proto ops
field will always be correctly
initialized and well that's that was not
a good assumption so you can see here
the code from 16 page and if you read
the very bottom line it just returns
suck-ups sent page without checking that
this is not null so of course it went
wrong and it was very wrong because
first a lot of drivers did not get
properly updated but the really funny
thing that we found out or that the the
very sock up wrap macro which is used to
initialize a lot of drivers had the bug
and the burg is quite circle I mean if
you won't take a look at some it's not
trivial to spot i would say because the
macro itself uses a lot of all those
macros it's it's a mess so basically
what happened is for many drivers even
those which had been updated sent page
was implicitly initialized to know so
well 16 page would happily start
executing code at null for you so the
expectation was just you map your
shellcode null you get you you you
trigger send page for instance by using
the sent file system call and you get
your code executed so we've wrote a
trivial exploit for this that we share
with vendors and but other people have
written public exploits for like pretty
much every every popular architecture so
you can find this is ed online shortly
after that we found another one which
was yeah not not not this not as bad but
way more complicated it was possible we
found out that it was possible to
trigger a special code pass in UDP send
message that would result in calling
some function called IP append data with
a new routing table
the interesting part of this bug is
mostly that that it's quite hard to spot
if you look at this function the cut
pass is really complicated and this time
it was a data and I went under reference
the attacker would control some canal
data a routing table through address
null and this turned out to be
exploitable as well although it was less
trivial you want to talk about this so
another interesting i admit we worked on
was a use after three in the linear
facing subsystem so if a driver wants to
provide asynchronous i/o notification
they have a linked list of FA sing
struts they contain the FDS and the
cause many file structures that they
want to notify when I always available
the same file structure turns out the
same file structure could be in multiple
FAS construct lists and there was a
special one specifically for locked
files if the file was locked and then
closed there was a logical book where
the file structure would be removed from
only the locked files linked list the
structure will be freed even though it
appeared multiple lists so then you have
this this the structure in in the second
list that in release that has been
passed out to anybody else who wants her
some came alok buffer so the driver
still had a reference to this plead file
structure so this was we vote a proof of
concept but we we didn't get next by
working simply because it was really
really complicated but we released the
information about it in Linux and a guy
called the Gabrielle campanha work next
point for it and he wrote an article in
a French their information security
magazine called misc mi SE I don't read
French but I'm told from from French
speakers that it was actually an awesome
article so if you do a friend she should
check it out he used some really cool
tricks to get a reliable and to make a
reliable code execution so yeah you
should check out a few interested
and so this bug is in net be as it's the
only net BS debug we are talking about
today but we really love this book
actually investigating this bug took me
more time than then for a lot of other
bugs we are talking about today it was
really nice so we found out well I mean
it's documented in the Intel manuals but
it's not very easy to find that an inter
a privilege irate can fail before the
previous switch occurs so what we called
we call this the the commit point where
the previous which occurs so we said I
read can fail pre-commit so for instance
if the restored eip is passed the code
segment limit general protection fault
will occur while in kernel mode so no
proofs which will occur so what's what
what difference does it make that no
previous which occurs well if no prints
which occurs no statutory nose tax which
occurs between user London and kernel
and stacks so basically you have no
saved stack information on the trap
frame so if you're operating system is
not expecting this and net bsd was not
expecting this to happen so it was
expecting a full trap frame all the time
well basically you will have your trap
frame shifted so of course you can you
can play with this and and and try to
exploit this and so we were thinking
about this and we also found out that
the way the the non-executive will stack
emulation work on net bsd is they they
they put us a cut segment limit just
below the stack so what and we found out
that that during a legitimate programs
execution we could we could trigger the
bug because if you happen to have
legitimate call on the stack so that
happens for instance if you have nested
functions in GCC you can get
champlin on the stack so if you're if
you're for instance in in a signal
handler in the kernel and you return
from the signal handler to to this
trampoline on the stack for a nested
function you will start you will
directly return from Colonel to code
that actually passed the segment limit
so that's exactly the situation we
described here and so what this means is
this book can actually happen like this
in in real life and just crush net bsd
kernels so we reported this a long time
ago i think more a year and a half ago
and i think it's still not corrected as
far as we know and that that one was
really interested interesting because
actually tavis used used this streak
later for his auntie vdm exploit which i
think you're going to take talk about
now okay so after we discovered these
fun bugs in various interrupt handlers
we decided this was going to be some
food for research so we decided to
remain altered the remaining interrupt
handlers we defined so we found one
section of code in ki Tripodi which is
the name of the GP trap handler in
microsoft public symbols and we found
one location where it appeared to trust
the contents of the trap frame this was
a bit of a WTF moment for us where we
saw we saw this code that was obviously
doing something completely bizarre we
could tell that this was a component of
the virtual 8086 mode monitor simply
because the the branch to reach this
code was was checking the vm flag in the
e clogs image so it the reaching this
code was was really hard work and it
took about two weeks of research to
figure out how to start of each this
code and on top of that we need to write
a reliable exploit but I think it was
worth it at the end we found a really
fascinating an ancient vulnerability in
really the core of Windows NT and yeah I
actually want a pony award for this last
night so I think it was like it was
worth it
so this is a recap of some of the
features that we needed to exploit this
if you remember most programming you'll
be familiar with in 21 which is used to
invoke system services but if you wanted
to make a bios call to interact with the
hardware than you needed call other
interrupt handlers most people remember
in 10 because it was used for things
like the demo scene I'd also that was
quite famous but obviously you can't you
can't allow a protected mode task to
interact the interactive hardware this
way so in virtual 8086 mode these are
services are intercepted by the monitor
so Intel Intel calls this concept
sensitive instructions so basically what
they do is any operation that a real
real mode program would be expected
would expect to work is made sensitive
and that basically means that in hell
will will cause this GP and give the
operating system a chance to to fix this
up or emulate it or do whatever ones so
in this way programs that could never be
allowed to work in protected mode can
can all the services they expect to be
able to use can be faked and if they can
they can think they were working on a
real and I star system or whatever so
yeah these actions trap and then the
colonel is given an opportunity to
decide how it wants to proceed so so the
design of the the virtual 8086 mode
monitor in Windows NT has really never
changed since it's since imputation and
implementation in the early 90s and in
fact yeah if you download these old
service packs from ftp microsoft com for
old out-of-date versions that they don't
support you can you can still get a copy
these kernels they even include public
symbols but obviously they're in DVD
format not PD be like we use nowadays
but still you can still pass them and
and look around it's a kind of
archaeology for code I guess it's kind
of fun
so yeah in order to support these by our
server two teams and stuff exists in the
GP trap handler that the restores
execution context for the trap frame in
order to access this code it's
authenticated but these were by magic
values that we already knew that we
could Forge from from VMware exploit and
from our previous work on interrupt
handlers so we knew that we were we will
under something that we could we could
really control there were lots of
hurdles on the way and it took us a long
time to get to reach this but each one
was an interesting exercise and I'm
talking about them so how do you
interact with the virtual 8086 polk
monitor on windows NT it's a non
undocumented system service called NT
vdm control it's authenticated you're
not allowed to access it and as you have
a special flag in your process structure
called vdm allowed you can't set this
flag unless you have setc be privileged
and you'll use something like I think
it's empty system information or set
process information and you need s ettv
privilege so if you have setc be
privileged like STC bears trusted code
base then you're already when there was
privileged processes on the system and
you don't really need to escape images
any further so this is so it's not
immediately obvious that you cancel you
can still access the system call but you
can defeat this really easily all you
have to do is invoke the real NTV DMSO
subsystem and then use the winter
youtube api create remote led to execute
within within it this way your thread is
meeting with in a process that already
has this flag set in its media in its
energy process structure so yeah auntie
vdm control is completely undocumented
the best documentation for it is really
Alex Insp was already reverse engineered
it so that you can work out the API from
his code in react OS so yeah he's
already done all the hard work so it's
you can understand it that way this is
still of other special cases that we
needed to understand for this particular
bug we needed to bypass things like a
checks for structure sizes and magic
checks and so on it took some time but
yeah Alex I know speech code in Viet Wes
was really hard to understand this stuff
so this code that we found in the trial
in the in the GP trap handler was gutted
by a test for a specific CSE I pee pad
we can forge these with these trap
frames by making an I read failed but we
still you can't request to turn into an
allergy code segment obviously that
would be stupid because you're just
you're just using the RPL 0 a value and
then you'd get instant kernel code
execution so nobody would just be silly
enough to make that mistake but as we
vote in OCS loses its magic value in
virtual 86 mode because you need to be
able to access these discs 2008 real
address space so it's completely
reasonable to request any value but we
still need to cause i right to GP and we
did this by by setting the TF flag in
the e flags image when returning so
intel actually considers this sensitive
and had ins control over the virtual
8086 mode monitor but this is actually
poorly documented and in fact there's no
mention of this at all in the
documentation and from research we know
that early versions of the pentium
processor would impact not treat IRA
flags TF sat in the e flags images
sensitive and that wasn't considered
sensitive at all but apparently doing
some later revisions of the pentium
intel updated this and and did consider
a sensitive and in fact this is really
documented by other members named the
sand pile yet so there's this great
resource online called sand pile where
lots of crazy intel tricks had
documented and yes so it's explained
that at some point intel decided that
this did this should be sensitive and
they updated it but they never issued
any Lovato or they never updated any
documentation so what we think might
have happened was that Microsoft Judas
when Microsoft implemented this they
believed that this would they could rely
on this and then Intel suddenly changes
the the the the x86 document
specification so that it was sensitive
and Microsoft never bothered to check
whether these checks were still valid
which is pretty reasonable I mean
how many people check this little level
code every day it's it's it's it's the
kind of thing that you why Quentin
nobody remembers how it works just don't
touch it so yeah so we found that we by
experimentation we proof that this was
this is actually still the case ok so i
have a video of this it's not
particularly to watch but it's ok so
yeah so I votive a libel exploit for
every every supported version of Windows
NT you basically just invoked a new
process and it would hand it over and
you a system token so yeah it was it was
very reliable and it worked perfectly
and in fact it was a bit of a challenge
to write because all the existing
published shell code for Windows NT
privilege escalation bugs we're never
expected anything to work across more
than one or two kernel versions so
everything published was like very
windows XP specific or whatever and they
had like hard coded offsets into
structures and so on and so yeah I spent
some time working on a completely
colonel neutral version that would work
on every version of Windows NT simply
because there wasn't an exploit exists
that no explore you existed like this
around that I could reference so I have
some code that i can i can show you so
what I did was so this is where my where
the colonel lands after I exploit this
vulnerability and so basically I have to
start biting a driver code as if I was
writing a real driver based on like
symbols that microsoft support so that I
could be sure that they would be
available on every kernel version so
yeah I basically have to work out where
my kernel is loaded and then start
passing the colonel export directing
myself manually so then I based and I
can basically write driver coded as if
it was as if I was writing a genuine
driver so because the kernel stack gets
d synchronized because I'm passing at
this fake stack that that I wanted to
swap to it turns out that the host my
whole cage reg structure gets completely
messed up and in order not to for this
corruption to propagate to other parts
of the system
I had to repair it so I find all
references to to this to my this fake
stack up set up and and we store them
because I'm going to kill this process
anyway because I only want it I only
wanted to use it to to pass to paste a
privilege token onto another process I
don't really care what a quitter points
out I just wanted to so that I just
wanted not to be corrupt anything so
yeah so basically I just search for all
these values then I find debate the most
privileged process on the system which
is the initial system process grab a
couple reference to its primary token
and then pasted on tomato paste it onto
my this process that's unprivileged and
yeah and this works on this only uses
exported symbols that microsoft support
but for driver developers so it's
completely reliable across every every
anti version that was affected so let's
see so yeah so basically yeah I set up
this kernel stack and the offsets for
things like we're strolling into TB and
the the new a new stack pointer which is
going to be a fake stack and user and
the use of address space and changed the
return address into my into my exploit I
mean my payload so you need in order to
access this code you did data structure
called a tip in your tab I don't know
what eid stands like this is that
information block or something like that
with the TV is obviously a fun
environment block then you in slice the
vdm subsystem and it turns out because
this data structure is unsupported and
undocumented microsoft in mind changing
it as much as much as they liked
obviously very reasonable but in order
to identify which version is is being
used they there's a size field which
which the if it isn't the correct value
they say they return access denied but
because i don't know which i don't know
what the size should be with in fact
leaving changes between service packs so
i can't even I can't even guess from the
virgin so I just basically had a brute
force and try every value until it works
and this would this works fine
so yeah because the real address in
virtual 8086 mode Intel expect you to
map the virtual the the fake wheel mode
address space on the first page needs to
map know the first page so there's no
documented way to do this and in fact if
you try to do it with any of the win32
API is it just doesn't work because no
special meaning and it it means you know
you have no preference whether this is
going to be mapped but if you if you use
NT allocate virtual memory which is the
system called the backs all the stuff
that all the regular allocation stuff
like virtual or consumer then it's
possible to do that because it round
style addresses to the nearest page so
if you wanted something map-21 the
address one then obviously one isn't a
page boundary so if you want something
map-21 you need to do it is maps and get
the next available page which is 0 so
you basically just pass in a really low
address it bans it down to the nearest
page and you get it you get it mapped
and there you go and that works so we've
also been working on automation and
automation and buzzing for the operating
system kernels so we've been working on
the system called exploration to try and
find interesting attack servers that we
want to reach on Windows the system call
interface it's complex it's unstable its
unsupported and it's undocumented and
it's also pretty vast if you consider
Linux has about 300 system calls windows
actually has about 1,400 but in fact
that that's a pretty conservative value
because Microsoft really like this
design of multiplexing system calls on
linux there's only one multiplexing
system call which is socket call so
things like bind except understand and
things like this of all of all the same
system called called socket call I need
to pass a value saying which year which
one you wanted but my tough love love
this and they have they have dozens and
dozens of them so you pass a magic value
it which tells them which system call
you actually want it and it can be
dozens available via one in the pier one
entry point so in fact 1400 is probably
pretty conservative value there's
1400 ssdd entries but there's more
likely I would guess about 3,000 system
calls really so on windows these are
designed only to to only ever be called
by Microsoft code it's they make it they
make it very difficult to call system
calls and it's they're not supported
across versions so they don't mind
breaking stuff which is totally
reasonable this is all this is all
expected so and as most people know I
guess they random I system calls
physical numbers between service packs
just to make sure that you're not trying
to rely on this well I guess that's
prolly not with this design to do they
just do that's part of the build process
but that's that's the effect because
nobody no windows program is called
these setting goals directly there you
go to the wind did you two supported and
documented abis they're rarely exposed
to malformed parameters so in general
simple fuzzing can still exposed
interesting bugs simply because real
world program is on touching their stuff
so ya on the next if if it's expected
that just regular programmers will call
system calls and in fact when you
sitting call functionality is a little
Linux it so it's quite common to see
regular programmers bugs or reports that
there oops has been Luke's has been
caused as they try out the new code and
this weeds out lots of bugs before it
reaches anything that could be security
sensitive in like Enterprise
distributions or whatever but yeah this
is in the case on Windows simply because
this isn't designed to be called by end
users but obviously there's nothing
stopping you actually do that if you
want attacker so also the design of
system calls on Windows NT is very
different from from the philosophy on on
Linux in general on the next structures
are very simple they can be read in one
or two operations and they're easy to
pass the very simple structures but on
home windows the often complex object
objects the multiple levels deep they
have large interdependencies that all
need to be passed if you set
pathological parameters in in these
complex structures you can reach some
very rarely exercised code
and in fact there's code that you just
simply cannot reach via any supported
interface and and it's it's difficult to
it's difficult to imagine how Microsoft
managed to test this and no and no end
users are going to complain simply
because they did the dead never never
rely on this code of course colonel is
also pass lots of interesting stuff like
fonts and other complex formats and this
is all done it rings you and these are
great first candidates so we've we've
been working on system called fuzzing so
trivial fuzzing can still find Windows
bugs the attacks her place is really
large and there's lots of system calls
to play with you can find buzzing with
you can find buzzing on Linux but in
general the task is not so trivial
simply because the interfaces are so
simple it's it's tough to get them wrong
you need to do some work need to set up
some some complex state with file
descriptors or whatever but buzzing real
find bugs and we've had some success
this way we've been developing some
techniques for working on this that
we're trying to integrate into things
like Chrome OS release so we're hoping
that that we're hoping that this can
help make things like Linux privilege
escalation via malformed system core
operations are easier to spot as they've
introduced a regression testing and so
on so we're hoping this is going to help
Linux a local security in future so yeah
now we can talk about protecting the
colonel from from military slang code
one of one of the the first way that was
quite popular to try and protect the
colonel from malicious user non-code was
just having trusted paths executables so
well I mean the idea is just to have
trusted executables on me so it's it's
reasonably old I think I've seen acting
this accent people running shell boxes
in in the mid-90s using this so it was
pretty popular and there was a very
naive way of doing it on Linux which was
to just mount all use of writable pass
to know exact so if you could write
somewhere you could not execute the code
there we are trivial bypass for this for
instance for for systems which already
supported
dynamic libraries at the time you could
just go through the dynamic loader
because the dynamic load el de wood
would be in a trusted pass and it would
happily map map your code that it's a
job and execute your code just secure he
had a good GI DUI debased 14 years i
think it was released in two thousand or
something of this and nowadays it would
actually work if you what it could
almost work if you would just just mount
something with no exact because nowadays
that semantic is actually respected and
it does prevent fine mapping a spot
exact and not only exactly so this
approach is gaining some popularity on
the windows platforms who whitelisting
whitelisting we've seen a few products
that portray and perform white listing
on the windows platform so the idea is
just to prevent gaining arbitrary code
execution in the first place so that you
can't attack the colonel but of course
there are tons of way to bypass this
because arbitrary code execution should
not only mean arbitrary up codes if you
have if you if you can expect lots of
colonel bugs from a Python or Ruby
interpreter so if Python or Ruby are in
your trusted pass you can just explode
can I box for this also if you think
about powerful executive birds such as
gdb you can do whatever you want for GDB
so if you have access to gdb you can
obviously run arbitrary code I'm so
quite interesting tweak if if you're
trying to build a system with trusted
pass executable it the straight model is
completely changed for many binaries for
instance a local vulnerability nethack
or the minesweeper on Windows would
would become useful because they would
allow you to run arbitrary code and you
you've probably seen a few releases such
as vulnerabilities in make of energy in
gsh which didn't really make any sense
but in this very parodying they they do
make make sense
so of course of course this is also
useless if the attacker already has
arbitrary code execution so if you're
trying to protect a broader sandbox with
this it's useless because you're
assuming the attacker already has
arbitrary code execution in sandbox same
same thing for openssh or vsftpd first
separated sandbox so what what could we
really do that would be useful to choose
to do proper sandboxing an attack
surface reduction for for the colonel
ideally a process could opt out for from
some kernel features it does not require
on Linux there is nothing really that
that allows you to to drop privileges in
a discretionary way and all the focus is
on mandatory access control on Linux and
basically the prodding is very different
if you're if you're a programmer what
you want is you know that you know your
program you know how it works so you
want to be able to define a policy for
your own program but mini access control
is more about an administrator on the
system being able to define a policy so
if you're if you're writing a web
browser is not what you want on Windows
there are slightly more previous
drooping like features thanks to the
control over token and more recently
since Windows Vista we have things like
integrity levels so there are some
previous drooping like features but
there is still nothing to protect the
canals attack surface so the options are
limited and on linux v44 for google
chrome we needed something like this and
we we did some some hacks and we have a
saturated sandbox design that you can
look at if you're interested in this
we've published slides at black hat you
rap about this and it's it's quite weird
because they I mean nothing was really
designed for this so we kind of
hacked our way through it also bitchface
based sandboxes are quite popular the
idea is to use pitch ways to to be to be
notified whenever an untrusted process
will perform a system call so this can
be a good choice and for me of course
it's slow but otherwise for security can
be a good choice but it's very hard to
get right because betrayal ptrace was
not designed for this at all also
there's onion you guys 11 feature which
we which could have been interesting for
this called second second is a special
mode you can switch your process into
that that will only allow the process to
reach for system calls it will allow the
process to reach read write and just
exit plus sig return to be able to
handle signals so it's just the four
system calls so of course the kind of
attack surface is incredibly reduced
through this but the problem is for for
instance for Chrome we were very limited
for system calls are not going to be to
be enough we need to be able to allocate
memory for instance and 11 Googler
Marcus gojco is working on a sec comp
base sandbox and he's using crazy tricks
such as sharing address space between
different processes sharing file
descriptors and then other processes
which are not under Sec comp are are
able to to to proxy the needed system
calls it sort of works but it's not
deploying to chrome yet but you can
already look at it so another popular
alternative is basically people say okay
we can protect the colonel from from
from malicious code so what can we do
well let's reduce the kind of religious
by using virtualization so lots of
people do this of course virtualization
has its problem and
also expose quite a lot of attack
surface nowadays especially in some
popular products so well it's a I mean
it's a good idea but of course it has
its drawbacks something else to protect
the colonel is you derive and as we've
mentioned unexpected to user on point I
references are an issue and I've
mentioned before that on Linux they used
to not be exploitable because of thanks
to segmentation and so the idea be
behind you TF is very simple is just to
to make the kind of segments the cannons
data segment descriptor expand down and
put its limit above above user on code
the problem is what what can you do on
64-bit system since segmentation for for
most of its segmentation is not there
anymore so you can always do full
address space switching or other small
tricks but it's going to have some
performance penalty so a map minute away
was a pragmatic attempt by the Linux
developers to tackle this problem in a
possible mania the idea is just to have
a system why minimum address that can be
used in a process usually it's set to
64k so processes you learnin process
cannot i cannot map behind 64k but there
is an exception of course for processes
with the caps destroy your capability so
lots of root processes for instance this
has been plagued with many bugs in the
past it's in much better shape now but
we found we found one bypass that will
present now and we found another one
that we need to investigate so we use
personalities the this systems 5 release
for operating system maps page 0 as a
swede only and so on for here's some
programs depend on the behavior and to
make porting programs easier from from
system fiber is for to linux linux
reports a system fiber is for
personality so the this personality is
pure
says and it's kept on xik v of course so
the funny thing is we could get this
path personality and just choose to
execute a statue Iggy binary and then
since this is a saturated binary it
automatically gaps the caps is fry your
capabilities in said it executors fruit
and thanks to this capability and map
the map minado a check is bypassed and a
pap a page is mapped as zero in the
address space but of course dies there's
not much we can do it's a it's a root
process we don't control which has a
page mapped at zero so yeah you could
imagine that if this root process if
this foot yeah this would process has a
vulnerability like a null pointer
dereference maybe you could exploit it
but we we were trying to actually regain
control of this process and so we
started to look for a binary that would
drop religious and let let us regain
control without going through exact V
and we actually found one per soldier
allowed us to do this and it was not a
bug in / soda which was just a bug in
the linux kernel that we expected
through / so you but then of course then
we discovered / so do and and we took a
look at it and of course we also found a
vanity a completely different random
teen / sodium that was underrated so
your other other canal protections were
there are a few kind of protection from
pax but we don't have much time now if
you want to take questions so i will go
through this quickly so there are lots
of birds to find in canada we found 20
of them in in a year and we were still
doing a lot of other job other work so
it's there are lots of work to find the
attack surface is growing in general and
the really interesting thing that's not
necessarily expected is it's actually
easier to reach these attacks for phase
from remote if you've attended our talk
on virtualization a
pack sec we also we've also said a sim
racing for theater ization because
basically what happens is for
performance is reasoned people want to
design system so that everything goes
through as fast as possible to the
hardware and there is actually more and
more low-level attacks of face exposed
remotely which is which might be
unexpected and so they are expert the
exploitation of those flows goes from
very easy to very challenging it can be
really trivial and really hard it's
really hard to also get rid of the
knesset extra face even even in systems
design with security in mind it remains
so yeah we're hoping that Microsoft will
have some kernels attack surface
reduction facilities soon in Windows
we'll see how it goes also you can
really say that use on prevention user
and exploitation prevention is kind of
mature but in in terms of Colonel
expectation prevention it's really the
beginning and all the current send
boxing techniques you see in Google
Chrome now in microsoft office soon in
other products really make the current
an ideal target so thank thank you for
attending and if you have any question
we can take them we still have six
minutes
no questions thank you bye