so I'm going to get started my name is
Chris Hoff and this thank you for coming
this morning by ten o'clock I know I had
trouble showing up so I appreciate the
fact you got here at this early hour
this talk is as you can tell about about
cloud computing and specifically is
targeted towards security practitioners
who are trying to get a hold or a grasp
on what they have to do differently
operationally architectural e to
understand what cloud computing is going
to do to what it is they do is part of
the daily lives so you know the
interesting notion here is that when you
talk about cloud and we look at where
it's evolved from we we hear an awful
lot of discussions about what you know
the mainframe models and where cloud
arose from how it's you know how
ultimately it's fundamentally new
technology some argue it's you know it's
not what's interesting about it is the
elements associated with what what cloud
computing means to security is is wide
and varied depending upon which models
what you mean by cloud computing so
we're going to talk about a whole bunch
of stuff in this talk and it's really
one of my kind of infotainment firehose
talks there's a ton of content that is
on these slides all kind of highlight
what's on the slides you'll have them
available to you they generally end up
being pretty decent reference points the
three things that we're really going to
focus on here are are in bold we're
going to talk about idempotent
infrastructure as it relates to public
infrastructure to cloud services and
I'll explain what item potent
infrastructure means in more detail but
if you start thinking about sameness of
infrastructure homogeneity from the
perspective of being able to scale
that's what that's going to focus on
we're going to talk about revisiting a
concept called survivability or
information survivability as well as
information centricity and these three
things will kind of make more sense as
we go along and discuss how cloud
computing is really bringing back a lot
of concepts that in many cases we've I
don't say abandoned but we've kind of
forgotten so we're going to talk about
the fact that not all public
infrastructure service providers and
services are created equal and not
they're not all really focused or
targeted the same type of customer
either and really there's
differentiation going on based on the
types of networking connectivity
security and a whole bunch of things
that ultimately make a big difference
between one infrastructure to service
cloud provider let's say at a
mass-market scale versus one that
specializes in certain niches we're
going to talk about the fact that public
infrastructure to cloud services can
absolutely allow you to take an
application today they'll engineer at in
your enterprise and be deployed just as
securely or even more so than then what
you do today that's that's a tough thing
to get your arm around however that
needs to be paired with a sentence that
if you are willing to fundamentally we
architects your applications your
infrastructure your operations your
organization and how much money you
spend where why and how then that
statement holds true so we're going to
talk about that ultimately it really is
time to kind of get the bell bottoms out
of the closet like every 15 years stuff
comes back into popularity and this is
one of those things we're going to see a
whole lot of applicability of stuff that
has lingered around for a while but was
solutions looking for problems today we
have those problems and speaking of that
this is really kind of one of a series
one that's kind of the fourth in the
series i started i started this with my
four horsemen of the virtualization
security apocalypse talk which talked
about how virtualization was really
impacting networking and security that
went on to this the frogs who desired a
king talk which really kind of out lied
or outlined the high level kind of
30,000 foot view issues associated with
how cloud was fundamentally changing
what we did in security and then the
cloud of fornication talk which was
really highlighting how infrastructure
kind of hot cloud on cloud action how
essentially you were getting cloud based
on clouds based on clouds with
staggering amounts of independency so
this last one is really more about okay
we know what the problems are what can
we do about them where are we trending
in terms of infrastructure as a service
while we have platform as a service in
software is a service also I find that
in many cases people are really trying
to grapple with what the differences are
between infrastructures our service and
what they do in the enterprise today so
we're going to focus on that so like
most good things in life you can blame
the French get food and wine and other
things but the point here is I like to
make an analogy to kind of stick with
people and maybe this one will maybe it
won't but for me I really like a siege
warfare and I love kind of being a
history
of military and so being a history buff
from the military and so from the
perspective of what a siege warfare and
why this relates the trebuchet was
really interesting um evolution of a set
of capabilities for siege warfare that I
find very interesting you had actually
not the French to blame initially but
the French and the Greeks and Romans who
also stole some stuff from other people
but you had stuff like the catapult a
pretty simple mechanical fulcrum arm and
the ballista which just launched these
big big Spears but then that the
trebuchet came online with this kind of
really interesting counter-balance
weight and this sling what was
interesting about it was the French
introduces around the 12th century and
it and what they really did was just
better the concepts associated with what
they saw in the balista and the catapult
so as I mentioned the trebuchet that
thing on the Left utilized this sling
with this counterbalanced armed with a
weight and it could basically doubled
the throwing throwing power of the
engine that you could use to hoist hoist
projectiles so catapults are really
efficient you could use them to kind of
lob things like a 50 60 pounds a couple
hundred feet but what you found with the
trebuchet is you can throw objects like
300 pounds several hundred feet so
instead of making like little Dinks in
in the side of a castle and kind of
chipping away at it you could knock down
entire walls right which is which is a
very very interesting tipping point from
the perspective of what siege warfare
and battle warfare and battlements had
to deal with so what that really
amounted to was a really a better
mousetrap but a much more operationally
complex model to deal with and I say
that because if you look at kind of how
this thing is constructed you had to
have an understanding of a great deal
more of physics and physical science to
pull this thing off it was really a
marriage of a lot of other previous
catapult designs but with better physics
and better applied a physical science
and it works on a simple principle but
ultimately there was absolutely nothing
simple about getting one of the things
set up making it work making it work
efficiently and in fact when things
didn't work efficiently it was it was
horrific so precision was a very
important part about about about the
trebuchet and more interesting enough
what does this have to do with cloud
what strength enough it was kind of when
you look at the trebuchet it was an
evolutionary application of some
revolutionary idea
is like gravity right it caused quite a
stir a whole shell shift in strategy no
longer could you just expect that your
castle was going to stand there and you
could would you know with a you could
withstand bombardment it really laid the
foundation for a whole lot more of the
mechanized sets of siege warfare
applications and even more innovation in
battlefield in the battlefield and
basically it was the precursor to a lot
of how people were thinking about
battlefield automation and what a
defender would also have to do to deal
with this so when you think about kind
of the progression there as an analogy
which I find useful in talks like this
there was a set of studies in the late
80s Early 90s from Carnegie Mellon that
was funded by DARPA that was called the
information survivability and it talked
about a bunch of shifts and these shifts
if you think of in 2000-2001 and you
think about where we are now in 2010 it
may not seem like an awful lot of time
but these these shifts were were pretty
recent they were they were amazingly
accurate and very interesting when we
look at how IT if you kind of compare
that analogy to the trebuchet is also
progressed so what they said was there
were seven shifts that we ultimately
were moving from a very centralized to
globalized way of interacting both from
an IT perspective and way of doing
business they talked about going from
bounded to unbounded ultimately from
insular to networked from predictable in
terms of events and timelines to
asynchronous right from single to shared
responsibility from overhead to
essential right from the way in which we
are perceived in terms of IT security
those sorts of things from security to
survivability and I'll highlight what
that means a little bit later but it
really is a is a little bit of a
wholesale shift in terms of how you
think about what we do and ultimately I
added two more on to this these weren't
in the original seven but from static to
dynamic and from manual to automated so
if you think and you look at where we
are with virtualization look at what we
were cloud computing these shifts have
really exactly manifested themselves in
the way that that Carnegie Mellon talked
about was going to happen about 10 years
ago so what's actually happened is we've
moved and consolidated from servers to
pools or of of resources in terms of the
compute layer networking storage has
moved from dedicated a local attached
storage and and
and disc two clusters and fabrics both
in hardware and in software ultimately
we have escaped from this kind of
tightly coupled set of applications and
infrastructure to a distributed
computing model that really makes makes
a fundamental shift in the way in which
we think about both application
deployment and security and ultimately
transition from infrastructure to this
notion of composable service layers and
these things are interesting from cloud
because if you look at what this is if
you look at these changes and you think
about where we are from the security
industry perspective we really have not
addressed these moves at all or at least
not very well right so when you think
about public cloud again it's very
important to think about the fact that
not all public clouds are created equal
or for the same purpose that really what
it talks about is in most people's eyes
is scale that is enabled by abstracted
and item potent infrastructure meaning
homogeneity with lots and lots of it so
massive data centers with hundreds of
thousands of cores a huge storage and a
lot of bandwidth ultimately and
extremely agile heavily virtualized and
and for the most part mostly completely
automated and hugely software driven
which is not really how we thought of
our data centers five years ago
ultimately also the way in which we
manage and interact with these stacks is
almost now moving exclusively to an API
model which means you don't have
standalone apps you you can spin up and
control the entire infrastructure
programmatically which is very very
interesting so when we think about
public cloud it is important to kind of
think about the enterprise version of it
just for dimension to compare and
contrast so if we think about a private
cloud or enterprise infrastructure to
service it really is there to leverage
virtualization right and basically
squeeze efficiency automation better
self-service those sorts of things it's
really focused on security and
compliance for the most part as one big
reason to keep it internally and the
infrastructure is still exposed in many
cases to the IT teams they can store you
know turn the knobs and total bits it's
really about the general preservation of
existing architecture and infrastructure
they may converge stuff networking
storage and compute it may look a little
different but the whole point is really
it's not really business as usual but
the fundamental operational practices
associated how an enterprise manages
this stuff is really very similar public
cloud on the other side is a fundamental
riorca texture of application
security compliance pretty much
everything that we talked about in
public cloud is about massive amounts of
abstraction we need to isolate and hide
the moving parts from you so you can get
on with actually running the business
instead of building the business what's
interesting here is it focuses on scale
on lower costs homogenate the
infrastructure layers and is for the
most part primarily software enabled or
software focused so when you think about
public cloud what this really means is
all about gracefully giving up direct
operational control over infrastructure
which is something most people are very
very uncomfortable with especially
security people because if you can't
touch it feel it don't understand how it
works don't have visibility transparency
we can't do a good job of securing it so
therein lies the problem right what we
have in public cloud is this large set
of essentially heterogeneous monoculture
of both operating system and hardware
that is abstract 'add we it's the
functional equivalent of what we had to
deal with the siebel if any of you
before Oracle acquired them if you
remember Siebel you didn't change the
software to fit the business you changed
the business to fit the software right
you had fundamental shifts in the way
you were supposed to operate your
business now that wasn't a sara lee a
bad thing but there were an awful lot of
challenges associated with what was
assumed we were supposed to do from a
security perspective to manage this
stuff so these shifts when we think
about how we've dealt with the security
models of the past attack origin
defensive strategy approach how we
manage identity how we deploy
applications how hardware and software
resources commingle and where our data
is as we kind of progressed along this
time line to the present and ultimately
the future with this notion of
ubiquitous cyber terror and the fact
that we have repolarization everything
should be turning towards being
information-centric federated trust
distributed software and cloud what's
interesting about that is when we think
about how security has shifted to deal
with this to this model of survivability
survivability versus security as I
talked about before when I alluded to
the fact i define it is really about
preserving operations in the face of
attack that we know we're going to get
attack that we're going to get owned so
you have to make the systems very
resilient and it has to be holistically
of architected ultimately depends on the
ability of these network systems to
provide continuity even if the service
levels are degraded it requires that
that only you
you protect only the critical assets
which is a really tough thing for most
security folks as well as the business
to understand they expect us to protect
everything equally with no budget
ultimately it complements the current
risk assessment methodologies it doesn't
really require you to go out and make a
left hand turn to understand how risks
change but you should have a decent
handle ultimately understanding how
these things change and impact you it
includes but is broader than traditional
information security we're going to get
into why so if you look at this this
game francisco's mid-year security
report where they kind of tracked things
that are interesting like connected
devices applications and security
threats so we're right here right now 35
billion divided interconnected network
devices on the planet enough for hours
at five per person right on the entire
planet 265,000 mobile applications 2.6
million security threats by 2013 you can
look at the number a trillion inter
connected devices 140 / human being on
the planet 1.5 million mobile
applications and 5.7 million security
threats I don't know how we're going to
really be able to keep up with that if
we don't adjust and we don't change so
one of the things we're going to talk
about here is why and what cloud does to
play with this in play playing this
particular issue so we're really you
know it should be no no surprise that
we're kind of we've got this case of
security a DD the threat model velocity
as well as the innovation of the
attacker far outpaces the defender we've
heard that the general said that this
morning by design security doesn't
really scale very well right it assumes
there's going to be some human being or
some level of intelligence or
interaction so automation of security
doesn't really work we don't almost by
design allow it to especially given how
siloed we are and that's a problem if we
think about moving to infrastructure
there's completely automated it's really
not about defense-in-depth anymore it's
about defense in width like we just
spray so much crap on a stack and hope
that ultimately it is going to be
protected that we don't know where how
or why we invest in things and
ultimately the economic model for
vendors is not incentivized to serve or
solve long-term problems stare to sell
product based on need and most people
aren't in the in the don't have the
ability to actually look downrange
they're dealing with threats today so if
we look at this ultimately
this from my last presentation we moved
from the mainframe model where stuff was
very centralized ultimately reasonably
reliable but slow connectivity the
client-server skipping minis to web 10
to web 20 with mashups to kind of
emergence of this dichotomy between
mobile computing and cloud computing and
at the same point in time the security
community as well as the industry has
been remarkably consistent in its
response to both programmatic
development as well as how the
architecture has changed so almost
consistently we have done a excellent
job of providing you one of these which
doesn't solve any of the actual
long-term problems and there's a reason
for that and that reason is called the
security hamster sine wave of pain some
of you may seen it before but I like to
use this because it actually explains
why we are where we are we really do on
the Left axis you basically have how we
invest and where we deploy from a
security perspective and we kind of
flip-flop between host-based and
network-based centricity for therefore
our solution sets almost constantly over
time right so what happens is you know
you can pick an arbitrary point in time
on the sine wave it's actually much more
bursty but it's moved and ribbed for
your pleasure in this presentation we
start up host right we deploy an agent
then we deploy 27 agents one per thread
then we converge those into a mega agent
that takes up eighty-six percent of the
CPU utilization and 14.7 gigs of memory
we say you know this isn't working so we
say what we need to do is focus on the
application will fix the apps so we
invest in sdlc we basically retool the
apps and everything breaks we deploy
laughs and things break heuristically
and we don't know why because the
developers are completely disconnected
from the security teams and the
infrastructure teams so we say you know
what will focus on the information will
just protect it oh where is it it's
everywhere I don't know you know I have
no ability to essentially get my arms
around the information so we'll move
will protect things by focusing on the
user will stop the monkeys from pushing
the wrong buttons and that doesn't work
because people give up password for
chocolate bars so then we say okay
speeds and feeds are awesome we'll do it
in the network except we've encrypted
all the data so now I can't gain
visibility without man in the middle
which breaks the applications and the
users and the information so it goes on
and on and on and to make it worse if I
oprah lie that sine wave with a cosine
which represents disruptive innovation
or new technology like cloud or
virtualization what you find is our
deployment methodology is focused up
here
we're the actual use case for deployment
aware of what you're actually able to
deploy from a compensated control is
down here what I mean by that is if you
look at mass-market public cloud
providers where the network is
abstracted I don't have access to the
network or its entire basis for what it
looks like and where it is completely
changes so I can't deploy a compensating
control the same way so I deploying my
guest right so now I'm installing
software instead of it for choke points
it it potentially hundreds of thousands
of endpoints that automatically scale so
what's interesting is that differential
180 degree out of phase is hugely
problematic right but we flip-flop this
way and we the stuff in the middle that
information sent centric part is where
we really ought to focus but we never
actually get time to do that so when we
look at this problem set and we look at
the stacks on the left I like two
separate things into three chunks and I
did I bought this up as a model in in
the cloud of fornication talk and I'm
going to do it again here I like to
break things down into three chunks
infrastructure which is kind of like
compute network storage all the moving
parts info structure at the top apps
data metadata and in the middle is
metastructure which is glue and guts
protocols in a non virtualized non cloud
world metastructure is supposed to bind
or provide affinity between the
infrastructure and applications sticks
them together that's the old world model
monolithic apps in virtualization or
cloud that middle layer nearly
ultimately if you introduce
virtualization in any concept or
abstraction is supposed to separate or
provide basically a a fluid layer
between the two so that they don't they
are actually not statically bound
they're separated the problem is all the
infrastructure stuff that is used to
interfacing with protocols that are very
stale and Static completely break this
model when we start to introduce
mobility of workloads of data of
information right so this notion of
automation is really really screwy
especially when you pair it with the
fact that in public cloud providers
they're building this notion of
idempotent infrastructure we're hardware
for example and the software blends into
this amorphous blob that abstracts
capabilities prevents you essentially
presents you with certain layers and
ways of interacting with the stack but
you don't know what they're you know how
they're composed and so I didn't potent
infrastructure is very interesting
because it Maps back to the root part of
how our practices have to change in the
security world so when everything looks
the same
it's it's both awesome and horrific at
the same time and we're going to talk
about this so idempotent basically is a
computer science mathematics earth at
means essentially once i deploy you know
III have one system when i deploy
multiple of them i essentially can
affect an issue of scale without change
so i'm essentially able to i mean that
you can call them multiple times and it
has the same result so when you think
about infrastructure here as it relates
to cloud it means i can spin up an image
or a hundred of them and essentially
what i do is just serve you know more
and better by a greater amounts of
volume so idempotent infrastructure is
interesting because when you think about
it and cloud the matrix is a great
example with agent smith right just keep
multiplying all the skill sets are the
same but there's just more of it ah this
notion is that homogeneity here provides
the ability to scale out right which is
something if you have the illusion of
infinite scale is awesome because you
can essentially if you have that need
continue to roll out more resources it
does not always imply commodity hardware
however i told you that in the beginning
there's very much a difference between
one extreme on the on the on the company
scale of of what public cloud providers
can can do an offer and on the other end
you have people that differentiate and
focus on a different set of problems so
on one side you could use commodity
hardware on the other on the other side
you could use a best-of-breed it does
not always imply commodity hardware to
get item potent infrastructure it really
is there to maximize density and
modularity of resources so i can quickly
refit reconfigure be it early extensible
so i can continue to add functions it
really relies on this notion of an agile
software methodology and deployment
constant deployment of software such
that it is really about being software
enabled and driven even if there's
infrastructure and hardware underneath
that empowers it it's kind of this
notion of code is infrastructure and if
you're a physical security if you're if
you're a security guy that's normally
used to deploying physical security of
things like firewalls you know where we
basically just choke down on port 80
code is infrastructure should terrify
you at the same point if you don't have
those skill sets because ultimately how
are you going to affect the ability to
audit secure and ultimately control
infrastructure that can change at a
moment by moment that's not
bad thing either and when we think about
this you know we're kind of we get
scared about this notion of elasticity
where in many cases it's not the biggest
problem that we have to solve and when I
talk about that we talk about these
stacks what's interesting today is um
this notion of what is powering these
clouds is is rapidly evolving we've got
market leaders right now that Thanks
that have really set the stage for the
evolution of a lot of what a lot of what
we we perceive as public cloud but you
also have a ton of movement now you've
got all of these providers is probably
20 more but but for example all of these
different cloud providers that have
released the capability to deploy their
software in any environment and build
stacks and open clouds on them so
OpenStack dot orgs a good a good example
it was basically NASA and Rackspace
getting together they're open sourcing
their code and making it available to
deploy you know a cloud a cloud
operating system and a CloudStack across
anybody's infrastructure you've got you
know cloud com citrix xen cloud a whole
bunch of these available stacks they'll
ultimately consolidate but what's
interesting here is the stacks and how
they function and how you interoperating
secure is pretty important so as we're
going to kind of go from the bottom of
the stack up if we look at the the
underlying functions that make up
infrastructure we look at the compute
cores and memory elements you've got
compute fabrics now that could be
commodity they could be kind of massage
or engineered solutions so I can be
completely proprietary and specialized
you have kind of a battle raging between
lots of CPUs versus fewer cpus with lots
of cores so that's kind of an
interesting thing that's occurring today
cpu versus GPU so now you have the for
one of the first GPU clouds being
powered by Nvidia that was I think
released a couple of days ago for doing
a huge amounts of 3d rendering right
very interesting so it's not just CPUs
anymore we've seen also GPUs being used
in password cracking and recovery and
those sort of things and also by botnets
the whole goal here is really about
lower power lower BTU output from
temperature and being highly dense we've
got interesting battles and discussions
raging between vendors about the stuff
between dedicated versus huge amounts of
shared memory and allowing the
hypervisors to man
its allocation and again everything is
really here in the compute layer talked
about as being managed by these restful
HTTP api's so you have things like that
last stack which was which was google's
a bunch of stuff strapped onto a
cardboard and plastic board you know
with even a battery backup you've got
stuff like cisco ucs you've got stuff
like HP's matrix you've got things like
the Talera 512 cores on a single CPU you
have things like this see man I think it
the name of the company five but 512
atom atom processors and a half a rack
right huge amounts of compute capability
being squeezed into really really small
amounts of space if we kind of go up the
stack down we think about all this
compute note and how its interconnected
James Hamilton who works at amazon web
services as part of a larger
presentation wrote this interesting deck
that basically said data center networks
are in my way like what I what I need
today from it from a network capability
in the traditional data center design is
really really stopping me from being
successful in deploying cloud so he
talked about a whole bunch of stuff like
I spent a lot of money it emits a bunch
of heat I don't have the density I need
I you where and how I can place
workloads is actually restricted it's a
mainframe business model I think all
valid points when mapped against the
business model of a public cloud
provider and what they do so when you
think of let's say a Google and Amazon
or a facebook or even a Twitter and you
think about what they do from a load
perspective and how they function and
how their software is architected what's
interesting is the network architecture
is very critical here or will be and
continued to be as it moves along so
these are some really really dense
slides I'm going to kind of highlight
them but really you have to figure out
first of all where is the network is it
in hardware is it in software is it a
hybrid model of both in many cases now
we have software modules open be
switched systems nexus 1000v OpenFlow
nicira that really talks about these
very interesting software driven models
of networking you have to look at the
fact that hugely abstracted networks
really create challenges with things
like network topology simple issues that
we've dealt with before layer 2 and
layer 3 but things now that have impact
on things like support for multicast and
broadcast spanning tree protocol our
understanding of how networks function
security how do I provide hooks to allow
me the plumbing physical
or a combination of security
capabilities to get me back visibility
and management the initiative of
mobility and the fact that as workloads
move around all of the network
properties and policies and things that
need to essentially be as asserted by
the network need to follow them and the
network network needs to be able to
enforce them so naming location
addressing and this isn't just in the
local concept this is a much broader
global concept as these clouds get
millions of cores and their data centers
across the entire globe you have to
figure out how your workloads and where
your workloads are and how you're going
to basically make them available this
notion of performance is huge issues
with IO and public clouds based on that
abstraction is still a huge issue
playing packet ping-pong with pata with
with traffic to move it in and out of
virtual machines and virtual switches to
actually allow and enable it to be
inspected or enforce is a huge issue and
this really brings back the issue for
most people of control when they think
about how they're going to interact with
legacy data or even private cloud to
public cloud interaction is the revenge
of the the the mesh overlay VPN
essentially what you see now is this
really really high level need for a
bunch of the return of pki to manage
certificates and point-to-multipoint a
multi point-to-multipoint dpns such that
you can essentially connect resources
and public cloud to those in private
cloud and/or thora business partners
securely you know what that brings up is
the need for both physical and logical
link encryption and the end
authentication tagging and understanding
that once all that stuff is encrypted
the network provider itself can't see
what what's in that traffic which is
both good and bad so if we follow this
along a little bit more what this gets
into is the argument between kind of big
dumb flat layer two networks on one end
the extreme of the spectrum and the need
for kind of taking that next step set of
evolution for the classical core
distribution access aggregation layer
sets of of networking and so what that
means is you know what in many cases
these large public cloud providers want
are heavily virtualized incredibly
highly dense very very low latency
non-blocking line rate 10 plus gig
connectivity so we're just getting to 10
gig most of us in the enterprise these
guys are looking at 40 100 gig pipes
with multi terabit switching fabrics
they control most of that stuff in
software right with a network they want
these big gigantic
flat fee lands well these gems are a big
gigantic fact lands not even vlans I
don't know about you but I remember when
we used to have giant big flat lands and
the problems both from a security and
performance perspective that that
brought so that introduces some
interesting challenges not the least of
which is this notion of full bisection
bandwidth versus massively
oversubscribed ports and what that means
is essentially that every port has the
ability to transmit at line rate without
jumping and stepping on another which is
very very important high-performing
compute environments because latency
kills when you're moving huge chunks of
data petabytes so what these guys look
for are these gigantic switching fabrics
right but that introduces issues for an
enterprise you in another cloud provider
who may not need that amount of of
connectivity at latency issues that are
an issue when they want to introduce
things like segmentation how I deal with
multi-tenancy in scale how do I deal
with things like when a lot of that
networking is extracted in the
hypervisor do I use private or do i use
VLANs private vlans don't even have a
concept of what that means how do I
separate maybe I separate control and
data planes which is a lot of what you
see in the open for example open flow
switch very interesting stuff where you
can use kind of an interaction of hybrid
physical and virtual networking so that
really brings up this issue of
programmable versus open and fixed
versus proprietary networking stacks
which has a huge implication of what we
do from a security perspective it also
brings up the issue and what we see both
in the enterprise and certain cloud
providers of this kind of classical data
only networking versus converging 10 you
know networking and data over 10 gig
pipes on the same physical interface
using things like data center ethernet
fiber channel over ethernet so you can
actually carry storage data sand traffic
and networking data on the same physical
pipe so if that essentially is now a
single pipe and most of our security
products like firewalls have no
knowledge or concept of what storage
looks like in that regard how do we
actually deal with injecting
compensating controls we've been
monitoring the providing visibility in
those environments and again everything
ends up being exposed via these
interfaces for automated provisioning
orchestration governance AP is these are
things were generally not used to being
able to secure right we can't just dump
a firewall in front of this thing and
expect us to do add any value to this
equation so when you think about what
this means to us we we have looked at
what virtualization is done
enterprise and what it's really brought
us is the fact that today practically
today the virtual machine boundary is
the new atomic unit of data center right
so it's really the logical perimeter
that we talk about today today for now
and what that means is ultimately you're
going to see the evolution of a new
definition of the perimeter but it's not
it's going to use different language
especially as
infrastructure-as-a-service bubbles up
the platform as a service so for example
Heroku doesn't talk about virtual
machines they provide Ruby on Rails
capabilities hosted on top of Amazon
they talk about slugs and dinos anybody
know what a slug or a dino is most you
probably haven't heard of that but these
are new terms that denote workload an
application and data content and most of
us have no idea what that means from the
perspective of security except for what
we can gain from a programmatic
perspective so the cloud operating
system platform networking in this but
in this particular instance has an awful
lot to do when we think about where and
how these vm boundaries exist in terms
of ability to enforce policy so it
depends determines on whether or not you
get good enough or best debris
capability it drives variability and how
what if or where you can even deploy
compensating controls and you have a
choice now right which is great but you
have a choice between much of the
hamster security sign of a pain whether
you deploy stuff at the physical virtual
network or appliances hypervisor or
hypervisor API enabled capabilities
whatever is exposed by the cloud
provider or in guest based software so
you know it's great to have choices but
in many cases we don't have we don't
have a lot of capability from the
perspective of what's available to us
from a control perspective that is
available to us today that actually
handles the scale flexibility and
agility that the cloud platform itself
derives right so we're kind of the mercy
of what a cloud provider gives us unless
we want to continue to deal with this
scale issue of deploying stuff and the
guest so when we think of storage again
we talked about moving from local disks
to San and as an object-based storage
has actually exposed via API so you
don't have logical file system units you
don't have disks you know you don't have
lungs what you have is an API you right
to to store data that's kind of weird
like how do i secure that how don't even
know what's being used for by the way it
can be persistent or non-persistent
which means on reboot it can go away or
it can remain
depends on the service level chosen
which is very interesting too for
forensics but also for how I protect
stuff that could essentially reboot and
disappear momentarily volume bucket and
file size limits are different than they
are in traditional storage we have
converged storage and networking I own
performance becomes an issue when we try
to add security to it it impacts
tremendously how we think about
application architecture the notion that
mobility of storage itself like you got
vm moving around but the file systems or
the storage that actually holds the data
that these things boot from it interacts
with also has to move sometimes across
data centers so bcp disaster recovery
resilience is very important and
ultimately and clearly isolation and
security things like forensics in multi
tell environments are huge like how do
you do a memory dump on a machine that
has 384 gigs of physical memory that's
segmented over I don't know 15,000
clients and make sense of what that
means to you if you're doing forensics
investigation on a particular VM and one
particular spot that that could move
very very interesting challenges from
particulars from the protective storage
so then we have we kind of go up the
stack to metastructure from
infrastructure we start talking about
protocols and van Jacobsen gave this
really fantastic talks about an hour and
a half long you can watch it on google
videos at this Earl down below he was
talking about kind of the evolution of
the Internet and I paired it well I got
a paraphrase it for cloud but basically
he said you know the cloud or in this
particular case of the evolution
networking was talking about it is
really like where ARPANET was yesterday
and this code he used was at the outset
the new network looked like an
inefficient way to use the old network
that's kind of where we are with cloud
today right we are we're looking at what
cloud offers and we say well that
doesn't make sense based on what we know
of networking and security today he said
you know what's interesting when it was
created tcp/ip was not made for
ubiquitous any to any communication at
that point there were a couple of these
giant machines sitting in these glass
rooms with a couple of users with a
little bit amount of data information
that would talk to each other right so
what was what was interesting was when
you look at that model where TCP has
evolved um the things ultimately that
people were doing with for example even
the telco environments making phone
calls was actually a side effect of what
was done inside the network so when we
think about cloud to what cloud does
inside the mechanical pieces of what it
is able to offer that
use cases are actually the side effect
of that based on how you actually design
the stacks and what they're optimized
for so communications today as van
Jacobson said are really disseminate Ori
you basically say Marco and somebody and
a whole bunch of people can say polo you
make one request it's very asymmetric
you make one tiny HTTP request and you
get petabytes of information back if you
want it right so it's really about
disseminate or e verses conversational
so the notion of locating where stuff is
naming location and trust models are a
huge issue so when you get down to the
end of it today's networking protocol
problems that we have at the
metastructure layer like DNS like BGP
like all these things we see you know
coming back in style that are being
attacked today and the fixes we're
putting in place like DNS SEC has
convinced he's been talking about it's
really not an architectural failing it's
really actually what van jake has been
called a success disaster right the side
effects of what tcp/ip I what tcp/ip
brought and the innovation that people
use to leverage it really is is is a
success disaster and we're dealing with
what that means because the
infrastructure again it was never built
to do that doesn't get doesn't give us
very quickly the ability to to handle or
secure it so what's interesting is we
kind of bubble up the stack and we think
about infrastructure this is this is the
very interesting and fascinating part
here where architectural you're a
classical interior design and
segmentation and asset grouping
methodology they used to use may no
longer apply based on how the networking
and platform of the cloud provider
functions you mean that may not make it
any sense whatsoever right there may be
kind of a shadowing a notion of how I
divide assets into logical groups but
they don't look anything like DMZ s
today especially if we think of that vm
boundary that I talked about
applications are likely not composable
this way anymore because they really
talk about being very distributed as
that shifts in architecture talk talked
about and they're becoming much much
more topologically and infrastructure
and sensitive than ever before right
they want big giant flat layer to
networks in many cases you have to
completely rewrite your applications to
make use of the platform in public cloud
and the security models have to change
then and what I and so ultimately when
you look at this and you think of
abstracted dumb networks in many cases
dumb networks equals dumber
security from the perspective of
visibility or at least from at least it
gives us less options in many cases and
to stuff catches up so workload
sensitivity or the network being aware
the network in the sum of all its parts
being aware of what is running over it
is really really important so people
still write crappy code so no matter how
good or abstracted ultimately the
infrastructure is that's still a problem
and if you look at the fact that people
continue to now adopt this notion of
DevOps or agile code deployment constant
deployment methodologies people are
pushing code constantly so how you going
to secure something with no known state
that ultimately is not persistent that
doesn't survive a reboot that could
change every 10 minutes right how do I
security models adjust and so when we
think of things this is out of an AWS
design presentation which talked about
the fact that we have a lot of
decoupling here like if the top level
with controllers or in this case
function programmatically you know they
used to be where one would call another
one on call another well now we have
this separated now we have essentially
controllers talking to cues and message
buses which if you've done anything in
enterprise architecture and software so
architected you may be familiar with but
most of us don't think of this way we're
used to essentially deploying a kind of
this notion of firewalls in between
these classical tears and everything's
going to be okay well ultimately now not
only do I have to control the the VMS
the processes the controllers I have to
deal with securing the cue and the
messaging that's used in between them
which is not a new concept but the point
here in arguing is that the the
fundamentally the solutions aren't
flawed but the problem has radically
changed right I made that point of in
surf and he literally kicked me in the
ass so the arm the notion here when we
think about security models from an
infrastructure service perspective and
we look at where the line is drawn in
terms of responsibility of who does what
the lower down the stack you go the more
responsible you still are so if you look
at infrastructure as a service right
everything above that orange line is you
you still have to do all of that
regardless of the fact that you're out
sourced or you are giving somebody else
control over the infrastructure platform
as a service essentially moves the line
up a little bit more software as a
service even more so so when we think
about this stack and we think about this
portion the left since we're talking
about infrastructure as a service all of
that security capability analogy is all
you
and when you think about the fact that
the VMS and especially the operating
system and applications are radically
changing that kind of presents a
challenge so when we think about this
there's not a whole lot you can do there
at the infrastructure layer so if we
focus here what this really means is if
I have to secure the VMS or my
containers the OS and applications in my
data it really falls upon these three
fundamental premises of what we're here
to talk about building survivable
systems that sustained attack regardless
of what the provider themselves do
building secure applications and
securing your data oh what a shocker
right the reality is these are things
that we still do regardless of the
deployment methodology so when we think
about these these three things and we
move up the stack to talk about what
survivable systems are you know it
really it really means in many cases
that if you continue to build based on
what you think are relevant design
patterns and in the enterprise you are
certainly going to be as I say kind of
if your security sucks now you'll be
pleasantly surprised by the lack of
change when you move to cloud right and
that's kind of the message uh when you
look at that same presentation I
reference before architecting for the
cloud here's the recommendations for
amazon right designs or failure
basically what this means is cloud isn't
unreliable but the mechanisms that make
up the pieces of cloud independently may
be unreliable and any piece of them can
do and will fail at any time so designed
for failure I don't know about you I
don't get paid to design for failure I
get way to protect based on maximum
uptime and that's kind of a disconnect
we talked about decoupling all pieces of
enterprise architecture think about
elasticity think about the security
models break constraints both
programmatically policy from a from the
perspective of how we actually think
about design think in parallel think
about different storage options so this
is advice in terms of public
infrastructure to cloud that's really
targeted towards system administrators
and developers the security model
elements we'll get to in a min in a
minute but when we talk about designed
for failure it means that your backup
and restore strategy has to radically
change that your applications and your
infrastructure has to be impervious to
reboot or relaunch that you have to
think about the fact that you have to
move in memory state of applications in
data to data stores again storage for
persistence you you should think about
as we always should use
multiple availability zones and regions
for high-availability using software
driven load balancers or hardware
depending upon the cloud provider using
relational database services that exist
to essentially enable the use of elastic
infrastructure in a data or database
environment and then using this notion
of elastic IP where the IP address is no
longer the static constraint of where
something lives or operates so in this
particular case you may find that you
are leveraging provider specific
attributes to get to get stuff done even
if you re architect all the stuff which
may be fantastic if you plan to single
source to provider to a single provider
no matter how resilient they are if you
want you know Federation if you want
interoperability and portability from a
security perspective what may work in
one provider may not work in another and
this is an issue with where the the the
arguments about the need for standards
come up or at least a standardized way
of explaining or expressing what it is
we need so i found this kind of this
this this set of advice very interesting
i further found that last year at source
Alex demos from ISEC have a great
presentation about securely moving your
enterprise to the cloud and his
presentation was really good what was
interesting was he basically said what
was kind of reiterating what was there
in Amazon I said look you current
thoughts about about cloud computing and
security and cloud computing is missing
the point that you cannot securely move
into the cloud without rewriting your
software and he's talking about public
cloud that secure cloud applications
really talk about collapsing the
perimeter kind of like that VM model I
talked about and that ultimately by the
time you go through this whole process
if you do it successfully you should be
quote unquote more secure well I looked
at these points and he went through a
whole series of illustrations and what
that really meant is for him summarized
in these points that you should from a
networking from a software architecture
perspective go completely flat that you
should collapse the perimeter use
external or even internally offer glue
services that allow you to dispatch and
separate infrastructure from
applications and use message queuing and
use a shitload of crypto now this is
interesting and good except and it
sounds easy enough but there's a big
difference between greenfield
applications and the legacy apps and
crap and bloatware that we have to deal
with in an enterprise right i don't have
the source code i can't rewrite exchange
i have
option right I can't rewrite a number of
legacy applications I'm able to move
them they not be efficient but then I if
I if I can't leverage the elasticity the
benefits of cloud it ultimately I end up
hitting roadblocks that are
unintentional and not the providers
fault it's the application architecture
issues that start to preclude me from
being able to do it so because the
software architecture changes
dramatically ah but the security models
themselves do not we have a real real
big problem and we haven't learned from
what we started to go down the path or
service oriented architecture where
things like XML security gateways and a
whole bunch of other technology started
rear its head but programmatically we
didn't have the delivery models to
actually make use of much of them so as
we move greenfield apps which are new
applications that are written
specifically for cloud that's one thing
as we move those at the same point in
time we're really forced to think about
really changing how we build survivable
systems because we can't depend on the
provider the provider does not care
what's in your workload it's not that
they don't care I say that wrong all the
time that the provider in many cases
doesn't have the visibility and their
service is not dependent upon knowing
what it is you do they're very single
function they provide you a maximally
available platform to allow you to
manage and deploy your virtual machines
what you transit the data you transit
with or transit in the applications the
operating systems are for the most part
of relevant to them so if you can't
depend on them you've got to focus on
the things that matter most right
surprisingly enough securing the VMS the
apps and the data so when we think about
this what this means practically is that
you have to assume all of the
environment every piece of the
environment including the infrastructure
you're operating on is hostile you
cannot rely on that right most of us
think that way but if in the enterprise
we kind of had this implicit thing of
trust well we're also the single tenant
in those environments when I move to an
environment that has coke and pepsi or
my biggest competitor or somebody who
was out to get me that doesn't
necessarily scale the same way you have
to think that this isolation and memory
in terms of tenancy will ultimately fail
that ultimately whatever is providing
the isolation will break and if it
breaks what does that mean to your
application and data means focusing on
GOC ustin of operating system not the
bloatware rings trimming this stuff down
and making incredibly more hardened than
we even do it in enterprise today
especially we compose these differential
service levels
it means investing heavily in what I
call entity management not just human
the machine but machine the machine
authentication with a lot of crypto it
means ensuring robust instrumentation
and telemetry at all levels of the
infrastructure it means choosing open
protocols and stacks so you know how
they function you have transparency in
visibility and you have options it means
leveraging introspection so you can
actually see what's going on it means
selecting platforms that enable robust
monitoring okay and in many cases that
monitoring is on you because you don't
get it from the provider it means
utilizing what is called the 3 R's and
the 3 R's are some of you may not have
heard of before but it's it's a design
philosophy that goes back quite a ways
it stands for resistance recognition and
recovery and it's the kind of the
premises survivable systems and what it
really talks about is that you know
again I'm going to deliver my essential
services even under degraded performance
in the face of attack it talked about
resistance the capability to repel
attack it talked about recognition which
is the ability to detect attack and
essentially evaluate the extensive
damage and communicate through secure
data planes the fact that this stuff is
happening at all tiers it means
ultimately that we have to recover that
not only am I going to be able to serve
what I serve the most critical part of
my operations in my mission but
ultimately that I can limit the extent
of further damage right we don't think
of these terms right these these seem
like abstract bizarre military jargon
that has no place in our lives because
we don't have the technology we're not
organized this way the reality is cloud
makes you absolutely function this way
if you are not looking at your
architecture in this way you were going
it's going to be painful all right so
when we kind of look at what this means
we've kind of gone from the
infrastructure side of the world would
looked at kind of protocols we've looked
at the underpinnings we looked at what
kind of survivability means at a high
level what's very interesting is is is
this return or this notion of
information centricity in the middle of
the hamster sine wave of pain and what
this really means is this kind of the
center of the universe needs to return
back to the thing that matters most of
us anyway which is the information and I
know this sounds like common sense and
preaching but the reality is we never
get an opportunity to do this right
cloud is that opportunity and I implore
you to kind of understand what why and
how this how this can actually be a very
good thing for us so the Jericho forum
almost
the same time that that the folks at
carnegie mellon started talking about
their design philosophies came up with
their 10 commandments I'm going to
highlight them really quickly says
fundamentally the scope and level of
protection be specific and appropriate
to the asset at risk security mechanisms
must be pervasive simple scalable and
easy to manage you should assume context
at your peril meaning what works in one
location may not work in another
ultimately devices and applications have
to communicate using open secure
protocols all devices maybe must be
capable of maintaining security policy
on untrusted Network right these were
written before cloud came into play but
really was talking about how security
has to has to evolve the rest of them
all people processing technologies must
essentially have a desire to transparent
levels of trust mutual trust assurance
has to be determinable meaning I have to
be able to understand what are these
your requirements are authentication
authorization accountability must
operate outside of your local your locus
of trust and control which means I have
to be able to establish trust access to
data should be controlled by security
attributes of the data itself it must be
self-describing and ultimately the data
privacy and security requires
segregation of duties and privileges by
default data must be appropriately
secured when stored in transit and in
use and ultimately this notion of what
they call depolarization i think it was
reprimanding has been in play for years
port 80 and 443 a perfect illustration
right we have no real perimeters anymore
so these ten commandments have been
around since I think this was like 2005
right when these things are first
written and they make more sense than
ever and when we think about these these
requirements it's up to you to
essentially go lay smack down on vendors
to support and build products that solve
these problems instead of bringing out
you know necessarily you know that the
shiniest newest greatest speeds and
feeds of a product that isn't actually
going to solve your long-term problems
so so if you if you summarize this
information and data must be
self-describing and ultimately allow it
to be self defending the Commission
Impossible theme right this miss message
will self-destruct in 30 seconds whether
that data is structured or unstructured
the policies and controls must account
for business context which means we
don't have to secure everything we did
you secure the stuff that matters most
information has to be protected as it
moves between silos and in and out of
these control perspectives and the
policies have to work
instantly throughout various locations
and what that means is without in
operability and portability in many
cases we're not going to be able to move
that that ball forward so not only you
have to press your security vendors you
have to press your cloud providers to
look at being able to describe and adopt
standards that are open that allow you
to get solutions for which the the
vendors third-party vendors can
interoperate because it does no good to
essentially say that a single source
stack provider that can do all of this
themselves is the only game in town
where what you actually need is the
ability to move your data and content
across multiple providers so again this
comes down to threat modeling and risk
assessment it it's you know it's not
information alchemy it's not rocket
science it's just a lot of crappy hard
work there's a lot of models you can use
Carnegie Mellon's octave are in lies
fair Microsoft's tried dread model for
threat modeling this stuff is out there
if you're not doing it already then when
you basically raise your hand saying we
can't move to cloud that's a problem
because you actually have no way of
assessing or communicating why so you
know the six key questions here are the
ones you should be asking anyway for
most assets you know how what happens if
I get exposed what what does it mean to
my business what happens if could we be
harmed if an employee of our cloud
provider access the data when we be
harmed at the process or function was
manipulated etcetera etc you know how do
we deal with availability and resiliency
issues and and the problem is in rich
mogan like I talk about this all the
time and I borrowed his his information
lifecycle model which talks about you
know across the entire information
lifecycle from creation to storage to
use to sharing to archival and
ultimately destruction this is a huge
problem for us we still have no real
good tools or the Apple we haven't had
for a while usable tools that allow us
across this entire lifespan to
essentially be able to enforce policy
across the data I mean you know there
now we're getting applications at the
time you create data at least structured
data you're able you have to input
metadata before you can save it which
allows you to potentially start getting
a leverage point in some of this but I
added discovery because trying to find
this stuff these are the hamster sine
wave of pain is a real problem you need
every single one of these controls to
essentially affect information-centric
solutions especially in the environment
for example
you don't own but in many cases these
capabilities are not present in those
systems so it's like what do you do we
have technology today that enable you
for example if you wanted to start
rolling your own you could do and you
could use the problem is their nascent
they cost a lot of money and all of the
agility cost flexibility and issues that
you get when people read page 1 of the
New York Times that say you're going to
say billions of dollars by moving to
cloud you have to explain why you have
to go buy it by the equal amount of
dollars to invest in new technology to
secure the stuff in the first place that
being said there's labeling technology
that based on metadata both in use in
flight and an at rest can use labels to
identify via metadata what data there is
and ultimately how it should be
protected that's available today you
have technologies that you know got
laughed at a couple of years ago they've
been around for a while they're starting
to mature like data leakage data loss
prevention products that are starting to
make their way in the cloud based
platforms both at the guest and the
network level depending upon your cloud
provider so dlp is a component you have
a wholly unpopular term and drm but for
an enterprise when you start thinking
about digital rights management and how
you it basically tell something that
this this piece of data can be consumed
for this period of time with these
particular control requirements ed RM is
is there are platforms operating systems
and applications that allow you to do
that you also have a you know huge huge
dependency on encryption today so when
you use most public cloud providers they
provide you for example storage
capability if you wish for that data to
be encrypted that's on you you have to
do that you have to engineer it which
means issues that come back to the
revenge of pki so if you haven't been
going down the path of understanding how
digital certificates and encryption are
going to function outside of a normal
VPN that's going to bite you but this
technology of course encryption has been
around for a long time but as it relates
to things like row and column based
encryption in databases and applications
and peering between various tiers in
these distributed application
environments encryption is a huge piece
of this right now we also have things
like then we have to deal with this
notion of entity management and mapping
that role based and claims based usage
capability against an identity or even a
machine to machine
interaction so identity access
management you know we have thousands of
tools at our disposal but again they're
not consistent you have to roll your own
and then new things like tokenization so
in for example PCI this is a hot topic
recently about substituting instead of
the real data instead storing actual
credit card data you're storing kind of
tokens that represent that data so
you're not at risk right you're
essentially of exposure of the actual
raw data you've got issues like data
dispersion so being able to chop up data
streams both in storage and in-flight on
the network chop them up into individual
packets encrypt them and then
essentially make M of n number of
packets reassembly reassemble based on
using encryption so data dispersion is
interesting because if you need to do
things for bc PDR or you need to make it
use of essentially of taking sets of
network and or storage data and
splitting them up so that they can't be
accessed inappropriately but then being
able to recombine them at at on demand
data dispersion capabilities are very
interesting mixes in the pools of
streams of storage or data but you can't
essentially extract those sorts of those
things holistically without being able
to reassemble the keys so stuff like
this are solutions in the information
centric perspective that that are
available to you today but again if you
look at this model you have to figure
out where you play and where those
solutions are deployed so if you don't
demand the solutions like that or at
least made available to you through
api's by your cloud provider it's going
to be real difficult for you to
implement because what that means is
you're gonna have to do it all on the
guest right which is incredibly costly
and that doesn't scale very well so
we're just take us we need contact
analysis fully integrated in both
productivity and what what rich call is
transaction applications as well as data
stores the rights have to be basically
sprayed across these stacks and the
things the VMS at a very at a very
minimum have to describe what they need
at the point of creation the interesting
i was listening to the general of this
keynote this notion of choke points
between kind of on-premise off premise
as well as application tears or at the
application VMS themselves need to
essentially enforce policies at the data
level not just at the vm level right we
have to become information-centric
enforced by encryption and drm the
rights transfer has to be
because I need somebody else to make
secondary reuse of that data and
maintain it between state changes you
should not expect for quite a while most
public cloud providers to do this for
you as I explained they're mostly blind
to your data or at least should be all
right that's what most people want so a
lot of it is on you which is which is
which is an issue so are we there yet
not quite like this is very much a Lego
blocks problem so in the last minute or
so as I wrap up here you know you're
already here cloud computing is already
happening we'll all your applications
move to cloud computing at public cloud
computing probably not at least not for
a long time which gives you the ability
internally if you start building and
leveraging private clouds to start
getting a hold on being able to deploy
technologies that work for you today so
we have to start thinking about
fundamental changes in architecture in
programmatic management and security
architectures that essentially wrap into
this we have to start thinking about
centers of data not data centers it's
kind of a funny little play on words but
it really means we have to build these
survivable systems and we have to start
working on requiring vendors and cloud
providers to give us visibility and
transparency back to this data the
policies have to travel with the data
and applications without that it's
useless ultimately we have to allow the
infrastructure to at least be made via
telemetry gain visibility and context
through standards-based telemetry
capabilities right and correlation so if
you think all the things like siem you
think about a log correlation you think
about telemetry monitoring and
management these are all things that are
just as consistently reasonable and
needed today so again the key takeaways
here when I kind of outlined the
distinction between different types
across the spectrum of cloud providers
they're not all created equal they're
not essentially all built for the same
reason for the same people and
differentiation is really starting to
crop up between being able to expose a
lot of what this networking and security
capability means public cloud providers
you can allow you to deploy applications
incredibly securely if you wish to
embrace requiring the need to profoundly
alter architectural security operational
and organizational changes right and
that's the hard part for most people to
get there
arms around and ultimately you need to
deal with technology and memes and
topics that we have for the last 15
years kind of been banging banging into
we're in a lot of the technology is
nascent it was you know again solutions
looking for a problem but ultimately we
have a lot of the key technologies
available to us you need to pressure
your vendors and pressure to providers
to start building them into products
right so to use a play on words it
really does take a village here it takes
the cooperation between two providers
there was a guy in the in back in the
kind of Russian history I think he was a
an ambassador of sort his name was
Potemkin and Catherine the Great wanted
to take a tour of her countryside
because she wanted to see how awesome
people thought of her so what they did
was essentially had the villagers
because there was about prosperity she
wanted to feel good about herself that
the villagers stand up fake entire fake
village fronts that basically gave the
illusion that everything was awesome I
thought everything was just perfect and
smiley and at this point that's kind of
where we are today with the cloud right
we look at these shiny awesome use cases
that don't talk about the things that
matter most to us and we don't have a
lot of the tools so ultimately do me a
favor if you want to learn more about
cloud and cloud security go to cloud
security alliance download the guidance
get a grasp on what's different what's
the same you can participate in cloud
security alliance as well as cloud audit
which is a project that I lead that's
bringing transparency and visibility
into cloud providers it gives you a lot
of this capability to understand how the
infrastructure that subtracted is
managed and and ultimately acted upon by
your providers so thanks very much for
for listening my contact info is here I
think the updated version is the one i
just presented will be on the DVD if not
it'll be at my blog and you can download
from there so i'm actually technically
out of time but i'll be available if you
have any questions comments i want to
hurl fruit at me later thanks very much