ok welcome this is the web app track
this is a Stefan s ur talking about
utilizing code reuse a return oriented
programming in PHP application exploits
ok hello welcome to utilizing code reuse
and return Orion programming in PHP
application x boys i will skip my
introduction so i just want to tell you
what the talks about today i want to
speak about something like return
oriented programming for PHP
applications so i want to take return
return oriented programming to the PHP
level this will be the first part of the
presentation and the second part of the
presentation will be i will demonstrate
a vulnerability and then PHP that can be
exploited with traditional return
oriented programming methods so during
the last day they were already several
presentations about return oriented
programming or return around programming
style topics so i just will give a short
introduction was returning the
programming is all about so the basic
idea of return oriented programming is
that you instead of injecting your
shellcode into an application you will
inject some kind of data that redirects
the applications code flow and your the
idea is to not inject code but to use
the already existing code and the
general idea is that when you have
pieces of already existing code in an
application you can rearrange them in a
way that there will be useful for your
attacker at least you hope so but when
the application is big enough you
usually will find something so in the
past people always analyze to return
oriented programming and culture your
topic on consumer architectures like x86
amd64 spark powerpc the ARM architecture
because of all the mobile devices and
when you saw the talk yesterday since an
amex guys are applying return oriented
programming today I reverse engineering
intermediate language which is called
rail and last year there was also paper
about people using return oriented
programming again selection of voting
system but so far there is no real
research on the turn oriented
programming or code reuse for PHP or web
applications so when you look at
co-produced techniques you can classify
them and usually cover uses like the
topic the the major team and when you
look at it return oriented programming
is just subset of code reuse techniques
techniques and when you look at this a
subset of return oriented programming is
returned to lipsy and on the other side
there's something most people don't
speak about but code reuse is usually
bigger so I put in the big question mark
for now so when you look at a return
oriented programming on the low-level
side of maybe x86 you see that all these
techniques returner and brimming and
return to lipsy based on the fact that
you somehow hijack the call stack of the
application and you usually try to
manipulate the call stack in a way that
the return instructions that are present
in the application will return to code
you wanted to execute and the code you
would usually execute is most of the
times some useful instructions for you
and then followed by the return and in
order to do this you need to full
control over the stack the example just
shows one of the possible stack frames
that it could be used to return around
programming in this case is some kind of
system call that is executed and yeah so
when you apply this technique directly
to PHP you will realize that that's not
possible in PHP
the reason for that is there's not a
single call stack that you could
overwrite the the PHP application called
stack is actually on three levels a part
of it is stored in the real stack and
the program stack a part of it is in in
allocated heap structures that is most
probably randomized on modern systems
and also the data segment contains
pointers that are used by the executed
x2 to change the execution so um a
traditional returner and programming
attack is not possible because you
usually can only override one piece of
memory but you cannot override three or
four at the same time especially if you
don't know the addresses so the other
thing is when you want to return to pge
by code for example PHP by code is
always allocated on the heap so it will
be in completely random positions on
modern linear systems so return aerial
priming seems impossible for PHP but if
you remember this picture there's a big
question mark on the side and we want to
fill those big question mark with a new
technique which I call property oriented
programming Charlie's pop so what is
property oriented programming the idea
is that instead of overwriting some call
stack or manipulating a call stack you
try to exchange the the objects used in
an application so normally when you have
objects they have properties and these
objects call other methods of other
objects stored in their properties and
now the idea is that I replace the
objects stored in the new properties and
so I can redirect the coleslaw this
graphic shows like the circles are just
random objects and you see one object is
calling the other in the method of
another object and so on and basically
if I can override the objects or the
properties of the objects and I can
choose which object is executed next the
only thing that's maybe static is which
method is called okay when you go down
to the x86 level this is not that easy
but this is just a general concept and
in Peach Pit words like this so just
believe me like I know so when you look
at peach speed the problem is this
technique has some limitations because
an x86 and returning to program
programming usually can jump anywhere in
the binary but in PHP you cannot jump
anywhere in the binary you can only jump
two starts of methods so this will
limitation and compare them to other
experts um the other thing is you
usually cannot just overwrite some
objects in memory because the objects in
memory are in random positions and yeah
so that's not another way to go normally
so what you need usually is a way to
create objects from remote and to fill
their properties and in PHP that's
usually done by the uncivilized function
I will go on that now so answer your
lies is a function of PHP that is used
to yeah deserialize previously
serialized data it supports nearly all
of peach pits data types the only data
type that's not support its resources
but all the normal things like integers
floating points bullion's arrays strings
objects and even references are can be
civilized and uncivilized and when you
look at PHP applications you will see
that they are often this expose this
function to user input and when you look
at the history of the function you see
that there are a lot of vulnerabilities
in the parlor in the answer lies padded
cell phonee in the history so what we
want to do is like create arbitrary
objects so the good singer of unser
Eliza's it allows us to create objects
and to fill all their properties the
problem you usually
when you have lots of vulnerabilities
that allows you to create an object this
that you can only overwrite the public
properties but was uncivilized you can
override each property the public the
private all protected ones but don't
mistake that for like a full uncivilized
of objects you can only answer lies in
instance of a class that already exists
so you cannot just inject a new or
method that here with with bytecode so
you cannot just inject code that gets
executed that's not possible however
whenever you answer eyes not check
Petrie will check if this object has a
wake up method in its class definition
if it has a wake up method it will
execute it and the other thing that's
new and php5 although php5 is already
old but um in PHP 5 the whole object
model was restructured and so now
objects have real destructors so the
thing is when you uncivilized an object
and you could literally destroy it the
destructor will be called in pitch
before nothing like this happened so
this means when you answer lies not
checked at existing an application there
are two possibilities where directly
code will be executed either it's a wake
up method all the destructor will be
executed as very strong so to show you
the internal working of ants your life I
have for a little example one thing
that's very important for the second
part of the presentation is on the right
side you see a variable table this is an
internal table of answer your lies that
keeps track of all the variables created
by the uncivilized powder during the
answer lies during the single call of
uncivilized and the idea of that is our
when you want to answer lies a reference
you need to know which variable you want
to reference to so what happens is that
answer lies creates a variable table
where every variable it creates is
inserted all right pointer to the
variables inserted and later when you
like creating reference to the third
slot then answer lies will look into the
variable table and
get the variable from there so this
example starts with an serializing in an
array this array is supposed to have six
elements and so you see PHP creates an
array with six elements learning
continues and creates all the content of
the array the first thing is the key is
a 0 and integer 0 and the value is an
integer 0 so it will insert it in the
first slot of the array and you see that
the variable table is already filling
with the array and appointed to the the
first entry and this continues to like a
floating point to burn through a string
ABCD and now we get a reference and now
it's a reference to the third slot so
PHP will go to the third slot and see oh
it's a pointer to the the floating point
to point zero so this will be reference
to the cook to 10 and the next element
should be like in any class i call it my
class in this time it could be any class
and you can see that this has two
properties a and B and PHP will now
continue to answer lies each property
which again will be a reference to the
class itself and a null value again you
see everytime variables created it's in
certain very good table and now we have
answer eyes the whole object and what
happens now is PHP will attempt to
execute the wake up if there's a wake up
it will be executed otherwise it will
just continue until lighting rest in
this case it will create an internal PHP
object of type SPL object storage we go
to this later and yeah after that it
will be finished okay that's how an
serialize works and already told you
that putting user input anuncios it's
maybe not a good idea so what actually
is required for an application to be
vulnerable so that we can do a property
or rental program
attacking and of course the most obvious
way that application can be vulnerable
to this is if it puts user input
directly into answer your lies but when
you look at PHP applications you will
see that uncivilized is used in very
many different places and not always its
user inputted put into interior lines
and when you look at all the different
types of verification vulnerabilities
you will see that there are other kind
of vulnerability classes that can be
leveraged to attack answer your lies so
I will go through each of the classes
now so the first ones what I repeated
several times now you just answer lies
user input directly why would you do
that PHP application developers are
usually lazy and it's the easiest way to
transfer bigger amounts of data between
for example the client in the server so
every time a PHP application and has to
transfer a whole array to decline and
back the PHP application developers to
choose a way to do that and
traditionally they were all lazy and
just used serialize and uncivilized so
they put the array to area to serialize
and just use a string for example for a
hidden form field and this is the most
most of the time you see uncivilized and
civilized content in hidden HTML form
fields or in the cookie actually this is
an example from tikiwiki and take a wiki
is even more nice it just not it just
uncivilized to request variables which
is a collection of pages that are
supposed to be printed and it will do
some modification of this data and later
the modified data is serialized again
and given back to you though this is a
very good for phone attack and then
you'll see later why so why do people do
that the reason for that is PHP code is
usually very old and they all learn
I mean peach be four days and in peach
before it was not so dangerous to use
uncivilized because there were no
destructors so there was no unintended
he called execution and wake up methods
were very very very seldom and you have
to program you're on your own so usually
no one used wake up so there was no
danger at all except for vulnerabilities
in the answer lies powder and we had a
lot of them in the past so the next
thing you would see in modern PHP
applications is that they always use
some kind of caching because they are
usually too slow so leakage a lot in
memory in the database or in files and
of course the files are still the most
often using to store big data arrays so
you will see that a lot of PHP
applications store serialized data in
files what does this mean this means
first of all when you when you the
application is able to store see release
data and files this means there must be
some directory on the web server that is
writable because otherwise it can cannot
be cashed it's not necessary that this
is inside the document root that can be
anywhere on the server maybe the temp
directory and subject of the temp
directly but there must be a single
directory that's why durable so this
also means when there's a fine up of
vulnerability in the application there
must be a single directory that's may be
writable for the file upload and
normally when you can like upload
something in a temporary directory yeah
and the a temporary directory is not
accessible that's usually not a problem
for an application so it's a file upload
vulnerability maybe but it's not ranked
so high in severity because you cannot
do anything with it but when you take
the casing files into considerations now
when you can run an upload and fire to
this temperature you can upload maybe a
case file that is used later and unser
so you can enter a tech unsterilized
again so the next part where you see
answer lies in seara is very often is
when you when you look at the web
application programming interface the
web appy many peach p style web
applications will provide civilized and
uncivilized way to maybe talk rest they
don't use jayden they use civilized
uncivilized the most popular application
like this is WordPress so when you have
a wordpress blog it will talk from time
to time with a pedo wordpress.org in PHP
serialized unsterilized form and the
problem here is it's talking HTTP so any
kind of HTTP men in the middle attack
can inject malicious serialized data
into your answer lies on your blog and
actually this example is really taken
from WordPress so you see it will send
some requests to the wordpress happy and
check if there's a new version of
plucking and then will unseal why's the
code and yeah and if work press would
have interesting objects this will be a
wrong remote code execution
vulnerability but luckily there is no
such object so only if you have a
vulnerability in a parcel you can maybe
attack wordpress the next thing where
you find uncivilized is with databases
and there are a lot of PHP applications
that store settings or sessions in a
serialized form in the database this
means if you have a SQL injection
vulnerability in PHP application you
maybe can modify the field that is
serialized with all our PHP applications
that was very tricky because you cannot
stack queries with my squirrel
in early pitch p versions but nowadays
especially all these sent framework
applications they use pto mysql to
access the medical database and PDL
mysql has no protection against tech
queries so when you have an application
with PDO mysql you can inject the usual
semicolon drop drop tables and this is
was not possible previously but now you
can do that with modern applications and
so you can modify all the database okay
when you can modify all the database
maybe you can do other interesting
things but you can still attack
uncivilized and actually I didn't audit
for our sister company mayflower who
develops pH project I did this in
February a sink and they had on they
have unsterilized of database and
content and they're also had a SQL
injection so I was able to answer lies
something and execute arbitrary code the
last thing I want to get into is a
vulnerability I disclosed during the
month of peach peace security and may it
was actually the last one on the last
day and the thing is that there is a
problem in the session deserializer and
the problem is whenever a session key
starts with the ! this deserializer gets
confused and so if you answer have an
application that allows you to put
arbitrary keys into a session or two to
have a prefix arbiter prefix for session
variables which sometimes happens you
see some examples down there when
something like this exists in your
application then you can more or less in
inject ! keys with arbitrary values and
now the problem is when this gets
deserialized during the session load it
will confuse the deserializer and
you can inject arbitrary serialized data
into this session okay if if the
application allows to put anything in
the session then you can put anything in
but these are always strings but due to
this vulnerability you can put anything
serialize in there so you can attack
uncivilized or you can just create our
rhetoric objects anyway in the
intersection may be a valid user object
normally you can just inject a string
but with this vulnerability you can
inject an arbitrary user object if your
application has something like that so
these were the vulnerability classes
that could allow a text against answer
your eyes but to do property oriented
programming you need more you need first
of all you need this deserialising of
malicious input but you also need
classes that are usable for your pot
change your property oriented
programming chain and a class is usable
for the pub chain if it's can start the
pop chain okay first of all the class
must be available and you're in the
application and at the time of the
anterior uncivilized then you need
something to start the pop chain you
need something to transfer the control
from one object to the other and in the
end you need some object with
interesting operations are we go on this
later so first of all class availability
when an application uncie or something
and it creates objects then you can only
create the objects that PHP knows about
at this moment so this means if you
answer lies an object called X a b c d
then peach p will check if this object
is available in this class is available
and if it's not available as will create
a so-called incomplete class which is
nothing more like a dummy object with
properties so this is not usable so
basically this means you can only use
classes for your attack that are already
included at the moment of the answer
lies this limits very much the amount of
classes you can use for the attack on
the other hand modern PHP applications
after possibility to reduce the so
called auto load function which is the
class autoloader so in the case peach P
doesn't find the object it will first
call the autoloader and the autoloader
can check if it snows the class or knows
how to load the class or create the
class so a modern application you
sometimes are able to instance every
single object of the application because
the autoloader we'll just load the right
object the right time so I already said
you are really limited in how your pop
chain will look like and what method you
can use so the problem in peach PS you
have to find a way to start the chain at
all so and this means your unsterilized
must somehow or the code afterwards must
somehow trigger execution of the objects
you you just created and I already
mentioned there is wake up and there's
distract the most obvious ways to start
a pop chain but there are some other
magic methods in PHP that might allow
you to startup option also this is a
two-string so every time you have an
object and gets concatenated to a string
it will call the two string so maybe
you'll find a usable two string method
when method is called an object and the
method is not known then it will try to
find the call magic method if it exists
and it will execute that and get in said
are for magic properties so that getter
and setter in real world so far i only
started pop change with wake up and
destruct so the others i'm theoretically
possible but so far I haven't found
application that is vulnerable to this
and the example just shows you have a
class i call it pop starter and it has a
destructor so when you answer like this
cars and if we get destroyed the
distract will be executed in this case
there's nothing in there so nothing
would be able so the next thing you
always need in in a pub chain is a way
to transfer control from wrong object to
another to the method of another because
you usually will not find the destructor
that does something very interesting for
you and the past you could find these
structures they were deleting files so
you could delete a file immediately or
you find something that writes a log
file so you could write a fire to the
disk but most of the time the destructor
will do nothing else then call like
another method of another object so you
need a way to transfer the control from
one object to the other the most obvious
thing is that you have a property that
gets dereferenced and the method of
these are these new objects is executed
you see this an example the property to
is used as object and the method b is
executed on the property on the other
object another way would be that
property 3 is also not checked and the
data property is assigned from value so
you maybe can hit a magic setter and
another object and the third thing is
a property is appended to a string so
you could hit an two string method of
another object so this always transfers
execution from one object to any other
and usually want to chain many of them
until you reach a method that is usual
for you and this all six the end of pop
chains are usually classes with
interesting methods this means an
interesting operation is a you can see
this file access database access access
to this session to access to the mail
function sometimes you even get the
execution of PHP code or inclusion of
PHP code and in this example this would
allow this would allow to load an
arbitrary file in memory mail it to any
email address and in the end attempt to
delete the file so if you find this
somewhere in the application you can
completely control what it does because
you have control of all the properties
and all the properties are required to
do what you want so you can choose any
file because you can set the temp file
property you can choose the two of the
email the subject of the email and yeah
most of the x files you want to steal
are not writable anyway so the unlink
will just arrow and you see this is
implemented in the method B so you would
have to combine it with the previously
found code flow transfer object that
called and that called the method B of
property to and because you also have
control about property to you can just
tell property to to be an object of type
operation so to make this more clear I
will give an example the example is P
week
p wig is a very popular open source user
tracking system it's supposed to be very
similar to Google Analytics and I don't
know about America but in Germany it's
used in many many many many places and
all the major German political parties
have installed on their website all the
smaller banks have it installed on their
website because all the smaller banks
are powered by two companies and these
two companies both use pedic so this
renders all the bank's vulnerable and
you will find ironically security
companies that use P big like the German
safer shopping which is supposed to be a
certificate for shops to be secure which
usually is not they are not and also
many popular open source projects have
it on their website for example to pour
dry which is the yeah at least in
Germany the most prominent content
management system and in the past KDE
dot org and so on they all had P big and
a vulnerability that was unsure lysing
user input and especially the cookie and
a lot remote code execution was
disclosed by me and december two
thousand mine and now we will look at
this vulnerability and the first thing
is when you look at it now seven months
later you will maybe thing always old
news is fixed but the problem here is
PHP developers always know think better
so my recommendation to remove the
answer lies was ignored to how to fix it
and so what I did is they used to answer
lies still and just put in a blacklist
and we all know that black lists are the
most effective way to ensure security
and after looking at it again and again
and looking at the uncivilized powder in
detail it was very obvious that the
blacklist is ineffective
so I I won't tell you how it works it
correctly but if you prepare the ante
ala the civilized string in a special
way you can bypass all the blacklists
this means the vulnerability I disclosed
seven months ago is still exploitable
and it's not yet fixed so I will not
give you the decides how to manipulate
but if you can read source code and can
compare patters to blacklist you maybe
find out how to exploit it so when you
want to exploit pivot and you need as
always a start of a pop chain so what
you do is you take the source code take
your favorite text editor or ide and you
would such search for wake up and
destroyed I really do that with pubic
you'll see that there are eight classes
from the sent from work because P
becomes with a small subset of the zend
framework eight classes of the same
framework come with wake up 11 classes
can with distract and 11 classes from
the pivot core classes also come with
destruct so what you would do now is you
would go through all the classes and
check the the method in detail and so
check what they do I can tell you with
the wake up's you will most of the time
will see that they're either empty and
setting some properties calling their
parents wake up or doing something else
that is not so interesting so we can
just keep wake up most of the time the
destructors on the other hand do more
complex things but the singers I will
only go into the center in book one this
time in December I show that the P big
core comes with a config object and this
context object can directly be used to
write arbitrary files to the hard disk
but i will use the other the more
complicated way no so i did a lot of
research in San framework last year so I
already know which of the classes are
usable for pop chains so I will just
tell you which one my most from
primum the most usable one is a scent
lok you see the destructor is not doing
very much the destructor just go through
all the writers properties and for each
writer property it will call the shuttle
method so no interesting operation just
transfer from of control from one object
to the other of course because you unser
like this you have full control of the
writers so you can put any object in
there that you want for the next thing
you want to do is you need to scan the
source code again for something that has
a shutdown method luckily this time you
only have 6 hits in inside the same
framework and only one of them is
interesting yes I just ya doing
completely useless things like closing a
file that was not open previously or
delete some property so the only
interesting one is the scent log writer
mail and this is actually a very
complicated method all it does is it
basically checks if it has events to
mail and if it has invents to mail then
it will ya call the mail class usually
and create the text section of the email
and later create the the HTML section of
the email and what you don't see after
that it will mail the mail so what you
can do here is actually you can spam
anyone with any text you want it's
utilizing and using this two classes I
just showed you if you just combine
these two classes you can send emails
but we want to have more you want to
have more control we want to have a code
execution so we continue so what we have
to do now is we have to find for each of
the properties that is usable which is
male and lay out in this case we have to
put in fitting objects for the male
property is very simple because there's
only the sent mail
they both fit so you just pull it in
there on the other end there's the
render method of the layout proper
property and the render method is in
many many many classes of pubic so in 14
classes of pubic score in six classes of
the HTML Peele library and in 21 classes
of the zend framework and even one pivot
plugin so you have up to log through a
lot a lot of classes and I don't want to
do that because we don't have the time
so I just tell you pubic viewers the
most interesting one p week view is
actually the render method is a large
piece of code and most of it is wrapped
in try catch blocks so actually you can
ignore nearly everything of this and
only the last line is very interesting
because it uses the property smarty and
calls the fetch method and you also see
that the parameter to the fetch method
it's the template property so you
control balls and obviously when it's
already called smarty than its supposed
to be a smart object and we go through
this now faster and it's really a smart
object you want to have in there because
when you know smarty you will know that
smarty allows you to have templates and
execute code and so on so when you look
at the fetch me that you will see that
it's a lot of cold and at some point it
will check if the resources already
compiled on its already mackage so it we
call the is compiled method and you see
down there it will call the fetch
response info and fetch resource info
will pass a resource name that you gave
it with your property and yeah and what
you see here is that the path resource
name we'll split the resource name you
give it and spread it into a resource
type and resource name and then for
every resource type that is defined
it's possible to define a call back then
it gets called on the on the name and
because we have complete control of the
properties of the sumantti object we can
just put in an arbitrary results we call
X pl4 exploit and you say that the
callback is this which is a smartie
class and the evil property method so
actually when it splits the resource
name and we'll take the X PL as type and
everything after that will be what it
will pass to this call back so we can
execute arbitrary PHP code and now you
just need to set this together and when
you see realize that you will get
something like this and then down below
and yeah when you uncivilized this from
within p week it will execute the PHP
info function in this case but by just
changing what kind of coat you want to
execute you can change it to whatever
you like you see in the pic view there
is a template a property and you just
say it's ex PL for the X PL resource you
just injected double point and then the
code you want to execute and you can put
anything you want in there so okay this
is pubic the problem is I told you like
there are some applications that
unsterilized user input like WordPress
but they don't have interesting object
so they have no distracters no way cups
and so you cannot exploit them with the
property oriented programming way you
need another way and what you need is a
winner Bertie and the answer lies father
itself and when I show you some use of
the free one ability in the SPL object
storage class of peach p and this
actually was zero day until like one
months ago and
one week ago it was fixed so it will not
work on the most neon on the new pitch
people but no one is using the latest
Petrie version anyway so the idea of the
back is that SPL objects objects stories
is the object map so you can put objects
into there and map some accelerator to
it so for example you can put 1 2 3 as
extra data for the Alpha object and you
put 54 56 for the better object as
accelerator but what you can also do is
put two different kinds of data for the
same object so this means you first put
in 1 2 3 and then 4 5 6 for the same
object what will happen is that SP
object storage will delete the old value
in this guy's one two three so why could
it be a problem a problem is because you
can also inject this inside uncivilized
so you can use uncivilized to to answer
your lies some SPL object storage thing
and use the same object as key two times
you can do that by using references or
because the actual type of the variable
was not checked in previous PHP version
you can choose the same integer to two
times what will happen is that in peach
p53 the extra data that was previously
at the same key will be deleted so this
is not a problem at all but the deletion
is done inside the SP object object
storage so uncivilized doesn't know
about it and uncivilized you remember
there was this variable table that's
used to reference us and so until eyes
it's still pointed to this variable that
was just freed so when you now until it
continues to answer your lies and use a
reference to the extra data that was
already freed it's
quickly possible because answer lies
doesn't know that this variable doesn't
exist anymore so you can put in
references to already deleted objects or
classes or whatever arrays or strings or
anything and now we'll show you how you
can use this for info leagues and code
execution first of all I remember you of
Tiki Wicki you can have code execution
if the application uncie arises but if
you want like a really good exploit you
need that the application until eyes it
modifies its see realises again and
gives it you're giving give us back to
you this worked in this case and take a
wiki this will also work in pubic or the
old version of pubic that is not
exploitable with property or in the
programming but through this back and it
should also be possible with up makes
the most prominent at software so we
will do league after three attacks um
the basic idea of league after three
taxes that you give the application some
serialized data it will uncivilized it
and the uncivilized ation will trigger
the exploit some back somehow and what
you want to do is you want to create
some variables in on serialize and then
free them so there are a lot of pointers
in the world table that point to non
existing variables and all these
variables are put to the memory cache
the free memory cache the next thing you
want to do in the uncivilized is to
create a string variable of the same
length as the internal data structure
used by PHP to keep track of variables
which is called set value and if you
create a string inside the answer lies
that looks like a fake said well it's
theoretically possible to use it and
because of the memory cage it will be
allocated in the same spot as the
previously freight variable and what you
cannot do now
is you can use the reference in Lance
your lies to create a reference to the
already freed variable and because
instead of the variable there's no your
string you have full control about the
the variable that is created inside of
PHP because you have you actually have
the you can change the binary
representation of the variable in memory
yeah so all the league after feel text
will work like this and in the end we
just read real civilized result back and
yeah so what we want to do first is we
want to leak arbitrary places in memory
and we can do that with them with the
kind of attack what we do is we create a
fake string variable inside PHP a string
variable inside PHP consists of a string
pointer followed by the string length
followed by a reference counter followed
by the bite 6 which says this is a
string and then followed by a bite of 0
which says this is not a copy on write
variable so what we have here is we have
told PHP that just obviously a string
variable in memory starting at B 734 21
18 which is a pointer 32-bit quarter and
our page people believe that if it sees
this variable and the reference to this
variable and when it modifies now the
uncivilized data and gives you the
serialized form back it will go to the
string and see oh yeah I have to take
the two 1024 bytes from this piece of
memory and give it back to him so to
actually achieve the the attack you just
have to send this little piece of cereal
I stator and what it does it first it
creates an array of integers then it
frees the the integers freecell race and
distress or the integers this means you
have a lot of free variables right now
and a lot of references
in the bar table that are pointing to
not allocated memory and now you put up
your fake set wall and because of the
memory cages will be allocated in the
same spot of one of the in previously
integer variables and when you then
create a reference to the right variable
to the right slot of the of the freight
variables then you suddenly have food
PHP that there's a string in memory at
the data you supplied and when you sent
this to Tiki Wicki ticket Ricky will
give you something civilized back and
this will look like this and you see
that there's a lot of garbage but
actually this is the memory content and
this I think that was the code segment
it was yeah it was a code segment of PHP
in this case and of course this is just
garbage usually get the real thing so
you have the real bites and you just
have leaked 1024 bytes of the memory the
problem here is of course when you do
when you put in this point on I just
showed you most probably your system
will crash because your PHP will not be
at the same place so you need a way to
start where to look for and this can be
done with a more complicated way again
you create a fake string but this time
you put in any pointer you want you
don't care in this case it's 41 41 41 41
and you will do more or less the same
attack it's not just a little bit more
complicated the idea now is you have
first to create an array of integers
just to allocate something to make the
memory cage empty then you again create
an array of integers that you free
immediately again so you have all these
empty spots in the variable table and
then you create an array that contains
your fake string and the empty object in
alternating sequence and then you freed
it again and this is very important you
freeze it again and then you create the
reference to two already free thing the
idea here is the moment you free the
fake integer the fake string the first
four bytes will be overwritten by the
memory cache with a pointer to the
previously freed memory so you have just
created the string variables into heap
because you have just let the memory
cage fill out the pointer that you
wanted for for your for you in an aside
from that the attack is the same when
you send this to Tiki Wicki you get
something back and this time you will
take this memory and scan for it you
will scan for object in there because
you had all the object in memory what
you will search for us like four times
zero followed by five followed by zero
because this is the the pattern that you
they will help you to find empty no
already freed objects because reference
count is 0 so and it's an object so when
you find this in memory you assume that
the four bytes before our pointer to the
object handlers and the object handlers
is a table usually in the data segment
especially for peach p internal object
is always in the PHP data segment and
yeah so I just going through the memory
just leaked you can find out where the
data segment of peach peers at least on
the the one struck that you are
interested we now and it's a previously
attack that allows you to to leak
anything you can just grab the memory at
this place read in the hunter table and
in the end the table you have a lot of
pointers in the code segment of PHP so
what you have now is you know where some
places of PHP I'm memory
the code segment in the data segment the
code the code segment is more
interesting because once you have the
code segment the pointer inside the code
segment of PHP you can just go backward
page by page until you hit the
executable header in case of Linux it
will be an e LF header and we're in
windows will build a portable executable
header but from now we concentrate on
Linux so it will be a kneeler fed up and
you can just read the header because you
can leak anything so you can leak all
these structures inside the LF header
and you can actually steal the whole
binary remotely you can just grab every
piece of the binary and get it through
tikiwiki on your own your server and of
course when you have a binary you can
look up all these symbols in memory you
can you know where which function of PHP
is and you can also go through other
modules for example PHP is linked to the
Apache modules so you can find the
Apache core and with the Apache core you
can find the other loaded Apache modules
for example mod ssl and from there you
can steal the private ssl key from
memory but you can also use this
information to create a code execution
exploit I will show you that now so the
ideas yeah the idea is to do the code
execution exploiters you first need to
know the location of the stack we have
steak is usually completely randomized
even more than all the other things so
it's really hard to find the stack but
you can already look up any symbol in
PHP so what you do is you look up the
executor Global's and the executor
executor Global's like I think its
biggest no second biggest struct inside
of PHP and one of these entries is to
jump off the jump off is the data used
by set jump and long jump and PHP uses
for a Malaysian of try-catch at the sea
level
and all you can do is you can find the
jump-off pointer and this jump of
pointer is stolen a stack so if you find
a jump-off point that you have an
address in the stack and of course from
there you can leak up and down as much
as you want okay until you hit like a
page that is not allocated the second
thing is you want to know to have
control of the stack because you want to
put some data structure on the stack
that you can use for your attack and PHP
is actually very simple to get control
of some piece of the stack because you
can send in a special type of post
request which is the RFC 1867 multi-part
form data which is used for file uploads
and when you do an upload like this the
plaza will use some stack buffers and
the stack ruffles are very big and
they're in a way on the stack that the
functions coming afterwards will not
completely over write them because the
function afterwards we'll also have big
stack Parker buffers so there is always
a big slot that is never over written so
if you can find it and put an arbitrary
data in there you have injected
arbitrary data to a known location on
the stack so what you do is you put in
like a post request with a special
layout and put in your pattern and then
you search just a pattern in your we are
the leaking and then you know the
address of this stack buffer and because
in PHP module it's all forked from
Apache in the non thread way and the
stick will always be in the same place
so all you do not how would you have
known as you have to you have a known
location on the stack that contains your
data and what you want to do now is you
want to create a fake object you saw how
we created fake string fake objects are
well that's the same and once you have
created a fake objects you want to
destroy it the reason for that is when
variable is destroyed that
call this set Baldy to a funk in the end
and in case of objects it will go to the
object handle table and uses the second
handler the dell ref handler and will
delete it when you look at the assembly
you will see that when this is called
the e SI ya es i read registers actually
pointing to your fake object and the eax
register is pointing to the handful
table so this is the table in stack that
you control so the idea of the exploit
is very simple you have an object
entered table which is actually your
data on the stack and the second entry
is your del ref handler and you will put
the dell revenge on to an exchange eax
asp followed by a red you can search
that by leaking the code segment of PHP
remotely so you can find it in memory
and because the handler table is pointed
to by eax the exchange x ESP will change
the stack pointer into your buffer and
from there you can just do the normal
return oriented programming so let's
will look like this you have a fake
variable in this case it's an object an
object is identified by the five not 26
x 25 you put in the reference count of
minus 1 so that it will be afraid you
put in the object handlers pointer will
be appointed to the stack location you
just leaked and controlled and the
object handle can be anything and what
you do now is actually you do the same
attack justjust time you don't put in a
string a fake string you use the same
code just to put in the object you just
replace a string and you can use the the
previously shown buffers for that so
what will happen now is at the end of
the lifetime of this data structure you
created with unsterilized this object
will be destroyed and the instructor we
go to the object handful table which is
your stack buffer and take the second
data entry and we'll call it you see
what we do is we just have an address
there that points to exchange eax ESP
and the rat so after the after the
exchange ESP the stack pointer will be
the firt pointing to the first slot of
your buffing so what you do there is you
put something more in there you want to
have a normal return rental programming
thing here so what you need to do now is
adjust the stack pointer and you just do
that by returning into a pop and rat
which is very easy to find because it's
all over the colon PHP and after that
you will actually return to the code
stored in the third slot to the to the
point of stolen asserts lot and what we
do is we will put in the address I'll
send evil string and this is just a
normal return to lipsy way to call a
function and the sender will string at
three parameters the first one is the
actual peach peacoat it's supposed to be
evaluated the second one is a null
pointer in this case but because it
should be the pointer pointing to the
return value but we don't need to return
value so you put in null and yet the
third one must be a pointer to reachable
memory and we just put in the same point
at the peach p.m. for string and again
this all is in the region of the stack
you completely know everything about you
know
the start address and the end of this so
you know where the PHP info string is
and this all only because you have put
it with the post data powder in the
right spot and the other thing is null
boys are no problem here because you can
also put another book no bites in the
opposed request yeah and for
completeness what you would do put in an
empty slot is the same payload function
so that when you return from the
executor PHP code you would end up and
send bailed anyway this would crash
because the address this is in a place
where I told you about the jump off the
jump off is a try-catch around all the
execution of PHP and Winston bear all
those curves called it reduces started
to jump off to to restore the indus tech
value and the problem here is that we
are in a way in a place of the stack
that's already above the jump off so the
jump up gonna work what will happen is
the PHP code will be executed and after
all it will crash you can of course
right make the computer the expert more
complicated to move it back down words
to the stack so that you don't overwrite
the jump off with the PHP code but this
the easy way your code will be executed
by the end of the crash so there was a
talk for now so i will show you in this
simple demo
actually it's not so spectacular because
so the first thing I show you is how i
create these exploits for return
oriented pro property oriented
programming what I do is I will select
the classes I wanted to use I told you I
use a scent Lok i will create all the
properties in the class with the same
accessory structions as in the original
class because must be up the same time
otherwise the answer lies will not
overwrite the rights of property and
then I will fill the constructor with ya
with something that fills the properties
in a way that the exploit works in this
case we remember the writers property it
has to be filled with a list of writers
and in this case I just instant this
class which i defined here and again i
have put in the properties i want to
have in the constructor i create the
specific objects or put in the right
data and again the sent mail class
doesn't need to any property at all in
this case because i just want a dummy
class so in just an empty class but the
pubic view again define the template in
a smart and the smarty object you see i
create a smarty object and in the temple
i put in the PHP code and in this case I
was very lazy and put in the global
variable pitch peacoat in there and yeah
this part in the smarty again will
define the properties that are required
to hit the code and yeah in the
constructor I will just create this
special resource XP l and set the output
filter to to an empty array because i
don't want an elevator right now and
here just tell the the callback for the
XP el resource is this object which is
piglets marty and the evil net method
here and then i can define the PHP code
i want in this case it's PHP f 0 and
then i initiate the scent Lok put this
all into an array the first element will
be the the payload and the second
element will be our just any value I
will see realize it and then there's a
little trick I replace the serialized
999 with a zero the idea here is I
already have a zero which is on my
payload and if I put a net another zero
in there and that will get uncivilized
then it will answer lies all the payload
and in the end it will put in the second
element to the array and the second
element will also be key 0 so it will
delete the first one so I can ensure by
manipulating the 0s data here that at
the end of the answer lies all the
payload is distracted and this is
sometimes required because otherwise you
made my might hit a fatal error or an
exception and this will end up in peach
p terminating the request in unsafe way
and so your district will never be
called so you have to ensure that the
destructors call in the end here and
then because I was very lazy at this
time I just create a get request i
equals ours the hostess t-test system in
this case the cookie public off which is
x equals the base64 encoded exploit
yeah and actually I ensure i patched my
pubic it's the latest version but I
patched it back to not half of the
blacklist so all the expert here will
not tell you anything how to bypass the
blacklist you would have to do something
to the serialize string afterward after
this year so you have to like three or
four modifications when you do that it
was the work but I don't show you so
uh
you shouldn't see that clear so what I
do is I will show you when I just
execute the exploit it will create the
header which is all the serialized data
and yeah and now I will just use net cut
to pipe it to net cut and you will see
oh it executed when you when you know
PHP use you know that this looks very
much where's the mouse it looks very
much like a PHP info and yeah it is a
PHP info so we executed PHP info on the
target system and now I would just go
back to the source code and change the
decode that is executed
yeah again I do the pivot export which
will be this time a different string and
now I pipe it again and you see it
executed system comment you name a and
use urban ID and by just changing this
thing you can execute anything you want
and of course sometimes you may be hit a
web so I always PHP safe mode and so on
or basedir so you would just take the
research i presented last year at black
hat and create a anti safe mode expert
on the open basedir export and just put
it in the serialized data yeah this was
the return the property oriented
programming thing now there's another
second example which it will be last one
yes it's a little python script i wrote
to exploit the eunseo wise use of the
free back if you saw something about my
sis can't talk you will see that i
already posted something like this but
actually if you compare it to the sis
can't talk you will see that all the
second half of the exploit how to
achieve code execution is completely
different from what I present at Siskin
because people told me I let their brain
explode with the other method so um this
one was actually far more simple than
the previous one so i'm okay i execute
it and oh actually it's really fast this
time and when i try this in my hotel
room it was endlessly slow i don't know
why same vmware so what what is
happening here it will first send some
civilized data and determine the size of
the ninta juror and so on and what PHP
version that is I didn't show this today
because I don't have the time but if you
look at the siskind slides you can see
how this is possible and then it will
leak the address of the object hunters
we leak the object handles will optimize
it to a better address and scan backward
in memory it will find the year
feder retrieve all the headers the
program Heather's the string table then
it will look up some symbols the
executor Global's snd volt string and
then search the jump-off inside the
executor Global's it finds a stack
address and now this will take a while
it searched all the code segment for
exchange eggs ESP followed by return
this takes a while and my hotel movement
took like two minutes but I hope it's
fast as know
maybe it will never end a what should
happen no is it first searches this
gadget and after that it searches the
pop red gadget which will be done in
less than a second oh there it is and it
sent over the the actual it sent over
the yeah it searches on the stack for
the data we the pattern we put in you
see it found a pattern at some address
on the stack and then it creates a fake
object with exactly this address as
object hangers and then it creates the
requested uses this object and destroys
it and what it does it returns into some
PHP code that actually spawns a shell on
44 44 which is the peach pit shell I
just already connected to it here it's a
nothing out then just to sing that
receives data and Eve else what you
would you send it and give you back what
it does so you can just put in PHP
called PHP info and you have PHP info
again or you put in system you name a
you see it's a federal and the last one
to prove that we are patchy use urban ID
and and you see we are patchy I hope you
can see that from behind we are Apache
and yeah there was a demonstration
finished actually I don't know any
questions am what I presented at sis can
would be protected by the sewage in this
time when I use the object destructor
way that would not be protected but
solution would make leaking the place
where you are in memory harder because
right now solution will I showed you
that when you free some memories of
first bites will be overwritten with the
previous block but with the latest
tuition version this is obfuscated the
pointer so what you would receive would
be an office cated pointer and when this
is reused as a string it will be some
garbage because the string will use a
real pointer but it will be of a skater
pointer so I really good oh yeah so yeah
and when you have swishing patch the
latest one a will not work like this it
will be possible somehow to get around
this but yeah it's a lot harder with
sushi yeah no more questions I saw my
expected that